<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-09-20T21:42:51Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Sigal Samuel</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[I give to charity — but never to people on the street. Is that wrong?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/372519/charity-giving-effective-altruism-mutual-aid-homeless" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=372519</id>
			<updated>2024-09-19T13:11:01Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-22T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your Mileage May Vary is an advice column offering you a new framework for thinking through your ethical dilemmas and philosophical questions. This unconventional column is based on value pluralism — the idea that each of us has multiple values that are equally valid but that often conflict with each other. Here is a Vox [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/PeteGamlen_Charity_9-13.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Your Mileage May Vary is an advice column o</em><em>ffering you a new framework for thinking through your ethical dilemmas and philosophical questions. This unconventional </em><em>column is based on value pluralism — the idea that each of us has multiple values that are equally valid but that often conflict with each other.</em><em> </em><em>Here is a Vox reader’s question, condensed and edited for clarity.</em> </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I think I have a duty to help people much poorer than me, and I give 10 percent of my salary to charities that I think are effective at preventing early death due to poverty. I also live in a city with a lot of visible homelessness, and am often solicited for money. My brain says that this is not an effective way to help people; the people asking might not be the neediest among the homeless in my city, and the people I’m sending malaria bednets and pills to are even needier. At the same time, I feel callous simply ignoring all these requests. What should I do?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Dear Would-Be Optimizer,</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nine times out of ten, when someone’s got an ethical dilemma, I think it’s because a couple of their core values are <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/370030/advice-column-aging-parents-retirement-community-elder-care">conflicting with each other</a>. But you’re that tenth case. I say that because I don’t actually believe your question represents a battle royale between two different values. I think there’s one core value here&nbsp;— helping people —&nbsp;and one strategy that’s masquerading as a value.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That strategy is optimization. I can tell from your phrasing that you’re really into it. You don’t just want to help people —&nbsp;you want to help people as effectively as possible. Since <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23152657/poverty-cash-graduation-ultra-poor-brac">extreme poverty</a> is concentrated in developing countries, and since your dollar goes much further there than it would in your home country, your optimizing impulse is telling you to send your charity money abroad.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Optimization started as a technique for solving certain math problems, but our society has elevated it to the status of a value — arguably one of the dominant values in the Western world. It’s been on the rise since the 1700s, when utilitarian thinkers seeded the idea that both economics and ethics should focus on maximizing utility (meaning, happiness or satisfaction): Just calculate how much utility each action would produce, and choose the one that produces the most.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can see this logic everywhere in modern life —&nbsp;from <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/office-space/the-frustration-with-productivity-culture">work culture</a>, with its emphasis on productivity hacks and agile workflows, to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2019/aug/02/athleisure-barre-kale-tyranny-ideal-woman-labour">wellness culture</a>, with its emphasis on achieving perfect health and optimal sleep. The mandate to “Live your best life!” is turbocharged by Silicon Valley, which urges us to <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/6/25/18682583/biohacking-transhumanism-human-augmentation-genetic-engineering-crispr">quantify every aspect of ourselves</a> with Fitbits, Apple Watches, and Oura Rings, because the more data you have on your body’s mechanical functions, the more you can optimize the machine that is you.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Have a question you want me to answer in the next Your Mileage May Vary column?</strong> </h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Feel free to email me at <a href="mailto:sigal.samuel@vox.com">sigal.samuel@vox.com</a> or <a href="https://forms.gle/wTU5egBukdhyKeL56">fill out this anonymous form</a>! Newsletter subscribers will get my column before anyone else does and their questions will be prioritized for future editions. <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Sign up here!</a></p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Optimization definitely has its place, including in the world of charity. Some charitable organizations are much more effective than others trying to achieve the same goal. All things being equal, we don’t want to blow all our money on the wildly ineffective ones. Effective altruists, members of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23458282/effective-altruism-sam-bankman-fried-ftx-crypto-ethics">utilitarian-flavored social movement</a> that aims to do the most good possible, are fond of noting that the most effective charities out there actually produce <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2020-63320-004">100 times more benefit</a> than the average ones. Why <em>not </em>get the biggest bang for your buck?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem is that we’ve stretched optimization beyond its optimal limits. We try to apply it to everything. But not every domain in life can be optimized, at least not without compromising on some of our values.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In your case, you’re trying to optimize how much you help others, and you believe that means focusing on the neediest. But “neediest” according to what definition of needy? You could assume that financial need is the only type that counts, so you should focus first on lifting everyone out of extreme poverty, and only then help people in less dire straits. But are you sure that only the brute poverty level matters?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Consider an insight from the Jewish tradition. The ancient rabbis were exquisitely sensitive to the psychological needs of poor people, and they argued that these needs should also be taken into account. So they decreed that you shouldn’t only give poor people enough money to survive on —&nbsp;they need to have more than that so they themselves can give charity to others. <a href="https://rabbisacks.org/covenant-conversation/reeh/tzedakah-the-untranslatable-virtue/">As Rabbi Jonathan Sacks writes</a>, “On the face of it, the rule is absurd. Why give X enough money so that he can give to Y? Giving to Y directly is more logical and efficient. What the rabbis understood, however, is that giving is an essential part of human dignity.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rabbis also figured that those who used to be well-off but who fell into poverty might feel an especially acute sense of shame. So they suggested helping these people save face by offering them not just bare necessities, but also —&nbsp;when possible — some of the nicer things that graced their former lifestyles. <a href="https://www.sefaria.org/Ketubot.67b.3?lang=bi">In the Talmud</a>, we hear about one rabbi who gave a newly poor person a fancy meal, and another who acted as the person’s servant for a day! Clearly, the ancient rabbis weren’t only aiming to alleviate poverty. They were also alleviating the shame that can accompany it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The point is that there are many ways to help people and, because they’re so different, they don’t submit to direct comparison. Comparing poverty and shame is comparing apples to oranges; one can be measured in dollars, but the other can’t. Likewise, <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23862090/subjective-wellbeing-wealth-philanthropy-gdp-happiness-givewell">how can you ever hope to compare</a> preventing malaria with alleviating depression? Saving lives versus improving them? Or saving the life of a kid versus saving the life of an adult?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet if you want to optimize, you need to be able to run an apples-to-apples comparison —&nbsp;to calculate how much good different things do in a single currency, so you can pick the best option. But because helping people isn’t reducible to one thing —&nbsp;it’s lots of incommensurable things, and how to rank them depends on each person’s subjective philosophical assumptions — trying to optimize in this domain will mean you have to artificially simplify the problem. You have to pretend there’s no such thing as oranges, only apples.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And when you try to do that, an unfortunate thing happens. You end up rushing past all the unhoused people in your city and, as you put it, you “feel callous simply ignoring all these requests.” Ignoring these human beings comes at a cost, not only to them, but to you. It has a damaging effect on your moral conscience, which feels moved to help but is being told not to.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Future Perfect newsletter</a>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">here</a> to explore the big, complicated problems the world faces and the most efficient ways to solve them. Sent twice a week.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even <a href="http://www.givinggladly.com/2019/02/you-have-more-than-one-goal-and-thats.html">some leaders in effective altruism</a> and the adjacent rationalist community recognize this as a problem and advise people not to shut up that part of themselves. Rationalist Eliezer Yudkowsky, for example, says it’s okay to donate some money to causes that make us feel warm and fuzzy but that aren’t producing maximum utility. His advice is to “<a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/3p3CYauiX8oLjmwRF/purchase-fuzzies-and-utilons-separately">purchase fuzzies and utilons separately</a>” —&nbsp;meaning, devote one pot of money to pet causes and another (much bigger) pot of money to the most cost-effective charities. You can, he says, get your warm fuzzies by volunteering at a soup kitchen and “let that be <em>validated</em> by your other efforts to purchase utilons.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I would also suggest diversifying your giving portfolio, but it’s <em>not </em>because I think you need to “validate” the warm fuzzies. Instead, it’s because of another value: integrity.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When 20th-century British philosopher and critic of utilitarianism <a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/ENTRIES/williams-bernard/">Bernard Williams</a> talked about integrity, he meant it in the literal sense of the word, which has to do with a person’s wholeness (think of related words like “integration”). He argued that moral agency does not sit in a contextless vacuum —&nbsp;it is always some specific person’s agency, and as specific people we have specific commitments.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For example, a mother has a commitment to ensuring her kid’s well-being, over and above her general wish for all kids everywhere to be well. Utilitarianism says she has to consider everyone’s well-being equally, with no special treatment for her own kid —&nbsp;but Williams says that’s an absurd demand. It alienates her from a core part of herself, ripping her into pieces, wrecking her wholeness —&nbsp;her integrity.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It sounds like that’s what you’re feeling when you pass a person experiencing homelessness and ignore them. Ignoring them makes you feel bad because it alienates you from the part of you that is moved by this person’s suffering — that <em>sees the orange</em><em> </em>but is being told there are only apples. That core part of you is no less valuable than the optimizing part, which you liken to your “brain.” It’s not dumber or more irrational. It’s the part that cares deeply about helping people, and without it, the optimizing part would have nothing to optimize!&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So rather than trying to override it, I would encourage you to honor your wish to help in all its fullness. You won’t be able to run a direct apples-to-apples comparison, but that’s okay. Different types of help are useful in their own way and you can divvy up your budget between them, even though there’s no perfect formula to spit out the “optimal” allocations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Diversifying your giving portfolio might look something like this. You keep a small amount of cash or gift cards on you, which you hand out to unhoused people you encounter directly. You put aside a larger amount to donate to a local or national charity with a strong track record. And you devote another amount to a highly effective charity abroad.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You might feel annoyed that there’s no universal mathematical formula that can tell you the best thing to do. If so, I get it. I want the magic formula too! But I know that desire is distinct from the core value here. Don’t let optimization eat the real value you hold dear.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bonus: What I’m reading</h2>

<ul>
<li>I recently read <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/670624/optimal-illusions-by-coco-krumme/"><em>Optimal Illusions</em></a>, a book by mathematician Coco Krumme that traces the roots of optimization’s overreach. As she puts it, “Over the past century, optimization has made an impressive epistemic land grab.”&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>When torn between competing moral theories, does it make sense to diversify your donations in proportion to how much you believe in each theory? Some philosophers argue against that view, but Michael Plant and coauthors defend it in <a href="https://philpapers.org/archive/KACMUP.pdf">this new paper</a>.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2024/09/16/are-your-morals-too-good-to-be-true">This gorgeously written essay</a> by anthropologist Manvir Singh introduced me to the term “cooperating without looking” (or, because it’s a New Yorker essay, “coöperating without looking”). This “tendency to willfully ignore costs and benefits when helping others” —&nbsp;to help without calculating what you’ll gain from the altruistic act — is “a key feature of both romantic love and principled behavior.” When we help this way, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/8/27/20829758/altruism-morality-molly-crockett-study-dating-do-gooders">people trust us more</a>.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Alex Abad-Santos</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Agatha All Along is a Marvel show you don’t have to do homework for ]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/373110/agatha-all-along-mcu-review" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373110</id>
			<updated>2024-09-20T18:58:18Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-21T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you think Patti LuPone would be able to explain who Tony Stark is? Does she know anything about the multiverse? Could she cobble together three facts about Kang the Conqueror? Or the difference between Captain Marvel and Ms. Marvel? Is she familiar with Wanda Maximoff and how she became Scarlet Witch? Did she watch [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Agatha and her coven! Will she backstab? Probably! | Chuck Zlotnick/Courtesy of Marvel" data-portal-copyright="Chuck Zlotnick/Courtesy of Marvel" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/MPY-105-11910_R.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Agatha and her coven! Will she backstab? Probably! | Chuck Zlotnick/Courtesy of Marvel</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Do you think Patti LuPone would be able to explain who Tony Stark is? Does she know anything about the multiverse? Could she cobble together three facts about Kang the Conqueror? Or the difference between Captain Marvel and Ms. Marvel? Is she familiar with Wanda Maximoff and how she became Scarlet Witch? Did she watch <em>WandaVision</em>?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like the probability of <a href="https://ew.com/patti-lupone-eats-death-wing-rather-than-apologize-to-madonna-8709982">Patti LuPone showing up to a Madonna concert</a>, the answer to all the above is no, never, or absolutely not.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://ew.com/patti-lupone-still-knows-nothing-about-the-mcu-no-intention-of-learning-8714356#:~:text=When%20asked%20how%20much%20she,t%20understand%20it%20at%20first.">LuPone will tell you herself</a> that she has no idea how anything in the Marvel universe works. That’s what makes her perfect for <em>Agatha All Along,</em> where she plays the kooky fortune teller Lilia Calderu. It might seem counterintuitive, but the fact that even one of the show’s stars lacks baseline Marvel knowledge goes to show how easy it is to get into the new <em>WandaVision </em>spinoff. It’s a perfectly silly spooky season teaser, even for non-Marvel fans. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Viewers require very little background knowledge to understand the show. That’s given the series a serendipitous story-telling cushion, allowing everyone involved a bit more creative slack to show us how the most maniacal 400-year-old witch to ever haunt the planet got her groove back. It’s a journey that takes us to a spoof of <em>Mare of Easttown</em>, an uncanny play on <em>Bravo’s Real Housewives</em>, a winking riff on <em>The Wizard of Oz</em>, and so many weird places in between.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Agatha</em> is more interested in creating witchy nonsense than sticking with superhero seriousness. Each episode is crammed with spells and potions and magic, rather than reminding you what the Avengers are up to. There’s comedic, spooky world-building happening here in a way that Marvel’s regular fare rarely allows.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All you need to know for <em>Agatha</em> is that Agatha Harkness (Kathyrn Hahn) is a magic user who messed with the very powerful Wanda Maximoff (Elizabeth Olsen),<a href="https://www.vox.com/22302680/wandavision-agatha-harkness-credits-scene-episode-8-scarlet-witch-mcu"> a.k.a. the Scarlet Witch</a>, and lost. Wanda took away all her power, zapped all her memories, and sentenced her to live in a New Jersey town called Westview. Stuck in the suburbs with no magic and no identity, Agatha’s career is in shambles.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her rock bottom is where <em>Agatha All Along </em>picks up.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thanks to the help of Teen (Joe Locke), a character that goes by the name “Teen” because of a spell that doesn’t allow him to say his actual name, and triggered by Wanda Maximoff’s death (see: <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/5/6/23059922/multiverse-of-madness-review-wanda-maximoff-avengers-coworkers"><em>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</em></a>), Agatha breaks out of her trance. Like anyone living a life of quiet desperation in suburban New Jersey, she realizes she needs to regain her powers, and to do so, Agatha will need to assemble a gang of witches — a divination expert (LuPone), a potion brewer (Sasheer Zamata), a protection mage (Ali Ahn), and an earth magic enchantress (Debra Jo Rupp) — to find the “Witches Road” and pass its various trials. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A group of misfits walking down a road and having to help each other along the way? It’s an inverted riff on another very famous story about a road, a wicked witch, a group of new companions, and a troublesome redhead with all the pieces mixed and matched. Unfortunately for her coven, Agatha is very into double-crossing. Fortunately for her coven, everyone knows that Agatha is a double-crosser. Getting to the end of the road will require teamwork and keeping Agatha in check — things neither Agatha nor her coven seem capable of doing. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/MPY-102-03933_R2.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,4.3439330439865,100,91.312133912027" alt="Rupp, Ahn, LuPone, and Zamata " title="Rupp, Ahn, LuPone, and Zamata " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="This is basically the English department at a small liberal arts college (compliment). | Chuck Zlotnick/ Courtesy of Marvel" data-portal-copyright="Chuck Zlotnick/ Courtesy of Marvel" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">When <em>Agatha All Along </em>was greenlit, Marvel mania was still riding high on the back of 2021’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/22229407/wandavision-review-disney-plus-marvel"><em>WandaVision</em></a>, the potential for a multiverse of parallel timelines and worlds, and the promise of a new era of Avengers. Controversy surrounding <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2023/3/28/23658154/jonathan-majors-assault-arrest-allegations-conviction-jail">Jonathan Majors’s</a> domestic abuse allegations and <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23612887/ant-man-quantumania-marvel-flop-era">a series of middling movies</a> has fully derailed that momentum, but the checks were already signed and <a href="https://coveredgeekly.com/agatha-coven-of-chaos-wraps-filming/">filming wrapped</a> for <em>Agatha</em> in May 2023. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Agatha</em> doesn’t have to set the table for the Marvel Cinematic Universe and the series doesn’t feature a character that prominently figures into Marvel’s bigger plans. This could all change, but there’s currently no expectation for the Tony Award-winning LuPone to be busting out of an Iron Man suit to take on Doctor Doom (as fantastic as that sounds). Nor does there seem to be a big plan for Hahn’s Agatha to link up with any of the existing Avengers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Without the pressure of being an integral piece of the Marvel design or needing the characters to save the world (as is the MO of so many Marvel projects), showrunner Jac Schaeffer and <em>Agatha</em>’s creative team have been allowed a bit more freedom to create a show on their terms. That materializes in the show’s penchant for silly musical moments and multiple costume changes. An episode later this season (critics were given four episodes to review) finds the women trapped in a Nancy Meyers-esque coastal mansion, complete with poison wine and a treacherous luxury bathroom.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The only predictable thing about the series is that not everyone in the coven is going to make it to the end, and no one, not even Agatha, is guaranteed a happy ending. Perhaps the witches will all turn on Agatha. Perhaps Agatha will, again, betray the witches who trust her. For once, anything and everything could happen in a Marvel show, and that’s an enchanting possibility.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Miles Bryan</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[New York’s governor wants to “liberate” kids — by taking their phones]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast/372874/phone-ban-school-new-york-governor-kathy-hochul" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=372874</id>
			<updated>2024-09-20T13:53:48Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-21T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Podcasts" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Social Media" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained podcast" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a hot new trend this back-to-school season: cellphone bans.&#160; At least eight states have enacted regulations limiting cellphone use in schools so far this year, and many more individual districts and schools have implemented similar policies on their own. The changes are driven by bipartisan concern that teenagers are unable to break away from [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kathy Hochul wearing a red blazer waves from on stage." data-caption="New York Gov. Kathy Hochul waves during the first day of the Democratic National Convention at the United Center on August 19, 2024, in Chicago, Illinois. | Kevin Dietsch/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Kevin Dietsch/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2167486793.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>New York Gov. Kathy Hochul waves during the first day of the Democratic National Convention at the United Center on August 19, 2024, in Chicago, Illinois. | Kevin Dietsch/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a hot new trend this back-to-school season: cellphone bans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/11/technology/school-phone-bans-indiana-louisiana.html">At least eight states have enacted regulations</a> limiting cellphone use in schools so far this year, and many more individual districts and schools have implemented similar policies on their own. The changes are driven by bipartisan concern that teenagers are unable to break away from their phones and concentrate in class, or even just talk to people in real life, as well as growing concern about the pervasive mental health challenges posed by social media.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“At first I thought it was going to be really annoying, but it’s actually not that bad,” said Lev Zitcer, a freshman at Science Leadership Academy in Philadelphia, which is limiting phone use this year. “I think there’s like a different level of communication that comes with, like, being bored.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">New York Gov. Kathy Hochul agrees. She’s been campaigning to enact a cellphone ban across the Empire State.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I&#8217;ve talked to schools where they have banned cellphones. We’ve found out that there are a lot of challenges involved. But if you get ahead of it, we can be successful,” Hochul told <em>Today, Explained</em> co-host Sean Rameswaram.&nbsp;</p>

<iframe frameBorder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP9434449812" width="100%"></iframe>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Below is an excerpt of Sean’s conversation with Hochul, edited for length and clarity. There’s much more in the full podcast, so listen to <em>Today, Explained</em> on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/today-explained/id1346207297">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3pXx5SXzXwJxnf4A5pWN2A">Spotify</a>, or <a href="https://link.chtbl.com/explainit?sid=site">wherever you get podcasts</a>.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Sean Rameswaram</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You’ve got a lot on your plate. You’ve got that — we saw you at the DNC. Obviously, a lot of election stuff in the air right now. There’s been a lot of controversy around congestion pricing. But we’re here to focus on getting cellphones out of the classroom. Why is this an important issue for you right now?&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Kathy Hochul</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is the end of a long journey that I started about a year-and-a-half, two years ago, when I was seeing data about teenagers really struggling after the pandemic. And I wanted to know what’s going on with the kids. And I have a lot of teenage nieces and nephews and I’m seeing things happening that are not positive. I started talking to teenagers, going around to schools, every corner of the state, convening them and finding out that they are so affected by the bombardment of addictive algorithms on social media throughout the day.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And also the extreme cases of FOMO. They need to know what’s happening — the girls meeting in the restroom without them? Is a party being planned and they’re not there? So these kids’ stress levels are off the charts. But meanwhile, this is during the school day when they’re supposed to be paying attention to a teacher, learning something and ultimately graduating. So it’s a huge distraction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I know the opposition, what they’re going to say — they’re going to tell me that they need to be able to reach their children if there’s a crisis. And I’ll tell you right now, that was my first reaction, like, well, okay, they may not need to have access to the internet, social media during the day, but they certainly need a cellphone to contact their parents if there’s a mass shooting — every parent’s nightmare. But what I heard from law enforcement disabused me of that notion … They said if there is a crisis on campus, no matter what it is, the last thing you want are your kids reaching for their cellphone, trying to communicate with them, take pictures, getting video of it. You want them to pay attention to the head of the classroom, their teacher, to lead them to safety. And I was persuaded the second I heard that from law enforcement.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Sean Rameswaram</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Interesting. As you alluded to, a lot of schools are doing this. Schools across the country are doing this, states across the country are doing this. Blue states, red states, they’re taking different approaches. What approach do you want to take in New York?&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Kathy Hochul</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We’re winding down in our information-gathering process. First of all, I can’t do anything as governor without the legislature. So I’m basically building the case, building the data, the narratives, the information from the surgeon general, other experts, authors who study this, building the argument that, first of all, our young people are better off without access to a cellphone during the school day. And teachers, 72 percent of <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2024/06/12/72-percent-of-us-high-school-teachers-say-cellphone-distraction-is-a-major-problem-in-the-classroom/">teachers in this country are saying</a> it’s a big distraction. It is not helping the learning process. In fact, it’s hindering. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So we are looking at and I’m going to be proposing this in the next few months before they meet again in January, more likely a cellphone ban … It is easier to lock them up at the beginning of the school day, get them out at the end of the school day instead of: “Who’s going to make sure they have them locked up again when they come back from recess? Who&#8217;s going to make sure they’re locked up after lunch? What if they go to the restroom?” … The teachers don&#8217;t want to be the phone police. They want to teach.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Sean Rameswaram</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I want to ask you about how parents might feel about that, because parents seem to be a big part of this equation. And it seems generally, and we’ve heard it from even, you know, a parent on our team, parents want to be able to communicate with their kids throughout the school day. And I’m wondering, one, are you hearing that from parents in New York state, and two, how you’re going to sell this to them when the time comes?&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Kathy Hochul</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s a good question. And here’s what I would say: Talk to the other parents who came to our meetings, but especially talk to the parents who are teachers. We get a lot of them. And people who understand what has happened to their child in this setting, that they’re a different person than they would otherwise be because of this constant communication to others when they’re supposed to [not be] distracted, they’re supposed to be learning. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One mom said, “My son is being bullied throughout the day. My husband now leaves work early, so he’s there to be there when he gets home from school to make sure he doesn’t take his own life.” Because the intense pressure on kids being bullied through their phones, through the social media platform, it’s intense. Now, this is maybe a rare case. I’m not saying it’s common, but people don&#8217;t realize the pressure they’re under about how the kids look, what they say. It’s a tough environment to be a teenager under any circumstance, but you exacerbate it when you have all these outside external factors that are hitting them at the same time.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I was growing up, yes, there were bullies. Yes there were mean kids. You walked down the other hall, you avoided them, right? You can’t avoid being bombarded with messaging throughout the day. And we need our kids to be liberated.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Sean Rameswaram</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Where do you think we&#8217;ll end up as a country? … Do you think we’ll end up in a place where every school will be doing some version of this?&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Kathy Hochul</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My view is that if we never start out with an expectation that they’re allowed in schools, this will be the first generation we liberate from that, and then the subsequent ones will not have that same pressure … It’s all about listening to the kids. They want us to save them. And I’m the adult who’s going to be willing to do that.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris and Oprah humanized the consequences of state abortion bans]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/abortion/373133/kamala-harris-oprah-winfrey-michigan-amber-thurman-abortion-bans-democrats" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373133</id>
			<updated>2024-09-20T21:42:51Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-20T21:45:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Abortion" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health Care" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Trump Administration" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris attended a town hall style forum hosted by Oprah Winfrey in Michigan Thursday night. Harris received questions on most of the 2024 campaign cycle’s top issues, including guns and immigration — but a segment on abortion proved to be an emotional centerpiece that has continued to generate conversation. That moment [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Harris and Oprah on abortion" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Saul Loeb/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2172275535.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris attended a town hall style forum hosted by Oprah Winfrey in Michigan Thursday night. Harris received questions on most of the 2024 campaign cycle’s top issues, including guns and immigration — but a segment on abortion proved to be an emotional centerpiece that has continued to generate conversation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That moment largely focused on a 28-year-old Black woman from Georgia named Amber Thurman, featured in a recent <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/georgia-abortion-ban-amber-thurman-death">ProPublica report</a>. Thurman died in August 2022 after doctors hesitated to treat her following a complication from a medication abortion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After that year’s Supreme Court ruling in <em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization</em>,<em> </em>which overturned the right to an abortion guaranteed by <em>Roe v. Wade</em>,<em> </em>Georgia implemented a strict abortion law that severely limited the abortion-related care available to anyone more than six weeks pregnant. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thurman was at least nine weeks pregnant; state law allows Georgia doctors to perform the procedure she required — a dilation and curettage, or D&amp;C — only <a href="https://www.legis.ga.gov/api/legislation/document/20192020/187013">when the mother’s life is in danger</a>. Doing so before then could result in a doctor going to prison for up to 10 years. At the time, the <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/georgia-abortion-ban-amber-thurman-death">hospital reportedly had no guidance or policy</a> in place about how to navigate the law and ascertain whether a pregnant person’s life was in danger. However, the ProPublica report suggests Thurman’s doctors waited too long — 20 hours after she went to her local hospital —&nbsp;before beginning to operate on her.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A state review found Thurman’s death was “preventable,” and that’s a theme her family stressed as they spoke with Harris and Winfrey.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They just let her die because of some stupid abortion ban,” Thurman’s older sister said. “They treated her like she was just another number.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris offered her condolences to Thurman’s family, and used the moment to argue that Thurman’s story underscores the need for a change for greater abortion rights — as well as the sort of abortion policy Democrats are running on.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Democrats are running on expanding abortion rights</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the wake of <em>Dobbs</em>, more than a <a href="https://www.kff.org/womens-health-policy/dashboard/abortion-in-the-u-s-dashboard/">dozen states</a> have passed strict abortion bans; nearly a dozen others, including Georgia, have laws that severely limit who is able to access an abortion. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Georgia’s law, the <a href="https://www.aclu.org/press-releases/georgia-supreme-court-allows-six-week-abortion-ban-to-remain-in-effect-as-legal-challenge-continues">LIFE Act</a>, was initially passed in 2019 and upheld last year. It outlaws abortion once embryonic cardiac activity is detectable, something that usually occurs around five or six weeks of gestation. It does allow abortions past that point for “medical emergencies,” but is vague about when doctors should declare an emergency, other than <a href="https://www.legis.ga.gov/api/legislation/document/20192020/187013">defining them</a> as a “condition in which an abortion is necessary in order to prevent the death of the pregnant woman or the substantial and irreversible physical impairment of a major bodily function of the pregnant woman.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In many states, there have been efforts to overturn abortion laws — or keep them from being instituted. In Michigan, where the town hall was held, voters enshrined the right to abortion <a href="https://www.aclu.org/news/reproductive-freedom/in-michigan-a-historic-victory-for-abortion-rights">into the state’s constitution in 2023</a>. In the wake of <em>Dobbs</em>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23451074/abortion-ballot-measure-midterms-kentucky-montana-michigan">ballot initiatives to protect abortion access</a> in Kansas, Kentucky, Michigan, Vermont, Montana, and California all passed. And this year, a new slate of states will decide whether to protect access.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There are 10 states with ballot initiatives for this November,” said David Cohen, a law professor at Drexel University who focuses on gender and abortion access. “Five of those states would change the current law in that state … going from [ending] a complete abortion ban [in] <a href="https://southdakotasearchlight.com/2024/09/03/abortion-ballot-measure-challenge-on-course-for-late-september-tr">South Dakota</a> and Missouri, to alleviating a six-week ban in Florida, a 15-week ban in Arizona, and a 12-week ban in Nebraska.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats have tied themselves to these initiatives, hoping that they boost turnout. The party <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/08/us/politics/election-results-democrats-abortion.html">successfully campaigned on abortion</a> in the 2022 midterms, and <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/03/26/abortion-winning-strategy-alabama-democrat-00149205">made abortion a factor</a> in several special elections that were Democratic wins. They hope to <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24101209/abortion-reproductive-freedom-biden-2024-election">make the issue a central part</a> of this year’s election too. According to the <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2024/09/09/issues-and-the-2024-election/">Pew Research Center</a>, abortion is a top five issue for Democratic voters, and a top 10 issue for voters overall.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris has repeatedly attacked former President Donald Trump as being responsible for the end of<em> Roe</em>, arguing as she did Thursday, “The former president chose three members of the United States Supreme Court with the intention that they would overturn the protections of <em>Roe v. Wade</em> — and they did as he intended.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris, meanwhile, has said that, as president, she would approve federal legislation protecting the right to abortion. The current model for that legislation is the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/118th-congress/house-bill/12/text">2023 Women’s Health Protection Act</a>, which would prevent state governments from imposing restrictions on abortion rights pre-viability. (Of course, Harris would probably need a Democratic majority in both the <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/ratings/house-race-ratings">House</a> and <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/ratings/senate-race-ratings">Senate</a> — which currently seems unlikely — for federal abortion protections to pass.) </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For his part, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/trump-was-able-kill-roe-v-wade-rcna84897">Trump has bragged</a> about being the president who overturned <em>Roe</em>, and has argued that abortion policy should be <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-abortion-2024-ban-7bf06e0856b88a710c79a6eb85cffa6a">left to the states</a>. He<em> </em>has said he <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-abortion-2024-ban-7bf06e0856b88a710c79a6eb85cffa6a">would not approve</a> a federal abortion ban if given another term. He has also sought to distance himself from <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce">Project 2025</a>, the conservative vision for the US that includes draconian restrictions on women’s health care, rights, and freedom. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But that’s not to say that a second Trump term couldn’t make even abortion more difficult to access, including through the method he used the first time around: court appointments.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Shohei Ohtani just did something no pro baseball player has ever done]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/sports/373181/shohei-ohtani-50-record-baseball" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373181</id>
			<updated>2024-09-20T21:20:28Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-20T21:20:28Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Sports" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[During a Thursday Los Angeles Dodgers game versus the Miami Marlins, baseball phenom Shohei Ohtani hit a record that no other player has reached.  In that game, Ohtani became the first baseball player to reach the elusive “50/50” milestone, which translates to hitting 50 home runs and stealing 50 bases in one season. This new [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Shohei Ohtani tosses his bat away after hitting a baseball." data-caption="Shohei Ohtani #17 of the Los Angeles Dodgers looks on after hitting a two-run home run against the Miami Marlins during the third inning at loanDepot park on September 17, 2024, in Miami, Florida. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Sam Navarro/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Sam Navarro/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2171952175.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Shohei Ohtani #17 of the Los Angeles Dodgers looks on after hitting a two-run home run against the Miami Marlins during the third inning at loanDepot park on September 17, 2024, in Miami, Florida. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Sam Navarro/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">During a Thursday Los Angeles Dodgers game versus the Miami Marlins, baseball phenom Shohei Ohtani hit a record that no other player has reached. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In that game, Ohtani became the first baseball player to reach the elusive “50/50” milestone, which translates to hitting 50 home runs and stealing 50 bases in one season. This new stat surpasses records set by then-<a href="https://x.com/CodifyBaseball/status/1829025004232577300?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1829025004232577300%7Ctwgr%5Eca092886a526146bbb6db27819986655ad2dd17e%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.si.com%2Fmlb%2Fmariners%2Fnews%2Flos-angeles-dodgers-star-shohei-ohtani-has-now-tied-seattle-mariners-legend-alex-rodriguez-in-baseball-history-with-42-home-runs-and-42-stolen-bases">Seattle Mariner Alex Rodriguez</a> in 1998, <a href="https://www.si.com/mlb/mariners/news/los-angeles-dodgers-star-shohei-ohtani-has-now-tied-seattle-mariners-legend-alex-rodriguez-in-baseball-history-with-42-home-runs-and-42-stolen-bases">when he achieved a “42/42</a>,” and <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/19/sport/shohei-ohtani-50-50/index.html">Atlanta Braves outfielder Ronald Acuña Jr.</a>, who hit 41 home runs and stole 73 bases in 2023. It’s particularly impressive because most players are either muscular power hitters or speedy base stealers, not both.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">HISTORY!<br><br>SHOHEI OHTANI IS THE ONLY MEMBER OF THE 50/50 CLUB. <a href="https://t.co/F1T5D4n6QD">pic.twitter.com/F1T5D4n6QD</a></p>&mdash; Los Angeles Dodgers (@Dodgers) <a href="https://twitter.com/Dodgers/status/1836902635921641963?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This latest record also only adds to Ohtani’s dominance in Major League Baseball. First signed to the Los Angeles Angels in 2017, Ohtani has long been considered uniquely talented because of how good he is at both hitting and pitching, a rare combination. Given his strengths as a “two-way player” – of a caliber not seen since the likes of Babe Ruth – he secured one of the most lucrative contracts in the sport when <a href="https://www.marketplace.org/2023/12/15/how-does-shohei-ohtanis-700-million-deal-actually-work-its-complicated/">the Dodgers offered him a 10-year $700 million deal in 2023</a>. Since joining the MLB, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/07/11/sport/shohei-ohtani-new-contract-record-spt-intl/index.html">Ohtani has become the first player in recent memory to be in the top 15</a> for both home runs scored and strikeouts pitched in a single season. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition to being the only member of the 50/50 club, Ohtani turned in a historically strong game on Thursday. In six at-bats, Ohtani hit three home runs, two doubles, and a single, scoring every time. His hits also led to 10 runs batted in (RBIs), setting a new Dodgers record. And on top of that, he stole two bases. (That means he didn’t just hit the 50/50 mark, he actually now has a record <a href="https://sports.yahoo.com/with-51-51-season-shohei-ohtani-shows-us-yet-again-that-hes-capable-of-the-impossible-232349466.html">51 home runs and stolen bases</a>.) </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Notably, Ohtani is also still <a href="https://bleacherreport.com/articles/10135995-shohei-ohtani-not-sure-if-he-can-pitch-in-playoffs-will-discuss-plan-with-dodgers">recovering from an elbow surgery</a> that’s left him unable to pitch this season.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All that has made Thursday’s game a neat encapsulation of what has made Ohtani a star. He’s demonstrated uncommon versatility in the game as a commanding pitcher and hitter, and now a record-breaking base-stealer, too. Players recovering from surgery often have slow seasons, but that just has not been the case for Ohtani. And as the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/2024/09/20/ohtani-50-50/">Washington Post notes</a>, it can take other players several games to do what Ohtani did Thursday in one. That Ohtani was able to achieve so much in Thursday’s game speaks to why he’s one of the most-hyped athletes in Major League Baseball, and already considered by many fans to be one of the greatest players of all time. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What the record means</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The record is a testament to Ohtani’s unique power as a hitter, as well as his speed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ohtani had one of his strongest offensive games of the season on Thursday, ultimately helping the Dodgers land a spot in this year’s playoffs with the runs he scored. He’s also refined his ability to steal bases, improving his “running mechanics” and broader offensive techniques, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/sports/baseball/shohei-ohtani-50-50-club-5051eafa">according to the Wall Street Journal</a>. As <a href="https://www.espn.com/mlb/story/_/id/41233296/shohei-ohtani-50-stolen-bases-50-50-los-angeles-dodgers">ESPN notes</a>, players in Ohtani’s current position — designated hitter, an athlete who stands in to bat for the pitcher — tend to be slow. Before this year, Ohtani hadn’t stolen more than 26 bases in a single season.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Following an injury in 2023, Ohtani was forced to take a break from pitching and instead used that time and energy to improve his base stealing. His latest success also comes after a dramatic sports gambling scandal earlier this year involving his former interpreter <a href="https://www.espn.com/mlb/story/_/id/40277006/ippei-mizuhara-ex-interpreter-shohei-ohtani-pleads-guilty" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.espn.com/mlb/story/_/id/40277006/ippei-mizuhara-ex-interpreter-shohei-ohtani-pleads-guilty">Ippei Mizuhara</a>, who allegedly stole money from Ohtani to cover debts and pleaded guilty to bank fraud. After an investigation by the League, Ohtani was ultimately exonerated of wrongdoing. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ohtani’s record-shattering game this week firmly established his ascendancy in the sport and was broadly cheered by other baseball greats including the <a href="https://x.com/JoseCanseco/status/1836924675185676490?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1836924675185676490%7Ctwgr%5E33f89c56306a7dbec7717323f9398cfb9ae89d74%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.si.com%2Fmlb%2Flose-canseco-shohei-ohtani-50-50-club">Oakland Athletics’ Jose Canseco</a>, who in 1988 was the first player to hit “40/40,” and fellow players like Tampa Bay Rays’ Taylor Walls, who said that his team was watching Ohtani’s game <a href="https://www.mlb.com/news/shohei-ohtani-50-50-reactions">while playing its own</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This guy is unreal,” basketball legend Lebron James <a href="https://x.com/KingJames/status/1836929696384090239?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1836929696384090239%7Ctwgr%5E9bc57872c38433eec2350ba1c88713abadd35b12%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.mlb.com%2Fnews%2Fshohei-ohtani-50-50-reactions">posted on X</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ohtani’s colleague on the Dodgers, second baseman Gavin Lux, best summed up Thursday’s game and Ohtani’s style of play.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That has to be the greatest baseball game of all time. It has to be,” <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/2024/09/20/ohtani-50-50/">Lux said after the game</a>. “There’s no way. It’s ridiculous. I’ve never seen anybody do that even in Little League, so it’s crazy that he’s doing that at the highest level.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Coleman Lowndes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Kodak invented the “snapshot”]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/373150/how-kodak-invented-the-snapshot" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373150</id>
			<updated>2024-09-20T20:06:33Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-20T20:10:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 1888, Eastman Kodak patented roll film and released the Kodak No. 1 box camera. The company’s business model — selling film, then processing and printing the photos taken on that film for their consumers — made photography available to the masses for the first time. Before then, photography was a complicated process requiring knowledge of [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A vintage advertisement shows a man in a 50s-style tan suit and a handheld Kodak camera smiling and holding it up to his eye, in front of a yellow background reading “Kodak snapshots.”" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Vox Video" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/thumb_clean.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In 1888, Eastman Kodak patented roll film and released the Kodak No. 1 box camera. The company’s business model — selling film, then processing and printing the photos taken on that film for their consumers — made photography available to the masses for the first time. Before then, photography was a complicated process requiring knowledge of chemistry and expertise working big, bulky equipment. <br><br>Later, when Kodak introduced the Brownie in 1900 and sold it for a dollar, photography went fully mainstream. The company dominated the film sales and development market during the 20th century and successfully marketed its automatic cameras as crucial to capturing fleeting moments — at home and on vacation. <br><br>But digital camera sales began to outpace film camera sales in the early 2000s, and Kodak failed to keep up. They filed for bankruptcy in 2012 but do still exist and sell film, albeit to a much smaller market.<br><br>You can find this video and all of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA"><strong>Vox’s videos on YouTube</strong></a>.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Will the Mark Robinson revelations tank Republicans in a key battleground state?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/373094/mark-robinson-slavery-nazi-north-carolina-trump-2024" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373094</id>
			<updated>2024-09-20T17:20:57Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-20T17:20:57Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mark Robinson, the GOP nominee for governor in North Carolina endorsed by former President Donald Trump, was already known to be an extreme right-wing candidate who appeared to be alienating voters in a key battleground state. New revelations about his inflammatory comments on a porn site and his sexual exploits have now shaken even some [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A bald and bearded black man speaking at a lectern and pointing toward the audience. The lectern reads “Trump Vance, make America great again 2024.”" data-caption="North Carolina Lt. Gov. Mark Robinson delivers remarks prior to Republican presidential nominee former President Donald Trump speaking at a campaign event at Harrah’s Cherokee Center on August 14, 2024, in Asheville, North Carolina.  | Grant Baldwin/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Grant Baldwin/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2166169078.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>North Carolina Lt. Gov. Mark Robinson delivers remarks prior to Republican presidential nominee former President Donald Trump speaking at a campaign event at Harrah’s Cherokee Center on August 14, 2024, in Asheville, North Carolina.  | Grant Baldwin/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Mark Robinson, the GOP nominee for governor in North Carolina endorsed by former President Donald Trump, was already known to be an extreme right-wing candidate who <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/governor/2024/north-carolina/">appeared to be alienating voters</a> in a key battleground state. New revelations about his inflammatory comments on a porn site and his sexual exploits have now shaken even some of his Republican colleagues. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/19/politics/kfile-mark-robinson-black-nazi-pro-slavery-porn-forum/index.html">CNN reported</a> on Thursday that Robinson regularly posted on a porn website’s message board between 2008 and 2012. In those posts, he identified himself as a “black NAZI!”, supported a revival of slavery, described himself as a “perv” for enjoying transgender porn, and admitted to “peeping” on women in public showers as a teenager. The posts were found on the site “Nude Africa.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite now supporting legislation that would ban abortion at around six weeks of pregnancy, he also said on the forum that he would not care if a celebrity had an abortion, though he would “wanna see the sex tape!” And though he would become North Carolina’s first Black governor if elected, he referred to Martin Luther King Jr. as a “commie bastard.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Robinson’s email has also been <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/19/north-carolina-lt-governor-mark-robinson-ashley-madison-00180107">connected to an account on Ashley Madison</a>, an online dating website for people seeking to have an affair.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Robinson, North Carolina’s current lieutenant governor, denied writing the posts, and his campaign said he has not made an Ashley Madison account.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, several North Carolina Republicans, including some running in competitive races this fall, subsequently <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/elections/2024/09/19/mark-robinson-north-carolina-governor/">pressured him to drop out</a> of the contest to succeed incumbent Democratic Gov. Roy Cooper, who is term-limited. He has <a href="https://x.com/AudreyFahlberg/status/1836841075291423034?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1836841075291423034%7Ctwgr%5E3c1d8d7fc455413cd5589b13e879cda3f381de8f%7Ctwcon%5Es1_c10&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fiframe.nbcnews.com%2F1yzZRDd%3F_showcaption%3Dtrueapp%3D1">opted to stay in the race</a>, in which he is running behind his Democratic rival, North Carolina Attorney General Josh Stein, by between 5 and 14 percentage points in <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/governor/2024/north-carolina/">polls conducted over the last month</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In doing so, Robinson might drag down not just down-ballot Republicans in a closely divided purple state, but also potentially Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We have few examples of reverse coattails where a down-ballot candidate hurts the top of the ticket,” Whit Ayres, a GOP pollster, told Vox. “But if anyone could do it, it’s this character.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Robinson is extreme even for MAGA</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The current scandals don’t mark the first time Robinson has been mired in controversy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He has hurled hateful remarks at everyone from <a href="https://www.facebook.com/mark.k.robinson.3/posts/pfbid02MBjRmDb76te7jCx9KTrq33YrGkz5UhndpgwSo8zcqkG4y5BAd1p9kquRKzz57z9Dl">Michelle Obama</a> to the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/05/04/politics/kfile-nc-lt-gov-mark-robinson-mocked-school-shooting-survivors/index.html">survivors of the Parkland school shooting</a>. He’s called the <a href="https://www.vox.com/lgbtq">LGBTQ</a> community “<a href="https://www.msnbc.com/rachel-maddow-show/maddowblog/n-c-republican-under-fire-after-calling-lgbtq-people-filth-n1281230">filth</a>.” He threatened to use his AR-15 against the government if it “<a href="https://www.msnbc.com/rachel-maddow-show/maddowblog/north-carolinas-robinson-faces-pushback-ar-15-rhetoric-rcna31411">gets too big for its britches</a>,” and he wants to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/01/17/politics/kfile-mark-robinson-abortion-ban-no-exceptions/index.html">outlaw all abortions</a> as well as <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/north-carolina-gop-mark-robinson-women-vote_n_65e7d899e4b0f9d26cacc002?hlo">return to a time when women couldn’t vote</a>. He’s also ridiculed the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/mark.k.robinson.3/posts/pfbid02GBDTEF8NNyCL4oZ57MFUPb3VrRAAG77zqsx9WCjX6eFbkQaDywKFYHqXaMWkTXufl">Me Too movement</a>, <a href="https://www.wral.com/story/nc-s-lieutenant-governor-we-are-called-to-be-led-by-men-not-women/20318578/">women generally</a>, and <a href="https://www.newsobserver.com/news/politics-government/article277465388.html">climate change</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It seems Robinson is willing to entertain all manner of conspiracy theories, too. He’s a <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/msnbc/watch/-double-trouble-holocaust-denier-maga-extremist-wins-nc-gop-gov-primary-205532741591">Holocaust denier</a> and has a <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/mark-robinson-north-carolina-governors-race-past-comments-trump-2024-2024-3">history of antisemitic remarks</a>. He’s suggested that the 1969 moon landing might have been fake, that 9/11 was an “<a href="https://www.facebook.com/mark.k.robinson.3/posts/10155870818062360">inside job</a>,” that the music industry is <a href="https://www.facebook.com/mark.k.robinson.3/posts/pfbid0BTKMBceuRFaoVMyW1CYtFaeicHd3hXB5QSfaq6hfFxBjw4ScJ5Wzabk9ZypoDXNPl">run by Satan</a>, and that billionaire Democratic donor George Soros <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/republican-mark-robinson-conspiracy-theorist-north-carolina-governor-race_n_64df8cabe4b0ce7f01203a6b">orchestrated the Boko Haram kidnappings</a> of school girls in 2014.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In spite of all of this, Robinson was not only able to win his party’s nomination for the state’s most powerful position, but he did so by a margin of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/03/05/us/elections/results-north-carolina-governor.html">more than 45 percent</a> over his rivals. The other Republican candidates, trial lawyer Bill Graham and state treasurer Dale Folwell, raised concerns about Robinson’s <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/03/05/north-carolina-gov-primary-00144815">electability</a>, but ultimately neither could compete with his name recognition nor his MAGA bona fides in a state that twice voted for Trump.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Will Robinson hurt the GOP’s chances this fall in North Carolina?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Robinson might function as an ideal foil for Democrats — not just in the governor’s race, but also in the presidential and down-ballot races. Robinson might struggle to capture the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/03/05/us/elections/results-north-carolina-governor.html">more than 35 percent</a> of GOP voters who opposed him in a contentious primary. Republican leaders certainly seem concerned.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We knew that [he was extreme], but I still think the revelations over the last 24 hours are stunning,” former Rep. David Price (D-NC) told Vox. “I believe the Republican leaders know that as well. A corner has been turned in terms of Robinson being able to count on even the most faithful Republican supporters.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Rep. Patrick McHenry (R-NC) <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4889585-north-carolina-gop-candidate-mark-robinson-scandal/">told the Hill</a> that the reports about Robinson are “not good.” And Rep. Richard Hudson (R-NC), chair of the National Republican Congressional Committee, said they were <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4889585-north-carolina-gop-candidate-mark-robinson-scandal/">“very concerning</a>.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“My hope is that [the] lieutenant governor can reassure the people of North Carolina that the allegations aren’t true,” he said. “He said they’re not true. I think he needs to have the opportunity to explain to the people in North Carolina exactly how these allegations aren’t true.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The fact that even Republicans are distancing themselves from Robinson suggests that the tide may turn further in Democrats’ favor in North Carolina.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That doesn’t mean, however, that Robinson will deliver Democrats a major victory. Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris are <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/north-carolina/">practically tied in the state</a>, according to FiveThirtyEight’s polling average. And Republican candidates have won three presidential elections in North Carolina since Barack Obama surprisingly took the state in 2008 — including Trump twice. The state has stayed on the red side of purple, though it does have a tradition of split-ticket voting. That helped power Cooper’s two election wins and has added to the belief that the state may be in reach for Democrats. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I don’t think celebration is called for because so much more is at stake than just the governor’s race,” Price said. “We know how tight this is.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Supreme Court is about to decide whether to interfere in the election again]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/372613/supreme-court-nevada-ballot-green-party" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=372613</id>
			<updated>2024-09-20T14:31:39Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-20T14:30:22Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor’s note, September 20, 10:30 am: The Supreme Court denied the Green Party’s request to be placed back on the Nevada ballot. No justice publicly announced their dissent, and the Court did not explain why it ruled the way it did. The original story, published September 18, follows. Earlier this month, Nevada’s Supreme Court ruled [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Stein speaking into a microphone in front of an audience." data-caption="Green Party Presidential Candidate Jill Stein holds a rally in New York City. | Justin Sullivan/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Justin Sullivan/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/7528747/614197134.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Green Party Presidential Candidate Jill Stein holds a rally in New York City. | Justin Sullivan/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Editor’s note, September 20</strong>, <strong>10:30 am: </strong>The Supreme Court <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/orders/courtorders/092024zr_h3cj.pdf">denied the Green Party’s request</a> to be placed back on the Nevada ballot. No justice publicly announced their dissent, and the Court did not explain why it ruled the way it did. The original story, published September 18, follows.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Earlier this month, Nevada’s Supreme Court ruled that <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A262/325988/20240913163035975_Nevada%20Green%20Party%20Application%20Appendix.pdf">the Green Party must be removed from that state’s 2024 ballot</a> because of a paperwork error.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevada law requires people who collect petition signatures seeking to place a “minor party” on the ballot to “verify that they believe each person signing the petition is a registered voter in the county of his or her residence.” The Greens did not comply with this requirement, so a majority of the state supreme court ruled that they cannot appear on the ballot this year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is, however, a slight complication.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When the Green Party originally submitted documents to the Nevada secretary of state’s office announcing its intention to start gathering signatures, they were given improper instructions. An employee of the Secretary of State responded to this submission, and said the party should use a specific form to gather signatures. Unfortunately, this employee attached the wrong signature collection form to that email — the attached form was the form that is used to collect signatures for a ballot initiative (that is, a vote to change Nevada law), not to collect signatures to place a minor party on the ballot.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And so the Green Party is now in the US Supreme Court, <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A262/325988/20240913162957159_Nevada%20Green%20Party%20Supreme%20Court%20Application%20for%20Vacatur.pdf">claiming that their constitutional rights were violated</a> because they complied with this employee’s instructions, and were later removed from the ballot because they did so. The case in the Supreme Court is known as <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/docket/docketfiles/html/public/24a262.html"><em>Nevada Green Party v. Aguilar</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Notably, the Greens are represented in the Supreme Court by Jay Sekulow, a <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/2/3/21120659/trump-impeachment-trial-jay-sekulow-mark-zaid-coup-whistleblower">former lawyer to Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump</a>. Sekulow is one of the better lawyers in Trump’s orbit — he’s <a href="https://jaysekulow.com/index.html">argued a dozen cases in the Supreme Court</a>, mostly on behalf of Christian Right causes — and his presence on this case suggests that Republicans are eager to put the Greens back on the ballot in a key swing state.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And why wouldn’t they be? The Green Party is largely a vehicle for leftier-than-thou candidates who <a href="https://dailyorange.com/2020/11/howie-hawkins-unsurprised-election-results-hopeful-green-party/">rarely garner even one percent of the popular vote</a>. To the extent that the Green Party matters at all, it’s because they might attract enough voters who would otherwise support Democrats to swing a very close election. (And the race in Nevada is expected to be <em>very</em> close: <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/nevada/">Polling averages</a> currently have the presidential candidates separated by less than a percentage point.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For this reason, it probably won’t surprise anyone to learn that the plaintiff in the lawsuit that kicked the Greens off the Nevada ballot was the state’s Democratic Party. Both major parties are quite aware of the potential that a Green Party presidential candidate could act as a spoiler in this November’s election. The Republicans want to help make that happen; the Democrats want to avoid it at all costs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But what does the law actually say about the Green Party’s bid to appear on Nevada’s ballot?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The short answer is that, if there were no procedural obstacles to the Supreme Court ruling in the Greens’ favor, then they would have a plausible — but not, exactly, airtight — case. In his <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A262/325988/20240913162957159_Nevada%20Green%20Party%20Supreme%20Court%20Application%20for%20Vacatur.pdf">brief to the justices</a>, Sekulow cites some precedents which are helpful to the Green Party, but that hardly compel the conclusion that the party has a right to appear on Nevada ballot.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That said, there are many procedural obstacles in this case that could prove fatal to the Green Party’s claims. Among other things, Nevada is <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A262/326182/20240917155213549_SCOTUS%20Opposition%20NGP%20v.%20Aguilar-Final.pdf">racing to meet a September 21 deadline</a> to mail ballots to overseas military personnel — a deadline that is set by federal law. If the Supreme Court orders Nevada to change those ballots so close to this deadline, it will probably be impossible for the state to meet it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, it’s always dangerous to bet that this Supreme Court, with its 6-3 Republican supermajority, will rule against the interests of Donald Trump. This is, after all, the same Court that recently said that <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">Trump has sweeping immunity from prosecution</a> for crimes he committed using the official powers of the president — a form of immunity that has no basis in the Constitution.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What are the legal issues in <em>Nevada Green Party</em>?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sekulow’s strongest argument is that the Green Party cannot be removed from the ballot for complying with a state employee’s instructions. In an email to the Green Party, Sekulow claims, a state employee told them to “<a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A262/325988/20240913162957159_Nevada%20Green%20Party%20Supreme%20Court%20Application%20for%20Vacatur.pdf">Please use the documents attached to begin collecting signatures</a>.” The Green Party then used the attached document to collect signatures, only to discover later that they’d used the wrong form.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This argument has some superficial appeal&nbsp;— it does, at the very least, seem unfair to punish a party that complied with a government employee’s instructions. Many of the Supreme Court’s past decisions, however, cut against Sekulow’s argument. As the Court said in <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/467/51/"><em>Heckler v. Community Health Services</em></a><em> </em>(1984), “those who deal with the Government are expected to know the law, and may not rely on the conduct of Government agents contrary to law.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sekulow does cite <a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=14251472317142949199&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=6&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr">two</a> <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/379/536/">cases</a> that suggest that someone cannot be charged with a crime if they acted consistently with the government’s instructions. But the Green Party is not accused of criminal activity. The only issue in this case is whether it may appear on the 2024 ballot in Nevada.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At best, in other words, Sekulow is asking the Supreme Court to extend these two criminal cases to a new context, and hold that the Constitution also protects political parties that comply with a government employee’s instructions regarding ballot access from being kicked off the ballot. But there are several very good reasons why the Court should not extend those precedents in this case.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One is that, while the state did provide the Green Party with the wrong form, it should have been obvious to the party that it was sent this form by mistake. The correct form requires petition circulators to certify that they believe each signatory is a registered voter in the county where they live. The form that the Green Party actually used, by contrast, was the correct form to collect signatures for ballot initiatives and referendums. It requires circulators to attest that signatories “had an opportunity before signing to <a href="https://casetext.com/regulation/nevada-administrative-code/chapter-295-initiative-and-referendum/section-295020-requirements-for-individual-documents-of-petitions-for-initiative-or-referendum">read the full text of the act or resolution on which the initiative or referendum is demanded</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It appears, in other words, that the Green Party’s petition circulators all attested, under penalty of perjury, that their petition signatories had an opportunity to read the full text of a ballot initiative that doesn’t actually exist.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Additionally, there are procedural reasons why the Green Party’s request to be put back on Nevada’s ballot should fail. One is the Supreme Court’s conclusion in <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supremecourt/text/06-375"><em>Purcell v. Gonzalez</em></a> (2006) that federal courts should be cautious about altering a state’s election rules as the election draws close, out of concern that late-breaking changes to those rules could foster confusion about how the election should be conducted.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This Court has not always applied <em>Purcell</em> consistently — frankly, it has historically applied it much more aggressively <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/2/8/22922774/supreme-court-merrill-milligan-alabama-brett-kavanaugh-racial-gerrymandering-voting-rights-act">when lower court decisions benefit Democrats</a> than it has <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/368310/supreme-court-rnc-mi-famila-vota">when they benefit Republicans</a> — but it’s hard to imagine a more compelling case for invoking <em>Purcell</em> than the <em>Nevada Green Party</em> case.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevada is trying to make a Saturday deadline, set by federal law, to deliver ballots to overseas military personnel. It’s now Wednesday. If the Supreme Court gets involved now, it will almost certainly be impossible for Nevada to meet its obligation under federal law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Indeed, according to Nevada Secretary of State Francisco Aguilar, at least one Nevada county has <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A262/326182/20240917155213549_SCOTUS%20Opposition%20NGP%20v.%20Aguilar-Final.pdf">already mailed out military ballots that do not include the Green Party</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s also another, closely related reason why the Supreme Court should rule against the Green Party. The Court has long held that a party forfeits certain relief, even if it otherwise would be entitled to it, if it shows a “<a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=5537667947736700885&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=6&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr">lack of diligence</a>” in asserting its rights, such as by waiting so long to assert a legal claim that the delay itself harms the opposing party. Yet the Green Party <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/nevada-green-party-v-aguilar/">waited an entire week</a> from the Nevada Supreme Court’s September 6 order removing it from the ballot to file its case in the US Supreme Court, rather than doing so immediately.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus, one of the reasons why it would likely be impossible for Nevada to comply with both the federal deadline governing military ballots, and a US Supreme Court order requiring it to place the Green Party on the ballot, is that the Green Party ran out the clock before seeking relief from the justices.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of which is a long way of saying that, while the Nevada employee’s misleading instructions to the Green Party should raise some eyebrows, a Supreme Court order putting the Green Party on the ballot would be inappropriate.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kelsey Piper</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What it means that new AIs can “reason”]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/372843/openai-chagpt-o1-strawberry-dual-use-technology" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=372843</id>
			<updated>2024-09-19T18:40:04Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-20T13:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[An underappreciated fact about large language models (LLMs) is that they produce “live” answers to prompts. You prompt them and they start talking in response, and they talk until they’re done. The result is like asking a person a question and getting a monologue back in which they improv their answer sentence by sentence. This [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="In this photo illustration, the sign of OpenAl o1, the first in a planned series of “reasoning” models that have been trained to answer more complex questions, is displayed on a smartphone screen on September 13, 2024, in Suqian, Jiangsu Province of China." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-2171652505.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>In this photo illustration, the sign of OpenAl o1, the first in a planned series of “reasoning” models that have been trained to answer more complex questions, is displayed on a smartphone screen on September 13, 2024, in Suqian, Jiangsu Province of China.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">An underappreciated fact about large language models (LLMs) is that they produce “live” answers to prompts. You prompt them and they start talking in response, and they talk until they’re done. The result is like asking a person a question and getting a monologue back in which they improv their answer sentence by sentence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This explains several of the ways in which large language models can be so frustrating. The model will sometimes contradict itself even within a paragraph, saying something and then immediately following up with the exact opposite because it’s just “reasoning aloud” and sometimes adjusts its impression on the fly. As a result, AIs need a lot of hand-holding to do any complex reasoning.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Future Perfect newsletter</a>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">here</a> to explore the big, complicated problems the world faces and the most efficient ways to solve them. Sent twice a week.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One well-known way to solve this is called <a href="https://www.promptingguide.ai/techniques/cot">chain-of-thought prompting</a>, where you ask the large language model to effectively “show its work” by “‘thinking” out loud about the problem and giving an answer only after it has laid out all of its reasoning, step by step.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Chain-of-thought prompting makes language models behave <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.11903">much more intelligently</a>, which isn’t surprising. Compare how you’d answer a question if someone shoves a microphone in your face and demands that you answer immediately to how you’d answer if you had time to compose a draft, review it, and then hit “publish.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The power of think, then answer</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">OpenAI’s latest model, <a href="https://openai.com/o1/">o1</a> (nicknamed Strawberry), is the first major LLM release with this “think, then answer” approach built in.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unsurprisingly, the company <a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-openai-o1-preview/">reports</a> that the method makes the model a lot smarter. In a blog post, OpenAI said o1 “performs similarly to PhD students on challenging benchmark tasks in physics, chemistry, and biology. We also found that it excels in math and coding. In a qualifying exam for the International Mathematics Olympiad (IMO), GPT-4o correctly solved only 13 percent of problems, while the reasoning model scored 83 percent.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This major improvement in the model’s ability to think also intensifies some of the dangerous capabilities that <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/openai-advanced-gpt-model-potential-risks-need-regulation-experts-1953311">leading AI researchers have long been on the lookout</a> for. Before release, OpenAI tests its models for their capabilities with <a href="https://assets.ctfassets.net/kftzwdyauwt9/67qJD51Aur3eIc96iOfeOP/71551c3d223cd97e591aa89567306912/o1_system_card.pdf">chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear weapons</a>, the abilities that would be most sought-after by terrorist groups that don’t have the expertise to build them with current technology.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As my colleague Sigal Samuel <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/371827/openai-chatgpt-artificial-intelligence-ai-risk-strawberry">wrote recently</a>, OpenAI o1 is the first model to score “medium” risk in this category. That means that while it’s not capable enough to walk, say, a complete beginner through developing a deadly pathogen, the evaluators found that it “can help experts with the operational planning of reproducing a known biological threat.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These capabilities are one of the most clear-cut examples of AI as a <a href="https://researchfeatures.com/ai-dual-use-technology-cautionary-tale/">dual-use technology</a>: a more intelligent model becomes more capable in a wide array of uses, both benign and malign.<br><br>If future AI does get good enough to tutor any college biology major through steps involved in recreating, say, smallpox in the lab, this would potentially have catastrophic casualties. At the same time, AIs that can tutor people through complex biology projects will do an enormous amount of good by accelerating lifesaving research. It is intelligence itself, artificial or otherwise, that is the double-edged sword.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The point of doing AI safety work to evaluate these risks is to figure out how to mitigate them with policy so we can get the good without the bad.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to (and how not to) evaluate an AI</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Every time OpenAI or one of its competitors (Meta, Google, Anthropic) releases a new model, we retread the same conversations. Some people find a question on which the AI performs very impressively, and awed screenshots circulate. Others find a question on which the AI bombs — say, “<a href="https://community.openai.com/t/incorrect-count-of-r-characters-in-the-word-strawberry/829618">how many ‘r’s are there in ‘strawberry</a>’” or “<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OpenAI/comments/1ctfq4f/a_man_and_a_goat/">how do you cross a river with a goat</a>” — and share those as proof that AI is still more hype than product.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of this pattern is driven by the lack of good scientific measures of how capable an AI system is. We used to have benchmarks that were meant to describe AI language and reasoning capabilities, but the rapid pace of AI improvement has <a href="https://cset.georgetown.edu/article/evaluating-large-language-models/">gotten ahead of them, with benchmarks often “saturated.”</a> This means AI performs as well as a human on these benchmark tests, and as a result they’re no longer useful for measuring further improvements in skill.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I strongly recommend trying AIs out yourself to get a feel for how well they work. (OpenAI o1 is only available to paid subscribers for now, and even then is very rate-limited, but there are new top model releases all the time.) It’s still too easy to fall into the trap of trying to prove a new release “impressive” or “unimpressive” by selectively mining for tasks where they excel or where they embarrass themselves, instead of looking at the big picture.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The big picture is that, across nearly all tasks we’ve invented for them, AI systems are continuing to improve rapidly, but the incredible performance on almost every test we can devise hasn’t yet translated into many economic applications. Companies are still <a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter/365292/ai-bubble-nvidia-chatgpt-stock-market-crash">struggling</a> to identify how to make money off LLMs. A big obstacle is the inherent unreliability of the models, and in principle an approach like OpenAI o1’s — in which the model gets more of a chance to think before it answers — might be a way to drastically improve reliability without the expense of training a much bigger model.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Sometimes, big things can come from small improvements&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In all likelihood, there isn’t going to be a silver bullet that suddenly fixes the longstanding limitations of large language models. Instead, I suspect they’ll be gradually eroded over a series of releases, with the unthinkable becoming achievable and then mundane over the course of a few years — which is precisely how&nbsp;AI has proceeded so far.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But as ChatGPT — which itself was only a moderate improvement over OpenAI’s previous chatbots but which reached hundreds of millions of people overnight — demonstrates, technical progress being incremental doesn’t mean societal impact is incremental. Sometimes the grind of improvements to various parts of how an LLM operates — or improvements to its UI so that more people will try it, like the chatbot itself — push us across the threshold from “party trick&#8221; to “essential tool.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And while OpenAI has come <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/5/17/24158403/openai-resignations-ai-safety-ilya-sutskever-jan-leike-artificial-intelligence">under fire recently</a> for ignoring the safety implications of their work and silencing whistleblowers, its o1 release seems to take the policy implications seriously, including collaborating with external organizations to check what their model can do. I’m grateful that they’re making that work possible, and I have a feeling that as models keep improving, we will need such conscientious work more than ever.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story originally appeared in the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect">Future Perfect</a>&nbsp;newsletter.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Sign up here!</a></em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Benji Jones</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The extremely messy, profoundly confusing fight over who should profit from animal DNA]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/372277/digital-sequence-information-dsi-cop16-explained" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=372277</id>
			<updated>2024-09-19T23:35:58Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-20T11:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Down to Earth" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Science" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stuck to rocks, shells, and piers in oceans around the world is a strange little creature called a sea squirt. It resembles a squishy potato and has two valves poking out, which it uses to suck in and expel seawater. Sea squirts are special for a few reasons. They tend to shoot water out of [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Marine animals known as sea squirts, shown here, produce defense compounds that can damage cancer cells. Scientists have used them to produce anticancer drugs. | Reinhard Dirscherl/ullstein bild via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Reinhard Dirscherl/ullstein bild via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-883204826.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Marine animals known as sea squirts, shown here, produce defense compounds that can damage cancer cells. Scientists have used them to produce anticancer drugs. | Reinhard Dirscherl/ullstein bild via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Stuck to rocks, shells, and piers in oceans around the world is a strange little creature called a sea squirt. It resembles a squishy potato and has two valves poking out, which it uses to suck in and expel seawater. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sea squirts are special for a few reasons. They tend to shoot water out of their valves when you squeeze them. And like oysters and clams, they filter ocean water, helping keep it clean. They also produce chemical compounds to defend themselves that are known to damage cancer cells. Scientists have used those compounds to develop drugs for patients with certain kinds of cancer.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sea squirts are among an endless list of animals, plants, and microbes that stand to improve human lives.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Researchers estimate that an astonishing <a href="https://pharmaceutical-journal.com/article/research/pharmaceuticals-from-marine-sources-past-present-and-future">70 percent</a> of antibiotics and cancer treatments in use today are rooted in natural organisms, from plants to snakes to sea sponges. The first medication to treat HIV <a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/23921394/deep-sea-mining-sea-sponges-medicine-drugs">came from a Caribbean sea sponge</a>. The cosmetic drug Botox is derived from a bacterium. The enzyme used to stonewash jeans was originally derived from wild microbes in salt lakes in Kenya.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Collectively, these natural derivatives — and the profits they generate — are considered the benefits of a planet with healthy biodiversity. And maintaining these benefits is a key justification for protecting nature: It can literally save our lives. But a key question that has long been a source of division among global conservation leaders is who, exactly, should reap those biodiversity benefits.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a <a href="https://theconversation.com/drawn-out-battle-over-genetic-resources-dampens-africas-hopes-57289">long history</a> of what some advocates and researchers call <a href="https://thinklandscape.globallandscapesforum.org/48905/biopiracy-the-largely-lawless-plundering-of-earths-genetic-wealth/">biopiracy</a>. It typically refers to when companies take organisms from poor nations and Indigenous communities, such as medicinal plants, and use them to develop commercial products, failing to share the benefits back with them. Those benefits include things like money but also access to those products and research results.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Until recently, the solution to exploitative innovation was, at least in theory, relatively straightforward. Under a United Nations treaty called the <a href="https://www.cbd.int/">Convention on Biological Diversity</a> (CBD), countries can require that foreign researchers sign benefit-sharing agreements before granting them permission to retrieve wild organisms. Essentially, under those agreements, you can’t walk out of a country with medicinal plants without first agreeing on how you’ll compensate that country and its people.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there’s an enormous loophole to this approach that keeps getting bigger.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Major advances in biotechnologies have made it <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC10376292/">easier to sequence</a> and analyze DNA. Now, researchers and companies no longer rely only on physical samples to make stuff derived from biodiversity. They increasingly make products — drugs, vaccines, better crops, and so on — using DNA and RNA sequences, or other genetic data.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This digital biodiversity data, referred to by the arcane term digital sequence information, or DSI, is found abundantly in scientific databases that are free for anyone to use. And it’s not regulated by the CBD treaty. That means industries can create vaccines and other commercial products using DSI without sharing the benefits from those products — the benefits of biodiversity — with whatever country or local community the sequence information originates from. It’s kind of like what platforms like<strong> </strong>Napster did to the music industry: Instead of having to buy CDs from stores and funneling money to musicians, once music was digitized, you could eventually stream unlimited music online for free.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you find DSI confusing, that’s because it is.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Experts who have been debating for years about how to regulate DSI don’t even agree on how to define the term. Does it cover just DNA and RNA sequences? Would it also include 3D images of proteins and epigenetic data (i.e., changes to how genes are expressed)? They also don’t agree on how benefit sharing should work. Some countries, especially those with smaller economies, want genetic information tracked from its place of origin all the way to the final products. Others say that’s essentially impossible.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-1314013253.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A petri dish with genetically modified barley sprouts at the Leibnitz Institute of Plant Genetics and Crop Plant Research in Gatersleben, Germany. | Sean Gallup/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Sean Gallup/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">This debate will come to a head this October in the Colombian city of Cali. Countries that are party to CBD — which notably does not include the US, in part because conservative lawmakers <a href="https://www.vox.com/22434172/us-cbd-treaty-biological-diversity-nature-conservation">tend to dislike global treaties</a> — will convene for their biannual meeting to discuss global conservation issues. One of their main goals this year, at what will be known as COP16 — but not <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24000157/cop28-climate-conference-uae-dubai-winners-losers-fossil-fuels-methane"><em>that </em>COP</a> — is to hammer out a plan to bring more accountability to the use of DSI around the world.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On one hand, such a plan seems impossible to put in place. Companies hold a tremendous amount of power and typically want fewer regulations, not more. But it could also be a massive opportunity. If developed nations and industries shared some of the money and knowledge that is derived from digital biodiversity data, it could be used to conserve nature in the places where it is most vital —&nbsp;and most at risk.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Who benefits from nature?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The debate and tensions around DSI are rooted in inequality. Put simply, rich nations have loads of scientific resources, whereas many poorer nations have loads of less-explored biodiversity. And up until now, the relationship between the two groups has been lopsided.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Decades ago, a US pharmaceutical company <a href="https://academic.oup.com/chicago-scholarship-online/book/35560/chapter-abstract/305951735?redirectedFrom=fulltext">developed</a> anticancer drugs with the help of a plant from Madagascar called the rosy periwinkle; the company didn’t share its profits with the people of Madagascar. You can find similar stories with the antifungal spray <a href="https://thinklandscape.globallandscapesforum.org/48905/biopiracy-the-largely-lawless-plundering-of-earths-genetic-wealth/">Neemax</a>, derived from a tree in India, and muscle relaxants made with compounds from <a href="https://hopp.uwpress.org/content/63/2/247">curare</a>, a group of poisonous plants from the Amazon.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-1239644558.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,12.845868224401,100,74.308263551199" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A praying mantis hides within a Madagascar rosy periwinkle plant. | Soumyabrata Roy/NurPhoto via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Soumyabrata Roy/NurPhoto via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">“Scientists from the global north have frequently extracted data and samples from the Global South without the permission of the people there, without collaborating meaningfully — if at all — with local scientists, and without providing any benefit to the countries where they conduct their work,” a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00545-3.pdf">team of researchers wrote</a> earlier this year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Global environmental leaders recognized this problem decades ago. When they established the <a href="https://www.vox.com/22434172/us-cbd-treaty-biological-diversity-nature-conservation">Convention on Biological Diversity</a> in 1992, still the world’s most important biodiversity agreement, they made benefit-sharing one of three main goals of the treaty, along with conserving biodiversity and using it sustainably. Under the agreement, benefits derived from plants and animals should, at a minimum, be shared with the countries and local communities where that biodiversity is found — and especially with the groups who have safeguarded it, such as Indigenous communities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nearly two decades later, CBD made the requirements around benefit-sharing more concrete and enforceable through an agreement called <a href="https://www.cbd.int/abs/default.shtml">the Nagoya Protocol</a>, named after the Japanese city where it was adopted. The agreement essentially affirms that countries have the legal right to regulate access to physical plants, animals, and other elements of biodiversity within their borders. All countries are also supposed to make sure that any bits of biodiversity they —&nbsp;or their companies —&nbsp;use that come from other nations are collected with the consent of that country.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Share your feedback</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Do you have feedback on this story or tips for the author? Reach out to Vox reporter Benji Jones at <a href="mailto:benji.jones@vox.com">benji.jones@vox.com</a>.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Protocol has, at best, a mixed record. Middle-income nations, like Brazil, or those with a lot of donor support, have established systems that work. In many poorer nations, however, access is still poorly regulated or unregulated. In general, very little money has flowed into countries via the Nagoya Protocol, said <a href="https://www.abdn.ac.uk/people/m.jaspars">Marcel Jaspars</a>, a professor at the University of Aberdeen and a leading expert on DSI in the Global North.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">DSI only adds to these benefit-sharing woes.&nbsp;When environmental leaders crafted the CBD and the Nagoya Protocol, digital biodiversity data wasn’t as easily accessible or as useful as it is today; these agreements don’t even mention DSI. It’s widely understood that CBD and the Protocol only pertain to physical materials — microbes, plants, compounds from a sea squirt — not genetic sequences. That leaves the use of DSI, now a massive source of scientific innovation, largely unregulated.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What DSI is and how it works</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">DSI is one of the most confusing concepts in the environmental world, which is already racked with confusing terminology and technical jargon. Here’s the gist: After researchers collect plants, animals, and other organisms, they commonly sequence their DNA, or part of it, and upload that information to a database. The largest global collection of DNA and RNA sequences — which is the subject of much of these discussions — is <em>(take a breath)</em> the <a href="https://www.insdc.org/">International Nucleotide Sequence Database Collaboration</a>. It houses billions of genetic sequences and is free for anyone to use. Downloading the data and using it to develop commercial products does not trigger the legal obligations under CBD that harnessing a biological sample would. You’re basically harvesting information from a computer instead of from the environment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Scientists use DSI for a mind-bending array of projects. Consider the <a href="https://www.dsiscientificnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/DSI-covid-vaccines-factsheet.pdf">Moderna Covid-19 vaccine</a>. The company used nearly 300 genetic sequences, according to the patent, many of which were drawn from open-access databases, to produce the shot (<a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/moderna-designed-coronavirus-vaccine-in-2-days-2020-11">which the company was able to design in just two days</a>).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Researchers also use DSI to figure out how unique a particular genetic sequence might be, or what it might do — as in, what physical trait it might be linked to. This is incredibly valuable for the biotech and agriculture industries. A seed company, for example, might have a crop that appears more drought tolerant in their private collection. They can sequence the plant’s DNA and cross-reference its genetic information with online databases. Those databases often list information about the role of different sequences. Ultimately, this can help the company identify which particular sections of the plant genome might be associated with an ability to survive droughts, a valuable trait. Artificial intelligence, including <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2022/8/3/23288843/deepmind-alphafold-artificial-intelligence-biology-drugs-medicine-demis-hassabis">projects like Google’s AlphaFold</a>, makes these sorts of predictions even easier.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Conservation scientists also benefit from DSI in a big way. They increasingly rely on an approach called environmental DNA (eDNA) to catalog what species live in a particular area, such as a stream or the forest floor. Researchers will gather samples of water or soil and filter out bits of DNA that were shed by animals or microbes into the environment.&nbsp;Then they’ll look for a direct match with those sequences in open-access databases, revealing what those animals are. If the species are rare or otherwise considered important, this information could, say, help justify protecting habitat.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is to say: DSI is useful! There’s a good reason it&#8217;s open to everyone. It both enables and speeds up research, some of which is literally life-saving. At the same time, it maintains inequities and furthers exploitation when the people who prosper from it are largely in wealthy economies (a problem that’s <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00545-3.pdf">especially pronounced</a> and worrying when it comes to developing vaccines.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“DSI makes it possible to get all kinds of commercial advantages,” said <a href="https://alliancebioversityciat.org/who-we-are/michael-halewood">Michael Halewood</a>, an expert in genetic resource policy at CGIAR, a global agriculture organization. “That creates a big gap that needs to be closed. We all agree on the inequities of the situation. What&#8217;s a sensible way to close that gap without undermining science?”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What a plan to regulate DSI might look like</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even as COP16 looms, the debate around DSI is still a mess. There’s a lack of trust between country negotiators, leading to an enormous amount of uncertainty about how this digital data might be regulated on a global scale.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Consensus has, however, grown around the idea that companies, entire sections of the economy, or perhaps even consumers should pay into a fund that supports conservation and development, especially in the Global South. From there, two big questions rise to the top: Who, exactly, pays to use DSI, and who ultimately receives those payments?</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/CBD_DSI2-7626_6b68ab.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.740836125969,100,78.518327748063" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Negotiators met in Montreal to hash out a draft agreement on DSI ahead of COP16. | Mike Muzurakis/IISD/ENB" data-portal-copyright="Mike Muzurakis/IISD/ENB" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">A handful of low- and middle-income countries want what negotiators refer to as a “track and trace” system. That would entail tracing genetic sequences, i.e., DSI, from open-access databases to specific products, such as medicines or drought-tolerant crops, that generate value. So if a company in Europe makes a drug using DNA from a sea squirt found in, say, Panama, it would have to share benefits from that drug — money and also access to the drug itself, perhaps — back with the Panamanian people.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many academic researchers and developed countries call this a nonstarter. The chain of development for drugs and other products is long and tangled and relies on hundreds if not thousands of individual sequences. Even if it’s clear that an end product is based on a specific bit of genetic code, the research process to find that sequence — which could involve scientists across dozens of institutions, all using their own bits of DNA — relies on sifting through unimaginable amounts of genetic material. That makes it hard to determine who, exactly, should receive the benefits. Plus, many of the sequences in global databases don’t come with location information; geotagging wasn’t required <a href="https://www.insdc.org/news/insdc-spatiotemporal-metadata-minimum-standards-update-03-03-2023/">until somewhat recently</a>. That makes it even harder to direct benefits to a specific country. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Scientists also fear that a complex tracking system would slow the pace of innovation, and be incredibly expensive to operate. “By making track and trace a necessity, the system will cost more than it generates, almost certainly,” Jaspars said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many of the groups who oppose a track and trace approach, including many developed economies and academic scientists, prefer what they describe as a “sector” approach. This would require companies in sectors of the economy that are highly dependent on DSI&nbsp;—&nbsp;such as agriculture and pharmaceuticals — to put a small percentage of their profits or sales (or other measure of value) into a DSI fund. That money would likely be dished out to countries or specific projects for the benefit of conservation and human development.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Proponents of this approach argue that it would allow money from DSI to flow quickly; it wouldn’t be contingent on companies profiting from specific DSI-based products. It’s also simpler because it doesn’t involve tracking sequences.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While this sector approach has a lot of support from scientists and rich countries, it’s still not clear how to determine which industry sectors, or parts of sectors, would need to pay up.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The corporate world, meanwhile, has serious concerns about requiring payments from broad sectors of the economy, according to <a href="https://blogs.worldbank.org/en/team/d/daphne-yong-dherve">Daphne Yong-D&#8217;Hervé</a>, who leads global policy at the International Chamber of Commerce. Different companies use vastly different quantities of DSI, she said. And generally speaking, trying to regulate DSI as separate from physical materials is problematic, Yong-D&#8217;Hervé said. Organisms and their genetic sequences are often used collectively during R&amp;D.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, she said, what corporations want is a simple, unified system to use DSI and physical materials that gives them a license to operate worldwide. Without paying too much, of course.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Businesses support the principle of benefit sharing, but this has to be implemented in a way which is aligned with scientific and business realities, is simple, and does not discourage investments in research and innovation,” Yong-D&#8217;Hervé told Vox.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-1184422443.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752726382539,100,78.494547234923" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Samples of marine life off the coast of French Guyana preserved in ethanol. | Alexis Rosenfeld/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Alexis Rosenfeld/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Then there are some wealthy countries, such as Japan and Switzerland, that seem to be in favor of the status quo. They prefer a deal that encourages companies that actively use digital biodiversity data to contribute to a DSI fund, but without the legal obligation to do so.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But advocates for lower-income countries say this, too, would be a nonstarter — a continuation of exploitation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We are asking for accountability,” said Nithin Ramakrishnan, a senior researcher at Third World Network (TWN), a group that advocates for human rights and benefit sharing. To TWN, Ramakrishnan says, the priority is getting an agreement that makes sharing benefits from DSI mandatory.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will this ultimately help biodiversity?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">None of these proposals are perfect, and they represent only a handful of the issues pertaining to DSI that countries disagree on.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are questions about sharing benefits other than money and access to drugs, such as lab equipment. Some researchers and advocates are also concerned about who will manage the DSI fund <a href="https://twn.my/title2/biotk/2024/btk240903.htm">and about the databases</a> that store genetic data. The big databases are largely hosted by organizations in developed nations, so poorer countries have little control over how they operate, Ramakrishnan said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Making everything more complicated is the reality that there are other international treaties —&nbsp;including those pertaining to <a href="https://www.fao.org/plant-treaty/en/">crops</a> and the <a href="https://www.vox.com/science/2023/4/10/23672443/high-seas-treaty-bbnj-marine-protected-areas">high seas</a> —&nbsp;that are also trying to figure out how to manage access to DSI. Regulating genetic data on a global scale will likely only work if all of these treaties are aligned and define DSI in the same way.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And even if countries come to an agreement, it’s not clear they’ll be able to enforce it at the national level. (This is a problem for other international agreements. The 2015 Paris Accord, for example, lacks teeth because it doesn’t have a strong<a href="https://climate.mit.edu/ask-mit/how-are-countries-held-accountable-under-paris-agreement"> enforcement mechanism</a>). Can environmental officials get entire corporate sectors to pay up? In some countries, these payments might also require governmental approval. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Also not helping: The US, the world’s premier scientific power, is not a party to CBD, so it wouldn’t be bound by any framework that officials finalize in Cali. (However, some of the big US pharmaceutical companies have told Jaspars they are “open to sharing benefits.”)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So yes, crafting an effective plan will not be easy. Then again, the payoff of such a system could be huge —&nbsp;it could be lifesaving.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Researchers <a href="https://www.paulsoninstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/FINANCING-NATURE_Full-Report_Final-Version_091520.pdf">estimate</a> that the gap in funding for biodiversity conservation globally is somewhere around $700 billion a year; that’s a key reason why <a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/2022/10/12/23399105/biodiversity-loss-wwf-living-planet-index">biodiversity is in peril</a>. And critically, any payments for using DSI could help close that gap, especially if they’re generated from entire sectors.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Far more support is needed for things like restoring coral reefs, managing parks, and preventing wildfires, much of which Indigenous groups and local communities have already been doing. These efforts help ensure that biodiversity, and all the secrets it still holds, is left intact. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There’s a whole incredible world still to discover,” said Sarah Laird, co-director of People and Plants International, a nonprofit environmental organization. “We know a lot, but there are things we can’t even imagine out there. There are amazing opportunities.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
