<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-08-28T18:21:16Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Georgia’s MAGA elections board is laying the groundwork for an actual stolen election]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/369275/georgia-elections-board-maga-stolen-election" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369275</id>
			<updated>2024-08-28T18:21:16Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-28T18:25:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Georgia State Elections Board recently enacted two new rules that seem designed to allow local election officials to sabotage the state’s vote-counting process. Republican nominee Donald Trump praised the three board members who supported these new rules, all of whom previously questioned the result of the 2020 election that Trump lost, as “pit bulls [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Former President Donald Trump with his running mate, JD Vance, in Georgia. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-portal-copyright="Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2165155459.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Former President Donald Trump with his running mate, JD Vance, in Georgia. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;br&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Georgia State Elections Board recently enacted two new rules that seem designed to allow local election officials to sabotage the state’s vote-counting process. Republican nominee Donald Trump praised the three board members who supported these new rules, all of whom <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/08/05/trump-praises-georgia-election-board/74674946007/">previously questioned the result of the 2020 election that Trump lost</a>, as “pit bulls fighting for honesty, transparency and victory.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rules seek to alter the role of local election officials known as superintendents, whose job is to gather the vote tallies from the polling places within their jurisdiction, add up the tallies, and report those numbers to Georgia’s secretary of state. For at least a century, the Georgia Supreme Court has held that this duty is “purely ministerial” and that these superintendents “have no right to adjudicate upon the subject of irregularity or fraud” in an election.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first of the state board’s new rules, however, provides that these local superintendents must conduct a “<a href="https://s3.documentcloud.org/documents/25074852/georgia-state-election-board-rules-lawsuit.pdf">reasonable inquiry</a>” before certifying an election to ensure that the results are “a true and accurate accounting of all votes cast in that election.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This upends the longstanding rule that superintendents merely perform the ministerial task of tabulating votes, and it would give these local superintendents broad new authority to search for supposed irregularities in an election and to refuse to certify an election if they claim to find some.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The second rule provides that all county election board members must have access to “all election related documentation created during the conduct of elections prior to certification of results,” although the rule does not define which documents must be provided. In much of Georgia, county election boards also act as the superintendent that tabulates the votes in that county.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear, Georgia election law already allows a party that believes misconduct, fraud, or some other irregularity occurred during an election to <a href="https://casetext.com/statute/code-of-georgia/title-21-elections/chapter-2-elections-and-primaries-generally/article-13-contested-elections-and-primaries/section-21-2-522-grounds-for-contest">file a lawsuit challenging the result</a>. This allows questions about whether the initial count was reliable to be decided using the same evidentiary rules that apply in any other Georgia court case, and to be decided after parties on both sides of the dispute have the opportunity to submit briefs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The state board’s new rules, by contrast, allow local elections officials to dig through documents looking for something they think could be an irregularity, and then to refuse to certify the results based on their own idiosyncratic conclusion that the election was not conducted properly. If Trump loses Georgia in November, moreover, his campaign will very likely lobby local officials to use this power aggressively in an effort akin to the <a href="https://www.vox.com/21562815/biden-trump-fraud-state-legislatures-electors">pressure Trump and his allies</a> put on local officials in 2020.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are several ways the new rules could be killed before November. Earlier this week, the Democratic Party and several Democratic officials <a href="https://s3.documentcloud.org/documents/25074852/georgia-state-election-board-rules-lawsuit.pdf">filed a lawsuit challenging the new rules</a>. The suit claims that the rules violate state election law, which mandates that superintendents must certify all local election results by a certain date, that the new rules violate state Supreme Court decisions limiting the role of these superintendents, and that the state board also didn’t follow the proper procedure when it created the new rules.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, Gov. Brian Kemp, a Republican who has <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/08/18/trump-kemp-feud-georgia-00174471">clashed with Trump in the past</a>, recently asked the state attorney general for “guidance” on whether Kemp has the authority to <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/us-politics/georgia-election-trump-brian-kemp-b2602111.html">fire the three MAGA board members</a> who are responsible for the new rules.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So there is a decent chance that, one way or another, the new rules will not be in effect when this November’s election takes place. Should the state board’s gambit succeed, however, get ready for chaos.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Are the new rules legal?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Democratic lawsuit against the Georgia State Election Board was only filed last Monday, so it remains to be seen how the state courts will handle this brand new suit. Nevertheless, the party’s <a href="https://s3.documentcloud.org/documents/25074852/georgia-state-election-board-rules-lawsuit.pdf">initial court filing</a> makes a persuasive case that Georgia law does not permit local election superintendents to delay certification of an election or to adjudicate election-related disputes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The lawsuit’s theory of how elections are supposed to be conducted in Georgia is straightforward. After the ballots are cast, they are tallied by local superintendents on a tight deadline. These tallies are then transmitted to the secretary of state, who tabulates them himself and certifies the result to the governor, also on a tight deadline. Moreover, in a presidential election year, federal law requires the state to appoint members of the Electoral College “<a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/3/5">not later than the date that is 6 days before the time fixed for the meeting of the electors</a>.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One missed deadline risks triggering a chain of consequences. If a local superintendent does not meet their deadline, that could set off a cascade where more senior officials also cannot meet their deadlines — unless they exclude the votes from the recalcitrant superintendent’s jurisdiction altogether. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Election challenges may occur, but they are resolved by courts and not by superintendents, and Georgia state law requires the relevant officials to <a href="https://law.justia.com/codes/georgia/title-21/chapter-2/article-12/section-21-2-493/">recertify an election</a> if a successful challenge changes the result.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Democratic Party’s legal theory is supported by multiple provisions of Georgia elections law. For starters, state law imposes a mandatory deadline on local superintendents, stating that local election results “<a href="https://law.justia.com/codes/georgia/title-21/chapter-2/article-12/section-21-2-493/">shall be certified by the superintendent</a> not later than 5:00 P.M. on the Monday following the date on which such election was held.” So state law doesn’t simply impose a tight deadline on local elections officials, it states that they “shall” certify an election regardless of what they think about the results.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, while superintendents might exercise some authority in the few days between an election and the certification deadline — perhaps tracking down some precinct returns that were mistakenly not transmitted or fixing transcription errors made during the process of tabulating the election results — they may not refuse to certify once the deadline arrives. Allowing superintendents to do so might not only cause the state to miss key deadlines, it also places an extraordinary amount of power in obscure local officials who are not at all equipped to adjudicate election disputes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This reading of state law is bolstered by other provisions of state law cited in the Democratic Party’s lawsuit, as well as state Supreme Court decisions like 1926’s <em>Bacon v. Black</em>, the case that established that the superintendent’s duty to certify an election is “purely ministerial.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Georgia’s practice of instructing local election officials to simply tally up the votes and leave election-related disputes to be decided in the courts also appears to be a longstanding practice that is nearly universal across the United States. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In its lawsuit, the Democratic Party quotes a <a href="https://law.stanford.edu/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/MILLER-WILDER-FINAL-1.pdf">2024 law review article</a> on election certification, which states that “[b]y 1897, the ministerial, mandatory nature of certifying returns was so well-established that one leading treatise declared ‘[t]he doctrine that canvassing boards and return judges are ministerial officers possessing no discretionary or judicial power, is settled in nearly or quite all the states.” The Democratic Party, in other words, isn’t asking Georgia to do anything out of the ordinary. It is asking the state to run its election the same way nearly every state has since the McKinley administration.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, the State Election Board’s three MAGA members don’t simply appear to be upending Georgia election law. They apparently seek to upend the standard practice for conducting elections in the United States that has been commonplace since the late 19th century.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, while it remains to be seen how Georgia’s courts will react, the Democratic suit against the State Election Board appears to be quite strong.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Joshua Keating</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Did Ukraine just call Putin’s nuclear bluff?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/369035/kursk-nuclear-escalation-zelenskyy-putin" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369035</id>
			<updated>2024-08-28T15:34:00Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-28T15:34:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Russia" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Russia-Ukraine war" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three weeks ago, Ukraine’s military launched a stunning operation to take the war in Ukraine back onto the territory of the country that launched it. Three weeks later, the Ukrainians still occupy hundreds of miles of territory in Russia’s western Kursk region.&#160;&#160; The incursion had a number of goals: to force Russia to divert its [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A statue of Lenin with the face blown off." data-caption="A damaged statue of Vladimir Lenin in the Ukrainian-controlled Russian town of Sudzha on August 16, 2024. | Yan Dobronosov/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Yan Dobronosov/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2166323213.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A damaged statue of Vladimir Lenin in the Ukrainian-controlled Russian town of Sudzha on August 16, 2024. | Yan Dobronosov/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Three weeks ago, Ukraine’s military launched a <a href="https://www.vox.com/russia-ukraine/367298/ukraine-russia-incursion-kursk-war-putin-zelenskyy-crimea">stunning operation</a> to take the war in Ukraine back onto the territory of the country that launched it. Three weeks later, the Ukrainians still occupy hundreds of miles of territory in Russia’s western Kursk region.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The incursion had a number of goals: to force Russia to divert its forces from Ukraine to defend its own towns and cities; to seize territory that might later be used for bargaining leverage in peace negotiations; and to send a political message to the Russian people and their leaders that they are not safe from the consequences of the war launched by Russian President Vladimir Putin nearly two-and-a-half years ago.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there was also a less obvious objective: Leaders in Kyiv likely hoped to send a message to their friends in the United States and Europe that their approach to the war has been overly cautious — that fears about “escalation,” “red lines,” and Russian nuclear use — a threat that Putin himself has voiced repeatedly — have been overblown.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy acknowledged this explicitly in a <a href="https://www.president.gov.ua/en/news/vid-nashoyi-spilnoyi-roboti-zalezhit-yaka-zbroya-v-rukah-u-n-92669">speech on August 19</a>, saying, “We are now witnessing a significant ideological shift, namely, the whole naive, illusory concept of so-called ‘red lines’ refs somewhere near Sudzha” — a town near the border now <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/18/ukraine-russia-sudzha-kursk/">under the control of Ukrainian forces</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He also confirmed that Ukraine had not informed its Western partners about the operation ahead of time, anticipating that they would be told “it was impossible and that it would cross the strictest of all the red lines that Russia has.” According to <a href="https://www.economist.com/europe/2024/08/18/russias-double-punch-back-against-ukraines-shock-raid">press reports</a>, the Ukrainians predicted — correctly, as it turned out — that the West would not object too strongly once presented with a fait accompli. &nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They were trying to push a boundary with their Western partners and what we’ve seen is that these partners have quietly accepted the new boundary,” said Liana Fix, fellow for Europe and the Council on Foreign Relations. In particular, they’re hoping the US will lift restrictions on using American-provided long-range missiles to strike deep into Russia, a step Washington has so far avoided.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In apparent retaliation for the Kursk invasion, Moscow on Monday launched the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/26/europe/ukraine-russia-air-attacks-intl-hnk/index.html?oref=d_brief_nl&amp;utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=The%20D%20Brief:%20August%2026%2C%202024&amp;utm_term=newsletter_d1_dbrief">largest missile and drone barrage</a> on Ukraine since the start of the war. But that still fell far short of the nuclear escalation that Putin has often threatened.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The Kursk operation and the subsequent shelling of Ukraine with missiles have indeed demonstrated that Putin’s arsenal of escalation tools has been exhausted,” Yehor Cherniev, a member of the Ukrainian parliament for Zelenskyy’s Servant of the People party, told Vox by email. “Our partners understand all these things very well, and therefore their cautious position is dictated more by political than military considerations. And this naturally causes bewilderment for us.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Ukrainian argument now is that, in effect, they have called Putin’s bluff and that it’s time for Ukraine’s allies to become much more aggressive in giving Ukraine the kind of support it needs to win the war. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Are Russia’s threats still working?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since Russia’s full-scale invasion in 2022, Ukraine’s Western backers, including the United States, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/interactive/2022/ukraine-road-to-war/">have had two priorities</a>: preventing Russian victory and avoiding “escalation” — meaning avoiding direct combat between Russia and NATO militaries or, in a worst-case scenario, use of nuclear weapons. At times, the second priority has taken precedence over the first.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Russian government has certainly done everything in its power to add nuclear uncertainty to Western leaders’ calculations. From the very first day of the invasion, Putin has made repeated references to his country’s nuclear arsenal — the largest in the world — and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putins-nuclear-warnings-since-russia-invaded-ukraine-2024-03-13/">warned</a>&nbsp; countries that get in Russia’s way of “consequences that you have never faced in your history.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the course of the war, Putin and other Russian officials have made repeated references to “<a href="https://www.kyivpost.com/analysis/23308">red lines</a>” that should not be crossed if Western governments don’t want to face a catastrophic response. Former Russian President Dmitry Medvedev has been particularly active in threatening foreign powers with “nuclear apocalypse” via his <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russias-medvedev-western-arms-ukraine-make-nuclear-apocalypse-more-likely-2023-05-23/">social media accounts</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not all rhetoric: The Russian government has taken steps such as <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2024/03/14/russia-nuclear-weapons-belarus-putin/">moving some of its nuclear weapons</a> to Belarus and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russia-says-its-non-strategic-nuclear-drills-involve-iskander-missiles-2024-06-12/">conducting realistic drills</a> for using tactical nuclear weapons — seemingly in an effort to remind Ukraine’s allies of Russia’s capabilities.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Beyond North Korea, the Russians have been the country that has used nuclear threats most vigorously,” said Nicole Grajewski, a fellow in the Nuclear Policy Program at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The threats work — but only to a certain extent and only for a time. Escalation fears were the reason Western countries ruled out taking actions like <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/2/27/22952220/ukraine-russia-no-fly-zone-nuclear-war">imposing a no-fly zone in Ukraine</a> or sending NATO troops into the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Escalation fears have also made them reluctant to provide certain weapons systems to Ukraine, though system-by-system, that reluctance has faded over time. There was a time when even shoulder-mounted stinger missiles were <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/national-security/didnt-us-allies-provide-ukraine-better-air-defense-system-rcna17317">viewed as too provocative</a>. Now, the Ukrainians are using <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/ukraine-uses-long-range-atacms-russia-first-time-rcna148309">US-provided long-range missiles</a> and recently received their <a href="https://www.defensenews.com/global/2024/08/01/first-group-of-us-made-f-16-jets-arrive-in-ukraine-officials-say/#:~:text=BERLIN%20%E2%80%93%20Ukraine%20has%20received%20its,several%20officials%20confirmed%20on%20Wednesday.">first batch of F-16 fighter jets</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That these capabilities have often been provided only after months of contentious political debate has been an endless source of frustration to Ukrainians.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’ve been hearing about nuclear escalation since the first day,” Oleksandra Ustinova, a Ukrainian member of parliament who chairs a committee monitoring arms supplies, <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/353796/us-weapons-ukraine-russia-putin-escalation-nuclear">told Vox last June</a>. “First it was, it was ‘if Ukraine gets MIGs from Poland, he’s going to use nukes.’ Then it was the HIMARS, then Patriots, then tanks.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She added: “It’s like we’re running behind the train. Every time we ask for something, we get it months or a year later when it won’t make as much of a difference as it would have before.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The fact that none of the steps Western countries have taken so far have resulted in Russia using a nuclear weapon or directly attacking a NATO country is taken by many Ukrainians and their international supporters as evidence that these threats were never real to begin with.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Are there any more “red lines”?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If anything could be considered crossing a “red line,” one would think it would be the first military invasion of Russian territory since World War II.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Russia’s <a href="https://archive.mid.ru/en/web/guest/foreign_policy/international_safety/disarmament/-/asset_publisher/rp0fiUBmANaH/content/id/4152094">official nuclear doctrine</a> permits the use of nuclear weapons under circumstances in which the “very existence of the state is in jeopardy.” Ukraine’s incursion into the Kursk region, which has <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/8/22/russia-faces-manpower-woes-after-failing-to-stop-ukraines-kursk-incursion">seized hundreds of square miles of territory</a>, might not be a direct threat to the regime in Moscow, but it certainly threatens that regime’s ability to defend its own territory and sovereignty — the basic function of any state.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Moreover, the Ukrainians appear to be using <a href="https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2024/08/23/ukraines-military-says-it-used-us-glide-bombs-for-strikes-in-russias-kursk-region">US-provided weapons inside Russian territory</a>, in apparent <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2024/08/23/ukraine-kursk-offensive-russia-weapons/">violation of US policy</a>. (The Biden administration agreed in May to allow the Ukrainians to use American weapons for <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/30/us/politics/biden-ukraine-russia-weapons.html?oref=d_brief_nl&amp;utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=The%20D%20Brief:%20May%2031%2C%202024&amp;utm_term=newsletter_d1_dbrief">limited strikes into Russia,</a> but only to defend against attacks on Ukraine.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And yet, there’s been markedly little saber-rattling from Putin and the Kremlin since the Kursk operation began. The president has downplayed what he calls a “<a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/blogs/ukrainealert/invasion-what-invasion-putin-is-downplaying-ukraines-kursk-offensive/">large-scale provocation</a>” and has taken a few seemingly unrelated trips in what appears to be an effort to project normalcy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The picture in the Russian media has been a bit more mixed: Vladimir Solovyov, host of the flagship pro-Kremlin talk show<em> Sunday Evening</em>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GA5wp9p7V5s">used one monologue</a> to both call on Russians to “calm down a bit” about the incursion and to call for nuclear strikes on European capitals.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless of what Solovyov says, it does not appear that Russia is planning to respond to the events in Kursk by using nuclear weapons, attacking NATO countries, or taking steps beyond — as we saw with Monday’s massive barrage — destroying more of Ukraine with conventional weapons.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This doesn’t, however, mean that Ukraine’s backers are ready to take the gloves off.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2024/08/23/on-the-record-press-gaggle-by-white-house-national-security-communications-advisor-john-kirby-23/">press call on Friday</a>, Vox asked US National Security Spokesperson John Kirby whether Zelenskyy was right that it was time to move beyond fears of escalation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We’ve been watching escalation risks since the beginning of this conflict, and that ain’t gonna change,” Kirby responded. “We’re always going to be concerned about the potential for the aggression in Ukraine to lead to escalation on the European continent.” He added that “it’s too soon to know whether what’s going on in Kursk…[what]&nbsp;potential impact that that could have in terms of escalation. But it is something that we remain concerned about.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The thinking in the administration appears to be that, as Pentagon Deputy Spokesperson Sabrina Singh recently put it, “just because Russia hasn’t responded to something doesn’t mean that they can’t or won’t in the future.” And given that it’s nuclear weapons we’re talking about, that’s a risk that has to be taken seriously.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Even if it’s only a 10 percent chance or 5 percent chance that they actually mean it, or they’re actually planning to act on it, that’s concerning enough,” said Carnegie’s Grajewski.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Does Putin have a breaking point?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Pavel Podvig, senior researcher on Russia’s nuclear arsenal at the United Nations Institute for Disarmament Research in Geneva, argues that “this whole kind of a business of red lines is actually quite misleading and not helpful.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In his view, there are few useful military applications for nuclear weapons inside Ukraine and given the catastrophic risks involved, Putin would be unlikely to consider any sort of nuclear use unless the very existence of the Russian state were threatened. “Even the loss of a region like Kursk technically would not qualify,” Podvig said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Putin has certainly implied, however, that his threshold for escalation was much lower. Just last May, for instance, he warned Western countries against allowing their weapons to be used to strike Russian territory, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putin-warns-west-not-let-ukraine-use-its-missiles-hit-russia-2024-05-28/">saying they should</a> “bear in mind our parity in the field of strategic weapons.&#8221; (“Strategic” is a euphemism for nuclear in this case.) These threats are getting harder to take seriously.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kyiv’s current campaign is to get the US to lift its restrictions on using US-supplied long-range missiles to strike deep into Russia, which would allow them to press the offensive in Kursk further and hit more Russian military targets than they are currently able to with domestically produced weapons.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Ukraine is separated from halting the advance of the Russian army on the front by only one decision we await from our partners: the decision on long-range capabilities,” Zelenskyy said in his speech. In a post on Twitter following Monday’s strikes, Ukraine’s defense minister said <a href="https://x.com/rustem_umerov/status/1828028537791500413">the attack showed </a>why&nbsp;“Ukraine needs long-range capabilities and the lifting of restrictions on strikes on the enemy’s military facilities.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If this debate follows the trajectory of those that preceded it, Washington will eventually come around to giving the Ukrainians what they’re asking for.&nbsp;But while the risky incursion into Kursk may have given Ukraine some more ammunition in these debates going forward, Western leaders are not about to simply abandon their caution and give Ukraine everything it wants.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the Council on Foreign Relations’s Fix put it, Western “red lines” on aid to Ukraine have clearly shifted. The problem is “we don’t know how the red lines are shifting in Putin’s mind.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Allie Volpe</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s what you need to know about the revamped FAFSA]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23977937/fafsa-changes-2024-2025-federal-student-aid-college" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/even-better/23977937/fafsa-changes-2024-2025-federal-student-aid-college</id>
			<updated>2024-08-28T15:47:40Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-28T15:15:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Education" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Personal Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Your Money, Explained" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[College tuition is a hefty sum for many students and their families in America: Average yearly tuition at a private university totals $42,162; $23,630 for public out-of-state tuition; and $10,662 for public in-state tuition. It’s no surprise, then, that over 85 percent of undergraduates are awarded some form of financial aid — including federal aid, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images/iStockphoto" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25115088/GettyImages_1419915787.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">College tuition is a hefty sum for many students and their families in America: <a href="https://www.usnews.com/education/best-colleges/paying-for-college/articles/paying-for-college-infographic">Average yearly tuition</a> at a private university totals $42,162; $23,630 for public out-of-state tuition; and $10,662 for public in-state tuition. It’s no surprise, then, that over 85 percent of undergraduates are awarded some form of <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/digest/d23/tables/dt23_331.20.asp">financial aid</a> — including federal aid, state and local grants and scholarships, institutional grants and scholarships, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/student-loan-debt">student loans</a> — according to data from the National Center for Education Statistics. The path to receiving money for college is through the <a href="https://studentaid.gov/h/apply-for-aid/fafsa">Free Application for Federal Student Aid</a>, or FAFSA. The <a href="https://studentaid.gov/help-center/answers/article/what-is-the-fafsa">FAFSA</a> is a form students and/or their parents complete to apply for federal grants, work-study funds, and loans. Many states and colleges also use this application to determine students’ eligibility for state and school financial aid. As the name says, it is completely free to submit the application.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last year’s FAFSA submission process for the current academic year was <a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/news/admissions/traditional-age/2024/01/03/fafsa-soft-launch-vexes-families-and-counselors#">beleaguered by issues</a>.<strong> </strong>The FAFSA form usually opens for the following academic year <a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/loans/student-loans/fafsa-deadline">on October 1</a> — <a href="https://studentaid.gov/help/renewal-fafsa">students must complete the form each year</a> — but the 2024-25 FAFSA form soft-launched in late December 2023 due to changes in the application. Students were only able to gain access to the form for limited windows each day; a mistake meant students initially <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/01/09/1222664638/fafsa-student-financial-aid-college">qualified for less aid than they should have</a> (the calculation <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-announces-more-31-million-fafsa-forms-successfully-submitted-and-update-student-aid-index-calculation">has been corrected</a>); <a href="https://www.chalkbeat.org/2024/01/25/better-fafsa-challenges-for-students-and-parents-social-security-number/">parents who did not have a Social Security number</a> were unable to start or contribute to a student’s form; the US Education Department said that <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-announces-more-31-million-fafsa-forms-successfully-submitted-and-update-student-aid-index-calculation">schools would not receive students’ FAFSA forms until March</a>. Typically, schools receive this information <a href="https://www.highereddive.com/news/fafsa-delay-march-applicant-info/706038/">shortly after students complete the form</a>. Overall, <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/24090669/fafsa-financial-aid-rollout-college-tuition">FAFSA submissions were down</a> significantly.<strong> </strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UOgIb7StyPU">changes to the form included</a> a direct transfer of tax information from the IRS to the FAFSA form, increased <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/08/11/your-money/fafsa-changes-college-aid.html">eligibility for need-based grants</a>, and the elimination of a discount for families with multiple children in college. While the updates aimed to provide an easier experience, the <a href="https://www.chronicle.com/article/frustration-all-around-the-fafsas-rocky-rollout">process frustrated</a> many students and their families.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In order to avoid these headaches yet again, the Department of Education <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-announces-schedule-and-new-process-launch-2025-26-fafsa-form">announced the 2025-26 FAFSA</a> would be released on October 1, 2024 for testing with a limited number of volunteer students and institutions. All students should have access to the form by December 1, 2024.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you are planning to attend college and want to receive financial aid for the fall 2025 and spring 2026 semesters, this is the form you will complete. The Federal Student Aid office has a <a href="https://studentaid.gov/announcements-events/fafsa-support">webpage dedicated to announcements related to the overhauled FAFSA</a> that you can check regularly for any updates. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The federal deadline to complete the <a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/loans/student-loans/fafsa-deadline">2025-26 FAFSA is June 30, 2026</a>,<strong> </strong>though <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/fafsa-deadlines">each college and state has its own deadline</a> by which they need students to complete the form. Even though the federal deadline falls after the school year ends, financial aid <a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/loans/student-loans/fafsa-deadline">funds can be applied retroactively</a> to what you already paid that year for tuition. (If you haven’t yet completed the form for the current academic year, it’s still not too late: <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/fafsa-deadlines">that deadline is June 30, 2025</a>.) Unfortunately, some aid is distributed on a <a href="https://studentaid.gov/resources/financial-aid-process-text">first-come, first-served basis,</a> a <a href="https://www.chalkbeat.org/2024/01/25/better-fafsa-challenges-for-students-and-parents-social-security-number/">frustrating reality</a> for students who were not able to complete their 2024-25 form due to <a href="https://fsapartners.ed.gov/knowledge-center/topics/fafsa-simplification-information/2024-25-fafsa-issue-alerts">persistent issues</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is <a href="https://studentaid.gov/understand-aid/eligibility">no income cutoff</a> to be eligible for federal student aid, so all college students are <a href="https://blog.collegeboard.org/what-is-the-fafsa">encouraged to apply</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether it’s your first time applying for financial aid or you’re well-practiced, here’s a primer on how to complete the FAFSA, including tips for both the 2024-25 and 2025-26 forms.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Where do I find the FAFSA form?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The 2025-26 FAFSA form, along with the 2024-25 FAFSA form, will be <a href="https://studentaid.gov/h/apply-for-aid/fafsa">online at StudentAid.gov</a>. If you have not previously applied for financial aid, <a href="https://studentaid.gov/fsa-id/create-account/launch">create a Federal Student Aid ID</a>. “The FSA ID is used to sign the FAFSA,” says Dean Bentley, the executive director of financial aid engagement at the <a href="https://www.collegeboard.org/">College Board</a>. “It’ll be required for all students and parents or guardians who provide information on the FAFSA.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re a <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/filling-out/dependency">dependent student</a> — which is any student who is under 24; is not married and does not have legal dependents; is not a graduate or professional student; is not a veteran or a member of the armed forces; or is not an emancipated minor — your parent or stepparent will need to create an FSA ID, too, so they can add their information to the form as a “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ROtS0SnscMI">contributor</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Contributors are one of the new features of the form. Anyone who will <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u8uubc08CDE&amp;list=PLtr3wy4M_CJ18cBXJb2r5mzyFoh9e9mcl&amp;index=3">provide tax and personal information to your FAFSA form</a> should be listed as a contributor. Contributors are determined by your dependency status, marital status, and tax filing status. (For example, a contributor for a student under the age of 24 will be their parent. Married students’ contributors will be their spouses.) Contributors, despite the name, are not expected to contribute money to your tuition, just information to your FAFSA form. Make sure the student and any contributors have their FSA ID ready to go before starting the application.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you or your contributors have a Social Security number, use it to create your FSA ID. If you or your contributors <a href="https://studentaid.gov/2425/help/ssn">don’t have a Social Security number,</a> check the box that says “I do not have a Social Security number.” You’ll be asked to input your Individual Taxpayer Identification Number (ITIN) later in the form.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u8uubc08CDE&amp;list=PLtr3wy4M_CJ18cBXJb2r5mzyFoh9e9mcl&amp;index=3">Contributors will receive an email</a> informing them that they need to complete information for the student’s FAFSA. Contributors should try to complete their portion sooner rather than later. If there is no activity on a FAFSA for 45 days, the form is deleted and you’ll have to start again, says MorraLee Keller, the senior director of strategic programming at the <a href="https://www.ncan.org/">National College Attainment Network</a>. Should your contributors need more time, a student can log in to their FAFSA form to reset the 45-day window.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re filling out the FAFSA on behalf of your child, <a href="https://studentaid.gov/articles/steps-to-complete-fafsa-form/">make sure to select</a> “I am a parent filling out a FAFSA form for a student.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What information should I have on hand?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The FAFSA requires students, their parents, or other non-parental contributors to enter a <a href="https://studentaid.gov/help/info-needed">host of personal information</a>. Here’s what you should have readily available:</p>

<ul>
<li>Your date of birth, <a href="https://www.vox.com/social-programs">Social Security</a> number, address, and email.</li>



<li>Your A-Number if you aren’t a US citizen.</li>



<li>Your parents’ Social Security numbers if you are a dependent student.</li>



<li>Tax returns for you, your spouse (if you’re married), or your parents (if you’re a dependent student).</li>



<li>Records of child support received for you or your parents (if you’re a dependent student).</li>



<li>Current balances of cash, savings, and checking accounts.</li>



<li>Net worth of investments, businesses, and farms.</li>



<li>Records of untaxed income, if applicable.</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As a part of the new FAFSA form, you’ll then need to provide consent and approval to import your federal tax information directly from the IRS. Your <a href="https://bigfuture.collegeboard.org/pay-for-college/financial-aid-basics/fafsa/how-to-complete-the-fafsa">family’s taxes for the previous year must be completed</a> before you can import the tax information. (For example, for the 2024-25 FAFSA, the family’s 2022 taxes must have been completed.) If you are a non-tax filer, there will be a code that the IRS will fill in that indicates you don’t have a tax return on file, Keller says. “The parts that people may have had anxiety about in the past [like] making sure they’re putting in the right numbers,” she says, “that is going to be alleviated with this process.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Further along in the form, the student or their parents can add up to <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/filling-out/school-list">20 colleges or career schools that will receive your information</a>. If you already know where you’re attending college — say, you’re a rising junior and have attended the same school since freshman year — add that college to the form. If you’re still in high school and have not committed to a college yet, <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/filling-out">add any school you applied to or plan on applying to</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What about my parents?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If a dependent student is filling out the form on their own, they’ll be prompted to <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/filling-out/parent-info">fill in their parents’ full names, Social Security numbers, dates of birth, and email addresses</a> so they can fill in their information separately. If the student’s parents are divorced or separated, the parent <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/filling-out/parent-info">who provided the most financial support over the last year</a> will need to fill out their portion of the FAFSA. If they provided the student with equal financial support, the parent with greater income and assets should fill out the FAFSA.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c7yWZyZfyEg">Parent contributors will need</a> their tax returns, records of child support received, current balances of cash, savings, and checking accounts, and net worth of investments, businesses, and farms. “Families that have income <a href="https://studentaid.gov/2425/help/skipping-asset-questions">above $60,000</a><strong> </strong>will need to report assets like cash savings, checking, real estate, stocks, bonds, and the net value of their small business or family farm,” Keller says. “While that sounds complicated, there’s a lot of instructions to help families understand,” Bentley says. “There’s even an overview video that they’ll be able to watch when they start the application.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A dependent student’s FAFSA form is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3c0jWxxyx6s&amp;list=PLtr3wy4M_CJ2Hrd0UwCAWJOgOPu8l_ZLf&amp;index=4">not completed until their parent (and other contributors) completes their section</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is the deadline to apply?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Again, the earlier you apply after the application opens the better. However, there are some <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/fafsa-deadlines">deadlines worth keeping in mind</a>. Each school has a different deadline for when you need to submit your FAFSA form, so check with your school (or the schools you applied to) to see when you need to submit your application for financial aid. <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/fafsa-deadlines#state">Every state has a different deadline</a>, too: For example, most state financial aid programs in California required the 2024-25 FAFSA to be submitted <a href="https://www.kqed.org/news/11957693/applying-for-fafsa-in-2023-will-be-different-what-to-know-including-deadlines">no later than May 2, 2024</a>. Federally, June 30 is the last day you can apply for financial aid for the previous school year.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What should I expect after I submit my FAFSA form?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After you and your contributors have finalized and sent off your FAFSA form, it will be <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lXY5GBumXcc&amp;list=PLtr3wy4M_CJ1QiU3gCEUDm9H8AZaPm4SP&amp;index=1">processed in one to three days</a> and sent to the colleges you listed on your form. After, you’ll receive an <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/review-and-correct">email notifying you that your FAFSA Submission Summary</a> is ready. <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/review-and-correct/fafsa-submission-summary">This summary</a> will give you an estimate of the amount of student aid you’re eligible for. Here is where you can make corrections to your FAFSA or send additional verification information requested by your school. If you don’t need to make any changes, just <a href="https://studentaid.gov/apply-for-aid/fafsa/review-and-correct/fafsa-submission-summary">keep the summary for your records</a>.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I1EbAs2XpgE">Schools will send their aid offers</a> in the spring before you’re set to start school. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The student,” Keller says, “will be waiting on the award notification to let them know how much financial aid they will have for next year, whether that’s federal and state aid, as well as institutional aid. So that award notification would be the primary document that the student is waiting on to receive after they file their FAFSA.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, August 28, 2024, 11:15 am: </em></strong><em>This story was originally published on November 29, 2023, and has been updated multiple times, most recently with the latest information on the 2024-25 and 2025-26 FAFSA.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Oshan Jarow</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What do you do if The Really Big One strikes on your vacation?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/368920/what-to-do-natural-disaster-vacation-travel-earthquake-wildfire-hurricane-flooding" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368920</id>
			<updated>2024-08-26T22:55:17Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-28T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Natural Disasters" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Travel" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this year, projections from UN Tourism put international travel on track to recover to pre-pandemic levels — putting a swell of tourism on a collision course with the increasing danger of climate disasters, from wildfires ripping through Greece to megaquake warnings in southern Japan. While peak tourism season is mostly behind us, off-season travel [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A person walks past an area of a damaged building, which is cordoned off with construction equipment nearby, in Hualien, Taiwan. " data-caption="The aftermath of an earthquake on April 4, 2024, in Hualien, Taiwan. A 7.5 magnitude earthquake hit eastern Taiwan, triggering a tsunami warning for coastlines in Taiwan, the Philippines and Japan. | Annabelle Chih/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Annabelle Chih/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2136599218.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>The aftermath of an earthquake on April 4, 2024, in Hualien, Taiwan. A 7.5 magnitude earthquake hit eastern Taiwan, triggering a tsunami warning for coastlines in Taiwan, the Philippines and Japan. | Annabelle Chih/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.unwto.org/news/international-tourism-to-reach-pre-pandemic-levels-in-2024">projections from UN Tourism</a> put international travel on track to recover to pre-pandemic levels — putting a swell of tourism on a collision course with the increasing danger of climate disasters, from wildfires <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/16/climate/greece-wildfires-athens-photos-climate-intl/index.html">ripping through Greece</a> to <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/08/15/1096682/what-japans-megaquake-warning-really-tells-us/">megaquake warnings</a> in southern Japan. While peak tourism season is mostly behind us, off-season travel is <a href="https://www.cnn.com/travel/the-end-of-off-season-travel-cmb/index.html">swelling</a>, which may or may not be evidence of a backlash against the “<a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/358195/the-case-against-summer">summer industrial complex</a>.” Volatility is in the air, as well as, apparently, the ground, seas, and forests. Plus, some extreme weather patterns, like the <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/news-release/noaa-predicts-above-normal-2024-atlantic-hurricane-season">Atlantic hurricane season</a>, are just kicking off.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And 2024 isn’t an anomaly (at least, in terms of climate patterns). Last winter, a 7.8 earthquake in Turkey and Syria leveled over 6,000 buildings and <a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2023/2/7/23589541/turkey-earthquake-syria-death-toll-news-updates">killed thousands</a>. In the spring, a half-year’s worth of rain in Italy’s Emilia Romagna region led to floods, canceled a Formula One Grand Prix, and <a href="https://climate-adapt.eea.europa.eu/en/metadata/case-studies/mental-health-support-for-people-affected-by-floods-in-emilia-romagna#:~:text=In%20May%202023%2C%20six%20months,Romagna%20report%2C%20CEMS%20bulletin%20n.">killed 17 people</a>. In the final dregs of summer, devastating <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/09/01/us/hawaii-tourists-economy.html">wildfires</a> closed the beaches of Hawaii and displaced thousands of locals in Maui.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then there’s all that lies in wait, like the “<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2015/07/20/the-really-big-one?_sp=ff8ebf55-e7a9-4a86-9986-a24f05fbccfa.1723657514668">Really Big One</a>,” a projected earthquake reaching up to a 9.2 on the Richter scale and subsequent 700-mile seismic wave that will, on some unknown day, devastate North America’s West Coast. Or that Nankai Trough Megaquake that southern Japan braced for earlier this month, now <a href="https://www3.nhk.or.jp/nhkworld/en/news/backstories/3509/">projected</a> to kill 230,000 people whenever it strikes.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now look, the odds that you’re vacationing in a spot where an anticipated natural disaster finally happens are very low. But as the climate of the planet changes, disaster patterns are shifting and are occurring in <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/downloads/faqs/IPCC_AR6_WGI_FAQ_Chapter_11.pdf">unprecedented locations</a>. Even traveling to places that have been <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/2023/7/13/23792409/floods-vermont-new-york-natural-disaster-insurance-global-climate-risk-change">historically mellow,</a> at least in terms of climate, still doesn’t guarantee a smooth ride. Tornado Alley — the oval-shaped epicenter of tornado formations in the US stretching from northeastern Texas to western Missouri —&nbsp;is <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/watch-out-tornado-alley-is-migrating-eastward/">traveling eastward</a>, spreading concentrated storms to new places. And hail, I kid you not, is <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-024-00728-9#:~:text=Near-surface%20hailstones%20%3C4%20cm,are%20expected%20across%20the%20U.S.">getting bigger</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And if your travels aren’t thwarted by a long-awaited supervolcanic eruption, even a modest thunderstorm, particularly in drought-stricken areas where the soil can’t absorb new moisture, can still cause flash flooding by your hotel and throw a wrench in your plans. (Moab, Utah, home of a popular hiking spot called the Morning Glory Arch, <a href="https://x.com/Rainmaker1973/status/1806289416475841017">saw extraordinary flooding</a> earlier this year during peak season.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That said, this doesn’t all mean that disasters themselves are on the rise. Despite very <a href="https://openknowledge.fao.org/server/api/core/bitstreams/7c48cdf4-6153-41df-b3ed-4db1d09a1b0f/content">high-profile</a> organizations <a href="https://unfccc.int/news/climate-change-leads-to-more-extreme-weather-but-early-warnings-save-lives">repeating</a> the claim that the rate of natural disasters has <a href="https://gadebate.un.org/en/72/secretary-general-united-nations">quadrupled</a> —&nbsp;or more —&nbsp;in the last 50 years, the nonprofit Our World in Data finds that <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/disaster-database-limitations#:~:text=UN%20Framework%20Convention%20on%20Climate,weather%2C%20and%20improved%20reporting.%E2%80%9D">it’s actually unclear</a> whether that’s just a byproduct of better technology enabling more reporting of disasters, or reflects a real increase in catastrophes. In fact, disaster deaths per capita have actually been on <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/decadal-average-death-rates-from-natural-disasters">a steep decline</a> in recent decades, thanks to improved infrastructure, early warning systems, and more adeptly coordinated responses.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2165981652.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Two men in helmets and jackets haul a long hose toward a forest fire burning twice as tall as they are, through dry grass and scrub." title="Two men in helmets and jackets haul a long hose toward a forest fire burning twice as tall as they are, through dry grass and scrub." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Volunteers extinguish a forest fire in Ano Patima in the northern Athens region of Greece, on August 12, 2024. | Socrates Baltagiannis/picture alliance via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Socrates Baltagiannis/picture alliance via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">But regardless of the overall rate or deadliness of natural disasters, climate change is pushing those that do occur to their <a href="https://www.vox.com/22616968/ipcc-climate-change-report-attribution-extreme-weather-heat-fire">extremes</a>. A warmer climate is an <a href="https://news.stanford.edu/stories/2021/12/warming-makes-weather-less-predictable">increasingly unpredictable</a> one, and the planet is on a 14-month <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/news/earth-just-had-its-warmest-july-on-record#:~:text=The%20average%20July%20global%20surface,high%20temperatures%20for%20the%20planet.">streak</a> of setting record-high temperatures. More disruptive heat waves, wildfires, flooding, droughts, tropical cyclones (the world is just now moving into the upswing of the Atlantic hurricane season, which is projected to be one of <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/news-release/highly-active-hurricane-season-likely-to-continue-in-atlantic">the most intense</a> on record), and landslides are all in the forecast.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We’ve seen with climate change that severe weather threats, including extreme heat, are happening outside of the time of year and places that people typically associate with these extreme weather events,” said <a href="https://wmo.int/profile/jonathan-porter">Jon Porter</a>, weather forecasting company AccuWeather’s chief meteorologist. “Do not be lulled into any false sense of security.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So unless you have an in at a <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24139145/fallout-amazon-prime-video-game-nuclear-war-existential-risk">billionaire’s bunker</a> to shield you from unexpected climate surprises along your journey, here’s how to be a bit more prepared for travel and learn to navigate a more unpredictable, disaster-prone world.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Before you travel, consider planning for chaos</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I’ve been fortunate to do a fair bit of travel in my lifetime, and whether going to Southeast Asia or Latin America, my natural disaster preparation has generally held steady: pay it no mind, travel anyway, and leave my fate up to the gods.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But, like many others, I’m starting to lose faith in that strategy. So I went looking to see how more prudent travelers might handle things. I expected to find a bunch of totally reasonable steps that I nevertheless couldn’t actually imagine myself doing. I’m stubborn, after all. But it turns out, there’s a number of pretty simple things a traveler can do to help lower the odds of getting caught unprepared during a disaster. I’m learning that the beginning of wisdom, at least when it comes to travel, might be something like downloading the Federal Emergency Management Agency’s (FEMA) <a href="https://www.ready.gov/fema-app">app</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Just like getting some Duolingo in to polish your Spanish before heading to Spain, you might browse some basic <a href="https://community.fema.gov/ProtectiveActions/s/article/Hurricane">hurricane protective strategies</a> before heading to Puerto Rico. Or peruse this <a href="https://www.ready.gov/earthquakes#:~:text=Prepare%20Before%20an%20Earthquake&amp;text=Make%20an%20Emergency%20Plan%3A%20Create,fire%20extinguisher%20and%20a%20whistle.">earthquake preparedness guide</a> before going anywhere near the Pacific Northwest. FEMA’s app bills itself as “your personalized disaster resource,” which rings pretty dystopian. But easy access to FEMA’s disaster resources —&nbsp;from real-time emergency alerts to help finding nearby shelter during a rushed evacuation —&nbsp;can help prevent a bad situation from getting worse. Although it’s a US agency, FEMA has resources for global travel, too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When planning a trip, you could pop open the <a href="https://gdacs.org/">Global Disaster Alert and Coordination System</a>, a joint project between the United Nations (UN) and European Commission that shows real-time global disaster alerts from the past four days on a handy map. In addition to not literally traveling into an active disaster, knowing the seasons and usual suspects of your destination can help you decide which among the FEMA app’s preparation guides you might skim beforehand.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once you know where you want to go, you could even enroll in the <a href="https://step.state.gov/">State Department’s Smart Traveler Enrollment Program</a>, a free service that registers your trip with the nearest US embassy to your destination. They’ll keep you updated with safety alerts in your destination country, and help the US embassy contact you if a natural disaster strikes while you’re there.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Skipping a flight to reduce emissions</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Although today, aviation makes up only <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/global-aviation-emissions#:~:text=Aviation%20accounts%20for%202.5%25%20of,to%20global%20warming%20to%20date.&amp;text=Flying%20is%20one%20of%20the,of%20the%20world%27s%20carbon%20emissions.">2.5 percent</a> of the world’s carbon emissions, that number is on a sharp upward trajectory that’s already quadrupled since the 1960s. That makes ditching big flights an extremely <a href="https://www.thetimes.com/article/92eb96e2-5dda-4d32-9533-56a763a1fab1">carbon-friendly</a> decision. For now, anyway. <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/2/27/20994118/carbon-offset-climate-change-net-zero-neutral-emissions">Carbon offsets</a> can hasten global decarbonization, even if they <a href="https://www.vox.com/23817575/carbon-offsets-credits-financialization-ecologi-solutions-scam">don’t actually offset</a> your flight’s emissions. And in the hopefully not-too-distant future, <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-022-01046-9">net-zero aviation</a> could become feasible.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The usuals of travel obviously still apply, like sending your itinerary to family or close friends, or making copies of important documents like your passport. But as extreme weather spreads to places that aren’t accustomed to it (like Vermont, which just experienced a magnitude of <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/30/weather/vermont-flooding-rain-climate/index.html">destructive rainfall</a> that is expected only once in every 1,000 years), some unusual steps might also be helpful. For example, you might look for social media accounts of local organizations that <a href="https://preparecenter.org/topic/social-media-disasters/">provide emergency alerts,</a> so that you aren’t reliant on official communication channels that may not be prepared to get information out fast. Or, if you really want to hedge your bets, you can travel with a satellite phone so that you don’t lose the ability to communicate even if the area you’re in does.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition, FEMA <a href="https://www.fema.gov/blog/travel-preparedness-3-tips-safe-adventure">recommends</a> adding an emergency kit to your packing list, with things like nonperishable food, first aid kits, flashlights, power banks for your phones, and flares. <a href="http://ready.gov">Ready.gov</a>, a public service campaign that helps Americans prepare for and respond to disasters, also has a sample <a href="https://www.ready.gov/plan-form">family emergency communication plan</a> you can have everyone in your party fill out before traveling. That way, if you do get separated or cut off from communication, everyone has contact numbers, emergency meeting places, and medical information on hand.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there’s a limit to the kinds of things you can really plan ahead for. The varieties of disaster may never cease to surprise us, like Boston’s <a href="https://www.boston.gov/news/100-years-ago-today-molasses-crashes-through-bostons-north-end">Great Molasses Flood</a> of 1919.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">If you happen to be a tourist during a disaster</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All right, so what if<em> </em>you actually are hanging out on Vancouver Island when the Really Big One does rumble and splash across the Pacific Northwest? What if you were traveling through the state of Rio Grande do Sul in southern Brazil when flooding killed <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/brazil-floods-death-toll-missing-persons-rio-grande-do-sul/">over 100 people</a> in May, forced 160,000 more from their homes, and effectively <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/extreme-weather-wreaks-havoc-around-the-world">shut down</a> a city of 4 million people?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/travel/article/what-to-do-if-youre-caught-in-a-disaster-while-travelling#:~:text=Basic%20things%20to%20remember%20include,and%20neck%20with%20your%20arms.">rules of thumb</a>: If you aren’t literally caught in the middle of what’s going on, try to assess the situation before springing into action. If you’re staying with a hotel, they’re usually in touch with local authorities, and are a good source of information. “It’s important to listen to local and state officials,” said <a href="https://www.fema.gov/profile/jaclyn-rothenberg">Jaclyn Rothenberg</a>, FEMA public affairs director. “Carefully monitor local radio, television, social media, and other local sources for updates.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The US Bureau of Consular Affairs website <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/international-travel/emergencies/what-state-dept-can-cant-do-crisis.html">advises</a>, shockingly, that “the best time to leave a country is before a crisis.” In this specific scenario, that’s hard to know. The US government’s main commitment is to keep citizens informed of both safety developments and travel options —&nbsp;only in limited circumstances will they actually help evacuate citizens. Specifically, if there are no commercial transport options, and consular officers are nearby, and conditions permit, then the government may help identify and/or arrange transport.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But keep in mind that if you do wind up in a US government-assisted evacuation, it won’t foot the bill. If you don’t have money on hand, you’ll have to sign a form promising the government you’ll pay it back before getting on the transport. Just imagine; there could be a tsunami rushing around your dwindling plot of high land while you’re stuck in a line to get on the escape bus as each American fills out the IOU paperwork. I doubt —&nbsp;I hope — that’s not how it plays out in practice. But when you’re dealing with bureaucracies, you never know. Also, pets are not allowed on the transport (but service animals are).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let’s say things happened too fast, and you’re still on the ground when disaster sets in. If you’re facing flooding or a tsunami, seek out high ground. If it’s an earthquake, get away from buildings, the collapse of which <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/4/27/8501281/earthquake-risk">kills far more people</a> than the actual quake itself. During wildfires or volcanic eruptions, make plans to evacuate, and cover your mouth and nose if the air is already thick with ash (N95 masks certified by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health <a href="https://ww2.arb.ca.gov/smokereadyca#:~:text=People%20who%20must%20be%20outdoors,NIOSH%2Dcertified%20N95%20respirator%20mask.">are best</a>, and make a good addition to your travel packing list).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Travel insurance can add another layer of protection — though it can nudge up the overall cost of your trip. Policies usually <a href="https://disb.dc.gov/page/taking-trip-information-about-travel-insurance-you-should-know-you-hit-road#:~:text=Cost%20of%20travel%20insurance%3A%20Travel,%24500%20depending%20on%20the%20coverage.">cost</a> between 4 and 10 percent of your trip’s price, but they often have an <a href="https://www.allianztravelinsurance.com/get-help.htm">emergency assistance number</a> you can call. They can help refer you to local medical providers, make emergency travel arrangements, or even get you emergency cash to get out. If you go this route, take care to check whether disaster-related expenses are included in your policy.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If phone lines are down and communication is cut off once you’ve found immediate safety, one of the most common recommendations across government agencies is to take to social media. Post that you’re all right, saving your family the trouble of waiting on the State Department’s hotline to make sure you’re okay.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The economics, and ethics, of disaster travel</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, you made it home. But let’s say the first-hand brush with disaster, and seeing the havoc it can wreak, particularly on less developed areas with fewer resources which will <a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2023/01/climate-crisis-poor-davos2023/">disproportionately shoulder the brunt</a> of climate change’s extreme weather upticks, left you unsettled. What can you do to help?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At an institutional level, economic development can help make communities more resilient in the face of disaster. A powerful way to soften the impact of an extremifying climate is, for example, <a href="https://www.unisdr.org/files/8545_povertyreduction1.pdf">to reduce poverty</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The UN’s 2019 <a href="https://hdr.undp.org/system/files/documents/hdr2019.pdf">Human Development Report</a> looked at this relationship more broadly, using their Human Development Index (HDI) that measures a combination of health, education, and standard of living. They found that from 1980 to 2017, natural disasters led to a 0.5 percent annual drop in the HDI of developed countries, but a larger 1.2 percent drop for countries with fewer resources.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The world has excelled in many <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/much-better-awful-can-be-better">measures of development and progress</a> through recent centuries (while <a href="https://royalsociety.org/news-resources/projects/biodiversity/human-impact-on-biodiversity/#:~:text=The%20main%20direct%20cause%20of,timber%20which%20drives%20around%2020%25.">others are backsliding</a>). But zooming into more recent times, progress on things like the UN’s Sustainable Development Goals that would raise HDI —&nbsp;like ending global poverty, or abolishing hunger and improving nutrition worldwide — is <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/9/22/23884636/united-nations-sustainable-development-goals-extreme-poverty-hunger-climate-change-ukraine">slowing to a crawl</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But neither you nor I can end global poverty or cut emissions worldwide on our own (though individual choices <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/368201/volunteer-charity-donations-systemic-change-activism-nonprofits-loneliness-philanthropy">can still influence</a> structural problems). One strategy is to consider how visitor presence and tourism dollars will interact with the local economy, and either align with the local community’s well-being, or not.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For example, during the Maui wildfires last year, local officials <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/aug/14/hawaii-fires-maui-requests-tourists-stay-away">all but begged</a> tourists to stay away. Part of the problem was the sheer absurdity of tourists snorkeling in the same waters that crews were still searching to find missing residents who’d jumped in to avoid the flames. Tourists were sucking away resources that residents of the Lahaina area badly needed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But tourism makes up roughly <a href="https://www.mauicounty.gov/DocumentCenter/View/102556/010_06_County-Profile">40 percent</a> of Maui’s economy. So a month after the fire, losing about <a href="https://www.hawaii.edu/news/2023/09/22/wildfires-maui-economy/#:~:text=Maui%20lost%20more%20than%20%2413,the%20weeks%20following%20the%20fire.">$13 million per day</a> in visitor spending relative to normal, residents, government officials, and business owners began <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/10/6/23898399/maui-reopening-wildfires-hawaii-tourism-displaced-residents">asking tourists to come back</a>, at least to the parts of Maui that weren’t most affected by the fires. Still, <a href="https://www.euronews.com/travel/2022/05/03/hawaiian-overtourism-residents-beg-tourists-to-stop-visiting-amid-post-pandemic-boom">overtourism</a> is a major issue across Hawaii at large. Even when there’s no disaster fallout demanding extra resources, many locals and government officials alike have been trying to <a href="https://pacificties.org/tourism-in-hawaii-needs-to-change/#:~:text=Bisch%20cites%20several%20negative%20effects,%2C%20as%20Bisch%20says%2C%20%E2%80%9C%E2%80%A6">slow the tide</a> of tourists, whose hordes have clogged infrastructure, deprived residents of resources as they’re diverted to high-demand areas, threatened endangered species, and trampled sacred land.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sometimes, though, locals are more unified in their embrace of tourism, even in the immediate wake of a disaster. When a 6.8-magnitude earthquake hit rural parts of Marrakesh, Morocco, in September 2023, thousands <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/morocco-earthquake-death-toll-passes-2800-survivors-camp-outdoors-2023-09-11/">died</a>, villages were devastated, roads were closed, and locals <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/09/12/travel/tourism-morocco-maui.html#:~:text=With%20the%20high%20tourism%20season,in%20funds%20for%20relief%20efforts.">continued</a> to <a href="https://www.euronews.com/travel/2023/11/17/solidarity-warms-the-heart-tourism-has-helped-morocco-recover-from-its-deadly-earthquake">welcome</a> the flow of tourism that, ultimately, helped fund relief efforts.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s no blanket recommendation here —&nbsp;different areas have different situations. Government officials and business owners might even send mixed messages on whether your presence would be welcomed. Cultivating a habit of trying to understand at least a little about the state of the local communities on our travel lists can help align trips with the well-being of more vulnerable places.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even as tourism rates trend toward a full rebound, the world is warmer and less predictable. “Extreme and severe weather events in the United States and around the world are becoming more frequent, having a greater impact, and affecting places where people may not be as prepared to handle them,” AccuWeather chief meteorologist Jon Porter said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Uncertainty is becoming the kind of travel companion you just can’t get rid of. Globally, we’re already on a path toward making natural disasters <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/natural-disasters#:~:text=Disasters%20%E2%80%93%20from%20earthquakes%20and%20storms,over%20the%20last%20few%20decades.">less and less deadly</a>. We’ll need to keep up that momentum, while maybe even doing the unthinkable: changing our own personal travel habits, at least a little bit.  </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Benji Jones</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[These beloved sea creatures are dying. Can human medicine save them?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/368728/disease-coral-reefs-caribbean-bonaire-solution" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368728</id>
			<updated>2024-08-28T15:26:00Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-28T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Down to Earth" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Several meters underwater off the coast of Bonaire, a small island in the south Caribbean, Danielle de Kool floated in place in front of a large head of boulder brain coral. The pattern across its surface looked like the maze you might find on the back of a cereal box.&#160; From a plastic syringe, de [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A scuba diver with their hands on a large brain coral." data-caption="Danielle de Kool, an ecologist at an environmental organization in Bonaire called STINAPA, applies a medicinal paste to a boulder brain coral." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-0447.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Danielle de Kool, an ecologist at an environmental organization in Bonaire called STINAPA, applies a medicinal paste to a boulder brain coral.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Several meters underwater off the coast of Bonaire, a small island in the south Caribbean, Danielle de Kool floated in place in front of a large head of boulder brain coral. The pattern across its surface looked like the maze you might find on the back of a cereal box.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From a plastic syringe, de Kool, an ecologist at a local environmental group, squeezed a toothpaste-like substance into her hand. She then pressed the paste onto the surface of the coral around the edge of a large white splotch that had recently appeared.  </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-0478.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="A scuba diver’s hand on a pale spot on an underwater brain coral." title="A scuba diver’s hand on a pale spot on an underwater brain coral." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="De Kool presses the paste onto a colony of boulder brain coral." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The coral was sick. And this paste might help heal it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the last decade, a mysterious illness called stony coral tissue loss disease (SCTLD) has been ravaging coral in reefs across the Caribbean. The disease — which is&nbsp;likely caused by a bacterium or virus — targets a number of hard, reef-forming coral species. It essentially pulverizes the soft coral tissue, killing centuries-old colonies in a matter of weeks. The plight has now spread to <a href="https://oref.maps.arcgis.com/apps/dashboards/54b5df5c111b4fcc986e300c6aea63a3">at least 30</a> countries and territories in the Caribbean, where corals were already suffering from pollution, climate change, and other threats. In regions hit by SCTLD, the disease has reduced the area of coral by anywhere from <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adk6808">30 percent to 60 percent</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Researchers say that SCTLD is now likely the <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/marine-science/articles/10.3389/fmars.2023.1321271/full">worst coral disease outbreak</a> ever recorded.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last spring, the disease was spotted in Bonaire —&nbsp;one of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/366763/bonaire-coral-reef-caribbean-climate-change" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/366763/bonaire-coral-reef-caribbean-climate-change">few spots in the Caribbean where you can still find an abundance of healthy coral</a>. The island, like many others in the tropics, is deeply dependent on its reef. Tourism is the engine of Bonaire’s economy, and the majority of visitors come to scuba dive and snorkel. Plus, large coral structures dampen waves that hit the shore, lessening flooding during big storms.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">SCTLD has already killed off more than 90 percent of some coral species in Bonaire, including boulder brain and maze corals, according to preliminary data from STINAPA, a local organization working to protect the reef. The outbreak is quite literally threatening Bonaire’s way of life, the primary source of income for its residents, and the island’s ability to defend itself from destructive hurricanes. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-5913.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A colony of elkhorn coral near the rocky coast of Bonaire, an island in the south Caribbean. | Jenny Adler" data-portal-copyright="Jenny Adler" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">With the stakes so high, ecologists across the Caribbean are trying desperately to ease the spread of SCTLD. And on that morning in July, de Kool, who works for STINAPA, was doing one of the few things that seems to work: smearing sick corals with antibiotics.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Liquifying coral from the inside out</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Each bit of coral is a colony of animals, comprising hundreds to thousands of tiny creatures called polyps. Those polyps produce skeletons made of calcium carbonate —&nbsp;the same material found in sea shells&nbsp;—&nbsp;which forms the hard structure of the reef.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was produced in collaboration with the Pulitzer Center</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">This is the second story in an ongoing series on the future of coral reefs as they face threats from climate change and disease. It was supported by the&nbsp;<a href="https://bandfdn.org/about/">BAND Foundation</a>&nbsp;and a grant from the&nbsp;<a href="https://pulitzercenter.org/">Pulitzer Center</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Read the first story at the link below. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/366763/bonaire-coral-reef-caribbean-climate-change">This coral reef has given scientists hope for years. Now they’re worried.&nbsp;</a></p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And like other animals, corals can get sick. Over the last century, a number of diseases have decimated coral populations worldwide. White band disease, for example, first appeared in the 1970s and has since killed more than <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.aax9395">80 percent</a> of staghorn and elkhorn corals in the Caribbean. These iconic species, named for their antler-like appearance, were once so abundant in the shallows that fishermen would have to cut them down in order to clear a path for their boats.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">SCTLD, meanwhile, is relatively new. Scientists first observed the disease a decade ago in Florida, and there are still many unknowns, such as where it first came from and even what SCTLD is. It could be a bacterium or a virus, or both working together. Some kind of bacteria, for example, could be making coral more susceptible to a virus, said Blake Ushijima, a microbiologist at the University of North Carolina Wilmington.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Scientists also aren’t sure how SCTLD has moved around the Caribbean. The spread generally seems to follow ocean currents, but it sometimes jumps between distant places, said Marilyn Brandt, a coral scientist at the University of the Virgin Islands. In some cases, cargo ships are likely responsible for the spread, she said. As ships load and unload cargo, they fill and empty ballast tanks&nbsp;that help stabilize the vessels. These tanks could be inadvertently transporting SCTLD-causing pathogens. (There are now regulations and technologies designed to minimize the spread of disease and invasive species in ballast water, though not all ships adhere to them, Brandt said.)&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-2 is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-6748.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="SCTLD spreads across a colony of symmetrical brain coral." data-portal-copyright="" />

<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-4727.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A colony of great star coral ravaged by the disease." data-portal-copyright="" /></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On that morning in July, I was diving with de Kool<strong> </strong>on a reef just off the northwest coast of Bonaire. The view underwater was stunning: a messy tapestry of colorful corals and sea sponges home to all kinds of sea creatures. About 20 minutes into our dive, a hammerhead shark swam by. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet there were also signs of SCTLD everywhere.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-5575.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="A scuba diver swimming in the distance, with lumpy coral in the foreground." title="A scuba diver swimming in the distance, with lumpy coral in the foreground." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="The author, Benji Jones, on a shallow dive in Bonaire." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Reefs get their signature bright coloring from a symbiotic algae that lives inside the live coral tissue. The sickened colonies, though, had big white spots where the disease had apparently destroyed the tissue, exposing the coral’s bone-white skeleton. Many of those spots were already turning green from different kinds of algae that grow on dead sections of coral.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’ve never seen a disease like this,” Caren Eckrich, an ecologist at STINAPA, told me. In Bonaire, it’s something close to an “extinction-level event,” she said, meaning it’s nearly wiping out some of the island’s coral species. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But scientists are not totally powerless against it. They have a weapon.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">A simple, time-consuming approach that works&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For years now, companies and hobbyists who grow coral in aquariums have used various antibiotics to treat sick sea creatures, including coral, Ushijima told me. They essentially dip pieces of coral into antibiotic washes or put medicine directly into the fish tanks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When SCTLD began spreading several years ago, scientists tried a similar approach —&nbsp;and it worked. They brought sick corals infected with SCTLD into the lab and treated them with antibiotics, including amoxicillin, the same drug humans use for bacterial infections. Most of them recovered.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-0596.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Dive instructor and educator Carmen Toanchina on a dive to treat corals with SCTLD." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Treating corals in the wild, however, is a different challenge altogether. That’s where that toothpaste-like substance de Kool was using comes in. Through trial and error, scientists figured out that they could mix powdered amoxicillin with a biodegradable putty, made by the company <a href="https://www.oceanalchemists.com/">Ocean Alchemists</a>, that sticks to the surface of coral underwater. When you apply the antibiotic paste around a SCTLD lesion, it can, as <a href="https://peerj.com/articles/9289/">studies</a> have <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-86926-4">shown</a>, stop or slow the disease from spreading through the colony. “It is very effective,” Brandt said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That amoxicillin works is actually a bit peculiar. While it’s still not clear what pathogen causes SCTLD, there’s some evidence suggesting the disease is viral, Brandt said. How would amoxicillin,&nbsp;which kills bacteria, stop a viral disease? One theory, she said, is that if it is indeed viral, the pathogen may still require bacteria to cause disease (in humans, bacteria and viruses sometimes <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6027610/">cooperate with each other</a>). Another possible explanation, she said, is that the pathogen targets the symbiotic algae living within coral tissue. Antibiotics often kill those algae without killing the coral, essentially removing the target of infection and stemming the spread. Or perhaps SCTLD is caused by bacteria after all, as other scientists suspect. No one knows for sure. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It seems very likely that the bacterial component is at least very important in the infection process,” said Karen Neely, a research scientist at Florida’s Nova Southeastern University who first trialed the antibiotic paste in the wild. “But regardless, the amoxicillin does work. It’s keeping corals alive.”</p>

<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-2 is-cropped wp-block-gallery-2 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-0651.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="De Kool applies the paste to a sick section of symmetrical brain coral." data-portal-copyright="" />

<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-0584.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Carmen Toanchina, who volunteers with STINAPA, carries several syringes of antibiotic paste on a dive in Bonaire to treat corals." data-portal-copyright="" /></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Back on the reef, I watched de Kool and a handful of other divers, including dive instructor and educator Carmen Toanchina, cruise around the reef and treat corals. They’d spot a colony with white lesions, unclip a syringe from their vest, squirt out some paste, and then, somewhat awkwardly, try to apply it to the coral’s surface. It was like watching someone stick strips of Play-Doh on weird-looking rocks but underwater — where masks fog up, sharks swim by, and one deep breath threatens your buoyancy. The work was slow going.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-0590.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="De Kool and Toy exit the water after a dive to treat coral." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">These treatments appear to be working, said Jeannine Toy, who oversees a squadron of STINAPA volunteers like Toanchina who apply the antibiotics. They’ve been treating reefs in Bonaire for more than a year now. “About 70 percent are healed after we treat them,” Toy told me after the dive.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The goal isn’t to treat every coral around the island, Toy said — that’d be nearly impossible. Rather, STINAPA wants to treat enough colonies so that there are plenty of live corals to spawn, or sexually reproduce, and create the next generation of corals in Bonaire. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Can SCTLD be stopped?&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The bad news is that SCTLD is unlikely to disappear anytime soon. It’s now endemic, or consistently present, in some regions, like Florida and the US Virgin Islands. Scientists also fear that it will soon spread to the Pacific, home to the Great Barrier Reef and, in general, a much higher diversity of corals. It’s not clear how susceptible Pacific corals will be. “The scary part is that we don’t know,” Ushijima said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Against the enormity of the ongoing outbreak, antibiotics are sorely inadequate. While amoxicillin can stem the growth of lesions, it doesn’t prevent infection. And applying the paste is incredibly labor intensive, Brandt said. “It requires tons of divers,” she said. “I have four people and that’s all they do.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some scientists, including Ushijima, are also concerned that the bacteria it kills might eventually develop a resistance to amoxicillin, making the treatment less useful.&nbsp;(So far there are no signs of antibiotic resistance, Neely says.)</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-0578.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A small SCTLD lesion on a colony of great star coral with antibiotic paste." data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-0516.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Orange tape marks corals that STINAPA is monitoring for SCTLD. | Jenny Adler" data-portal-copyright="Jenny Adler" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">For now, Brandt points out, giving sick corals antibiotics is the best option available. “It was the only effective solution that we were able to deploy in a large way,” she said, referring to her conservation work in the US Virgin Islands. Her team, she said, “has saved quite a lot of coral.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, scientists like Ushijima are also working on other potential treatments, such as coral probiotics. Some corals appear to be naturally resistant to SCTLD;<strong> </strong>the microbes found in and around them may have something to do with this resistance. Certain kinds of bacteria, for example, help corals fight off disease, Ushijima said. Biologists are trying to identify those defense microbes so they can inoculate wild coral with them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This approach points to something hopeful: Some corals are doing just fine. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Again, this could have to do with those microbes or with genetics; resistance to disease can be rooted in coral DNA. But it also has to do with the environment, Brandt said, and the other threats corals are exposed to. Reefs that are already weakened by extreme heat or pollution are more likely to get sick, just as it’s easier to catch a cold when you’re stressed. What’s more, Brandt said, is that reducing local sources of stress gives corals a better chance of growing back after they suffer a loss from SCTLD. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/adler_final-0619.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="De Kool places a fragment of smooth flower coral into a bucket, which she’ll deliver to Reef Renewal Bonaire, an organization that raises coral to restore reefs." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">If any reef can survive the impacts of SCTLD, it’s Bonaire. The island has protected its reef from threats like overfishing for more than half a century, longer than pretty much any other region worldwide. And the corals here have demonstrated that they can bounce back from major die-offs, as I <a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/366763/bonaire-coral-reef-caribbean-climate-change">recently reported</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As de Kool and I cruised around the reef, she wasn’t only treating sick corals but also monitoring colonies that have so far resisted infection. There were a lot of them, including big heads of brain coral and even some pillar corals, which have been hit especially hard by SCTLD in the Caribbean. Perhaps these colonies are resistant to the disease. Perhaps they will seed the next generation of corals around the island, helping this once-vibrant reef recover.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If not, doctors are standing by with medicine. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I spent a good part of my career monitoring corals to death,” Neely told me. “We can’t do that anymore. We have to be active. We are part of the reason that reefs are dying and to not do something about it is really just unacceptable at this point.” </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Christian Paz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How is Kamala Harris getting away with this?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/369177/democrats-kamala-harris-truce-immigration-progressive-border-security" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369177</id>
			<updated>2024-08-28T14:20:31Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-28T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Immigration" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since Vice President Kamala Harris’s ascension to the top of the Democratic ticket, a careful truce has settled in place between centrist, liberal, and progressive Democrats. No loud or public spats among elected Democrats or Democratic voters over Harris’s candidacy or campaign have made headlines, save for some premature skepticism by online progressives over Harris’s [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="US Vice President and 2024 Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris speaks at the Democratic National Convention | Andrew Caballero-Reynolds/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Caballero-Reynolds/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2167183594.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>US Vice President and 2024 Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris speaks at the Democratic National Convention | Andrew Caballero-Reynolds/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Since Vice President Kamala Harris’s ascension to the top of the Democratic ticket, a careful truce has settled in place between centrist, liberal, and progressive Democrats.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No loud or public spats among elected Democrats or Democratic voters over Harris’s candidacy or campaign have made headlines, save for some <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/364677/tim-walz-harris-vp-josh-shapiro">premature skepticism by online progressives</a> over Harris’s vice presidential selection; Harris has nearly<a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/649127/democrats-give-harris-nearly-unanimous-positive-ratings.aspx"> universal favorability</a> among her fellow partisans. The Democratic National Convention (DNC) did not succumb to the kind of chaos and division that was anxiously predicted when Biden was the presumptive nominee; in fact, Democrats are showing heretofore unseen levels of <a href="https://www.thebulwark.com/p/democrats-in-array">being in array</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps no issue is more emblematic of this party unity than the thorny topic Democrats have long hoped to avoid: the politics of immigration and the southern border. At the DNC last week, Harris and the speakers who addressed the nation made clear that the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/368138/dnc-immigration-border-security-latino-voters">Democratic Party of 2024 is moving right</a>, toward the political center, when it comes to how they talk about immigrants, migration, and security at the southern border. While humanitarianism, openness to migrants, and rolling back restrictive Trump-era policies used to be the Democratic focus, Democrats are locked in on stopping the flow of migrants, limiting asylum, and funding more Border Patrol operations. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s partially out of a need to appeal to moderate, swing, and independent voters in the various battleground states that will decide the 2024 election. But it’s also a recognition of the very different national environment Democrats are operating in. American adults of all stripes have <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/351535/3-theories-for-americas-anti-immigrant-shift">turned much more negative</a> in their thinking about immigration and border security. The days of talking up a humanitarian approach to immigration, of expanding opportunities for asylum seekers, and racing to <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/6/26/18760665/1325-immigration-castro-democratic-debate">outflank</a> other Democrats from the left, are gone. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Presidential candidates pivoting to the middle on key issues ahead of a general election is unsurprising. What is surprising is that, on immigration, the Harris campaign is doing so without facing much opposition from liberal politicians, progressive activists, or even longtime pro-immigrant advocacy groups. Progressive activists and advocates say that truce will likely hold — at least until after Trump is defeated and a more receptive President Kamala Harris is elected.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Yes, there is a palpable and deep worry about how much Democrats are willing to compromise on immigration,” Vanessa Cárdenas, the executive director of the pro-immigration reform group America’s Voice, told me. “We’re in a very different political moment than years past. We’re going to have to make hard choices. But ultimately as advocates, we need to keep our eye on the ball and make sure we win as much as possible.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Democratic Party’s shift on immigration was on full display at the DNC</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris previewed her new vision, and the Democratic Party’s new direction, during her acceptance speech last Thursday when she promised to “bring back the bipartisan border security bill that [Donald Trump] killed.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That bill, negotiated earlier this year by Biden and a bipartisan group of senators, would have put $20 billion toward new security measures at the southern border and imposed <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/2/5/24062710/senate-immigration-bill-border-security-ukraine-2024">new, more restrictionist policies</a> toward asylum seekers and other migrants. The bill failed once Trump began to voice his opposition, on the grounds that it could defuse an issue that, left unaddressed, could benefit him in the election, but its mere existence was remarkable for the absence of a pathway to citizenship or other pro-immigrant priorities Democrats have traditionally advocated for.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s embrace of the bill is a major signal for how her administration would deal with immigration: She’s just fine with border policy that is tough on migrants and strengthens border security without offering much to pro-immigrant groups.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But her support for the measure has received scrutiny from Trump’s campaign and some in the press, who note that the bill included hundreds of millions of dollars in <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/27/kamala-harris-flip-flops-border-wall">funding for southern border wall construction</a>, something Harris previously criticized and called “un-American.” The VP’s campaign argues that the money was just a continuation of spending authorized during the Trump presidency, updated with new guidelines on where it can be spent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And she’s not making a full break with Democratic tradition.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I know we can live up to our proud heritage as a nation of immigrants and reform our broken immigration system,” she also said to thunderous applause in her DNC speech. “We can create an earned pathway to citizenship — and secure our border.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Pro-immigrant activists described the position Harris articulated in her DNC speech to me as a “both/and” approach to immigration: reforming a broken system for processing asylum claims, providing a pathway to citizenship for those undocumented immigrants living in the US for a substantial period of time, and restoring order at the southern border without demonizing immigrants.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a palatable balance for now but one that may not be sustainable in the longer term given some of the harder-line stances, including embracing the bipartisan border bill, that Harris, Biden, and the rest of the party have taken. The 2024 DNC platform, for example, acknowledges that part of the reason immigration reform is critical is to speed up the deportation of economic migrants and those deemed not to have a legal reason for immigrating. It also calls for Congress to “strengthen requirements for valid asylum claims” and boosts Biden’s executive actions to limit asylum when border crossings reach an untenable level.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why the left is holding back its ire for now</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For some progressives, the party’s embrace of the border bill is worrying because the negotiation process that produced it in early 2024 marked a significant departure from the way Democrats have traditionally dealt with immigration and border politics.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For most of the last decade and a half, Democratic politicians would generally only consider enforcement and border security funding when paired with pro-immigrant reforms or policies. Biden’s deal with Senate Republicans didn’t address the human side of the immigration debate and instead dealt only with border security.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Some of the lessons learned in the past are that sometimes Democrats give in so much to enforcement, and it&#8217;s not congruent with what is obtained on the legalization side,” Cárdenas said. “We are concerned about the often-cited Senate bill — we’re concerned that that might be the starting point of any legislation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But elections are binary choices, Cárdenas and other advocates point out. Right now, Harris is triangulating a position that responds to real-world factors: the images of people crossing the border, the overwhelmed border communities dealing with constant flux, Republicans politicizing the issue and demonizing migrants, and public opinion turning away from the pro-immigrant movement.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The RNC and DNC offered “a very clear difference on how both parties and candidates are speaking about immigration,” Yadira Sanchez, the executive director of the progressive organizing group Poder Latinx, told me. One convention was a rally in favor of mass deportations and used “the border and immigrants themselves as scapegoats to spread hate and xenophobia around the border crisis,” Sanchez said. The other convention presented their candidate as the daughter of immigrants, who honors the country’s immigrant past while wanting to crack down on transnational gangs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sanchez also pointed out the Democrats’ pivot to the center in speeches and the party platform, but she noted that the alternative to Democratic governance would be untenable for immigration advocates and immigrants alike.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Yes, we didn&#8217;t get everything that we wanted as an immigrant rights organization. We want to have fair, equitable, dignified, humane asylum processes for folks that are seeking that refuge, that are experiencing that turmoil in their countries, that are looking for safety. The border talk was something where we saw the shift, but I wouldn&#8217;t say it completely complicates our advocacy work because our advocacy work goes beyond any candidate, in the sense that we will hold them accountable,” Sanchez said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The overriding sense I picked up from these activists is that they and their constituencies understand the trade-off in front of them: To accomplish their policy goals, they need a Democratic president and Democratic congressional majorities, so they’ll remain part of the big-tent coalition that Harris and the party are trying to build in order to win in November. It mirrors what moderate candidates like New York Rep. <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/20/tom-suozzi-border-immigration-speech-dnc">Tom Suozzi</a> did to respond to suburban concerns about immigration, and what even some progressive candidates, like Michelle Vallejo in the Rio Grande Valley, <a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/inside-congress/2024/08/23/the-race-to-watch-on-the-south-texas-border-00176230?nname=playbook&amp;nid=0000014f-1646-d88f-a1cf-5f46b7bd0000&amp;nrid=767af309-421c-4f12-9633-f7aea351bc0c&amp;nlid=630318">are doing now</a>: recognizing that electoral victories are the top priority and pivoting to tougher talk on the border in the hope of winning congressional majorities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That doesn’t mean progressives don’t have some strong disagreements with the approach Harris and the Democratic Party are currently taking, but they’ll likely avoid direct confrontation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Right now, the assignment is very clear,” Cárdenas said. “We have to make sure that Trump is defeated, and in February 2025, we can have a conversation about what kind of reforms we need to make.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dylan Scott</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[This ancient disease still kills 1 million people every year]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/369095/hepatitis-vaccine-deaths-symptoms-infections" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369095</id>
			<updated>2024-08-27T23:26:46Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-28T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health Care" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than a decade ago, scientists achieved a historic breakthrough: They found a first-ever cure for hepatitis C, one of two related liver diseases that, combined, take more than a million lives every year.&#160; In 2016, just three years after the antiviral drug Sovaldi received FDA approval, the World Health Organization (WHO) set the audacious [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="hepatitis B C virus infection deaths" data-caption="Hepatitis has been known to humankind for centuries. But despite the development of promising new treatments, global deaths have been on the rise." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-508573194.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Hepatitis has been known to humankind for centuries. But despite the development of promising new treatments, global deaths have been on the rise.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">More than a decade ago, scientists achieved a historic breakthrough: They found <a href="https://www.gilead.com/news-and-press/press-room/press-releases/2013/12/us-food-and-drug-administration-approves-gileads-sovaldi-sofosbuvir-for-the-treatment-of-chronic-hepatitis-c">a first-ever cure for hepatitis C</a>, one of two related liver diseases that, combined, take <a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/09-04-2024-who-sounds-alarm-on-viral-hepatitis-infections-claiming-3500-lives-each-day#:~:text=According%20to%20the%20World%20Health,tuberculosis%2C%20a%20top%20infectious%20killer.">more than a million lives</a> every year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <a href="https://www.globalhep.org/about/about-hepatitis-elimination#:~:text=Global%20hepatitis%20elimination%20goals&amp;text=In%20the%20same%20year%2C%20the,C%20from%202015%20to%202030.">2016</a>, just three years after the antiviral drug Sovaldi <a href="https://www.gilead.com/news-and-press/press-room/press-releases/2013/12/us-food-and-drug-administration-approves-gileads-sovaldi-sofosbuvir-for-the-treatment-of-chronic-hepatitis-c">received</a> FDA approval, the World Health Organization (WHO) set <a href="https://www.who.int/health-topics/hepatitis/elimination-of-hepatitis-by-2030#tab=tab_1">the audacious goal</a> of eliminating the two most common versions of viral hepatitis, B and C. The benchmark was, by 2030, to reduce new infections by 90 percent and deaths by 65 percent. The year before that goal was set, 1.3 million people <a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/21-04-2017-new-hepatitis-data-highlight-need-for-urgent-global-response#:~:text=Viral%20hepatitis%20caused%201.34%20million,caused%20by%20tuberculosis%20and%20HIV.">died</a> from hepatitis B and C.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Much of that optimism behind that goal has now evaporated. After a brief dip, the number of hepatitis deaths worldwide <a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240091672">has been rising</a> again — from 1.1 million in 2019 to 1.3 million in 2022, according to WHO. New infections are down somewhat over the same period, from 3 million to 2.2 million, but it has not been enough to turn the tide on fatalities. About 6,000 people are still being diagnosed with hepatitis B or C every day, and more than 3,500 people die daily from these infections.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Future Perfect newsletter</a>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">here</a> to explore the big, complicated problems the world faces and the most efficient ways to solve them. Sent twice a week.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Chari Cohen, now the president of the <a href="https://www.hepb.org/">Hepatitis B Foundation</a>, which advocates for investments in research and treatment for the disease, started her career researching the disease around the turn of the century. “Twenty-five years later, I thought we&#8217;d be in a better place,” she told me recently.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The main hurdles to stamping out these diseases, especially in Africa and South Asia <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/hepatitis/global/index.htm">where the burden is highest</a>, include under-resourced health systems and lingering stigma against patients who contract hepatitis. And while hepatitis C has been solved by science, a clinical solution to the deadlier hepatitis B remains elusive. The prognosis for other long-time public health challenges is improving with new treatments, but the world will fall far short of its 2030 goals for slowing hepatitis.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We are nowhere near the ability to do that. Unfortunately, we are gonna fall very short of that target,” Andrea Cox, who studies hepatitis at Johns Hopkins University, told me. “If the current trends continue, by the year 2040 the number of people dying of hepatitis B and C will exceed the number of people dying globally of HIV, [tuberculosis], and malaria combined.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hepatitis B and C have proven hard to stamp out</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://medlineplus.gov/hepatitis.html">Hepatitis</a> is a viral infection of the liver, causing chronic inflammation that can lead to cirrhosis, liver cancer, and eventually death over time.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://www.immunize.org/wp-content/uploads/catg.d/p4075.pdf">B and C variants</a> spread through contact with bodily fluids; there are also versions that result from alcohol use and autoimmune disorders. In developing countries, people often become infected with hepatitis at a young age through exposure to infected blood, and more serious complications develop years later. In rich and poor countries alike, hepatitis can also spread through the sharing of needles for intravenous drug use and through sexual contact.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hepatitis B <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/microbiology/articles/10.3389/fmicb.2022.972687/full">integrates</a> into the host’s DNA, which makes it more difficult for the body’s immune system to find and eliminate all of it. With hepatitis C, the new generation of cures that debuted with <a href="https://www.webmd.com/drugs/2/drug-165500/sovaldi-oral/details">Sovaldi</a> in 2013 was able to activate the human immune system to eliminate the virus entirely when used in combination with other existing drugs. Hepatitis B has so far proved resistant to a similar approach. The fact that few animals naturally develop a hepatitis infection has also <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/microbiology/articles/10.3389/fmicb.2021.715450/full">slowed down research</a>, Cohen said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, hepatitis B is the more pernicious disease: It is responsible for most of all hepatitis deaths (<a href="https://www.paho.org/en/news/10-4-2024-who-sounds-alarm-viral-hepatitis-infections-claiming-3500-lives-each-day">87 percent</a>) and more than half of the new infections globally. In recent years, <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/hepatitis-b/treatment/index.html">treatments</a> such as tenofovir&nbsp;have been <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/liv.14155">proven capable</a> of allowing people to live longer, more normal lives after a diagnosis and <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/hcp/vis/vis-statements/hep-b.pdf">an effective infant vaccine</a> is available to prevent infections in the first place.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The availability of both antiviral medications and vaccines means we have the tools to significantly reduce hepatitis’s damage. How can we be losing ground instead?</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why the world’s goal of eliminating hepatitis is slipping away</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beyond biology, the fight against hepatitis is up against two distinct challenges.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, the disease is particularly prevalent in developing countries where <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/357805/global-health-security-explained-us-africa-pandemics-ebola-covid">the local health system may be ill-equipped</a> to perform the kind of prevention, surveillance, and treatment necessary to bring these diseases under control. In Africa, vaccine uptake is particularly low; in Asia, antivirals are not as easily available as experts would like.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Diagnosing hepatitis is notoriously difficult, as it can have few symptoms until the damage to liver functions becomes more severe. Only an estimated 13 percent of people living with chronic hepatitis B worldwide had been diagnosed by the end of 2022, and, as a result, only 3 percent have received the available antivirals. For hepatitis C, an estimated 36 percent of cases had been diagnosed between 2015 and 2022 and only 20 percent of people had received the combination medication that cures the disease.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More than 60 percent of new hepatitis B infections occur in Africa and yet only 18 percent of the continent’s newborns receive the vaccine that effectively eliminates the risk of infection. Less than half of infants worldwide received the hepatitis B vaccine in 2022, according to the WHO estimates. It will require a more aggressive public health campaign, with better education and an increased capacity to get doses out in the field, to improve those figures.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Developing countries are already facing a variety of health problems, of which hepatitis is only one. While they have been focused on getting <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/1/25/24047975/malaria-mosquito-bednets-prevention-fishing-marc-andreessen">malaria</a> or <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/366903/mpox-monkeypox-africa-continental-emergency-drc-who-clade">mpox</a> or <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24099834/dengue-fever-virus-mosquito-brazil-vaccine">dengue</a> under control, that has left limited resources for yet another disease — and one that is heavily stigmatized.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some of the countries that are most affected by hepatitis struggle to acquire the medical tools to combat the disease, according to WHO. Even though hepatitis B medications should be available for just a few dollars per dose and the hepatitis C cures can be had for $60 or so, most of the 25 nations that bear the biggest hepatitis burden are failing to procure those medicines at those low prices, reducing their overall supply.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Prejudices against people with hepatitis, both personal and institutional, are also the result of its association with drug use and sex. In some of the most affected countries, people can face officially sanctioned <a href="https://www.hepb.org/blog/zero-discrimination-day/">discrimination</a>, losing their job or being denied an immigration visa or admission to school.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That stigma reduces the willingness of clinicians and government officials to be more proactive about trying to control the disease. It also reduces the willingness of patients to seek out a test if they are worried about symptoms. If we don’t know who has hepatitis B or C, we can’t put these effective drugs to use.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">​​“If a family is known to have hepatitis B in many areas of the world, they really are shunned,” Cohen said. “I wouldn’t want to be tested if I lived in a country and I knew that if I tested positive, I was going to lose my job.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are some signs of the stigma breaking, of more people speaking out about their experiences with hepatitis, especially in developed countries like the US. But breaking such a long-held bias is difficult. And until the hepatitis community can mobilize a political movement that public officials can no longer ignore, the dream of eradicating hepatitis could keep slipping away.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I kind of felt that after 25 years, I wouldn’t have to constantly argue about prioritizing. I figured it would be a no-­brainer,” Cohen said. “But the communities that are most impacted by hepatitis B are the disenfranchised communities, the communities that don’t typically have a political voice. They don’t have political strength. And when you don’t demand action, you don’t get it.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden’s plan to shield undocumented spouses of Americans is on hold. Here’s what to know.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/369180/biden-undocumented-spouses-legalization-court-ruling" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369180</id>
			<updated>2024-08-27T22:46:44Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-27T22:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Immigration" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="US Federal Courts" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A federal court in Texas has put one of the biggest legalization programs in over a decade on hold temporarily, leaving more than half a million people in limbo.&#160; The program, announced by the Biden administration in June, allows undocumented spouses of Americans to apply for a green card without having to leave the country. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Several people stand in sunshine against a blue sky, holding American flags. " data-caption="A naturalization ceremony held on November 19, 2022, at the National Cemetery in Gettysburg, Pennsylvania. | Andrew Lichtenstein/Corbis via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Lichtenstein/Corbis via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1443027720.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A naturalization ceremony held on November 19, 2022, at the National Cemetery in Gettysburg, Pennsylvania. | Andrew Lichtenstein/Corbis via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">A federal court in Texas has put one of the biggest legalization programs in over a decade <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.txed.232527/gov.uscourts.txed.232527.27.0_1.pdf">on hold temporarily</a>, leaving more than half a million people in limbo.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The program, announced by the Biden administration in June, allows undocumented spouses of Americans to apply for a green card without having to leave the country. Approximately 500,000 spouses and 50,000 stepchildren would be eligible for the program, according to senior administration officials.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The attorneys general of 16 red states — including Texas, Florida, and Georgia — <a href="https://www.texasattorneygeneral.gov/sites/default/files/images/press/Parole%20in%20Place%20Complaint%20Filed.pdf">argued</a> that the program was an illegal attempt to circumvent Congress and create a new pathway to citizenship. The court has given those states two weeks to provide evidence that they would be permanently harmed if the program resumes. Then, the court will rule whether blocking the program on a longer-term basis is appropriate. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The individuals eligible for the new program were always technically able to apply for permanent residence through their US citizen spouse or stepparent but to do so, their families would have to separate, making applying impractical, if not impossible. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s because undocumented immigrants would have to leave the country as part of the green card application process. They wouldn’t be legally allowed to reenter for 10 years if they had initially come to the US without permission and stayed for more than a year. Immigrants can <a href="https://www.fwd.us/news/parole-in-place-citizen-spouses/">apply for waivers</a> of this 10-year bar, but the process faces major backlogs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If upheld, the new program would essentially allow noncitizen spouses and stepchildren to bypass that 10-year bar by offering them parole, which protects them from deportation and gives them work authorization.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While the government won’t be able to process applications to the program under the court’s order, individuals can still file applications in the hope that the program will be allowed to resume.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Critically, that might only happen after an appeals process that could extend beyond the November election. If former President Donald Trump is elected, he is expected to scrap the program because it conflicts with his campaign promise to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/11/us/politics/trump-2025-immigration-agenda.html">deport undocumented immigrants</a> living in the US.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What are the chances that the program survives court challenges?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Based on previous cases involving the legal authority Biden invoked to create the program, it should survive court challenges, said <a href="https://www.mckinneyimmigration.com/jeremy-mckinney/">Jeremy McKinney</a>, former president of the American Immigration Lawyers Association.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The program relies on the president’s power to issue what’s called “parole in place,” which has been used for decades by both Republican and Democratic presidents to allow immigrants to remain in the US temporarily, as well as on a case-by-case basis for humanitarian reasons — or because it would significantly benefit the public. For instance, the US government has offered <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/sites/default/files/document/brochures/Brochure-Immigration_Options_for_Family_of_Certain_Military_Members_and_Veterans.pdf">parole in place to undocumented relatives of US service members</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of what could help the new program as it faces legal challenges is the fact it isn’t creating a new path to citizenship for immigrants, but instead relies on parole in place to make it easier for undocumented spouses to obtain legal status that they are already eligible for.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“All it does is make it easier for mixed-status households to stay together while they are going through the legal immigration process,” McKinney said. “This is not a shortcut of the normal system.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He noted that the Fifth Circuit, the appeals court that might review this case, previously recognized the president has parole-in-place authority as recently as 2021 when it called it a “means of removing bars that stand between an [immigrant] and government benefits.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I do think that the legal landscape looks favorable to these applicants,” he said.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Should undocumented spouses still apply?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those eligible for the program can still move ahead with their applications.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be eligible for the new program, spouses must be present in the US without having been legally admitted to the US or previously provided parole. They must have also lived in the US for at least a decade and have a legally valid marriage to a US citizen as of June 17, 2024. And they must “merit a favorable exercise of discretion” and not pose a threat to public safety, according to a senior administration official.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For stepchildren to be eligible, they must be unmarried and under 21. Their parent must have married a US citizen before the stepchild turned 18.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The decision of whether to apply might ultimately come down to whether applicants are willing to take on the financial risk while the program is on hold. The application fee is $580 per person, excluding any fees associated with hiring a lawyer to prepare the application. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They are making a financial bet, so to speak,” McKinney said. “And so if money is tight, maybe they want to wait until the litigation is resolved.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg’s letter about Facebook censorship is not what it seems]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/369136/zuckerberg-letter-facebook-censorship-biden" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369136</id>
			<updated>2024-08-28T14:05:24Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-27T20:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Big Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Facebook" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Social Media" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Tech policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology &amp; Media" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Mark Zuckerberg sent Rep. Jim Jordan (R-OH) a letter outlining how the Biden administration pressured his company to “censor” free speech on Facebook — specifically misinformation about Covid-19. The letter also made reference to Hunter Biden’s laptop and Zuckerberg’s lack of plans to spend money on the election. This sounds bad. But none [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Mark Zuckerberg said in a letter to Rep. Jim Jordan that he regretted Facebook’s reaction when the Biden administration pressured it to remove Covid-19 misinformation. | Jason Henry/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Jason Henry/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2162539369.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Mark Zuckerberg said in a letter to Rep. Jim Jordan that he regretted Facebook’s reaction when the Biden administration pressured it to remove Covid-19 misinformation. | Jason Henry/Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">This week Mark Zuckerberg sent Rep. Jim Jordan (R-OH) a letter outlining how the Biden administration pressured his company to “censor” free speech on Facebook — specifically misinformation about Covid-19. The letter also made reference to Hunter Biden’s laptop and Zuckerberg’s lack of plans to spend money on the election. This sounds bad. But none of this information is new.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s interesting that Zuckerberg decided to dive into the free speech snake pit this week. It’s also not surprising that Republicans, who have been on <a href="https://www.latimes.com/world-nation/story/2023-04-22/book-bans-soaring-schools-new-laws-republican-states">a book-banning spree</a> at schools nationwide, are propping up old facts as if they were new revelations in their ongoing quest to blame Democrats for censorship. It’s election season, and questioning reality is part of the fun.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As we enter the final two months before the election, there are <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-2024-misinformation-ai-social-media-trump-6119ee6f498db10603b3664e9ad3e87e">fewer guardrails for misinformation in place</a> on major social media platforms, and writing a letter about the Biden administration and censorship, Zuckerberg seems to be throwing Republicans a political grenade, something that can fire up the base and use to get mad about Democrats. In reality, though, Zuckerberg is probably just trying to keep his company out of more hot water and to <a href="https://www.wsj.com/style/fashion/mark-zuckerberg-meta-gold-chain-outfits-76533bb2">continue revamping his own public image</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To understand how Zuckerberg’s letter could do this, it helps to know why he sent it to Rep. Jordan in the first place.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Jordan, chair of the House Judiciary Committee, has <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/07/27/how-mark-zuckerberg-became-a-republican-punching-bag-00108403">singled out</a> the Meta CEO in an ongoing investigation that alleges the Biden administration and tech companies colluded to censor free speech online. Jordan even <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/07/27/jordan-postpones-zuckerberg-contempt-of-congress-vote-00108570">threatened</a> to hold Zuckerberg in contempt of Congress for ignoring a subpoena for documents. Zuckerberg now seems rather forthcoming.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/08/27/meta-zuckerberg-covid-misinformation-jordan-white-house/">his letter</a>, Zuckerberg acknowledges that the Biden administration pressured the company “to censor certain Covid-19 content, including humor and satire” and says that the pressure was “wrong.” Zuckerberg added that his company was “ready to push back if something like this happens again.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is not news. The Biden administration did pressure Meta, as well as its competitors, to crack down on Covid-19 misinformation throughout the pandemic. In 2021, Surgeon General Vivek Murthy <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2021/07/15/1016013826/the-u-s-surgeon-general-is-calling-covid-19-misinformation-an-urgent-threat">called it “an urgent threat,”</a> and Biden himself said that misinformation was “killing people,” <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/07/19/politics/joe-biden-facebook/index.html">a statement he later walked back</a>. This pressure was also at the center of a recent Supreme Court case, in which justices <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/26/us/politics/supreme-court-biden-free-speech.html">ruled in favor of the Biden administration</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We also knew that Meta, then known simply as Facebook, pushed back at efforts to stop the spread of misinformation on its platforms. Not long after Biden’s “killing people” remark, leaked company documents <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-mark-zuckerberg-vaccinated-11631880296?mod=article_inline">revealed that Facebook knew</a> that vaccine misinformation on its platforms was undermining its own goal of protecting the vaccine rollout and was causing harm. It even studied the broader problem and produced several internal reports on the spread of misinformation, but despite pressure from Congress, Facebook <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/10/28/facebook-covid-misinformation/">failed to share that research with lawmakers</a> at the time.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We actually learned about the specific kind of pressure the White House put on Facebook a year ago, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-bowed-to-white-house-pressure-removed-covid-posts-2df436b7">thanks to documents</a> the company turned over to, you guessed it, Jim Jordan and the House Judiciary Committee.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-1968446598.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.782006784713,100,78.435986430574" alt="Mark Zuckerberg, in a black suit and gray tie, sits behind a nameplate with his name on it at a Senate desk." title="Mark Zuckerberg, in a black suit and gray tie, sits behind a nameplate with his name on it at a Senate desk." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Mark Zuckerberg appears before the Senate Judiciary Committee hearing “Big Tech and the Online Child Sexual Exploitation Crisis” on January 31, 2024. | Brendan Smialowski/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Brendan Smialowski/AFP via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden administration issued a statement after <a href="https://x.com/JudiciaryGOP/status/1828201780544504064">Zuckerberg’s latest letter</a> became public. It said, in part, “Our position has been clear and consistent: We believe tech companies and other private actors should take into account the effects their actions have on the American people, while making independent choices about the information they present.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the Zuckerberg letter didn’t stop with details of the well-known crackdown on Covid misinformation. It also reminds the public of the time, ahead of the 2020 election, the FBI warned social media companies that a New York Post article about Hunter Biden’s laptop could be part of a Russian disinformation campaign. Without mentioning any direct pressure from the government, Zuckerberg says in the letter that his company <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/08/27/meta-zuckerberg-covid-misinformation-jordan-white-house/">demoted the laptop story</a> while it conducted a fact-check. He <a href="https://nypost.com/2022/08/25/mark-zuckerberg-criticizes-twitters-handling-of-the-posts-hunter-biden-laptop-story/">told podcaster Joe Rogan something similar in a 2022 interview</a>, when he mentioned that <a href="https://judiciary.house.gov/media/press-releases/testimony-reveals-fbi-employees-who-warned-social-media-companies-about-hack">an FBI disinformation warning</a> contributed to the decision to suppress the story. Twitter also suppressed the laptop story, and its executives <a href="https://apnews.com/article/technology-politics-united-states-government-us-republican-party-business-6e34ad121a1e52892b782b0b7c0e59c3">denied that there was pressure</a> from Democrats or law enforcement to do so.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Zuckerberg also addresses some donations he made to voting access efforts in the 2020 election through his family’s philanthropic foundation. “My goal is to be neutral and not play a role one way or another — or to even appear to be playing a role,” the billionaire said. “So I don’t plan on making a similar contribution this cycle.” The House Judiciary Committee <a href="https://x.com/JudiciaryGOP/status/1828204002187587867">responded in a tweet</a>, “Mark Zuckerberg also tells the Judiciary Committee that he won&#8217;t spend money this election cycle. That’s right, no more Zuck-bucks.” Neither party mentioned that Zuckerberg <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2022-election/zuckerberg-money-wont-aid-elections-rcna24002">also declined to make a contribution in the 2022 cycle</a> for the same reasons.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The right is taking a victory lap over this Zuckerberg letter. Others are simply wondering why on earth, on an otherwise quiet week in August, did Zuckerberg even bother to remind us of all of these familiar facts?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One theory comes <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/mark-zuckerberg-letter-jim-jordan-meta-facebook-censorship-politics-meaning-2024-8">from Peter Kafka at Business Insider</a>: “Zuckerberg very carefully gave Jordan just enough to claim a political victory — but without getting Meta in any further trouble while it defends itself against a federal antitrust suit.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear, Congress is not behind the antitrust lawsuit. The case, which dates back to 2021, comes from the FTC and 40 states, which say that Facebook <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/19/technology/ftc-facebook-antitrust.html">illegally crushed competition</a> when it acquired Instagram and WhatsApp, but it must be top of mind for Zuckerberg. In a landmark antitrust case less than a month ago, a federal judge <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/05/technology/google-antitrust-ruling.html">ruled against Google</a>, and called it a monopoly. So antitrust is almost certainly on Zuckerberg’s mind.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s also possible Zuckerberg was just sick of litigating events that happened years ago and wanted to close the loop on something that has caused his company massive levels of grief. Plus, allegations of censorship have been a distraction from his latest big mission: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/18/24042354/mark-zuckerberg-meta-agi-reorg-interview">to build artificial general intelligence</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Zuckerberg, according to his new style, is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/style/fashion/mark-zuckerberg-meta-gold-chain-outfits-76533bb2">a newly minted member of Gen Z</a>, one who’s future-focused and patriotic in a way. For all we know, dashing off controversial-seeming letters to Congress is part of this revamped image and yet another way of reminding the world that he <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/02/10/politics-meta-threads-instagram/">does not want to be involved in politics again</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, August 28, 10 am ET: </strong>A previous version of this story misstated what organization warned social media companies about the spread of a New York Post article about Hunter Biden’s laptop ahead of the 2020 election.</em> </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[SpaceX’s risky mission will go farther into space than we’ve been in 50 years]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/science/369106/spacex-polaris-dawn-jared-isaacman-elon-musk-tesla-space-crew-dragon" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369106</id>
			<updated>2024-08-27T19:38:19Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-27T19:40:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Billionaires" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Elon Musk" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Influence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Science" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Space" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="SpaceX" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Travel" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[SpaceX plans to send four people into Earth orbit as soon as Wednesday in a daring mission that will test new technology, expose astronauts to high levels of radiation, and potentially change how future spacewalks are conducted. The privately funded mission, called Polaris Dawn, will be led by billionaire Jared Isaacman, who participated in and [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Workers surround a large white and silver cylinder-shaped spacecraft at NASA’s Kennedy Space Center with launch platforms in the background." data-caption="Workers prepare SpaceX’s Polaris Dawn Falcon 9 for another launch attempt at NASA’s Kennedy Space Center on August 27, 2024, in Cape Canaveral, Florida. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2168837151.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Workers prepare SpaceX’s Polaris Dawn Falcon 9 for another launch attempt at NASA’s Kennedy Space Center on August 27, 2024, in Cape Canaveral, Florida. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">SpaceX plans to send <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/26/science/spacex-polaris-dawn-mission-spacewalk.html">four people</a> into Earth orbit as soon as Wednesday in a daring mission that will test new technology, expose astronauts to high levels of radiation, and potentially change how future spacewalks are conducted.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The privately funded mission, called Polaris Dawn, will be led by billionaire Jared Isaacman, who participated in and funded <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/09/18/science/spacex-inspiration4.html">the first private, all-civilian space mission in 2021</a>. Polaris Dawn will also include SpaceX engineers Sarah Gillis and Anna Menon, as well as former Air Force pilot Scott Poteet. The mission was scheduled to launch Tuesday, but the flight was <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/science/space/spacex-polaris-launch-postponed-helium-leak-detected-rcna167168">delayed due to a helium leak</a>. The team will spend five days aboard SpaceX’s Crew Dragon vessel, and will travel 870 miles away from Earth, in the <a href="https://www.space.com/spacex-polaris-dawn-launch-delay-helium-leak">farthest crewed mission since 1972’s Apollo 17 spaceflight</a> to the moon. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That distance will put the craft more than 200 miles inside the Van Allen radiation belts — <a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/phenomena/radiation-belts">regions in space that encircle the planet</a> and are highly radioactive. They were <a href="https://spacecenter.org/what-are-the-van-allen-radiation-belts/#:~:text=The%20Van%20Allen%20radiation%20belt,by%20that%20planet's%20magnetic%20field.">detected on the first US space mission</a>, in 1958, and their highly charged, energetic particles can damage spacecraft instruments. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The tech aboard the capsule will have to withstand that radiation — as will the astronauts. Two members of the crew, Isaacman and Gillis, will exit their vehicle via a hatch that exposes the entirety of the capsule to space, rather than through an airlock, as astronauts typically do.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The passengers will acclimate to depressurized conditions over the course of about 45 hours to avoid getting nitrogen bubbles in their bloodstreams —&nbsp;which can be deadly.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of the crew, and all of the systems onboard, need to be able to withstand radiation; each of the passengers need to don SpaceX’s new spacesuits before Isaacman and Gillis start their walk. The capsule underwent rigorous testing on Earth to ensure the radiation wouldn’t fry its circuits, stranding the astronauts. But testing the equipment on the ground isn’t the same as putting it in space, and SpaceX hopes the mission will provide valuable information about how to construct instruments and spacecraft for future missions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s of particular importance for future missions to the moon and beyond — computers have advanced a lot since the ’70s, the last time humans had to deal with the level of Van Allen radiation the Polaris Dawn crew could face.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Our current technology is ever more susceptible to these accelerated particles because even a single hit from a particle can upset our ever smaller instruments and electronics,” David Sibeck, Van Allen Probes mission scientist at NASA’s Goddard Space Flight Center, <a href="https://spacecenter.org/what-are-the-van-allen-radiation-belts/#:~:text=The%20Van%20Allen%20radiation%20belt,by%20that%20planet's%20magnetic%20field.">told Space Center Houston in a 2020 interview</a>. “As technology advances, it’s actually becoming even more pressing to understand and predict our space environment.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Crucially, Isaacman and Gillis will also test how protective their suits are when they venture out of the Crew Dragon.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These suits were designed <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/19/science/spacex-polaris-dawn-jared-isaacman-spacewalk/index.html">in just two and a half years</a> — an astonishingly quick turnaround by space exploration standards — and are meant to be upgrades to the bulky suits NASA has made famous. Rather than having life support systems integrated into the suit, like in NASA’s, Space X’s new suits connect to the spacecraft via a tube —&nbsp;that’s how Isaacman and Gillis will be able to breathe and function while performing their spacewalk.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Besides radiation, the suits may also need to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/19/science/spacex-polaris-dawn-jared-isaacman-spacewalk/index.html">withstand microimpacts</a>. There are all manner of small objects whizzing in Earth’s orbit at around 17,000 miles per hour; a puncture could be catastrophic. The suits were put through debris testing on Earth, but just like with the instruments, controlled tests are different from the real thing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">SpaceX argues that the mission should go on despite the risks because of all the knowledge there is to gain. Should the flight be successful, humans will obtain a lot of fresh data on how Van Allen radiation affects our latest technology and our bodies; astronauts may gain an alternative way to do spacewalks; and scientists will have a lot to dissect about spacesuit design.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And that’s not to mention the impact the mission could have on long-term goals to send humans back to <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/artemis/#:~:text=With%20NASA's%20Artemis%20campaign%2C%20we,term%20presence%20on%20the%20Moon.">the moon</a> and <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/humans-to-mars/">Mars</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">SpaceX has specifically highlighted the importance of its new suit in making that happen, writing on its <a href="https://polarisprogram.com/dawn/">website,</a> “The development of this suit and the execution of the spacewalk will be important steps toward a scalable design for spacesuits on future long-duration missions as life becomes multiplanetary.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">SpaceX has said it doesn’t plan to stop here: Polaris Dawn is part of the Polaris Project, which will include two subsequent missions —&nbsp;all of which Isaacman is funding in conjunction with the company.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
