<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-07-25T02:25:48Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/05/vox-favicon.jpeg?w=32</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Allie Volpe</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Inspired by the Olympics? You can become an athlete at any age.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/362550/getting-into-sports-age-olympics-motivation-athlete-gymnastics-track-basketball-swimming" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362550</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T16:42:24Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Olympics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Sports" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a child, Brian Hankerson daydreamed not of watching television or getting into trouble with friends after school. He wanted to high jump. A grade school-aged Hankerson would rush home from class, set up a fishing pole supported by two chairs, lay out a blanket beneath it, and hurtle his body over the makeshift setup.  [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An illustration of eight people playing different sports, including tennis, soccer, volleyball, golf, badminton, football, and running." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1973203086.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">As a child, Brian Hankerson daydreamed not of watching television or getting into trouble with friends after school. He wanted to high jump. A grade school-aged Hankerson would rush home from class, set up a fishing pole supported by two chairs, lay out a blanket beneath it, and hurtle his body over the makeshift setup. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the decades following, Hankerson never formally trained or competed as a runner or high jumper. That is, until his mid-40s, when he noticed adults racing at a track-and-field meet his kids were also participating in. “They weren’t young adults, they were older adults,” Hankerson says. Hankerson, a Coral Springs, Florida-based accountant, signed up to compete in a division called masters — <a href="https://world-masters-athletics.org/world-masters-athletics/">for those aged 35 and up</a> — and wound up setting meet records for the high jump and long jump. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now 64, Hankerson still competes across the country and internationally — he’s headed to the World Masters Athletics Championships in Sweden this August — and continues to sing the praises of organized athletics for adults. “If I can get out and push the envelope beyond what I think I can do, or I feel like I can do, then so can you,” he says. “Do you believe you can get out there and accomplish something? You will absolutely not know until you try.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Hankerson can attest, there’s no time like the present to pursue athletics, no matter your age. But the older we get, the more we suspect our time has passed. While kids are offered the freedom to dabble and play when they first pick up a sport, adults <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23979535/permission-to-suck-terrible-hobbies">feel like they have to be good at it</a> or else the endeavor isn’t worth their time. “When adults come in for our gymnastics classes, they’re very apprehensive about doing new things with their body, or doing things they haven’t done in a very long time, and they get scared,” says Jackie Alexis, the recreational gymnastics coach at <a href="https://www.industrygymnastics.com/">Industry Gymnastics</a>, a Long Island-based gymnastics school for all ages and abilities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p> “Do you believe you can get out there and accomplish something? You will absolutely not know until you try.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With the <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/358882/simone-biles-olympic-trials-paris-floor-vault">2024 Paris Olympics</a> upon us, you might be feeling particularly inspired to learn a sport, or wistful about ones you weren’t able to try in the past. But there’s so much to gain when picking up — or returning to — a sport, coaches say. Not only are you moving your body and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6908518/">learning new skills</a>, but you’re <a href="https://systematicreviewsjournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13643-023-02264-8">fostering social connections</a> in a niche community — all of which have positive <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9902068/">impacts on mental</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC11043276/">physical health</a>. If you don’t know where to start or are unsure of how to build athletics into your routine, coaches and athletes have some tips.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Let your interests motivate you</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From baseball to badminton, there are a myriad of athletic endeavors to choose from. Think about the sports currently capturing your attention, whether it’s Olympic gymnastics or <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/24139393/challengers-sexy-tennis-zendaya-luca-guadagnino-investigation">tennis, thanks to <em>Challengers</em>,</a> and the ones that intrigued you as a kid. Use your interests — past and present — as a guide when selecting your sport.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If nothing comes to mind, let yourself be influenced. Patrick “Pat The Roc” Robinson began offering adult basketball classes at his <a href="https://pattherocacademy.com/">basketball skills academy</a> to keep parents of youth players engaged while their kids were practicing. Over time, parents began to take notice of the other lesson taking place during their child’s practice. “Each week, we get more and more parents that just happen to be in the gym,” Robinson says, “and they see the other adults participate. Now, they’re not ashamed or they’re not nervous about joining.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Sign up for classes, but don’t splurge on gear</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Enrolling in a class is often the best first step when diving into a new sport. Coaches will teach you proper form, safety, and the rules of the game, and have equipment for you to use. Knowing you have practice every Thursday night offers structure and consistency, which is helpful for building routine, Robinson says. You can also join a local club for free but less individualized instruction. Resist the urge to spend exorbitant amounts of money on new gear, Alexis and Robinson say.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are a few options to find classes near you. See if your town’s parks and recreation department offers adult sport lessons or leagues — these may be cheaper than private gyms. Browse social media, like your city’s subreddit or local Facebook groups dedicated to specific sports to find recommended coaches or instructors.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Start with small, consistent efforts every day</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When people are super inspired, they tend to jump into their new sport headfirst, says <a href="https://www.teamsoho.org/coaches.html">Lucy Glanville</a>, the youth programming head coach at <a href="https://utaholympiclegacy.org/soldier-hollow-sports/">Soldier Hollow Nordic Center</a>, a facility that was used during the 2002 Olympic Winter Games in Salt Lake City. This excitement is motivating in the short-term, but a two-hour pickleball lesson might leave you so sore the next day that you never want to pick up a paddle again. Small, daily, consistent efforts will ensure you won’t get burned out, Glanville says. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For instance, Robinson tells his adult students to practice their shooting form sans basketball throughout the week between practices; Alexis breaks down every gymnastics move into incremental steps. “Some people come in, and they’re like, ‘I want to do a backflip,’” they say. “I’m like, ‘Let’s work our way up to that.’” </p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“You can control getting your shoes on, stepping outside, and starting.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can also set incremental goals or milestones that support your consistency-building habits, Glanville says, making sure they are easily achievable and within your control. If your ultimate goal is to run a 10k, give yourself mini-goals that are more about the <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23344385/beginners-guide-running">process of running, rather than the outcome</a> of finishing a race. “You can’t control whether your body’s going to make 10k that first time,” Glanville says, “but you can control getting your shoes on, stepping outside, and starting. Focusing on that start process and what it is that you can do, as opposed to what the dream is.” These smaller wins boost your confidence and allow you to set bigger goals. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bring a friend (and be open to making friends)</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re nervous about starting a new sport with a bunch of strangers, enlist a friend to come with you. Not only will you feel comfortable with a familiar face, but you can hold each other accountable. At Industry Gymnastics, friend groups often sign up for adult classes, Alexis says. “And if they come by themselves, they quickly make friends with the other people who come by themselves,” they say.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The social aspect of athletics is what brings players year after year to the adult basketball training center <a href="https://nevertoolate.com/">Never Too Late Basketball</a>, according to its founder, Steve Bzomowski. Ever since Never Too Late held their first clinic over 30 years ago, players have remarked on the organization’s ability to bring people together to collaborate. “People just really like the idea of getting together, meeting people you never knew before,” Bzomowski says, “and creating something that you had no idea that you could create.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Push yourself, but know your limits</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bzomowski wants to remind beginner adult athletes that they are capable of learning a new skill — it’s why he named his basketball clinic Never Too Late. At the end of weekend-long camps, each player is recognized for their particular strengths, whether it’s passing or effectively communicating, he says. Regardless of your skill level, there are areas where you will excel. While everyone’s bodies and abilities vary, Hankerson says you may be surprised at what your body can achieve. “I do something at 60 better than I did at 50,” he says.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kelley Shaw, the program director at Industry Gymnastics, believes no one is too old to learn gymnastics, but “you don’t have to do every skill,” she says. “You can do the ones that you feel comfortable with and don’t hurt.” This approach can apply to all sports: Give a drill or exercise your best effort, but listen to your body and ask your instructor for modifications if needed.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Don’t compete with anyone but yourself</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Adult gymnasts at Industry Gymnastics are often concerned with doing a move or drill perfectly, Shaw and Alexis say. But both instructors say learning a new skill or brushing up on old ones requires some imperfection before you start to improve. As difficult as it may be, don’t compare your abilities to your classmates’ — or your younger self. “Just try to do better than yourself each day,” Hankerson says, “not someone else you see on TV or on YouTube or at the track meet. Don’t worry about that.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Through these struggles, small accomplishments, and big wins, you learn about yourself, Bzomowski says. You learn what your body is capable of, how you work with other people, and what you’re able to overcome. “It’s not <em>just</em>, ‘I didn’t know whether I was capable of this physically,’” he says. “Feeling resistance within myself and overcoming that — I think that’s a big part of it.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kyndall Cunningham</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[There’s one perfect way to see Twisters]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/362928/how-to-see-twisters-4dx-perfect-way-imax-rpx-explained" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362928</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T23:34:08Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Movies" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had no business enjoying Twisters as much as I did.&#160; For one, I’m not a fan of disaster movies. Nor do I have a relationship to the original 1996 film Twister — although, it turns out you don’t need to know anything about the first movie to watch this stand-alone sequel. I didn’t walk [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Characters in the movie Twisters: one lying on the ground holding the other, who is being pulled into the air." data-caption="A still of actors Sasha Lane and Glen Powell from the new film Twisters. | Melinda Sue Gordon/Universal Pictures, Warner Bros. Pictures, and Amblin Entertainment" data-portal-copyright="Melinda Sue Gordon/Universal Pictures, Warner Bros. Pictures, and Amblin Entertainment" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/2571_D038_00298RV2_CROP_641680.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A still of actors Sasha Lane and Glen Powell from the new film Twisters. | Melinda Sue Gordon/Universal Pictures, Warner Bros. Pictures, and Amblin Entertainment</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">I had no business enjoying <em>Twisters</em> as much as I did.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For one, I’m not a fan of disaster movies. Nor do I have a relationship to the original 1996 film <em>Twister</em> — although, it turns out you don’t need to know anything about the first movie to watch this stand-alone sequel. I didn’t walk out of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/359689/storm-chasing-twister-tornado-expert"><em>Twisters</em></a> thinking that it was particularly good. The performances by Daisy Edgar-Jones and (sorry) <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/361486/glen-powell-explained-twisters-hit-man-anyone-but-you">Glen Powell</a> were mediocre. The dialogue was silly. The music cues were laughable. Every aspect of the film felt like it was focus-grouped, including the omission of a climactic kiss between the two “romantic” leads. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So how did I manage to leave<em> Twisters</em> elated, you might ask? I paid an extra $6 to see it in 4DX, an “immersive” theater experience that feels like the only way anyone should consume this ridiculous film. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the uninitiated, 4DX is sort of like if you watched an entire action movie inside one of those virtual-reality space shuttles at an amusement park — only a lot more visceral. The experience at Regal Cinemas includes motion-enabled seats that jolt and rotate. In the case of <em>Twisters</em>, there are bursts of wind, trickles of rain, and fog. You’re also guaranteed a heightened communal experience. At my screening, several set pieces were followed by loud applause, including after a tragic scene where innocent characters die. By the end of the film, I had no idea whether everyone was responding to the events in the film or to the chaotic bodily experience we had all endured together. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/2571_FP_00623B-3587x1500-d3275b2.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=10.064120434904,0,79.871759130192,100" alt="A man and woman stand with their backs to the camera, facing a swirling cloud." title="A man and woman stand with their backs to the camera, facing a swirling cloud." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Glen Powell and Daisy Edgar-Jones in &lt;em&gt;Twisters&lt;/em&gt;. | Universal Pictures, Warner Bros. Pictures, and Amblin Entertainment" data-portal-copyright="Universal Pictures, Warner Bros. Pictures, and Amblin Entertainment" />
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Twisters</em> has already done a lot of <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@tyvid5/video/7393766876129578283">good advertising</a> for the limited format. The film made $2.1 million in 4DX tickets during its opening weekend, and <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@mnelson1610/video/7394233559055142175">moviegoers</a> can’t <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@thevelasquezfamilia/video/7393819455521901867">stop</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@tyvid5/video/7394553154374831403">raving</a> about the <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@trulyoliviaa/video/7395063773020589342">experience</a> on social media. It’s certainly good advertising leading up to <em>Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</em>, out this weekend, which can also be experienced for a limited time in 4DX.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">4DX is just one of many movie formats that has made moviegoing more exciting but also a lot more confusing — and expensive. With streaming keeping more people at home, theater chains seem focused on selling premium experiences. However, are they enhancing the experience of moviegoing or complicating it with all these different options? The answer might be both. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Why are there so many movie theater formats?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’ve bought a movie ticket recently, you’ve probably noticed the increasing number of premium formats available. The list of options for <em>Twisters</em> in the New York City area is comically long and utterly perplexing. In addition to 4DX, you can also pay to see the film in IMAX, Laser at AMC, IMAX with Laser at AMC, Dolby Cinema at AMC, Prime at AMC, RPX, and Screen X. You could also see it in the standard digital 2D format, the cheapest of all these options. However, when listed alongside all these formats that sound innately fancy — even if you don’t have the vaguest idea what they mean — a standard screening might seem less ideal. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-660166846.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.669135487166,100,78.661729025667" alt="4DX seats in a theater." title="4DX seats in a theater." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="The 4DX “Twist and Sway” chairs displayed during 2017 CinemaCon in Las Vegas, Nevada. | Bryan Steffy/Getty Images for 4DX" data-portal-copyright="Bryan Steffy/Getty Images for 4DX" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">So what do these formats entail exactly? For the most part, they magnify how you see and hear a movie. IMAX, which is shot on IMAX cameras using 70mm film, is probably the best-known. A more exclusive format like RPX is still a bit more foreign. <a href="https://www.regmovies.com/rpx">RPX</a> (Regal Premium Experience) is Regal Cinema’s in-house larger-screen format, which features an updated sound system. It’s not as high-quality as IMAX, nor is it as premium as <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/dolby-showcases-the-immersive-power-of-dolby-cinema-in-latest-love-more-global-brand-campaign-302073543.html">Dolby Digital Cinema</a>, which is located in AMC theaters. Dolby Cinema uses dual 4K laser projectors, which has four times more resolution than a standard theater projector. These theaters are also equipped with Dolby Atmos, an ultra-surround sound system that includes speakers in the ceilings and transducers in the seats.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Laser at AMC uses laser projectors in place of digital ones, while <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/imax-launches-next-generation-imax-with-laser-experience-to-enhance-blockbuster-moviegoing-at-amc-theatres-300635259.html">Laser with IMAX</a> simply combines their respective technologies. <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/amc-to-bring-cinionic-laser-to-all-prime-at-amc-locations-301814426.html">PRIME at AMC</a> boasts Cinionic laser projectors, better acoustics, and “sublime seating.” (On paper, it doesn’t seem that different from Laser.) Lastly, Screen X is a more immersive experience, using a 270-degree panoramic presentation system. Like 4DX, it’s an export from South Korea. It’s equally gimmicky, expanding images along the walls during key scenes to make audiences feel like they’re inside a room or on a battlefield. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As confusing and even unnecessary as they may be, the advent of these new, snazzy formats makes sense in a time when people need some extra motivation to leave their couches to go sit in a theater. With the popularity of streaming and with films going quickly from <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/28/media/movies-streaming-box-office-theaters/index.html">theaters to VOD</a>, it seems as though theater chains have to promote themselves differently — not just with their film offerings but with a unique experience that can’t be emulated at home. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The strategy of selling a movie in a special format seemed to work for <a href="https://variety.com/2023/film/news/oppenheimer-imax-70mm-craze-projectors-1235697085/"><em>Oppenheimer</em></a>. While IMAX is hardly a new format, Christopher Nolan’s urging of the public to see <em>Oppenheimer</em> on the biggest screen possible, whether in IMAX 70mm or non-IMAX 70mm, seemed largely related to the overall success of the film. Not only did IMAX theaters sell out rapidly, particularly in New York City, but the level of demand prompted an <a href="https://variety.com/2023/film/news/oppenheimer-imax-70mm-extended-tickets-1235689899/">extended IMAX run</a>. It also reminded audiences how much the size of their screens and quality of a picture can highlight good filmmaking. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">4DX, however, is an entirely different beast. Its goal is to entertain the audience, not elevate art. While it could grow into a huge cash cow for theater chains, it’s hard to know if it’s ultimately what’s best for cinema as a whole.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>How does 4DX affect moviegoing?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Twisters</em> might do for 4DX what <em>Oppenheimer</em> did for IMAX. Critics and average moviegoers alike are spreading the gospel of the format online and selling out showings. This is certainly the most PR 4DX screenings have gotten since they arrived in America in 2014. But is this something we could see the film industry push back on? </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">4DX is designed to heighten moviegoers’ senses and put them inside of the film. But there’s an argument to be made that all the movement and effects distract from the story being told onscreen. I spent most of my <em>Twisters </em>viewing waiting for action sequences so that I could be jolted in my seat and giggle with my friends. Additionally, it was hard to pay much attention to the direction of the film, the dialogue, or the <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/359689/storm-chasing-twister-tornado-expert">science behind the storm-chasing</a> while being thrashed around. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the case of a silly movie about tornadoes, I didn’t feel like I was robbed. My friends and I agreed we would’ve been bored out of our minds if we had watched <em>Twisters</em> in any other format. Still, we walked away with a reaction that wasn’t truly genuine. Nor did we respond properly to the tone the film was trying to create in certain moments. For instance, a devastating opening sequence that sets up a post-traumatic arc for Edgar-Jones’s character, Kate, was met with excitement and laughter. Who knows whether being more locked into this moment would’ve made the stakes of the film feel more real. It’s hard to argue that you need to respect the gravitas of a film like <em>Twisters</em>, but for a higher-quality movie with good performances, one can imagine some seriousness being lost. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It has yet to be seen if 4DX will be an actual “threat” to cinema. Right now, there are only 50 4DX theaters in the United States. Plus, the higher ticket price, an <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/05/27/4dx-movie-experience.html">average of $8</a> more than a standard ticket, may not be worth it to certain moviegoers. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, it’s not hard to see this becoming the next great film-viewing debate. Given the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/5/1/8528111/watching-movies-on-smartphones-spike-lee">panic</a> filmmakers have already displayed over young people watching movies on their iPhones, one can imagine the sort of uproar in Hollywood if 4DX became a bigger phenomenon. For now, though, it seems Americans haven’t been more excited about a new theater technology since before the pandemic. If film executives continue to feed us horrible IP, we might as well be allowed to rock out in our seats. </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[J.D. Vance has made it impossible for Trump to run away from Project 2025]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362917/jd-vance-project-2025-book-kevin-roberts-trump" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362917</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T21:52:20Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former President Donald Trump has lately been trying to distance himself from Project 2025, claiming it was cooked up by the “severe right” and that he doesn’t know anything about it. But it turns out the severe right is coming from inside the house. Kevin Roberts, the self-proclaimed “head” of Project 2025, has a book [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="J.D. Vance, with a serious expression, points while speaking from a podium reading Trump Vance 2024, and standing in front of a US flag." data-caption="Sen. J.D. Vance (R-OH) speaks at a campaign rally at Radford University on July 22, 2024, in Radford, Virginia. | Alex Wong/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Alex Wong/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2163101562.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Sen. J.D. Vance (R-OH) speaks at a campaign rally at Radford University on July 22, 2024, in Radford, Virginia. | Alex Wong/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Former President Donald Trump has lately been trying to distance himself from <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce">Project 2025</a>, claiming it was cooked up by the “<a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/us-politics/donald-trump-project-2025-rally-b2583142.html">severe right</a>” and that he doesn’t know anything about it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it turns out the severe right is coming from inside the house.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kevin Roberts, the self-proclaimed “head” of Project 2025, has a book coming out in September — and the book’s foreword is written by Trump’s vice presidential candidate, J.D. Vance, who lavishly praises its ideas.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Never before has a figure with Roberts’s depth and stature within the American Right tried to articulate a genuinely new future for conservatism,” Vance writes, according to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dawns-Early-Light-Burning-Washington/dp/0063353504">the book’s Amazon page</a>. “We are now all realizing that it’s time to circle the wagons and load the muskets. In the fights that lay ahead, these ideas are an essential weapon.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What ideas? Like <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361455/jd-vance-trump-vice-president-rnc-speech">Vance</a>, Roberts is obsessed with the idea that the left controls major American institutions — he lists Ivy League colleges, the FBI, the New York Times, the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, the Department of Education and even the <a href="https://www.netgalley.com/catalog/book/420673">Boy Scouts of America</a>. The book argues that “conservatives need to burn down” these institutions if “we’re to preserve the American way of life.” (Vox has requested a copy of the book, but has not yet received one at the time of this writing.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Obviously, this poses a problem for Trump’s attempts to distance himself from the virally unpopular Project 2025 and its lengthy agenda for what he should do if he wins, which includes proposals to restrict abortion access and centralize executive power in the presidency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And it’s one more indication that Trump’s pick of Vance <a href="https://newrepublic.com/post/184106/trump-picking-jd-vance-mistake-biden-kamala-harris">might be politically problematic</a> for him. Vance <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23373795/curtis-yarvin-neoreaction-redpill-moldbug">has a fascination</a> with provocative and extreme far-right thinkers, and a history of praising their ideas. He is not a running mate tailored to win over swing voters who are concerned Trump might be too extreme — quite the opposite.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The book was written and announced before Vance was chosen as Trump’s running mate. But there’s some indication that people involved had some late second thoughts about it. It was <a href="https://x.com/Bon__Mots/status/1813587219351048196">originally announced</a> as “Dawn’s Early Light: Burning Down Washington to Save America,” with a cover image showing a match over the word “Washington.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More recently, though, the subtitle <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dawns-Early-Light-Burning-Washington-ebook/dp/B0CQHPFHWT/ref=sr_1_2?crid=3F2DU567XZRSM&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.JJLB_KRiLLo1NMFtP-Gn4QnL_zVCR2ltpQaz8WLfQv5qVRf1xKTRhDIadUQ1KDANwziEvWMvIWXuq0d1vCJ5CgwkqFh0izVjpNc5Sz4-vudQnl90jezYmPx2BwZ3kcDtO4GIU83tYBEf9CkFqakSU0et4r0Kx8AvQD6v4zA1Qmht_1dWAzZdbSBzkt1ny8RF9ODuCzbcx9BpmrUQLWC2R4XjMqTQDEFsBIukdihaN1M.FMN8-LJ7hQn6C46DwhNNw32atyu_1it28xVsF8M3bnU&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=dawns+early+light&amp;qid=1721743470&amp;s=books&amp;sprefix=dawns+early+light%2Cstripbooks%2C123&amp;sr=1-2">has been changed</a> to “Taking Back Washington to Save America,” and the match has vanished from the cover.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Roberts headed Project 2025 — and contributed some of its most controversial proposals</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Project 2025, which I recently <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce">wrote about at length</a>, is the conservative movement’s detailed and specific plan for what the next Republican president should do with his power.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was crafted by people who have long worked closely with Trump and includes many policies Trump clearly supports — like centralizing power in the presidency over career civil service professionals, slashing regulations, and abandoning efforts to fight climate change. It also contains some proposals Trump currently finds politically problematic: aggressively using federal power to prevent abortions, restricting some contraceptive coverage, and banning pornography.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Project 2025 was put together by the conservative Heritage Foundation, which worked on it with more than 100 conservative groups. Though much of <a href="https://static.project2025.org/2025_MandateForLeadership_FULL.pdf">its 922-page policy document</a> is written in dry, wonkish language, Roberts wrote the fiery introduction. The porn ban is his idea specifically — he writes:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">Pornography should be outlawed. The people who produce and distribute it should be imprisoned. Educators and public librarians who purvey it should be classed as registered sex offenders. And telecommunications and technology firms that facilitate its spread should be shuttered.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On abortion, Roberts writes: “Conservatives in the states and in Washington, including in the next conservative Administration, should push as hard as possible to protect the unborn in every jurisdiction in America.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.heritage.org/staff/kevin-d-roberts-phd">Roberts</a>, who has led Heritage since late 2021, has a history of controversial statements. “We are in the process of the second American Revolution, which will remain bloodless if the left allows it to be,” he <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/kevin-roberts-man-behind-project-2025-just-said-the-quiet-part-out-loud">recently said</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Vance is a big fan. “I was thrilled to write the foreword for this incredible book, which contains a bold new vision for the future of conservatism in America,” he <a href="https://x.com/JDVance/status/1803537040555876682">tweeted in June</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tucker Carlson, who was heavily featured at the recent Republican National Convention, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/0063353504#:~:text=%E2%80%9CThere%20aren%E2%80%99t%20many%20public%20policy%20executives%20in%20Washington%20who%20actually%20understand%20where%20the%20world%20is%20going%20or%20why.%20In%20fact%2C%20I%E2%80%99ve%20met%20just%20one%3A%20Kevin%20Roberts%20of%20The%20Heritage%20Foundation.%20This%20is%20his%20plan%20to%20save%20America.%20It%E2%80%99s%20deep%20and%20wise.%E2%80%9D%20%E2%80%94%20Tucker%20Carlson">has also praised</a> the book and Roberts’s “plan to save America,” calling it “deep and wise.”&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Vance agrees quite a bit with Project 2025’s most extreme ideas</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Project 2025 contains a multitude of proposals in its 922-page plan, not all of which J.D. Vance necessarily supports.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he’s on record backing ideas similar to those put forth in two of Project 2025’s most controversial issue areas.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first is abortion. Project 2025 lays out <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce#:~:text=3)%20A%20hardline,fetal%20cell%20research">a sweeping agenda</a> by which the next president could use federal power to prevent abortions, including using an old law called the Comstock Act to prosecute people who mail abortion pills, and working to prevent women from abortion-banning states from traveling out of state to get abortions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance is on record supporting these ideas. Last year, he <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2024/07/17/jd-vance-abortion-comstock-vice-presidential-nominee/">signed</a> a letter demanding that the Justice Department prosecute physicians and pharmacists “who break the Federal mail-order abortion laws.” In 2022, he said he was “sympathetic” to the idea that the federal government <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/17/politics/kfile-jd-vance-abortion-comments/index.html">should stop</a> efforts to help women traveling out of their states to get abortions. That year, he <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/17/politics/kfile-jd-vance-abortion-comments/index.html">also said</a>: “I certainly would like abortion to be illegal nationally.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At other points, Vance has struck a different tone. ““We have to accept that people do not want blanket abortion bans,” he said <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/17/politics/kfile-jd-vance-abortion-comments/index.html">last December</a>. And this month <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/2024/06/supreme-court-preserves-access-to-abortion-pill/">he said</a> he supported a Supreme Court decision that allowed the abortion bill mifepristone to remain available. Here, Vance is trying to align with Trump, who — fearing political blowback — argues he merely wants abortion to be a state issue, despite his long alliance with the religious right. But Vance’s record implies his true agenda might be otherwise.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The second controversial area where Vance is sympatico with Project 2025 is centralizing presidential power over the executive branch. The project lays out various proposals to rein in what conservatives view as an out-of-control “deep state” bureaucracy — mainly, by firing far more career civil servants and installing far more political appointees throughout the government.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361455/jd-vance-trump-vice-president-rnc-speech">as I wrote last week,</a> has backed a maximalist version of this agenda. In 2021, Vance <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2022/04/inside-the-new-right-where-peter-thiel-is-placing-his-biggest-bets">said</a> that in Trump’s second term, Trump should “fire every single midlevel bureaucrat, every civil servant in the administrative state, replace them with our people.” The courts would try to stop this, Vance continued, and Trump should then “stand before the country like Andrew Jackson did, and say, ‘The chief justice has made his ruling. Now let him enforce it.’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So it’s no big surprise that Vance would write the foreword for a book by Project 2025’s architect. They fundamentally agree on how they see the world, and in much of what they want out of politics: a battle against the left for control of institutions, and expanded government power to stop abortions.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[So what does Joe Biden do now?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362997/biden-speech-drop-out-election-harris" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362997</id>
			<updated>2024-07-25T01:32:24Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T01:35:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[President Joe Biden addressed the nation from the Oval Office Wednesday night in the culmination of a pivotal few weeks that saw him relinquish the Democratic presidential nomination — an act that may one day be the defining moment of his political career.&#160; The speech was an attempt to exit political life gracefully, but it [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Biden standing beside a door." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Kevin Dietsch/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2162012636.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden addressed the nation from the Oval Office Wednesday night in the culmination of a pivotal few weeks that saw him relinquish the Democratic presidential nomination — an act that may one day be the defining moment of his political career.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The speech was an attempt to exit political life gracefully, but it also served as a reminder that only days after the president announced his unprecedented decision, the nation has already moved on. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democratic delegates quickly consolidated behind Biden’s chosen successor, Vice President Kamala Harris, and nearly 90 percent of Democratic voters surveyed said he made the right choice in a recent <a href="https://s3.documentcloud.org/documents/24989839/cnn-poll-harris-improves-on-bidens-performance-against-trump-in-early-look-at-new-matchup.pdf">CNN poll conducted by SSRS</a>. The media limelight has shifted to Harris, the new presumptive Democratic nominee, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/362619/kamala-harris-president-vision-political-ideology-2024-election">what her presidency would look like</a>. And Democrats have been able to refocus with <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/07/23/kamala-harris-donations-election/">renewed enthusiasm</a> on their task at hand, which is beating former President Donald Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s left Biden suddenly in the role of elder statesman. Under extraordinary circumstances just months before the 2024 election, he’s unexpectedly fulfilled his 2020 promise to become a “<a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/03/09/politics/joe-biden-bridge-new-generation-of-leaders/index.html">bridge</a>” to the next generation of leadership.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I decided the best way forward is to pass the torch to a new generation,” Biden said in his speech. “It is the best way to unite our nation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now that he’s done so, the question arises: What, if anything, is left for an outgoing president to do? </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden himself insists that his work is not done, and made it clear Wednesday night that he wants to tie up loose ends on policy. For instance, he promised to continue his efforts to protect democracy, at home and abroad. And he’s vowed to deliver a <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/07/22/biden-gaza-war-end-hostages-return-pledge">ceasefire in Gaza</a> before he leaves office.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But beyond Biden’s legacy — and the needs of the country — there’s still a campaign going on. So what role can he play in both?</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Does Harris give Democrats a better chance in 2024?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362043/kamala-harris-vice-running-mate-democratic-presidential-ticket" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Who could be Harris’s running mate?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Harris’s strengths and vulnerabilities as a presidential candidate</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What can Biden do on the campaign trail — and what should he do?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Strategists and pollsters agree: Biden can be useful to Harris on the campaign trail.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden clearly thinks so too. On Monday, he <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/07/22/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-at-a-campaign-event-wilmington-de-2/">said at a campaign event</a> in Delaware via teleconference, “I’m going to be on the road, and I’m not going anywhere.” He reiterated his support for Harris Wednesday night: “She’s tough; she’s capable. She’s been an incredible partner to me and a leader for our country.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Chuck Rocha, a former senior adviser for Sen. Bernie Sanders’s 2020 campaign, said that Biden has an opportunity to help Harris with union members and white working-class voters in Pennsylvania and Michigan — groups that <a href="https://www.cnn.com/election/2020/exit-polls/president/national-results">helped power his 2020 victory</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Evan Roth Smith, lead pollster for Blueprint, said that Biden also needs to speak to the voters who have been most loyal to him, even over the course of the last month, and tell them that it’s important that they not just turn out to vote for Harris, but knock on doors on her behalf.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fernand Amandi, a Democratic pollster, said that Biden can reassert the successes of his administration as a “political wind behind the sails of the Kamala campaign,” emphasizing her role in getting things done.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Harris also has the unusual opportunity to get a second chance at a first impression and to define herself outside of being Biden’s vice president. Voters don’t associate her as much with the issues on which they rated the administration poorly, like inflation and immigration, Roth Smith said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“So she has this important opportunity to distance herself a little bit,” he said. “It’s important to not squander that and not overly tie her to Biden.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden also risks generating further questions about whether or not he should continue as president until the end of his term if he participates in the kinds of campaign events in which he has proven more likely to commit verbal flubs, Amandi said. Though Amandi added that he believes Biden wouldn’t complete his term if the president and his doctors didn’t think him capable, Republicans have recently argued that Biden is not fit for office and <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cnd0ek9el6ro">should step down now</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There was a lot of pressure on Biden to get out there, particularly following the debate performance, and do the kinds of events that he was less comfortable doing,” Roth Smith said. “He doesn’t need to do those kinds of events anymore … We don’t necessarily need him all over the campaign trail.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s especially the case given that, soon, Harris will have another major surrogate on her team in the form of her vice presidential candidate. Once she chooses a running mate, “there will literally be three people who can help bring this thing home for November for the Democrats,” two of which — Harris and her vice presidential pick — can provide “a fresh-faced contrast to Donald Trump,” Rocha said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Essentially, the move for Biden experts say, is for him to help out Harris where he can, but not overexpose himself. Biden seemed to recognize Wednesday that it was time for him to take something of a step back. “I know there is a time and a place for long years of experience in public life,” he said. “There is also a time and a place for new voices, fresh voices. Yes, younger voices. That time and place is now.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What about Biden’s remaining time as president?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Strategists and pollsters told me that Biden should focus on being president for the remainder of his time in office, and as he noted in his speech, that’s what he intends to do.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“An important role for the president is to be this statesman, to show that Democrats can govern,” Roth Smith said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Being competent, while finding opportunities to remind voters of the accomplishments of his administration — from the Inflation Reduction Act to the bipartisan infrastructure law — is one of the best ways he can support Harris. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The Biden-Harris administration has a fantastic story to tell,” Amandi said. “It was a story that had been undermined by the legitimate concerns about whether or not the president could continue another four years.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kyle Kondik, managing editor of Sabato’s Crystal Ball at the University of Virginia Center for Politics, said that “Biden’s ability to do anything truly substantive is muted” given that he faces a divided Congress and election season is in full swing. But there are certain things that the president can do unilaterally. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For one, Americans are depending on his vast foreign policy experience at a tenuous moment for the Middle East and Europe. In his speech, he said he would seek to “bring peace and security to the Middle East” and keep rallying a coalition of nations to stop the Russian takeover of Ukraine, bolstering NATO and US allies in the Pacific. All that may not be achievable in five months, but he can work on making visible progress. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden may also look for domestic policy wins on issues that had dogged his candidacy, including immigration and inflation, which seems to be improving in time for the Federal Reserve to likely cut interest rates later this year. He can also highlight accomplishments on lesser-known, but still incredibly popular policies such as <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/issue-brief/faqs-about-the-inflation-reduction-acts-medicare-drug-price-negotiation-program/">negotiating decreases in drug prices</a> for Americans on Medicare. On Wednesday, he highlighted <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-16/biden-to-propose-supreme-court-reforms-including-term-limits?srnd=homepage-americas&amp;embedded-checkout=true">proposed Supreme Court reforms</a> and his <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/04/29/congress-is-killing-bidens-cancer-moonshot-00154718">cancer “moonshot”</a> among his priorities.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And as the administration makes progress, Biden needs to make sure he is “sharing the stage,” Roth Smith said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If there is going to be a great inflation report or a consumer confidence report, [Harris] needs to get credit for that,” he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That also serves the dual purpose of solidifying Biden’s legacy and increasing his approval rating, which Kondik said is also helpful to Harris. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think President Biden will leave office in January with significantly higher approval ratings because the one obstacle to judging him in the context of his success has now been removed, which is the concern that he would seek reelection at an age where his physical limitations wouldn’t allow him to continue,” Amandi said. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The stakes are still high for Democrats. Biden’s remaining time in office has the potential to lay the groundwork for a smooth transition to another Democratic administration that could protect the policies he set in motion. But as Biden himself has put it, before anyone — even Harris — can take over, he has to “<a href="https://ny1.com/nyc/all-boroughs/politics/2024/07/12/biden-vows-to-finish-the-job-at-press-conference">finish the job</a>.”&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Joshua Keating</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Has Netanyahu finally lost America?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/israel/362954/netanyahu-israel-congress-gaza-democrats-biden" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362954</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T22:59:39Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-24T22:45:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Congress" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was back in a very familiar building. Not only was he making his fourth address to a joint session of Congress — breaking Winston Churchill’s record for foreign leaders — he’s also been a presence in the building’s halls since serving as a diplomat in the early 1980s. Since [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Netanyahu holds his fist at the lectern. " data-caption="Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu addresses Congress on July 24, 2024. | Bryan Dozier/Anadolu via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-portal-copyright="Bryan Dozier/Anadolu via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2162700786.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu addresses Congress on July 24, 2024. | Bryan Dozier/Anadolu via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was back in a very familiar building. Not only was he making his fourth address to a joint session of Congress — breaking Winston Churchill’s record for foreign leaders — he’s also been a presence in the building’s halls since serving as a diplomat in the early 1980s. Since he made his first speech to Congress in 1996, Netanyahu has been almost as much a fixture of politics in America as in Israel. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Things felt different today. It’s not just that Netanyahu is a controversial figure, one who drew <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/24/netanyahu-congress-protests-security">thousands of protesters</a> onto the streets of Washington. That’s not new; Netanyahu’s 2011 speech to Congress was <a href="https://www.americanrhetoric.com/speeches/benjaminnetanyahujointsession2011.htm">interrupted by a pro-Palestinian protester</a> in the chamber. What is new is that he has become an increasingly marginalized one.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even a few weeks ago, when Netanyahu’s speech was announced, it had the makings of a marquee political event. Today, it was overshadowed by President Joe Biden’s highly anticipated Wednesday night speech to address his decision to drop out of the presidential election. Dozens of lawmakers — <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/07/24/half-house-senate-democrats-boycott-netanyahu">around half of Congress’s Democrats</a> — skipped Netanyahu’s speech altogether.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Soon-to-retire Maryland Sen. Ben Cardin’s presence behind Netanyahu on the rostrum attested to how much of a partisan figure Netanyahu has become. Vice President Kamala Harris, Senate President Pro Tempore Patty Murray, and Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer, one of whom would normally have been in that seat, all <a href="https://www.jpost.com/israel-news/article-811586">declined the role</a>. Netanyahu, who has been Israel’s prime minister for 17 of the last 30 years, has done more than anyone to make support for the country an increasingly partisan issue in the United States, in part through actions like his<em> </em>speech to Congress in 2015. That time, he was invited by congressional Republicans to lobby against the Iran nuclear deal then being negotiated by the Obama administration in what was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2015/02/26/politics/democrats-missing-netanyahu-whip-list/index.html">considered a remarkably partisan speech</a> for a foreign leader.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In today’s address, by contrast, Netanyahu made little news. It was a speech that gave little indication of a plan to end the war in Gaza, and likely undermined diplomatic efforts underway to do so. It was a notably defensive speech for Netanyahu, devoted more to refuting criticism of Israel than to charting a way forward out of the morass it has found itself in. Former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi <a href="https://x.com/SpeakerPelosi/status/1816208313572364356">called</a> it “by far the worst presentation of any foreign dignitary invited and honored with the privilege of addressing the Congress of the United States.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What Netanyahu said — and what he’s doing</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu recounted the horrors of Hamas’s October 7 attacks and vowed to the families of hostages currently being held in Gaza that he “would not rest until all their loved ones are home.” Not all of those families may be inclined to take him at his word. <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/international/4786324-hamas-hostages-netanyahu-speech/">Many of them</a> are calling for the prime minister to accept a ceasefire deal to secure the hostages’ release, but today Netanyahu vowed that “Israel will fight until we destroy Hamas’s military capabilities and its rule in Gaza and bring all our hostages home,” adding, “That’s what total victory means and we will settle for nothing less.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu also said, as he has in several previous remarks, that “[Israel] must retain overriding&nbsp;control [in Gaza] to ensure that Gaza never again poses a security threat to Israel” — a demand likely to be a nonstarter for any ceasefire deal.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite that, Netanyahu <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-says-deal-could-be-nearing-hostages-gaza-2024-07-23/">has said in recent days</a> that a ceasefire deal may be near, and the deal currently being negotiated is likely to be the focus of the prime minister’s meeting at the White House with Biden on Thursday. The Biden administration has tended not to respond directly to Netanyahu’s public statements on the deal, and this time was no exception. Asked if Netanyahu’s remarks made that deal less likely, a senior US administration official told reporters on Wednesday afternoon, “We were in the Situation Room doing some other stuff, so I have not seen the speech.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu didn’t indicate any specific asks beyond continued US military support. “Give us the tools faster and we’ll finish the job faster,” he said, riffing on a famous Churchill line from World War II. As he has in all three of his previous addresses, going back to the mid-1990s, Netanyahu kept the focus on Iran, which he mentioned before Hamas. He made the case that Israel’s fight against Iran-backed groups like Hamas and Hezbollah serves to “keep American boots off the ground while protecting our shared interests in the Middle East.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He pushed back against criticism of Israel over civilian casualties and preventing food from entering Gaza. He ripped into anti-Israel protesters in the United States, accusing them of being “useful idiots” for Iran, criticized university presidents, and compared “gays for Gaza” to “chickens for KFC.” This was likely the first speech on Mideast policy that included a shout-out to the “<a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/white-house-praises-unc-frat-bros-protected-american-flag-anti-israel-agitators-admirable">fraternity brothers of the University of North Carolina.</a>”&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to lose friends and influence</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu praised President Biden for his “half a century of friendship to Israel” and noted that the president describes himself as a “proud Zionist.” But that only served to highlight the shrinking number of Democratic politicians who would publicly describe themselves that way. Polls have consistently shown a <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/472070/democrats-sympathies-middle-east-shift-palestinians.aspx">deep partisan divide</a> opening up over sympathy toward Israel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He also thanked former president and current Republican nominee Donald Trump for actions in support of Israel during his presidency, including recognizing Israeli <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/presidential-actions/proclamation-recognizing-golan-heights-part-state-israel/">sovereignty over the Golan Heights</a> and moving the <a href="https://il.usembassy.gov/statement-by-president-trump-on-jerusalem/">US embassy to Jerusalem</a>. Netanyahu will be traveling to Florida to meet with Trump (<a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/netanyahu-requested-date-for-trump-meeting-falls-on-miami-based-son-yairs-birthday/">and possibly celebrate the birthday of his son</a>, who lives in Miami). Still, while Trump has not exactly turned on Israel, he has clearly soured somewhat on Netanyahu, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2021/12/10/trump-netanyahu-disloyalty-fuck-him">who he is still angry at</a> for congratulating Biden on his election victory in 2020. It doesn’t seem like a coincidence that Trump posted a <a href="https://x.com/BarakRavid/status/1815939398841847899">friendly letter</a> from Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas on the day he announced the Netanyahu meeting.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From a purely visual standpoint, Netanyahu may have gotten what he wanted today: rapturous standing ovations, even if mainly from Republicans. But more than <a href="https://www.jpost.com/israel-news/article-810113">70 percent of Israelis now say that Netanyahu</a> should resign. His own defense establishment is turning on his <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/show/israeli-defense-minister-publicly-criticizes-netanyahus-gaza-strategy#:~:text=Israel's%20defense%20minister%20accused%20Netanyahu%20of%20indecision%20and%20leading%20Israel,he's%20here%20with%20us%20now.">handling of the war</a> and he’s under fire over issues ranging from his long-running legal troubles to the controversial question of whether the ultra-Orthodox should serve in the country’s military.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the past, Washington has served as a sort of relief valve for Netanyahu, a place he could count on strong support, even when his political position looked rocky at home. In that first speech back in 1996, after receiving a five-minute standing ovation from Congress, he <a href="https://www.americanrhetoric.com/speeches/benjaminnetanyahujointsession1996.htm">quipped</a>, “If I could only get the Knesset [Israel’s parliament] to vote like this.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, though, “the magic is gone,” Nimrod Novik, a former senior Israeli foreign policy official who is now an analyst at the Israel Policy Forum, told Vox. “The fellow that mastered verbal acrobatics to the point that different audiences could hear different messages in the same speech —&nbsp;that’s over. Those who were in awe of his verbal skills now take it with a grain of salt.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In more than 40 years of coming to Washington, Netanyahu has surely grown used to being a controversial figure. He may have to get used to being an irrelevant one.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, 7 pm ET: </strong>An earlier version of this story referred to Netanyahu as a former ambassador to the US. He was a deputy chief of mission.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Could a short campaign be exactly what Kamala Harris needs?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362890/harris-biden-democrats-election-europe-france-uk-president-parliament-parties-republican" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362890</id>
			<updated>2024-07-25T00:24:36Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-24T22:25:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Abortion" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Campaign Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Elon Musk" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="European Union" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Influence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Social Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris has 103 days to convince the American public to vote for her for president. It’s not a lot of time — especially considering former President Donald Trump launched his campaign in November 2022 — but it’s a timeline not too different from that of other countries, many of which have short [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris, in a navy jacket and white blouse, holds both hands in front of her, gesturing while she speaks from a podium, with an array of young people standing behind her." data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris speaks during an NCAA championship teams celebration on the South Lawn of the White House on July 22. | Andrew Harnik/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Harnik/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2162426041.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris speaks during an NCAA championship teams celebration on the South Lawn of the White House on July 22. | Andrew Harnik/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris has 103 days to convince the American public to vote for her for president. It’s not a lot of time — especially considering former <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-launch-new-white-house-bid-while-his-party-licks-its-wounds-2022-11-15/">President Donald Trump launched his campaign in November 2022</a> — but it’s a timeline not too different from that of other countries, many of which have short campaign cycles.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The US has the longest campaign cycle of any of its peer countries partly because we operate on a presidential system. We have fixed terms of leadership, and we know there will be elections every four years, so it’s easy to start early (especially given all <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2024/01/31/primary-elections-frontloading-voters-00138616">the procedural hurdles to running for president</a>).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That’s different from most other democracies, which are parliamentary systems and which have irregularly scheduled elections where you can have — as in Israel —&nbsp; five elections in a very brief period of time,” <a href="https://truman.missouri.edu/people/squire">Peverill Squire</a>, professor of political science at the University of Missouri, told Vox. “Or you can call a snap election, as happened in France or the election <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/358985/uk-labour-keir-starmer-tories-migration-politics-elections-july-4-rishi-sunak-boris-johnson">in Great Britain</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So how do other countries with shorter campaign periods manage their leadership elections — and can that tell us anything about what the next three months could look like for Harris’s campaign?</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The US system has unique factors that make comparison difficult</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Comparing US presidential campaigns to those in other countries —&nbsp;even our allies and peers —&nbsp;is kind of like comparing apples and oranges for many reasons.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A parliamentary system’s uneven cycles force campaign apparatuses — from how debates are run to deadlines for printing ballots — to be a lot more flexible than they are in the US. Plus, many of these systems are highly centralized, rather than federalized like in the US. In parliamentary systems, candidates run on relatively narrow party manifestos; there’s less individual variance between candidates of the same party. That means in a case like Harris’s, where one candidate is substituted for another late in the race, voters don’t really have to figure out how the new candidate differs from the old.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One major challenge Democrats may face is the role that money plays in the US election system. The 2010 Supreme Court decision in<em> </em><a href="https://www.oyez.org/cases/2008/08-205"><em>Citizens United vs. Federal Election Commission</em></a><em> </em>essentially qualified political donations as free speech. It determined that corporations have the rights of individuals when it comes to campaign donations and <a href="https://www.fec.gov/help-candidates-and-committees/candidate-taking-receipts/contribution-limits/">can in some cases donate unlimited amounts</a>. That’s caused astronomical increases in campaign fundraising, which alters the course of American politics in critical ways that just don’t apply in European countries like France.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362043/kamala-harris-vice-running-mate-democratic-presidential-ticket">Who could be Harrris’s running mate?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc">Does Harris give Democrats a better chance in 2024?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee">Harris’s strengths and vulnerabilities as a presidential candidate</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris has raised more than <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/kamala-harris-fundraising-100-million-biden-drops-out/">$100 million since gaining President Joe Biden’s endorsement</a> on Sunday, but will need to keep the money flowing; Trump’s <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/kamala-harris-fundraising-100-million-biden-drops-out/">second-quarter haul</a> was more than $60 million more than Biden’s. Campaigns run through money quickly as they fund ad buys and ground operations, and their outside partners do too. In an era of unlimited political spending, there’s a race to have the largest war chest — a competition that just isn’t an issue in European politics, <a href="https://tec.fsi.stanford.edu/people/patrick-chamorel">Patrick Chamorel</a>, senior resident scholar at the Stanford Center in Washington, told Vox.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It&#8217;s parties that receive the money” in European elections, “and this money is public money.” Plus, Chamorel said, “in Europe, you have spending limits, which would in the US be considered an encroachment on freedom of expression.” There’s always a ceiling on how much the parties can spend in European elections —&nbsp;and there are very strict limits on corporate donations, which is meant to maintain the independence of the candidates and to ensure a pluralistic political system by keeping a relatively even playing field.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And in most European countries, “you don&#8217;t have money spent on advertisement in the media,” Chamorel said. Media organizations are required to give equal airtime to official candidates — “even the small candidates from the tiny parties, they have equal time.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s not the case in the US. And in the absence of spending caps or media rules, Democrats — who have emphasized getting the <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/08/04/biden-dems-grassroots-donations-00109766">support of small donors in recent years</a> — will need to continue to find ways to keep Harris’s fundraising numbers high, particularly as they work to ward off the <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361087/trump-silicon-valley-fundraising-musk-andreessen-horowitz">large individual donors</a> who have promised sizable donations to outside groups allied with Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One other key difference Democrats will have to contend with is the idea that voters need to be introduced to candidates. Harris, though vice president for the last four years, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/362619/kamala-harris-president-vision-political-ideology-2024-election">remains something of a blank slate</a>, leading to a lot of <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/362782/kamala-harris-gaza-israel-palestine-biden-netanyahu">speculation about what her policy positions are</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She has just over three months for voters to get to know her, but her European counterparts don’t face the same struggle in their short election cycles. Party leaders are usually a known quantity already, having worked their way up through leadership over many years after holding different positions in government. Plus Europeans tend to pay much more attention to politics than Americans, Chamorel said —&nbsp;so voters are likely to know candidates and what their parties actually stand for in a way American voters don’t.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>But there is a way that circumstances could play to Democrats’ advantage</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is one way Harris could really benefit from the European-style campaign cycle she faces.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Normally, America’s campaign cycles are so long that candidates run the risk of voters becoming disengaged by the time Election Day rolls around. That certainly appeared to be the case this cycle, with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/americans-dismayed-by-biden-trump-2024-rematch-reutersipsos-poll-finds-2024-01-25/">voters regularly telling pollsters</a> they wished they had <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/06/23/double-haters-biden-trump-deciders/">choices other than Trump and Biden</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“One of the problems of having candidates running for years in advance of an election is the public can become tired of them and their message,” Squire said. “[Harris will] reap the benefits of having an organization in place; she can just take over the Biden-Harris organization,” while still being relatively fresh to voters. “She can run as not really the incumbent, and as somebody who is known a little bit, but not that well by many Americans.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris may, to an extent, have the best of both worlds: She already has the benefit of being in national leadership positions. She has the Democratic machinery behind her, including Biden and former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi, and she will have <a href="https://www.vox.com/joe-biden/361991/361991biden-campaign-funds-after-drops-out">access to Biden’s fundraising dollars</a>. But voters haven’t been seeing her campaigning everywhere for months now, which means she’ll <em>seem </em>new.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a two-party system in which the Democrats have a broad mix of ideologies —&nbsp;think of centrist Democrats like Biden versus more left-wing politicians like Sen. Bernie Sanders (who is an independent, but is broadly part of the Democratic coalition) — Harris will need to clarify and explain her positions. She’ll have to maintain a balance of staying close enough to Biden’s policies while offering the change that voters have expressed they want, which could prove to be a challenging needle to thread in a short period of time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, the shorter campaign cycle may mean less opportunity for errors like the debate performance that ultimately caused Biden to step down. And there will be less time for Trump and the Republican Party to create damaging narratives about Harris that overshadow her policy and performance —&nbsp;provided she creates a narrative about herself first.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris has clinched the support of all the major Democratic players —&nbsp;now she’ll have to concentrate on what’s most important, which is broadcasting her policy and building a coalition of voters who think she can be the next president.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Who could be Kamala Harris’s VP? The potential list, briefly explained.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362043/kamala-harris-vice-running-mate-democratic-presidential-ticket" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362043</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T22:57:12Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-24T19:40:21Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following President Joe Biden’s exit from the 2024 presidential race, and his endorsement of Vice President Kamala Harris as his choice for the Democratic nominee, one of the next big questions that’s emerged is who could potentially be her running mate. Though Harris is not the nominee yet, Biden’s backing gives her a significant boost [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Sen. Mark Kelly, a concerned look on his face, is surrounded by a crowd of reporters with microphones. " data-caption="Sen. Mark Kelly of Arizona is among the rumored contenders for Harris’s running mate. | Tom Williams/CQ Roll Call, Inc. via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Tom Williams/CQ Roll Call, Inc. via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2160744008_a0c39e.webp?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Sen. Mark Kelly of Arizona is among the rumored contenders for Harris’s running mate. | Tom Williams/CQ Roll Call, Inc. via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">Following President Joe Biden’s exit from the 2024 presidential race</a>, and his endorsement of <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee">Vice President Kamala Harris</a> as his choice for the Democratic nominee, one of the next big questions that’s emerged is who could potentially be her running mate. Though Harris is not the nominee yet, Biden’s backing gives her a significant boost ahead of <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024">other potential contenders</a>, fueling speculation about who else could join the ticket.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, vice presidents have been selected to complement the main candidate. Biden, for instance, named Harris because she would bring youth, diversity, and legal experience. And former President Donald Trump chose Vice President Mike Pence because he was a traditional conservative and offered legislative expertise that he didn’t have.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc">Does Harris give Democrats a better chance in 2024?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee">Harris’s strengths and vulnerabilities as a presidential candidate</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What might Harris look for? Based on that history, there are a few guesses: Her pick could be someone from a purple or red state, who offers geographic diversity given her roots in California. And — to assuage voters who still hold sexist or racist attitudes, as President Barack Obama did with Biden in 2008 — it might be a white man.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Below is a rundown of some of the possible candidates who might be considered — and what they’d bring to the ticket.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2159037882_26f6dd.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. Roy Cooper, in a navy suit, speaks from a podium to a large crowd holding Biden-Harris campaign signs." title="Gov. Roy Cooper, in a navy suit, speaks from a podium to a large crowd holding Biden-Harris campaign signs." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="North Carolina Gov. Roy Cooper speaks before President Joe Biden at a post-debate campaign rally on June 28, in Raleigh, North Carolina. | Allison Joyce/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Allison Joyce/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Roy Cooper</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Cooper, 67, is the governor of North Carolina, a battleground state that Trump won narrowly in 2020 and 2016 that offers <a href="https://www.ncsbe.gov/about-elections/electoral-college">16 electoral votes</a> (of the 270 needed to win). He’s known for winning repeatedly statewide even as other Democratic candidates have struggled to do the same for roles like the Senate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor, he’s also vetoed Republican bills on abortion and guns, and has strong approval <a href="https://abc11.com/post/2024-elections-could-governor-roy-cooper-replace-president/15011995/">ratings overall</a>. Prior to becoming governor, he served as the state’s attorney general and in the state legislature.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Cooper could help improve Democrats’ chances in a battleground state, though it will still likely be an uphill battle given past contests in North Carolina. He’s also been pretty popular in his role, and has secured backing from some moderates and Republicans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He previously collaborated with Harris while they each served as their states’ AG, meaning they have experience working alongside one another. And more recently, Harris and Cooper <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bsVNTI1BqZo">have campaigned together</a> in the wake of <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357788/biden-trump-debate-winners-losers">Biden’s disastrous June debate</a>, during which the governor cautioned against the return of “Donald Trump’s America.”</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2150001600_c3763f.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.736744421098,100,78.526511157804" alt="Gov. Josh Shapiro, in glasses and a navy suit jacket, waves at reporters and a crowd." title="Gov. Josh Shapiro, in glasses and a navy suit jacket, waves at reporters and a crowd." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Pennsylvania Gov. Josh Shapiro arrives to deliver remarks at a building trades union conference on April 24, in Washington, DC. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Josh Shapiro</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Shapiro, 51, is the governor of Pennsylvania, another likely battleground state (with <a href="https://www.archives.gov/electoral-college/allocation">19 Electoral College votes</a>), which Biden won in 2020 and which former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton lost in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He was elected in 2022, the same year that freshman Sen. John Fetterman (D-PA) was elected to the Senate. Shapiro ran far ahead of Fetterman, <a href="https://www.politico.com/2022-election/results/pennsylvania/">winning 57 percent of the vote, to Fetterman’s 51 percent</a>. Shapiro has established himself as a moderate who helped negotiate bipartisan deals when he was in the state legislature, and is also known for his work as attorney general, when he secured settlements for victims of sexual abuse by the Catholic Diocese. He’s also been a vocal supporter of Israel amid the country’s devastating military offensive in Gaza, following Hamas’ brutal October 7 attack.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him?</strong> Like Cooper, he’s the popular Democratic governor of a swing state and could help the party improve their chances there. He’s also seen as more of a centrist who could appeal to moderate voters and independents, though his staunch backing of Israel could turn away progressive Democrats.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161807297_5538e2.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. Andy Beshear, in a light blue shirt and wearing a lapel mic, speaks to reporters while standing outdoors." title="Gov. Andy Beshear, in a light blue shirt and wearing a lapel mic, speaks to reporters while standing outdoors." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Kentucky Gov. Andy Beshear speaks to reporters following a ribbon-cutting ceremony in Hazel, Kentucky, in October 2023. | Lexington Herald-Leader/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Lexington Herald-Leader/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Andy Beshear</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Beshear, 46, is the governor of Kentucky and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/11/7/23950792/election-day-2023-kentucky-governors-race-results-democrats-republicans">has won twice in a red state that previously overwhelmingly voted for Trump</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor, he’s been praised for his handling of the Covid-19 pandemic as well as multiple crises in the state, including <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/4/11/23679512/louisville-kentucky-shooting-workplace">a mass shooting at a bank</a> and severe flooding. Prior to this role, he also served as Kentucky’s attorney general.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Beshear is the rare Democrat who has been able to win multiple times in a red state and could offer additional appeal to some swing voters. In addition to the support he’s received for his leadership during various crises, he’s also touted infrastructure and private sector investment in the state during his tenure.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unlike other possibilities, though, he probably wouldn’t increase Harris’s chances of winning his home state, which is solidly GOP.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2160763179.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. J.B. Pritzer, in a dark suit and pink striped tie, speaks into a microphone at a podium, with a screen lighting him from the back." title="Gov. J.B. Pritzer, in a dark suit and pink striped tie, speaks into a microphone at a podium, with a screen lighting him from the back." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Illinois Gov. J.B. Pritzker speaks during to a Chicago-area chamber of commerce meeting on June 4, 2024, in Chicago. | Eileen T. Meslar/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Eileen T. Meslar/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. J.B. Pritzker</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>J.B. Pritzker, 59, is the governor of Illinois, a Democratic state that Biden and Clinton both won in 2020 and 2016. Before becoming governor, he was a businessman and philanthropist, and is a scion of the family behind Hyatt hotels, who’ve also been consistent and influential Democratic donors.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor, Pritzker has established a modest national profile, including remarks he’s given attacking Trump and calls he’s made for more federal resources to address immigration in Illinois.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Pritzker has already built some name recognition as a fixture on cable news, and has proven to be a vocal Trump antagonist. Pritzker’s personal wealth could also potentially be a boon to the campaign, though his own state is not a battleground that would expand the Democratic map.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2160744008_a0c39e.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Sen. Mark Kelly, in a navy suit and blue-striped tie, wears a serious expression while speaking to a gaggle of reporters with microphones and smartphones. " title="Sen. Mark Kelly, in a navy suit and blue-striped tie, wears a serious expression while speaking to a gaggle of reporters with microphones and smartphones. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Sen. Mark Kelly (D-AZ) is questioned about the candidacy of President Joe Biden after a Senate luncheon on July 9. | Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Sen. Mark Kelly</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Kelly is the junior senator of Arizona — a swing state with <a href="https://www.archives.gov/electoral-college/allocation">11 Electoral College votes</a> — <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/11/5/21537670/senate-2020-results-arizona-mark-kelly-winner">who was elected in 2020</a> by framing himself as a candidate willing to work across the aisle. Previously, Biden won Arizona in 2020, while Clinton lost the state in 2016. Kelly is also known for his career as an astronaut alongside his twin brother Scott Kelly, and as the husband of gun control advocate and former US Rep. Gabby Giffords.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Kelly has a higher profile than some of the other names on this list, and is respected both for his scientific expertise and contributions as an astronaut in addition to his time in the Senate. He’s been a prominent gun control advocate alongside Giffords and made pushing these policies a priority.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given his efforts to appeal to both Republicans and independents in Arizona, he’d be another option who could help with trying to reach those voters. Arizona also continues to be an important battleground this time around, including in its <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/ratings/senate-race-ratings">Senate race</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1394802139.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Pete Buttigieg, in a navy suit and white shirt, is shown from the side, while pinning an index card onto a wall full of similar cards with handwritten notes. " title="Pete Buttigieg, in a navy suit and white shirt, is shown from the side, while pinning an index card onto a wall full of similar cards with handwritten notes. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg attends a White House correspondents’ brunch on April 30, 2022, in Washington, DC. | Paul Morigi/Getty Images for White House Correspondents Insider" data-portal-copyright="Paul Morigi/Getty Images for White House Correspondents Insider" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Secretary Pete Buttigieg</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he?</strong> Buttigieg, 42, is the secretary of transportation who rose to prominence as a former 2020 presidential candidate. He’s staked out more moderate positions and was previously mayor of South Bend, Indiana.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He’s become known for his media savvy and strong television appearances as an advocate for the Biden-Harris administration. He’s also had to respond to crises including the train accident and <a href="https://www.vox.com/science/2023/2/18/23603471/east-palestine-ohio-derailment-water-contamination-health">chemical spill in East Palestine</a>, Ohio, as well as the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024/1/8/24030677/boeing-alaska-airlines-plane-737-max-door-plug">Alaska Airlines mishap</a> when a door plug dropped out of a plane.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Buttigieg has been a strong spokesperson for the Biden-Harris White House and is well-established among the Democratic electorate. He’s among the youngest of possible choices, would contribute more representation from the Midwest,<strong> </strong>and could appeal to centrist voters. He’d also become the first openly LGBTQ person to be on a presidential ticket.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161013764_474f9c.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752616398754,100,78.494767202492" alt="Gov. Gavin Newsom, in a gray striped jacket and blue shirt, squints into the sun as he speaks outdoors." title="Gov. Gavin Newsom, in a gray striped jacket and blue shirt, squints into the sun as he speaks outdoors." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="California Gov. Gavin Newsom speaks during a press conference in Oakland, California, on July 11. | Stephen Lam/San Francisco Chronicle/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Lam/San Francisco Chronicle/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Gavin Newsom</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Newsom, 56, is the governor of California, and a longstanding political personality. He’s been a vocal advocate for more progressive policies, and for Democrats to more directly confront Republicans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Prior to being governor, he was also lieutenant governor and mayor of San Francisco.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Newsom has already made clear that he wants to be a fighter for Democrats and has supporters who are interested in his approach. He’s also used opportunities like a debate against Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis to make some splashy points for the party and to get more attention, and could do the same for a possible campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor of California, however, he wouldn’t bring additional geographic diversity to the ticket, and he also wouldn’t help with delivering a swing state, as his own is solidly Democratic. In addition, Newsom and Harris are both Californians, so they’d also likely have to contend with issues raised by the 12th Amendment of the Constitution, which prohibits two running mates from the same state.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1953489582.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,9.6422338568935,100,80.715532286213" alt="Walz — white haired, balding, and clean shaven — raises a hand as he speaks at a podium, clad in a navy suit and white dress shirt." title="Walz — white haired, balding, and clean shaven — raises a hand as he speaks at a podium, clad in a navy suit and white dress shirt." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz speaks about funding for the I-535 Blatnik Bridge before a visit by US President Joe Biden at Earth Rider Brewery on January 25, 2024 in Superior, Wisconsin. | Stephen Maturen/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Maturen/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Gov. Tim Walz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he?</strong> Walz, 60, is in his second term as governor of Minnesota. A <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/national/2024/07/who-is-minnesota-governor-tim-walz-one-of-the-top-contenders-for-vice-president/#:~:text=Tim%20Walz%20was%20a%20high,one%20of%20the%20student's%20wallets.">former high school teacher</a>, he’s been in politics for decades, having started as a member of Congress in 2007. He received national attention for leading his party through a <a href="https://apnews.com/article/minnesota-taxes-abortion-health-racial-justice-transportation-marijuana-c3cc7db0cd92c022817ef3ae41097c73">2023 legislative session</a> that saw Democrats in the state achieve a litany of long-held ambitions, including on police reform, boosting education funding, marijuana legalization, abortion protections, child tax credits, and more.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him?</strong> Walz is the <a href="https://www.kaaltv.com/news/approval-rates-for-minnesota-leaders/#">well-liked leader</a> of a <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/ratings/presidential-race-ratings">purplish state</a> with a record of advancing Democratic priorities through his state legislature and with <a href="https://minnesotareformer.com/2023/12/15/public-sector-unions-spend-more-on-politics-in-minnesota-than-in-nearly-any-other-state/">strong ties to organized labor</a>. A Midwesterner, Walz could prove to be a useful surrogate for <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-campaign-midwest-after-clinching-democratic-nomination-2024-03-13/">shoring up support</a> in his own state, as well as ones like Michigan and Wisconsin. And like many of the other potential vice president picks on this list, he’s already proved to be a <a href="https://www.axios.com/local/twin-cities/2024/07/23/tim-walz-vice-president-kamala-harris-vet-minnesota">strong Harris surrogate</a> on television news.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Out of the running</h2>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1247112367.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. Gretchen Whitmer, in a snakeskin-patterned blouse, speaks into a set of microphones, smillng, with the state seal of Michigan behind her." title="Gov. Gretchen Whitmer, in a snakeskin-patterned blouse, speaks into a set of microphones, smillng, with the state seal of Michigan behind her." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Michigan Gov. Gretchen Whitmer speaks at a press conference about an electric-vehicle battery plant in February 2023 in Romulus, Michigan. | Bill Pugliano/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Bill Pugliano/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Gretchen Whitmer</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is she? </strong>Whitmer, 52, is the governor of Michigan, a key swing state with <a href="https://www.archives.gov/electoral-college/allocation">15 Electoral College votes</a> that Biden won in 2020 and that Clinton lost in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She’s been a popular leader in this role, and was initially known for how much she emphasized infrastructure and “fixing the damn roads.” Since then she’s been an outspoken advocate for abortion rights and for gender equity, speaking openly about how she was sexually assaulted in college. Prior to being governor, Whitmer was a member of the state legislature and the first woman to become the Democratic leader of the state Senate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What was the case for her? </strong>She’s among the members of the list who have strong and positive national recognition, and who could help raise Democrats’ chances in a pivotal swing state. Whitmer has also focused on issues including infrastructure and health care, which could broaden Democrats’ appeal to moderate voters. And if Harris and Whitmer were on the same ticket, they would form a groundbreaking all-woman ticket — something that neither major party has run before.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Why she won&#8217;t be the new VP:</strong> Less than 24 hours after Biden endorsed Harris, Whitmer emphatically told reporters that she has no desire to be vice president. “I’m not planning to go anywhere,” <a href="https://x.com/kenvogel/status/1815417822056755621">she said, adding</a>, “I am not leaving Michigan; I&#8217;m proud to be the governor of Michigan.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, July 24, 2024, 3:30 pm ET:</em></strong> <em>This piece was originally published on July 21 and has been updated multiple times, most recently to include Gov. Whitmer’s remarks and the consideration of Gov. Tim Walz. </em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, July 21, 2024, 11:59 pm ET: </strong>A previous version of this story misstated Gabby Giffords’s position on guns. She is a gun control advocate.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What Kamala Harris really thinks about Israel and Gaza]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/362782/kamala-harris-gaza-israel-palestine-biden-netanyahu" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362782</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T23:01:13Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-24T17:45:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[President Joe Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s war in Gaza created a rift between moderates and progressives in his party. Now that he has stepped aside in the 2024 presidential race, the question is whether Vice President Kamala Harris, the presumptive Democratic nominee, would chart a different path forward as president. One early signal that [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris speaking from behind a lectern." data-caption="Then-Sen. Kamala Harris addressing the 2017 American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC) Policy Conference in Washington, DC. | Michael Brochstein/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Michael Brochstein/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-878131632.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Then-Sen. Kamala Harris addressing the 2017 American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC) Policy Conference in Washington, DC. | Michael Brochstein/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s war in Gaza created a rift between moderates and progressives in his party. Now that he has stepped aside in the 2024 presidential race, the question is whether Vice President Kamala Harris, the presumptive Democratic nominee, would chart a different path forward as president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One early signal that she might: Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is scheduled to address Congress on Wednesday, and Harris will not preside in her role as vice president due to a previously scheduled event she is attending in Indianapolis. A slew of congressional Democrats (not just progressives) have decided not to attend in <a href="https://rollcall.com/2024/07/23/netanyahu-address-creates-a-dilemma-for-democrats/">protest of Netanyahu’s strategy in Gaza</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris will meet with Netanyahu one-on-one on Wednesday, and the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/harriss-support-for-gaza-cease-fire-hints-at-foreign-policy-shift-bbe8dc2a">Wall Street Journal reported</a> that she is expected to tell him “it is time for the war to end in a way where Israel is secure, all hostages are released, the suffering of Palestinian civilians in Gaza ends, and the Palestinian people can enjoy their right to dignity, freedom, and self-determination.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Only days into her campaign, Harris has yet to articulate her Gaza policy, but the fact that she is not attending Netanyahu’s speech and privately communicating the urgency of a ceasefire signals that she might not follow Biden’s lead in giving the Israeli leader a “<a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/world/biden-netanyahu-bear-hug-disaster/">bear hug</a>.” Biden literally embraced Netanyahu on the tarmac when the president landed in Tel Aviv in November as a symbolic gesture of unequivocal support for Israel, and has since kept the prime minister close metaphorically, offering military and financial support.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Harris does change course, even slightly, that could alter the US-Israel relationship, but could also have important electoral consequences as well.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Does Harris give Democrats a better chance in 2024?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362043/kamala-harris-vice-running-mate-democratic-presidential-ticket" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Who could be Harris’s running mate?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Harris’s strengths and vulnerabilities as a presidential candidate</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What does Kamala Harris think about Israel and the war in Gaza?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris has longstanding ties to the American Jewish community and Israeli interest groups.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her husband, second gentleman Doug Emhoff, is Jewish and has been at the forefront of the Biden administration’s <a href="https://jewishinsider.com/2024/01/world-economic-forum-davos-antisemitism-herzog-greenblatt-emhoff-rosen/">initiative against antisemitism</a> since Hamas’s October 7 attack on Israel. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She has a good working relationship with Israeli President Isaac Herzog, who <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/kamala-harris-has-long-embraced-jewish-ties-but-critics-take-issue-with-gaza-stance/">shares a passion for climate issues</a>. She has also been on every one of the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/harriss-support-for-gaza-cease-fire-hints-at-foreign-policy-shift-bbe8dc2a">more than 20 phone calls</a> that Biden has had with Netanyahu throughout the war.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In her presidential bid, she has <a href="https://jewishinsider.com/2024/07/kamala-harris-jewish-democrats-vice-president-presidential-race/">won the backing</a> of major Jewish interest groups, including Democratic Majority for Israel, J Street, and the Jewish Democratic Council of America. She also has connections to the <a href="https://x.com/VP/status/1110301531306409986">American Israel Public Affairs Committee</a> (AIPAC) and gave a speech at the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=McK8bPR8pzU">organization’s annual conference in 2017</a> soon after she was elected to the US Senate, saying that one of her first acts in office was to introduce a resolution opposing a United Nations Security Council resolution condemning Israel. At the time, she said, “I believe the bonds between the United States and Israel are unbreakable.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Concerning the war in Gaza, Harris has repeatedly upheld Israel’s “<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">right to defend itself</a>” against Hamas and emphasized that the threat posed by Hamas to Israel must be “<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">eliminated</a>.” This suggests she’s largely in agreement with Biden’s posture. Harris has, however, taken a sharper tone than Biden concerning Israel’s treatment of civilians in Gaza.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a high-profile <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">speech in March</a>, she became the first person in the Biden administration to call for an immediate ceasefire, albeit only a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">temporary</a> one. She also said that the Israeli government must do more to increase the flow of aid to Gaza, “no excuses,” and called the situation in Gaza a “humanitarian catastrophe.” The version of the speech that was ultimately delivered had reportedly <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/white-house/kamala-harris-gaza-speech-watered-down-cease-fire-rcna141750">been softened</a> from its original draft, which more directly criticized Israel for its obstruction of aid trucks into Gaza.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She also has expressed empathy for <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024/4/24/24138333/columbia-student-protests-gaza-nyu-divest-faculty">student protesters on college campuses</a> who are horrified by the death and destruction in Gaza and have attempted to pressure their schools into cutting ties with Israel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They are showing exactly what the human emotion should be, as a response to Gaza,” Harris <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/politics/kamala-harris-interview-profile-excerpt/">told the Nation</a>. “There are things some of the protesters are saying that I absolutely reject, so I don’t mean to wholesale endorse their points. But we have to navigate it. I understand the emotion behind it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If she becomes president, the Wall Street Journal reported that Harris is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/harriss-support-for-gaza-cease-fire-hints-at-foreign-policy-shift-bbe8dc2a">expected to replace</a> some of the chief architects of the Biden administration’s strategy in Gaza, including national security adviser Jake Sullivan, Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin. It’s to be expected that a new president would want their own team in place, but any changes would open up possibilities for taking a different tack.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s national security adviser, Philip Gordon, has emphasized diplomatic rather than military solutions in foreign policy and written extensively about the difficulties of regime change in the Middle East. That background may prove relevant as Israel seeks to root out Hamas and install a new government in Gaza.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this suggests that Harris might be somewhat to Biden’s left on Gaza — but by how much is an open question and one that she will have to clarify.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“She does have an opportunity. She’s using the right language in some instances. But we need a clearer explanation from her on where she stands,” said Abed Ayoub, national legal and policy director of the American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And — as with Joe Biden’s campaign promises to make Saudi Arabia a pariah state — there’s always a chance that what Harris does eventually say while campaigning may change once she’s in office.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Biden’s Gaza policy has been divisive&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Politically, Harris faces the quandary of determining if — and by how much — she should distance herself from Biden’s record on Gaza, which has fractured the Democratic base.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden at one point <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/05/08/congress/progressives-cheer-israel-weapon-pause-gop-fume-biden-00156857">paused shipments of large munitions</a> to Israel over concerns about how they would be potentially used against civilians in Gaza but has otherwise continued to offer material support for the war, even after Israeli operations in Gaza’s southernmost city of Rafah <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/07/middleeast/destruction-inside-rafa-gaza-israel-intl/index.html">wreaked widespread destruction</a>. Over <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-israeli-strikes-southern-gaza-palestinian-death-toll-112159613">39,000 Palestinians</a> have already died in the course of the conflict, according to the Gaza Health Ministry.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In May, Biden called for a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/05/31/politics/biden-middle-east-remarks/index.html">deal to end the war</a> and return the remaining Israeli hostages in Gaza, while continuing to advocate for a two-state solution to the decades-long Israeli-Palestinian conflict. But the Israeli parliament has since voted to <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/israels-knesset-votes-overwhelmingly-palestinian-statehood-netanyahu-p-rcna162466">reject a two-state solution</a> and ceasefire talks are still ongoing two months later.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Monday, Biden promised he would <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/07/22/biden-gaza-war-end-hostages-return-pledge">deliver a ceasefire</a> deal before he leaves office. He did not elaborate on how he plans to overcome the roadblocks that have stalled negotiations thus far.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Progressives have for months been calling on Biden to halt weapons shipments to Gaza and put more pressure on Israel to end the war. Over 650,000 Democrats <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/06/05/biden-uncommitted-primary-vote-00161700">voted “uncommitted”</a> in the primary to protest Biden’s policies, and the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/video/opinion/100000009565908/biden-voters-dearborn-michigan.html">scale of the opposition to Biden in the Midwest</a> appeared as though it could have tipped the election in Trump’s favor in swing states including Michigan and Wisconsin. Depending on how Harris positions herself, she could win back some of those voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think there is excitement that [Biden] is not at the top of the ticket,” said Layla Elabed, a Palestinian American organizer in Michigan who helped lead the uncommitted movement, and the sister of Rep. Rashida Tlaib (D-MI). “But we are also right now watching and listening to what Harris is going to do next.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Overall, however, Democrats and Republicans <a href="https://www.newsnationnow.com/world/war-in-israel/most-americans-support-israel-over-hamas-poll/">remain largely supportive</a> of Israel’s campaign. Since Israel’s establishment in 1948, the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/10/11/politics/presidents-israel-cnn/index.html">US has maintained a special relationship with the country</a>. It has been the largest cumulative recipient of American foreign aid since its founding, <a href="https://www.cfr.org/article/us-aid-israel-four-charts">totaling about $310 billion</a> (adjusted for inflation) in total economic and military assistance.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For these reasons, it’s unlikely that Harris will deviate substantially from Biden on Israel — and if there is any change in her policy, it would be only slight. The question will be whether any changes can win back voters that the president has alienated without losing the voters who embraced his stance.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This leaves Harris with a difficult political tightrope to walk. But unlike Biden, she isn’t weighed down with the direct responsibility for all that has happened so far.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The worst internet outage still hasn’t happened yet]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/362735/the-worst-internet-outage-still-hasnt-happened-yet" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362735</id>
			<updated>2024-07-25T02:25:48Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-24T17:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Tech policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world is still dealing with the fallout from the CrowdStrike screwup that took millions of computers offline last week. Some IT workers have had to fix each computer manually, walking from machine to machine with a USB stick, and some remote workers say they’re locked out of their computers with no fix in sight. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Billboards in Times Square went dark on July 19, after a Crowdstrike bug brought down millions of computers worldwide." data-caption="Billboards in Times Square went dark on July 19, after a bad Crowdstrike update crashed millions of computers worldwide. | Michael Nagle/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Michael Nagle/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2162047236.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Billboards in Times Square went dark on July 19, after a bad Crowdstrike update crashed millions of computers worldwide. | Michael Nagle/Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The world is still dealing with the fallout from <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/361740/crowdstrike-outage-windows">the CrowdStrike screwup that took millions of computers offline last week</a>. Some IT workers <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/21/24202960/crowdstrike-windows-outage-it-workers-photos-videos">have had to fix each computer manually</a>, walking from machine to machine <a href="https://lifehacker.com/tech/fix-the-crowdstrike-bug-with-usb-drive">with a USB stick</a>, and some remote workers <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sysadmin/comments/1e8z91i/comment/leckaz9/">say</a> they’re locked out of their computers with no fix in sight. All because of <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/crowdstrike-outage-update-windows/">a few lines of bad code</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It started in the early morning hours of Friday, July 19, when the cybersecurity company CrowdStrike pushed an update to its millions of customers. Unfortunately for all of them, there was a mistake in the code that caused Windows computers to crash repeatedly. This caused lots of problems for airlines, banks, hospitals, TV broadcasters, government agencies, and everyone who interacted with these organizations as <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/19/24201717/windows-bsod-crowdstrike-outage-issue">the dreaded “blue screen of death”</a> took over millions of computers. It took CrowdStrike <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/23/24204196/crowdstrike-windows-bsod-faulty-update-microsoft-responses">just 78 minutes</a> to identify the problem and issue a fix, but because many computers needed to be manually restarted, the problems persisted through the weekend and into this week. As of Wednesday morning, Delta Air Lines <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/travel/delta-air-lines-flight-cancellations-delays-wednesday-rcna163398">was still experiencing delays</a> due to the outage. The ongoing Delta flight cancellations <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/travel/2024/07/23/delta-flight-cancellations-unaccompanied-minors/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">separated countless unaccompanied minors from their parents for days</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is all annoying and anxiety-inducing. But a massive outage like this — whether caused by a faulty update, as was the case with CrowdStrike, or by a cyberattack — could have been much worse. <em>Much</em> worse. Like, getting kicked back to the 19th century overnight worse, and it’s not clear what we can do to stop it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This was just an accident,” Mark Atwood, an open source policy wonk and former Amazon employee, told me. “This could have been something that … just turned everybody’s computers into bricks, possibly unrepairable.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The really scary thing is that there’s honestly not much you or I can do to prevent a catastrophe like that from happening in the future. If you work for CrowdStrike, sure, you could do your part, but for the most part, building a more resilient internet is a job for the federal government. As trite as it may sound, one thing you can do is call your representatives in Congress and demand action. Because even if there’s not much you can do on an individual level to prevent the next big internet outage or cyberattack, you will likely be affected.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One big problem — and a key reason why this outage was so huge — is that CrowdStrike controls so much market share, and its software is so deeply integrated into so many computers, that one bad update can bring them all down.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regulations require companies in critical industries, like <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-professionals/security/laws-regulations/index.html">health care</a> and <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/business-guidance/privacy-security/gramm-leach-bliley-act">banking</a>, to protect people from harm, which means they must follow cybersecurity guidelines and use endpoint security software, which protects internet-connected devices from cyberattacks. CrowdStrike <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/opinion/msnbc-opinion/crowdstrike-outage-safety-update-rcna163127">tends to be the default option</a> to comply with these regulations, and in 2021, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) even picked CrowdStrike <a href="https://www.crowdstrike.com/press-releases/cisa-selects-crowdstrike-to-protect-the-nations-critical-endpoints-and-workloads/">to secure multiple government agencies</a>. CrowdStrike now controls nearly 25 percent of the market for endpoint security. So when CrowdStrike pushes out a bad update, a lot of people are affected. This particular incident affected 8.5 million Windows devices, <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2024/07/20/helping-our-customers-through-the-crowdstrike-outage/">according to Microsoft</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Lawmakers and regulators can and should learn from this CrowdStrike fiasco. It could be an opportunity for the federal government to redouble its efforts at improving cybersecurity and for security companies to do better. We have to demand they build products that are truly secure, says Dan O’Dowd, CEO of Green Hills Software and founder of <a href="https://dawnproject.com/">the Dawn Project</a>, an organization dedicated to making computers safe for humans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We know how to do it. It’s been done for years and years in the military and in aviation,” O’Dowd told me. “But it does cost more, and people just have to accept that we’re going to have a somewhat higher cost, so that we don’t lose it all.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Cybersecurity experts <a href="https://www.govtech.com/blogs/lohrmann-on-cybersecurity/cyber-attacks-is-the-big-one-coming-soon.html">talk about “the big one” a lot</a> these days, and that’s what O’Dowd is referring to when he says we could lose it all.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2162028098.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="A monitor screen in a subway station reads “the global technical outage,” as people walk underneath it in the direction of signs pointing to the exits." title="A monitor screen in a subway station reads “the global technical outage,” as people walk underneath it in the direction of signs pointing to the exits." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="The global outage brought down information screens on the New York City subway on July 19. | Adam Gray/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Adam Gray/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The big one might involve hackers <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/04/17/biden-admin-ports-prep-for-cyberattacks-as-us-infrastructure-targeted.html">attacking physical infrastructure</a>, like the power grid, water treatment plants, or shipping ports. Bad actors <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-security-2024-threats-cybersecurity-russia-69b130e9896a8e8a229b7a668000183f">could target elections</a>, hack voting machines, and spread misinformation. These kinds of things are actually already happening, but so far, there has not been a truly catastrophic outage or an attack so successful that it’s brought down large swaths of modern society. Not yet, at least.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The CrowdStrike incident should be a wakeup call, a reminder that the big one is coming and that there’s more we could do to stop it. Republican lawmakers have called on CrowdStrike CEO George Kurtz <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/07/22/house-committee-calls-crowdstrike-ceo-testify-global-outage/">to testify before the House Homeland Security Committee</a> to explain what happened to cause the outage and what the company was doing about it. CrowdStrike told me it was “actively in contact with relevant congressional committees,” and on Wednesday <a href="https://www.crowdstrike.com/falcon-content-update-remediation-and-guidance-hub/">published a preliminary incident report</a> detailing what went wrong and how it planned to prevent something like this from happening in the future.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Attention on Capitol Hill may also signal interest in legislation to create new regulations for the cybersecurity industry, although nothing has been announced.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, FTC Chair Lina Khan <a href="https://x.com/linakhanFTC/status/1814395610788929649">is drawing attention to</a> how the concentration of power can mean “a single glitch results in a system-wide outage, affecting industries from healthcare and airlines to banks and auto-dealers.” She seems to suggest that a better regulated cybersecurity industry could reduce that harm. Others, <a href="https://x.com/_Mark_Atwood/status/1814391019951272387">including Atwood</a>, have pointed out that, in some ways, the regulations are in place, but companies like CrowdStrike still aren’t following best practices.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Everyone believed there was no silver bullet, there was no cure for this other than try to think harder,” Atwood told me. “There are still bullets and best practices that, if you do them, the odds of making mistakes like this fall a lot.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Truth be told, there’s no easy way to make our networks and computers completely secure. But the federal government is continuing to try. It established CISA in 2018 to do everything from securing elections to protecting the power grid <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/resources-tools/programs/electromagnetic-pulse-and-geomagnetic-disturbance">from electromagnetic pulse, or EMP, attacks</a>. President Joe Biden also <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/12/executive-order-on-improving-the-nations-cybersecurity/">issued an executive order in 2021</a> to improve the nation’s cybersecurity with 55 new requirements, <a href="https://fedscoop.com/cybersecurity-executive-order-requirements-gao-omb-cisa/">almost all of which have now been completed</a>. (That executive order is also what led CISA to pick CrowdStrike as the federal government’s endpoint security partner.) And this year, following <a href="https://apnews.com/article/2022-midterm-elections-technology-colorado-donald-trump-voting-95b862c0cb66aac446a213aace504776">a series of breaches</a> during the 2020 midterm elections, CISA also launched a program to bolster election security, including protections for non-voting systems, like voter registration databases.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That just represents a handful of the federal government’s efforts to avoid a catastrophic cyberattack or outage. And the cybersecurity industry <a href="https://www.statista.com/outlook/tmo/cybersecurity/worldwide#revenue">is growing in lockstep</a> with increasing anxiety about such a disaster. Spending on cybersecurity rose about 70 percent from 2019 to 2023, <a href="https://www.moodys.com/web/en/us/about/insights/data-stories/2023-cyber-survey-highlights.html">according to Moody’s</a>, and the rise of generative AI <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2024-02-22-gartner-identifies-top-cybersecurity-trends-for-2024">will only complicate the picture</a> in the years to come. The 2024 election cycle <a href="https://apnews.com/article/biden-robocalls-artificial-intelligence-new-hampshire-texas-a8665277d43d05380d2c7594edf27617">has already seen AI-generated robocalls</a> that mimicked President Biden’s voice and told people not to vote, which does not sound as frightening as a cyberattack bringing down a power plant, but is an attack on democracy nevertheless.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The big one is still out there, lurking in some unknown future, waiting for the right string of events to occur and lead to catastrophe. Some of the worst nightmare scenarios have actually already happened, only not at a global scale. Ransomware attacks on hospitals and health care providers that threaten lives <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/change-healthcare-22-million-payment-ransomware-spike/">are a regular occurrence</a> in the US these days. After <a href="https://www.wired.com/2016/03/inside-cunning-unprecedented-hack-ukraines-power-grid/">taking out a portion of Ukraine’s power grid</a> with a cyberattack in 2015 and 2016, Russia <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/russia-ukraine-frostygoop-malware-heating-utility/">used a novel cyberattack</a> to cut the heat to 600 buildings in the Ukrainian city of Lviv this past January. So far, and very luckily, we have not seen a cyberattack lead to a nuclear disaster, but <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2017/06/27/europe/chernobyl-cyber-attack/index.html">such a thing</a> is <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/dec/04/sellafield-nuclear-site-hacked-groups-russia-china">not out</a> of <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-06-15/us-national-lab-nuclear-waste-site-hit-by-cyberattack?sref=qYiz2hd0">the realm of possibility</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“So I just rewatched <em>Chernobyl</em> last week,” Atwood said, referring to <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/6/4/18647339/chernobyl-finale-hbo-truth-how-accurate">the HBO series</a> about the 1986 nuclear disaster. “And that was one of the key lines: Why worry about something that hasn’t happened yet?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s how some cybersecurity executives think about the unimaginable, he told me, even when their own employees are warning against it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If we’ve learned anything from the past week — or even the past decade — it’s that the scale of outages and cyberattacks is getting larger as the world depends more on internet-connected devices to run itself. There’s no better time than now to reconsider whether we’re doing enough to stop the next one.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story was also published in the Vox Technology newsletter.&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/newsletters"><em><strong>Sign up here</strong></em></a><em>&nbsp;so you don’t miss the next one!</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Republicans ask the Supreme Court to gut student loan relief a second time]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/362750/supreme-court-student-loans-major-questions-alaska-cardona" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362750</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T16:58:04Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-24T16:10:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Student Loan Debt" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little more than a year ago, in Biden v. Nebraska (2023), the Supreme Court struck down one of the Biden administration’s student loan forgiveness plans. The Court’s decision took extraordinary liberties with the law, misreading a statute that clearly authorized the plan and relying on a doctrine known as “major questions.” The major questions [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Protesters in front of the Supreme Court building lobby for student loan debt relief." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/24763321/1364051755.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Protesters in front of the Supreme Court building lobby for student loan debt relief.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">A little more than a year ago, in <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/22pdf/22-506_nmip.pdf"><em>Biden v. Nebraska</em></a> (2023), the Supreme Court struck down one of the Biden administration’s student loan forgiveness plans. The Court’s decision took <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">extraordinary liberties with the law</a>, misreading a statute that clearly authorized the plan and relying on a doctrine known as “major questions.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The major questions doctrine, as I’ve <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">previously explained at length</a>, has no basis in any federal statute or constitutional provision, and appears to be entirely made up by the Court’s right flank. Some defenders of the doctrine claim that it traces back to a <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/529/120/">2000 Supreme Court decision</a>, but the very strong version of the major questions doctrine that the Republican justices often invoke to block President Joe Biden’s policies <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">did not emerge until he became president</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In applying the doctrine in <em>Nebraska</em>, however, the Court struck down just one of multiple programs the Biden administration created to reduce student loan burdens. Now, in a case known as <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A11/316401/20240705173618326_Alaska%20v%20Cardona%20Application%20to%20Vacate%20Stay%20final.pdf"><em>Alaska v. Cardona</em></a>, a trio of red-state attorneys general are asking the Supreme Court to neutralize much of a separate student loans plan which relies on an entirely different statute to justify its existence. (The “Cardona” in this case is Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The plan at issue in the <em>Alaska </em>case is known as the Saving on a Valuable Education or “SAVE” plan. <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A11/316401/20240705173618326_Alaska%20v%20Cardona%20Application%20to%20Vacate%20Stay%20final.pdf">Estimates of its costs vary</a>, and they range from $137.9 billion over the course of a decade to about three times that amount. Republicans <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/education/2024/03/28/student-loan-lawsuit-save-repayment-plan/">object to the cost of the SAVE plan</a>. The plaintiffs challenging the plan rely heavily on <em>Nebraska</em>, and on the major questions doctrine at the heart of that case, in their <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A11/316401/20240705173618326_Alaska%20v%20Cardona%20Application%20to%20Vacate%20Stay%20final.pdf">brief to the justices</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <em>Alaska</em> case arises on the Court’s “<a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/8/11/21356913/supreme-court-shadow-docket-jail-asylum-covid-immigrants-sonia-sotomayor-barnes-ahlman">shadow docket</a>,” a mix of emergency motions and other matters which the Court can decide on an expedited basis. So a decision in the <em>Alaska</em> case will probably be handed down soon.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In its <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A11/318299/20240717143843099_24A11%20Alaska%20Opp%20FINAL.pdf">brief to the justices</a>, the Biden administration offers a few persuasive reasons why the Court should stay its hand. But, frankly, after <em>Nebraska</em>, it is difficult to determine whether legal arguments play any role in the student loans cases the Supreme Court takes. The decision in <em>Nebraska</em> was <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">so egregious</a> — so <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">lacking in respect for statutory text</a> — that it’s far from clear whether any student loans plan created by this Democratic administration can receive a fair hearing in this GOP-controlled Supreme Court.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What’s at stake in <em>Alaska?</em></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The immediate stakes in the <em>Alaska</em> case are somewhat smaller than those in <em>Nebraska</em>. The program at issue in the latter case would have outright <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">canceled at least $10,000 in student loans</a> for student borrowers who earned less than $125,000 a year. The program at issue in <em>Alaska</em>, the SAVE plan, is more complicated. It has three parts, and only one of those parts is currently before the justices (although challenges to the other two parts are likely to make their way up to the Court eventually).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The SAVE plan <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A11/318299/20240717143843099_24A11%20Alaska%20Opp%20FINAL.pdf">makes three significant changes</a> to something known as “income contingent repayment plans.” Under these plans, a certain amount of every borrower’s income is protected from student loan repayments.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before the SAVE plan, a borrower earning up to 150 percent of the federal poverty rate (about $22,000 for a single person with no dependents) did not have to make student loan payments. And borrowers who earned more than this amount could subtract the amount from their income when determining how much they owed. The SAVE plan increases the amount of income protected from student loan repayments to 225 percent of the poverty rate (or just under $33,000 a year for a single-income earner with no dependents).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Additionally, before the SAVE plan, student loan repayments were capped at 10 percent of each borrower’s remaining income. The SAVE plan lowers that cap to 5 percent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, before the SAVE plan, borrowers could have their loans forgiven after making payments for 20 to 25 years. The SAVE plan accelerates this schedule, allowing some borrowers to have their loans forgiven after only 10 years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The specific issue before the Supreme Court right now is whether the second of these three changes — the decision to lower the cap from 10 percent to 5 percent — is authorized by federal law. The other two parts of the SAVE plan are likely to come before the justices eventually.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The biggest obstacle to the SAVE plan is the Court’s decision in <em>Nebraska</em></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To defend the provision of the SAVE plan at issue in <em>Alaska</em>, the Biden administration primarily points to a federal law that provides that income-contingent loans “shall require payments that <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/20/1087e">vary in relation to the appropriate portion of the annual income of the borrower</a> (and the borrower’s spouse, if applicable) as determined by the Secretary.” That language provides strong support for the proposition that the secretary of Education, and not the Supreme Court, gets to determine what percentage of a borrower’s income must be repaid each year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <em>Nebraska</em>, however, the six Republican justices in the majority seemed to divorce its analysis of student loan policy entirely from the text of federal law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The student loan policy in <em>Nebraska</em> was authorized by a law known as the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/STATUTE-117/pdf/STATUTE-117-Pg904.pdf#page=1">Heroes Act</a>, which gives the Education secretary broad authority to “waive or modify any statutory or regulatory provision applicable to the student financial assistance programs &#8230; as the Secretary deems necessary in connection with a war or other military operation or national emergency.” The Biden administration pointed to the Covid pandemic as a “national emergency” that triggered the Heroes Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This one provision of the Heroes Act alone should have been enough to justify the student loan forgiveness program at issue in <em>Nebraska</em>, but that law also contained other provisions which <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">should have removed any doubt</a> that the Education secretary had the power to create the loan forgiveness program that the Republican justices struck down.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Among other things, the Heroes Act waived a lengthy process known as “notice and comment” that federal agencies normally must undergo before changing federal policy. It provided that the secretary may dole out loan forgiveness <em>en masse</em> (“the Secretary is not required to exercise the waiver or modification authority under this section on a case-by-case basis”). And the Heroes Act also instructed courts not to interpret other federal statutes to limit the secretary’s loan forgiveness authority unless that statute was “enacted with specific reference to” the Heroes Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hard to imagine a statute, in other words, which more clearly signaled that the secretary should be allowed to cancel student loans during a national emergency, regardless of whether the political party that controls the Supreme Court agreed with the secretary’s decision.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, <em>Nebraska</em> reached the implausible conclusion that the student loan forgiveness program at issue in that case was not authorized by the Heroes Act. It also claimed that the program violated the so-called “major questions” doctrine.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The major questions doctrine — which, again, <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">appears in no law or constitutional provision</a> and was made up entirely by recent Supreme Court decisions — provides that Congress must “<a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">speak clearly</a> if it wishes to assign to an agency decisions of vast ‘economic and political significance.’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The student loan forgiveness program in <em>Nebraska</em> would have wiped out hundreds of billions of dollars in student loan debt, so it plausibly concerned a matter of great economic significance. But even if one concedes this point, it’s still hard to conceive of a statute that speaks more clearly than the Heroes Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Congress gave the secretary broad authority. It waived the normal procedural constraints on the secretary. It explicitly gave him or her the power to dole out relief to many borrowers at a time. And it forbade courts from reading any federal statute to limit the secretary’s authority unless that statute specifically mentioned the Heroes Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <em>Nebraska</em> decision, in other words, was so poorly reasoned that it raises serious questions about whether the Republican justices were interpreting the law in good faith. And that doesn’t bode well for the alternative student loans plan at issue in <em>Alaska</em>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What are the best arguments for the plan at issue in <em>Alaska</em>?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Again, federal law provides that the Education secretary may determine the “appropriate portion of the annual income of the borrower” that should be repaid. That language provides very strong support for the student loan plan currently before the Court.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s also some doubt about whether the Court has jurisdiction over this case to begin with. No federal court may hear a lawsuit challenging a federal policy unless the plaintiff can show that they were injured in some way by that policy. The red-state plaintiffs essentially argue that they are injured because the SAVE plan will cause some borrowers who owe money to those states to pay back those loans more quickly, depriving the states of interest on the loans. (For complicated reasons, the states would be fully reimbursed, even if the borrower has a portion of their loans canceled.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it’s far from clear that a state is injured by having a loan repaid early — if the state wishes to earn interest income, it can always invest the repaid money in something else that pays interest. As the Biden administration says in its brief, “<a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A11/318299/20240717143843099_24A11%20Alaska%20Opp%20FINAL.pdf">full repayment ‘would ordinarily be cause for celebration, not a lawsuit.’</a>”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, the Biden administration points to one significant difference between the SAVE plan and the plan at issue in <em>Nebraska</em>. In <em>Nebraska</em>, the Supreme Court faulted the Biden administration for creating what it claimed was a “<a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/22pdf/22-506_nmip.pdf">novel and fundamentally different loan forgiveness program</a>” than anything that had previously existed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The SAVE plan, by contrast, does not create a novel program. It takes an existing program that capped student loan payments and exempted a certain amount of income from loan repayments, and simply lowered the cap and increased the amount of the exemption.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Will these arguments be enough to rescue the SAVE plan? Maybe in a Court that is interested in following the law. After <em>Nebraska</em>, however, it is far from clear that this Court cares to do so.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
