<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-07-30T03:06:35Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/05/vox-favicon.jpeg?w=32</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Where J.D. Vance’s weirdest idea actually came from]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/363473/jd-vance-weird-voting-parents-demeny-postliberalism" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363473</id>
			<updated>2024-07-29T21:16:44Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-30T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since his selection as former President Donald Trump’s running mate, Sen. J.D. Vance has developed a reputation for being a bit strange.&#160; News articles and social media alike are riddled with strange Vance comments: his belief that “childless cat ladies” are running America into the ground, his hostility to no-fault divorce, and his choice to [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="J.D. Vance, in a navy suit and tie with a neatly trimmed beard and slight smile." data-caption="Republican vice presidential candidate Sen. J.D. Vance speaks on stage at the Republican National Convention on July 17, in Milwaukee. | Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2162475833.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Republican vice presidential candidate Sen. J.D. Vance speaks on stage at the Republican National Convention on July 17, in Milwaukee. | Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Since his selection as former President Donald Trump’s running mate, Sen. J.D. Vance has developed a reputation for being <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/363230/jd-vance-couch-sex-hillbilly-elegy-rumor-false">a bit strange</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.thebulwark.com/p/vance-galaxy-brained-style-american-politics">News</a> <a href="https://talkingpointsmemo.com/morning-memo/jd-vance-vice-president-controversy">articles</a> and social media alike are riddled with strange Vance comments: his belief that “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7gPGxB2FqEc">childless cat ladies</a>” are running America into the ground, his <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2024-07-17/republicans-are-targeting-no-fault-divorce?embedded-checkout=true">hostility to no-fault divorce</a>, and his choice to describe <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23373795/curtis-yarvin-neoreaction-redpill-moldbug">a neo-monarchist blogger as a notable intellectual influence</a>. Even Democratic politicians are getting in on the act, with Illinois Gov. J.B. Pritzker <a href="https://x.com/PritzkerForPrez/status/1815926731619885368">telling CNN</a> that he “has a weird view of America, honestly.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One instance of Vance’s alleged weirdness <a href="https://x.com/patrynard/status/1816183353772761538?s=46&amp;t=WDV3NvpmCLI-fO5R13Teug">that’s gone viral</a> — his proposal that parents of under-18 children should get extra votes — is especially clarifying. It helps explain where Vance’s ideas really come from and why they’ve become such a problem for the Trump-Vance ticket.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Specifically, it clarifies that Vance’s intellectual debt to peculiar segments of the conservative elite has led him to embrace a brand of politics that’s alien to the vast American middle.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The “extra votes for parents” proposal came in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jBrEng3xQYo">a 2021 speech</a> sponsored by the <a href="https://isi.org/">Intercollegiate Studies Institute</a>, a conservative organization that encourages college students to engage with right-wing ideas. About halfway through the speech, Vance says that he wants to “take aim at the left, specifically the childless left.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He knows these comments will be controversial: He says “I’m going to get in trouble for this,” and then asks the hosts if he’s being recorded. But he continues on by listing off leading Democratic politicians who didn’t have children at the time — Kamala Harris, Pete Buttigieg, Sen. Cory Booker, Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez —&nbsp;and then asks, “Why have we let the Democrat Party become controlled by people who don’t have children?”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, this is misleading: Harris is a stepmother and Buttigieg has <a href="https://people.com/all-about-pete-buttigieg-children-8683180">become a father</a> since Vance’s remarks. But the specific examples are less important than Vance’s general point, which is a moral one.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In his view, being a parent is the primary source of happiness and meaning in a person’s life, and people who don’t have kids can’t be trusted to make decisions in the interest of society writ large. Societies are good, per Vance, when they have babies; if they don’t have enough, they rot.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what to do about it? Vance suggests borrowing ideas from Viktor Orbán, Hungary’s authoritarian prime minister who has made increasing Hungary’s birthrate <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/eu-populist-right-want-you-make-more-babies-viktor-orban/">a centerpiece of his policy agenda</a>. But Vance also worries that a Hungarian model might not be possible because families suffer from a “structural democratic disadvantage”: children can’t vote. Hence, he concludes, we should let parents cast votes on their behalf.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Let’s give votes to all the children in this country and let’s give control over votes to the parents in this country,” he says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s an old idea called “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/03/opinion/sunday/parents-teenagers-voting.html">Demeny voting</a>,” named after 20th-century <a href="https://www.ae-info.org/ae/Member/Demeny_Paul/CV">Hungarian demographer Paul Demeny</a> (a vocal champion of the idea). Typically, the argument for Demeny voting is rooted in fairness. Children are people who, like anyone else, deserve political representation. Since they lack the maturity to make informed choices about their interests, parents should vote on their behalf —&nbsp;much in the same way they make decisions about children’s medical care or education. To get a sense of how this argument works, I’d recommend <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4723276">a recent paper by two law professors</a> at Harvard and Northwestern making the case at length.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But for Vance, the policy isn’t just about ensuring fairness for families: it’s about punishing childless adults. Vance sees Demeny voting as a tool for creating two-tiered citizenship, one where parents have more and better political representation than other adults.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“When you go to the polls in this country, you should have more power —&nbsp;more of an ability to speak your voice in our democratic republic — than people who don’t have kids,” he says. “If you don’t have much of an investment in the future of this country, then maybe you shouldn’t get nearly the same voice.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is not the language of a liberal looking to expand the sphere of people whose interests are represented in the system to children. Vance’s defense of Demeny voting reveals a belief that people who aren’t like him, who don’t share his values about childrearing, are social unequals: non-participants in the political project of ensuring America survives across generations, and hence deserved targets of political discrimination.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In short, Vance wants to turn the law into a vehicle for legislating hard-right morality.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This isn’t being unfair to Vance: he explicitly identifies as a “<a href="https://www.ncregister.com/news/j-d-vance-is-a-catholic-post-liberal">postliberal</a>,” a school of thought that believes it’s the government’s job to push people toward living morally upright lives, defined in conservative religious terms. In particular, he has cited Patrick Deneen — a Notre Dame professor and chief postliberal theorist — as a major influence. Speaking at a release event for Deneen’s book<em> </em><a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/6/15/23734340/patrick-deneen-regime-change-review"><em>Regime Change</em></a>, Vance described himself as an “<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360283/jd-vance-trump-vp-vice-president-authoritarian">anti-regime</a>” politician — meaning that he aimed to act on Deneen’s call for fundamentally transforming American politics along postliberal lines.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem is that vanishingly few Americans are postliberals, while many Americans are actively turned off&nbsp;by its right-wing moral paternalism. They’re seeing the ideology at work and it strikes them as, well, <em>weird</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance, however, seems to sincerely believe in their ideas, or at very least believe it’s advantageous in intra-GOP competition to be seen as the postliberal champion. Indeed, it may very well have helped him become a vice presidential candidate: Tucker Carlson, postliberalism’s most prominent voice in the media, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/16/us/politics/tucker-carlson-jd-vance-trump.html">played a central role in pushing Trump to pick Vance</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But whether out of sincere conviction or political opportunism, Vance has trapped himself into speaking the language of postliberals. He shares their preoccupations and fears, their philosophy and their ideology. His world is that of a handful of intellectuals whose values and way of thinking are wholly at odds with Middle America’s.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The great conservative populist hope turns out to talk like a creature of a very nice intellectual elite&nbsp;—&nbsp;and <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/jd-vance-lowest-vice-president-approval-rating-republican-convention-2024-7#:~:text=Vance%2C%20however%2C%20is%20polling%20at,long%20polled%20behind%20other%20Republicans.">voters don’t like it</a>.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Rachel M. Cohen</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The movement desperately trying to get people to have more babies]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/363543/pronatalism-vance-birth-rates-population-decline-fertility" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363543</id>
			<updated>2024-07-29T22:54:47Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-30T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abortion was always slated to be a top issue in the 2024 presidential election. But virtually no one predicted that politicians would be openly blasting those ambivalent about having children.&#160; “We are effectively run in this country … by a bunch of childless cat ladies who are miserable at their own lives and the choices [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="J.D. Vance carrying a young child through a group of people." data-caption="Republican vice presidential nominee Sen. J.D. Vance carries his daughter Maribel Vance as he arrives to greet supporters at the Park Diner on July 28, 2024, in St Cloud, Minnesota. | Stephen Maturen/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Maturen/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2163513739.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Republican vice presidential nominee Sen. J.D. Vance carries his daughter Maribel Vance as he arrives to greet supporters at the Park Diner on July 28, 2024, in St Cloud, Minnesota. | Stephen Maturen/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Abortion was always slated to be a top issue in the 2024 presidential election. But virtually no one predicted that politicians would be openly blasting those ambivalent about having children.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We are effectively run in this country … by a bunch of childless cat ladies who are miserable at their own lives and the choices that they’ve made, and so they wanna make the rest of the country miserable, too,” J.D. Vance, the Republican vice presidential nominee, said in<strong> </strong>a now-famous statement in<strong> </strong>2021. “It’s just a basic fact. You look at Kamala Harris, Pete Buttigieg, AOC (Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez), the entire future of the Democrats is controlled by people without children.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That wasn’t all on the subject from Vance. He also argued in 2021 that parents <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jBrEng3xQYo">should get additional votes</a> on their children’s behalf. People without kids “should face the consequences and the reality,” he said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other conservative voices have joined in. Speaking in Vance’s defense last week, Blake Masters, the former Arizona Senate candidate, <a href="https://x.com/bgmasters/status/1816295040081354853">said bluntly</a> that people without children shouldn’t lead in politics:&nbsp; “If you aren’t running or can’t run a household of your own, how can you relate to a constituency of families, or govern wisely with respect to future generations?” he asked.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Elon Musk, the billionaire Tesla CEO, weighed in to call Harris an “extinctionist” because she <a href="https://x.com/DonaldJTrumpJr/status/1817288993740095986">noted some young people cite climate anxiety</a> as a reason not to have kids. “The natural extension of her philosophy would be a de facto holocaust for all of humanity!” Musk <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1817300216011251712">concluded</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One starting place to understand where all this is coming from is pronatalism: a broad ideological movement driven by concern that the world is not producing enough children and that society should work to change that.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not all pronatalists are politically conservative, and not all conservatives are particularly pronatalist. People with different backgrounds and ideologies are concerned about what a shrinking population will mean for future generations, though the movement does include anti-abortion advocates like Vance and Masters who have been more vocal. Still other card-carrying pronatalists staunchly oppose coercing women into having children they don’t want.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those worried about declining birth rates paint a scary picture of the future. As the number of babies dwindles, the number of workers will shrink, too. There will be fewer people paying taxes to support welfare systems, which will still be supporting large elderly populations.<strong> </strong>The result, they warn, will be economic stagnation and political strife: higher unemployment, more acute labor shortages, diminished investment, fewer innovations, and greater poverty.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is some reason to be wary of these grim predictions. Past population panics have fueled some of the world’s most horrific chapters. Back when leaders thought the world was producing too many humans, governments around the globe pushed mass sterilization campaigns, forced abortions, and gruesome eugenic regimes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Others<strong> </strong>see the increased focus on birth rates as a way to scapegoat individuals — primarily women — for societal issues that politicians could otherwise address, such as improving care for the elderly or taxing the rich more aggressively.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That there’s a “proximate economic problem … doesn’t necessarily mean increasing birth rates is the solution,” said Nancy Folbre, an economist at the University of Massachusetts Amherst.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The concerns about fertility aren’t taking place in a political vacuum, in the US or anywhere else.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Around the world, far-right leaders have campaigned on platforms to roll back abortion rights, restrict immigration, and boost the number of native-born children. In China, government officials recently <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/02/world/asia/china-communist-party-xi-women.html">scrapped</a> gender equality as a priority and <a href="https://www.economist.com/china/2023/11/09/china-wants-women-to-stay-home-and-bear-children">advised</a> women “to establish a correct outlook on marriage and love, childbirth, and family.” In Hungary, Prime Minister Viktor Orbán has promoted a policy of “<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/sep/06/viktor-orban-trumpets-far-right-procreation-anti-immigration-policy">procreation not immigration</a>.”&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Inside this story</strong>:</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>An overview</strong> of the increasingly vocal movement concerned about declining birth rates</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Perspectives</strong> from those who see risk to women’s autonomy if society panics too much about shrinking population</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>A look</strong> at existing research on policy and fertility</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Context</strong> on why these birth rate questions have become more pressing and prominent</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even talking about population decline as an issue can feel risky. Though not all pronatalists are against reproductive rights, a louder conversation that frames falling birth rates as a major problem inevitably boosts the issue’s salience, creating space for potentially more reactionary ideas.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still,<strong> </strong>those who want to voluntarily increase the number of children say we must have a real conversation, no matter how uneasy it makes us. Some are hopeful about emerging technologies — like <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2024/04/12/1241895501/artificial-womb-premature-birth">artificial wombs</a> and <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2023/07/15/1184298351/conception-human-eggs-ivg-ivf-infertility">lab-grown eggs</a> — to one day bring more humans to life. Others warn that sexist, racist, and ethnonationalist forces will fill the void if liberal leaders fail to solve the problem themselves.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If we wait, the less inclusive, less compassionate, less calm elements within our society and many societies worldwide may someday call depopulation a crisis and exploit it to suit their agendas — of inequality, nationalism, exclusion or control,” <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2023/09/18/opinion/human-population-global-growth.html">warned Dean Spears</a>, the director of the Population Wellbeing Initiative at UT Austin. “Paying attention now would create an opportunity to lay out a path that would preserve freedom, share burdens, advance gender equity, value care work and avoid the disasters that happen when governments try to impose their will on reproduction.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Spears may be right, but it’s a gamble. Nobody really knows whether you can<em> </em>sustainably boost birth rates without coercing women into having kids or restricting the opportunities they might otherwise pursue. Efforts to substantially reverse declining fertility in other countries have so far failed, and right now, at least in the US, most adults without children <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/social-trends/2024/07/25/the-experiences-of-u-s-adults-who-dont-have-children/">say they just don’t want them</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why people are talking about birth rates more now</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All <a href="https://www.unfpa.org/swp2023/too-few">over the world</a>, fewer children are being born, including in some of the most populous nations like China, India, the US, Brazil, and Mexico. Earlier this month, the UN <a href="https://apnews.com/article/un-world-population-growth-e2adab27719bb94ea19626dc53c57384">announced</a> it is likely the number of people on earth will peak in the next 75 years — a big change from even a decade ago, when demographers thought that moment was still well over a century away.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Concern about declining birth rates is not new, but until recently, it didn&#8217;t seem to have much domestic relevance for the United States.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By the turn of the 21st century, many countries were already grappling with plummeting fertility. In 2004, journalist Phil Longman published <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Empty-Cradle-Birthrates-Threaten-Prosperity/dp/0465050506"><em>The Empty Cradle</em></a><em>, </em>outlining the political and economic risks of depopulation; he traveled all over the world encouraging leaders to take it more seriously.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the time, there was a major exception: the United States. Even as the US provided virtually no support for working parents, American birth rates stayed elevated. Experts attributed this primarily to higher birth rates among Latino immigrants, higher teen births, and <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2007/05/04/AR2007050401891.html">potentially America’s religious culture</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“At that time it was possible to look at all these numbers and say the United States is immune to this,” Longman told me. “Our birth rates were still barely above replacement level, so people could be like, ‘Oh well that’s the European disease, that’s the South Korean culture, American exceptionalism will save us.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Holding the US as an exception, the overarching consensus became that countries that were more successful at boosting birth rates were those that provided more support for women to balance their domestic life with jobs and other pursuits. Sweden’s egalitarian welfare policies were designed by intellectuals in the 1930s who specifically <a href="https://womensenews.org/2014/04/sweden-pushed-gender-equality-boost-birth-rates/">wanted to boost Swedish birth rates</a>, and by the end of the century, Nordic countries with more expansive welfare systems seemed to be doing better on the birthrate front than more socially conservative countries like Italy and Japan.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Feminism is the new natalism,” a Tory member of Parliament in the United Kingdom said in a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2003/sep/24/childrensservices.comment">2003 report</a> on the threat of low fertility in Europe.&nbsp;Over the last 10 years, though, even the Nordic countries have seen hastening <a href="https://thl.fi/en/-/birth-rate-decreased-in-all-nordic-countries-in-2022-finland-had-lowest-overall-fertility-rate">drops in fertility</a>. Declining birth rates finally hit the US starting in 2007 and have <a href="https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/jep.36.1.151">continued to fall</a> ever since.<br></p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/birthrates.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.481809352638,100,79.036381294723" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Why? There are several leading explanations advanced by different people:&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
<li>Women are postponing marriage and childbearing later into their reproductive years and using more effective birth control methods more consistently.</li>



<li><a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10508-021-02125-2">People are having less sex</a> overall, with <a href="https://crisismagazine.com/opinion/how-social-media-may-lead-to-lower-birth-rates">some arguing</a> that smartphones and the internet have <a href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/news/2024/jun/internet-addiction-affects-behaviour-and-development-adolescents">dominated attentio</a>n that previously went toward dating and love.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Some say people have recognized that smaller families are easier to manage if women want to balance child-rearing with careers and other personal pursuits.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Others argue the <a href="https://www.vox.com/23013483/mental-health-pandemic-young-people-sapien-labs">mental health crisis</a> has brought more despair about the future and a corresponding unwillingness to bring unconsenting children into an overheating world.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Others look to broader <a href="https://thedispatch.com/article/what-child-care-doomerism-misses/">“doomer” narratives</a> about parenting and lament the <a href="https://www.vox.com/features/23979357/millennials-motherhood-dread-parenting-birthrate-women-policy">overly negative messages</a> some media outlets send about raising kids.</li>



<li>Still others say birth rates are falling primarily because of high costs and <a href="https://americancompass.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/American-Compass_2021-Home-Building-Survey_Final.pdf">point to surveys</a> suggesting people would have more kids if they felt it was easier to afford.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The decline in birth rates since 2007 has been driven primarily by women in their 20s. Maybe people will have the same number of kids ultimately, but just later in life? Experts say that no longer seems very likely.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This may be because the decline is less about fewer large families with four or five kids and more about significantly fewer families having even one or two children compared to a generation ago. “The decline in the rate from zero kids to one kid is mostly driven by singleness,” said Lyman Stone, a demographer who identifies as a pronatalist. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Can policy really make people more willing to give birth?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The burning question in the pronatalism conversation is whether governments can do anything to restore a country to “replacement rate” (an average of 2.1 births per woman) without restricting women’s rights.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some social conservatives have blamed falling birth rates in Western countries primarily on women’s career aspirations and the overall decline in marriage. But Spears, of UT Austin, says that can hardly explain why we’re seeing similar drops in nations like India, where marriage rates remain high and where most women don’t work in the formal labor market.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Can governments do anything to reverse this? Last year, <a href="https://www.vox.com/23971366/declining-birth-rate-fertility-babies-children">my colleague Anna North reviewed examples</a> of countries that were trying to reverse fertility declines. Germany increased investments in child care. Russia began offering lump-sum payments of about $7,000 to families with more than two kids. Hungary started offering <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/mar/04/baby-bonuses-fit-the-nationalist-agenda-but-do-they-work">newlyweds loans of $30,000</a>, which Orbán said would be forgiven if the couple had three children. None of these interventions have been enough to fully reverse the population decline, and Spears tells me there isn’t anything he’s seen “with strong evidence of an effect.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But some experts and advocates believe that it’s possible — if the incentives are large enough.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“A lot of the pronatalist policies have been worse than half-hearted,” Folbre, the economist, told me, pointing to examples like $4,000 in subsidies from governments <a href="https://famiglia.governo.it/it/politiche-e-attivita/contributi-economici/archivio-misure-non-piu-in-vigore/assegno-di-natalita-bonus-bebe/">in Italy</a> and <a href="https://www.income.com.sg/blog/baby-bonus-singapore">Singapore</a>, which really amounts to just a couple months of child care aid.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“What’s actually being spent [by governments] is a very small percentage of the cost of raising children, and leaders should take as many steps as possible to socialize those costs and reduce costs of parents,” she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Stone, the demographer, <a href="https://ifstudies.org/reports/southern-europe-report/2024/executive-summary">is optimistic</a> about the potential of policy to voluntarily boost birth rates, and he recently established a think tank — <a href="https://ifstudies.org/blog/ifs-launches-the-pronatalism-initiative-under-new-senior-fellow-lyman-stone">the Pronatalism Initiative</a> at the Institute for Family Studies — dedicated to researching these questions.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He pointed to some recent empirical reviews on the topic, <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/padr.12431">like this one from 2021</a> that assessed family policies in Europe, the United States, Canada, and Australia since the 1970s, and found social reforms can increase fertility. Another review from 2022 looked <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41599-022-01270-w">specifically at maternity leave policies</a> and concluded they “do in fact increase fertility when benefit increases are generous.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Stone is motivated by <a href="https://medium.com/migration-issues/how-big-is-the-fertility-gap-in-america-fd205e9d1a35">surveys that suggest women are having fewer children</a> than they really want, but he recognizes that most women don’t want very large families, either.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Boosting fertility, in Stone’s view, may ultimately come down to more muscular spending while reducing other costs, such as <a href="https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/-/media/boe/files/working-paper/2019/monetary-policy-and-birth-rates-the-effect-of-mortgage-rate-pass-through-on-fertility.pdf">housing</a> and student loans. While incentives with sticker prices upward <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/want-more-american-babies-make-the-u-s-more-livable/">of $200,000 per baby</a> may seem initially eye-popping, Stone argues that it looks more reasonable when compared to <a href="https://x.com/lymanstoneky/status/1729527294903865670">annual Medicaid spending</a> and other health interventions.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The darker corners of the pronatalism movement</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not everyone concerned about falling birth rates is interested in gender equity or voluntary solutions.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last December, a relatively fringe group gathered in Austin for the <a href="https://www.natalism.org/blank">first-ever Natal Conference</a> to discuss boosting babies, with some guest speakers decrying the liberal cultural forces they see as responsible for the world’s decline.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Peachy Keenan, a pseudonym for one conservative speaker, argued her fellow pronatalists need to make motherhood and large families a more hotly desired status symbol, but to avoid “market[ing] natalism” to progressive feminists.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other speakers included right-wing blogger Charles Haywood, who lamented that “the actual meaning of masculinity has been destroyed by vampire feminists,” and Malcolm and Simone Collins, who were subjects <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/article/2024/may/25/american-pronatalists-malcolm-and-simone-collins">of a viral Guardian profile earlier this year</a><strong> </strong>that revealed they smack their children.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This corner of “pronatalism” is composed mostly of tech enthusiasts and hyper-rationalist types,&nbsp;religious fundamentalists and some far-right activists worried about immigration and demographic change.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the most prominent members of this coalition is billionaire Tesla CEO Elon Musk, who <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1545046146548019201?lang=en">claimed</a> the falling fertility rate is <em>“</em>the biggest danger civilization faces, by far.” Musk recently led the push to get Vance nominated as Donald Trump’s vice president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some mainstream conservatives like Washington Examiner columnist Tim Carney <a href="https://t.co/BvdfI3Jp5B">argue</a> that focusing on more extreme voices within the pronatalist movement amounts to “nut-picking”: As he correctly notes, it’s not just far-right conservatives who worry about falling birth rates.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But extreme pronatalists also increasingly hold positions of power. Pronatalist intellectuals with <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/02/20/donald-trump-allies-christian-nationalism-00142086">influence in the Trump world</a> have endorsed policies like limiting contraception and banning no-fault divorce. Trump has said he wants to see <a href="https://www.c-span.org/video/?c5060348/user-clip-trump-baby-boom">“a new baby boom.”</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republican House Speaker Mike Johnson has blamed <em>Roe v. Wade </em>for killing potential American workers, resulting in strained welfare systems today. “If we had all those able-bodied workers in the economy, we wouldn’t be going upside down and toppling over like this,” he <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fdyifVvEO-w&amp;t=160s">said during a 2022 congressional hearing</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The presence of such perspectives in the movement is not something most women can afford to ignore.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“<em>The Handmaid’s Tale</em> is a very real risk,” Folbre said, referring to Margaret Atwood’s dystopian novel in which a government weaponizes women’s fertility. “A lot of the energy behind Donald Trump is related to a panic about the consequences of women having more reproductive choice.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Stone, the demographer, is against abortion, and I asked him how people concerned about rollbacks of reproductive rights should feel about him directing this new pronatalism think tank. He agreed he “would like to see all the babies born” but said “the key thing to understand” is that evidence showing abortion restrictions lead to higher birth rates is minimal, since in societies with good contraceptive access, people mostly just switch to that.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The data isn’t great, but Stone estimates that one prevented abortion “likely gets you .05 to .15 extra 18-year-olds 18 years later.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another <a href="https://sites.utexas.edu/pwi/files/2024/06/lawson_spears_abortion.pdf">study co-authored</a> by Spears at UT Austin similarly found “no evidence of a significant association between abortion legality and birth rates” and that abortion bans can even lower total birth rates overall. (It’s worth noting too since <em>Roe </em>v. <em>Wade </em>was overturned, US abortion incidence <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024/3/20/24106109/dobbs-roe-abortion-reproductive-rights">has increased</a>.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, efforts to restrict abortion are getting more aggressive, and there’s no certainty that abortion incidence will stay elevated as leaders seek new ways to cut off access. Plus, it’s a less comforting fact about contraception when there are anti-abortion activists in the US <a href="https://www.vox.com/24087411/anti-abortion-roe-dobbs-birth-control-contraception-ivf">working now to conflate abortion with birth control</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Stone argues that liberals will ultimately have to consider compromise with anti-abortion groups on policies where there’s common ground — like child care and affordable housing — even if they support the measures for different reasons.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“At the end of the day, every single political vote involves holding your nose to some extent,” he said. “And if your view is that you can’t support reducing child poverty by 40 percent through a child allowance because pro-life people are also supporting it, then maybe you hate kids.”&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Reproductive desires, reproductive justice</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the top arguments pronatalists make to support their case is that research surveys tend to suggest women have not had as many children as they hoped.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the United Nations wrote in its <a href="https://www.unfpa.org/sites/default/files/swop23/SWOP2023-ENGLISH-230329-web.pdf">2023 State of the World Population report</a>, current evidence suggests that across Europe and the US, as well as throughout East Asia, women nearing or at the end of their reproductive years say they would have had more children than they actually did. “These data do ultimately point to an appreciable gap between desired and realized fertility across the globe,” the UN concluded.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Leslie Root, a demographer at the University of Colorado Boulder, focused her graduate studies on these types of “child-bearing intention” surveys but eventually stopped because she grew concerned with how the data was being interpreted.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She explained that some surveys lacked nuance, failed to consider how desires can change over time, and&nbsp;didn’t account for the context in which a survey is administered, including the presence of family members or partners.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s not always clear what the surveys are asking, especially these retrospective surveys of women over 45,” Root told me. “They ask looking back at your life if you could have had more kids would you have done so but there is obviously a social stigma to saying you wish you had fewer.” (Stone, who also spent his graduate studies focused on the surveys, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/13/upshot/american-fertility-is-falling-short-of-what-women-want.html">argues they still provide credible data</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Root ultimately doesn’t think birth rates are that low, but even if they were, she thinks leaders should treat the problem as an economic one, not a demographic one.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The view that birth rates are “neutral” is shared by Emily Klancher Merchant, <a href="https://www.emilyklancher.com/">a historian</a> and author of <a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/building-the-population-bomb-9780197558942?cc=us&amp;lang=en&amp;"><em>Building the Population Bomb</em></a>, which traces the rise of overpopulation fears in the 20th century.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If women say they haven’t had as many children as they want, then that’s the primary issue to focus on, not birth rates,” she told me. “And if the problem is with the economy or how to support the elderly, there are many more direct ways to deal with that than through population measures.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Root and Merchant both say the conversation would be better focused on reproductive justice — a feminist movement focused on supporting one’s right to have children, to not have children, and to parent children in safe, healthy communities — than pronatalism.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many policies supported by reproductive justice advocates are also supported by pronatalists, but feminists say building support for family-friendly measures like universal child care as a way to boost fertility risks gutting them later on if leaders conclude they’ve been insufficient to reverse population trends.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Spears, who believes in reproductive freedom but also thinks falling birth rates are a serious problem, compares this moment to decades ago when leaders realized they needed to address climate change.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Spears’s view, there’s still time for leaders to reverse declines in population since we’re still years away from when the number of people on earth is set to peak. “Six decades ago there weren’t university majors in sustainability science, there wasn’t a journal called <em>The Future of Climate Change</em>,” he told me. His point is that we have never really brought our best resources to bear to tackle these questions, and if we seriously invest in doing so, we could potentially build more economically stable societies that better align with families’ reproductive desires.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think that if we truly change society&#8217;s commitment to taking care of one another, and to taking care of the people who take care of one another,” he said, “then we could invent new ways to live.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden’s new Supreme Court reform proposals are mostly useless]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/363557/supreme-court-biden-kamala-harris-reform-term-limits-ethics" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363557</id>
			<updated>2024-07-29T22:44:57Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-29T22:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Monday, President Joe Biden announced three proposals to reform the Supreme Court: term limits for justices, a binding code of Supreme Court ethics, and a constitutional amendment overturning the Court’s decision allowing sitting presidents to violate the criminal law. Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic Party’s presumptive presidential nominee, also endorsed the proposals. But [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25342424/1246877112.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">On Monday, President Joe Biden announced <a href="https://x.com/HerbieZiskend46/status/1817857906718503334">three proposals to reform the Supreme Court</a>: term limits for justices, a binding code of Supreme Court ethics, and a constitutional amendment overturning the Court’s decision <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">allowing sitting presidents to violate the criminal law</a>. Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic Party’s presumptive presidential nominee, also <a href="https://x.com/edokeefe/status/1817899333343154183?s=61&amp;t=TQlk4x44ENcfSu3Y1ke6ew">endorsed the proposals</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But if you’re hoping these ideas will rein in a Court that’s essentially <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/7/8/23784320/supreme-court-2022-term-affirmative-action-religion-voting-rights-abortion">become the policymaking arm of the Republican Party</a>, expect to be disappointed. Amending the Constitution is <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/1/30/20997046/constitution-electoral-college-senate-popular-vote-trump">virtually impossible</a> — it requires approval from three-quarters of the states —<strong> </strong>so Biden’s proposal to amend the Constitution to overturn the presidential immunity decision in <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/23pdf/23-939_e2pg.pdf"><em>Trump v. United States</em></a> (2024) is almost certainly dead on arrival. Similarly, the term limits proposal is at odds with Article III of the Constitution, which provides that justices “<a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/constitution/articleiii">shall hold their offices during good behaviour</a>,” language that’s historically been understood to <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/9/16/20867558/remove-supreme-court-brett-kavanaugh-no-impeachment">protect judges unless they engage in serious misconduct</a>. So that proposal is equally dead.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Proposing a constitutional amendment is not entirely useless. By proposing two amendments targeting the Supreme Court, Biden makes clear that his Democratic Party opposes much of the Court’s recent behavior, much like President George W. Bush used a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2004/02/24/politics/bush-backs-ban-in-constitution-on-gay-marriage.html">proposed constitutional amendment banning same-sex marriage in 2004</a> to communicate to voters that Republicans were the anti-gay party. But Bush’s amendment was never enacted, and Biden’s amendments almost certainly won’t become law, either.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The call for a binding ethics code, by contrast, could potentially impose some limited constraints on the Court. The Constitution states that most of the Supreme Court’s jurisdiction must be exercised “<a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/constitution/articleiii">under such regulations as the Congress shall make</a>.” So Congress should have the power to enact a Supreme Court ethics code with an ordinary statute, rather than with a constitutional amendment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s unclear, though, whether the justices would follow such a code if Congress enacted one. At least one justice, Samuel Alito, has <a href="https://apnews.com/article/supreme-court-ethics-alito-d98b0edf1340ff3ed66b345c5ddcf0dc">claimed that such an ethics code would be unconstitutional</a>. If Congress were to pass such a code, and the justices wanted to ignore it, all they’d need to do is sign onto whatever argument Alito came up with to justify striking down the code.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if the same justices who concluded that presidents are above the law decided not to declare themselves immune from ethical reform, a binding ethics code would do little to cure the Court’s partisanship. While two of the justices, Alito and Justice Clarence Thomas, <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/359206/supreme-court-incompetent-abortion-trump-immunity">accepted lavish gifts from Republican billionaires</a>, seven of the nine justices have thus far not been caught in similar scandals. Four of the Court’s six Republicans might not be affected in any serious way by an ethics reform law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While a binding ethics code might stop Thomas from <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/clarence-thomas-scotus-undisclosed-luxury-travel-gifts-crow">sailing around the world on billionaire Harlan Crow’s yacht</a>, it wouldn’t stop him from voting to, say, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/23622299/ron-desantis-first-amendment-press-new-york-times-v-sullivan">eliminate freedom of the press</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s proposals, in other words, are mostly symbolic. The ethics proposal is meaningful but limited in scope. And the two other proposals? They won’t accomplish anything that couldn’t also be accomplished by a presidential press conference denouncing the Supreme Court.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A constitutional amendment will not pass</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Constitution, according to University of Texas law professor Sanford Levinson, “is the <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/1/30/20997046/constitution-electoral-college-senate-popular-vote-trump">most difficult to amend or update</a> of any constitution currently existing in the world today.” Three-quarters of the states <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/11/6/20951458/equal-rights-amendment-era-virginia-legislature-elections-results-democrats">must ratify any constitutional amendment</a>, a requirement that virtually ensures that either major political party can block any amendment, even if the other party wins supermajorities in Congress.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This explains why the Constitution has only been amended 27 times in all of American history, and 10 of those amendments was the Bill of Rights, which was enacted almost immediately after the Constitution took effect. The last time the Constitution was amended was <a href="https://www.archives.gov/founding-docs/amendments-11-27">more than 30 years ago, in 1992</a>. And that was a <a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/constitution/amendment-27/">very minor amendment</a> involving congressional pay.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As President Franklin Roosevelt once said, “No amendment which <a href="https://go.gale.com/ps/i.do?id=GALE%7CA273615586&amp;sid=googleScholar&amp;v=2.1&amp;it=r&amp;linkaccess=abs&amp;issn=07427115&amp;p=AONE&amp;sw=w&amp;userGroupName=anon%7E9cd6d8e8&amp;aty=open-web-entry">any powerful economic interests or the leaders of any powerful political party</a> have had reason to oppose has ever been ratified within anything like a reasonable time.” Indeed, as a practical matter, any amendment is likely to fail if it garners opposition from any substantial interest group. American history is replete with popular proposed amendments that failed because of strong but narrow opposition from such a group.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 1924, supermajorities in Congress proposed a constitutional amendment to overrule the Supreme Court’s decision in <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/247/251/"><em>Hammer v. Dagenhart</em></a> (1918), which struck down a federal ban on child labor. The <a href="https://archive.thinkprogress.org/john-paul-stevens-second-amendment-d25525bc0de4/">amendment died</a> largely due to opposition from cotton mill owners, but oddly enough also because of opposition from the Catholic Church, which feared that a child labor amendment would lead to federal regulation of parochial schools.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, the Equal Rights Amendment, which would have written gender equality into the Constitution, seemed <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/9/7/12817958/phyllis-schlafly-activism-feminism">destined to become law after Congress proposed it in 1972</a>. In one year alone, 22 states ratified it. But then <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/9/7/12817756/phyllis-schlafly-dies-started-war-on-women">anti-feminist activists like Phyllis Schlafly organized against it</a>, spreading fears that the amendment would mandate unisex bathrooms and even lead to (gasp!) same-sex marriages.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the end, the required 38 states did ratify the Equal Rights Amendment, but <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/2/11/21133029/ruth-bader-ginsburg-equal-rights-amendment-supreme-court">not before a 1982 deadline set by Congress</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is, however, a lesson to be garnered from these two failed amendments. A federal child labor ban is <a href="https://www.worker.gov/child-labor-wages/#:~:text=Federal%20child%20labor%20law%20generally,18%20in%20any%20hazardous%20occupation.">now law</a>, not because proponents of the child labor amendment eventually overcame opposition from the cotton mills but because the Supreme Court overruled <em>Hammer</em> in 1941 <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/312/100/">after Roosevelt appointed several new justices to the Court</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The ERA is not part of the Constitution, but a series of Supreme Court decisions — many of which were argued by future Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg — established that “a party seeking to uphold government action based on sex <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/2/11/21133029/ruth-bader-ginsburg-equal-rights-amendment-supreme-court">must establish an ‘exceedingly persuasive justification’ for the classification</a>.” Thus implementing a prohibition on sex discrimination by the government that is almost as strong as the prohibition proposed by the ERA.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Democrats want to overturn the Supreme Court’s error in the <em>Trump</em> decision, in other words, their best bet is to follow the same playbook Republicans followed to <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/7/8/23784320/supreme-court-2022-term-affirmative-action-religion-voting-rights-abortion">overturn decisions like <em>Roe v. Wade</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Because it is virtually impossible to amend the Constitution by writing a new amendment into the document, constitutional disputes in the United States are resolved by the judicial appointments process. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whoever controls the Supreme Court controls the Constitution.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Imposing term limits on the Supreme Court would also require a constitutional amendment</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">President Biden’s term limits proposal calls for “a system in which the President would appoint a Justice every two years to <a href="https://x.com/HerbieZiskend46/status/1817857906718503334">spend eighteen years in active service on the Supreme Court</a>.” This is a longstanding proposal that has, at times, enjoyed bipartisan support. Former Texas Republican Gov. Rick Perry, for example, <a href="https://archive.thinkprogress.org/rick-perrys-term-limits-proposal-for-justices-isn-t-crazy-but-it-is-still-a-bad-idea-1aeeb3ab4556/">offered a similar proposal in a 2010 book</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hard to imagine such an idea garnering Republican support today. Republicans, after all, enjoy a supermajority on the current Supreme Court. Term limits endanger GOP control of the judiciary.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Constitution is widely understood to allow justices to serve for life. That said, there are some academic arguments that the Constitution’s language allowing justices to keep their “office” during “good behaviour” isn’t entirely airtight.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I’ve argued, for example, that future appointees to the Supreme Court could potentially be term-limited without a constitutional amendment because they could be appointed to a different “office” — one that only allows them to sit on the nation’s highest Court for 18 years <a href="https://www.vox.com/23186373/supreme-court-packing-roe-wade-voting-rights-jurisdiction-stripping">before they are rotated onto a lower court</a>. But even if this argument is correct, it won’t do anything about the Court’s current 6-3 Republican supermajority.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other scholars have made other arguments that could support imposing term limits with an ordinary act of Congress. Yale law professor Jack Balkin, for example, suggested that justices who have served more than 18 years could be <a href="https://balkin.blogspot.com/2020/10/dont-pack-court-regularize-appointments.html">stripped of most, but not all, of their authority to hear cases</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But let’s be realistic. If Congress does enact an ordinary law imposing term limits on the justices, the constitutionality of that law would ultimately be resolved by the Supreme Court. And unlike, say, <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2024/4/22/24133424/supreme-court-donald-trump-immunity-january-6-president">Donald Trump’s arguments that he was allowed to commit crimes while he was president</a>, the argument that justices serve for life actually has a strong basis in the Constitution’s text.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So the likelihood that the justices would allow themselves to be term-limited, at least without a constitutional amendment, is vanishingly small. The justices obviously have an interest in keeping their jobs. And the text of the Constitution is actually on their side.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">It’s not clear that the Supreme Court would allow an ethics reform law to take effect</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ethics reform would do nothing to make the Supreme Court less partisan or less ideological, but it could prevent Justice Thomas from <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/359206/supreme-court-incompetent-abortion-trump-immunity">taking millions of dollars in gifts</a> from Republican billionaires. It could also stop Justice Alito from going on <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/samuel-alito-luxury-fishing-trip-paul-singer-scotus-supreme-court">another $100,000 trip</a> paid for by a different GOP billionaire. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are worthy goals. Thomas’s and Alito’s corruption would not be tolerated in any other part of the federal government. Members of Congress and their staff, for example, are typically <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/11/14/23960027/supreme-court-new-ethics-code-clarence-thomas-unenforceable">forbidden from accepting gifts worth more than $50</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are, however, good reasons to doubt whether the justices would comply with a law prohibiting corrupt behavior. In a 2023 interview published in the Wall Street Journal, for example, Alito claimed that “<a href="https://apnews.com/article/supreme-court-ethics-alito-d98b0edf1340ff3ed66b345c5ddcf0dc">no provision in the Constitution gives [Congress] the authority to regulate the Supreme Court — period</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Alito is incorrect. Article III of the Constitution provides that the Court must exercise its authority to hear appeals from lower courts “<a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/constitution/articleiii">under such regulations as the Congress shall make</a>.” But the text of the Constitution also means little if a majority of the justices are willing to ignore it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus far, moreover, the Court has allowed Alito to get away with defying Congress. Last May, after Alito was <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/352380/supreme-court-alito-ethics-recusal-insurrection-flags">caught flying two flags</a> associated with the MAGA movement and efforts to overturn President Biden’s victory in the 2020 election (Alito has blamed the flags on his wife), several members of Congress <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/352380/supreme-court-alito-ethics-recusal-insurrection-flags">asked Alito to recuse</a> from cases involving Trump’s failed attempt to steal the election and the January 6 insurrection.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Alito’s recusal was arguably required by a federal statute, which provides that “any justice, judge, or magistrate judge of the United States <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/28/455">shall disqualify himself in any proceeding in which his impartiality might reasonably be questioned</a>.” But in his letter refusing to recuse, Alito rather pointedly ignored this statute, instead pointing to the Court’s non-binding internal ethics code, which states that “a justice is <a href="https://fixthecourt.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Alito-letter-to-House-5.29.24.pdf">presumed impartial and has an obligation to sit</a> unless disqualified,” to justify remaining on two cases.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Alito, in other words, seems to believe that only the Court gets to decide which ethical rules the justices must follow. And no justice stepped in when Alito thumbed his nose at the recusal statute enacted by Congress.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Which isn’t to say that Alito’s misbehavior is a reason for Congress to stay its hand. No government official should be allowed to accept lavish gifts from politically interested billionaires. And a federal statute could potentially open corrupt justices like Thomas or Alito to real consequences or even prosecution, even if that prosecution were eventually struck down by Thomas and Alito’s fellow justices.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the fact remains that ethics reform would be limited in scope. It would not stop the justices from implementing Republican Party policies from the bench. And it would likely lead to a protracted battle with justices who believe that ethical constraints are for people less important than them.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">So how can the Supreme Court be reformed?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One pathology of the Constitution is that it does not permit moderate judicial reforms such as term limits, but it absolutely permits highly disruptive solutions such as <a href="https://www.vox.com/23186373/supreme-court-packing-roe-wade-voting-rights-jurisdiction-stripping">adding more seats to the Supreme Court</a> and immediately filling them with Democrats. The Constitution permits Congress to decide how many justices there will be, and that number has varied from as few as five to as many as ten.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But court-packing is a dangerous proposal that threatens to <a href="https://democracyjournal.org/magazine/51/lets-think-about-court-packing-2/">delegitimize the entire federal judiciary</a>, including decisions that are far less reckless than the Court’s decision in <em>Trump</em>. And it could trigger massive resistance in red states that may not voluntarily comply with a decision that, say, reinstates abortion rights — at least if that decision comes from a packed Court. It could also set off a cycle of retribution where each party adds seats to the Supreme Court whenever it controls Congress and the presidency until the Court has dozens of justices, all of whom are political hacks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I’ve argued that court-packing is justified <a href="https://democracyjournal.org/magazine/51/lets-think-about-court-packing-2/">if the justices become an existential threat to US democracy</a> but it is a weapon that Congress should deploy only as a last resort.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Congress does have other ways to rein in a rogue judiciary. While the Constitution <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/constitution/articleiii">forbids Congress from reducing the justices’ salaries</a>, it could strip the Court of its staff and evict the justices from their government-provided office space. The Constitution also permits Congress to make “exceptions” to the Court’s jurisdiction, a provision that arguably allows it to <a href="https://www.vox.com/23186373/supreme-court-packing-roe-wade-voting-rights-jurisdiction-stripping">strip away the justices’ power to hear certain matters</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, a jurisdiction-stripping law could run into the same problems that could face a congressionally imposed ethics code. If the justices don’t want to be bound by it, they could simply strike it down.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Realistically, in other words, the most promising way to eradicate decisions like <em>Trump</em> and to fill the Court with justices who will not mimic Thomas or Alito’s corruption is the same way that Republicans eliminated decisions like <em>Roe</em> that they disapprove of. Democrats need to win elections while simultaneously <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/7/8/23784320/supreme-court-2022-term-affirmative-action-religion-voting-rights-abortion">organizing against Supreme Court decisions they don’t like</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Trump </em>was a 6-3 decision. It is two Supreme Court appointments away from becoming a bad memory of a more authoritarian era.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Men like Thomas and Alito, in other words, are likely to be defeated at the polls or not at all. If voters do not want to be ruled by these men, they can frustrate them by voting to elect Kamala Harris and a Democratic Congress in November. And then they can keep doing so until Republicans are in the minority on the Supreme Court.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Venezuela’s Maduro just tightened his grip on power. What comes next?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/363558/venezuela-maduro-elections-south-america-machado-gonzalez-chavez-oil" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363558</id>
			<updated>2024-07-29T22:48:58Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-29T21:20:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Economy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Energy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Fossil fuels" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Immigration" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years of turmoil, Venezuela held national elections on Sunday. Voters of various political affiliations hoped the contest would put an end to the political strife and economic difficulties that have gripped the country for a decade. But with most of the votes counted, both current Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and opposition candidate Edmundo González [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Incumbent President of Venezuela Nicolás Maduro shows his marked finger after casting his vote during the presidential elections at Escuela Ecológica Bolivariana Simón Rodríguez on July 28, 2024, in Fuerte Tiuna, Caracas, Venezuela. | Jesus Vargas/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Jesus Vargas/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2164043790.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Incumbent President of Venezuela Nicolás Maduro shows his marked finger after casting his vote during the presidential elections at Escuela Ecológica Bolivariana Simón Rodríguez on July 28, 2024, in Fuerte Tiuna, Caracas, Venezuela. | Jesus Vargas/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">After years of turmoil, Venezuela held national elections on Sunday. Voters of various political affiliations hoped the contest would put an end to the political strife and economic difficulties that have gripped the country for a decade. But with most of the votes counted, both current Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and opposition candidate Edmundo González have declared victory.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Maduro claimed 51 percent of the vote, with González earning 44 percent according to the national electoral commission. But González was quick to challenge those results, with his party claiming their exit polls <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/venezuelans-vote-highly-charged-election-amid-fraud-worries-2024-07-28/">showed the opposition winning</a> as much as 70 percent of the vote. Several countries, including the US, have cast doubt on Maduro’s victory given alleged irregularities, and the fact that international election observers were, in many cases, unable to perform their duties.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Maduro exercises significant control over the government, including the parliament and the judiciary. Though the election commission is nominally independent, the opposition claims that it acted on behalf of the Maduro government. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For now, González and his allies, as well as US officials, have asked for tabulated results from the elections authority and told supporters to remain calm. Small protests have broken out in Caracas, after the regime <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-29/venezuela-identifies-machado-as-suspect-in-electoral-sabotage?sref=qYiz2hd0">accused María Corina Machado and other opposition leaders of planning a cyber attack against the country’s electoral apparatus on Monday</a>. Venezuelans rose up against the Maduro government in 2014, 2017, and 2019. The opposition has urged followers to remain calm, but If protests break out again, it could mean further repression and violence.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Maduro’s victory shouldn’t come as a surprise</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sunday’s results mean Maduro seems headed for a third term in office —&nbsp;something that wasn’t possible before his predecessor and mentor Hugo Chávez amended the constitution in 2009 to remove presidential term limits.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Maduro seemed to backtrack on his authoritarian tendencies in October 2023, when his government agreed to hold free and competitive elections in exchange for further easing of US sanctions (Chevron has been permitted to operate in Venezuela since 2022).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this past January the supreme court — understood to be tightly aligned with Maduro and his followers, the Chavistas — <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/26/world/americas/venezuela-presidential-election-opposition.html">barred a popular opposition leader</a> (former lawmaker and longtime opposition activist Machado) from running for office for the next 15 years due to supposed financial irregularities from her time in parliament. Then, when a coalition of opposition factions tried to rally around another candidate, the government also prevented him from running, days before the registration deadline. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the last minute, the opposition coalesced around González, a retired diplomat, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/06/world/americas/edmundo-gonzalez-venezuela-elections.html">who was not widely known before the presidential race</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even with these maneuvers, polling indicated that González posed a credible threat to Maduro; González <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/venezuelans-vote-highly-charged-election-amid-fraud-worries-2024-07-28/#:~:text=Local%20firm%20Meganalisis%20predicted%20a,votes%20of%20the%20Venezuelan%20people.%22">was expected to earn about 65 percent of the vote</a>, according to multiple surveys.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If Maduro had both the capacity and the desire to totally shut this thing down, he would have done it by now — so he’s either lacking the will or the capacity,” <a href="https://www.cfr.org/expert/will-freeman">Will Freeman</a>, a fellow for Latin American studies at the Council on Foreign Relations, told Vox. “My guess is he’s lacking the capacity, there’s some kind of internal politics within Chavismo, some kind of internal constraints keeping him from taking more radical action like banning González or arresting María Corina Machado.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, while the opposition might have been a threat to Maduro’s rule, they weren’t necessarily looking to upend the political order. “I think they [were] being pretty realistic that they’re going to have to work with some of the Chavista-controlled institutions,” Freeman told Vox — institutions like the military, the judiciary, and the parliament. “Nowhere has the opposition said that they want to hold a constituent assembly and write a new constitution, which would be the only real way of making a clean break.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Maduro’s Chavismo, rather than being practiced as a consistent socialist ideology, is more about understanding the US as interlopers in Venezuelan politics — and the opposition as their proxy. That’s not totally without foundation, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/miami-us-news-ap-top-news-venezuela-south-america-79346b4e428676424c0e5669c80fc310">given a bizarre 2020 coup attempt</a> that involved Americans and the US’s extremely antagonistic stance towards Maduro, with the Trump administration <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/12/4/22152597/venezuela-election-juan-guaido-nicolas-maduro">supporting a rival who declared he was the true president</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the ruling class’s priorities are not advancing Venezuelans’ interests or autonomy. They are much more about maintaining control of the justice system and avoiding prison time under a new government — as well as keeping access to the wealth they accrue from government contracts and oil rents. Venezuela is the most oil-rich country in South America, which still drives the country’s economy despite heavy US sanctions on the industry and <a href="https://www.cfr.org/backgrounder/venezuela-crisis">a lack of investment and production under Maduro</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With six more years of Maduro seemingly in store, Venezuelans are likely in for more of the same: government corruption, severe inequality, mass poverty, and state repression and violence. Voters who put their hope in the opposition could take to the streets in protest — but as long as the military remains allied with Maduro, demonstrations are unlikely to provoke a change in leadership. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The international community is watching, and we will respond accordingly,” a senior US State Department official said during a press call Monday.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But what that response might look like is unclear. The US reimposed sanctions in April, after loosening them last October on the basis of Maduro’s concession to hold elections. And the Biden administration gave up Maduro ally Alex Saab in a prisoner swap deal <a href="https://apnews.com/article/venezuela-alex-saab-us-pardon-00682eda8afe81e189513e3e9cc926bd">earlier this year</a> — depriving the US of key leverage.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Venezuelans have suffered. The opposition offered hope.</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After Chávez was elected in 1998, poverty decreased due to socialist government programs, but his mismanagement of the oil sector — plus a variety of <a href="https://www.cfr.org/in-brief/do-us-sanctions-venezuela-work">US sanctions</a> — meant that, over time, there wasn’t enough money to support those programs. Chávez also seriously damaged democratic institutions, yet he was still highly popular among Venezuelans, especially those in the working class. Maduro, once Chávez’s bodyguard, continued and even accelerated Chávez’s authoritarian tendencies, without really being able to uphold the socialist measures that made his predecessor popular. Venezuela’s economy has spiraled particularly since he took office, resulting in a surge of migration out of the country — to neighboring Colombia and to the US. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For those who’ve stayed, life has increasingly spiraled into economic precarity; though inflation has cooled to 50 percent, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/latino/venezuela-inflation-cooled-voters-say-still-cant-make-ends-meet-rcna163210">it’s been as high as 130,000 percent in recent years</a>, due to a drop in oil prices and crushing economic sanctions imposed by the US. Even though inflation is improving, wages haven’t risen even to mitigate that 50 percent rate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ordinary people, unable to afford the basic necessities of life, hoped for a return to more prosperous times. And perhaps just as importantly, there was hope that some of the 7.7 million Venezuelans who have fled the country for better opportunities elsewhere or to escape repression, might return and help rebuild the country.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/programs/adrienne-arsht-latin-america-center/venezuela-working-group/">Now, that future seems unlikely</a>. Still, Venezuelans are heading out to the streets now, despite <a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2019/01/25/venezuela-arrests-killings-anti-government-protests?gad_source=1&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjw74e1BhBnEiwAbqOAjLfdOevplKNMsCyEZf_9mDRviFzEPVO3C8oeBVM-yBtAXTJwSD3J2BoCqVYQAvD_BwE">credible accusations of serious human rights violations</a> against the security forces, including extrajudicial killings, excessive use of force against protesters, politically motivated prosecutions, unlawful detentions, and torture.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kyndall Cunningham</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Who is Noah Lyles? For this sprinter, the Paris Olympics could be everything.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/olympics/361261/noah-lyles-explained-paris-olympics-track-field-netflix-sprinter" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=361261</id>
			<updated>2024-07-29T19:18:31Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-29T19:18:30Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Olympics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Sports" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[During every Olympic Games, lesser-known professional athletes are catapulted into household names overnight. Typically, they have to win medals. Other times, their personalities are enough to build their own fandoms. Heading into this summer’s Olympics in Paris, Noah Lyles expects to be recognized for both.&#160; If you don’t follow track and field, you may not [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A Black man wearing colorful athletic clothes, with a pair of sneakers hung around his neck, raises his arms in the air, forming peace signs with his fingers to hold up a large American flag. " data-caption="Noah Lyles celebrates after winning gold in the Men’s 200 meters at the World Athletics Championships on August 25, 2023." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1623507818.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Noah Lyles celebrates after winning gold in the Men’s 200 meters at the World Athletics Championships on August 25, 2023.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">During every Olympic Games, lesser-known professional athletes are catapulted into household names overnight. Typically, they have to win medals. Other times, their personalities are enough to build their own fandoms. Heading into this summer’s Olympics in Paris, Noah Lyles expects to be recognized for both.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you don’t follow track and field, you may not be familiar with Lyles — although his name could soon become inescapable. Already, the new Netflix docuseries <em>Sprint</em>, set around the <a href="https://www.nbcsports.com/olympics/news/track-and-field-world-championships-results-2023">2023 World Athletics Championships</a> in Budapest, has shone a bigger spotlight on him. The six-part series follows track and field’s brightest stars in the 100- and 200-meter sprints, including the fastest woman on Earth, Sha’Carri Richardson; Jamaican gold medalist Shericka Jackson; and British record-holder in the 100 and 200 meters, Zharnel Hughes. Despite this star power, the series’s main attraction has been Lyles, whose ambitions to outrun retired legend Usain Bolt have ruffled <a href="https://www.essentiallysports.com/us-sports-news-olympics-news-track-and-field-news-not-likable-at-all-noah-lyles-receives-heavy-criticism-from-twitters-track-field-community-for-netflixs-sprint-documentary/">some feathers</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many of Lyles’s soundbites in <em>Sprint</em> have been <a href="https://x.com/BadgyalTerryG/status/1811176867061260790">perceived</a> by <a href="https://x.com/willthefred/status/1811185176766038069">viewers</a> as <a href="https://x.com/pernillatweets1/status/1809892070334570956">arrogant</a>. In one scene, he says that to be a successful athlete, “you have to have the mindset of a God.” “I’m a true believer in that the moment isn’t bigger than me, the moment was made for me,” he says in another. Compare this attitude to Shericka Jackson’s. When asked by someone off-camera about claims that she’s the best in the sport, she refused to comment. Meanwhile, others seem confused about Lyles’s claim to “the fastest man in the world” title while Bolt is still living. Lyles maintained this stance at an Olympics news conference on July 26 after a Team USA video of the sprinter introducing himself as such went viral and drew more backlash. Lyles joked, “It’s always going to me” before stating that the title goes to “the Olympic champion and the world champion, which I am one of. And soon to be another one of.”<strong> </strong>Much like <a href="https://www.vogue.com/article/shacarri-richardson-august-2024-digital-cover-interview" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vogue.com/article/shacarri-richardson-august-2024-digital-cover-interview">Richardson</a>, his bravado, personal style, and penchant for trash-talking has given Americans someone to place their bets on at the upcoming Olympics. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Currently, Lyles holds the title of the fastest man in the world after winning the 100 and 200 meters — also known as the sprint double — at last year’s World Championships. (He ran the 100 meter in 9.83 seconds and the 200 meter in 19.52.) Altogether, he holds six world titles. He also earned the bronze medal in the 200 meter at the 2020 Olympics in Tokyo, a disappointing result that he says inspired his lofty goals at this year’s games. Not only does he want to beat Bolt’s record times, he plans to take home four gold medals.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether he can actually achieve this feat is anyone’s guess. Regardless, it seems like he’ll leave this year’s Olympics having achieved another career goal — having everyone talk about him.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Lyles may have his critics, but it’s all part of his mythmaking&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When we think of celebrity athletes whose fame extends beyond their sport, sprinters aren’t exactly the first people to come to mind. While Bolt has practically become synonymous with running, it’s fair to say the sport doesn’t offer its athletes the same level of visibility that the NBA, for example, offers even its most unassuming players. For instance, it took a <a href="https://www.vox.com/22565419/shacarri-richardson-olympics-marijuana-ban-war-on-drugs">drug-test scandal</a> — coming up positive for marijuana, not performance-enhancing drugs — and her subsequent suspension from the Tokyo Olympics for Richardson to become a national talking point and a currently beloved underdog.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Lyles wants this to change. “You have all these other athletes as stars, rockstars, popular wherever they go,” he says in the first episode of <em>Sprint</em>. “Track and field needs to be the same.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The 26-year-old has certainly been doing his part to bring attention to the sport, or maybe just to himself. While he doesn’t represent the most head-turning style in track and field right now — that may belong to Richardson with her occasionally flame-colored hair, numerous tattoos, and Flo Jo-esque acrylics — he frequently shows up to meets in snazzy, designer looks, like F1 champion Lewis Hamilton or one of a handful of NBA stars. Also in the spirit of ’80s icon Florence Griffith Joyner, he even enjoys a <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@nbcolympics/video/7344869517991922990">flashy manicure</a>. His accomplishments, thus far, have also gotten him a few magazine covers, most recently <a href="https://time.com/6991825/noah-lyles-olympics-2024-interview/">Time</a>, and an extremely lucrative contract for a track star with Adidas.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-tiktok wp-block-embed-tiktok"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@nbcolympics/video/7344869517991922990" data-video-id="7344869517991922990" data-embed-from="oembed"> <section> <a target="_blank" title="@nbcolympics" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@nbcolympics?refer=embed">@nbcolympics</a> <p>Noah Lyles paid tribute to his love of anime at the <a title="worldindoorchamps" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/worldindoorchamps?refer=embed">#WorldIndoorChamps</a> in a unique way. 🔥 <a title="anime" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/anime?refer=embed">#anime</a> <a title="trackandfield" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/trackandfield?refer=embed">#trackandfield</a> <a title="noahlyles" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/noahlyles?refer=embed">#noahlyles</a> <a title="nailart" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/nailart?refer=embed">#nailart</a> </p> <a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - NBC Olympics &#038; Paralympics" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-7344869620353862446?refer=embed">♬ original sound &#8211; NBC Olympics &#038; Paralympics</a> </section> </blockquote> 
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On social media, he delivers the same high-quality, fashion-forward content of a major influencer. (In <em>Sprint</em>, he refers to himself as an “artistic director.”) On his Instagram (<a href="https://www.instagram.com/nojo18/?hl=en">@nojo18</a>), where he’s approaching a million followers, you’re just as likely to see high-res photos of his pre-meet fits, posts with <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C8k6QGHI7qq/?hl=en&amp;img_index=1">Snoop Dogg</a>, and wardrobe selections inspired by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C8yKXDnRYer/?utm_source=ig_web_copy_link&amp;igsh=MzRlODBiNWFlZA==">his favorite anime</a> as you are content related to track. He also posts playful videos with his girlfriend, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9LDOhMvteN/?hl=en">fellow runner Junelle Bromfield</a>, the pair seeming to be a power couple in the making.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On his way to becoming America’s most beloved track star, though, Lyles has already rubbed some sports fans the wrong way. In an interview following his World Championship wins last year, he questioned why NBA Finals winners are referred to as “world champions.” “World champions of what?” he asked at a post-meet conference.“The United States?” Soon came a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/08/29/sport/noah-lyles-nba-backlash-spt-intl/index.html">pile of responses</a> from NBA players, including Kevin Durant, Aaron Gordon, and Devin Booker denouncing his comments. Drake, a supporter of the Toronto Raptors, even chimed in, poking fun at Lyles. Others, like Ghanaian sports journalist <a href="https://twitter.com/garyalsmith/status/1696087026154541245?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1696087026154541245%7Ctwgr%5E95a150cf499700a49eda9372113c58a1dfff9e17%7Ctwcon%5Es1_c10&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.npr.org%2F2023%2F08%2F28%2F1196396026%2Fnoah-lyles-nba-world-champions-basketball-drake-kevin-durant">Gary Al-Smith</a>, said Lyles was simply observing a larger problem of American exceptionalism in basketball.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ironically, Lyles has been accused of displaying the same superior, <a href="https://x.com/wiiissssss/status/1810777524630397169">culturally American</a> attitude in his own sport. On the fourth episode of <em>Sprint</em>, Lyles discussed the backlash he received after he posted his predicted times in the 100 meter and 200 meter at last year’s World Championships on Instagram, which he ultimately fell short of, despite taking home the gold. “What the heck does me saying my goal have to do with you?” he asks in a talking-head interview. It’s a good question, considering that it’s every athlete’s goal to perform at their best and destroy their opponents, whether or not they vocalize it as much as Lyles does. Fans’ negative responses to this sort of behavior have also confused Richardson, who says in the docuseries that there should be “more trash-talking” in the sport.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This poor reception online can at least be partially explained by a heated rivalry between American and Jamaican sprinters that intensified at the<a href="https://bleacherreport.com/articles/1269260-olympic-track-2012-breaking-down-team-usas-rivalry-with-jamaican-sprinters"> 2008 Beijing Olympics</a> where Bolt won the gold in the 100 meter and 200 meter, while achieving record times in both sprints. Jamaican track stars Shelly Ann-Frazer and Veronica Campbell-Brown also won the 100 meter and 200 meter, respectively. More than any athlete, though, Bolt has become a national symbol and icon in Jamaica, where track and field is the dominant sport. Announcing your plans to overthrow him, as Lyles has done, expectedly has some repercussions.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>All eyes are on Lyles at the Paris Olympics&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the US claims both the fastest man and woman in the world right now, one can assume an even larger number of American viewers will be tuned in to track this year, and there’s a lot at stake for Lyles’s reputation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, the Olympics have been fraught territory for the runner. In 2020, fans&nbsp;witnessed the emotional toll that training for and competing at the Olympics has had on Lyles, and how he handles disappointment when he’s fallen short of his goals.&nbsp;After landing in third place in the 200 meter in Tokyo, Lyles broke down during a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/olympics/2021/08/04/noah-lyles-bronze-olympics-depression/">post-meet interview</a> with the Washington Post. Tears started to fall when talking about his brother, Josephus Lyles, another professional sprinter, who failed to qualify for the Olympics that year. He spoke&nbsp;about his mental health and his journey with antidepressants leading up to the Olympics, as well as his experience marching alongside his brother in 2020’s Black Lives Matter protests, and the pressure he feels as a Black American athlete and a Black American man.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I knew there were a lot of people out there like me who were too scared to say something or start that journey,” he said. “I wanted them to know if you guys see me in a big light, I want you to know that it’s okay not to feel good and you can go out and talk to somebody … This is a serious issue.”</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2158934967_fdcc65.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Noah Lyles, pictured from below, wears a red track suit and a gold medal around his neck, stands beside a replica of the Eiffel tower." title="Noah Lyles, pictured from below, wears a red track suit and a gold medal around his neck, stands beside a replica of the Eiffel tower." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Noah Lyles celebrates with the gold medal after winning the men’s 100-meter final on day three of the 2024 US Olympic Team trials Track &amp; Field at Hayward Field on June 23, 2024, in Eugene, Oregon. | Patrick Smith/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Patrick Smith/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, following a double-sprint win at the World Championships, Lyles is displaying more confidence than ever. During a recent appearance on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CZRVEX2OG10"><em>The Tonight Show</em></a>, Lyles took the opportunity to tell the country what he planned to achieve in Paris. For one thing, he wants to beat Bolt, who holds the top two times in the 100-meter dash at 9.63 and 9.69 seconds. But he also wants to take home four gold medals. “It’s not just good enough to be faster than that,” Lyles told Fallon. “You also have to have the medals to go with it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition to taking home the gold in the 100 and 200 meter, Lyles wants to win in the 4&#215;100&nbsp;and 4&#215;400 meter relays. It wouldn’t be the first time an American sprinter nabbed four gold medals at one Olympics. For instance, Jesse Owens, Alvin Kraenzlein, and Carl Lewis have each won four. Their wins included the long jump, however; Lyles would be making history for those four sprints. Beyond any potential medals, the energy surrounding him and Richardson feels like a new era for American track stars, one defined by attitude and swagger. If Lyles can impress the world with his personality, he’ll at least have achieved half of his goals.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, July 26, 3:15 pm ET: </strong>This story was originally published on July 23 and has been updated to include Lyles’s most recent comments at an Olympics press conference.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The ugly calculus behind MAGA’s racist and sexist attacks on Harris]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362929/kamala-harris-maga-racism-sexism" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362929</id>
			<updated>2024-07-29T18:36:01Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-29T18:40:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In their opening wave of attacks on the Democrats’ likely presidential nominee, some Republicans are homing in on Vice President Kamala Harris’s race and gender — despite certain party leaders’ pleas for them to steer clear. Members of the religious right have dubbed her a “jezebel,” while other conservative activists suggested that she’s slept her [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris attends an NCAA championship teams celebration on the South Lawn of the White House on July 22, 2024, in Washington, DC. | Andrew Harnik/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Harnik/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2162425804.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris attends an NCAA championship teams celebration on the South Lawn of the White House on July 22, 2024, in Washington, DC. | Andrew Harnik/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/maga-republicans-racist-sexist-attacks-kamala-harris-1235065295/">In their opening wave of attacks</a> on the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc?utm_campaign=vox.social&amp;utm_content=voxdotcom&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social">Democrats’ likely presidential nominee</a>, some Republicans are homing in on Vice President Kamala Harris’s race and gender — despite certain <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-harris-attacks-johnson-hudson-76f8e90d24004e49449087787ac031a5">party leaders’ pleas for them to steer clear</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Members of the religious right have <a href="https://x.com/RightWingWatch/status/1816128743301316931">dubbed her a “jezebel,”</a> while other conservative activists <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/maga-world-pivots-to-debunked-kamala-harris-affair-story">suggested that she’s slept her way to the top</a> by citing past romantic relationships she’s had. GOP commentators have also echoed many of the same <a href="https://x.com/dallasnews/status/1816156401573548169">“birtherism” attacks</a> that were once used against former President Barack Obama, <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/old-falsehoods-about-citizenship-status-racial-identity-resurface-online-as-kamala-harris-becomes-likely-democratic-nominee/">falsely claiming that her candidacy isn’t viable</a> because her parents were Jamaican and Indian immigrants. (Harris is a US citizen who was born in California.) And they’ve tapped into common <a href="https://x.com/abbydphillip/status/1815592526516228286">GOP talking points about diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI)</a>, implying that Harris isn’t up for the job and was selected for VP solely because of her identity. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The media propped up this president, lied to the American people for three years, and then dumped him for our DEI vice president,” Rep. Tim Burchett (R-TN) <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/congress/gop-rep-tim-burchett-calls-kamala-harris-dei-president-rcna163096">said in a post on X</a>. (Burchett has since said he wishes he hadn’t said this, <a href="https://www.siriusxm.com/clips/clip/ffb27e63-5124-283a-3d3f-01aaa6447d7a/db65f5ac-7ee6-4ac8-a85e-0ec47c9fcef8">while adding that it’s the “truth.”</a>)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is a common thread in all these attacks: They take aim at Harris’s identity, rather than her agenda or experience.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And they come despite the fact that last week, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-harris-attacks-johnson-hudson-76f8e90d24004e49449087787ac031a5">House Speaker Mike Johnson</a> implored his party to focus their criticisms on policy and politics. “This is not personal with regard to <a href="https://apnews.com/article/harris-campaign-trump-indiana-sorority-031e3afa51f9ed42e0acd979e80019a8">Kamala Harris</a>, and her ethnicity or her gender have nothing to do with this whatsoever,” Johnson said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many of these remarks are simply hateful and examples of misogynoir, a compounded form of sexism and racism directed at Harris, a Black and South Asian woman.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there’s a sinister political calculus to them as well. Collectively, they aim to undercut Harris’s legitimacy as a candidate and are one prong of sweeping critiques <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/362186/supreme-court-biden-ballot-harris-lawsuits">Republicans have made about her eligibility</a>. Plus, they strive to leverage existing racism and sexism against Harris, activating voters who share those biases. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They hope to taint her with the suspicion of not having earned the positions she has achieved and harness the fears of those who resent seeing women and people of color in elite spaces,” says <a href="https://polisci.brown.edu/people/juliet-hooker">Juliet Hooker</a>, a Brown University political scientist and author of <a href="https://press.princeton.edu/books/hardcover/9780691243030/black-griefwhite-grievance"><em>Black Grief/White Grievance</em></a>, a book on race and politics. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The MAGA attacks try to question Harris’s legitimacy</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The throughline across the attacks against Harris is that they utilize aspects of her identity to argue that she isn’t suited for the job.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://x.com/wiczipedia/status/1815114243265708128">In a thread on X</a>, Nina Janckowicz, an expert on disinformation who’s published the book <em>How to Be a Woman Online </em>and who ran the short-lived Biden administration initiative on this issue, noted that there are consistent threads that have emerged in past statements, which she evaluated as part of a 2020 study.<strong> </strong>Other experts, like <a href="https://www.isdglobal.org/isd_team/melanie-smith/">Melanie Smith</a>, director of research for the Institute for Strategic Dialogue, have noted, too, that <a href="https://19thnews.org/2024/07/racist-misogynist-online-disinformation-is-being-used-against-kamala-harris-campaign/">women of color bear the brunt of this type of abuse</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These statements include implications that Harris is promiscuous and that she’s weaponized her sexuality to get to where she is — a misogynistic claim that’s often used against successful women to question whether they deserve the position that they’re in. Such attacks have manifested in conservative references to her past relationship with former San Francisco Mayor Willie Brown and repeated offensive taglines like “Joe and the Ho.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s often paired with questions about why Harris hasn’t had any biological children, and how that discredits her from being a leader due to claims that she’s not sufficiently invested in the country’s future. Beyond the fact that this line of attack is incredibly dismissive of the role of stepparents in America (Harris is the stepmother to a son and daughter), these sexist statements both superimpose traditional expectations on women and seek to undermine the VP by arguing that she doesn’t conform to those standards. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Racist narratives, including <a href="https://www.snopes.com/fact-check/harris-presidential-campaign-foreign-born-parents/">“birtherism” style attacks</a> that question Harris’s citizenship status, similarly seek to cast doubt on whether she’s eligible for office. It’s part of a long tradition of conservatives portraying nonwhite politicians as short of “real Americans” and therefore not fit to hold these positions.<strong> </strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And statements referring to Harris as a “DEI candidate” also intend to poke at her qualifications and ignore the significant experience she’d bring as a nominee.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those remarks stem from Biden’s statement committing to <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/03/15/biden-woman-vice-president-131309">selecting a woman as his number two</a> when he ran for office in 2020. He then <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/07/21/politics/joe-biden-four-black-women-vice-president/index.html">narrowed his final list of contenders to include four Black women</a>. Those choices were intended to improve representation and diversity at the highest levels of the party, which had never previously had a Black woman as president or vice president. Republicans, however, have seized on his decision to suggest that Harris was picked only for this reason, and not because she also <a href="https://variety.com/2024/politics/columns/dei-hire-kamala-harris-racist-1236081872/">brought significant qualifications</a> including decades of experience as a legislator and prosecutor. Such monikers are so demeaning because they suggest that people of color are undeserving of the roles they get, and “implies that [they] can only succeed when we are needed to fill quotas, and not because of merit, hard work or talent,” <a href="https://variety.com/2024/politics/columns/dei-hire-kamala-harris-racist-1236081872/">writes Variety’s Clayton Davis.</a> </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The misogynoir directed at Harris aims to suggest that she’s somehow illegitimate as a candidate, and signals to people who hold these biases that the GOP is a home for them. <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/06/30/politics/democratic-party-replacement-worries-joe-biden/index.html">Democrats have been guilty of such rhetoric toward Harris, too</a>, says Howard University political scientist <a href="https://profiles.howard.edu/keneshia-grant">Keneshia Grant</a>, who notes that calls from some <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6d9e121a-b493-4305-8016-f43fb381552f">party donors about selecting other presidential candidates than her</a> included variations of these same themes. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The recent MAGA onslaught, in particular, however, points to how focused Republicans have been on activating white, male grievances — and exploiting fears of women and people of color obtaining more power. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“White supremacy is above all a powerful organizing construct,” Grant told Vox. “The GOP repeatedly makes these claims that we can’t succeed together in a society, that one group absolutely has to be failing, and that one group is absolutely stealing from another.”&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>David Zipper</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Do bigger highways actually help reduce traffic?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/363013/wide-highways-climate-environment-pollution" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363013</id>
			<updated>2024-07-29T16:50:45Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-29T11:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Cities &amp; Urbanism" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Transportation" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Massachusetts to California, transportation departments are pursuing controversial plans to widen highways, expansions that are sure to compel more people to drive, thus increasing greenhouse gas emissions. Yet state and federal officials are, absurdly, justifying such projects by claiming that they can help fight climate change.&#160;&#160; Consider a report issued last fall, in which [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Aerial view of a very wide highway with looping interchanges" data-caption="Intersection of interstates 10 and 101 in Los Angeles." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-960093634.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Intersection of interstates 10 and 101 in Los Angeles.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">From <a href="https://usa.streetsblog.org/2023/11/13/highway-boondoggles-2023-a-cape-cod-canard">Massachusetts</a> to <a href="https://www.octa.net/programs-projects/projects/freeway-projects/i-405-improvements-project/overview/">California</a>, transportation departments are pursuing controversial plans to widen highways, expansions that are sure to compel more people to drive, thus increasing greenhouse gas emissions. Yet state and federal officials are, absurdly, justifying such projects by claiming that they can help fight climate change.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Consider a <a href="https://www.txdot.gov/content/dam/docs/tpp/texas-crs-2023-final.pdf">report issued last fall</a>, in which the Texas Department of Transportation (TxDOT) outlined its strategy to reduce pollution attributable to its road network, which a 2018 department report <a href="https://www.texasobserver.org/the-road-home/">found</a> generated 0.48 percent of all global — not national — CO2 emissions. Along with improving public transit, installing energy-efficient streetlights, and building electric vehicle charging stations, TxDOT suggests expanding highways.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to TxDOT’s report, projects like adding turnaround lanes on frontage roads will reduce emissions because they “[reduce] vehicle idling due to delay.” State DOTs from <a href="https://www.kuer.org/health-science-environment/2023-10-19/udot-expects-a-30-air-quality-bump-with-the-i-15-expansion-is-that-possible">Utah</a> to <a href="https://x.com/andrewsalzberg/status/1448312473703038983">New York</a> have likewise claimed that adding lanes to congested highways will lower emissions because fewer cars will be stuck in traffic.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Framing highway widening as a cure for climate change has allowed state DOTs to justify spending <a href="https://www.urban.org/policy-centers/cross-center-initiatives/state-and-local-finance-initiative/state-and-local-backgrounders/highway-and-road-expenditures">billions of dollars</a> in their ongoing war on gridlock. Businesses and residents alike complain about traffic, and widening the road is an easy way to placate them because it feels like progress. But decades of research — along with common sense — show that <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2z7o3sRxA5g">congestion will inevitably</a> return. New roadway lanes invite more cars, which generate more emissions, trapping us in a cycle of ever-increasing driving that only makes it harder to slow the increase in global temperatures.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>How could they possibly be saying bigger highways are good for the climate?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It&#8217;s worth pausing to consider how state DOTs justify conclusions that seem so far off-base. When considering potential highway projects, staff use computer models to forecast their impact on future traffic. These models <a href="https://t4america.org/community-connectors/what-they-mean/modeling/">project</a> that driving will grow at a rate reflecting past trends, often with a bump for population expansion. Any gas-powered car will create emissions when driven, but one stuck in gridlock will produce more since its journey takes longer.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How cars and highways shape America</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">One overlooked, often hidden factor has profound consequences for American life: cars. Read more of Vox’s deep reporting on how building a nation around driving has impacted our health, safety, and culture.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">• <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/354672/hochul-congestion-pricing-manhattan-diners-cars-transit" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/354672/hochul-congestion-pricing-manhattan-diners-cars-transit">Business owners are buying into a bogus myth about driving</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">• <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24139147/suvs-trucks-popularity-federal-policy-pollution" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24139147/suvs-trucks-popularity-federal-policy-pollution">The reckless policies that filled our streets with ridiculously large cars</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">• <a href="https://www.vox.com/23178764/florida-us19-deadliest-pedestrian-fatality-crisis" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/23178764/florida-us19-deadliest-pedestrian-fatality-crisis">The deadliest road in America</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">• <a href="https://www.vox.com/23784549/pedestrian-deaths-traffic-safety-fatalities-governors-association" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/23784549/pedestrian-deaths-traffic-safety-fatalities-governors-association">Why pedestrian deaths in the US are at a 40-year high</a></p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">State DOTs’ rigid assumptions about driving growth lead them to predict that traffic will eventually overwhelm the existing highway network. “Their thinking is, ‘if we don’t do anything, these cars are going to be sitting on this highway and not moving,’” Wes Marshall, a licensed traffic engineer, urban planning professor at the University of Colorado-Denver, and author of the new book <a href="https://islandpress.org/books/killed-traffic-engineer#desc"><em>Killed by a Traffic Engineer</em></a>, told me. “If that’s the baseline condition, any [expansion] is going to be better.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It&#8217;s a nice, tidy story — but it’s totally wrong.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These projections have a fatal blind spot: They fail to consider how humans respond to changing conditions like new vehicle lanes. When people see cars traveling freely over a recently expanded highway, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/01/06/us/widen-highways-traffic.html#:~:text=But%20while%20adding%20lanes%20can,along%20with%20it%20%E2%80%94%20often%20returns">they will recalibrate their travel decisions.</a> Some will choose to drive at rush hour when they would have otherwise driven at a non-peak time, taken public transit, or perhaps not traveled at all. When a roadway is widened, Marshall said, “You might have less congestion at first, but it quickly goes away.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such behavioral adjustments will continue until traffic is as thick as it was before, when the roadway was narrower. The only difference is now there will be more cars stuck in traffic, emitting even more pollution.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This phenomenon is known as <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-09-28/why-widening-highways-doesn-t-bring-traffic-relief">induced demand</a>. In his book <a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/9780262516129/fighting-traffic/"><em>Fighting Traffic,</em></a> historian Peter Norton notes that as early as the 1920s, a New York City engineer warned that new roadways “would be filled immediately by traffic which is now repressed because of congestion.” In the 1960s, the economist Anthony Downs wrote a seminal economics paper that codified the concept, which has been called the <a href="https://www.denverpost.com/2015/07/02/highway-widening-and-the-iron-law-of-congestion/">Iron Law of Congestion</a>. As one researcher <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tranpol.2018.12.006">put it</a>, “If you build it, they will drive.”</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="How highways make traffic worse" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2z7o3sRxA5g?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Induced demand is the bane of highway expansion projects. In Houston, average rush-hour journey times on the Katy Freeway <a href="https://cityobservatory.org/reducing-congestion-katy-didnt/">lengthened</a> by 15 to 20 minutes three years after TxDOT spent $2.8 billion widening it to as many as 26 lanes (including frontage lanes) in 2011. In England, researchers examining the expansion of the M1 motorway north of London found that “<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0965856423001696?via%3Dihub">traffic moved more slowly than before the scheme opened</a>.” The blunt conclusion of a 2011 <a href="https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/aer.101.6.2616">study</a> in the American Economic Review<em>: </em>Adding road lanes “is unlikely to relieve congestion.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If highway expansions don’t relieve gridlock, they cannot reduce emissions. To the contrary, they worsen them. As a <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trd.2012.06.008">2012 study</a> put it: “In the long run, capacity-based congestion improvements  … can reasonably be expected to increase emissions of CO2e, CO, and NOx&nbsp;through increased vehicle travel volume.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The total environmental toll of roadway expansions looks even worse when considering the second-order effects. Wider highways convince more people to drive, which may increase car purchases — and once people own a car, they tend to use it. Expanded roadways could compel some to <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25098858">relocate</a> to bigger homes that sprawl further from the urban core, elongating commutes. The billions of dollars that state DOTs are allocating toward a Sisyphean war on congestion could instead be spent on projects that can credibly reduce driving, such as mass transit and <a href="https://railyards.com/blog/5-incredible-examples-of-urban-infill">dense development</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“By adding more lanes to a highway, you’re inducing more car-oriented land uses,” Marshall said. “Zooming out, you’re creating a much more auto-oriented environment, not just for that one roadway, but for the whole area.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The faulty logic is hard to dislodge</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, the idea that wider highways are good for the planet remains widespread within state DOTs, including in blue states where officials cultivate an image of environmental stewardship. <a href="https://www.oregon.gov/odot/Projects/Project%20Documents/19071_I5_RQ_01.02_Environmental-Assessment.pdf">Oregon’s DOT used it</a> to justify its proposal to widen I-5 in Portland in 2019, and California’s transportation department continues to argue that widening I-80 between Sacramento and Davis <a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2024-06-20/the-road-to-the-capitol-is-a-test-case-for-freeway-expansions">would reduce emissions</a>, an assertion that environmental groups are <a href="https://fox40.com/news/local-news/northern-california-environmental-groups-suing-caltrans-interstate-80-ecos-sierra-club/">challenging in California state court</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be fair to state DOTs, this misconception is enshrined in federal policy. In the early 1990s, Congress created the Congestion Mitigation and Air Quality program, whose very name implies a linkage that does not necessarily exist. Its funding, now totaling <a href="https://www.fhwa.dot.gov/bipartisan-infrastructure-law/cmaq.cfm">$2.6 billion</a> per year, has gone toward climate-friendly investments in <a href="https://ddot.dc.gov/page/congestion-mitigation-and-air-quality-improvement-program-cmaq">bikeshare</a> in the District of Columbia and <a href="https://www.fhwa.dot.gov/environment/air_quality/cmaq/profile1.cfm">the MBTA Green Line in Boston</a> — but also toward <a href="https://www.usaspending.gov/award/ASST_NON_693JJ22430000Y400CA6053130_6925/">highway</a> <a href="https://www.usaspending.gov/award/ASST_NON_693JJ22330000Y400CA6207059_6925/">widening</a> projects such as <a href="https://dot.ca.gov/-/media/dot-media/programs/local-assistance/documents/cmaq/ffy2020/mar/lamtamarch2020.pdf">adding lanes to I-10</a> in Los Angeles County. (Over email, an FHWA spokesperson did not answer directly when asked whether the agency believes that roadway expansions reduce total emissions, responding that the agency “provide[s] an array of tools and programs to help mitigate congestion impacts.”)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To this day, federal policymakers struggle to acknowledge the linkages between highway construction and pollution. <a href="https://www.codot.gov/news/2024/may/cdot-celebrates-start-of-i25-north-express-lanes-mead-to-berthoud">Speaking in May</a> at an event celebrating new lanes being added to I-25 north of Denver, FHWA administrator Shailen Bhatt said, “By eliminating the bottleneck between Mead and Berthoud  … we’re advancing safety, trip reliability, freight efficiency, and reducing emissions.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Clear thinking on such matters is difficult due to powerful political pressures behind highway construction, which generates thousands of jobs and billions of dollars in business for contracting firms. In May, the head of a California alliance of labor and business groups <a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2024-06-20/the-road-to-the-capitol-is-a-test-case-for-freeway-expansions">declared</a> it a “false equivalency” to claim “we cannot meet our climate change goals and not continue to invest in our roads, bridges and highways.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In reality, striving to reduce emissions while expanding roadways is like trying to become healthier while continuing to gorge on junk food.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The good news is that a small but growing number of state legislatures recognize the trade-off between environmental progress and roadway growth. <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/31/headway/highways-colorado-transportation.html">Colorado</a> and <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/other-nonprofit-media/2024/06/minnesota-highway-projects-will-need-to-consider-climate-impacts-in-planning/">Minnesota</a>, for instance, recently passed bills requiring state DOTs to minimize the climate impact of their investments. New projects that enable drivers to take shorter trips — or better yet, travel by riding transit or a bike instead of driving a car — ought to be able to easily pass muster, but highway widenings should not. In Colorado, several planned expansions have already been canceled because of the new rules. <a href="https://mgaleg.maryland.gov/mgawebsite/Legislation/Details/HB0836?ys=2024RS">Maryland</a> is considering similar legislation demanding “methods for evaluating induced demand in assessments that measure greenhouse gas emissions.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Marshall told me that he doesn’t know whether transportation officials claiming that roadway projects will curtail emissions are simply parroting what their faulty models tell them or whether they are knowingly spreading misinformation in order to keep building the projects that business and labor groups demand. Flawed though their models are, state DOTs have a political incentive to keep using them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless, the facts are clear: Rather than mitigating climate change, highway expansions exacerbate it. “There’s enough research out there showing again and again that it doesn’t work,” Marshall said. “You would think they would know better.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Amanda Lewellyn</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s 2024’s “song of the summer”?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/363120/charli-xcx-chappell-roan-song-summer" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363120</id>
			<updated>2024-07-25T21:43:07Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-29T11:15:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Music" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained newsletter" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few weekends ago, I had the distinct pleasure of introducing my friends’ parents to Chappell Roan.&#160; It started when I had a few bars of “Good Luck, Babe” stuck in my head and couldn’t stop humming it. The next thing I knew, we were all learning the “HOT TO GO” dance. And by the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A singer in exaggerated makeup and a minidress onstage, pointing." data-caption="Chappell Roan performs during 2024 Bonnaroo Music &amp; Arts Festival on June 16, 2024, in Manchester, Tennessee." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2157868302.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Chappell Roan performs during 2024 Bonnaroo Music &amp; Arts Festival on June 16, 2024, in Manchester, Tennessee.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">A few weekends ago, I had the distinct pleasure of introducing my friends’ parents to <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/358464/chappell-roan-rise-and-fall">Chappell Roan</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It started when I had a few bars of “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1RKqOmSkGgM">Good Luck, Babe</a>” stuck in my head and couldn’t stop humming it. The next thing I knew, we were all learning the “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xaPNR-_Cfn0">HOT TO GO</a>” dance. And by the end of the weekend, we were sitting on their deck in upstate New York, listening to lyrics about a “sexually explicit kind of love affair” like it was the most normal dinner music in the world.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now that I’m back home in Brooklyn, I’ve got a new favorite reference: You can’t walk a block without hearing someone bumpin’<em> </em>one of Charli xcx’s instant club classics (from her album <em>Brat</em>) — even more so now that Kamala Harris’s presidential campaign has <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/362300/kamala-harris-meme-brat-summer">embraced the internet’s delighted moves tying her to brat<em> </em>summer</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And now’s as good a time as any to mention that for weeks earlier this year, I was perpetually working laaaaate (cuz I’m a singerrrrr). That’s that me, “<a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2024/5/14/24155699/sabrina-carpenter-espresso-career-olivia-rodrigo-explained">Espresso</a>.”&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="Sabrina Carpenter - Espresso (Official Video)" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eVli-tstM5E?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These artists —&nbsp;Chappell Roan, Charli xcx, “Espresso”’s Sabrina Carpenter — have ruled my playlists this summer. My friends are playing their songs at parties. My social media feeds are overwhelmed with news and memes about them. They’re inescapable.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So they must all be contenders for 2024’s song of the summer, right? … Right?!&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Wrong. Take a look at the top of the <a href="https://www.billboard.com/charts/summer-songs/">Billboard Songs of the Summer chart</a> right now and you’ll find that the Top 10 is chaos. Post Malone and Morgan Wallen occupy the top spot with their song “I Had Some Help,” a song that I really don’t think I could hum for you, even if pressed. Someone that I have literally never heard of, Tommy Richman, is in the fourth spot. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what gives? How are these no-names beating out the biggest pop girlies for song of the summer? And if I barely recognize the most popular song in America right now, is there even such a thing as a song of the summer anymore?&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="Chappell Roan - Good Luck, Babe! (Official Lyric Video)" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1RKqOmSkGgM?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is the song of the summer? </strong>&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the absence of an agreed-upon definition, it’s helpful to take a look at the history of the song of the summer. The concept goes back further than you might expect — all the way to the 19th century, when tunes mostly circulated via sheet music.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Phil Edwards <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/6/17/8796289/summer-song-history">wrote for Vox</a> a few years ago, sales were slow-going. It could take decades for early bops like 1826’s “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9YgtCfE-DMk">The Old Oaken Bucket</a>” to permeate across the country.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As we rolled into the next century, new technologies like the radio helped popularize songs much more widely&nbsp;and quickly. But while songs could become popular in the summertime, there was still no official song of the summer.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s not like people were walking around in 1925 and saying, ‘You think that’s the summer song this year?’” music critic and author David Hajdu <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/06/20/entertainment/song-of-the-summer-year-history-cec/index.html">told CNN</a>. “But the phenomenon was beginning to happen.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When Billboard dropped <a href="https://www.billboard.com/lists/songs-of-summer-chart-history/1958/">its first Hot 100 chart</a> in 1958 with Domenico Modugno’s Italian ballad <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7wWiC0e3b2I">“Nel Blu di Pinto de Blu (Volaré)”</a> at the top, it gave us a metric to define the song of the summer, but it certainly didn’t invent the concept. For a while, the Hot 100 seemed to <a href="https://www.billboard.com/lists/songs-of-summer-chart-history/1961/">correctly identify</a> the most omnipresent music of the season: 1964, The Supremes’ “Where Did Our Love Go?”; 1976, “Don’t Go Breaking My Heart” by Elton John and Kiki Dee; 1982, Survivor’s “Eye of the Tiger.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But that changes when we get into the 2000s. The aughts begin with songs so recognizable that we felt we didn’t even need to play them on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/0dZ0xxAOdgF71GnpXWYPf9?si=720ae70fbdc84895">our recent episode</a> of <em>Today, Explained</em>: “Crazy in Love.” “Umbrella.” “Call Me Maybe.” “Despacito.” By the 2020s, things start to get wacky: I don’t know about you, but DaBaby’s “Rockstar” certainly didn’t define 2020 for me. Last year, I didn’t even hear <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/country-star-morgan-wallen-caught-video-using-n-word-label-n1256630">n-word user</a> Morgan Wallen’s “Last Night” so how could it have been the song of the summer?&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="Shaboozey - A Bar Song (Tipsy) [Official Visualizer]" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/t7bQwwqW-Hc?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">So do we have a song of the summer anymore, or what?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You might be shocked to learn that music listening has changed since Billboard first started naming summer hits. We are now in what scientists have tentatively begun calling the “streaming era,” where a <a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2023/02/world-consume-music-infographic/#:~:text=As%20of%202022%2C%20paid%20subscription,fourth%20of%20main%20platform%20share.&amp;text=Short%2Dform%20video%20platforms%20like%20TikTok%2C%20with%20an%208%25,are%20a%20fast%2Dgrowing%20medium.">huge chunk of listening</a> takes place on platforms like YouTube, Spotify, and Apple Music&nbsp;in addition to the radio.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The change has diminished radio DJs and music executives’ ability to name hits, and it has shifted power to the listeners,&nbsp;many of whom are influenced by Spotify’s personalized <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2024-01-04/spotify-s-editorial-playlists-are-losing-influence-amid-ai-expansion?sref=qYiz2hd0">recommendation algorithms</a>, which the company has prioritized at least since 2020.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since Billboard’s Hot 100 chart takes streaming into account, musicologist and <em>Switched on Pop</em> co-host Charlie Harding argues that the charts are more accurate now.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“In the era of mass media monoculture, we just weren’t as talented at capturing people&#8217;s collective listening,” Harding said on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/0dZ0xxAOdgF71GnpXWYPf9?si=720ae70fbdc84895"><em>Today, Explained</em></a><em>. </em>“Sure, maybe they were being broadcast more of the same stuff, but you didn&#8217;t know what people were playing back to back on their boombox. Now we can actually count exactly what people are listening to on streaming services.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The streaming era has <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/show/how-streaming-platforms-are-changing-the-way-we-listen-to-music">allowed</a> new and different kinds of artists to enter the charts organically, building fandoms via nontraditional pathways. Right now, Harding points out, the top of the charts reflects all sorts of different communities of listening: a Black country artist in Shaboozey, pop princess Sabrina Carpenter, Big Three rapper Kendrick Lamar, alternative indie slow-burn Hozier …&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="Hozier - Too Sweet (Official Video)" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NTpbbQUBbuo?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But music listening is,&nbsp;to some extent, a zero-sum game. As we stream our way into our niche listening rabbit holes, the very biggest artists have started to see their streams decrease, too. All this creates a world in which you might not recognize the Billboard-ordained song of the summer.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But maybe that doesn’t matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Whatever your community is listening to, that&#8217;s going to be your song of summer,” Harding told us. “I think you shouldn&#8217;t stress about what everyone is listening to. I think you should pay attention to what your friends and community are connecting with.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story originally appeared in&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Today, Explained</a></em></strong><em>, Vox’s flagship daily newsletter.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/today-explained-newsletter-signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here for future editions</a></em></strong><em>.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Amy Westervelt</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Oil companies sold the public on a fake climate solution — and swindled taxpayers out of billions]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/363076/climate-change-solution-shell-exxon-mobil-carbon-capture" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363076</id>
			<updated>2024-07-30T03:06:35Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-29T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Energy" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This story was published in partnership with Drilled, a global multimedia reporting project focused on climate accountability, and was supported by the Pulitzer Center. This spring, Democrats wrapped up a nearly three-year investigation into the fossil fuel industry’s role in climate disinformation, and asked the Department of Justice to pick up where they left off. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A protester from the Extinction Rebellion climate action group wears an Exxon Mobil mask." data-caption="A protester from the Extinction Rebellion climate action group wears an ExxonMobil mask outside the Africa Energies Summit in May 2024 in London." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2153021385.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A protester from the Extinction Rebellion climate action group wears an ExxonMobil mask outside the Africa Energies Summit in May 2024 in London.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story was published in partnership with </em>Drilled<em>, a global multimedia reporting project focused on climate accountability, and was supported by the </em><a href="https://pulitzercenter.org/projects/drilled-denial-delay"><em>Pulitzer Center</em></a><em>.</em></p>

<p class="has-drop-cap has-text-align-none">This spring, Democrats wrapped up a nearly three-year <a href="https://drilled.media/news/may-disinformation-hearing">investigation</a> into the fossil fuel industry’s role in climate disinformation, and asked the Department of Justice to pick up where they left off. In House and Senate Democrats’ <a href="https://www.budget.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/fossil_fuel_report1.pdf">final report</a> and hearing, investigators concluded that major oil companies had not only misled the public on climate change for decades, but also were continuing to misinform them about the industry’s preferred climate “solutions”— particularly biofuels and carbon capture.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sen. Sheldon Whitehouse (D-RI) and Rep. Jamie Raskin (D-MD), who spearheaded the investigation, also accused oil companies of “obstructing”&nbsp; the investigation, submitting few documents, and redacting much of what they did send. One ExxonMobil employee who spoke with Drilled and Vox under condition of anonymity for fear of retaliation described what the company sent as “a truly random assortment of unimportant documents.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there was at least one notable exception in the form of a report detailing the company’s projections for the future of carbon capture technology.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’ve <a href="https://drilled.media/news/drilled-mediagreenwashing">read the New York Times recently</a>, or seen <a href="https://vimeo.com/985252161?share=copy">this ad</a> on Politico’s website or heard it on one of its podcasts,<strong><em> </em></strong>or listened to <a href="https://vimeo.com/985310172?share=copy">the <em>Planet Money</em> podcast</a>, you may have noticed the industry’s relentlessly positive marketing of carbon capture, which aims to collect and store CO2 emissions from power plants and industrial and fossil fuel extraction facilities, so they don’t add to global warming. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) has said carbon capture might be necessary to reduce the emissions of certain “hard to abate” sectors like steel, concrete, and some chemical manufacturing, but noted that in the best-case scenario, with carbon capture technology working flawlessly and deployed at large scale, it could only account for a little <a href="https://ieefa.org/sites/default/files/2024-02/fact-sheet-CCS-ADR.pdf">over 2 percent</a> of <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/sixth-assessment-report-cycle/">global carbon emissions reductions</a> by 2030.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That hasn’t stopped major oil companies <a href="https://www.shell.com/what-we-do/carbon-capture-and-storage.html#iframe=L3dlYmFwcHMvQ0NTX0dsb2JlLw:~:text=At%20Shell%2C%20we%20believe%20that%20CCS%20will%20be%20essential%20for%20helping%20society%20to%20achieve%20net%2Dzero%20emissions">from claiming</a> that carbon capture and storage “will be essential for helping society achieve net-zero emissions,” that they are delivering “carbon capture for American industry,” <strong> </strong>working on reducing emissions in their own businesses (also referred to as “carbon intensity”), and delivering <a href="https://vimeo.com/946232118?share=copy">“heavy industry with low emissions.”</a> But internal documents obtained during the federal investigation, as well as information that industry whistleblowers shared with Drilled and Vox, reveal an industry that is decidedly more realistic about the emissions-reduction potential of carbon capture and storage technology, or CCS, than it presents publicly.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1702525023.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.8583435611416,100,92.283312877717" alt="Under a blue sky and at the end of a long asphalt road stand many power plant towers and walkways in a large energy complex." title="Under a blue sky and at the end of a long asphalt road stand many power plant towers and walkways in a large energy complex." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Coal-burning power plants stand behind the Petra Nova carbon capture plant at NRG Energy’s power plant in 2022 near Houston, Texas. | Elizabeth Conley/Houston Chronicle via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Elizabeth Conley/Houston Chronicle via Getty Images" />
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Companies touted the potential of CCS publicly, as they downplayed the technology internally</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2018, the oil and gas company Shell released an <a href="https://www.shell.com/news-and-insights/scenarios/what-are-the-previous-shell-scenarios/_jcr_content/root/main/section_1789847828/promo_copy_142460259_336956354/links/item0.stream/1696514061120/eca19f7fc0d20adbe830d3b0b27bcc9ef72198f5/shell-scenario-sky.pdf">updated energy scenario</a>, a forecast that served as a standard for the rest of the oil industry, in which it laid out what <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/energy-environment/wp/2018/03/26/shell-yes-that-shell-just-outlined-a-radical-scenario-for-what-it-would-take-to-halt-climate-change/">the Washington Post called</a> a “radical” new approach on climate. Beginning in 1965, Shell pioneered the now-common practice of “scenario planning” for oil companies: mapping out what the industry and the world are likely to look like in the future; other oil companies will still often compare their scenarios to Shell’s.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Exxon’s own internal <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fo/sluokjrnefm0jxiynra8v/ACS7P28PAx3PIgTJUbTle5s/Exxon%20Documents/EM-HCOR3-00005564.pdf?rlkey=9a3l8q3nn08fbm48xqagvr66b&amp;e=1&amp;dl=0">2018 scenario comparison</a> was included in the most recent batch of documents handed over to Senate and House investigators. In it, ExxonMobil compared its future projections with Shell’s rosiest forecast for the energy transition. Buried in a chart in that projection is ExxonMobil’s belief about the global potential for CCS.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/hcor-climate-chart.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,5.4416843043333,100,89.116631391333" alt="A chart on page six of ExxonMobil scenario documents obtained by a congressional subpoena." title="A chart on page six of ExxonMobil scenario documents obtained by a congressional subpoena." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A scenario included in an internal report by Shell and ExxonMobil detailing the projected emissions from CCS facilities. | These documents were originally obtained by congressional subpoena to a House committee and have been reproduced here by Drilled and Vox.&lt;br&gt;" data-portal-copyright="These documents were originally obtained by congressional subpoena to a House committee and have been reproduced here by Drilled and Vox.&lt;br&gt;" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Even without the massive stamp on this page marking it as part of <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/24712572-em-hcor3-00005564">a set of documents obtained</a> by congressional subpoena, these graphs would be difficult to read. The one above compares the projected number of CCS units in Shell’s scenario versus the number projected by ExxonMobil, while the graph on the right compares the two companies’ forecasts for future CO2 emissions.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Shell’s optimistic projection envisions 10,000 large-scale CCS facilities operational by 2070, with more than 2,500 facilities by 2050, Exxon predicts somewhere between 250 and 500 facilities by 2050. Elsewhere in the scenario, Exxon also envisions that “global scale is limited” for CCS and hydrogen tech by 2050.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Exxon’s past projections were much more in line with what critics of CCS have been saying for years. The IPCC, for example, has said that even if realized at its full announced potential, CCS would only account for about<a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/sixth-assessment-report-cycle/"> 2.4 percent of the world’s carbon mitigation</a> by 2030. In its <a href="https://ieefa.org/ccs">fact sheet on CCS</a>, the Institute for Energy Economics and Financial Analysis (IEEFA), a nonprofit, nonpartisan think tank in Ohio that produces market-based research on the energy transition, states: “It’s worth noting that not one single CCS project has ever reached its target CO2 capture rate.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Stanford University researcher <a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/mark-jacobson">Mark Jacobson</a> said that because it also requires energy and materials to function, CCS attached to a fossil-fueled power plant is still worse for the climate than replacing fossil energy with renewables. “They actually increase carbon dioxide emissions by doing this, in addition to increasing air pollution,” he said, referencing <a href="https://news.stanford.edu/stories/2019/10/study-casts-doubt-carbon-capture">a study he conducted in 2019 </a>quantifying the lifecycle CO2 emissions of various carbon capture scenarios. Even when CCS is powered by wind, Jacobson said it’s not worth doing, from a climate perspective. “If you just used wind to replace coal in the first place, you’d get a higher reduction in CO2 emissions,” he said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And oil giants themselves have been hedging on the technology for years, despite marketing its potential. When the Environmental Protection Agency proposed requiring that power plants install CCS in its rules for power plants, for example, both fossil fuel companies and <a href="https://www.eei.org//-/media/Project/EEI/Documents/Resources-and-Media/TFB/EEIComments_111Rules_FINAL_080823.pdf">utilities</a> expressed far less faith in the technology in their public comments on the rule than they have in their ads about carbon capture. In Exxon’s public comment, the company <a href="https://downloads.regulations.gov/EPA-HQ-OAR-2023-0072-0641/attachment_1.pdf">encouraged the agency</a> to reduce its requirements around capture efficiency from 95 percent to 75 percent, which is more in line with the actual performance of existing CCS projects.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Last year, when the first EPA power plant rule was released, it was going to mandate either using CCS on a power plant in order to reduce greenhouse gas emissions or to take some action that would be equivalent to adding CCS, and the response from industry was ‘Hey, the tech is really not proven,’” said <a href="https://ieefa.org/people/david-schlissel">David Schlissel</a>, director of resource planning analysis for IEEFA. “Many, many comments from oil companies and utilities, in response to both the initial EPA rule and the current one, were saying this tech really doesn’t work.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Exxon’s low internal projections for CCS back in 2018 map to the company’s own experience with the technology, too. To date, the only “successful” carbon capture project Exxon points to in its materials is its <a href="https://sequestration.mit.edu/tools/projects/la_barge.html">LaBarge Shute Creek gas facility</a> in Wyoming. The Shute Creek facility is often referenced by the industry in general as a successful large and longstanding CCS project. On paper, LaBarge is responsible for <a href="https://ieefa.org/articles/shute-creek-worlds-largest-carbon-capture-facility-sells-co2-oil-production-vents-unsold">around 40 percent</a> of the total carbon emissions ever captured in the world. But the details tell a different story.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1252158353.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="A woman walking in a London city street holds a large sign reading “ExxonMobil Planet Killers, BP, Shell Oil" title="A woman walking in a London city street holds a large sign reading “ExxonMobil Planet Killers, BP, Shell Oil" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Climate activists march on the final day of four days of climate protest activities organized by Extinction Rebellion in London, in April 2023. | Mark Kerrison/In Pictures via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Mark Kerrison/In Pictures via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">According to Exxon’s own disclosures and <a href="https://ieefa.org/articles/shute-creek-worlds-largest-carbon-capture-facility-sells-co2-oil-production-vents-unsold">an analysis</a> conducted by IEEFA in 2022, only around 3 percent of the carbon captured there (roughly 6 million tonnes) has been permanently sequestered underground. Of the rest of the 240 million tonnes of carbon emitted over the facility’s first 35 years in operation, half has been sold to various oilfield operators for enhanced oil recovery, or EOR — a process by which oil companies inject carbon underground to get more oil out — and approximately 120 million tonnes <a href="https://ieefa.org/articles/shute-creek-worlds-largest-carbon-capture-facility-sells-co2-oil-production-vents-unsold">has been vented</a> into the atmosphere.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When asked to comment for this story about its 2018 scenario plan and overall record on CCS, ExxonMobil sent the following statement by email: “False narratives that downplay our CCS efforts deliberately fail to recognize the strides we’re making in our Low Carbon Solutions business. Referencing one possible scenario from over six years ago does not represent our business outlook. We continuously evaluate our business plan based on market conditions.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Exxon pointed to its public-facing <a href="https://corporate.exxonmobil.com/-/media/global/files/global-outlook/2023/2023-global-outlook-executive-summary.pdf">2023 Global Outlook</a> as its most current thinking on the potential of carbon capture. That report states: “Carbon capture and storage<strong> </strong>is a proven and safe technology that reduces emissions from manufacturing and power generation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But in commenting on its scenario plan, Exxon’s spokesperson spoke only to “market conditions” and its shifting “business outlook,” not to the technology itself. The business outlook and market conditions for CCS have changed because of an increased tax credit for CCS that oil companies, including Exxon, lobbied for — and, according to <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/24832210-bpa_hcor_00156030">the documents</a> subpoenaed by federal investigators, heavily influenced — and that Sen. Joe Manchin (D-WV) <a href="https://www.energy.senate.gov/2021/3/manchin-introduces-carbon-capture-legislation">introduced in 2021</a> as part of the negotiations that saw the Biden administration’s proposed “Build Back Better” legislation morph into the Inflation Reduction Act. That’s thanks to major changes to the CCS tax credit known as 45Q, which started out in 2008 paying $10 for every metric ton of carbon sequestered and now pays as much as $85 per metric ton, and up to $60 per ton stored and then used for EOR. Suddenly, <a href="https://www.upstreamonline.com/energy-transition/exxonmobil-sees-enhanced-oil-recovery-expertise-as-learning-path-for-climate-action/2-1-1274460">EOR is CCS</a> and CCS is profitable.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There is no cap on 45Q and stored emissions are entirely self-reported,” <a href="https://www.sehn.org/carolynstaff">Carolyn Raffensperger</a>, executive director of the Science and Environmental Health Network, said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The credit nominally requires companies to verify their claims, but aside from some <a href="https://www.epa.gov/ghgreporting/subpart-rr-geologic-sequestration-carbon-dioxide">specific requirements</a> to ensure condensed CO2 doesn’t wind up in groundwater, the EPA is not verifying how much carbon is actually sequestered by these projects.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When asked about verification of carbon stored under the 45Q tax credit, the EPA told Drilled and Vox that it “does not implement the Section 45Q tax credit program and is not privy to taxpayer data,” and that questions about how tax claims are verified should be directed to the IRS. The IRS confirmed that it ensures companies claiming the credit have filed paperwork outlining their claims, including a lifecycle analysis, but that it does not have the scientific or technical expertise to verify that the amount of carbon claimed is actually being permanently sequestered.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“What the IPCC actually said in its mitigation report was that carbon capture might be necessary for hard-to-abate industries, but that it’s one of the most expensive options and it only equates to small emissions reductions,” said <a href="https://pipelinefighters.org/expert/paul-blackburn/">Paul Blackburn</a>, an environmental lawyer and advisor to the Bold Alliance, a nonprofit network of frontline communities focused on protecting land and water. “So we’re doing the most expensive, least applicable thing first rather than cheapest, easiest things first, at great expense to taxpayers and with no analysis of net climate benefit.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But even before the creation of a remarkably generous tax credit, and despite their own internal projections or challenges with the technology, major oil companies painted a rosy picture of CCS. Emails obtained by federal investigators show that Shell pulled together an <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/24799230-bpa_hcor_00126551">“Alliance of Champions”</a> to promote CCS, and BP worked with the <a href="https://www.ogci.com/">Oil and Gas Climate Initiative</a> to develop what it called <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/24799274-bpa_hcor_00268188">“CCS enabling narratives,”</a> while Exxon began promoting itself as a leader in carbon capture.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the last five years, Exxon has produced multiple pro-CCS <a href="https://corporate.exxonmobil.com/-/media/Global/Files/carbon-capture-and-storage/CCS-Infographic.pdf">brochures</a> and <a href="https://vimeo.com/945012799?share=copy">ads</a>, comparing the carbon capture potential at industrial plants to the carbon sequestration of <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/24661711-em-hcor3-00521304">actual plants and trees</a>. An <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/24661702-em-hcor3-00524824">NPR sponsorship from 2018, for example</a>, describes ExxonMobil as “the company that believes that carbon capture technologies are critical for lowering global CO2 emissions.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The company even worked on a series of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XkCeA14jqt8">kids’ videos touting CCS</a>. In one <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/24680219-em-hcor3-00758838">subpoenaed email</a>, Exxon executives asked the creative team working on the kids’ series to steer away from the idea that carbon is bad or that carbon capture is difficult. “De-emphasize concept that catching carbon is difficult or hard,” the feedback reads.&nbsp;</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XkCeA14jqt8?si=o_RfUgeQmFtvuhE4" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet that is precisely the company’s experience with CCS, according to several current and former Exxon staffers who agreed to speak with Drilled and Vox on condition of anonymity for fear of retaliation. Some of them were involved in the early days of researching CCS as a potential climate solution at Exxon, which they said only began in earnest in 2018, the same year that the 45Q tax credit first increased (from $10 for every metric ton of sequestered carbon to about $50 per metric ton).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The company’s experience before then, the sources said, was entirely focused on enhanced oil recovery — the process of injecting CO2 into a separate well to increase enough pressure in a reservoir to push additional oil out of a production well. While enhanced oil recovery, or EOR, does sequester carbon — some of it stays underground after it&#8217;s been injected — <a href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/es902006h">experts say</a> the process could release 40 percent of the CO2 back into the air, and the oil it helps to get out of the ground also generates CO2 emissions when it’s burned.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Exxon is not the only one that embraced EOR for years before repositioning it as a climate solution. The industry has known for decades that compressed carbon works really well to vacuum up any remaining oil from porous rock, but it’s expensive to store and transport carbon. The industry’s embrace of natural gas helped drive down costs a bit, because while the finished product might be “low carbon,” gas often comes out of the ground bringing quite a bit of CO2 with it. That CO2 needs to be stripped out to make natural gas, a process called “gas sweetening,” leaving companies with excess CO2.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, the process of storing and transporting it remained expensive, so it didn’t always make financial sense to do EOR. Now, with investor-owned oil companies like Exxon, Chevron, BP, and Shell hurtling toward an inevitable decline in production rates — an inflection point referred to as “peak oil” — they need EOR more than ever. By rebranding it as a climate solution and tying it to a tax credit, they’ve not just made the process cheaper, they’ve created a new revenue stream — called Low Carbon Solutions at Exxon and Shell, Gas &amp; Low Carbon Energy at BP, and Lower Carbon at Chevron.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The 45Q tax credit revenue will also make it feasible for these new business units to supply carbon capture where it might genuinely be needed, on facilities with hard-to-abate emissions, like concrete, steel, and ammonia plants. But the vast majority of carbon that US taxpayers are paying oil companies to capture will either be going toward generating more oil, or would have greater emissions reductions benefits had the companies opted not to drill for gas in the first place.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-documentcloud wp-block-embed-documentcloud"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/24832210-bpa_hcor_00156030/?embed=1" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>The above emails, showing ExxonMobil employees’ conversations about marketing carbon capture and storage to an audience of children and Gen Z consumers, were originally obtained by congressional subpoena to a House committee and have been reproduced here by Drilled and Vox.</em></p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Clouded in carbon complexity</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.iea.org/commentaries/can-co2-eor-really-provide-carbon-negative-oil">According to the International Energy Agency</a>, using “naturally occurring” carbon — the CO2 that comes up with methane as part of natural gas, for example — for EOR as opposed to “anthropogenic CO2,” the emissions captured from a facility like a power plant or factory, “clearly provides no benefit in terms of emissions intensity.” That’s because absent the drilling in the first place, there would be no CO2 or methane emissions in those cases.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the United States, <a href="https://www.iea.org/commentaries/can-co2-eor-really-provide-carbon-negative-oil">more than 70 percent</a> of the CO2 injected underground as part of the EOR process is from natural sources. That’s true of Exxon’s showcase facility — the Shute Creek facility in LaBarge, Wyoming — as well. The CO2 source there is the gas that’s being drilled. ExxonMobil calls this “anthropogenic CO2,” but when pressed, a spokesperson told Drilled it’s generated by the separation process, or gas sweetening. In other words, absent the gas drilling, there would be no CO2 emissions at the site in the first place.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite that, when ExxonMobil talks about itself as the <a href="https://corporate.exxonmobil.com/-/media/Global/Files/carbon-capture-and-storage/CCS-Infographic.pdf">“global leader”</a> in CCS, pointing to its “<a href="https://lowcarbon.exxonmobil.com/lower-carbon-technology/carbon-capture-and-storage">more than 30 years capturing and storing carbon dioxide</a>,” and the fact that it has captured more CO2 than any other company in the world, it is <a href="https://lowcarbon.exxonmobil.com/lower-carbon-technology/carbon-capture-and-storage#Contactus">referring</a> to <a href="https://sequestration.mit.edu/tools/projects/la_barge.html">LaBarge</a>, which has been in operation since 1986.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to a <a href="https://sequestration.mit.edu/tools/projects/la_barge.html">case study from MIT</a>, where Exxon has <a href="https://corporate.exxonmobil.com/who-we-are/technology-and-collaborations/university-and-national-labs-partnerships/collaborating-with-leading-universities-to-meet-global-energy-demand#x_MassachusettsInstituteofTechnology">long funded research</a> on CCS and other industry-friendly “climate solutions,” from 1986 to 2008, LaBarge reinjected about 400,000 tonnes of CO2 a year back into the reservoir from which it came, and vented 180 million cubic feet of CO2 per day from the facility’s smokestacks. In 2008, it was ordered by Wyoming’s Oil and Gas Conservation Commission to reduce its vented CO2 emissions, which it did by building out a carbon capture system that redirected CO2 into pipelines for enhanced oil recovery.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2022, <a href="https://ieefa.org/articles/shute-creek-worlds-largest-carbon-capture-facility-sells-co2-oil-production-vents-unsold">a study</a> from IEEFA found that LaBarge was selling half of its captured carbon for enhanced oil recovery and venting the rest. This means that millions of tonnes of carbon the company claimed to have “captured” were ultimately emitted.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Climate scientists say CCS connected to fossil fuel use or production delivers little benefit when it comes to tackling climate change, period.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It doesn’t&nbsp;make sense to use CCS to prolong our use of fossil fuels, especially to produce electricity,” said <a href="https://people.climate.columbia.edu/users/profile/david-t-ho">David Ho</a>, professor at University of Hawaii and senior researcher at Columbia University. “The argument in favor of enhanced oil recovery is often that if they weren’t using this captured CO2, they’d be using some other CO2, but I don’t think you can call anything where you’re getting more oil out of the ground to burn a climate solution.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet, so far, major oil companies have struggled to deploy CCS technology in any other capacity. “When we talk about the failure of CCS, we generally talk about capturing, not storage, but when you look at capacity and how much has actually been sequestered, it’s very little,” Ho said.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/Protest_Against_Carbon_Capture_and_Storage_51697301719-1.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752726382539,100,78.494547234923" alt="A sign at a protest reads “We have carbon capture already!” and points to plants as carbon sinks." title="A sign at a protest reads “We have carbon capture already!” and points to plants as carbon sinks." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A sign at a protest in Melbourne against a large Chevron-Exxon carbon capture project in Australia. | Mark Hrkac" data-portal-copyright="Mark Hrkac" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">When CO2 is actually sequestered underground, there’s no guarantee it stays there. “CO2 has a way of moving through the air, of leaking through pipelines, and because we have no cradle-to-grave tracking, we have no way of actually knowing how much is leaking, how much is really being collected, how much is hitting the wellhead, and how much is really staying underground,” Raffensperger said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s not just concerning from a climate perspective, but from a public health perspective as well. Raffensperger notes that the pipelines built to transport condensed carbon from oil fields to storage facilities, or to other oil fields for EOR, are surrounded by “<a href="https://www.co2pipelinezone.com/">kill zones</a>.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“These are not your grandmother&#8217;s pipelines,” Raffensperger said. “They could be lethal. We talk about the kill zone or a fatality zone around a CO2 pipeline. We don’t talk about that with oil and gas pipelines. These are uniquely dangerous and underregulated.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Following a 2020 CO2 leak and explosion in <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/gassing-satartia-mississippi-co2-pipeline_n_60ddea9fe4b0ddef8b0ddc8f">Satartia, Mississippi</a>, that abruptly stopped cars on roadways, caused widespread dizziness and nausea, and sent several residents to the hospital, the federal Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration began looking into rules for CO2 pipelines. They were set to finalize that rule this summer, pending review by the Office of Management and Budget and the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, but that deadline has been <a href="https://www.reginfo.gov/public/do/eAgendaViewRule?pubId=202210&amp;RIN=2137-AF60">extended</a> to fall 2024. The lack of finalized safety regulations has not stopped the permitting of CO2 pipelines, though. The Summit pipeline, a massive project that would carry carbon across five states, just got the go-ahead in June for the first step of its construction process in Iowa: <a href="https://www.iowapublicradio.org/state-government-news/2024-06-26/summit-carbon-capture-pipeline-approved-eminent-domain-iowa-ethanol-emissions">seizing land</a> through eminent domain to make way for the pipeline.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Carbon capture and storage is a fantasy — and taxpayers are footing the bill&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to current and former Exxon employees, the company’s efforts to explore the “S” part of the CCS equation — storage, or sequestration — only began when it pulled together a team of technical experts to look for weaknesses in a 2018 <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/centers/geology-energy-and-minerals-science-center/science/methodology-development-and-assessment">US Geological Survey assessment</a> that showed enormous potential for CCS.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They thought the USGS was overly optimistic [about the potential of CCS] and they wanted us to basically bring industry technical expertise in to tell them their projections were overblown,” one Exxon staffer said. The team brought together to study CCS was then tasked with running an experiment to see if it was even possible to permanently store captured carbon. When the study showed that it was indeed possible, current and former Exxon staffers told Vox and Drilled the company’s executives were “surprised.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To truly sell CCS as a climate solution, Exxon had to show that storage at scale was feasible. Former employees told us that at the end of the last decade, executives came up with a prioritized list of the company’s export and import terminals and refineries where it might be relatively easy to attach CCS. As of this year, none of those projects have been built (though the company did <a href="https://www.exxonmobil.be/en-be/news/newsroom/news-releases/exxonmobil-to-build-ccs-pilot-plant-with-fuelcell-energy-using-carbonate-fuel-cell-technology">publicly announce</a> in late 2023 that it was working on a fuel-cell-powered carbon capture and hydrogen project at its Rotterdam refinery, one of the options on that&nbsp;list).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While it hasn’t managed to build commercial-scale carbon storage itself, Exxon did <a href="https://corporate.exxonmobil.com/news/news-releases/2023/1102_exxonmobil-completes-acquisition-of-denbury">acquire enhanced oil recovery company Denbury</a> in 2023, which brought 1,300 miles of CO2 pipelines and 15 onshore carbon storage sites under Exxon’s control. Again, this system is focused on enhanced oil recovery.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“CCS is a proven and safe technology that experts agree is pivotal to achieving net zero,” an ExxonMobil spokesperson said in response to a request for comment for this story. “We&#8217;re making progress in our Low Carbon Solutions business, with current plans to capture and permanently store more CO2 than any other company.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fatih Birol, executive director of the International Energy Agency, <a href="https://x.com/fbirol/status/1727552767256932766">has called</a> the industry’s plan to offset its emissions with carbon capture “fantasy.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the US government is all in on that fantasy now.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“[The carbon capture tax credit] 45Q is not based on net climate benefit or net CO2 reductions, it’s based on gross CO2 capture,” Blackburn, the environmental lawyer, said. “Why would you think making carbon a commodity would reduce CO2 emissions? It’s like the opposite of carbon tax, we’re actually paying them to produce more of it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Ugochi Anyaka-Oluigbo, Royce Kurmelovs, and Molly Taft also contributed reporting to this story.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump proposed bombing Mexico and it somehow wasn’t a big story]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/363146/trump-policy-war-mexico-trade-deportation-border" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363146</id>
			<updated>2024-07-29T15:24:24Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-29T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Donald Trump went on national TV last week and proposed bombing Mexico. Asked by Fox News’s Jesse Watters if he’d consider strikes against drug cartels operating in the country, Trump said yes —&#160;and framed his answer as a threat against the Mexican government. “Mexico’s gonna have to straighten it out really fast, or the answer [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Trump making a fist." data-caption="Republican presidential nominee, former President Donald Trump, speaks during a campaign rally at the Van Andel Arena on July 20, 2024 in Grand Rapids, Michigan. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2162834073.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Republican presidential nominee, former President Donald Trump, speaks during a campaign rally at the Van Andel Arena on July 20, 2024 in Grand Rapids, Michigan. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Donald Trump went on national TV last week and proposed <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/strikes-against-mexican-drug-cartels-absolutely-still-table-says-former-president-trump">bombing Mexico</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Asked by Fox News’s Jesse Watters if he’d consider strikes against drug cartels operating in the country, Trump said yes —&nbsp;and framed his answer as a threat against the Mexican government. “Mexico’s gonna have to straighten it out really fast, or the answer is absolutely,” the former president said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is not a one-off answer to a stray question. Trump suggested firing missiles at Mexico <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/03/us/politics/trump-mexico-cartels-republican.html">during his presidency</a>, asked advisers for a “<a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/donald-trump-mexico-military-cartels-war-on-drugs-1234705804/">battle plan</a>” against the cartels last year, and recently proposed <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/trump-mexico-kill-teams-drug-cartels-1235016514/">sending special operators to assassinate drug kingpins</a>. The idea of war in Mexico <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/4/21/23686510/mexico-invade-bomb-trump-republicans-cartels">is popular among the Republican elite</a>; a Trump-aligned think tank even drew up a <a href="https://americarenewing.com/issues/its-time-to-wage-war-on-transnational-drug-cartels/">broad-strokes plan</a> for how such a war might work.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is every reason to take Trump’s proposal seriously. Presidents tend to at least try to deliver on campaign promises, and they have nearly unlimited war-making power nowadays. As unthinkable as it may sound, there is a reasonable chance the United States will be at war on its southern border in the coming years if Donald Trump returns to office.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So how come nobody is talking about it?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Fox interview has barely gotten any pickup in other media. The prior years of Trump musings about war with Mexico have been mostly ignored. A major party candidate is proposing the first North American war in over a century and, somehow, it’s not even on the radar in Washington.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is part of a bigger pattern. If you actually look at Trump’s policy agenda, he’s called for some wild stuff: policies so extreme that, had they been proposed prior to 2016, would have defined the entire course of the campaign. Today, a few get some coverage, but mostly feel like sideshows — with policy as a category taking a backseat to personality and polling.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Recently, the lack of policy focus is partly due to a remarkably chaotic stretch of American political life. One candidate, the incumbent president, bungled his debate performance so badly that his party replaced him with his vice president. The other almost got killed on national television by a would-be assassin.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But even in more normal times this is a general problem with the media: Policy is technical and boring, while horse-race reporting is exciting and easier for audiences to grasp.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Elements of Trump’s persona also make policy reporting a lot tougher. The combination of habitual lying, flip-flopping, and personal disinterest in detail can make it tough to know what’s an actual proposal and what’s something he said just for the hell of it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there are some times when it’s really clear that Trump means what he says. And in those areas where he clearly does — like trade and the southern border —&nbsp;a second Trump administration would have extraordinary consequences.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trump’s biggest policies are deeply radical</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before I started writing this story, I asked my colleagues at Vox what stood out as Trump’s signature policy proposals in this election — the equivalent of “Build the Wall” in 2016. We came up with two big answers: Trump’s proposal for a general 10 percent tariff and his plan for “the largest deportation in American history.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Each of these policies is genuinely extreme.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A 10 percent blanket tariff isn’t just putting a tax on specific imports to protect a particular industry, or to retaliate against a country like China engaging in unfair trade practices. It’s a blanket attempt to make all imports from every country, including from neighbors like Canada and allies like the European Union, 10 percent more expensive.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is a radical shift from the way that trade policy typically works in the United States&nbsp;— one with huge and predictably negative implications for US consumers and the economy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The tariffs mean that people will either buy American-made goods that cost more than their current foreign competitors, or they will keep buying foreign-made goods at <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/02/opinion/tariffs-trump-china-taxes.html">a 10 percent markup</a>. That’s inflation basically by definition: an odd proposal for a candidate running against inflation as his central issue.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The center-right <a href="https://taxfoundation.org/research/all/federal/trump-tariffs-biden-tariffs/">Tax Foundation</a> estimates that the tariffs would shave nearly 1 percent off of US GDP growth annually, costing roughly 684,000 jobs. This estimate did not take into account retaliation from other countries, who almost certainly would impose their own tariffs on American goods in response. A second estimate, from the centrist Peterson Institute, finds that every group of Americans — from the poorest to the wealthiest — would <a href="https://www.piie.com/sites/default/files/2024-05/pb24-1.pdf">see drops in their annual income</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Neither of these estimates takes into account the all-but-certain retaliation from the affected countries, especially China (who Trump wants to hit with a special 60 percent across-the-board tariff). Typically during trade wars, countries respond to tariffs with in-kind measures. In this case, that would mean a flat tariff on all US-made goods. Both the American and world economy would suffer immensely from everything becoming more expensive everywhere.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The point is not just that the Trump trade policy is bad, though it is. It’s that it is shocking: such a radical break with the way that trade policy works that it would have massive ripple effects throughout the global economy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, people don’t appreciate just how radical Trump’s proposals for mass deportations are.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No one is exactly sure how many people are going to be targeted for deportations: Trump never sets a specific target, but often implies he’s going to deport every undocumented immigrant in the United States (there are currently <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2024/07/22/what-we-know-about-unauthorized-immigrants-living-in-the-us/">around 11 million</a>). A group of four NBC reporters tried to figure out how deporting so many people <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/investigations/mass-deportation-migrants-trump-actually-work-rcna161637">was supposed to work</a>, and ended up concluding that it was such a break with the way immigration enforcement typically works that it was near-impossible to grasp the scope of the effort.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Typically, police don’t go out looking for undocumented migrants currently residing in the United States. They find them by accident, during a traffic stop or criminal arrest, and then discover that they are undocumented and notify ICE to begin deportation. Targeted enforcement raids happen, but they’re comparatively rare and make up only a fraction of annual deportations.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Trump’s “mass deportation” policy to work, he would need to devote extraordinary resources — state, federal, and local —&nbsp;to finding and apprehending undocumented immigrants. Once found, they still pose a massive logistical challenge: current law does not allow ICE to deport longstanding US residents without a hearing (or the migrant’s consent), posing a huge burden on the legal system. The government would also need to figure out the travel logistics for deportation, including negotiating with home countries that might not be very happy to receive large numbers of functional refugees.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During all of this, the US government would need to house millions of people — which ICE currently lacks the capacity to do. Hence the now-infamous Trump proposals for <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/11/us/politics/trump-2025-immigration-agenda.html">keeping detained immigrants in camps</a>: there’s literally nowhere else to put them while they await deportation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this is not only a human rights disaster, but an economic and law enforcement one. The cost of devoting police and judicial resources to this task, in terms of trade-offs with addressing actual crime, would be significant. So too would be the financial cost of building immigrant camps and providing them with food and medical care.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Removing so many people from the workforce would also be inflationary, far outweighing any (questionable) increase in wages for native-born workers. <a href="https://cmsny.org/publications/mass-deportations-impoverish-us-families-create-immense-costs/#:~:text=They%20concluded%20that%20a%20%E2%80%9Cpolicy,10%20years%20by%20%244.7%20trillion.%E2%80%9D">One estimate</a> suggests that, all told, mass deportations would cost the American economy $4.7 trillion over a 10-year period.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The point, in short, is that Trump is proposing sweeping changes to the way the US economy and legal system operates — ones with consequences for every American&nbsp;—&nbsp;and we’re barely even talking about what they would mean.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Trump gets away with his radicalism</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of the problem with Trump’s radical policies, from war in Mexico on down, is that they’re so outlandish that most people can’t believe they could happen.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/27/us/politics/trump-trade-tariffs-imports.html">the New York Times interviewed David Autor</a>, a leading trade economist at MIT, about Trump’s 10 percent tariff, he said, “I don’t think they’ll do it.” The reason, Autor added, was that the impact would be catastrophic: it would have “a very large effect on prices almost immediately” and “easily cause a recession.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, when NBC interviewed Ammon Blair —&nbsp;a former Customs and Border Protection agent who is currently a fellow at the right-wing Texas Public Policy Foundation — he said mass deportations were unlikely because they’d be disastrous.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I honestly just don’t see it happening,” Blair said. “One, because I think it’s political suicide, and two, I think we need to focus on national security issues.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, this is exactly the kind of thing people said before Trump’s first term about policies like the Muslim ban or overturning <em>Roe v. Wade</em>. Those things happened, and so too could a 10 percent tariff or a war with Mexico — especially since trade, immigration, and war are three policy areas where presidents enjoy broad discretionary authority.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Moreover, it’s fairly normal for politicians to try and implement their campaign promises. Again and again, political scientists have found that elected leaders <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/11/27/9801800/politicians-keep-campaign-promises">take such promises seriously and try to fulfill them</a>. In this respect, Trump’s first term is not an aberration but in line with the historical norm.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I suspect some of the incredulity about Trump’s policies is that it’s hard to tell what actually counts as a promise.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump is a habitual liar who has a habit of saying whatever comes to mind. Oftentimes, an interviewer will ask him a policy question and he’ll leave the door open to whatever idea they’re suggesting should be on the table.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Moreover, it’s not obvious who speaks for Trump on policy. His campaign doesn’t focus very much on developing detailed policy plans, leaving a vacuum for others to fill. The issue page on his website, for example, does not contain any original information —&nbsp;it simply links out to the 2024 RNC platform. Journalists often have to cobble together his policy ideas by looking at documents like the platform <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce">Project 2025</a> and white papers by various former Trump White House officials scattered around conservative think tanks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet there’s a difference between Trump’s random utterances, or what he might do about some obscure policy issue, and his consistent instincts on the issues central to his political identity&nbsp;— like trade and the southern border. And there, he could not be clearer: across-the-board tariff, mass deportation, and waging war on the drug cartels.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if we set aside everything else we know (or think we know) about what Trump would do, these three items alone would have the potential to transform life in America as we know it. It’s time to start covering Trump like he means what he says.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
