<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-09-04T16:57:29Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The real reason Netanyahu won’t end the Gaza war]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/369934/israel-gaza-protests-hostages-netanyahu-war-september" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369934</id>
			<updated>2024-09-04T16:57:29Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-04T17:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This weekend, Israeli soldiers in Gaza discovered the bodies of six hostages executed by Hamas. The response was an outpouring of protests: Israelis flooding the streets to call for a ceasefire that would bring all hostages back and end the war, a demand that a majority of Israelis support. The Histadrut, Israel’s national labor union, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Israeli protestors condemn Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and his handling of the hostages being held by Hamas in Gaza on September 1, 2024 in Tel Aviv, Israel." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2169799600.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Israeli protestors condemn Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and his handling of the hostages being held by Hamas in Gaza on September 1, 2024 in Tel Aviv, Israel.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">This weekend, Israeli soldiers in Gaza discovered the bodies of six hostages executed by Hamas. The response was an outpouring of protests: Israelis flooding the streets to call for a ceasefire that would bring all hostages back and end the war, a demand that <a href="https://en.idi.org.il/articles/55520">a majority of Israelis support</a>. The Histadrut, Israel’s national labor union, called a (<a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/09/02/g-s1-20547/general-strike-in-israel-over-hostages-leads-to-uneven-closures">swiftly ended</a>) general strike.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The response from Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was to double down on war. In a Monday night press conference, he insisted that any ceasefire would depend on <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/philadelphi-corridor-explainer-israel-hamas-talks-cease-fire-gaza-rcna169274">Israeli control</a> over a stretch of territory in southwestern Gaza called the Philadelphi Corridor — something Hamas is not prepared to give. Netanyahu’s presser was so belligerent, in fact, that it may have <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/official-says-netanyahus-press-briefing-torpedoed-hostage-deal-efforts-report/">single-handedly torpedoed ongoing ceasefire talks</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s clear that the Israeli public has no faith in Netanyahu’s handling of the war: <a href="https://www.jpost.com/israel-news/article-810113">Roughly 70 percent</a> believe he should resign his position. Yet despite <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/netanyahu-protests-philadelphi-corridor-hostage-deal-demand-rcna169484">ongoing protests</a>, it’s equally clear that the prime minister will not be changing course voluntarily. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And it looks like he’ll likely get away with it, at least for now.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">His government has weathered dismal polling on its war effort, as well as sporadic protests, since the war began last October. And yet, as with past demonstration flare-ups, there has been no evidence that this weekend’s events have brought his government to the brink of collapse. How can this be?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The answer is brute power politics. The 2022 election gave right-wing parties a clear majority in the Knesset (Israel’s parliament), allowing Netanyahu to build the most far-right government in Israeli history. Though this coalition has since become extremely unpopular, there’s no way for voters to kick it out on their own. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The government could only collapse if it faces defections from <em>inside</em> the governing coalition. But at present, the greatest threat to Netanyahu’s coalition comes from his extreme right flank, which wants him to continue the war at all costs. And for that reason, he seems intent on doing so.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not impossible that other cracks in the government begin to show. There are certainly signs of stress, and escalating mass publication could exacerbate them. But as of right now, the situation looks bleak. The Israeli public wants to end the killing in Gaza, but their government won’t let them.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Netanyahu’s coalition has been so durable</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Israel’s parliamentary system, governments are formed by legislative majorities; Netanyahu’s government currently commands 64 out of the 120 seats in the Knesset.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of those 64 seats, half come from Netanyahu’s own right-wing Likud party. Twenty-five seats come from ultra-Orthodox parties, and the remaining seven belong to the even further right Religious Zionism faction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These parties don’t agree on everything, but it’s hard to see any of them rebelling against the government to push for a ceasefire deal.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Likud, once Israel’s relatively normal center-right party, is now a hollowed-out vehicle for Netanyahu’s ambitions. Its parliamentary ranks are mostly made up of the prime minister’s toadies. Yoav Gallant, the current defense minister, is an exception; he has bitterly and publicly feuded with Netanyahu over the prime minister’s incompetent handling of the war. Indeed, Gallant’s support is a major reason why the 2023 mass protests <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2024/1/3/24022467/israel-supreme-court-judicial-overhaul-reasonableness-basic-law-overturn">successfully blocked</a> Netanyahu’s master plan to seize control of Israel’s court system.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But those protests were bigger and more disruptive than the current anti-war demonstrations. And so far, there is little evidence that Gallant has enough supporters inside the government to fuel a wave of defections that might topple the government.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The religious parties in Netanyahu’s coalition care less about the war itself than they do preserving the rights and privileges of the ultra-Orthodox community. Foremost among these priorities is <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c6p24expzd5o">fighting a recent Supreme Court ruling</a> that ends the community’s exemption from Israel’s national conscription law, a court order that Netanyahu is slow-walking and that a center-left coalition would almost certainly implement in full.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One ultra-Orthodox party, Shas, has <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/shas-urges-netanyahu-to-move-forward-with-hostage-deal-ignore-far-right-threats/">expressed support for a hostage deal</a>. But so far, there is no indication that Shas cares <em>enough</em> about the plight of the hostages to threaten to topple the government over it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Religious Zionism, by contrast, cares deeply about the war — and they want it to continue. Their party’s raison d’être is expanding Israeli Jewish control over all the land between the Jordan River and the Mediterranean Sea, and the war has proven an extraordinary boon to this cause. The party’s radical leaders, Bezalel Smotrich and Itamar Ben-Gvir, have <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/smotrich-threatens-to-quit-govt-over-hostage-deal-eisenkot-slams-far-fight-blackmail/">repeatedly</a> <a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2024-06-01/ty-article/.premium/ben-gvir-smotrich-reject-u-s-hostage-proposal-threaten-to-quit-netanyahu-coalition/0000018f-d552-d5bc-a1bf-df7225960000">threatened</a> to quit the coalition if Netanyahu strikes any kind of long-term ceasefire deal. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu cares very deeply about maintaining his grip on power: it’s the closest thing to a literal get-out-of-jail-free card that a prime minister <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/netanyahus-lawyer-tells-court-pm-can-only-testify-in-corruption-trial-in-march-2025/">staring down criminal conviction</a> could have. This means that he cares a great deal about the far-right threats to quit his government, and will want to maintain the war as long as he can, absent a major political threat on his other flank.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So far, one hasn’t emerged.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Can the opposition turn mass discontent into political power?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The protest movement, while large, primarily draws from the ranks of the Israeli center and left. As such, it’s thus unlikely to sway parliamentarians from the right-wing coalition parties as long as they keep their core voters.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Both these things are true: the government does not enjoy a majority in the polls, but it still holds a sizable base of support,” says Noam Gidron, a political scientist at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Moreover, Gidron says, the fractured Israeli opposition has not yet figured out how to translate its majority public support into a concerted strategy to break Netanyahu’s coalition.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The opposition is divided between the centrists, the more leftist wing, and the Arab parties — and they have not figured out how — and perhaps even whether — they should operate together against the government,” he says. Benny Gantz, the leader of the most popular opposition party, seems “reluctant to use all the political power and go in full force against Netanyahu.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s one way things could change: the opposition getting its act together, linking up with the street demonstrations, and trying to force Netanyahu’s hand. You could also imagine Gallant finding a few more Likud defectors, Shas having an attack of conscience, or tensions over <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24114496/benjamin-netanyahu-ultra-orthodox-conscription-coalition-gaza">the conscription of ultra-Orthodox men boiling over</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But as of right now, none of this appears to be on the horizon.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“For [the government to fall], Israeli political leaders would need common sense, political courage, and a moral backbone. Too clearly, the overwhelming majority have none,” <a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2024-09-04/ty-article/.premium/furious-israelis-are-protesting-to-save-the-hostages-can-they-change-netanyahus-mind/00000191-bc49-d9c6-a997-be6996320000">Dahlia Scheindlin</a>, a leading Israel pollster, writes in the Haaretz newspaper.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Aja Romano</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The storm of controversy around Black Myth: Wukong, explained]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/369903/black-myth-wukong-controversy-feminist-what-happened" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369903</id>
			<updated>2024-09-04T16:06:13Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-04T16:10:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[How did a fairly straightforward video game based on an ancient legend become the latest battleground in the war over “woke”? Black Myth: Wukong takes the ancient legend of Monkey, or the Monkey King, an iconic character whose travels were most famously described in the Ming dynasty masterpiece Journey to the West, and expands on [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/sc8i9d.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">How did a fairly straightforward video game based on an ancient legend become the latest battleground in the war over “woke”?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Black Myth: Wukong</em> takes the ancient legend of Monkey, or the Monkey King, an iconic character whose travels were most famously described in the Ming dynasty masterpiece<em> Journey to the West</em>, and expands on it. The game first attracted interest in 2020, when its makers debuted a 13-minute-long <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O2nNljv0MOw">trailer</a> that drew over 10 million views and won <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/action-rpg/black-myth-wukong-hands-on-preview/">wild praise</a> from gamers around the globe. The ensuing four years of anticipation paid off: Within a day of its August 20 release, it had <a href="https://gameworldobserver.com/2024/08/21/black-myth-wukong-sales-4-5-million-copies-report">reportedly</a> sold 4.5 million copies and soared to over 2.2 million concurrent players on Steam; it’s currently <a href="https://steamdb.info/charts/?sort=peak">ranked</a> as the platform’s second most-played game of all time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This might have been a simple and exciting win for the Chinese gaming industry; <em>Wukong</em> is the country’s first major top-tier game release — not to mention a major exportation of Chinese culture at a mass global scale. But therein lies the problem: Some of the game’s US audiences seem to <a href="https://seandknight.com/index.php/2024/06/17/why-western-gamers-should-boycott-black-myth-wukong-dei-free-but-not-ccp-free/" rel="nofollow">believe</a> the game itself is Chinese propaganda. It doesn’t help that prior to the game’s release, the game’s co-publisher, Hero Games, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cnvyre936zvo">attempted to issue a moratorium</a> among reviewers and streamers on certain unsavory topics — including elements that have nothing to do with the game itself, like “feminist propaganda” and Covid-19. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Was this dictum merely a face-saving gesture for the Chinese Communist Party? Was it a sign that the game is actually serving a conservative agenda? Or was it something else altogether? No one is sure; but in the wake of the game’s success, a mix of wariness about China and right-wing embrace has led to a backlash against the game by some on the left. Now, being angry about the game is being seen as tantamount to being angry about the American right.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All this over a game whose only real aim is arguably to have players have fun battles and collect cool pretty things.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>No one can agree on whether </strong><strong><em>Wukong</em></strong><strong> is good. Either way, it’s undeniably popular.</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <em>Journey to the West</em>, Monkey, a.k.a. Sun Wukong, is a trickster archetype who becomes immortal but rebels against Buddha. He then gets kicked out of heaven before repenting and slowly redeems himself, eventually leveling up through constant battles to achieve enlightenment and become a Buddha himself. It’s a perfect story for a video game.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>, a single-person action fighter RPG, imagines that Monkey died at some point after his journey to enlightenment. In this loose sequel, you play as a reincarnation of Monkey, working to collect six relics that can help revive you to your former state as Buddha. You do this by fighting bad guys. Lots and lots and lots of bad guys. There are anywhere from 90 to 113 “bosses” in the game’s six chapters, depending on how you’re counting.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether or not Wukong is good based on the merits of its gameplay alone is, like many things, in the eye of the beholder. Some say the game is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/23/24226834/black-myth-wukong-hands-on-impression-game-science">boringly easy</a>; others, <a href="https://gamerant.com/black-myth-wukong-review/">prohibitively</a> <a href="https://x.com/NikTekOfficial/status/1826626808151998788">difficult</a>.&nbsp; The game’s linear structure, in which you face off against the game’s bosses one after the other, is either <a href="https://www.inverse.com/gaming/black-myth-wukong-chinese-nationalism-anti-woke">too uninventive</a> or just <a href="https://youtu.be/KMZohKOEaoM?t=350">basic fun</a>. It’s either <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2358720/discussions/0/4426562258568484005/">wildly overhyped</a> or actually <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xAoZs5sEl3w">even better</a> than players expected. (That last review poses an important question: “What other game lets you transform into a giant rock so you can battle another giant rock?”)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nearly everyone <a href="https://www.chinausfocus.com/society-culture/chinas-black-myth-wukong-looks-like-a-hit">agrees</a>, however, that <em>Wukong</em>’s art design is flawless. The graphics and visuals are gorgeous, the animation is superb, and the details are careful, with especially careful attention given to recreating actual Chinese relics and artifacts. (A closed museum that preserves such artifacts in China’s northern Shanxi province, where much of <em>Wukong</em> takes place, recently <a href="https://www.shine.cn/feature/travel/2408276474/">announced</a> its re-opening in the wake of the game’s popularity.)&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/sc8i9c.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4613147178592,100,93.077370564282" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Sun Wukong, the Monkey King and protagonist of the game. | Game Science" data-portal-copyright="Game Science" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The game builds and expands upon the mythos of <em>Journey</em>, with <a href="https://gamerant.com/black-myth-wukong-six-senses-buddhism-relics-abilities/">elements of Buddhist and Chinese folklore</a> ever present throughout. The main goal — to retrieve the six relics from different regions — is based on the six senses of Buddhism (that is, eye, ear, nose, tongue, body, and mind). Players have praised the game’s worldbuilding as well, from the many pseudo-historical characters inspired by <em>Journey</em> to the litany of customizable RPG mechanics, many of which draw further on Chinese culture.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But while all the praise cited above comes from English-speaking gamers, the most prominent line of attack against the game from people who seek to disparage its popularity is <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1ex2cnn/90_of_wukong_players_are_from_china/">the claim</a> that most of <em>Wukong</em>’s massive sales have come from China. While this doesn’t seem like much of a problem, unless you assume all Chinese gamers have poor taste or are brainwashed nationalists, there is plenty of evidence that the game is experiencing popularity worldwide. It currently stands at a score of 82 on the English-language <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/black-myth-wukong/">Metacritic</a>, and on Steam, <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2358720/charts/">95 percent</a> of the 700,000-plus user reviews are positive, and they seem to be written in a <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2358720/reviews/?browsefilter=toprated&amp;snr=1_5_100010_&amp;filterLanguage=all">balanced mix</a> of languages.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The game, however, has set off a strange discourse about — guess what — diversity and inclusion that the game itself barely invites. Now, far overshadowing all conversation about its themes and use of Chinese mythology, players and critics alike have been thrust into a discomfiting argument about whether <em>Wukong</em> is “<a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/21437879/stay-woke-wokeness-history-origin-evolution-controversy">woke</a>” or not.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Wukong</em></strong><strong> is neither woke nor anti-woke, but that hasn’t stopped players from using it to fuel their own agenda</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Wukong has been mired in controversy since well before its release. Just prior to August 20, the game’s co-publisher <a href="https://www.si.com/videogames/news/black-myth-wukong-streamers-feminist-propaganda">sent out</a> the aforementioned <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/exserv.bsky.social/post/3kzvr3jr54225">list of taboo topics</a> to gamers, reviewers, and streamers who had requested preview access to the game and who might be preparing to livestream their gameplay on platforms like Twitch and YouTube. The list of “Don’ts” the gamers were instructed to avoid reportedly ran thus:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Do NOT insult other influencers or players.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Do NOT use any offensive language/humor.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Do NOT include politics, violence, nudity, feminist propaganda, fetishization, and other content that instigates negative discourse.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Do NOT use trigger words such as ‘quarantine’ or “isolation” or “COVID-19.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Do NOT discuss content related to China’s game industry policies, opinions, news, etc.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Needless to say, gamers of all varieties <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/08/18/the-black-myth-wukong-no-feminist-propaganda-no-covid-19-discussion-email-is-real/">bristled</a> <a href="https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/boards/264562-playstation-5/80831395/981785468">at</a> these restraints on their freedom of speech. Yet there are several reasons the company might have sent out this list for in-game discussion rules that have nothing to do with trying to quash discussion for the sake of quashing discussion.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s important to understand the role of the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) in this moment. The CCP has a way of essentially freezing industries that grow too popular too quickly; see, for instance, that time it banned palace dramas for a couple of years because of the runaway popularity of <a href="https://www.vox.com/22968747/story-of-yanxi-palace-review-palace-drama-recommendations">one palace drama</a> in particular. Gaming has already come under <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/its-time-to-pay-attention-to-china-inside-the-worlds-largest-pc-games-industry/">increasing fire</a> from the government, which has attempted to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/30/business/media/china-online-games.html">dramatically limit</a> the number of hours children spend playing video games. So sending out a list like this could be a tactical way for its developer, Game Science, and publishers to potentially stave off backlash from the CCP while mediating the government’s view of the game and its sudden popularity.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, some critics on the left who may have already been suspicious of a game originating from China took off their gloves. One outlet blasted the game for its “<a href="https://dotesports.com/black-myth-wukong/news/black-myth-wukongs-shameless-lack-of-diversity-is-attracting-the-wrong-type-of-fans">shameless lack of diversity</a>;” another <a href="https://screenrant.com/black-myth-wukong-review/">argued</a> that “The lack of diversity and inclusivity resonates with the misogynistic comments reported to have been made by developers &#8230; the underlying feeling that women aren’t welcome in this world felt present throughout my gameplay experience.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even the Hong Kong-based South China Morning Post <a href="https://www.scmp.com/opinion/china-opinion/article/3276212/why-black-myth-wukongs-success-should-spark-reflection-sexism-gaming">took issue</a> with the workplace sexism that may have undermined the game. As multiple media outlets <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cnvyre936zvo">pointed out</a>, there’s some evidence to suggest that Game Science isn’t exactly progressive. In November 2023, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-black-myth-wukong-developers-history-of-sexism-is-complicating-its-journey-to-the-west">IGN reported</a> on a history of lewd and misogynistic remarks made against women by multiple staffers at the company on social media, including two co-founders. One co-founder fantasized about expanding staff and getting fellatio from all the new employees; another staffer claimed women’s games were different from men’s because of differences in their biology.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other gamers unearthed <a href="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fbe92c4f9-73b5-4ad2-9535-d029b5383f5e_1195x1632.jpeg">ribald promotional images</a> the studio has used in the past. The juvenile imagery, and the glib tone of many of the staff remarks, fit into the typical “boys will be boys” gamer milieu that dominated gamer culture in the US prior to the last decade. But years of concerted efforts to make games more accessible to women and other marginalized players have diminished that rampant sexism, and in 2024, it’s difficult to read some of these statements as anything but hopelessly dated at the least and actively hostile to women in games at worst.&nbsp;It doesn’t help that the company has so far <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/action/black-myth-wukong-sexism-controversy-interview-no-comment/">responded</a> to media requests regarding this history with “no comment.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To gamers on the right, this outcry from the left was validation — a sign that the woke media had gone off the rails in its haste to bash anything that appeared to be anti-diverse. “Let me tell you, I am delighted just as the next guy that journalists and DEI advocates just can” cope with Wukong’s success,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/KotakuInAction/comments/1f0tgu1/is_black_myth_wukong_a_good_game_though/">wrote</a> one redditor on Reddit’s longstanding pro-<a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/1/20/20808875/gamergate-lessons-cultural-impact-changes-harassment-laws">gamergate</a> subreddit KotakuInAction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet despite all of this background, there’s nothing really objectionable in the game itself. Claims that <em>Wukong</em> has no women are false; there are plenty of female characters, including <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uDe27jK6Do4">female</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0YYLB_cNFEU">bosses</a>, and (as far as we could see from a jaunt across the internet) there’s nothing overly sexualized or fetishistic about their designs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for claims that the game lacks diversity, while this is true in a technical sense, in that it lacks racial diversity, it’s also a fantasy about an anthropomorphized rhesus macaque fighting a huge array of other fantastical creatures of all shapes, sizes, and species. And it’s set in a world based on a culture to which US gamers generally have limited exposure. The game itself offers a valuable experience merely by introducing its players to the culture and folklore of China.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Is that a low bar? Possibly, but it’s still one not everyone meets. “I was in a second-hand bookshop the other day and suddenly held<em> The Monkey King</em> in my hands,” one gamer <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/KotakuInAction/comments/1f0tgu1/is_black_myth_wukong_a_good_game_though/ljue8ix/">wrote</a> on the aforementioned KotakuInAction post. “I might buy it next time and read it and then buy the game (on sale!). I think it will enhance the experience significantly.” This might be a rare perspective (that user, alas, was ruthlessly downvoted). Fans of <em>Wukong</em> using the game to rail against wokeness aren’t necessarily <em>for</em> embracing Chinese culture, but a nimble riff on that culture is still on offer through the game.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The most annoying thing about the debates surrounding <em>Wukong</em>, in fact, is just how little they have to do with the actual game. They’re being waged almost entirely in meta-arguments rather than actual consideration for either the narrative itself or the aims of the developers who made it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What this fight <em>does</em> tell us, however, is that unlike neighboring Korea, China’s <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3275726/will-black-myth-wukong-gaming-mania-mark-turning-point-chinas-soft-power-fortunes?module=perpetual_scroll_1_RM&amp;pgtype=article">foray</a> into exporting its soft power will likely be fraught with distrust and even bad faith. Fandom, and gaming, are toxic cultures on a good day — and the tentative entry of Chinese creators into the fray will likely only exacerbate the worst tendencies of the worst players.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Whizy Kim</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[That Chase “money glitch” hack was just fraud]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/money/369894/chase-bank-glitch-tiktok-fraud-free-money" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369894</id>
			<updated>2024-09-04T15:39:01Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-04T14:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Social Media" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="TikTok" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Who doesn’t want free money? In the world of video games, it’s possible with a simple cheat code — type “motherlode” in The Sims, watch a flood of money roll in, redecorate your whole mansion. For a brief, wild moment, a viral TikTok trend suggested that such a shortcut could exist in real life, too.  [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Chase called the TikTok trend “fraud, plain and simple.”" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-1246506426.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Chase called the TikTok trend “fraud, plain and simple.”</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Who doesn’t want free money? In the world of video games, it’s possible with a simple cheat code — type “motherlode” in <em>The Sims</em>, watch a flood of money roll in, redecorate your whole mansion. For a brief, wild moment, a viral TikTok trend suggested that such a shortcut could exist in real life, too. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The money “hack” worked like this: Over the weekend, news of a “glitch” spread on TikTok claiming that Chase bank was allowing people to withdraw funds from a deposited check right away. People took advantage by writing themselves massive checks, depositing them, and then withdrawing stacks of cash at ATMs. “We are aware of this incident, and it has been addressed,” a spokesperson for Chase wrote to us over email. “Regardless of what you see online, depositing a fraudulent check and withdrawing the funds from your account is fraud, plain and simple.” Chase did not clarify how much money had been withdrawn, or what repercussions there would be for people who had cashed fake checks. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the weekend bonanza, videos of <a href="https://x.com/seamorechaos/status/1829946659687547205">people</a> who had allegedly scammed Chase seeing negative balances in the tens of thousands have also started popping up. While there are countless videos talking about the so-called “Chase money glitch” on TikTok now, many of the top ones are wisely noting that <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@darryl2times/video/7409753108596903214">cheating a</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@jazmindaneen/video/7409428372666813727">big bank</a> out of money is not likely to end well. The Chase fraud isn’t particularly sophisticated, and very easy to trace — especially when you brag about it online. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This is pretty much traditional check fraud,” says Kimberly Palmer, a personal finance expert at NerdWallet. “There’s nothing really new about this.” Banks have been reporting <a href="https://www.fincen.gov/news/news-releases/fincen-alert-nationwide-surge-mail-theft-related-check-fraud-schemes-targeting">soaring rates of check fraud</a> in recent years, which can take different forms. This form, where you write a check you can’t back and take advantage of the money the bank supplies in the interim, is known as “check kiting,” but someone could also steal your check and carefully change the amount and recipient. <a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/articles/how-spot-avoid-report-fake-check-scams">Fake check scams</a> have been on the rise, too: You get mailed a check from someone asking you to deposit it, using a variety of lies and excuses as to why they can’t do it themselves. Then they ask you to send some or all of the money back. It’s a scam because the funds from the check might show up in your account, but it “doesn’t necessarily mean that it’s already been checked,” says Palmer. By the time the bank verifies that it was a fraudulent check and takes back the money, you’ve already sent the cash back to the scammer.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If you cash a check that’s fake and then withdraw money, you’re still responsible for the money that you withdrew,” Palmer says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Chase did not respond to a question on whether it was an error in its system that allowed people to withdraw more money than they typically could from a newly deposited check, or whether they were exploiting the ordinary way that a portion of funds is made available when someone deposits a check, known as the “float.” Usually, there’s a <a href="https://www.chase.com/personal/banking/education/basics/how-long-does-it-take-for-a-check-to-clear">waiting period</a> for the full balance of a deposited check to appear in your bank account — it can take a few business days for larger amounts, or if you don’t have an open account with the bank. “Sometimes, as a courtesy, the bank does make a portion of the check available right away,” notes Palmer. US banks are also generally required to make <a href="https://www.helpwithmybank.gov/help-topics/bank-accounts/funds-availability/funds-availability-check.html">at least $225 available</a> by the next business day. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s worth noting that even when banks make a mistake — no fraud involved — customers usually <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/personal-finance/bank-error-your-favor-can-you-keep-cash-n735316">don’t get to keep the money</a>. Financial institutions don’t operate under “no takesy-backsies” rules. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Chase Check Fraud Incident of 2024 is emblematic of a pattern of financial pro-tips and quick hacks offered on social media platforms like TikTok: They’re not smart shortcuts to save money or earn a little more. At best it’s bad advice that won’t improve your finances, and at worst they’re straight-up illegal. One example from last year: a TikToker telling viewers they can easily charge a $100,000 watch on a <a href="https://www.fool.com/the-ascent/credit-cards/articles/dont-believe-this-terrible-tiktok-advice-about-getting-free-money-from-business-credit-cards/">business credit card</a> and never pay it off. “With business credit, you are not personally held responsible for that line of credit,” the user @greenthumbgotbands claims in <a href="https://x.com/TikTokInvestors/status/1671513512236163073">the video</a>. (In a later video, he said <a href="https://x.com/TikTokInvestors/status/1672351601804341248">it was a joke</a>.) To be clear, even with a limited liability company, or LLC for short, you can absolutely be personally liable for business debt, especially when it’s fairly easy to prove that you were <a href="https://weisblattlaw.com/blog/protect-assets-with-llc/">mingling personal and business purchases</a> — like a flashy watch. Your credit card company might also <a href="https://www.bankrate.com/credit-cards/business/using-business-credit-card-for-personal-expenses/#consequences">shut down</a> your business’s credit line. Early this year another <a href="https://www.dailydot.com/debug/tiktok-investing-credit-card-advice/">TikToker made waves</a> by promoting one easy trick to increasing your credit limit: by <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TikTokCringe/comments/19827mp/tiktok_business_coach_posts_video_advertising_how/">sending invoices</a> to your own LLCs and then paying them with a credit card. It looks like your business is getting a lot of income, and it looks like your credit cards are getting high usage, which are both factors used to determine higher credit limits. This is also likely fraud.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Australia, a viral financial tip in 2021 advertised as a way to get a quick government loan led to the country’s tax office being <a href="https://www.afr.com/companies/professional-services/tiktok-gst-fraud-hit-on-tax-office-blows-out-to-4-6b-20230813-p5dw2y">defrauded of $4.6 billion</a>. The advice, which spread widely on TikTok, instructed people to register a fake business and claim tax refunds on fake business expenses.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The genre of uncredentialed <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/22229551/tiktok-personal-finance-day-trading-tesla-scam">money gurus</a> teaching social media disciples how to get rich quick has exploded in recent years. While you can find some sensible, common sense guidance on money, bad TikTok financial advice runs the gamut from morally questionable to the downright ruinous, whether it’s advising homeowners to get a roommate and charge them the entire monthly mortgage (or more) without disclosing that they’re the landlord — that’s <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@twoguystakeonrealestate/video/6942652559534460166">called “house hacking”</a> — or maxing out credit cards to buy an Airbnb property you can’t actually afford. “I see a lot of real estate advice that really doesn’t make sense,” says Palmer. “Nothing is stopping someone from calling themselves a financial expert, or adding letters after their name on social media.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re really unlucky, the advice you uncritically follow from TikTok won’t just drain your bank account or tank your credit score — it could actually be a crime. It’s unclear what will happen to the money glitch fraudsters. “It’s really up to Chase if they want to follow up and prosecute fraud that has been done to them,” says Palmer. Check fraud laws vary across jurisdictions, but in some states writing a bad check can be a felony if the amount is large enough (in Texas, for example, it’s <a href="https://www.rtoddbennettpc.com/blog/2023/07/understanding-theft-by-check-in-texas/">$2,500</a>).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With the proliferation of digital banking and personal finance apps, it has become easier to download an app, open an account with a financial institution, and start making some pretty consequential money-related decisions. There’s a sense in which much of our financial transactions and systems don’t quite feel grounded in reality — money isn’t cold hard cash, it’s a number displayed in an app. It’s easier to <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/23875697/ios-17-apple-pay-overspending-tap-to-pay-tech">overspend</a>, and also easier to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/01/28/your-money/mobile-payment-venmo-zelle-cash-app.html">simply get scammed</a>. The FTC reported a <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/business-guidance/blog/2024/02/facts-about-fraud-ftc-what-it-means-your-business">record amount of money</a> lost to scams last year, with about $10 billion reported lost. Younger people, spending a lot of time online, are actually <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/23882304/gen-z-vs-boomers-scams-hacks">more likely to fall prey to a scammer</a> than baby boomers are.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“People have to be really skeptical when they see these sorts of suggestions online, because they can easily lead you down a path where you are breaking a law without even possibly realizing it,” says Palmer. The “I didn’t know” defense typically doesn’t absolve someone in the eyes of the law, even if it leads to a lesser penalty.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s also true that sometimes — if you’re already wealthy or in the right, secretive financial circles — you can <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/jun/28/how-to-get-away-with-financial-fraud">get away with fraud</a> for many years. You can wade in the muddy waters where the law is untested on whether you’re only <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/2024/3/13/24086102/billionaires-wealthy-tax-avoidance-loopholes">minimizing the taxes you owe</a> or outright evading them. Tax laws and benefits are already structured to <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/billionaires-tax-avoidance-techniques-irs-files">favor capital and the ultra-rich</a>, and even if you get into legal trouble, you can hire lawyers to mount a strong challenge in court. But for the vast majority of us, there simply isn’t a shortcut to making a heap of money.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump’s biggest fans aren’t who you think]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/369797/trump-support-class-local-rich-arlie-hochschild" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369797</id>
			<updated>2024-09-03T23:08:16Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-04T11:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In her forthcoming book Stolen Pride, sociologist Arlie Russell Hochschild describes her time spent in the towns and hollers of Kentucky’s Fifth Congressional District — one of the whitest, poorest, and most-Trump-supporting districts in the entire country. During her time there, she noticed something interesting about who tended to be most excited about the Trump [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Trump yells to a crowd of supporters." data-caption="A Trump rally in Lexington, Kentucky, on November 4, 2019. | Bryan Woolston/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Bryan Woolston/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-1180018937.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A Trump rally in Lexington, Kentucky, on November 4, 2019. | Bryan Woolston/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In her forthcoming book <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Stolen-Pride-Loss-Shame-Right/dp/1620976463"><em>Stolen Pride</em></a>, sociologist Arlie Russell Hochschild describes her time spent in the towns and hollers of Kentucky’s Fifth Congressional District — one of the whitest, poorest, and most-Trump-supporting districts in the entire country. During her time there, she noticed something interesting about who tended to be most excited about the Trump movement.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Those most enthralled with Donald Trump were not at the very bottom — the illiterate, the hungry,” she writes. Rather, Trump’s biggest fans could be found among “the elite of the left-behind,” meaning people “who were doing well within a region that was not.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s an observation that cuts against <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/8/4/23818817/trump-support-david-brooks-economic-anxiety">the prevailing theory of Trumpism</a>: that he is the tribune of the left-behind and impoverished white people suffering due to globalization. It is also one that is backed by hard data.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.scholars.northwestern.edu/en/publications/nationally-poor-locally-rich-income-and-local-context-in-the-2016">In 2020</a>, three political scientists studied <a href="https://statmodeling.stat.columbia.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Ogorzalek-Piston-and-Puig-2020-Nationally-rich-locally-poor.pdf">how location and income affected white voters’ voting decisions</a>. They found that, on a national level, poorer white people were indeed more likely to vote for Trump than richer ones.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But when you factored in local conditions —&nbsp;the fact that your dollar can buy more in <a href="https://www.payscale.com/cost-of-living-calculator/Mississippi-Biloxi">Biloxi</a> than <a href="https://www.payscale.com/cost-of-living-calculator/Massachusetts-Boston">Boston</a> — the relationship reverses. “Locally rich” white people, those who had higher incomes than others in their zip codes, were much more likely to support Trump than those who were locally poor. These people might make less money than a wealthy person in a big city, but were doing relatively well when compared to their neighbors.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Put those two results together, and you get a picture that aligns precisely with Hochschild’s observations. Trump’s strongest support comes from people who live in poorer parts of the country, like KY-5, but are still able to live a relatively comfortable life there.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what does this mean for how we understand the Trump-era right? It cuts through the seemingly interminable debate about Trump’s appeal to “left behind” voters and helps us understand the actual complexity of the right’s appeals to region and class in the United States. America’s divisions are rooted in less income inequality per se than is widely appreciated, and often tied to divisions inside of communities and social groups.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <em>Stolen Pride</em>, Hochschild locates the heart of Trump’s appeal to rural voters in emotions of pride and shame — including pride in their region’s traditions and shame in what it’s become in an era of declining coal jobs and rising drug addiction.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Roger Ford, a KY-5 entrepreneur and Republican activist who serves as Hochschild’s exemplar of Trump’s “locally rich” base, Trump helps resolve those emotions by offering someone to blame. Ford may not be suffering personally, but his region is&nbsp;— and Trump’s rage at liberal coastal elites helps him locate a villain outside of his own community.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“He based his deepest sense of pride, it seemed, on his role of defender of his imperiled rural homeland from which so much had been lost — or, as it could feel, ‘stolen,’” she writes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ford’s comments to Hochschild shift seamlessly between economic and cultural grievances. In discussing his opposition to transgender rights, he situates it as the latest in a long line of dislocations that people in his region faced. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“With all we’re coping with here, we’re having a hard <em>enough</em> time,” he tells Hochschild. “Then you make it fashionable to choose your gender? Where are we going?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This comment might make it seem as if economic concerns are somehow prior to cultural ones, and people like Ford are angry at transgender people because of economic deprivation in coal country. But high-quality research tells a different, more complicated story.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2022, scholars Kristin Lunz Trujillo and Zack Crowley examined the political consequences of <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0962629822000725">what they call “rural consciousness” for politics</a>. They divide this consciousness into three component parts: “a feeling that ruralites are underrepresented in decision-making (‘Representation’) and that their way of life is disrespected (‘Way of Life’) — both symbolic concerns — and a more materialistic concern that rural areas receive less resources (‘Resources’).”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When they tried to use these different “subdimensions” of rural consciousness to predict Trump support among rural voters, they found something interesting. People who saw the plight of ruralities in cultural and political terms were most likely to support Trump, while those primarily concerned about rural poverty were, if anything, less likely to support him than their neighbors.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Taken together, these findings suggest that the story isn’t simply that economic deprivation breeds cultural resentment. Trump’s strongest supporters in rural areas tend to be angry that their regions don’t set the social terms of American life: that they don’t control the halls of power and that, as a consequence, both political and cultural life is moving away from what they’re comfortable with. Economic decline surely exacerbates this sense of alienation, but <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Reactionary-Spirit-Insidious-Political-Tradition-ebook/dp/B0CMQB8S94">it isn’t at the heart of it</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This more sophisticated understanding of rural white politics contributes to a <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2021/09/trump-american-gentry-wyman-elites/620151/">broader</a> literature <a href="https://www.dissentmagazine.org/article/family-capitalism-and-the-small-business-insurrection/">complicating</a> how we think of Trumpism’s class base, be it <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2021/09/trump-american-gentry-wyman-elites/620151/">Floridian boat paraders</a> or <a href="https://www.dissentmagazine.org/article/family-capitalism-and-the-small-business-insurrection/">GOP mega-donors</a>. This body of work suggests that the conventional class shorthands political commentators use — rural versus urban, elite versus the working class, the one percent versus the rest — are of limited utility in discussing the political economy of Trumpism. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To really understand what’s happening on the right today, we need to pay attention to the divisions within these broad groupings.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Caitlin PenzeyMoog</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Organize your kitchen like a chef, not an influencer]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/369691/kitchen-tips-organization-chef-fridge-tiktok-influencers" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369691</id>
			<updated>2024-09-03T20:05:53Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-04T10:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re a regular on TikTok or Instagram, you may feel your kitchen is under attack. It started with #CleanTok, wherein cleanliness influencers shared tips for sparkling stainless steel sinks and competed to have the most hygienic kitchen. Then, influencers got more ambitious with “decanting” videos documenting a method of pantry organization involving transferring foodstuffs [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/kitchen-organization.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re a regular on TikTok or Instagram, you may feel your kitchen is under attack.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It started with <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/discover/CleanTok?lang=en">#CleanTok</a>, wherein <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/24031823/cleantok-cleanliness-tiktok-performative-hygiene">cleanliness influencers</a> shared tips for sparkling stainless steel sinks and competed to have the most hygienic kitchen. Then, influencers got more ambitious with “<a href="https://www.eater.com/24105047/you-dont-need-to-decant-your-groceries-kitchen-storage">decanting</a>” videos documenting a method of pantry organization involving transferring foodstuffs from the grocery store packaging to clear containers in neat rows.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now it’s “fridgescaping.” This is roughly what it sounds like: The interiors of refrigerators are organized and decorated, with the most popular posts of the genre featuring fridges that look less like cold storage and more like a bohemian fairy garden. Milk goes in farmhouse pitchers, eggs line up ceramic trays, and butter hides under dishes shaped like animals. Berries, ever ubiquitous, are placed attractively in vintage bowls, raw vegetables stand at attention, and items that have no place in a fridge — bouquets of flowers, photos in frames, string lights — are given prominent placement. That the refrigerators are meticulously clean is a given, and they’re often new and large.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-tiktok wp-block-embed-tiktok"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@lynziliving/video/7400918601911389470" data-video-id="7400918601911389470" data-embed-from="oembed"> <section> <a target="_blank" title="@lynziliving" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@lynziliving?refer=embed">@lynziliving</a> <p>A Hobbit refrigerator has been my most requested fridgescape theme ever, so I went on a quest to tackle it. I’ve honesty been very nervous because I really wanted to do it justice for everyone. I was heavily influenced by Bilbo Baggins’ kitchen in The Hobbit right down to the doilies! This was also very similar in a lot of ways to Outlander with the very primitive style dishware and fresh herbs and plethora of textures. It was very fun to create as I’m currently vibing the natural texture in the refrigerator.  I wish I had been recording, but when Dave opened the refrigerator he was so excited. It’s his favorite one yet. I love getting his refrigerator stamp of approval. 😭😭  Side note: the bread was eaten for dinner. It’s fine, I promise. 😂 I also forgot the potatoes. 😭 <a title="theshire" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/theshire?refer=embed">#theshire</a> <a title="shire" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/shire?refer=embed">#shire</a> <a title="thehobbit" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/thehobbit?refer=embed">#thehobbit</a> <a title="hobbithouse" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/hobbithouse?refer=embed">#hobbithouse</a> <a title="hobbitcore" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/hobbitcore?refer=embed">#hobbitcore</a> <a title="hobbithome" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/hobbithome?refer=embed">#hobbithome</a> <a title="lordoftherings" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/lordoftherings?refer=embed">#lordoftherings</a> <a title="fridgescaping" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fridgescaping?refer=embed">#fridgescaping</a> <a title="fridgescape" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fridgescape?refer=embed">#fridgescape</a> <a title="refrigeratororganization" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/refrigeratororganization?refer=embed">#refrigeratororganization</a> <a title="fridgeorganization" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fridgeorganization?refer=embed">#fridgeorganization</a> <a title="kitchenorganization" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/kitchenorganization?refer=embed">#kitchenorganization</a> <a title="kitchendecor" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/kitchendecor?refer=embed">#kitchendecor</a> </p> <a target="_blank" title="♬ The Shire: Concerning Hobbits (From Lord of the Rings) - San Fernando Symphonic Assembly" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/The-Shire-Concerning-Hobbits-From-Lord-of-the-Rings-6791379316836927489?refer=embed">♬ The Shire: Concerning Hobbits (From Lord of the Rings) &#8211; San Fernando Symphonic Assembly</a> </section> </blockquote> 
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a trend piece, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/03/style/fridgescaping-fridge-decorating-tiktok.html">the New York Times declared</a> “[N]ot even the inside of your fridge is safe from decorating.” It reports on fridgescaping as a “creative outlet” for some and, according to one influencer, a means to make food “more accessible” to her three young children. Another tells the Times that spending three hours on a forest-themed fridge is worth it because she is “more excited” to eat her produce.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>It’s hard to fathom that influencers are meticulously creating a <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@lynziliving/video/7400918601911389470"><em>Hobbit</em>-inspired fridgescape</a> and buying so much produce that their fridge <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@jenefertaylor/video/7150726446682623275?lang=en">looks like</a> a Dutch Golden Age still life</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As someone with a cooking background — my father has been a chef for 35 years, my mother’s side of the family runs a spice business, and I grew up running around commercial kitchens and worked for a year as a line cook, in addition to writing <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Spice-Advice-Wisdom-History-Saltiness/dp/1510735259">a book on spices</a> — I find myself deeply disturbed by fridgescaping. It is, I believe, the culmination of a series of trends that serve to alienate people from food. It removes all the labor, the mess, the physicality, and the pleasure inherent in eating, and replaces it with public performance. There are better ways to organize a kitchen, techniques that can improve functionality and prioritize goals like reducing food waste — and, yes, that could even lead to eating more fruits and vegetables.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The rise of fridgescaping</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Cooking at home for the majority of us not wealthy enough to outsource it requires an immense amount of time and labor: coming up with a meal plan, making a list, going to the store, shopping, unloading, chopping, sautéing, simmering, and doing the dishes after. This is out of reach for <a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/topics/food-nutrition-assistance/food-security-in-the-u-s/key-statistics-graphics/">millions of Americans</a> experiencing food insecurity, the many millions more living with low food security, or those who simply don’t have enough hours in the day.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-tiktok wp-block-embed-tiktok"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@shabazsays/video/7384908970835594528" data-video-id="7384908970835594528" data-embed-from="oembed"> <section> <a target="_blank" title="@shabazsays" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@shabazsays?refer=embed">@shabazsays</a> <p>If you’re not fridgescaping.. what are you doing?  🤯🤯<a title="duet" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/duet?refer=embed">#duet</a> <a title="stitch" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/stitch?refer=embed">#stitch</a> with  @lynziliving <a title="fridgescaping" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fridgescaping?refer=embed">#fridgescaping</a> <a title="restock" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/restock?refer=embed">#restock</a> <a title="restocking" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/restocking?refer=embed">#restocking</a> <a title="bridgeton" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/bridgeton?refer=embed">#bridgeton</a> </p> <a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - Shabaz Says" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-7384909007951317793?refer=embed">♬ original sound &#8211; Shabaz Says</a> </section> </blockquote> 
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given that reality, it’s hard to fathom that influencers are meticulously creating a <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@lynziliving/video/7400918601911389470"><em>Hobbit</em>-inspired fridgescape</a> and buying so much produce that their fridge <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@jenefertaylor/video/7150726446682623275?lang=en">looks like</a> a Dutch Golden Age still life. It goes without saying that fridgescaping — and its pantry cousin, decanting — prioritizes displaying and arranging food, instead of preparing and eating it. That’s not to mention all the unnecessary aesthetic upkeep, like changing out the water of that bouquet. Imagine doing all that and also recording yourself doing it, then sitting down to edit the footage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That is to say: Fridgescaping is a scam of the classic keeping-up-with-the-Joneses variety for the TikTok age. In these clips, hours of labor are squeezed into 30 seconds of beautification, following the before-and-after formula so successful on social media. These videos suggest you too can have the beauty and bounty of a fridge decked out <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@lynziliving/video/7381862181010181407"><em>Bridgerton</em> style</a> if you <a href="https://www.shopltk.com/explore/Lynziliving/productsets/11ef1bc31026792d929a0242ac11002d">purchase</a> the additional storage and knickknacks. Conveniently, you can click a link and buy everything you see from the influencer’s online store, where they receive a cut. <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@lynziliving/video/7407151543646014751">Plenty</a> of rationalizations exist (the produce!) but they’re undercut when those same creators urge their followers to “shop my fridge!”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s very easy to connect any capitalist endeavor to food,” said <a href="https://utulsa.edu/people/emily-contois/">Emily Contois</a>, an associate professor of media studies at the University of Tulsa and co-editor of <a href="https://www.press.uillinois.edu/books/?id=58mye9fd9780252044465"><em>Food Instagram</em></a>, “because it’s something we have to do to survive — but it’s also something we genuinely want to do because it’s pleasurable, and doing it with other people, eating it with other people, preparing it with other people can also bring such profound pleasure.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Add in the gendered expectations around food preparation and cleaning, and fridgescaping can be seen as yet another domestic task expected of women: to not only shop, cook, and clean the kitchen, but to make it all look beautiful, too.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Your kitchen should be a space of purpose, not just aesthetics</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I no longer cook professionally, but as a regular working person who cooks daily in a well-functioning home kitchen with an average amount of storage space,<strong> </strong>I have good news: You don’t need to live a life of ample wealth and leisure to smartly organize your kitchen. There are free or very cheap ways to do it with function in mind, without totally sacrificing aesthetics (although you won’t be needing fairy lights anytime soon).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I consulted with the chefs in my life — my dad Brian Moog, and my brother-in-law Justin Behlke — for their practical advice on making the best use of your own time, space, and labor — and, as an avid home cook, added some tried-and-true tips of my own.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Make your produce last much longer</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You should store most fresh produce in the refrigerator to maximize lifespan and give space and air to anything that’s packed tightly together to help it stay good for longer — I guess you’d call that a kind of decanting.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“You can look at how they’re storing produce in the store,” my dad said. “If they’re storing something in water, like asparagus, you can do that at home too.” In addition to freeing the asparagus from their rubber band, he cuts the bottom of the stems, like flowers, and puts them in half an inch of water in a deli container in the fridge, where they last up to 10 days. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He also removes lettuces and pre-cut greens from bags and clamshells and places them in&nbsp;airtight containers with paper towels at the bottom and top. Raspberries, blackberries, and strawberries are likewise placed in a single layer on a piece of paper towel in airtight containers. Heads of lettuce, kale, herbs, and scallions can be simply wrapped in dry paper towels to achieve similar results.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For my dad and brother-in-law, paper towels are the secret weapon to keeping produce fresh. As fruits and lettuces spend time in the fridge, moisture leaks out, which condenses and leads to the foods going bad faster. You want paper towels to absorb that excess. “The amount of paper towels I use …” Justin said. “There are all sorts of specialty containers, but usually those specific things are marketing gimmicks.” (For those who want a reusable option, try plain cotton or linen napkins to achieve a similar keep-fresh effect.)</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>Paper towels are the secret weapon to keeping produce fresh</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So don’t be ashamed of paper towel use. “There’s a lot of value in paper towels,” Justin said. “There’s balance to keep in mind, but there’s a lot of practicality.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Flour is the only dry good he puts in a plastic container, with a lid that’s easy to get off and an opening wide enough to dip a measuring cup into — mostly because flour bags create a mess every time they’re opened. “Keeping yourself and the cooking area clean saves time,” he said. “It seems nominal but it adds up.” That’s the kind of practical consideration you should keep in mind as you’re making your own kitchen decisions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I also recommend putting brown sugar in an air-tight container. After years of gouging it, rock-hard, from the bag, I can pop off the lid and scoop soft, moist sugar.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Keep perishables front and center</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fridgescaping influencers talk a lot about how their methods help them keep track of their produce, but a few simpler methods achieve the same results.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s true that “out of sight, out of mind” is a cursed reality when it comes to perishables in the fridge, so keep short shelf life items at the front.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don’t use the crisper drawers for fruits and veggies. I put condiments in one and, being a Wisconsinite, cheese in the other. I know certain produce lasts longer in the crisper drawers, but all that meant for me was produce languishing there for a few extra days because I’d forget about it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, if your household consumes meat, try putting it in a see-through plastic container at the front. This keeps it front of mind and cordons it off from other food.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The real key to my family’s approach to reducing food waste is the use of a whiteboard on the fridge, where we note the meals we’ve bought ingredients for. Seeing those meals listed reminds us about the foods likely to go bad fastest, so we cook those first.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We also keep a running shopping list on a second whiteboard. Whenever we’re low or out of something, we add it to the list, so by the time we’re going shopping we’re not trying to remember everything we need.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>You don’t need to buy expensive plastic “storage systems”</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You don’t need professional-grade equipment or specialty gadgets, but professional-grade storage is key. For a lot of chefs, this means deli containers and cambros.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.webstaurantstore.com/779/deli-take-out-containers.html?srsltid=AfmBOoob6HEfRB8Do4xUff1usM9FoID_WrNkpHi9Z3ULOMS6sO_6_Msl">Delis</a> are round plastic storage containers most commonly used in <a href="https://www.webstaurantstore.com/choicehd-32-oz-microwavable-translucent-plastic-deli-container-and-lid-combo-pack-case/128HD32COMBO.html">32-ounce</a>, <a href="https://www.webstaurantstore.com/choicehd-16-oz-microwavable-translucent-plastic-deli-container-and-lid-combo-pack-case/128HD16COMBO.html">16-ounce</a>, and <a href="https://www.webstaurantstore.com/choicehd-8-oz-microwavable-translucent-plastic-deli-container-and-lid-combo-pack-case/128HD8COMBO.html">8-ounce</a> sizes. They stack in the cupboard, saving room, but also when used in the fridge, freezer, or pantry, regardless of which size you’re using. They’re a staple in restaurant kitchens, and they’re cheap and sturdy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.webstaurantstore.com/3087/food-storage-containers.html?vendor=Cambro">Cambros</a> are larger containers made of thick, sturdy plastic with tough lids. A couple of these live on top of our fridge, and we pull them down to use as a mixing bowl, to make dough, and to cook big batches of food. The square cambros are ideal for storing large-batch leftovers, prepped ingredients (like chopped onions and carrots), and soups,&nbsp;they take up just as much room as a mixing bowl but because of their square shape they fit more efficiently and stack more readily.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Use tape to label the food in the delis and cambros (no, you don’t need to cut it with scissors like they do on <em><a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/358672/the-bear-season-3-review-food-main-character-fine-dining">The Bear</a></em>). Noting the date something was made can come in handy in both the short and long term. A “made on” date attached to leftovers containing meat, for example, is helpful when deciding whether to dig back in after a few days. And for items that won’t spoil, like syrups or caramel, it’s helpful when clearing out the fridge to realize which products have been occupying valuable real estate for six months without being used. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/IMG_5775_f51367.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,15.095986038394,100,69.808027923211" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A shelf in the author’s pantry. | Caitlin PenzeyMoog" data-portal-copyright="Caitlin PenzeyMoog" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">For pantry organization, try recycling old containers or using what you have instead of buying new ones. For instance, I use my loaf tins for granola bars and baby crackers on a pantry shelf to make the packages more accessible.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don’t buy the idea that putting everything in clear plastic containers is helpful. I know how much cereal is left in the box every time I pour it into a bowl; I know how much mustard is left each time I squirt it out. When I notice them running low, I add them to the running grocery list.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Kitchen organization is a process, not a one-off event</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My dad and Justin both say that organizing a kitchen is less an exercise in perfection and more about refining as you go along. “My biggest piece of advice is to remain conscious,” my dad told me. “I’ve set up a lot of kitchens, and I see the angst of it. People want to be able to move into a new space and put every item in the best place, but that’s just not realistic.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Don’t worry about finding the right spot for each and every item. Know that you’ll figure it out with an open mind combined with time spent in the kitchen. “It takes time. It takes trial and error,” my dad told me. “You just need to exist in your kitchen space for a while before you set it up perfectly.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My dad is still fine-tuning his own organizational scheme. He recently realized pasta rollers were taking up a prime spot in a drawer when he hadn’t made pasta from scratch in two years. “It’s time to go to the basement,” he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“One day you’ll realize, ‘this just doesn’t work here,’ and you’ll move it to the right spot,” said Justin. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A kitchen is a living and ripening room. Not only will items gravitate to the correct spots, but those spots will likely evolve. Farmers market hauls in the summer require a different setup than cookie-baking season in the winter, and that’s to say nothing of new functions needed in a kitchen when a baby is born or a new roommate moves in. Even when you’ve achieved a well-functioning kitchen, it’s helpful to internalize Heraclitus’s adage that the only constant in life is change. “It’s a mindset,” my dad said. Somebody just needs to tell the fridgescapers.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Eric Levitz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Harris is swimming in cash — but Democrats may still have a fundraising problem]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/369878/kamala-harris-fundraising-transfer-state-legislature-abortion" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369878</id>
			<updated>2024-09-03T23:02:13Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-04T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Democrats have been raining cash on their presidential nominee like it’s confetti. Vice President Kamala Harris’ campaign raised $204 million in July — more than four times the $48 million former President Donald Trump brought in, according to new filings with the Federal Election Commission. This was enough to erase the Republican nominee’s previous cash advantage; at [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris, in a white suit, smiles behind a pair of microphones." data-caption="Vice President and presidential candidate Kamala Harris speaks at a campaign rally in Savannah, Georgia, on August 29. | Peter Zay/Anadolu via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Peter Zay/Anadolu via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2168350036.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President and presidential candidate Kamala Harris speaks at a campaign rally in Savannah, Georgia, on August 29. | Peter Zay/Anadolu via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats have been raining cash on their presidential nominee like it’s confetti.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"> Vice President Kamala Harris’ campaign raised $204 million in July — more than four times the $48 million former President Donald Trump <a href="https://docquery.fec.gov/cgi-bin/forms/C00828541/1812280/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">brought in</a>, according to <a href="https://docquery.fec.gov/cgi-bin/forms/C00703975/1812381/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new filings with the Federal Election Commission</a>. This was enough to erase the Republican nominee’s previous cash advantage; at the start of August, Harris <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/08/21/trump-harris-campaign-spending-fec-00175377">had</a> $220 million in cash on hand, while Trump held just $151 million. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Official data on August fundraising has yet to be released. But there’s reason to believe that Harris’s money advantage grew last month, due in part to the Democratic National Convention. According to the Democrat’s campaign, it <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/harris-raises-540-million-since-launching-her-presidential-campaign-2024-08-25/">raised $540 million</a> in the first six weeks since President Joe Biden handed off the nomination. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet this torrential downpour of campaign cash hasn’t trickled down the Democratic ballot: Even as Harris has begun outraising Trump, the Republican committee responsible for funding GOP state legislative candidates has amassed far more money than its Democratic counterpart.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From January 2023 through the second quarter of this year, the Democratic Legislative Campaign Committee (DLCC) — the body tasked with electing Democratic state legislators — had raised $35 million, according to the committee. Over the same period, its GOP rival, the Republican State Leadership Committee (RSLC), had <a href="https://www.nationalreview.com/corner/two-gop-spending-groups-raise-15-million-in-second-quarter-to-boost-down-ballot-republicans/">raised $62 million</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those figures do not include the fundraising of party-aligned outside groups that focus on state legislative races. In recent years, progressive organizations such as <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2023/01/michigan-democrats-2022-midterm-results-the-states-project.html">The States Project</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/3/9/17092822/foward-majority-liberal-super-pac-state-legislatures-2018-midterms">Forward Majority</a> have spent large sums on state-level races. It’s possible that when super PACs are taken into account, the GOP loses its apparent cash advantage. Then again, there are also conservative outside groups, such as <a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/news/2024/01/koch-network-super-pac-ramping-up-political-activity-2024-election/">Americans For Prosperity Action,</a> that invest in down-ballot elections. What we know for sure is that, when it comes to the parties themselves, Republicans are outraising Democrats in the fight for statehouses.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That fight is often neglected by the national spotlight — but it can have profound implications for Americans’ daily lives.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Harris campaign appears to be conscious of its party’s down-ballot challenges. This week, it <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/elections/2024/09/03/harris-25-million-transfer/">transferred $2.5 million</a> of its own funds to the DLCC. Yet that largesse scarcely narrows the RSLC’s cash advantage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, only Democratic donors can ensure that the GOP enjoys no down-ballot edge. Given blue America’s current enthusiasm and engagement, this should be possible — at least, if liberals come to appreciate the high stakes, and low cost, of winning state legislative races.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Small elections can have big consequences</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In our nation’s federal system, a great deal of policy is set at the state level. It is a state’s governor and legislature — not Congress — that primarily determines its public education spending and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/24136266/housing-states-affordable-rent-homes">housing policies</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the parties have polarized ideologically, so have policy outcomes between states with Democratic and Republican governments. Whether Democrats or Republicans wield power in a given state can determine whether its working-class families have access to <a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/health-law-and-business/state-medicaid-expansion-gains-momentum-despite-gop-opposition">affordable health insurance</a>, or its parents <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/article/the-state-of-paid-family-and-medical-leave-in-the-u-s-in-2024/">receive paid leave</a>, or its labor unions can <a href="https://www.nber.org/digest/202208/impacts-right-work-laws-unionization-and-wages">fend off rapid decline.</a>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the wake of the Supreme Court’s overturning of <em>Roe v.Wade</em>, the stakes of state legislative elections became even higher. Throughout much of the country, the right to an abortion has become contingent on the outcomes of down-ballot races.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/us/abortion-laws-roe-v-wade.html">22 states</a> that currently ban abortion — or restrict access to the procedure more tightly than <em>Roe</em> did — have GOP-controlled state legislatures. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/05/02/state-houses-next-battle-abortion-rights/">all 16 states</a> that have enacted new abortion protections since the end of <em>Roe </em>are governed by Democrats. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Arizona narrowly averted a near-total ban on abortion this year, thanks largely to the Democratic Party’s large minorities in both the state Senate and House. When the Supreme Court overturned <em>Roe</em>, the state’s 1864 abortion law went into effect. Only five of Arizona’s Republican state legislators <a href="https://apnews.com/article/arizona-abortion-1864-ban-repeal-24578e546b69ca087e01034bcaf4aa01">supported</a> repealing that archaic statute. But this was enough to enact a law overturning it, as Democrats <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Arizona_House_of_Representatives">lay claim</a> to 29 of the state’s 60 House seats and 14 of its 30 state senators. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, a ban on abortions after 15 weeks remains in effect in the state. A November <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Arizona_Proposition_139,_Right_to_Abortion_Initiative_(2024)">ballot measure</a> could nullify that law by enshrining abortion rights into the state’s constitution. If it fails, however, Democrats could also expand abortion rights legislatively by flipping a tiny number of state legislative seats.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">State legislative races are a bargain</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the stakes of state legislative races are high, the cost of meaningfully influencing their outcomes can be remarkably low.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2022, Democrats won control of the Minnesota state Senate by a single seat — which Democratic state Sen. Judy Seeberger won <a href="https://www.axios.com/local/twin-cities/2023/05/04/minnesota-democrats-progressive-bills-moderate-divide">by just 321 votes</a>. Seeberger’s <a href="https://www.followthemoney.org/entity-details?eid=55630218&amp;default=candidate">campaign cost</a> $123,992, while her Republican opponent <a href="https://www.followthemoney.org/entity-details?eid=19069432">raised</a> $137,143. In a race that tight and inexpensive, it’s conceivable that a dozen small-dollar donations could have tipped the balance in Seeberger’s favor. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whatever the exact cost of Seeberger’s narrow victory, her donors got an extraordinary bang for their buck. With their single-vote Senate majority, Minnesota Democrats established paid <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/politics-policy/2023/04/legislators-work-out-details-of-bill-that-would-create-a-paid-family-and-medical-leave-program-in-minnesota/">family and medical leave</a>, barred <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/jun/07/minnesota-pro-worker-paid-leave-union">non-compete clauses</a> in labor contracts, banned employers from holding compulsory anti-union meetings, bolstered workplace protections for meatpacking and Amazon workers, formed a statewide board to set minimum labor standards for nursing-home workers, directed <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/greater-minnesota/2023/05/why-lawmakers-finally-reached-a-deal-on-bonding-and-what-it-means-for-infrastructure-in-greater-minnesota/">$2.58 billion</a> into improved infrastructure, made <a href="https://www.startribune.com/minnesota-gov-tim-walz-signs-free-school-meals-bill-into-law/600259831/">school breakfast and lunch free</a> for all Minnesota K-12 students, restored the <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/state-government/2023/02/minnesota-supreme-court-state-can-bar-felons-from-voting-until-probation-ends/">voting rights</a> of ex-felons, invested $1 billion into <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/state-government/2023/05/minnesota-legislative-big-big-deal-spends-1b-on-affordable-housing-adds-metro-sales-tax/">affordable housing</a>, imposed background checks on private gun transfers, initiated a <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/state-government/2023/05/four-takeaways-from-the-dfls-vote-to-approve-gun-regulations/">red-flag warning system</a> to remove firearms from people courts deem to be a threat to themselves or others, <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/state-government/2023/05/minnesotas-soon-to-be-law-allowing-recreational-marijuana-explained/">legalized recreational marijuana</a>, and mandated that utilities go <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/environment/2023/02/how-small-city-utilities-are-grappling-with-minnesotas-new-100-carbon-free-standard/">carbon-free</a> by 2040, among other measures. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Were it not for 321 votes — and quite plausibly, a few thousand dollars of campaign contributions to Seeberger — few, if any, of these reforms would have passed. What’s more, it’s possible that Seeberger’s victory was also responsible for Gov. Tim Walz’s ascent to the Democratic ticket: Thanks to Minnesota’s flurry of legislating, Walz became a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/06/04/democratic-party-minnesota-legislature-progressives/">nationally renowned</a> progressive darling, which might well have put him on Harris’s radar. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This November, Democrats have a chance to replicate their 2022 triumph in Minnesota. The party has an <a href="https://penncapital-star.com/election-2024/can-democrats-flip-the-pennsylvania-senate-for-a-trifecta/">outside shot</a> at winning a narrow majority in Pennsylvania’s state Senate, thereby giving the party a trifecta in the Keystone State and unlocking all manner of liberal reforms. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The party also has a chance of accomplishing a similar feat in Wisconsin, where GOP gerrymanders had previously all but guaranteed Republican state legislative control. Last year, the state’s Supreme Court <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/wisconsin-supreme-court-strikes-gop-drawn-legislative-maps-rcna130983">declared</a> such gerrymanders unconstitutional, and forced <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/2/20/24078666/new-wisconsin-legislative-maps-legislature">the composition of new electoral maps</a> that feature a roughly even split of Democratic-leaning and Republican-leaning districts. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Michigan and Minnesota, meanwhile, the party is fighting to defend existing trifectas, and enable further policy gains.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democratic donors’ fixation on presidential politics is understandable. The stakes of keeping Donald Trump out of power are certainly high. But tossing another $20 (or even $2,000) onto Harris’s $540 million pile is much less likely to meaningfully change Americans’ lives than making a similar contribution to a pivotal state legislative campaign. At the national level, the cost of progress is exorbitant. In the right down-ballot races, however, it retails at a steep discount.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Abdallah Fayyad</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How a disease the world (mostly) vanquished reared its head in Gaza]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/369872/polio-gaza-who-vaccination-campaign-israel" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369872</id>
			<updated>2024-09-03T21:39:28Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-04T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Vaccines" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For 25 years, there had not been a single confirmed case of polio in Gaza. But after 10 months of Israel’s war in the strip — which has devastated the health care system and created dangerous and unsanitary conditions for Palestinians — a baby became partially paralyzed last month after contracting the disease.&#160; As the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="A child receives a polio vaccine in Deir al Balah, Gaza on September 01, 2024. | Ashraf Amra / Anadolu via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Ashraf Amra / Anadolu via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2168978397.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A child receives a polio vaccine in Deir al Balah, Gaza on September 01, 2024. | Ashraf Amra / Anadolu via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">For 25 years, there had not been a single confirmed case of polio in Gaza. But after 10 months of Israel’s war in the strip — which has devastated the health care system and created dangerous and unsanitary conditions for Palestinians — a <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cevjz7zreyxo">baby</a> became partially paralyzed last month after contracting the disease.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the virus spread in the besieged enclave, UN Secretary-General António Guterres <a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2024/08/1153276">called for</a> an immediate humanitarian ceasefire to allow for a mass vaccination campaign in Gaza. Since then, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn02z5kjn40o">Israel has agreed</a> to a series of three-day humanitarian pauses in the northern, central, and southern parts of the strip. As of Monday, the World Health Organization (WHO) said that vaccination efforts have hit their targets so far, reaching more than <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy8xwxjy4y7o">161,000 children under 10</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there is still a long way to go before health officials can declare that polio is no longer a public health threat in Gaza. To get there, WHO <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/03/world/middleeast/polio-vaccinations-gaza-who.html">must reach 90 percent</a> of children under 10, or an estimated 640,000. Each child needs to receive two rounds of vaccines, and the second round of vaccinations is <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/polio-vaccination-campaign-gaza-israel-world-health-organzation/">set to start four weeks</a> after the first doses are administered. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That makes the vaccination drive hard to implement, especially if the war continues between humanitarian pauses because more people will be displaced and more infrastructure will be destroyed. If Israel continues issuing evacuation orders or its attacks on infrastructure in Gaza, for example, it will be “very difficult for humanitarian actors to move around and be able to provide vaccines for not only polio but for other diseases,” said Julia Bleckner, senior health researcher at Human Rights Watch.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The nearly eradicated disease poses a serious risk for Palestinians in Gaza. And while health officials say it’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/30/health/polio-gaza-vaccines.html">impossible to tell</a> if polio cases will remain contained, experts warn that a broader outbreak is possible and could have consequences for the region and <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/31/nx-s1-5095736/children-in-gaza-get-polio-vaccines-but-the-virus-may-already-be-spreading">potentially spread beyond</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How did polio make a comeback in Gaza?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Polio, which <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/poliomyelitis#:~:text=Polio%20mainly%20affects%20children%20under,protect%20a%20child%20for%20life.">mostly affects children</a> under 5, is a highly infectious disease that attacks the nervous system and can quickly cause total and permanent paralysis. While there’s no cure, it can be prevented through vaccines, which is why most countries have been able to successfully eradicate the disease. In fact, since the <a href="https://polioeradication.org/who-we-are/">Global Polio Eradication Initiative</a> launched in 1988, confirmed polio cases have decreased by <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/global-polio-vaccination/about/index.html#:~:text=Since%20the%20launch%20of%20GPEI,two%20countries%3A%20Afghanistan%20and%20Pakistan.">99 percent around the world</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For decades, Gaza was an area where polio was considered to be eradicated. But in July, health officials <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/what-is-known-about-polios-return-gaza-strip-2024-08-30/">detected the polio virus</a> in wastewater samples in Khan Younis and Deir al Balah, in southern and central Gaza. ​​“Left unchecked, [the poliovirus] would have a disastrous effect not only for Palestinian children in Gaza, but also in neighboring countries and the region,” Guterres <a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2024/08/1153276">said last month</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The spread of polio in Gaza is likely the result of what are known as vaccine-derived strains of the virus. One version of the polio vaccine works by exposing people to a live but weakened form of the poliovirus. As a result, people who receive that vaccine can shed some of that weakened virus, usually in wastewater. If that virus is allowed to keep circulating through a community for long enough, it can eventually turn back into the kind of strain that can get people sick.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Overcrowded areas with poor sanitation <a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/disease-outbreak-news/item/2024-DON500#:~:text=On%20rare%20occasions%2C%20when%20replicating,%2C%20poor%20sanitation%2C%20or%20overcrowding.">are especially vulnerable</a> to spreading the virus through contaminated food or water —&nbsp;and those are exactly the conditions Palestinians in Gaza have been living in since the war started last October, particularly since Israel <a href="https://www.oxfam.org/en/press-releases/israel-using-water-weapon-war-gaza-supply-plummets-94-creating-deadly-health#:~:text=Israel%20has%20destroyed%2070%25%20of,of%20Oxfam%20water%20testing%20equipment.">has attacked</a> water and sanitation infrastructure.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Add to that the fact that this war has significantly reduced the number of vaccinated people in Gaza. Before October 2023, 99 percent of people in the strip had been routinely immunized, but that number dropped to lower than 90 percent in the first three months of this year, <a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2024/09/1153851">according to the WHO</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That this is the first polio case in 25 years is “not a coincidence,” Bleckner said.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Will enough Palestinians be vaccinated in time?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The most pressing concern for health officials is to ensure that 90 percent of Palestinian children under 10 are vaccinated as quickly as possible. So far, the results of the campaign have been promising: According to the WHO, the 160,000 children <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-attacks-gaza-kill-33-palestinians-pauses-allow-third-day-polio-2024-09-03/">vaccinated</a> in the first two days of its drive have surpassed the agency’s projection of reaching 150,000 children at this point.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it’s unclear how sustainable that success will be given that the war is still ongoing. As humanitarian pauses lift, obstacles could emerge that could prevent health officials from meeting their targets. Last week, for example, the United Nations said that Israel’s near-constant evacuation orders have <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/aug/27/gaza-polio-vaccine-rollout-hindered-by-israeli-evacuation-orders-says-un">hindered their aid workers’ efforts</a> to reach Palestinians in need.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Within Gaza, it’s also possible that health officials will run into some vaccine hesitancy —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/9/2/polio-returns-to-gaza-where-else-has-the-virus-re-emerged">one of the reasons</a> polio has been spreading in some parts of the world. And for some Palestinians, the fact that the vaccination campaign is coming from international organizations rather than Israel isn’t enough to alleviate their skepticism. As one Palestinian mother <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2024/9/3/tragic-childhood-gaza-children-vaccinated-against-polio-war-continues">told Al Jazeera</a>, “People here have lost faith in anything global or Western.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s also the question of safety. “For parents trying to bring their kids to get vaccinated, how are they going to move safely to health care centers when the majority of health care centers are inaccessible at this point and barely functioning?” Bleckner said. And after Israel attacked <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/11/5/israel-bombs-al-maghazi-refugee-camp-killing-dozens-gaza-officials-say">refugee camps</a>, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1e5y8ny1l4o">schools</a>, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/05/21/gaza-hospitals-attacks-bombed-israel-war/">hospitals</a>, and even <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/02/29/1234906745/gaza-food-aid-convoy-israel-hamas">food distribution sites</a>, it’s understandable that some parents might have some concerns that no facility is safe.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Around the world, the spread of polio has been very limited, but it’s still considered to be endemic in Afghanistan and Pakistan. According to the Global Polio Eradication Initiative, every part of the world will remain at risk until the virus is eradicated from those countries. That’s especially true for low-income countries with inadequate public health infrastructure. In recent years, <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/9/2/polio-returns-to-gaza-where-else-has-the-virus-re-emerged">Mozambique and Malawi</a> reported wild poliovirus cases — that is, poliovirus that is circulating naturally as opposed to the vaccine-derived strains. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the health of Palestinians in Gaza and others in the broader region, it’s critical for the current vaccination drive to succeed. But because it’s taken so long to implement — experts <a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2024-07-23/ty-article/who-warns-of-high-polio-risk-in-gaza-and-beyond-its-borders-amid-dire-water-sanitation/00000190-dfde-dab4-afb9-fffeebf10000">have been warning</a> Israel and the world about a potential polio outbreak for months, and Israel has been <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn02z5kjn40o">vaccinating its soldiers</a> since July — it’s going to require an extraordinary effort. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There’s no reason why any kid in 2024 should have polio. It’s an entirely preventable disease, so even one confirmed case — and the WHO has also identified that there are multiple kids now showing symptoms of paralysis — that’s already too late,” Bleckner said. “The conditions that people are living in in Gaza are so honestly horrific and enabling the spread of disease, it’s really a fight against time in order to stop the catastrophic spread of this disease and others.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Whizy Kim</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The hidden cause behind your miserable flight delays]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/money/369808/flight-delays-airlines-flight-attendant-pay" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369808</id>
			<updated>2024-09-04T13:47:01Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-03T18:20:30Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Labor" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Travel" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[No one likes it when their flight is delayed. For flight attendants, though, a delay isn’t just a hassle – it’s a lot of unpaid work. You’re at the airport, in your uniform, yet the pay clock doesn’t start until the plane is pulling out of the gate.&#160; “I don’t know another job in the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images/PCH-Vector" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-1502967192.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">No one likes it when their flight is delayed. For flight attendants, though, a delay isn’t just a hassle – it’s a lot of unpaid work. You’re at the airport, in your uniform, yet the pay clock doesn’t start until the plane is pulling out of the gate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I don’t know another job in the world where you can show up, clock in, essentially, and just not get paid,” says Rory Kimbrough, who represents JetBlue flight attendants as the executive board member at large for the Transport Workers Union Local 579. Kimbrough has been a flight attendant for 20 years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Treatment like not being paid throughout the labor-intensive boarding process or during delays&nbsp;isn’t just shoddy, it’s indicative of a delicate and strained system for airline workers that, in the end, makes flying worse for everyone. When other common problems crop up, such as understaffed support teams and difficulty getting a hotel room for proper rest, those issues can just make delays even worse for passengers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Not getting paid is a huge issue,” says Brittany Norris, a member of the <a href="https://deltaafa.org/">Delta AFA Organizing Committee</a> who has been a flight attendant for eight years. “When something is delayed and passengers are upset, we&#8217;re also upset.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More people have been jetting around this summer than <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/23862850/flights-travel-delays-fees-nightmares-compensation-airlines">last</a>, with a record <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/GMA/Travel/tsa-sets-new-single-day-record-3-million/story?id=111750113">3 million travelers</a> passing a TSA screening point on the Sunday of Fourth of July weekend. Between late May and August this year, about 25 percent of flights were delayed — roughly the same as last summer — according to data from flight tracking site Flight Aware. Compare that to summer 2019, when 18.6 percent of flights were delayed. When the CrowdStrike IT outage hit in late July, over <a href="https://www.marketplace.org/2024/07/23/crowdstrike-outage-flight-delays-passenger-rights/">46,000 flights were delayed</a> in one day. The outage lasted for days. Throughout July, almost 24,000 flights in North America were canceled, according to the aviation analytics firm <a href="https://www.cirium.com/thoughtcloud/cirium-monthly-on-time-performance-reports2024/">Cirium</a>. Delta was the hardest hit, with delays and cancellations rippling on for almost a week after the issue first surfaced.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Passengers and flight attendants alike were stranded at airports for days. While CrowdStrike started out as an IT issue that brought down computer systems crucial to airline operations, the Delta organizing committee, which has been fighting for a union since 2019, blames a <a href="https://deltaafa.org/news/where-plan-ed">lack of communication</a> and understaffed teams as reasons why the flight disruptions lasted so long.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How flight attendant pay works</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In an email, Delta explained they are “the industry leader in operational performance,” canceling fewer flights, leading to less time delayed in airports and more in the air. “Delta is the only major airline that provides boarding pay for our flight attendants, and we’ve been doing it for more than two years,” they wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Indeed, the way pay works for flight attendants can be a bit head-spinning. In general, there’s a base rate that applies to flight time and distance flown that roughly mimics an hourly wage while in the air, often called “block” time. The entire duty period, however, can include multiple flights and includes the 45 minutes to nearly two hours flight attendants would have to arrive at the airport to “sign in” for work, as well as about 15 minutes after the plane lands. Most unionized airlines have some minimum pay protections around duty time, however, like being guaranteed flight time rate pay for at least half of the duty hours.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>Some unionized flight attendants have gone years without meaningful raises</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The flight time rate is supposed to be high enough to make up for those on-the-ground hours, but pay increases haven’t caught up with inflation or how much more work flight attendants do now compared to many decades ago. Particularly after Covid-19, delays in new contract negotiations have meant some unionized flight attendants have gone years without meaningful raises in a period of high inflation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They are working harder than ever before, with full aircraft, minimum staffing, long days, short nights, and no return for their hard work,” says Sara Nelson, the president of the Association of Flight Attendants-CWA. The industry underwent seismic changes after the 9/11 terrorist attacks and ensuing <a href="https://thehill.com/opinion/finance/488219-lessons-from-9-11-for-the-post-covid-19-airline-industry/">airline bankruptcies</a>. “The number of hours that the airline could schedule us increased, the number of hours that we could schedule ourselves increased,” she says. “Everyone was willing to do that because there were such <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2011/TRAVEL/09/06/flight.attendant.attacks.anniversary/index.html">steep cuts in pay</a>, and they had to make up for those losses in some way.” After 9/11, flight attendants essentially became the “last line of defense in aviation security,” Nelson notes. After the pandemic, they had to become public health enforcers too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beyond the duty time pay protection, there’s also usually a small per diem (ranging from around $2 to $3 per hour) while on duty, meant to cover paying for food and other expenses that pop up while working. Some airlines also offer overtime pay if a flight attendant exceeds a certain number of hours per month or higher pay for working certain hours and routes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All this means that if a flight is delayed before the plane door is shut, many flight attendants are waiting even longer to start making money.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-tiktok wp-block-embed-tiktok"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@moreperfectunion/video/7272809614796672299" data-video-id="7272809614796672299" data-embed-from="oembed"> <section> <a target="_blank" title="@moreperfectunion" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@moreperfectunion?refer=embed">@moreperfectunion</a> <p>Flight attendants at American Airlines are nearing the end of a strike authorization vote. They&#8217;ve gone without a raise since 2019 and aren&#8217;t paid until the door to the plane closes. Now 26,000 workers are fighting for more, and we talked to one about life on the job. <a title="union" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/union?refer=embed">#union</a> <a title="unionworkers" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/unionworkers?refer=embed">#unionworkers</a> <a title="corporategreed" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/corporategreed?refer=embed">#corporategreed</a> <a title="labormovement" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/labormovement?refer=embed">#labormovement</a> <a title="workingconditions" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/workingconditions?refer=embed">#workingconditions</a> <a title="economy" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/economy?refer=embed">#economy</a> <a title="leftist" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/leftist?refer=embed">#leftist</a> <a title="economicjustice" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/economicjustice?refer=embed">#economicjustice</a> <a title="leftisttiktok" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/leftisttiktok?refer=embed">#leftisttiktok</a> <a title="americanairlines" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/americanairlines?refer=embed">#americanairlines</a> <a title="flightattendant" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/flightattendant?refer=embed">#flightattendant</a> </p> <a target="_blank" title="♬ Aesthetic - Tollan Kim" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/Aesthetic-7072513628145977346?refer=embed">♬ Aesthetic &#8211; Tollan Kim</a> </section> </blockquote> 
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Flight attendants who have worked for an airline for decades can make much higher trip rates. At Delta, the scale now tops out at close to <a href="https://deltaafa.org/news/june1-increase">$80 per hour</a> of flight time (an hourly rate of $77.43, the new <a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/business/airlines/2024/04/24/southwest-airlines-flight-attendants-land-new-contract-first-for-industry/">top rate at Southwest</a>, works out to about $74,332 per year.) But that’s only if you can survive the first several years. In recent years, some flight attendants have reported experiencing homelessness due to their <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/travel/2024/08/26/flight-attendant-pay-flying-hours-homelessness/">low wages</a>. Others work multiple jobs to afford basics. A <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/americanairlines/comments/1cnyt19/the_actual_letter_aa_gives_new_fas_when_they_move/">proof of income letter</a> for an <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/05/17/business/american-airlines-flight-attendants-wages/index.html">American Airlines flight attendant</a> went viral earlier this year when it showed that, at a rate of $30.35 per flight hour, a first-year employee would make about $27,315 per year. According to the <a href="https://livingwage.mit.edu/pages/methodology">MIT Living Wage calculator</a>, a single adult in <a href="https://livingwage.mit.edu/states/54">West Virginia</a> — which has one of the lowest costs of living in the US — would need roughly $39,386 a year to cover the cost of their basic needs. Kimbrough says that some of his fellow union members are on government assistance programs such as SNAP.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“It’s the first time in the industry that we’ve actually had people quitting because they can’t afford to be a flight attendant”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“These new people coming in, I don&#8217;t know how they&#8217;re surviving being flight attendants,” says Maria Teresa Hank, a member of TWU 556, the union of Southwest flight attendants. “It’s the first time in the industry that we’ve actually had people quitting because they can’t afford to be a flight attendant.” A spokesperson for the company told Vox in an email that “Southwest and its Flight Attendants union negotiated an industry-leading contract, which <a href="https://swamedia.com/releases/release-f9b0d09b13627fa65cf1f5e65d072ad8-southwest-airlines-flight-attendants-ratify-new-contract">our Flight Attendants ratified back in April</a>.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many are fed up. Flight attendants from American Airlines and United have been fighting for more pay, and also to be paid for the entire time they’re working. There have been some recent wins and movement on the issue; the <a href="https://skift.com/2024/04/24/southwest-flight-attendants-score-new-contract/">new contract</a> ratified between Southwest and its flight attendants does provide some extra pay if there are long delays. A <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/19/business/american-airlines-flight-attendants-union-new-contract/index.html">tentative agreement</a> that was reached between American and its flight attendants offers half-pay during boarding the same way Delta does. On August 28, flight attendants at United voted to authorize a strike if negotiations break down, with an overwhelming 99.99 percent of yes votes.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How delays can throw a wrench in the workday – and your travel plans</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not uncommon for a flight attendant to be scheduled for multiple flights a day. Delays can mess up their route, which — you guessed it — can trigger a domino effect of more delays. When airlines are ill-equipped to quickly react to disruptions, that slows everything down even more.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The flight attendants we spoke to all emphasized that their employers could stand to be more proactive when disruptions, called “irregular operations” in the industry, occur. One example: ensuring flight attendants can get hotel rooms when delays stretch on for more than a few hours. Flight attendants are legally not allowed to work more than a certain number of hours, often between 14 to 16 hours for domestic routes. Long airport waits eat into the time that a flight attendant can legally be on duty before they need to get nine consecutive hours of legal rest. “Then when we are ready to go, the customers are like, ‘Why is the crew timing out, we didn&#8217;t even go anywhere’?” says Norris.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hank says that airlines tend to wait right up until the minute they’re contractually obligated to provide a hotel room. Finally, when flight attendants are allowed to request one, there’s the time it takes to reserve and travel, so “by the time you get to the hotel, you literally get an hour, maybe 30 minutes, of just sitting down and being restful before you have to go back to the airport.” They then return to work not feeling rested and closer to timing out of being able to fly, which is an especially big problem if there are multiple legs on their schedule.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“People think of us as just serving drinks and snacks, but we&#8217;re really there for the important stuff, like if there&#8217;s an evacuation of an aircraft or if you have a medical [emergency] on an airplane,” says Hank. “You need your flight attendants alert and ready to go.”</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>They just end up sleeping on the plane, in airport chairs, in the crew lounge</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given that a lot of people — including passengers — are looking for lodgings during major disruptions, it’s not entirely uncommon for flight attendants to struggle to obtain a hotel room for themselves. Even if rooms are available, it can take hours to get in touch with someone from the airline hotel team. That means they just end up sleeping on the plane, in airport chairs, in the crew lounge (if there is one at the airport), or on the floor, as stranded passengers do.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I&#8217;ve had to actually pay for other [flight attendant’s] rooms before,” says Kimbrough. Newer flight attendants in particular may not have a few hundred dollars in the bank to drop on a hotel room, and a full reimbursement isn’t necessarily guaranteed. Norris says that until recently, Delta capped reimbursements at $200 per night. Now, it reimburses up to a “reasonable amount.” (The company told Vox that receipts should be submitted for reimbursement for any out-of-pocket hotel costs but did not clarify whether it only reimbursed up to a “reasonable amount.”) Sometimes, Hank says, pilots at Southwest end up paying for a room on behalf of flight attendants, as she says they seem to have an easier time getting reimbursed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When a flight attendant times out, they are supposed to rest in a hotel room, not kick back in the crew lounge at the airport or get shut-eye on the floor. The Delta AFA organizing committee is hoping that, once they’re negotiating their first union contract, they’ll get a minimum of 10 hours of legal rest with “nine hours behind the actual hotel room door,” says Norris.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Why the CrowdStrike delay was worse for Delta passengers</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s still not clear why Delta was hit hardest by the CrowdStrike outage in late July, taking almost a week to recover when other carriers bounced back within <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/business/air-travel-delays-continue-though-most-airlines-have-recovered-from-global-tech-outage/">two to three days</a>. One factor that might have impacted Delta is that its computers had to be <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Business/delta-days-restore-normal-service-after-crowdstrike-outage/story?id=112299966">manually fixed and restarted</a> instead of being done remotely. That took a lot of time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the Delta AFA organizing committee suspects there’s another reason that contributed: a lack of staff on the airline’s crew scheduling team. “Right now, we have the fewest amount of schedulers of any of the major carriers,” says Norris. Crew schedulers are the people who assign flight attendants to specific flights, communicate with them about delays, and make reassignments when there are irregular operations. It’s impossible to solve delays without a robust crew-scheduling system.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The committee estimates that there are as few as <a href="https://deltaafa.org/news/where-plan-ed">53 crew schedulers</a> at the airline, while at United there are about 120, and at American there are about 200. Delta has about <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/tedreed/2024/02/16/labor-hero-shawn-fain-backs-flight-attendant-union-at-delta-detroit-hub/">28,000</a> flight attendants, a little more than <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/tedreed/2023/11/30/after-lost-year-for-contracts-american-and-united-flight-attendants-look-to-2024/">American and United</a>. Taylor Garland, communications director at the Association of Flight Attendants-CWA, notes that United and American have more crew schedulers because their flight attendant unions pushed for more staff. “That is a really, really critical backbone infrastructure team,” says Garland.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Without an adequate scheduling team, an airline can lose track of where their crew is and where they could best be rerouted, which is exactly what happened to Norris.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>In all, Norris was “lost” to the crew tracking system for about 40 hours</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On July 19, the first day of the CrowdStrike outage, Norris recalls how hard it was to get in touch with crew tracking at Delta. She showed up to the airport and was told that her scheduled flight couldn’t leave because the airline didn’t have any pilots who were “legal” to work at the time — as in, they hadn’t gotten the required amount of rest between flights. In all, Norris was “lost” to the crew tracking system for about 40 hours and ended up being unable to work one of her trips.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When asked about Delta’s crew scheduling staff numbers, a spokesperson said that its “scheduler process is not comparable to others as their crew assignments are not built out the same way.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When there are waves of delays messing up flight assignments and leaving some flight attendants stranded far from where they’re needed, airlines call on a team of reserves — often early-career flight attendants — to jump in. When disruptions last for days, though, those reserves can dry up. Carriers offer higher pay to incentivize off-duty flight attendants to pick up extra flights during such times, but even so, some turn down the offers because of the possibility of ending up stranded without a hotel room during the disruption, says Kimbrough.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If airlines want fewer, shorter flight delays, they need to beef up their support staff. This staff “is not seen but is crucial to getting flight attendants and pilots in the correct places,” Garland says. They should also be quicker to offer incentives for flight attendants picking up extra shifts when irregular operations occur.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many of us have groused about how much more frustrating and conflict-ridden air travel feels today compared to before the pandemic. The percentage of flights that are delayed these days isn’t all that much higher compared to pre-2019, but there are more fellow travelers to bump shoulders with, and there’s been a huge spike in the number of “<a href="https://www.faa.gov/unruly">unruly passenger</a>” reports since 2019, according to the Federal Aviation Administration. The aviation industry is more fragile now, in part because of how many experienced workers left during Covid-19. <a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/business/airlines/2020/04/30/39000-american-airlines-workers-take-early-retirement-leave-or-reduced-hours-in-face-of-covid-19-pandemic/">Tens of thousands</a> of pilots and flight attendants were laid off or retired early in 2020, when there was virtually no demand for air travel. By mid-2020, over <a href="https://www.ajc.com/business/delta-posts-billion-loss-cites-staggering-pandemic-impact/8XIEEs2ntPd9uWDvuGS8ZK/">17,000 Delta employees</a> had left the company. In the past few years, airlines have rushed to hire <a href="https://www.marketplace.org/2023/05/08/airline-hiring-booming-summer-travel/">thousands of new pilots and flight attendants</a>. A lot of institutional knowledge has been lost; it also means that a greater number of flight attendants we see today are making the lower end of the pay scale.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The flight attendants Vox spoke to implored passengers not to take their frustrations about delays out on them. “We are sometimes in the exact same situation as you, with a canceled flight, no way to get back,” says Kimbrough.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, September 4, 9:45 am ET:</strong> Taylor Garland&#8217;s name was misstated in a previous version of this post.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Vox Staff</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Vox podcasts tackle the Israel-Hamas war]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/podcasts/23948960/israel-hamas-palestine-podcasts" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/podcasts/23948960/israel-hamas-palestine-podcasts</id>
			<updated>2024-09-03T17:08:07Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-03T17:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Podcasts" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained podcast" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Israel-Palestine conflict goes back decades, but this latest war has taken an unprecedented toll in terms of the number of people killed, and represents a significant step back from any hopes of securing a two-state solution and a permanent peace. Vox podcasts are covering the conflict in depth, offering our listeners context and clarity [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Israeli forces’ flares light up the night sky in Gaza City on November 6, 2023. | Abed Khaled/AP" data-portal-copyright="Abed Khaled/AP" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25069266/AP23310764413057.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Israeli forces’ flares light up the night sky in Gaza City on November 6, 2023. | Abed Khaled/AP</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The Israel-Palestine conflict goes back decades, but this <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/10/7/23907683/israel-hamas-war-news-updates-october-2023">latest war</a> has taken <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-hamas-war-news-11-6-2023-51286d15dddd77ae0dd7ea76ee52bc71">an unprecedented toll in terms of the number of people killed</a>, and represents a significant step back from any hopes of securing a two-state solution and a permanent peace. <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/podcasts">Vox podcasts</a> are covering the conflict in depth, offering our listeners context and clarity about the history of the conflict, a deeper understanding of the players in Israel and Palestine and on the world stage, and the toll of Hamas’s attack and Israel’s retaliation on the people in the region.</p>

<p><a href="https://vox.com/todayexplained"><em>Today, Explained</em></a>,<strong> </strong>Vox’s daily news explainer podcast, has been covering the conflict since it began,<strong> </strong>with an episode posted right after Hamas’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/10/7/23907683/israel-hamas-war-news-updates-october-2023" data-source="encore">October 7 attack on Israel</a> that took the lives of around 1,200 people and resulted in the kidnapping of an estimated 240 hostages. The show has since continued to cover many threads in this story, from<strong> </strong>where Hamas comes from to<strong> </strong>how false information about the conflict has spread on social media and how information warfare is used in the Middle East. Vox podcasts <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-weeds"><em>The Weeds</em></a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-gray-area"><em>The Gray Area</em></a> have also been covering the unfolding crisis, its stakes, and its impact.</p>

<p>You can find those and all our other episodes on the topic below; we’ll continue to add more as new episodes are published.</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-css-opacity" />

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">&nbsp;Israel vs. Hezbollah</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX829">August 29, 2024</a> | The two are on the brink of starting a regional war. An analyst and a negotiator say that without a ceasefire in Gaza, the Middle East could spin out of control.</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4289052329" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">It’s not Islamophobic, it’s anti-Palestinian</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX625">June 25, 2024</a> | Islamophobic and antisemitic incidents are on the rise. Author Moustafa Bayoumi and Vox’s Abdallah Fayyad tell us about another kind of invisible discrimination: anti-Palestinian racism.</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4148829716" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Was that antisemitic?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX611">June 11, 2024</a> | Since October 7 there has been a lot of debate over what is and isn’t antisemitic. Rabbi Jill Jacobs and Harvard law professor Noah Feldman explain why the definition is so important.</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP5770834334" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The Hamas org chart</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX528">May 28, 2024</a> | Seven months in, Israel has not “eliminated” Hamas leadership. Newsweek’s Tom O’Connor introduces them, and Mairav Zonszein from International Crisis Group explains what it means for the war.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7294550951" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Biden’s breaking point on Gaza</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX0508">May 9, 2024</a> | President Joe Biden says the US won’t supply further weapons if Israel is going to use them in Rafah. Axios reporter Barak Ravid explains what that means for the war.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8718689187" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel, Gaza, and Eurovision</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX0507">May 7, 2024</a> | The pop music competition is facing boycott calls over Israel’s participation. Switched on Pop’s Charlie Harding and historian Tess Megginson explain why the apolitical event keeps getting political.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP3223606607" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is divesting from Israel possible?</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX0506">May 6, 2024</a> | Yes, but it’s hard. Inside Higher Ed’s Josh Moody and UC Merced’s Charlie Eaton explain.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP3557683503" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Columbia’s free-speech fight</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX424">April 24, 2024</a> | Daily Spectator news editor Sarah Huddleston reports on the protests at her university. AAUP President Irene Mulvey explains the stakes for campus free speech.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4660296382" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Iran attacked Israel</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXApril15">April 15, 2024</a> | The Economist’s Gregg Carlstrom explains. Jerusalem-based journalist Noga Tarnopolsky explores whether the unprecedented attack hurts or helps Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP1751931241" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel’s attack on World Central Kitchen</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXApril4">April 4, 2024</a> | The Wall Street Journal’s Stephen Kalin explains what happened, and Refugees International president Jeremy Konyndyk lays out what this means for Gazans.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8483025580" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Israel is upending Democratic races</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/XkhCpuXi">March 5, 2024</a> | Super Tuesday is the biggest day of the presidential primary campaign, but the biggest race in the biggest state isn’t about Biden or Trump. Instead, the leading candidates for California’s open Senate seat — three Democrats and a Republican — are finding themselves talking a lot about Israel, Palestine, and the war in Gaza.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7327599366" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The protest vote against Biden</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/SFSTGt27">February 27, 2024</a> | Michigan’s primary today will test President Biden’s viability with Muslim voters amid the war in Gaza. One Arab American leader says the community is abandoning Biden and looking for alternatives — Donald Trump might be one of them.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP1472451344" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Rafah, the last “safe” zone</h2>

<p><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/rafah-the-last-safe-zone/id1346207297?i=1000645493072">February 15, 2024</a> | Palestinians are trapped in Rafah, Gaza’s southernmost city, where about 1.5 million people have sought refuge. After Israel bombed Rafah this weekend, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is threatening a ground invasion. Palestinian journalist Aseel Mousa takes us inside Rafah, and the Economist’s Anton La Guardia explains why diplomatic efforts to halt the fighting have stalled.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8017917831" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Iran and the Axis of Resistance</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/Tex131">January 31, 2024</a> | Iran-backed militias use drones, missiles, and even TikTok dances to antagonize the United States and Israel. The International Crisis Group’s Ali Vaez explains how the war in Gaza has energized the self-described Axis of Resistance.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP9744025655" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel at the International Court of Justice</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/Tex129">January 29, 2024</a> | South Africa took Israel to court over claims of genocide. Courthouse News reporter Molly Quell and the International Crisis Group’s Robert Blecher explain what happened next.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4209187305" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How the war in Gaza ends</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXGaza118">January 18, 2024</a> | Israel’s war against Hamas has now been raging for over 100 days. According to Ian Lustick, professor emeritus at the University of Pennsylvania, history tells us what it will take to end it.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7914504391" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel’s next move</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/IsraelsNextMove">January 3, 2023</a> | Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu faces trouble at home and abroad. AP correspondent Tia Goldenberg and scholar Hussein Ibish explain the significance of a high-profile killing in Lebanon.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8484180035" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The fight over campus antisemitism</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXCampusAntisemitism">December 12, 2023</a> | Three elite university presidents walk into Congress for a hearing on antisemitism. Only two still have their jobs. New York magazine reporter Nia Prater tells us what happened, and a Harvard professor of Jewish history explains why he thinks resignations won’t make campuses safer.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4405751236" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Palestine went global</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX124">December 4, 2023</a> | People with no direct connection to the Middle East have taken to seeing the Palestinian cause as an anti-colonial struggle connected to their own experience. Columbia historian Rashid Khalidi explains why “decolonization” is resonating worldwide.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7675203676" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The American politics of Israel</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXIsraelPolitics">November 29, 2023</a> | The Israel-Hamas war is dividing the previously united Democrats and uniting the recently fractured Republican Party. Semafor’s David Weigel explains what that means going into 2024.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP1957625702" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The hostage deal (brought to you by Qatar)</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXHostageDeal">November 27, 2023</a> | After 50 days of the Israel-Hamas war, both sides took a breather to save lives. And it couldn’t have happened without Qatar.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP6031095818" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Inside the occupied West Bank</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXWestBank">November 20, 2023</a> | With the world focused on Gaza, Israeli settlers and soldiers are increasing attacks on Palestinians in the West Bank. Writer Nathan Thrall and journalist Dalia Hatuqa explain the decades of tension that shape life in the West Bank.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8588452161" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A call from Gaza</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXCallFromGaza">November 14, 2023</a> | People are desperately trying to escape Gaza as the siege on the strip continues. Mohammed Ghalaieny, a Palestinian British man, tells us why he is choosing to stay, even as other foreign nationals escape through the Rafah border crossing with Egypt.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP6452223851" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A Jew and a Muslim get honest about Israel and Gaza</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/GrayArea1113">November 13, 2023</a> | <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/zack-beauchamp">Zack Beauchamp</a>, a Vox senior correspondent who writes about democracy and Israel, speaks with Shadi Hamid, a columnist at the Washington Post, research professor of Islamic studies at Fuller Seminary, and author of<em> The Problem of Democracy: America, the Middle East, and the Rise and Fall of an Idea</em>. They discuss the October 7 attack, the subsequent war in Gaza, what it means for Israelis and Palestinians, and how Jews and Muslims in the United States can find common ground amid their communities’ grief. This conversation was recorded on November 2, 2023.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP5837160411" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">BDS and the history of the boycott</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/WeedsBDS">November 8, 2023</a> | If you turn on the news or scroll through your social media feed of choice, there’s a good chance you’ll see the latest on the Israel-Hamas war — and the reaction to it. But there’s one call to action making its way down social media feeds that feels different from all these other responses. It’s called <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/23935054/boycott-movement-palestine-against-israel-bds">BDS, short for boycott, divest, and sanction</a>. And like just about everything related to this conflict, it’s complicated and controversial. <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-weeds"><em>The Weeds</em></a> host <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/jonquilyn-hill">Jonquilyn Hill</a> sits down with Vox senior reporter <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/whizy-kim">Whizy Kim</a> to explain the controversial movement, and with Cornell professor and author of <em>Buying Power: A History of Consumer Activism in America</em> Lawrence B. Glickman to discuss the history of boycotts and whether they even work.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP3708406014" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ceasefire?</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXCeasefire">November 8, 2023</a> | Protesters, politicians, and the pope are <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/2023/11/9/23953714/biden-campaign-alumni-want-gaza-ceasefire-state-department-dissent-memo">calling for a ceasefire in the Israel-Hamas war</a>, but the US and Israeli governments remain opposed. Vox’s Jonathan Guyer and Jon B. Alterman from the Center for Strategic and International Studies explain what happens next.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7707398742" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The view from Israel</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXviewfromisrael">November 2, 2023</a> | Israelis overwhelmingly disapprove of their government’s handling of the October 7 attacks, but their desire for unity keeps Prime Minister <a href="https://www.vox.com/23910085/netanyahu-israel-right-hamas-gaza-war-history" data-source="encore">Benjamin Netanyahu</a> in power. Michael Koplow of the Israel Policy Forum explains what Israel’s government should do next, and professor Noah Efron of Bar-Ilan University describes the mood among Israelis.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7944317880" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Gaza’s humanitarian crisis</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXgazacrisis">October 30, 2023</a> | Cut off from water and power and recovering from a communications blackout, Gaza is plunged deeper into crisis. It’s not just a humanitarian problem, says leading human rights attorney Kenneth Roth — it’s a violation of international law.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP2717258243" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why does the US always side with Israel?</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXisraellistenerQs">October 25, 2023</a> | This was the top question we got when we asked <em><a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast" data-source="encore">Today, Explained</a></em> listeners hat they wanted to know about this conflict. Joel Beinin, Middle East history professor emeritus at Stanford, has answers.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8490887695" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hearts, minds, and likes</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXheartsmindslikes">October 23, 2023</a> | False information about what is happening in Israel and Gaza is taking over social media faster than journalists like BBC Verify’s Shayan Sardarizadeh can check it. That’s exactly how digital propagandists want it, says professor and social media expert Marc Owen Jones.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP6875482691" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Biden goes to Israel</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXbidenisrael">October 18, 2023</a> | It’s been 11 days since Hamas attacked Israel, killing civilians and taking hostages. Israel’s retaliation has killed hundreds of Palestinians and created a humanitarian crisis in Gaza. Senior fellow at the Carnegie Endowment Aaron David Miller and Middle East analyst Michael Wahid Hanna explain what role diplomacy will play in the coming days.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP1718190767" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Palestinians view Hamas</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXpalestiniansviewhamas">October 16, 2023</a> | The US, along with Israel and many of its allies, has long considered Hamas a terrorist group. Khaled Al-Hroub, a professor at Northwestern University in Qatar, explains how its reputation is a lot murkier among Palestinians, who elected the group to political power in 2006.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP6885524911" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel, Hamas, and how we got here</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXIsraelHamas">October 10, 2023</a> | This Israel-Hamas war is unlike the ones that came before it, says Haaretz’s Allison Kaplan Sommer. But it was years in the making, says Vox’s Zack Beauchamp.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8658633452" width="100%"></iframe>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Celia Ford</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Should we think twice about fluoride?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter/369470/fluoride-iq-kids-brain-development-toothpaste-water-science-study" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369470</id>
			<updated>2024-08-30T13:59:56Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-03T11:15:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained newsletter" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you live in the US, there’s a good chance you’re one of the approximately 209 million people drinking tap water that contains added fluoride. Local governments have been putting fluoride in city water supplies for nearly 80 years. In many ways, its addition has been a remarkable public health success: According to the Centers [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A close-up of a toothbrush with red and white bristles, with a dab of toothpaste. " data-caption="Most of us brush our teeth with fluoride toothpaste twice a day. | Matthias Balk/picture alliance via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Matthias Balk/picture alliance via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1888389534.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Most of us brush our teeth with fluoride toothpaste twice a day. | Matthias Balk/picture alliance via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">If you live in the US, there’s a good chance you’re one of the approximately<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/fluoridation/php/statistics/2020-water-fluoridation-statistics.html"> 209 million people</a> drinking tap water that contains added fluoride. Local governments have been putting fluoride in city water supplies for <a href="https://www.wired.com/2008/01/dayintech-0125/">nearly 80 years</a>. In many ways, its addition has been a remarkable public health success: According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), drinking fluoridated water <a href="https://dph.illinois.gov/topics-services/prevention-wellness/oral-health/fast-facts-oral-health/fluoride-prevent-decay.html#:~:text=According%20to%20CDC%2C%20drinking%20water,reduces%20tooth%20decay%20by%2025%25.">reduces tooth decay by 25 percent</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But in late August, the US National Toxicology Program (NTP) published a long-awaited <a href="https://apnews.com/article/fluoride-water-brain-neurology-iq-0a671d2de3b386947e2bd5a661f437a5">report</a> declaring, with “moderate confidence,” that drinking water with elevated fluoride levels is linked to lower IQ in children.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fluoride in our drinking water has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N1KvgtEnABY">inspired conspiracy theories</a> for generations. Robert F. Kennedy Jr., who is also a prominent anti-vaxxer and Covid-19 skeptic, is one of the most <a href="https://fluoridealert.org/content/rfk-jr-michael-connett-fluoride-lawsuit/">vocal proponents</a> of banning fluoridation to protect children from neurodevelopmental problems.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This, though, isn’t a conspiracy theory. Scientists have spent decades <a href="https://nap.nationalacademies.org/catalog/11571/fluoride-in-drinking-water-a-scientific-review-of-epas-standards">trying to figure out</a> what level of fluoride strikes the best balance between oral health and healthy brain development. The NTP’s new <a href="https://ntp.niehs.nih.gov/whatwestudy/assessments/noncancer/completed/fluoride">324-page report</a> reviews results from over 500 experiments, lending more weight to the idea that fluoride can be connected to brain problems than, say, a single fraudulent, <a href="https://time.com/5175704/andrew-wakefield-vaccine-autism/">now-retracted study</a> linking vaccines to autism.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Science is a frustratingly non-linear process. Facts that seemed unquestionable a decade ago can be overturned by new data at any moment. If you’ve never thought about fluoride outside of the dentist’s office, hearing that it might have neurotoxic effects could be confusing, scary, or infuriating. Why is fluoride still in our water and toothpaste, then?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not because dentists and scientists are lying to us (although <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/368350/scientific-research-fraud-crime-jail-time">sometimes they do</a>). It’s because finding the whole, unshakable truth is a never-ending process.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, don’t throw out your toothpaste and stockpile bottled water just yet. Here’s what the science says (and doesn’t say) about fluoride and the brain.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why does the government want us to drink fluoride?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fluoride is a mineral found naturally in soil, water, and things we consume, like <a href="https://nutritionsource.hsph.harvard.edu/fluoride/">brewed tea and shellfish</a>. It’s also in the toothpaste most of us use. Fluoride <a href="https://eclkc.ohs.acf.hhs.gov/oral-health/brush-oral-health/understanding-how-fluoride-helps-prevent-repair-tooth-decay">strengthens our enamel</a> and prevents cavities. It’s about more than maintaining pearly white teeth; left untreated, <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/10946-cavities">tooth decay</a> leads to severe infection, which can spread throughout the entire body.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the turn of the 20th century, dental researchers noticed that many people living near high-fluoride water sources had splotches on their teeth, a condition called fluorosis. Once scientists began <a href="https://www.nidcr.nih.gov/health-info/fluoride/the-story-of-fluoridation">studying the effects of fluoride on dental health</a>, they realized that, while fluoride can damage teeth and bones at high concentrations, drinking water with low levels of fluoride actually prevents tooth decay. Today, many cities add a small amount of fluoride to their tap water — about 0.7 milligrams per liter (mg/L).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But around 1.9 million people in the US live in areas where <a href="https://undark.org/2024/05/06/tap-water-high-dose-of-fluoride/">tap water naturally contains more fluoride</a> than the government recommends, according to the report. For example, the <a href="https://www.twdb.texas.gov/groundwater/aquifer/majors/ogallala.asp">Ogallala Aquifer</a>, which provides water for West Texas, is infused with fluoride-rich volcanic ash, bringing its <a href="https://nccd.cdc.gov/DOH_MWF/Default/Default.aspx" data-type="link" data-id="https://nccd.cdc.gov/DOH_MWF/Default/Default.aspx">fluoride concentrations</a> up to a whopping 5 mg/L.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The report linked fluoride levels of 1.5 mg/L — about twice the level <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4547570/">recommended by federal health officials</a> — with lower IQ in children. According to the NTP, more research is needed to figure out whether there are also risks associated with higher levels of fluoride for adults, or with the lower concentrations the government recommends.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While these findings have been reproduced enough times to be worth taking seriously, the science of intelligence — including the concept of IQ itself — is questionable.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Measuring brain development is complicated&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Measuring brain function isn’t straightforward. After all, the brain has many functions: keeping the body alive, helping us walk and talk, guiding our learning and decision-making.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More than 70 of the 100 human studies reviewed by the NTP specifically looked at children’s IQ as a proxy for brain development — IQ tests are easier and cheaper to run than, say, brain scans or full neurological exams. Of those 72 IQ-related studies, only 19 were flagged by the NTP as having a low risk of bias, controlling for factors like socioeconomic status, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4641149/">which could also contribute</a> to differences in IQ scores. Only a handful of those 19 studies were conducted in North America, and none in the US.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, critically, none of these human studies tell us anything about how fluoride changes the brain at a biological level. Even studies in lab animals and cells did not identify how fluoride might affect learning, memory, or intelligence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&nbsp;IQ scores also only capture an incomplete picture of early childhood brain development and are tangled up in a number of <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3270016/">socioeconomic</a>, <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2013/08/jason-richwine-race-iq-genetics-095765">racial,</a> and <a href="https://nrcgt.uconn.edu/newsletters/winter052/">cultural</a> factors beyond how much fluoride someone is exposed to.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, <a href="https://www.pbs.org/pov/films/refrigeratormothers/">mothers were blamed</a> for their children’s cognitive disabilities. Redirecting that blame to environmental factors like <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/6/19/18684109/autism-vaccines-treatment-cure-bleach">MMR vaccines</a> — or, say, fluoridated water — can give parents a sense of control over scary-sounding diagnoses. A 2017 <a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/does-fluoride-drinking-water-lower-iq-question-looms-large-court-battle#:~:text=The%20fluoride%20lawsuit%20is%20the,a%20%E2%80%9Cscientifically%20defensible%20basis.%E2%80%9D">federal lawsuit</a> calling on the EPA to ban water fluoridation already has the <a href="https://fluoridealert.org/content/rfk-jr-michael-connett-fluoride-lawsuit/">enthusiastic support of high-profile anti-vaxxers</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The trial hinges on the results of NTP’s final report, a draft of which was originally presented over a year ago. The drawn-out legal battle has been <a href="https://undark.org/2024/03/06/fluoride-drinking-water/">messy</a>, with dental health advocates obstructing fluoride research and <a href="https://fluoridealert.org/content/national-toxicology-program-finds-no-safe-level-of-fluoride-in-drinking-water-water-fluoridation-policy-threatened/">denying the NTP’s findings</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the court decides fluoride poses health risks that outweigh its benefits, it could end water fluoridation in the US.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Amid scientific uncertainty and political shadiness, it’s hard to know what to believe.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Who should I believe? What should I do?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For now, the NTP has simply determined “with moderate confidence” that there is a correlation between higher fluoride exposure and lower IQ in children — specifically, IQs 2 to 5 points lower.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it’s hard to know how we would measure the differences in lived experiences based on a few IQ points.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re concerned about your family’s fluoride exposure, you can check your tap water’s fluoride levels on the CDC’s <a href="https://nccd.cdc.gov/DOH_MWF/Default/SearchByWaterSystem.aspx">My Water’s Fluoride page</a>. If you happen to live somewhere with levels above around 1.5 mg/L, your tap water crosses the threshold of neurodevelopmental concern. No need to switch to bottled water, though; <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-under-sink-water-filter/">home water purifiers</a> can <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3793412/">filter fluoride out completely</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To make sure you don’t throw out the oral health benefits of fluoride with the bathwater, keep using fluoride toothpaste for those <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/68/wr/mm6804a3.htm#:~:text=However%2C%20ingestion%20of%20too%20much,toothpaste%20at%20age%202%20years.">over the age of 2</a> (just don’t swallow it).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And if you’re still fluoride-skeptical, you can order some <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2024/07/toothpaste-fluoride-hydroxyapatite/679200/">hydroxyapatite toothpaste</a> — which has similar cavity-preventive benefits — from Europe or Canada, where it’s been approved and endorsed by dental associations.<br><br><em>This story originally appeared in </em><a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter"><strong><em>Today, Explained</em></strong></a><em>, Vox’s flagship daily newsletter. </em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/today-explained-newsletter-signup"><strong><em>Sign up here for future editions</em></strong></a><em>.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
