<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-09-11T14:22:19Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How a 2006 book by a Harvard professor explains the Trumpist right’s gender politics]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/370829/trump-vance-manliness-harvey-mansfield" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=370829</id>
			<updated>2024-09-11T14:19:03Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-11T14:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you think about the defining voices of the Trump-era Republican party, Harvard political theorists aren’t typically at the top of the list. But Harvey Mansfield should be an exception.&#160; He is, in some ways, the godfather of the Trumpist right’s current approach to gender and masculinity&#160;— an increasingly open celebration of the virtues of [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An elderly white man wearing a suit and red tie sits at a desk, surrounded by shelves of books." data-caption="Recently retired Harvard professor Harvey Mansfield poses for a portrait in his study. | Erin Clark/Boston Globe via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Erin Clark/Boston Globe via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2035880670.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Recently retired Harvard professor Harvey Mansfield poses for a portrait in his study. | Erin Clark/Boston Globe via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">When you think about the defining voices of the Trump-era Republican party, Harvard political theorists aren’t typically at the top of the list. But Harvey Mansfield should be an exception.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He is, in some ways, the godfather of the Trumpist right’s current approach to gender and masculinity&nbsp;— an increasingly open celebration of the virtues of traditional gender norms that I’ve termed “<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/366601/the-rights-plan-to-fix-america-patriarchy-2-0">neopatriarchy</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mansfield began teaching at Harvard in 1962 and stayed there until his retirement last year. During that 61-year tenure at America’s most famous college, he became a conservative institution unto himself: a beachhead in enemy-occupied territory, an Ivy Leaguer who has been mentor to some of the movement’s leading lights. His former graduate students include Sen. Tom Cotton (R-AR), leading pro-Trump intellectual <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/22278065/donald-trump-conservative-politics-charles-kesler">Charles Kesler</a>, and the famous Never Trump writer Bill Kristol.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mansfield, an erudite Tocqueville scholar, disdains Trump — describing him <a href="https://www.persuasion.community/p/mansfield">as a demagogue and a vulgarian</a>. Yet in <a href="https://www.thecrimson.com/article/2023/7/12/harvey-mansfield-retires/">a recent interview</a>, Mansfield said he voted for said vulgarian in 2020 “with many misgivings” (Mansfield adds that he “crossed [Trump] off my list entirely” after the January 6, 2021, Capitol riot).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he has offered striking praise of Trump in one area: gender. Trump, he <a href="https://contemporarythinkers.org/harvey-mansfield/commentary/manhood-age-trump/">said in one interview</a>, was “really the first American politician” to win office via “a display of manliness and an attack on political correctness.” He beat Hillary Clinton, per Mansfield, because American elections are “tests of manliness” — and “it’s difficult for a woman to do that in a graceful way, and to maintain her femininity.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Manliness, </em></strong><strong>explained</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Masculinity is one of Mansfield’s enduring interests. In 2006, he published a book — <a href="https://www.google.ca/books/edition/Manliness/NsIU55H6_DUC?hl=en&amp;gbpv=1">titled <em>Manliness</em></a> — that attacked modern feminism’s ideal of a “gender-neutral society,” calling for a return to a world where men and women were understood to have different skills and aptitudes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mansfield’s book begins with a well-known contradiction: While everyone in public life claims to believe that men and women are equal, reality is anything but. Men continue to dominate in high-status professions and leadership roles; women continue to do the lion’s share of home labor despite their entry into the workforce.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Mansfield, this inequality reflects the enduring and vital influence of “manliness.” Manliness, in his account, is a kind of self-reliant commanding decisiveness — a willingness to blaze a risky path and lead others along it. While women can be manly — Mansfield cites Margaret Thatcher as an example — they generally are not. For Mansfield, “common sense” stereotypes about men and women are mostly true and validated by the evidence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Women still rather like housework, changing diapers, and manly men. The capacities and inclinations of the sexes do not differ exactly or universally, but they do seem to differ,” he writes. “These differences are, one could say, all the more impressive now that they are no longer supported, indeed now that they are denied or opposed, by society’s ruling conventions.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The persistence of manliness among men helps explain, in large part, why the “gender-neutral society” is failing to produce equality in the workplace or at home. Given that men are men and women are women, Mansfield argues, it cannot help but fail.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Men reject and resist the expectation that they should abandon their manliness,” he argues. “They do not so much mind sharing their traditional opportunities with whoever can exploit them, and they have shown newfound respect for women who can. But they draw the line at doing what women have left behind.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Mansfield and the Trumpian moment</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I used to think that Mansfield’s writing on manliness was idiosyncratic: an older professor’s way of lashing out at a changing world. But the Trump era has proved Mansfield’s work to be far more than that. His writings represent an unusually coherent formulation of a value system deeply embedded in modern conservatism, one that has found its voice in the past several years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ask any conservative about what defines their worldview, and one of the first things they’ll tell you is that they stand for eternal truths against passing fads. Liberals, they believe, have an unjustified faith in the plasticity of human nature —&nbsp;which for conservatives is a fixed and unchangeable thing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of those enduring facts, they believe, is binary gender difference. Men are generally one way and women are generally another; this, for conservatives, is an eternal truth about humanity that liberals deny at their peril.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are many different ways of making this argument, ranging from the science of sex difference to an appeal to scripture. Mansfield himself appeals to history, writing that “the tradition of different roles for the two sexes is impressively long — long enough to comprise all societies except advanced liberal democracies today.” Different kinds of conservatives may make the argument differently, but the general sentiment remains consistent across the movement.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many modern conservatives can be a bit squeamish about the implications of these views. They don’t want to come across as sexist, after all. So they talk quite a bit about the differences between men and women without drawing conclusions about the implications of these ideas for who deserves to wield political power and rule households.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is what’s behind the rise of the “<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/366601/the-rights-plan-to-fix-america-patriarchy-2-0">neopatriarchy</a>” movement: the call from leaders like JD Vance and Josh Hawley for America to rediscover the lost virtues of a patriarchal society <em>without</em> explicitly calling for women to depart the workforce and return to the home.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mansfield, by contrast, is open about what he’s attacking: the very idea of a “gender-neutral society.” And with this openness comes an arch self-awareness.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Certainly I am sexist,”  <a href="https://www.thecrimson.com/article/2022/9/9/harvey-mansfield-political-polarization/">Mansfield told</a> the Harvard Crimson in 2022. “I say that plainly.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Marin Cogan</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Wait, Kamala Harris owns a gun?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/371304/what-kamala-harris-gun-ownership-reveals-about-american-politics" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=371304</id>
			<updated>2024-09-11T14:22:19Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-11T14:25:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris had a quick comeback for Donald Trump when he accused her of wanting to take people’s guns away at Tuesday’s debate. “Tim Walz and I are both gun owners. We’re not taking anybody’s guns away. So stop with the continuous lying about this stuff,” Harris said. While the remark caught attention [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris pictured mid-speech with hands raised, speaking into a podium microphone." data-caption="At the debate on Tuesday, Harris dismissed Trump’s attack on her record with guns by revealing that she and Tim Walz are both gun owners." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2169924597.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>At the debate on Tuesday, Harris dismissed Trump’s attack on her record with guns by revealing that she and Tim Walz are both gun owners.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris had a quick comeback for Donald Trump when he <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/370942/harris-trump-debate-who-won-bait-kamala-donald">accused her</a> of wanting to take people’s guns away at Tuesday’s debate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Tim Walz and I are both gun owners. We’re not taking anybody’s guns away. So stop with the continuous lying about this stuff,” <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/harris-trump-presidential-debate-transcript/story?id=113560542">Harris said</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While the remark caught <a href="https://x.com/search?q=kamala%2C%20gun&amp;src=typed_query">attention online</a>, it wasn’t actually news. Harris had spoken about being a gun owner during her last campaign for president. “I am a gun owner, and I own a gun for probably the reason a lot of people do — for personal safety,” Harris <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2019/04/11/politics/kamala-harris-gun-owner/index.html">told reporters</a> after a campaign event in 2019. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the time, Harris pointed to her career as a prosecutor by way of explanation. It’s not unusual for people who work in law enforcement, from parole officers to police to chief law enforcement officers, to own a gun out of concern that someone they’ve encountered in the legal system might try to exact revenge — <a href="https://apnews.com/article/maryland-judge-shot-killed-394b2eaf2570813d1f2845c45f8a99fe">as</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/maryland-judge-shot-killed-394b2eaf2570813d1f2845c45f8a99fe">has</a> <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/newyork/news/judge-esther-salas-applauds-federal-law-to-help-protect-other-judges-and-their-families/">happened</a> <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/texas/news/eric-williams-jury-hears-about-hasses-death/">before</a>. The surprise is almost certainly for another reason altogether: Harris is a multiracial woman from a liberal state who has called for <a href="https://kamalaharris.com/issues/">banning assault weapons</a> and passing universal background checks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this shouldn’t be all that shocking, either. As I wrote in <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/353878/new-guns-us-violence">my feature last month</a> about the millions of Americans who decided to buy their first guns during the pandemic, women — particularly Black and Hispanic women — are among the fastest growing cohort of gun owners in the country. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Between 1980 and 2014, only <a href="https://www.norc.org/content/dam/norc-org/pdfs/GSS_Trends%20in%20Gun%20Ownership_US_1972-2014.pdf">9 to 14 percent of women</a> owned guns. But <a href="https://www.acpjournals.org/doi/10.7326/M21-3423">half of first-time gun buyers between 2019 and 2021 were women,</a> according to a study from Northeastern University. Another study of new gun owners found that, from 2020 to 2022, <a href="https://www.norc.org/research/library/one-in-five-american-households-purchased-a-gun-during-the-pande.html">69 percent were people of color</a>. As of last year, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/meet-the-press/meetthepressblog/poll-gun-ownership-reaches-record-high-american-electorate-rcna126037">more than half of Americans</a> said they or someone in their household had a gun.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris is right that the vast majority of gun owners <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2023/08/16/for-most-u-s-gun-owners-protection-is-the-main-reason-they-own-a-gun/">say they own a gun for protection,</a> and the fact that she counts herself among the millions of Americans who own guns reveals an important truth that often gets hidden. While the national debate is typically framed as a fight between two opposing interests — anti-gun liberals who want to take everyone’s guns away and pro-gun conservatives who steadfastly refuse any regulation — the reality is much more nuanced. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s true that support for measures like banning assault weapons <a href="https://www.monmouth.edu/polling-institute/reports/monmouthpoll_us_042423/">is mixed</a>. But the notion that all gun owners are totally against any gun regulation is clearly false and a narrative that gun control advocates have been working to unravel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not just that a <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2023/08/16/for-most-u-s-gun-owners-protection-is-the-main-reason-they-own-a-gun/">majority</a> of Americans say it’s too easy to get a gun and regulations should be stricter. <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/10/19/gun-owners-support-safety-policies-00062335">Even a majority of American gun owners</a> say they support things like universal background checks, permits, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23141651/gun-control-american-approval-polling">extreme risk laws</a> meant to keep guns away from domestic abusers and others likely to commit violence.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <a href="https://www.vox.com/23672891/gun-violence-mass-shootings-us-deaths">interviews I’ve done</a> with gun control activists and in other <a href="https://www.mariashriversundaypaper.com/meet-these-gun-supporting-moms-who-are-mad-as-hell-and-fighting-for-change/">news articles</a>, these advocates highlight the gun owners in their midst who are fighting for stronger gun laws. It’s not just urban and coastal liberals and people who’ve never owned guns before who want to see better regulation, but a wide range of Americans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris understands this dynamic well. “We are being offered a false choice,” she <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2019/04/11/politics/kamala-harris-gun-owner/index.html">said</a> in 2019. “You’re either in favor of the Second Amendment or you want to take everyone’s guns away. It’s a false choice that is born out of a lack of courage from leaders who must recognize and agree that there are some practical solutions to what is a clear problem in our country.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She’s right, of course. As the polls show, millions of Americans own guns and have complicated feelings about them. It’s only the people who don’t want to see any regulation who have an interest in pretending otherwise.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Celia Ford</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Science has a short-term memory problem]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/370681/science-research-grants-scientific-progress-academia-slow-funding" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=370681</id>
			<updated>2024-09-10T15:02:34Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-11T13:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Science" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in 2016, Vox asked 270 scientists to name the biggest problems facing science. Many of them agreed that the constant search for funding, brought on by the increasingly competitive grant system, serves as one of the biggest barriers to scientific progress. Even though we have more scientists throwing more time and resources at projects, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="A biologist peers into a microscope." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/diane-serik-M3t3E7gzPKQ-unsplash.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A biologist peers into a microscope.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Back in 2016, Vox asked 270 scientists to name the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/7/14/12016710/science-challeges-research-funding-peer-review-process#1">biggest problems facing science</a>. Many of them agreed that the constant search for funding, brought on by the <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/1/18/18183939/science-funding-grant-lotteries-research">increasingly competitive grant system</a>, serves as one of the biggest barriers to scientific progress.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even though we have more scientists throwing more time and resources at projects, we seem to be blocked on big questions — like how to help people live healthier for longer — and that has major real-world impacts.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Future Perfect newsletter</a>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">here</a> to explore the big, complicated problems the world faces and the most efficient ways to solve them. Sent twice a week.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Grants are funds given to researchers by the government or private organizations, ranging from tens to hundreds of thousands of dollars earmarked for a specific project. Most grant applications are very competitive. <a href="https://report.nih.gov/nihdatabook/category/10">Only about 20 percent</a> of applications for research project grants at the National Institutes of Health (NIH), which funds the vast majority of biomedical research in the US, are successful.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you do get a grant, they usually <a href="https://www.nigms.nih.gov/Research/Application/Pages/ResearchProjGrantDuration.aspx">expire after a few years</a> — far less time than it normally takes to make groundbreaking discoveries. And most grants, even the most prestigious ones, don’t provide enough money to keep a lab running on their own.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Between the endless cycle of grant applications and the constant turnover of early-career researchers in labs, pushing science forward is slow at best and Sisyphean at worst.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, science has a short-term memory problem — but there are steps funding agencies can take to make it better.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Grants are too small, too short, and too restrictive</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Principal investigators — often tenure-track university professors — doing academic research in the US are responsible not only for running their own lab, but also for funding it. That includes the costs of running experiments, keeping the lights on, hiring other scientists, and often covering their own salary, too. In this way, investigators are <a href="https://academia.stackexchange.com/questions/188722/why-do-academics-have-to-get-their-own-grants">more like entrepreneurs than employees</a>, running their labs like a small-business owner.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the US, basic science research, studying how the world works for the sake of expanding knowledge, is <a href="https://sgp.fas.org/crs/misc/R44307.pdf">mostly funded by the federal government</a>. The NIH funds the vast majority of biomedical research, and the National Science Foundation (NSF) funds other sciences, like astrophysics, geology, and genetics. The <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23384446/future-perfect-50-renee-wegrzyn-arpa-h">Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health</a> (ARPA-H) also funds some biomedical research, and the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) funds technology development for the military, some of which finds uses in the civilian world, <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/about-us/timeline/modern-internet">like the internet</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The grant application system worked well a few decades ago, when <a href="http://mbio.asm.org/content/7/2/e00422-16.full">over half of submitted grants were funded</a>. But today, we have more scientists — <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6294951/">especially young ones</a> — and <a href="https://drugmonkey.scientopia.org/2020/12/16/updating-the-erosion-of-the-purchase-power-of-the-modular-nih-r01/">less money, once inflation</a> is taken into account. Getting a grant is harder than ever, scientists I spoke with said. What ends up happening is that principal investigators are forced to spend more of their time writing grant applications — which often take dozens of hours each — than actually doing the science they were trained for. Because funding is so competitive, applicants increasingly have to <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/1745691616687745">twist their research proposals</a> to align with whoever will give them money. A lab interested in studying how cells communicate with each other, for example, may spin it as a study of cancer, heart disease, or depression to convince the NIH that its project is worth funding.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Federal agencies generally fund specific projects, and require scientists to provide regular progress updates. Some of the best science happens when experiments lead researchers in unexpected directions, but grantees generally need to stick with the specific aims listed in their application or risk having their funding taken away — even if the first few days of an experiment suggest things won’t go as planned.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This system leaves principal investigators constantly scrambling to plug holes in their patchwork of funding. In her first year as a tenure-track professor, <a href="https://www.buckinstitute.org/lab/garrison-lab/">Jennifer Garrison</a>, now a reproductive longevity researcher at the <a href="https://www.buckinstitute.org/">Buck Institute</a>, applied for 45 grants to get her lab off the ground. “I’m so highly trained and specialized,” she told me. “The fact that I spend the majority of my time on administrative paperwork is ridiculous.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Relying on a transient, underpaid workforce makes science worse</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the most part, the principal investigators applying for grants aren’t doing science — their graduate students and postdoctoral fellows are. While professors are teaching, doing administrative paperwork, and managing students, their early-career trainees are the ones who conduct the&nbsp;experiments and analyze data.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since they do the bulk of the intellectual and physical labor, these younger scientists are usually the lead authors of their lab’s publications. In smaller research groups, a grad student may be the only one who fully understands their project.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In some ways, this system works for universities. With most annual stipends falling <a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/loans/student-loans/how-much-do-graduate-students-get-paid">short of $40,000</a>, “Young researchers are highly trained but relatively inexpensive sources of labor for faculty,” then-graduate researcher Laura Weingartner <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/7/14/12016710/science-challeges-research-funding-peer-review-process#1">told Vox in 2016</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Grad students and postdocs are cheap, but they’re also transient. It takes an average of <a href="https://www.usnews.com/education/best-graduate-schools/articles/2019-08-12/how-long-does-it-take-to-get-a-phd-degree-and-should-you-get-one">six years to earn a PhD</a>, with only about three to five of those years devoted to research in a specific lab. This time constraint forces trainees to choose projects that can be wrapped up by the time they graduate, but science, especially groundbreaking science, rarely fits into a three- to five-year window. CRISPR, for instance, was <a href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/what-broad/areas-focus/project-spotlight/crispr-timeline">first characterized in the ’90s</a> — 20 years before it was first used for gene editing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trainees generally try to publish their findings by the time they leave, or pass ownership along to someone they have trained to take the wheel. The pressure to squeeze exciting, publishable data from a single PhD thesis project forces many inexperienced scientists into roles they can’t realistically fulfill. Many people (admittedly, <a href="https://neuroscience.berkeley.edu/news/2023-qa-neuroscience-phd-program-graduates">myself included</a>, as a burnt-out UC Berkeley neuroscience graduate student) wind up leaving a trail of unfinished experiments behind when they leave academia — and have no formal obligation to complete them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When the bulk of your workforce is <a href="https://www.aps.org/apsnews/2024/03/grad-students-postdocs-fair-wages">underpaid</a>, <a href="https://gradresources.org/dealing-with-emotional-fatigue/">burning out</a>, and constantly turning over, it creates a continuity problem. When one person leaves, they often take a bunch of institutional knowledge with them. Ideally, research groups would have at least one or two senior scientists — with as much training as a tenured professor — working in the lab to run experiments, mentor newer scientists, and serve as a stable source of expertise as other researchers come and go.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One major barrier here: Paying a highly trained scientist enough to compete with six-figure industry jobs costs far more than a single federal grant can provide. One $250,000/year NIH R01 — the primary grant awarded to scientists for research projects — barely funds one person’s salary and benefits. While the NIH has specialized funding that students, postdocs, junior faculty, and other trainees can apply for to pay their own wages, funding opportunities for senior scientists are limited. “It’s just not feasible to pay for a senior scientist role unless you have an insane amount of other support,” Garrison told me.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How can we help scientists do cooler, more ambitious research?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Funding scientists themselves, rather than the experiments they say they’ll do, helps — and we already have some evidence to prove it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://hhmi.org/our-approach">Howard Hughes Medical Institute</a> (HHMI) has a funding model worth replicating. It is driven by a “people, not projects” philosophy, granting scientists many years worth of money, without tying them down to specific projects. Grantees continue working at their home institution, but they — along with their postdocs — become employees of HHMI, which pays their salary and benefits.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">HHMI reportedly provides enough funding to operate a small- to medium-sized lab without requiring any extra grants. The idea is that if investigators are simply given enough money to do their jobs, they can redirect all their wasted grant application time toward actually doing science. It’s no coincidence that <a href="https://hhmi.org/about/nobel-laureates">over 30 HHMI-funded scientists</a> have won Nobel Prizes in the past 50 years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://arcinstitute.org/">Arc Institute</a>, a <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2021/12/18/22838746/biomedicine-science-grants-arc-institute">new nonprofit collaboration</a> among research giants Stanford, UC Berkeley, and UC San Francisco, also provides investigators and their labs with renewable eight-year “no-strings-attached” grants. Arc aims to give scientists the freedom and resources to do the slow, unsexy work of developing better research tools — something crucial to science but unappealing to scientific journals (and scientists who need to publish stuff to earn more funding).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Operating Arc is expensive, and the funding model currently <a href="https://arcinstitute.org/about">relies on donations</a> from philanthropists and tech billionaires. Arc supports eight labs so far, and hopes to expand to no more than 350 scientists someday — far short of the <a href="https://nexus.od.nih.gov/all/2024/02/21/fy-2023-by-the-numbers-extramural-grant-investments-in-research/">50,000-some biomedical researchers</a> applying for grants every year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For now, institutional experiments like Arc are just that: experiments. They’re betting that scientists who feel invigorated, creative, and unburdened will be better equipped to take the risks required to make big discoveries.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Building brand-new institutions isn’t the only way to break the cycle of short-term, short-sighted projects in biomedical research. Anything that makes it financially easier for investigators to keep their labs running will help. Universities could pay the salaries of their employees directly, rather than making investigators find money for their trainees themselves. Federal funding agencies could also make grants bigger to <a href="https://nexus.od.nih.gov/all/2022/06/29/inflation-and-nih-research-project-grants/">match the level of inflation</a> — but Congress is unlikely to approve that kind of spending.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Science might also benefit from having fewer, better-paid scientists in long-term positions, rather than relying on the labor of underpaid, under-equipped trainees. “I think it would be better to have fewer scientists doing real, deep work than what we have now,” Garrison said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not that scientists aren’t capable of creative, exciting, ambitious work — they’ve just been forced to bend to a grant system that favors short, risk-averse projects. And if the grant system changes, odds are science will too.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Christian Paz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[3 winners and 2 losers from the Harris-Trump debate]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/370958/harris-trump-debate-winners-losers" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=370958</id>
			<updated>2024-09-11T14:00:06Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-11T04:56:51Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[After Vice President Kamala Harris’s first debate with former President Donald Trump Tuesday, Democrats across the country breathed a sigh of relief and thought: That’s more like it. Harris, by widespread consensus, was the clear winner. “Make no mistake about it, Trump had a bad night,” Fox News’s Brit Hume said on the network afterward. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris and Donald Trump shake hands, smiling at each other. " data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris shakes hands with former President Donald Trump during a presidential debate in Philadelphia, on September 10, 2024. | Saul Loeb/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Saul Loeb/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-2170587742.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris shakes hands with former President Donald Trump during a presidential debate in Philadelphia, on September 10, 2024. | Saul Loeb/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">After Vice President Kamala Harris’s first debate with former President Donald Trump Tuesday, Democrats across the country breathed a sigh of relief and thought: That’s more like it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris, by widespread consensus, was the clear winner. “Make no mistake about it, Trump had a bad night,” Fox News’s Brit Hume said on the network afterward. “My sense is she came out of this in pretty good shape.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The online prediction market Polymarket — reflecting bettors’ estimates of what’s likely to happen — <a href="https://polymarket.com/event/who-will-win-the-debate-according-to-polls">showed</a> a 97 percent chance that the debate would help Harris in the polls. Prediction markets typically just reflect the conventional wisdom, but what this does tell us is that very few people are willing to bet actual money that the debate will help Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The conventional wisdom matters, because the winner of the debate isn’t just determined by what happened onstage, but also by the spin war that ensues afterward. The narrative of who won, the kind of groupthink of the commentariat, gets endlessly discussed in the days after the debate — and, in this case, that narrative is: <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/370942/harris-trump-debate-who-won-bait-kamala-donald">Harris</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/370942/harris-trump-debate-who-won-bait-kamala-donald">won</a> by <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/2024-presidential-debate-kamala-harris-donald-trump-meltdown.html">effectively</a> <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/10/harris-trump-debate-taunts-analysis-00178517">baiting </a><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/kamala-harris-trolled-donald-trump-about-rally-crowd-size-2024-9">Trump</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s too early to say how much the debate will impact the race. Though politics junkies are near-unanimous that Trump lost, it is at least possible that swing voters will have different takeaways. Early signs, though, suggest they may have the same takeaway: a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/elections/interactive/2024/presidential-debate-voter-poll/?itid=hp-top-table-main_p001_f002">Washington Post focus group</a> of 24 undecided swing state voters found that 22 thought Harris performed better. And a <a href="https://twitter.com/mkraju/status/1833718682435870989">CNN post-debate poll</a> found that 63 percent of debate watchers thought Harris won.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is also possible the debate will have little effect on the polls — or, that if it does help Harris, it will help her only briefly, since other events will impact the polls in the nearly two months remaining before Election Day.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But, running the briefest presidential campaign in modern history, the stakes were high for Harris — voters have seen little of her so far, particularly in unscripted high-pressure settings like a debate. And she delivered the strong performance she needed.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Loser: Donald Trump</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before the debate, the conventional wisdom was that to have a strong night, Trump needed to do a few things. He needed to remain focused on tying Harris to the Biden administration’s unpopular record on the economy, immigration, and foreign policy. He had to avoid minefields for him on his weakest issues, abortion and democracy. And he needed to avoid getting sidetracked on rants or conspiracy theories.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he mostly failed to do those things.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On abortion, Trump took credit for the Supreme Court overturning <em>Roe v. Wade</em>, saying it happened “through the genius and heart and strength” of the conservative justices.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He also repeatedly dodged the question of whether he’d veto a national abortion ban if Congress sent one to his desk — saying (probably accurately) that Congress wouldn’t pass such a ban. And yet, despite several opportunities, he couldn’t bring himself to clearly say he’d veto such a bill — perhaps fearing angering his pro-life allies, who have been <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/pro-lifers-blast-trump-betrayal-shifting-abortion-stance-answer-florida-amendment-4">disgruntled</a> with his handling of the issue of late.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Asked whether he regretted anything he did on <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2021/1/6/22217657/us-capitol-breach-trump-rally-presidential-election">January 6, 2021</a>, when his supporters attacked the US Capitol, he didn’t come up with anything. The only thing he complained about was that, in the midst of the chaos inside the building, one of his supporters, Ashli Babbitt, “was shot by an out of control police officer,” he said. (Babbitt and other angry rioters <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/7/13/22573658/trump-who-shot-ashli-babbitt-january-6-martyr">were trying</a> to breach the last barrier separating them from members of Congress who feared for their lives.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And he repeatedly voiced ludicrous-sounding <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/370760/jd-vance-racist-cat-eating-haitian-immigrants">conspiracy theories</a> about immigrants eating cats and dogs, or states <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/3/11/18246702/trump-abortion-ralph-northam-virginia-green-bay">executing babies</a> after they are born.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Late in the debate, Trump claimed that Harris “is Biden,” but he wasn’t even consistent on that — earlier in the evening, Trump had insisted that President Joe Biden “hates” Harris and “can’t stand her,” an odd choice if your campaign strategy is to make Harris responsible for Biden’s record.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And while it is true that Trump hit Harris on inflation and the border many times, it seems unlikely that any of that messaging will sink in when he was saying so many other bizarre and nonsensical things that will get far more attention.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps the clearest indication Trump lost, though, is that his supporters <a href="https://x.com/lindseygrahamsc/status/1833686591564595494?s=61&amp;t=TQlk4x44ENcfSu3Y1ke6ew">took to social media</a> to complain vociferously about the moderators — the telling move of whining about the refs when the outcome isn’t what they’d hoped.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>—Andrew Prokop</em></p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Winner: Kamala Harris</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the days before the debate, it had seemed that the good vibes Kamala Harris had enjoyed since her sudden ascent as the Democratic presidential nominee were in danger of disappearing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Polls showed <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/369827/harris-trump-polls-models-2024-nate-silver">a very close toss-up race</a>. Nate Silver’s election forecast model tipped toward <a href="https://www.natesilver.net/p/nate-silver-2024-president-election-polls-model">making Trump the favorite</a>. Criticism <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/185705/kamala-harris-imitating-biden-bad-media-strategy">rose</a> of Harris for <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/367868/kamala-harris-interviews-press-conferences-criticism">mostly avoiding</a> media interviews in unscripted settings. A <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/08/us/politics/trump-and-harris-times-siena-poll.html">New York Times/Siena College poll</a> released Sunday even showed Trump taking the lead by 1 percentage point nationally — an excellent result for Trump, given the Electoral College’s slant against Democrats.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But in retrospect, Harris’s avoidance of the media helped her debate performance have more impact. She preferred a high-stakes setting where she’d be contrasted with Trump over one in which she’d be squaring off against journalists.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And she was very effective at drawing that contrast.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris hammered home her core message that Trump only cares about himself, not ordinary Americans. She repeated, several times, that her campaign plan includes tax cuts for young families and tax deductions for startup small businesses. She voiced righteous outrage about how Trump’s Supreme Court appointees eliminated national abortion rights protections. She promised to unite Americans rather than divide them, and said she’d represent a new generation of leadership.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Repeatedly, she baited Trump into wasting time indulging in his narcissism — asked about immigration, she threw in a claim that people often leave Trump’s rallies early. Trump couldn’t resist using some of his time to clarify that his rallies are great and everyone loves him.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There were some questionable moments for Harris. It was clear she did not want to talk about inflation — not wanting to get drawn into a discussion about Biden’s record, in contrast to her own tax plan. Asked why she no longer supported some very progressive positions she took while running for president in 2020, she really didn’t give a clear answer on why.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it’s not clear she had any real perfect answer on those topics — avoiding them may have been her best strategic option.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And where she had points to make and punches to land on Tuesday night, she did.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>—Andrew Prokop</em></p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Winner: ABC News’s debate moderators</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">David Muir and Linsey Davis had a difficult task going into Tuesday night’s debate, but they mostly acquitted themselves well. The pair of ABC News moderators ran a tight debate, keeping the candidates to their allotted times (for the most part) and finding the right moments to step in to fact-check as needed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A particularly striking moment came when Trump repeated multiple times the false claim that Democrats support killing babies even after birth. Trump went on to ramble about how he is fine with abortion policy being decided by the states, and waffled about his support for a national abortion ban. As soon as he finished, Davis clarified to the audiences at home: “There is no state in this country where it is legal to kill a baby after it’s born.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, when Trump expounded on the racist far-right conspiracy theories that undocumented immigrants in Springfield, Ohio, are <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/370760/jd-vance-racist-cat-eating-haitian-immigrants">killing and eating pets</a>, Muir once again fact-checked the claim, saying ABC News “did reach out to the city manager there. He told us there have been no credible reports of specific claims of pets being harmed, injured, or abused by individuals within the immigrant community.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No similar fact-checks of Harris were made, which contributed to a feeling among Trump allies that the moderators were conducting a “<a href="https://x.com/JamesSurowiecki/status/1833692429049827699">rig job</a>.” “Trump needs to directly challenge the moderators. Say they’re in the tank for Kamala. Put them on the defensive,” the far-right activist Chris Rufo <a href="https://x.com/realchrisrufo/status/1833684559747252247?s=61&amp;t=TQlk4x44ENcfSu3Y1ke6ew">said on X</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And yet, despite the rules allowing the moderators to mute mics to prevent crosstalk, Trump was repeatedly allowed to talk over Harris, to get the final word during exchanges, and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/09/10/us/elections/trump-harris-attacks-debate-tracker.html">generally</a> to <a href="https://x.com/zeynep/status/1833690991745810584">speak for longer</a> than Harris — a fact that rankled liberal viewers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, the moderators did a good job of keeping the debate on track, at least to the degree you can when moderating a debate involving Trump. The fact-checking may have been controversial with Trump supporters, but they did what journalists should do: call out falsehoods and insist on accuracy. They walked a fine line and managed to mostly stay on it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>—Christian Paz</em></p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Loser: Immigration</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The national debate over immigration has shifted greatly, and that was on full display Tuesday night.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, Democrats emphasized Trump’s cruelty toward asylum seekers and other migrants at the border, while Trump made exaggerated —&nbsp;or outright false — claims about the alleged dangers immigrants posed to citizens’ safety and sovereignty.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Throughout the 2024 campaign, Trump has stayed the course, only growing more extreme in his rhetoric. But Democrats have pivoted greatly. On Tuesday, Harris eschewed any significant mention of immigrants’ plight —&nbsp;or their massive contributions to the country. Instead, she accused Trump of being insufficiently attentive to border security.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Specifically, Harris criticized Trump for urging Republicans in Congress <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/2/5/24062710/senate-immigration-bill-border-security-ukraine-2024">not to vote for a right-wing border bill</a> that Democrats tried to pass in February. The bill was a bipartisan compromise that would have instituted a Republican priority — a new authority to quickly expel migrants arriving on the southern border at times of high demand — in exchange for something Democrats wanted: closing gaps in the legal immigration system that have left everyone from the children of high-skilled foreign workers to Afghan refugees in limbo.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“He preferred to run on a problem instead of fixing a problem,” Harris said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump responded by repeating the <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/09/10/nx-s1-5107320/jd-vance-springfield-ohio-haitians-pets">racist and dehumanizing claim</a>, for which local authorities <a href="https://www.springfieldnewssun.com/news/springfield-police-say-no-reports-of-pets-stolen-after-viral-social-media-post/3WSIZQNHQVE4NP4TS5BVHBB2PY/">have identified no evidence</a>, that <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/370760/jd-vance-racist-cat-eating-haitian-immigrants">Haitian migrants in Springfield, Ohio, eat pets</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“A lot of towns don’t want to talk about it because they’re so embarrassed by it,” Trump said. “This is what’s happening in our country. And it’s a shame.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At no point in the exchange, however, did the Democrat come to the defense of immigrants — a marked departure from the political dynamic that has ruled this issue for years. And that is perhaps a reflection of the fact that <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/368889/immigration-border-polls-election-2024-trump-harris">anti-immigrant sentiment in the electorate is higher</a> than at any point since the early 2000s, just after the 9/11 terror attacks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Border crossings have <a href="https://x.com/ReichlinMelnick/status/1833540264079855691">come down significantly in recent months</a> due to a crackdown by Mexican authorities and Biden’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/353835/asylum-border-biden-policy-trump-shutdown">implementation of new asylum restrictions</a>. Voters have correspondingly become <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/08/14/harris-trump-biden-polling-economy-immigration/">more favorable toward Harris</a> on immigration. But Harris nevertheless did not seem compelled in the debate to take a more empathetic stance on immigration.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>—Nicole Narea</em></p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">​​Winner: Swifties for Kamala</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Seemingly the only way a presidential debate could possibly be overshadowed would be to have the biggest star in the world break some news immediately after it — which is what happened when Taylor Swift <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_wtAOKOW1z/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;ig_rid=463fa03a-269b-4044-b5cc-cb9a38a5d1ce">officially endorsed Harris</a> via an Instagram post released about half an hour after the end of the debate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Like many of you, I watched the debate tonight,” Swift wrote. “I will be casting my vote for Kamala Harris and Tim Walz in the 2024 Presidential Election … I’ve done my research, and I’ve made my choice. Your research is all yours to do, and the choice is yours to make.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The endorsement comes after some uncertainty over whether Swift would even comment on the election, despite vocally supporting Democrats <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BopoXpYnCes/">in past elections</a>. To the extent politics touched Swift, it centered over her <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/369543/brittany-mahomes-likes-trump-instagram">recent friendship with Kansas City quarterback Patrick Mahomes’s wife Brittany</a>, who appears to be supportive of Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But tonight, “Swifties for Kamala” got their wish.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swift’s endorsement offered the slyest of subtweets of Trump’s running mate Sen. JD Vance.&nbsp; She highlighted how she admired Harris’s running mate Gov. Tim Walz, and his “standing up for LGBTQ+ rights, IVF, and a woman’s right to her own body for decades.” The piece de resistance: She signed off the endorsement as a “<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/363473/jd-vance-weird-voting-parents-demeny-postliberalism">childless cat lady</a>” — the most influential one alive.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>—Christian Paz</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Kamala Harris goaded (and goaded and goaded) Trump into a debate trainwreck]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/370942/harris-trump-debate-who-won-bait-kamala-donald" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=370942</id>
			<updated>2024-09-11T04:04:06Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-11T03:48:11Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[By any reasonable metric, Vice President Kamala Harris soundly beat former President Donald Trump in Tuesday night’s presidential debate.&#160; She did it by demonstrating superior knowledge not only of policy, but also of her opponent’s psychology. Harris figured out exactly how to get Trump angry, how to trick him into veering off course, and how [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris, in a black suit and white blouse, rests one hand under her chin while listening to a debate answer, looking to her right." data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris during the second presidential debate in Philadelphia, on September 10, 2024. | Doug Mills/New York Times/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Doug Mills/New York Times/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2170584934.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris during the second presidential debate in Philadelphia, on September 10, 2024. | Doug Mills/New York Times/Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">By any reasonable metric, Vice President Kamala Harris soundly beat former President Donald Trump in Tuesday night’s presidential debate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She did it by demonstrating superior knowledge not only of policy, but also of her opponent’s psychology. Harris figured out exactly how to get Trump angry, how to trick him into veering off course, and how to keep the debate on favorable terrain.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To put it more bluntly: Harris manipulated Trump into spiraling at several points during their first (only?) debate.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
 <blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">it&#039;s so funny how for weeks everyone telegraphed &quot;she&#039;s gonna bait him&quot; and her team was like &quot;we&#039;re gonna bait him&quot; and he managed to act normal for like 3 minutes and then she said one thing about his rallies and it was like feeding a gremlin after midnight</p>&mdash; Sal Gentile (@salgentile) <a href="https://twitter.com/salgentile/status/1833684067859976519?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let me give you an example. Early on in the debate, the moderators tried to press Harris on President Joe Biden’s unpopular immigration record, asking her if she would have done anything differently from her current boss — a topic favorable for Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris answered the question — but then took a seemingly unrelated shot at Trump’s rallies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’m going to invite you to attend one of Donald Trump’s rallies because it’s a really interesting thing to watch. You will see during the course of his rallies he talks about fictional characters like Hannibal Lecter. He will talk about [how] windmills cause cancer. And what you will also notice is that people start leaving his rallies early out of exhaustion and boredom,” the vice president said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This gave Trump a choice; either prosecute Harris on immigration, an issue where she’s weak, or go on a rant in defense of his vaunted rallies. You can guess what he chose.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Let me respond as to the rallies,” Trump said. “She said people start leaving. People don’t go to her rallies. There’s no reason to go. And the people that do go, she’s busing them in and paying them to be there.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That began a tailspin: a series of weird tangents, including a humiliating rant about the completely fake problem of <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/370760/jd-vance-racist-cat-eating-haitian-immigrants">Haitian migrants supposedly eating dogs in Springfield</a>, Ohio, punctuated by immense concern about the honor of Trump rallies. He never really got back to what he should have been doing —&nbsp;attacking Harris on migration across the southern border.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By needling Trump where it hurts — the rallies he cares about so much — Harris managed to get him off balance, and he honestly never really recovered.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris deployed this strategy again and again.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During an exchange on crime, Harris brought up Trump’s own criminal conviction — leading him to go on a diatribe about “political prosecutions” instead of effectively pushing Harris on her <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/10/us/politics/harris-trump-flip-flops.html">flip-flops on crime policy</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She brought up world leaders calling him a “disgrace,” pushing him into bragging about his relationship with <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/5/21/21256324/viktor-orban-hungary-american-conservatives">Hungarian “strongman” (in Trump’s words) Viktor Orbán</a>, perhaps not a callout that the swing voters of Michigan, Wisconsin, or Pennsylvania were clamoring for. She needled his closeness with Russia’s Vladimir Putin, blasting “what you think is a friendship” with a “dictator who would eat you for lunch.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Each time, Trump took the bait —&nbsp;losing control of his temper and going off message, while Harris looked on what must have been glee.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In hindsight, this strategy might seem innovative, but it speaks to something well-known about Trump’s psychology.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Covering foreign policy during the Trump years, one fear I heard a lot from national security professionals was that Trump could be easily manipulated: His well-known vanity and narcissism made it easy for foreign powers to extract policy favors through personal flattery and lavish receptions. This seems to explain, at least in part, how Trump went from hostile to friendly with foreign leaders like Kim Jong Un and Xi Jinping.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But if foreign leaders could figure out how to manipulate Trump’s self-absorption, so too could his domestic opposition. Harris played on that immense pride Tuesday night.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This tactic wasn’t the only reason she won the debate — see her <a href="https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/harris-trump-presidential-debate-election-2024/card/harris-delivers-a-strong-punch-on-abortion-rights-02n3irYiXHiJjdihta36">strong answer on abortion</a>, among other things — but it was a vital one.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Tyreek Hill’s disturbing detention by police, explained]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/criminal-justice/370894/tyreek-hill-police-detention-traffic-stop" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=370894</id>
			<updated>2024-09-10T22:18:10Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-10T22:20:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A brutal police encounter involving Miami Dolphins football player Tyreek Hill is the latest to underscore the enduring problem of violence by law enforcement and how force has been disproportionately used against Black Americans.&#160; On Sunday morning, officers pulled Hill over for a traffic stop near the Dolphins’ Hard Rock Stadium in Miami Gardens and [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Miami Dolphins’ wide receiver Tyreek Hill looks on before a game. " data-caption="Tyreek Hill on the sidelines during an NFL preseason football game against the Tampa Bay Buccaneers at Raymond James Stadium on August 23, 2024 in Tampa, Florida. | &lt;p&gt;Kevin Sabitus/Getty &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;p&gt;Kevin Sabitus/Getty &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2169369514_9e6d7b.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Tyreek Hill on the sidelines during an NFL preseason football game against the Tampa Bay Buccaneers at Raymond James Stadium on August 23, 2024 in Tampa, Florida. | &lt;p&gt;Kevin Sabitus/Getty &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">A brutal police encounter involving Miami Dolphins football player Tyreek Hill is the latest to underscore the enduring problem of violence by law enforcement and how force has been disproportionately used against Black Americans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Sunday morning, officers pulled Hill over for a traffic stop near the Dolphins’ Hard Rock Stadium in Miami Gardens and quickly escalated the situation. After Hill handed over his identification, he rolled his window up. When he was slow to roll it back down, an officer violently dragged him out of the car, threw him to the ground, and handcuffed him.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hill was then forced to sit on the side of the road while cuffed and received <a href="https://x.com/JeffDarlington/status/1833583556708471122">two traffic citations</a>, before getting released prior to the start of that afternoon’s game. Two of Hill’s teammates, Calais Campbell and Jonnu Smith, also <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/10/sport/tyreek-hill-what-we-know-miami-dolphins-detainment-spt/index.html">stopped their cars</a> after seeing police confront Hill. Because he didn’t respond to a request to move his car, Campbell was also handcuffed and later released without a ticket.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hill has told reporters that <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/09/sport/dolphins-tyreek-hill-mike-mcdaniel-spt-intl/index.html">he was “shell-shocked”</a> by the entire exchange, noting that it went rapidly <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/sports/nfl/tyreek-hill-police-stop-miami-dolphins-rcna170253">from “zero to 60.”</a> He spoke, too, of fears that things could have escalated further had he not been a famous football player. “What if I wasn’t Tyreek Hill?” <a href="https://www.espn.com/nfl/story/_/id/41183143/tyreek-hill-trying-process-pregame-detainment-police">he asked</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://x.com/MiamiDolphins/status/1833316157463449919?">The Miami Dolphins</a> lambasted the officers’ “overly aggressive and violent conduct,” in a statement as well, noting that it was “maddening” and “heartbreaking” to “watch the very people we trust to protect our community use such unnecessary force and hostility toward these players.”</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/Wz6mQt3Owc">pic.twitter.com/Wz6mQt3Owc</a></p>&mdash; Miami Dolphins (@MiamiDolphins) <a href="https://twitter.com/MiamiDolphins/status/1833316157463449919?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Miami-Dade Police Department <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BnK5aH9uKCs">released body camera footage</a> of the disturbing encounter on Monday evening, and has placed one of the officers involved on administrative duties. It’s also conducting an Internal Affairs investigation on the incident, <a href="https://x.com/MiamiDadePD/status/1832875203816284510">Chief Stephanie Daniels said in a statement</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">SLATER SCOOP: Tyreek Hill body-cam video from Miami-Dade Police. <a href="https://t.co/aJvD4SamZk">pic.twitter.com/aJvD4SamZk</a></p>&mdash; Andy Slater (@AndySlater) <a href="https://twitter.com/AndySlater/status/1833273674033463799?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The violence directed at Hill puts another spotlight on the pervasiveness of police brutality and systemic racism — including the threat that traffic stops can pose to Black Americans. <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/investigations/police-shootings-database/">According to a Washington Post tracker</a>, 810 people have been fatally shot by police in 2024, and that figure reached a record high of 1,163 people in 2023. Black Americans are also twice as likely to be killed by police than white Americans, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/investigations/police-shootings-database/">the Post notes</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Lord knows, I probably would have been, like, worst-case scenario, I would have been shot or would have been locked up,” <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/sports/nfl/tyreek-hill-police-stop-miami-dolphins-rcna170253">Hill told NBC News</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>How police escalated a speeding ticket</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hill was driving to the Dolphins game when police pulled him over <a href="https://apnews.com/article/dolphins-tyreek-hill-detained-b7818aea160bed284444594a689f453d">for speeding and reckless driving</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">An officer knocked on his window and Hill handed him his identification, rolling the window back up after doing so. The officer then knocked on his window multiple times and asked him to keep it down.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hill then rolls the window down part way, and the officer states: “Keep that window down, or else I’m going to get you out of the car.” Without waiting for Hill to roll the window further, the officer then says, “As a matter of fact, get out of the car,” and goes to pull the driver’s side door open.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While he does this, a second officer comes up and starts yelling, “I’ll break that freaking window.” That second officer pulls the door open and starts yanking Hill out of the car, slamming him to the ground. Once he’s on the ground, one of the officers uses his knee to pin Hill to the ground as the two pull his arms behind his back and handcuff him.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’m getting arrested, Drew,” Hill can be heard saying to Drew Brooks, <a href="https://www.palmbeachpost.com/story/sports/nfl/dolphins/2024/09/10/drew-brooks-dolphins-security-chief-tyreek-hill-detained/75159960007/">the head of Miami Dolphins’ security</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“When we tell you to do something, you do it, you understand? Not what you want, but what we tell you,” one of the officers says. “You’re a little fucking confused.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Take it easy, bro, do what you gotta do,” Hill says.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The officers bring Hill up to his feet as two of his teammates — Campbell and Smith — pass by in other cars. “They beating on my window, like he crazy. I didn’t do nothing,” Hill says.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The officers then try to make Hill sit down on the curb on the side of the road, while he asks them to “hold on.” “I just had surgery on my knee,” Hill says, as one of the officers hooks his arm around his neck and upper body, dragging him to a seated position. “I just had surgery on my knee,” Hill repeats.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Really, what a coincidence. Did you have surgery on your ears when we told you to put the window down?” the officer yells.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Bro, chill,” Hill says.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Smith’s car pulls up a few meters down the road and he then gets out and calls someone, saying “They got Tyreek. The cops over here beating on him.” The officers confront Smith and ask him not to park there, and to get back in the car. An officer starts yelling at Smith for his license, and says “or I’m going to lock you up.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Campbell also parks his car on the side of the road behind the police officers’ motorcycles, and he’s repeatedly yelled at to “leave” or risk the consequences. “If you don’t leave, I’m going to take you to jail,” one officer says. That officer then proceeds to handcuff Campbell and force him to sit down as well.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Campbell is down and kneeling, the officer says, “I told you to leave. Why didn’t you leave?” “Because you have my friend in handcuffs,” Campbell says. The officers eventually release Campbell, and then later release Hill.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s crazy that me and my family had to go through this,” Hill told CNN.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The regional police union has claimed that officers’ conduct was due to Hill not complying quickly enough with their demands. “Upon being stopped, Mr. Hill was not immediately cooperative with the officers on scene who, pursuant to policy and for their immediate safety, placed Mr. Hill in handcuffs,” Steadman Stahl, president of the South Florida Police Benevolent Association, said in a statement.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think the officers felt like I wasn’t doing it on they time, but I was doing it,” <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/10/sport/tyreek-hill-what-we-know-miami-dolphins-detainment-spt/index.html">Hill said in the CNN interview.</a> After his release, Hill and his teammates went on to play in their season opener against the Jacksonville Jaguars, during which Hill scored a pivotal touchdown. After he scored, Hill put his hands behind his back to mimic being arrested.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The police brutality Hill experienced is widespread</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sunday’s violent traffic stop adds to systemic problems law enforcement has long had with use of force.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Police use force on at least 300,000 people annually, according to a review by Mapping Police Violence, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/28/police-use-of-force-violence-data-analysis">a nonprofit research organization.</a> These incidents include the use of stun guns, chokeholds, and dog attacks, among other methods. The data, like the FBI’s, is incomplete, because it only includes information from the police departments that <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1q2rl7FInse4tf82mbAJ5VHvj6ZnAlcAs/view">voluntarily responded to a request</a> from Mapping Police Violence.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The report also determined that Black people were more than three times as likely to be the subjects of force from police officers than white people. “All the inequities we’ve identified about police deadly force appear to be even more extreme in the context of overall police force,” Mapping Police Violence founder <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/28/police-use-of-force-violence-data-analysis">Samuel Sinyangwe told The Guardian.</a> As Vox’s Marin Cogan <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23614082/sarah-seo-traffic-police-tyre-nichols">has explained</a>, traffic stops are also a common mode of interaction people have with police, and turn deadly at a concerning frequency, particularly for Black drivers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These disparities and violence by police were the subject of massive protests in 2020, following officers’ <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/5/29/21274844/protests-minneapolis-george-floyd-policing-racial-disparity">murder of George Floyd in Minnesota</a>. Such outrage has persisted as police killings, including those of <a href="https://www.vox.com/criminal-justice/363206/sonya-massey-police-killing-sean-grayson">Sonya Massey</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/24153974/roger-fortson-police-killing">Roger Fortson</a> this year, have continued.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Let’s make a change,” <a href="https://x.com/cheetah/status/1833295115680682337">Hill wrote in a post on X</a>, formerly known as Twitter, after the body-camera footage was released on Monday. When asked to elaborate on his post in a CNN interview, he said he was trying to figure out a way forward to address these abuses. “We done tried it all. We done protested. We even took a knee. … So, what’s next?” Hill said.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Republicans threaten a government shutdown unless Congress makes it harder to vote]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/370713/republican-government-shutdown-save-act-voter-disenfranchisement" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=370713</id>
			<updated>2024-09-10T20:36:20Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-10T20:35:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Congress" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Voting Rights" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s that time again. The last act of Congress funding the federal government expires on September 30. So, unless Congress passes new funding legislation by then, much of the government will shut down. House Speaker Mike Johnson (R-LA), egged on by the House Freedom Caucus and by former President Donald Trump, reportedly wants to use [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Mike Johnson, in a navy suit and blue and red striped tie, wearing glasses, smiles while he talks, with an American flag visible behind him." data-caption="House Speaker Mike Johnson at a news conference at the US Capitol in Washington, DC, in July. | Graeme Sloan/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Graeme Sloan/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2162530073.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>House Speaker Mike Johnson at a news conference at the US Capitol in Washington, DC, in July. | Graeme Sloan/Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s that time again. The last act of Congress funding the federal government <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/09/09/congress-government-spending-shutdown-deadline/">expires on September 30</a>. So, unless Congress passes new funding legislation by then, much of the government will shut down.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">House Speaker Mike Johnson (R-LA), <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/house/4850815-proof-of-citizenship-voting-bill-government-shutdown/">egged on by the House Freedom Caucus</a> and by <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/03/30/no-big-wave-immigrants-voting-illegally-trump">former President Donald Trump</a>, reportedly wants to use this deadline to force through legislation that would make it harder to register to vote in all 50 states.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson plans to pair a bill funding the government for six months with a Republican bill called the “Safeguard American Voter Eligibility Act” or “<a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/118th-congress/house-bill/8281/text">SAVE Act</a>,” that would require new voters to submit “documentary proof of United States citizenship,” such as a passport or a birth certificate, in order to register to vote.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As recently as Monday night, Johnson’s plan to tie government funding to passage of the SAVE Act <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/09/10/mike-johnson-government-shutdown-funding">seemed dead</a>. At least five House Republicans oppose the spending bill, enough that Johnson would need to secure Democratic votes in order to pass it. But Trump, the GOP’s presidential nominee, demanded on Tuesday that congressional Republicans “<a href="https://x.com/PhilipWegmann/status/1833580787045646535">SHOULD, IN NO WAY, SHAPE, OR FORM, GO FORWARD</a>” with legislation funding the government unless it also includes something like the SAVE Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is no evidence that noncitizens vote in US federal elections in any meaningful numbers, and states typically have safeguards in place to prevent them from doing so. Georgia Secretary of State Brad Raffensperger, a Republican, for example, <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/noncitizen-voting-is-extremely-rare-yet-republicans-are-making-it-a-major-election-concern">claims to have identified 1,634 “potential noncitizens”</a> who attempted to register during a 15-year period. But these possible noncitizens were caught by election officials and were never registered. In 2020, <a href="https://www.politico.com/2020-election/results/georgia/">nearly 5 million Georgians voted</a> in the presidential election.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More broadly, according to the Bipartisan Policy Center, “illegal registration and voting attempts by noncitizens are routinely investigated and prosecuted by the appropriate state authorities, and there is <a href="https://bipartisanpolicy.org/blog/five-things-to-know-about-the-save-act/">no evidence that attempts at voting by noncitizens</a> have been significant enough to impact any election’s outcome.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While noncitizen voting — which is, of course, illegal — has never been proven to have affected an election, there is evidence that the SAVE Act could have an impact on elections. That much is clear from Arizona, which already has a SAVE Act-like regime. <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/367701/supreme-court-arizona-rnc-republicans-mi-familia-vota">Data from Arizona</a> suggests the state’s law has made it slightly harder for people of color, a group that skews Democratic, to vote. And at least one analysis of Arizona voter data suggests that the SAVE Act could <a href="https://www.votebeat.org/arizona/2023/12/18/arizona-federal-only-voters-concentrated-college-campuses-proof-of-citizenship/">suppress voter registration among another group that tends to vote for Democrats</a>: college students. So the bill could make it slightly more difficult for Democrats to win elections.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That said, the SAVE Act law does have a vague provision allowing voters who “cannot provide” the required documentation to submit other evidence that they are a citizen, and it provides that state or local officials “shall make a determination as to whether the applicant has sufficiently established United States citizenship.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s unclear what, exactly, that means.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Notably, the SAVE Act would <a href="https://bipartisanpolicy.org/blog/five-things-to-know-about-the-save-act/">take effect immediately if enacted by Congress</a>, and it imposes significant new administrative burdens on state and local election offices. So, if the law did take effect in the two months before a presidential election, it could potentially throw that election into chaos.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Realistically, that outcome is unlikely. Axios reports that Senate Minority Leader Mitch McConnell (R-KY) is <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/25/mcconnell-republicans-save-act-immigrant-voting">opposed</a> to making continued funding for the US government contingent on passing the SAVE Act. Most Democrats and President Joe Biden also oppose the bill.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, the battle over the SAVE Act could put the US in danger of a government shutdown. And though it is unlikely to become law in the next two months, it is likely to be on the short list of bills that Republicans will be eager to turn into law should they prevail in this November’s election.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How would the SAVE Act actually impact US elections?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the SAVE Act became law, it would likely only have a marginal impact on election results — although even a modest shift in who is allowed to vote could <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/367701/supreme-court-arizona-rnc-republicans-mi-familia-vota">potentially flip very close elections</a>, particularly in swing states. On its face, the bill addresses a non-problem — again, there are no legitimate concerns about noncitizen voting in the United States. And most voters do have some documentation they could use to register under the SAVE Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, Arizona offers a useful window into what voting might be like under the SAVE Act. In 2004, the state enacted a SAVE Act-like law requiring new voters to submit documentary proof of citizenship to register. This law, however, <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/367701/supreme-court-arizona-rnc-republicans-mi-familia-vota">conflicts with a federal law</a> which requires states to register voters who submit a standardized federal form. In 2013, the Supreme Court ruled that Arizona could not prevent voters who register using this form from voting in federal elections.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Arizona, however, responded to this decision by creating a second-class tier of voters. Arizona voters who submit the federal form without documentary proof of citizenship are allowed to vote in federal elections (for Congress and the president), but not in state elections.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Data from Arizona suggests that <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/367701/supreme-court-arizona-rnc-republicans-mi-familia-vota">non-white voters</a> (who tend to prefer Democrats to Republicans) are more likely to be registered as federal-only voters than white voters. But college students appear to be hardest hit by Arizona’s two-tiered regime.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A report by Votebeat, a news outlet that reports on election administration, found that most Arizona voting precincts have fewer than a dozen total federal-only voters. But, “of the dozen outliers with more than 300 federal-only voters,” Votebeat reports that “<a href="https://www.votebeat.org/arizona/2023/12/18/arizona-federal-only-voters-concentrated-college-campuses-proof-of-citizenship/">all but one are located at least partly on a college campus</a>.” The one exception was a Phoenix precinct that includes a homeless shelter.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This conclusion is intuitive. College students who leave home to earn their degree often do not bring their passport or birth certificate to school with them, so they are unable to submit it when they register to vote. (People without permanent housing are also likely not to have immediate access to these documents because they do not have a home to store them in.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a close election, a law disenfranchising many college students could be dispositive.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the razor-thin 2000 election, for example, official tallies showed that President George W. Bush <a href="https://constitutioncenter.org/blog/on-this-day-bush-v-gore-anniversary">won the crucial state of Florida by 537 votes</a>. Meanwhile, the University of Florida alone <a href="https://www.usnews.com/best-colleges/university-of-florida-1535/student-life#:~:text=University%20of%20Florida%20has%20a,students%20and%2056%25%20female%20students.">enrolls nearly 35,000 undergraduates</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, while the SAVE Act wouldn’t do much to address the fake problem of noncitizen voting, it would have at least some impact on US elections.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, September 10, 4:35 pm ET: </strong>This piece was originally published on September 9 and has been updated to note Trump’s demand that a bill funding the government must include the SAVE Act.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple’s new AI is magically mediocre]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/370836/apple-intelligence-iphone-16-ios-update-siri" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=370836</id>
			<updated>2024-09-10T20:34:08Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-10T20:10:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Apple" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Big Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Intelligence is cool, useful, and perhaps most importantly, charmingly unfinished. Unlike some other AI projects, this upgrade to the software that powers iPhones, iPads, and Macs does not appear to threaten our very existence. Its standout features are supposed to include privacy and a Siri that actually works. But none of it works quite [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Tim Cook stands on a stage with a giant neon outlined Apple logo behind him." data-caption="Apple announced that its new AI technology would be available in October at an event at its Cupertino campus on September 9, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-2170394608.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Apple announced that its new AI technology would be available in October at an event at its Cupertino campus on September 9, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Apple Intelligence is cool, useful, and perhaps most importantly, charmingly unfinished. Unlike some other AI projects, this upgrade to the software that powers iPhones, iPads, and Macs does not appear to <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/354794/apple-artificial-intelligence-ai-wwdc">threaten our very existence</a>. Its standout features are supposed to include <a href="https://security.apple.com/blog/private-cloud-compute/">privacy</a> and a <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/how-siri-made-apple-cautious-about-ai.html">Siri that actually works</a>. But none of it works quite yet, and despite its imminent launch, it probably won’t for many months.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At this year’s annual new iPhone announcement, Apple revealed that, months after announcing the new product, it will finally release Apple Intelligence in <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/09/apple-intelligence-comes-to-iphone-ipad-and-mac-starting-next-month/">October</a>. Apple Intelligence will only work on the latest iPhone models, including the iPhone 15 Pro, and MacBooks and iPads with M1 processors or better. It also won’t ship as a finished product. When you update your devices with Apple Intelligence in a few weeks, you’ll get a beta version that may or may not work better than the beta version I’ve been testing on my phone and laptop for the past couple of weeks.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even through the unfinished glitches, however, I can see how Apple Intelligence will change the way I use my iPhone and my Mac. It’s a subtle, meaningful shift, but I doubt any of these new AI-powered habits would change my life, at least not in the next year or so.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before I dig into what it’s like to use Apple Intelligence, let’s review Apple’s surprisingly sober promises about the product. Apple Intelligence is not designed to blow you away. Apple is calling it “<a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-intelligence/">AI for the rest of us</a>,” which translates as “AI that won’t frighten you” when you consider the competition. Google’s Gemini got in trouble earlier this year after its image generation showed an <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/2/28/24083814/google-gemini-ai-bias-ethics">unusual bias</a>. ChatGPT has been <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2022/12/15/23509014/chatgpt-artificial-intelligence-openai-language-models-ai-risk-google">scaring people</a> pretty much since it launched in the fall of 2022. Meanwhile, experts have said that the steady march of ultra-capable AI technology — something we <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/368537/ai-artificial-intelligence-capabilities-risks-warning-system">don’t fully understand</a> and that <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/2024/3/28/24111721/climate-ai-tech-energy-demand-rising">devours vast amounts of resources</a> — might <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23447596/artificial-intelligence-agi-openai-gpt3-existential-risk-human-extinction">kill us all</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So yes, I personally would like the diet version of that. I am the rest of us. Apple Intelligence is for me. It’s just too bad I won’t really get to use it all that soon.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Apple Intelligence is slow and steady and definitely not scary</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The new Apple Intelligence technology is baked into the latest versions of iOS, iPadOS, and macOS. When you update your software, you’ll get the option to turn it on, and at that point, you might not even notice it because some of the features are buried in menus. When you find them, though, they sort of work!</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/9/24237601/apple-iphone-16-event-announcements-products">its iPhone 16 announcement on Monday</a>, Apple described the four pillars of Apple Intelligence: language, images, action, and personal context. The first two refer to features that exist in a lot of generative AI software. Language refers to Apple Intelligence’s ability to read and summarize things like your email inbox and notifications as well as rewrite stuff you write in apps like Notes and Pages. Images refers to its image-editing features, like Clean Up, which lets you remove objects from photos.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of these features were available in the developer beta I tested. (Beta versions of software are pre-release versions that developers release to a large group of people to see how they stand up to stress tests.) The new Apple Intelligence features are fine. The summaries are adequate if <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/09/09/iphone-16-apple-intelligence-ai-event-2024/">occasionally error-prone</a>. The email summaries were the first Apple Intelligence feature I noticed, although you won’t notice them if you use the Gmail app. The Writing Tools feature can do a lot more — if you think to highlight the text you want to fool with and then tap to activate the dashboard. There you can do some pretty simple rewriting of the text to make it sound friendlier or more professional. You can also record meetings or phone calls and then get Apple Intelligence to transcribe and summarize what was said. None of this is revolutionary, but even basic writing tools <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-00528-w">can save you time</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the image front, the Clean Up feature is neat, although very similar to what you’ve been able to do with the Magic Eraser in Google Photos <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en_us/photos/editing/">for months</a>. Once you activate the Clean Up tool, you literally use your finger or mouse to erase the part of the photo you want gone and it magically disappears. It did, however, leave my photos looking obviously manipulated. Removing a swan from a picture of my wife and daughter by a pond made the water look doctored. But at least that gets around the problem of AI creating fake images you can’t tell are fake.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/Apple-Intelligence-Triptych-copy.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,13.549476030119,100,72.901047939762" alt="Three screenshots in a row: Apple’s Writing Tools (left) can jazz up your prose, while the new Clean Up tool (center) does a mediocre job of doctoring images, as the unusual texture of the sidewalk in the bottom right reveals. Siri (right) is still mostly the same except you can type instead of talk now." title="Three screenshots in a row: Apple’s Writing Tools (left) can jazz up your prose, while the new Clean Up tool (center) does a mediocre job of doctoring images, as the unusual texture of the sidewalk in the bottom right reveals. Siri (right) is still mostly the same except you can type instead of talk now." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Apple’s Writing Tools (left) can jazz up your prose, while the new Clean Up tool (center) does a mediocre job of doctoring images, as the unusual texture of the sidewalk in the bottom right reveals. Siri (right) is still mostly the same except you can type instead of talk now. | Vox" data-portal-copyright="Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">There are two more image-generation features — one called Image Playground that lets you create illustrations and one called Genmoji that lets you make your own custom emoji — that will roll out “later this year and in the months following,” according to Apple.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That disclaimer applies to the other two pillars of Apple Intelligence: action and personal context. Generally speaking, these vague terms just refer to the new Siri and how it can do things and know more about you. The example that Apple continues to offer for this further future of Apple Intelligence is that you’ll be able to ask Siri to send photos of a specific group of people at a specific event to a specific person (e.g. “Text Grandma the pictures of our family from last weekend’s barbecue”) and Siri will just do it. You can also now type your Siri request into a new menu that you pull up when you double-tap the bottom end of the screen. This is a game changer for people like me who don’t like talking to computers in public.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I have no idea if this works because these new Siri features were not available in the version of Apple Intelligence I tested, and it’s not clear when they will be. But the new Siri — or at least the initial features Apple has so far revealed — is better for sure. It can understand the context if you ask follow-up questions after an initial query. Siri will also understand what you’re saying if you stutter or change your mind, which does not represent a revolution in the capabilities of natural language processing but is a step in the right direction for the <a href="https://www.cultofmac.com/news/former-apple-engineer-explains-why-siri-still-sucks">famously limited and clumsy Siri</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once Apple Intelligence is released to the public, however, we’ll also start to see what third-party apps do with the new Siri functionality. “Siri will gain screen awareness,” Apple senior vice president Craig Federighi said at Monday’s event. “It will be able to take hundreds of new actions in your apps.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, Siri will know what you’re doing on your phone when you make requests and act on them — hence the buzzwords “action” and “personal context.” But again, these more advanced features, cool as they sound, are not ready yet.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>We have to wait for the best features. That’s a good thing.</strong>&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It would be a gross overstatement to say that Apple Intelligence has transformed the way I use my iPhone and MacBook. Because the AI-powered features are so far limited and out of view, I actually forget they’re there. It’s also worth emphasizing that I’m testing an unreleased version of the software. Although it probably looks very close to what Apple will release next month, the version of Apple Intelligence I’ve been using is buggy and unfinished. Apple will work out many of the bugs in the weeks to come. However, it will not release a finished product in October.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Apple hasn’t said when Apple Intelligence will graduate from beta. It could be years. After all, Google <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2009/07/08/technology/companies/08google.html#:~:text=Released%20on%20April%201%2C%202004,product%20to%20be%20fully%20baked.">left Gmail in beta for five years</a> before shedding the label. And as long as Apple wants to distance itself from any mistakes Apple Intelligence makes — and generative AI makes mistakes, namely <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/15/24154808/ai-chatgpt-google-gemini-microsoft-copilot-hallucination-wrong">hallucinations</a>, essentially by design — we should expect the label to stick around.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One potential limitation Apple is facing in its quest to bring more advanced AI features to its users is its commitment to privacy. I mentioned privacy earlier as a key feature, although I haven’t described what it looks like because it’s invisible. While AI technology like Google Gemini and OpenAI’s ChatGPT require sending vast amounts of your <a href="https://hai.stanford.edu/news/privacy-ai-era-how-do-we-protect-our-personal-information">data to servers</a> in the cloud, Apple, which is famously serious about privacy and security, promises its proprietary AI models will do as much on your device as it can, as Apple does with much of your data. And when Apple does need to send your data to a server, it will do so in a secure way with <a href="https://security.apple.com/blog/private-cloud-compute/">a new system called Private Cloud Compute</a>. As more advanced features require more computing power, it remains to be seen how this system keeps up with its competitors.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then there’s the matter of cost. It was free for me to test Apple Intelligence through the beta version of iOS 18, but it’s not clear that all of the features will be free for everyone. First of all, you’ll need a device that supports Apple Intelligence, which, again, only works on the <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-intelligence/">latest devices</a>. For most people, that will mean buying a new iPhone. For the most advanced features, Apple will reportedly <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2024-06-11/will-apple-intelligence-features-boost-iphone-sales-it-may-take-years?srnd=undefined">charge a monthly fee</a> at some point in the future. So while a super-smart Siri sounds useful, your life probably won’t be totally transformed <a href="https://s2.washingtonpost.com/camp-rw/?trackId=6669a85845de251494a100e9&amp;s=66e0740e7189150e28b3cd27&amp;linknum=2&amp;linktot=50">unless you’re willing to pay</a> for the privilege.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So here I am, having almost stumbled into Apple Intelligence. I upgraded to an iPhone 15 Pro ahead of the Apple Intelligence announcement, and if I hadn’t, I would not buy a new phone just to get the new AI technology. But since Apple Intelligence works on my phone, I’ve been enjoying the extent to which it makes a lot of things I do a little easier. When I think to use it, Apple Intelligence saves me a few moments of work that I would have otherwise spent reading every notification or editing a photo. At this point, I have to check the AI’s work, but that doesn’t bother me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s the imminent future in which the AI’s work is indistinguishable from our own that I dread. For now, I’m happy with the simplicity of Apple’s diet AI, and I don’t mind that it screws up sometimes. So do I.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story was also published in the Vox Technology newsletter.&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/newsletters"><em><strong>Sign up here</strong></em></a><em>&nbsp;so you don’t miss the next one!</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Keren Landman, MD</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Yet another person got bird flu. Now should I freak out?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/370804/bird-flu-h5n1-missouri-human-cows-raw-milk" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=370804</id>
			<updated>2024-09-10T18:31:30Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-10T18:31:30Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last Friday, the Missouri health department announced a recent human case of bird flu. What’s unsettling about the case is that the patient — hospitalized on August 22 and later released — is the first among 15 people infected in the US who didn’t report having contact with animals. That raises the possibility that the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-530055943.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Last Friday, the Missouri health department announced a recent <a href="https://health.mo.gov/news/newsitem/uuid/0ca9d648-cb9b-4eca-99a8-f9a1c96a01bd/human-h5-bird-flu-case-confirmed-in-missouri?utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email">human case of bird flu</a>. What’s unsettling about the case is that the patient — hospitalized on August 22 and later released — is the first among <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/bird-flu/h5-monitoring/index.html">15 people infected in the US</a> who didn’t report having contact with animals. That raises the possibility that the illness has already begun spreading among humans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not yet clear whether the virus involved is the <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/bird-flu/avian-timeline/2020s.html">H5N1 influenza subtype</a> that has infected wild birds, poultry, and dairy cows worldwide since it was first identified in 2020 and raised flags among experts about another potential pandemic. If it is, though, there’s concern about what the Missouri case could represent. “There’s a few steps before this potentially becomes a pandemic threat,” says <a href="https://www.bu.edu/ceid/about-the-center/team/nahid-bhadelia-md-mald/">Nahid Bhadelia</a>, who directs the Boston University Center on Emerging Infectious Diseases. “But I’m a lot more worried about it than I was.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bird flu’s threat to most people remains pretty low. Still, here’s what makes this case concerning to experts, and what you can do to keep yourself safe.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What experts are worrying about</strong></h2>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The Missouri patient was sick enough to be hospitalized</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the virus first spread to American dairy cows in January of this year, all 13 of the bird flu cases identified in humans before last Friday caused <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/bird-flu/spotlights/h5n1-response-07192024.html">pretty mild disease</a> — eye redness, otherwise known as conjunctivitis, and in one person, a cough without a fever. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s where the latest case is different: The patient was hospitalized, suggesting severe disease. The Missouri health department noted the adult patient “has underlying medical conditions,” but we don’t know their age or other risk factors.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For a flu virus to cause a human pandemic, says <a href="https://med.emory.edu/directory/profile/?u=SLAKDAW">Seema Lakdawala</a>, a virologist and flu expert at Emory University, it needs to overcome three hurdles: It must access and replicate efficiently within the respiratory tract to cause disease; it must spread easily from person to person; and it must be novel to our immune systems. If the virus infecting the latest case turns out to be H5N1, the fact the patient was hospitalized suggests this germ is evolving to replicate more efficiently in our airways (and coming closer to overcoming the first hurdle).&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">We don’t know how the Missouri patient got infected</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"> Another thing all previous US human H5N1 cases shared was that they could be <a href="https://www.avma.org/resources-tools/animal-health-and-welfare/animal-health/avian-influenza/avian-influenza-virus-type-h5n1-us-dairy-cattle#:~:text=Since%20April%202022%2C%20infection%20with,one%20person%2C%20cough%20without%20fever.">traced back to close contact</a> with infected farmed poultry or dairy herds. This case doesn’t appear to have that link.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>Spread through casual contact — for example, between people standing next to each other on a bus — hasn’t been reported with this virus, and would be much more worrisome</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Without a known exposure to an infected animal, there’s concern that H5N1 may be spreading in other ways — for example, through drinking raw milk or, even more consequentially, from person to person, which could lead to a much larger outbreak.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some spread between household contacts or from a sick patient to health care workers has happened with H5N1 in the past, but hasn’t been sustainable, says <a href="https://vivo.brown.edu/display/jnuzzo">Jennifer Nuzzo</a>, an epidemiologist who leads the Pandemic Center at Brown University’s School of Public Health. However, spread through casual contact — for example, between people standing next to each other on a bus — hasn’t been reported with this virus, and would be much more worrisome.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Spread through casual contact would represent a step toward overcoming Lakdawala’s second hurdle for a pandemic: sustained person-to-person transmission. “The last time a flu virus did that, which was 2009, it was around the globe in a matter of days,” says Nuzzo. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a promising sign that since the Missouri patient was hospitalized, there <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/flu/weekly/usmap.htm">has not been a big bloom</a> of flu-like illness in the state. “I don’t think there’s a whole iceberg out there that we don’t see,” says Nuzzo, but more details about the case would put her and other experts at ease.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Transmission through raw milk would also be bad news. Although most of the US milk supply is pasteurized — that is, heated to the point that bacteria and viruses are killed — about 1 in 100 Americans surveyed in the late 2010s said they <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9241341/#:~:text=Regardless%20of%20the%20risk%20of,per%20week%20or%20more%20often.">drank raw milk every week</a>. We don’t yet know whether the person who got infected in Missouri was a raw milk consumer, but that’s greatly preferable to the alternative of person-to-person spread, says Bhadelia. It’s more straightforward to control what you eat and drink than who you have contact with.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Two weeks elapsed between the patient’s hospitalization and <a href="https://health.mo.gov/news/newsitem/uuid/0ca9d648-cb9b-4eca-99a8-f9a1c96a01bd/human-h5-bird-flu-case-confirmed-in-missouri?utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email">public health</a> authorities’ <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2024/s0906-birdflu-case-missouri.html">announcements</a> about the case</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That long delay, says Nuzzo, suggests the US hasn’t switched on its sensitive flu surveillance system that would more rapidly identify bird flu infections in people with fever, cough, muscle aches, and other flu-like symptoms.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If there were a lot of person-to-person spread happening, having that system switched on would mean detecting that spread early — perhaps at a stage when it could still be contained. If the system isn’t on, however, transmission among humans could get out of hand before there’s a chance to stop it using the vaccines and medications that we know work to prevent severe flu symptoms and flu transmission.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">There’s very little transparency about how much infection is taking place on US dairy farms</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The more infection there is among dairy cows, the more infection there’s likely to be among the people who work with them, and the more opportunities that are created for H5N1 to mutate into a virus that spreads efficiently between people. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite this risk, most states rely on farmers to self-report infections among their herds. Widespread distrust of government and public health across the agriculture industry means <a href="https://www.notus.org/healthcare/farmer-bird-flu-cases-hide-cows-federal-government">self-reporting is rare</a>, and farms can’t be forced to test <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/17/health/bird-flu-tests.html">workers</a> or <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/05/06/bird-flu-dairy-farms-cdc-00156119">animals</a> unless their state agencies mandate it. “If these state public health agencies are not willing to do that, and the state governors are not willing to say, ‘Hey, there&#8217;s an ongoing outbreak that&#8217;s causing public health concern, we need to know what&#8217;s going on,’ we&#8217;re not going to have information,” says Lakdawala.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although bird flu has been reported in Missouri only in poultry farms and not on dairy farms, that doesn’t mean it isn’t there, said Nuzzo. It just means farmers may not be testing their workers or cows for the virus, or they aren’t reporting it.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">We’re not prepared for another pandemic</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many experts are concerned that Americans’ low trust in institutions would create enormous challenges in the event of another pandemic, especially one involving a virus transmitted through the air. That makes it particularly important to do what’s needed to get a handle on this outbreak, says Lakdawala. This would largely involve preventative measures instituted on dairy farms and having stockpiled vaccines available for those at highest risk of infection.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Seasonal flu is coming</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a few months, the seasonal flu virus is going to be spreading in the US. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When animals get co-infected with different flu viruses at the same time, they can serve as “<a href="https://journals.plos.org/plospathogens/article?id=10.1371/journal.ppat.1008330">mixing</a> <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33657971/">vessels</a>” for the viruses, allowing them to exchange segments of their genomes. That can lead to new viruses that are easier to transmit, better at causing disease, and above all, novel to the human immune system.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That could lead to getting H5N1 closer to jumping Lakdawala’s third hurdle. “We don’t want those two viruses to swap genes,” says Nuzzo.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What you can do</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are steps you can take to minimize your already low risk.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Get a seasonal flu shot</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Every episode of bird flu infection in a human makes a good case for a <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/370363/an-extremely-practical-guide-to-this-years-cold-flu-and-covid-season">seasonal flu shot</a>, says Nuzzo, especially in people who work on poultry or dairy farms. Every person who’s immunized against seasonal flu is less likely to be a mixing vessel for some new nightmare Frankenflu.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Avoid raw milk</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a ton of H5N1 virus <a href="https://www.vox.com/24158356/raw-milk-pasteurization-h5n1-bird-flu-sales-consumption-government-trust">in raw milk</a>: In April, 14 percent of American raw milk products <a href="https://www.unmc.edu/healthsecurity/transmission/2024/07/03/fda-finds-infectious-h5n1-bird-flu-virus-in-14-of-raw-milk-samples/">contained the live virus</a>, and the number may be higher now that more farms are affected. It’s never been safe to drink raw milk, but it’s particularly dangerous now; sticking with pasteurized dairy products is much safer, says Nuzzo.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Prevent risky contact with farm animals</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fall often brings farm festivals, and with them, opportunities for lots of contact with animals that might be asymptomatically infected with H5N1, says Lakdawala. “Don’t get close with animals,” Lakdawala says, and wash your hands often during and after a farm visit. If you work on a dairy farm or a veterinarian&#8217;s office, wear a face shield and other personal protective equipment (the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has some <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/bird-flu/prevention/farm-workers.html">helpful recommendations</a>) to protect yourself from splashes.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Protect yourself from high-risk infections</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People tend to have only two settings when thinking about their risk of catching an emerging infection, says Bhadelia: “low risk and ‘oh my god.’” It’s more helpful to think of risk as a spectrum, and on that spectrum, Covid-19 and mpox currently pose a bigger threat to the general public than H5N1. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So if you’re someone who wants to avoid getting sick, Nuzzo suggests getting your <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/370363/an-extremely-practical-guide-to-this-years-cold-flu-and-covid-season">Covid booster</a> sometime this fall, wearing a mask in busy spots, and gathering outdoors instead of crowding inside. If you’d benefit from an <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/mpox/vaccines/vaccine-recommendations.html">mpox vaccine</a>, get one.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For now, it’s mostly public officials’ and farm owners’ job to worry about bird flu. The best path forward for the general population is to control the variables you can, Nuzzo says. “Being worried is not a protective action.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Aja Romano</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How “Am I the Asshole?” ate the internet]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/370577/am-i-the-asshole-aita-verse-advice-ecosystem-tiktok" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=370577</id>
			<updated>2024-09-10T23:34:17Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-10T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s the stories that draw people in: A bride feeling upstaged on her wedding day; the woman whose husband insists on bringing his sister with them on their honeymoon; an airline passenger who wonders if she should have given up her first-class seat for a stranger’s child. These are all tales of questionable behavior from [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/AmITheAsshole.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s the stories that draw people in: A bride <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AmItheAsshole/comments/x8zm9t/aita_for_telling_my_sil_that_she_upstaged_me_at/">feeling upstaged</a> on her wedding day; the woman whose husband <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@history.aliens/video/7359759267735358753">insists on bringing his sister</a> with them on their honeymoon; an airline passenger who wonders if she should have <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AITAH/comments/1dx3zyu/aita_for_not_giving_up_my_first_class_ticket_for/">given up her first-class seat</a> for a stranger’s child.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are all tales of questionable behavior from <a href="https://reddit.com/r/amitheasshole">r/AmItheAsshole</a>. AITA, as it’s known for short, is hosted by Reddit, the one-stop clearinghouse for internet drama, comeuppances, and popcorn gallery judgments on the behavior of strangers. The mothership has been on a hot streak, tripling its traffic over the last year, when Google <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/business-news/reddit-traffic-triples-posts-prioritized-in-google-search/472869">tweaked its search algorithm</a> to prioritize content made by and for real people. Since then, Reddit has risen to over 340 million weekly unique users. Starting from around that same period, AITA has ascended rapidly from niche forum to mainstream forum to omnipresent cultural juggernaut.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The AmITheAsshole subreddit, as Reddit’s topic-based forums are known, boasts 20 million members ready to decide who’s right in a given situation and who’s wrong, if a hair more evocatively. It’s seen numerous spin-offs; not just advice subreddits and confessional subreddits that get at the same yen for revelation and judgment, but subreddits devoted to filtering and curating all those other advice and confessional subs, so that readers can find only the best (or worst) stories. But AmITheAsshole’s cultural dominance doesn’t end there.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This Reddit sprawl has spilled over outside of the platform itself, spawning a whole internet ecosystem dedicated to reading and sharing content from advice subreddits. TikTok is full of automated accounts that <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@reddit.day11/video/7275595186854513962">read stories from AITA</a> in monotone against weirdly hypnotic footage of games. Twitter and Instagram are replete with screenshots of Reddit stories, while <a href="https://player.fm/podcasts/AITA">dozens of audio podcasters</a> and YouTubers have sprung up to retell and comment on the latest scandalous post. The ecosystem has spawned merch of all types, from <a href="https://www.redbubble.com/shop?iaCode=u-mugs&amp;query=aita">coffee mugs</a> to <a href="https://www.etsy.com/listing/668352995/am-i-the-asshole-comedy-childrens-book?ga_order=most_relevant&amp;ga_search_type=all&amp;ga_view_type=gallery">children’s book parodies</a> to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1708354107/">self-help journals</a>. The memes practically <a href="https://x.com/skyler_higley/status/1828624225533653113?s=46&amp;t=FEmqCqEQaUqCryzD4XtZ4w">make themselves</a> at this point.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How did we get here? What is it about these endlessly tawdry tales that have us so addicted?&nbsp;</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">Advice subreddits are nothing new. AITA was first created in 2013, the same year as the site’s first breakout advice forum, r/Relationships. In the years that immediately followed, that sub and its various spin-offs dominated the site. Their purpose was simple enough: ask other Redditors for advice about your relationships and other conflicts, be they tiny or epic. And Redditors responded en masse: Since it was created r/Relationships grew to over 3.5 million subscribers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">AITA built on that promise, by streamlining the comment section debates from those other subs into a simple, clean voting system: YTA (you’re the asshole), NTA (not the asshole), and ESH (everyone sucks here). (There’s another designation, NAH for “no assholes here,” but that one gets less use. The internet demands villains!) This structure cut down on lots of needless debate and got to the point: Were you the asshole or not?</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>This is meta-gossip: gossip about the <em>idea</em> of a person and about ideas of human nature</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As a cultural phenomenon, AITA’s impact has been wide-ranging: It’s been the subject of <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24145761/reddit-am-i-the-asshole-moral-philosophy">philosophical</a> and <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/am-i-the-asshole-reddit/">demographic</a> study; it’s been credited with <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/reading-reddit-relationships-amitheasshole-aita-helps-some-leave-bad-relationships/">helping people leave</a> their own toxic and unhealthy relationships. The dynamics of the forum itself have spawned their own <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/reddit-aita-obsessions/">obsessive scrutiny</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To an extent, a lot of this is familiar. The recent <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2022/12/27/23520870/gossip-is-back-dont-worry-darling-drama-try-guys-normal-gossip-podcast">gossip trend</a> aligns perfectly with AITA’s rise in popularity. Yet much of those elements have been about the titillation of knowing the people behind those stories were real, be they petty celebrities engaged in in-fighting or your neighbor’s neighbor’s best friend. AITA, however, along with other recently ascendant phenomena like the hit podcast <em>Normal Gossip</em> and The Cut’s <a href="https://www.thecut.com/article/how-i-knew-marriage-over.html">anonymous confessionals</a>, expand that concept even further. This is meta-gossip: gossip that’s not about a person we know, not about a famous person, and quite frequently not even about a <em>real</em> person. It is gossip in the abstract — gossip about the <em>idea</em> of a person and about ideas of human nature.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hardly surprising, then, that this approach easily led to numerous spin-offs in theme and variation; every time you think you’ve reached the end of the offshoots of offshoots of advice subs and curation subs, another one pops up with the slightest variation. For instance, AITA is the central nervous system of the network, but it doesn’t allow users to post a range of content that falls outside of what it deems “interpersonal conflict”; enter <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AITAH/">AITAH</a> — short for “Am I The Asshole <em>Here</em>” — a crucial one-letter distinction, sure, but that sub <em>does</em> allow users to post a wide range of other drama. So, for instance, while AITA might not allow you to ask for advice after you’ve <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AITAH/comments/1f7466d/aita_for_breaking_a_mans_nose_because_he/">broken a man’s nose</a>, the moderators who approve and deny posts on AITAH will embrace you.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Alongside the advice subs themselves, curation subreddits for all the advice subs have <em>also</em> exploded. The biggest curation machine on-site is arguably <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BestofRedditorUpdates/">r/BestofRedditorUpdates</a> (BORU), which pulls stories from all around the site and even some advice columns off-site. Because BORU isn’t just limited to AITA, it gets a broader range of wild and unbelievable stories, from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BestofRedditorUpdates/comments/x5opa1/tifu_my_20f_girlfriend_of_two_years_told_me_the/">inappropriate music</a> during sex to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BestofRedditorUpdates/comments/wcstm8/company_throws_a_corporate_retreat_at_a/">making your employees do period cosplay at a plantation</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These curation subs, too, have been divided into their own areas of focus. If you want your curation to deliver a little more schadenfreude, there’s <a href="https://reddit.com/r/ohnoconsequences">r/OhNoConsequences</a>. Want content that’s not just written by an asshole but by a proper spawn of Satan? Try <a href="https://reddit.com/r/amithedevil">r/AmITheDevil</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not all of this rapid growth is attributable to the Google bump. A BORU moderator who goes by boringhistoryfan speculated to Vox that the success of these stories is less about search engine magic and more about people seeking engaging material from an easily accessible platform, “wanting content they can relate to and respond to.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Redditor amireallyreal, another BORU mod, was more direct, explaining that people embrace these twisty tales “for the same reason they like reality TV.” They explained, “They like drama, emotion, and laughs. They get all the excitement without any of the stress of actually being involved in these scenarios. This is just reality TV but in written form.” This hunger for more is an extra boost for the meta-subs, because “having an entire saga compiled in one place makes for easy access to the whole story.” Often those sagas take up multiple posts, spawning entire mini-arcs across the website as updates to what began as a single story become an ongoing narrative. Such updates can be piecemeal, incomplete, and scattered in different places throughout either the forum, a user’s profile, or in comments. It can take work to even find them, much less curate them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s no wonder, then, that increasingly, audiences of this type of melodramatic content are turning toward sources outside of Reddit itself to get it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Dustin Storm, a.k.a. YouTuber and podcaster <a href="https://www.dusty-thunder.com/">Dusty Thunder</a>, says he was “never a Reddit head.” It was his wife and daughter who loved the site’s stories. “So when they pulled me into this, I essentially became a mouthpiece or a bridge to the other non-Reddit heads because I’m not one.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Storm’s family members had been seeing more and more creators on Instagram and TikTok turn to narrating the Reddit stories they so enjoyed. They encouraged him to start the podcast; now Storm reads posts on his show, curated by his wife and daughter. In order to react authentically to the stories as he reads them on air, Storm actively avoids the Reddit advice subs so he won’t get spoiled. The formula has paid off; since he started his show in 2022, his audience has topped 30,000 subscribers on YouTube and nearly a million TikTok followers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It&#8217;s a different kind of entertainment,” he said. “Instead of tuning into <em>Grey’s Anatomy</em>, now they’re jumping on and listening to some of the crazy stories that have been going on Reddit, and it’s just a completely different form of content that people have latched onto. As long as there’s no shortage of drama in the world right now, at least it flows through Reddit.”  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Storm’s podcast, YouTube, and TikTok are among many dedicated to surfacing this content for broader audiences, including hits like the <em>Two Hot Takes</em> podcast and its various platforms. TikTok has also given rise to an endless array of strange faceless accounts devoted to narrating Reddit stories while playing uncanny footage of, for example, <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@reddit.day11/video/7275595186854513962">racing games</a> or Minecraft <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@scalingstories/video/7410642856676887854">parkour videos</a>. Want your subreddit drama with a side of food videos? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hIyJKhauiQ0">You can have that, too</a>.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“To me, it’s fake no matter what”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many of the off-platform content creators trawl the meta forums because they have serialized stories and a sense (sometimes) of resolution. Their appeal makes sense; not only are Redditors churning out a bottomless well of free content for podcasters and other creators to curate, but the stories themselves reside in that irresistible space between the real and the fictional: just believable enough to seem plausible, but escalated enough to feel like pure escapism.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Their popularity has expanded beyond the content creator milieu; media outlets like People and The New York Post have generated <a href="https://people.com/real-people-family-dynamics">reams of articles</a> just built on repurposed advice subreddit posts, now repackaged into generalized human interest stories of nameless, faceless gossip. Of course, there’s no way to fact-check the veracity of these Reddit stories. You might think that the growing influx of stories that seem to be total fakes — garish fantasies of revenge or validation — would make them less appealing to readers, but the opposite effect seems to have taken hold. “We aren’t too concerned with whether posts are fake or real and it can become very difficult to tell whether a post is fake or real based on anecdotal evidence,” BORU moderator amireallyreal said. Fans seem to feel the same way.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“To me, it’s fake no matter what,” Storm said. “It doesn&#8217;t touch me. It doesn’t affect me. It doesn’t change things. So for us, it’s entertainment, number one. And number two, it’s an exercise in being able to make better decisions and relationships. And if it serves that purpose, I give zero shits if it’s real or fake.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Storm acknowledged the difficulty of knowing the veracity of the stories but joked that the wildest ones were probably true. Indeed, my anecdotal experience of reading AITA or BORU usually involves being convinced a post is fake only to encounter multiple people in the comments relating similar experiences; the implausibility of a post often seems to stretch no further than one person’s lived experience.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ironically, Storm told me that the Dusty Thunder <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dustythunder/">subreddit</a>, which they began as an easy way of allowing his audience to submit their own stories to the podcast, had now become an example of the very subreddits the podcast was narrating.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We originally started it as kind of a submission portal, but for our community to engage with as well,” he said. “It’s grown well beyond that. I’m sure there are a lot of people on there who have no idea who I am, but it’s taken on a life of its own now.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a strange mini-version of the asshole ecosystem itself: An endless ouroboros of content, both feeding and digesting more and more content.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“So some people are using the Dusty Thunder subreddit like AITA,” Storm said, laughing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“And they’re like, yeah, it’s a really weird name. I don’t get it. But I like the stories.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
