<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-08-06T21:26:45Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/05/vox-favicon.jpeg?w=32</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[A historic ruling against Google could change the internet as we know it]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/big-tech/365575/google-monopoly-search-case-biden-big-tech" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365575</id>
			<updated>2024-08-06T21:26:45Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-06T21:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Antitrust" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Big Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Google" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Tech policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="US Federal Courts" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A federal judge found Monday that Google’s search business constitutes an illegal monopoly, a landmark ruling and major victory for the Biden administration as it seeks to clamp down on Big Tech. The decision has the potential to bring major changes to the internet — and sends a signal that no company is too big [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="An attendee walks past a Google logo during the Viva Technology conference at Parc des Expositions Porte de Versailles on June 14, 2023 in Paris, France. | Chesnot/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Chesnot/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1498442986.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>An attendee walks past a Google logo during the Viva Technology conference at Parc des Expositions Porte de Versailles on June 14, 2023 in Paris, France. | Chesnot/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">A federal judge found Monday that Google’s search business constitutes an illegal monopoly, a landmark ruling and major victory for the Biden administration as it seeks to clamp down on Big Tech. The decision has the potential to bring major changes to the internet — and sends a signal that no company is too big to regulate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">US District Judge Amit Mehta found that “Google is a monopolist, and it has acted as one to maintain its monopoly.” That involved protecting its dominance in the search engine market; Mehta focused particularly on the fact that Google signed contracts with companies, including Apple, to become the default search engine on their devices. Google currently enjoys a nearly 90 percent share overall and an almost 95 percent share on mobile devices.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Google has vowed to appeal the ruling, which it has framed as an attempt to make it harder for consumers to access a search engine they prefer. The appeals process could take years to play out, and Judge Mehta has yet to levy specific penalties against Google, which will be decided following a hearing in September. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While it may be true that many consumers prefer Google over any currently available alternative, should the ruling stand, it may allow a competitor to devise a better product, and one that actually has a real chance to penetrate the market. And that could mean more search options for consumers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If the door is locked, you can’t get consumers,” said <a href="https://som.yale.edu/faculty-research/faculty-directory/fiona-m-scott-morton">Fiona Scott Morton</a>, a professor at Yale School of Management and former chief economist at the Justice Department’s antitrust division. “The door isn’t locked anymore. The door is open [to] a whole industry of innovators who have good ideas, and then we would see a change in competition going forward.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What the Google antitrust ruling means for the company, the internet, and consumers</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The implications of the case, which was initially brought under the Trump administration, aren’t yet entirely clear. Much of it may depend on exactly how Mehta decides to penalize Google, and how difficult that penalty makes doing business. In weighing punishment, Mehta will need to meaningfully penalize Google while minimizing any negative impacts on consumers — and that is a “real quandary,” said <a href="https://www.law.upenn.edu/faculty/hhovenka">Herbert Hovenkamp</a>, an antitrust scholar at the University of Pennsylvania Carey Law School.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps the most likely remedy would be to force Google to exit any contracts it signed allowing device makers to offer Google as a default search engine for a certain sum of money. But that might have minimal immediate impact on Google: those makers may still decide to make Google their default search engine, but without having to pay Google for the privilege.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Apple will just end up doing what it&#8217;s already doing,” Hovenkamp said. “And that may be true for a lot of device makers.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But if a better search engine eventually comes along — say, one powered by AI, with better safety and privacy standards, or even a different way of displaying ads — then device makers don’t have to stick with Google. Fundamentally, that kind of competition should spur innovation, which is good for consumers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Scott Morton said that Google is currently the best search engine in part because almost everyone uses it and it has exclusive positions on various device operating systems, which creates a “self-perpetuating circle.” Its user base gives it a large volume of data and reliable revenue opportunities that it can then use to cover the development, marketing, and acquisition costs that help it keep its edge.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Once you break that, we don&#8217;t know what might happen,” she said. “It could be very exciting.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What the ruling means for other Big Tech companies</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition to its implications for the future of the internet, the ruling could affect the way other Big Tech companies do business.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“What it signals is that if you’ve got a dominant product, you’ve got to be very careful to make sure that your licensing and contract agreements are open, because making them exclusive can be dangerous,” Hovenkamp said. That could mean greater caution around partnerships between companies. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Google ruling could also serve as a template for future antitrust cases, Hovenkamp said. But it’s not clear how predictive this case will be of the other pending antitrust lawsuits that the Biden administration has filed against Big Tech companies. It has several in process:</p>

<ul>
<li>It has accused Apple of <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/2024/3/21/24108155/apple-new-antitrust-lawsuit-iphone-monopoly">maintaining a monopoly</a> on the US market for smartphones, of which the iPhone makes up <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/media/1344546/dl?inline">65 percent</a>. The complaint alleges that Apple has deliberately thwarted apps, products, and services that would make it easier for users to switch from the iPhone to other smartphones and lower costs for consumers and developers.</li>



<li>It sued Google a second time over the company’s ads business, which it claims has achieved dominance through anti-competitive mergers and by strong-arming publishers and advertisers.</li>



<li>It has <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/19/technology/ftc-facebook-antitrust.html?action=click&amp;pgtype=Article&amp;state=default&amp;module=styln-big-tech&amp;variant=show&amp;region=MAIN_CONTENT_1&amp;block=storyline_levelup_swipe_recirc">accused Meta</a> of acquiring Instagram and WhatsApp to stymie competition and prevent consumers from having access to other social media platforms. A federal judge initially dismissed the lawsuit, ruling that the government had failed to define the market in which Meta has held a monopoly, before allowing the administration to refile.</li>



<li>It has <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/03/technology/google-apple-amazon-meta-antitrust.html">accused Amazon</a> of preventing its sellers from offering lower prices on other online platforms and prioritizing its products over third-party products, artificially keeping prices high and quality down.</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Scott Morton said that each of those cases is different in terms of their content and precedent from the Google case, which relied on a ruling against Microsoft in the late ’90s over its anticompetitive practices to maintain its monopoly in the PC market.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The behavior of Google was very similar to the behavior of Microsoft, and so that similarity allowed the Justice Department to show the judge that this conduct really fit into that same pattern and therefore should be treated the same way, namely made illegal,” she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Google case might not therefore serve as a precedent in the existing cases against other Big Tech companies. But it has contributed to a significant vibe shift in terms of how tech companies can expect to be regulated.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“What is different is a change in the temperature,” Scott Morton said of the effect of the ruling in Silicon Valley. “These firms are not too big. We have applied the law to them, and we have found that — even though they’re American, even though they’re innovative and spend money on R&amp;D, even though they have executives who look good in the suit — they can still be found liable.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The left loves Tim Walz. Can he unite the Democrats?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365416/tim-walz-kamala-harris-vp-vice-president-democrats-left" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365416</id>
			<updated>2024-08-06T17:40:17Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-06T17:40:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minnesota Governor Tim Walz has been picked as Kamala Harris’s running mate — and the American left couldn’t be happier. This is not because Walz himself is an ideological leftist. While he certainly has progressive credibility — in 2023, he passed a series of left-liberal reforms dubbed the “Minnesota Miracle” — he’s also taken more centrist positions on a [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Minnesota Governor Tim Walz arrives to speak at a press conference regarding new gun legislation at City Hall on August 1, 2024 in Bloomington, Minnesota. | Stephen Maturen/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Maturen/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2164176277.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Minnesota Governor Tim Walz arrives to speak at a press conference regarding new gun legislation at City Hall on August 1, 2024 in Bloomington, Minnesota. | Stephen Maturen/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Minnesota Governor Tim Walz has been picked as Kamala Harris’s running mate — and the American left couldn’t be happier.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is not because Walz himself is an ideological leftist. While he certainly has progressive credibility — in 2023, he passed a series of left-liberal reforms dubbed the “<a href="https://peoplesworld.org/article/minnesota-miracle-state-legislature-passes-avalanche-of-progressive-and-pro-labor-laws/">Minnesota Miracle</a>” — he’s also taken more centrist positions on a whole slate of issues, including hot-button ones like crime. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The left’s romance with Walz is deeply entwined with hostility to his chief rival for a spot on the ticket: Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro. Harris’s decision on Shapiro, who has <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/184151/one-vice-president-ruin-democratic-unity-josh-shapiro">a history of hostility</a> with the party’s pro-Palestinian faction, had become seen as a bellwether for whether she’d be meaningfully different from Biden on Gaza. Walz looked like the most progressive available anti-Shapiro, and so emerged as the left’s preferred alternative.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Walz’s elevation earns the left a big victory. Yet because Walz himself isn’t <em>of</em> the left, the pick seems intended to serve a unifying purpose: a candidate who appeals to all different stripes of Democrats for different reasons. The fact that <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/08/06/2024/pragmatic-midwestern-governor-or-cornucopia-of-liberal-psychosis-the-race-to-define-tim-walz-begins">Democrats across the political spectrum</a> seem thrilled by the pick — with effusive support coming from people ranging from <a href="https://www.manchin.senate.gov/newsroom/press-releases/manchin-statement-on-governor-walz-as-pick-for-vice-president">Sen. Joe Manchin</a> (WV) to<a href="https://x.com/AOC/status/1820819039955947605"> Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez</a> (NY) — seems to validate the theory. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s important to be clear: The VP selection matters <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/363899/kamala-harris-vp-pick-josh-shapiro-walz-kelly">way less for elections than people think</a>. It’s much more important to select a potential president than an optimal running mate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But you can see why Harris sees picking Walz as smart politics. It allows her to simultaneously hand the left a win without necessarily tacking left —&nbsp;potentially keeping her coalition united even as she works to win over the general election’s decisive centrists.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Tim Walz a progressive or moderate? Yes.</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Record-wise, it might seem like there are two Tim Walzes: the <a href="https://x.com/jeremyslevin/status/1820808981285065116">progressive governor</a> beloved by the American left, and the <a href="https://x.com/MattGrossmann/status/1820813473963561472">centrist member of Congress</a> who predated him. Yet in actuality, the two men are easier to reconcile than you might think.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Minnesota Miracle reforms, enacted in a single legislative session, read like a progressive wishlist. They include paid family leave, free school meals, marijuana legalization, a 100 percent clean energy mandate by 2040, and a slew of protections for organized labor.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I use the word “progressive” and not its cousin “leftist” deliberately. The Minnesota Miracle policies are all squarely within the Democratic mainstream: none betray an ideological commitment to the party’s socialist or otherwise radical wings. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In fact, Walz has <a href="https://takeactionminnesota.org/statement-takeaction-minnesota-statement-on-gov-walz-opposition-to-yes-4-minneapolis-charter-amendment/">clashed with the left</a> in the past.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor of the state where George Floyd was murdered, he faced significant pressure to sign on to defunding police. Yet he rejected the idea, instead <a href="https://www.kare11.com/article/news/politics/republican-ad-makes-false-claim-gov-tim-walz-record-minnesota-politics/89-1dcdfca8-d789-48bc-a4fb-c10cc6cbed01">signing a slate of police reforms</a> that kept police funding static in 2020 and sending <a href="https://mn.gov/governor/newsroom/press-releases/?id=1055-604780#:~:text=View%20entire%20list-,Governor%20Walz%20Announces%20%24300%20Million%20in%20Public%20Safety,to%20Local%20Governments%20Next%20Week&amp;text=%5BST.,to%20local%20governments%20next%20week.">$300 million to local public safety offices</a> in 2023.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Walz has become the left’s factional choice not because he’s one of them, but because he was the best they could plausibly hope for. The left-wing case for Walz can be hard to disentangle from the left-wing case against Shapiro —&nbsp;someone <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/184151/one-vice-president-ruin-democratic-unity-josh-shapiro">the left detested</a> for <a href="https://www.jpost.com/american-politics/article-813157">offensive comments</a> about Palestinians he made in college and hardline hostility to campus pro-Palestinian protestors.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Walz’s position on Israel-Palestine is hardly left-wing. The Atlantic’s Yair Rosenberg has put together a <a href="https://x.com/Yair_Rosenberg/status/1820473963958383077">list</a> of <a href="https://x.com/Yair_Rosenberg/status/1820474774218572276">Walz’s positions and actions</a> that basically reflect the traditional pro-Israel consensus. Walz’s position on how to end the current Gaza war is <a href="https://x.com/Yair_Rosenberg/status/1820547704293937629">virtually identical to Shapiro’s</a>. The most important difference is less Middle East policy than domestic: Shapiro has been far harsher on pro-Palestine campus protests than Walz has.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So while Walz is the left’s chosen candidate, he is not a candidate <em>of</em> the left. He’s a mainstream Democrat with a record containing elements that both progressives and moderates can like.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">When appeasing the left is good politics</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The best political case against Walz is that Minnesota is not really a battleground. If Harris had chosen Pennsylvania’s Shapiro instead, she would have been maximizing her odds of winning the most important state in the Electoral College.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the idea that vice presidents deliver their swing states is at best overstated —&nbsp;and most likely probably wrong. My colleague Eric Levitz recently did <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/363899/kamala-harris-vp-pick-josh-shapiro-walz-kelly">a deep dive</a> into the political science research on the subject, and the weight of the evidence strongly suggests that vice presidents don’t really have much of an effect on the ultimate presidential outcome.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By contrast, there’s at least some reason to believe that Walz’s unique ability to appeal to all factions of the Democratic Party might help Harris down the stretch.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The strongest Trump attack on Harris, at least to date, is that she’s too far to the left. Scored by one (<a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/08/17/politics/kamala-harris-most-liberal-senator-fact-check/index.html">dubious</a>) metric as the most liberal member of the Senate in 2019, she has drawn Republican flak for previous positions ranging from Medicare-for-all to banning fracking to decriminalizing border crossing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In response, Harris has tacked to the center: repudiating many of her past unpopular positions in favor of more moderate stances that align better with mainstream public opinion. The message that Republicans are “weird” &nbsp;is designed to play up the notion that she represents the vast American middle while Trump is the true extremist.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Walz helps make this message more credible.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A very ordinary-seeming Midwestern white guy, he <a href="https://www.fox9.com/news/gov-walz-kicked-off-harris-campaigns-weird-attack-line">literally invented the “weird” attack</a> on Trump and J.D. Vance. While he’s recently played up his progressive accomplishments, he’s also demonstrated the ability to take centrist positions when it’s politically convenient. He has a talent for winning over people with displays of empathy, including speaking about Trump supporters as <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/02/opinion/ezra-klein-podcast-tim-walz.html">relatives and neighbors</a>. In his Walz endorsement, Sen. Manchin says, “I can think of no one better than Governor Walz to help bring our country closer together and bring balance back to the Democratic Party.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Moreover, his celebrity status on the left gives Harris crucial running room to keep up the strategic centrism. By handing her left flank a victory, she’s theoretically built major credibility that she can spend to defray a left-wing revolt over some of her more centrist stances.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From Harris’s perspective, the Walz pick is an exercise in coalition management. It helps her keep the Democratic base united and energized while continuing her new moderate outreach to general election swing voters. If she’s right, the choice might end up mattering more in Pennsylvania — and elsewhere — than attaching herself to Shapiro’s brand.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Vox Staff</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris picks Tim Walz as running mate]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365437/tim-walz-kamala-harris-vice-president-live-news-updates" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?post_type=vm_stream&#038;p=365437</id>
			<updated>2024-08-06T19:48:36Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-06T17:03:45Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris selected Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz as her running mate in the 2024 election.&#160; A former high school teacher and military veteran, Walz has been in politics for almost two decades, having started as a member of Congress in 2007. He has a record of winning over rural conservative voters and of [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Tim Walz, a middle-aged man with white hair and glasses, has a serious expression on his face, seen from a low angle." data-caption="Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz speaks to reporters after a meeting with President Joe Biden at the White House on July 3, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2160509325.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz speaks to reporters after a meeting with President Joe Biden at the White House on July 3, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris selected Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz as her running mate in the 2024 election.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A former high school teacher and military veteran, Walz has been in politics for almost two decades, having started as a member of Congress in 2007. He has a record of winning over rural conservative voters and of advancing bills on police reform, abortion protections, and education funding. A Midwesterner, Walz could prove to be a useful surrogate for shoring up support in his own, usually blue state, as well as crucial battlegrounds in Michigan and Wisconsin.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris and Walz are set to make their first joint appearance at a campaign rally in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. They will face off against former President Donald Trump and Ohio Sen. J.D. Vance in the 2024 election.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Follow here for the latest news, analysis, and explainers.</p>
<ul>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/365535/tim-walz-minneapolis-burning-riot-george-floyd-minnesota-2020-protest">How Tim Walz actually handled the George Floyd protests in Minnesota</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365416/tim-walz-kamala-harris-vp-vice-president-democrats-left">The left loves Tim Walz. Can he unite the Democrats?</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/364677/tim-walz-harris-vp-josh-shapiro">Will Kamala Harris regret picking Tim Walz over Josh Shapiro?</a>
		</li>
	</ul>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Eric Levitz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Will Kamala Harris regret picking Tim Walz over Josh Shapiro?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/364677/tim-walz-harris-vp-josh-shapiro" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=364677</id>
			<updated>2024-08-06T17:12:49Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-06T17:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris chose Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz as her running mate Tuesday. Walz’s selection came as something of a surprise. For much of last week, betting markets had given Pennsylvania Gov. Josh Shapiro a more than 60 percent chance of joining the Democratic ticket. In opting for Walz instead, Harris defied the conventional [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris in Washington, DC, on July 22, 2024, and Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz in Washington, DC, on July 3, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2165044765.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris in Washington, DC, on July 22, 2024, and Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz in Washington, DC, on July 3, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/08/06/tim-walz-kamala-harris-vice-president-running-mate/74512447007/">chose</a> Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz as her running mate Tuesday.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Walz’s selection came as something of a surprise. For much of last week, <a href="https://www.predictit.org/markets/detail/8089/Who-will-win-the-2024-Democratic-vice-presidential-nomination">betting markets</a> had given Pennsylvania Gov. Josh Shapiro a more than 60 percent chance of joining the Democratic ticket. In opting for Walz instead, Harris defied the conventional wisdom among <a href="https://x.com/jmart/status/1820810623103488400">Democratic consultants</a>, who had broadly favored Shapiro. And on Tuesday morning, some close to the Trump campaign <a href="https://www.cnn.com/politics/live-news/kamala-harris-trump-election-08-06-24/index.html">told CNN</a> that they were “breathing a sigh of relief” that the Democratic nominee had not tapped the popular Pennsylvania governor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The wisdom of choosing Walz over Shapiro is therefore bound to be widely debated. And each side in that argument has reasonable points. Here is a rundown of the case for, and against, believing that Harris’s first major decision as leader of her party was a mistake.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why picking Shapiro might have increased Harris’s odds of victory</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The case for picking Shapiro over Walz is twofold:</p>

<ul>
<li>Pennsylvania is this election’s most important swing state, and Shapiro is popular there. Unless Harris loses in a national landslide, meanwhile, Minnesota will be a safe blue state. </li>



<li>Harris’s greatest liability with swing voters may be her reputation as a left-wing San Franciscan. Shapiro arguably could have done more than Walz to mitigate that liability. </li>
</ul>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">1. <strong>The road to the White House runs through Pennsylvania&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Right now, Harris is polling a <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-harris">bit worse</a> in Pennsylvania than in the other key Rust Belt battlegrounds. The likely Democratic nominee trails former President Donald Trump by 1.2 points there, while tying Trump in <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/wisconsin/trump-vs-harris">Wisconsin</a>, and leading him by 2 points in <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/michigan/trump-vs-harris">Michigan</a>, according to RealClearPolitics’s polling averages. Close the gap in Pennsylvania, and Harris will be in striking distance of sweeping the three Midwestern swing states, which could be sufficient to win her the White House.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Further, Pennsylvania holds four more Electoral College votes than Michigan and nine more than Wisconsin. As long as Democrats win Pennsylvania, they can lose both of those states and still retain some other plausible routes to victory. With Pennsylvania in her corner, Harris could lose Nevada, Michigan, and Wisconsin — and still get just over 270 Electoral College votes by taking Georgia and Arizona.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Shapiro could plausibly have helped Harris pull past Trump in Pennsylvania. In some recent polls, the governor’s approval in the state sits <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/pittsburgh/news/josh-shapiro-kamala-harris-running-mate-questions/">at 60 percent</a>. Last month, <a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/west-wing-playbook/2024/07/18/so-you-wanted-some-harris-polling-00169524">a Public Policy Polling</a> survey found Trump leading Harris in Pennsylvania by 2 points — but when the same respondents were presented with a choice between a Harris-Shapiro ticket and one featuring Trump and Ohio Sen. J.D. Vance, the former led by 1 point.</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">2. <strong>Shapiro could have countered the perception that Harris is “dangerously liberal”</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although winning Pennsylvania is important, it is obviously not sufficient. But there is some reason to think that Shapiro could have helped Harris in other pivotal states. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s greatest political liability may be the widespread perception that <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/07/23/2024/the-upside-for-harris-is-huge-democratic-poll-finds-kamala-needs-to-define-her-brand-quickly">she is very left-wing</a>. The Democratic nominee hails from one of the most liberal parts of one of America’s most liberal states. During her time in the Senate, she racked up one of Congress’s <a href="https://voteview.com/person/41701/kamala-devi-harris">most progressive voting records</a>. And in her ill-fated primary campaign in 2020, Harris embraced several very left-wing policies, such as the <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/decriminalizing-border-crossing-democrats-2020_n_5d15884ee4b03d6116392906">decriminalization of border crossing</a>, <a href="https://www.inquirer.com/politics/election/kamala-harris-josh-shapiro-fracking-pennsylvania-20240801.html#:~:text=Harris'%20original%20call%20for%20a,takes%20place%20on%20private%20properties.">a fracking ban</a>, and <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2019/07/kamala-harriss-medicare-for-all-plan-makes-no-sense.html">Medicare-for-all</a>. Republicans are already trying to use these positions against her in <a href="https://delawarevalleyjournal.com/new-mccormick-ad-ties-casey-and-harris-agendas-together/">attack ads</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris has tried to neutralize this vulnerability by disavowing her past positions, championing <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/4801766-kamala-harris-donald-trump-border/">bipartisan border security legislation</a>, and spotlighting her career as a <a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter/363859/kamala-harris-prosecutor-record-tough-crime">moderate, “smart on crime” prosecutor</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Shapiro’s selection could have aided this rebranding effort. The Pennsylvania governor has a well-earned reputation for moderation. Since Republicans control Pennsylvania’s Senate, Shapiro has only ever enacted bipartisan legislation. He is therefore associated with various anodyne, broadly appealing initiatives, such as <a href="https://www.pa.gov/en/governor/newsroom/press-releases/governor-shapiro-highlights-universal-free-breakfast-proposal-fo.html">establishing universal, free public school breakfasts,</a> removing <a href="https://www.pa.gov/en/governor/newsroom/press-releases/governor-shapiro-leads-the-nation-on-eliminating-college-degree-.html'">college degree requirements</a> for many public sector jobs, and spearheading the rapid reconstruction of a <a href="https://www.cityandstatepa.com/politics/2023/06/i-95-bridge-success-shapiro-has-passed-his-first-big-test/387962/">collapsed stretch of I-95 in Philadelphia</a>. As New York magazine’s Jonathan Chait <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/josh-shapiro-vice-president-moderate-popular-governor-pennsylvania-palestine-kamala-harris.html">notes</a>, Shapiro has also proven himself a deft communicator to those on the right side of the aisle. After a would-be assassin wounded Trump and killed one of his most prominent local supporters at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, Shapiro delivered a stirring eulogy for the deceased, a firefighter named Corey Comperatore. His tribute to the civic pride and familial devotion of a political adversary had wide resonance, and may be partly responsible for his strong approval in recent polls.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="Pennsylvania Gov. Josh Shapiro says victim killed at Trump rally was former fire chief" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vwxNmywVBFQ?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Shapiro’s credibility with voters who dislike Trump — but distrust progressives — is arguably enhanced by his <a href="https://www.thedp.com/article/2024/04/penn-palestinian-encampment-pennsylvania-shapiro-safety-antisemitism">high-profile criticism of pro-Palestinian campus occupations</a>, and the Democratic left’s consequent opposition to his candidacy for vice president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be sure, Walz is scarcely an inveterate progressive. For more than a decade, he represented a Republican-leaning, rural House district and assembled the voting record to prove it. During his last session in Congress, Walz <a href="https://heritageaction.com/scorecard/members/W000799/115">voted in line</a> with the preferences of the conservative group Heritage Action 15 percent of the time, which was more than twice as often as the average House Democrat.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, as governor of Minnesota in 2023, Walz <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2023/06/why-are-minnesota-democrats-so-progressive.html">assembled</a> an impressively vast and progressive governing agenda. Despite the fact that his party held the state senate by a single seat — which it had won by just 321 votes — they nevertheless managed to enshrine <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/state-government/2023/05/minnesota-lawmakers-plan-to-solidify-courts-rejection-of-abortion-restrictions-limit-state-data-reporting/">abortion rights</a>, establish paid <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/politics-policy/2023/04/legislators-work-out-details-of-bill-that-would-create-a-paid-family-and-medical-leave-program-in-minnesota/">family and medical leave</a>, restore the <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/state-government/2023/02/minnesota-supreme-court-state-can-bar-felons-from-voting-until-probation-ends/">voting rights</a> of ex-felons, invest $1 billion into <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/state-government/2023/05/minnesota-legislative-big-big-deal-spends-1b-on-affordable-housing-adds-metro-sales-tax/">affordable housing</a>, impose background checks on private gun transfers, <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/state-government/2023/05/minnesotas-soon-to-be-law-allowing-recreational-marijuana-explained/">legalize recreational marijuana</a>, create a <a href="https://www.mprnews.org/story/2023/03/24/you-belong-here-minnesota-house-passes-trans-health-refuge-bill?gclid=CjwKCAjwm4ukBhAuEiwA0zQxk5RdtxtcOM0fkfu6rK75hb7lRLLdAum34DpJQvpg5GJQ4ZL6OiHtzRoC5lcQAvD_BwE">refuge program for trans people</a> denied gender-affirming care in other states, mandate that utilities go <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/environment/2023/02/how-small-city-utilities-are-grappling-with-minnesotas-new-100-carbon-free-standard/">carbon-free</a> by 2040, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/jun/07/minnesota-pro-worker-paid-leave-union">prohibit</a> non-compete clauses in labor contracts, empanel a statewide board to set minimum labor standards for nursing-home workers, direct <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/greater-minnesota/2023/05/why-lawmakers-finally-reached-a-deal-on-bonding-and-what-it-means-for-infrastructure-in-greater-minnesota/">$2.58 billion</a> into improved infrastructure, and increase taxes on corporations and high earners, among myriad other reforms.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Minnesota’s frenzy of progressive legislating caught the attention of <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/06/04/democratic-party-minnesota-legislature-progressives/">progressives nationally</a>. And when Harris named both Walz and Shapiro to her shortlist, <a href="https://www.commondreams.org/news/tim-walz-vice-president">left-wing</a> groups and commentators began agitating for the former’s selection and against the latter’s.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For these reasons, Walz’s selection may abet a Republican narrative that Harris is a “dangerously liberal” figure in respect to the left, while Shapiro might have theoretically undercut that impression.<strong> </strong></p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Why Walz might have been the right choice</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But none of that necessarily means that choosing Walz was a mistake. There are at least five arguments for favoring him over Shapiro:</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">• Walz balances the Democratic ticket in some ways that Shapiro wouldn’t have. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">•The Minnesota governor has excelled in recent television appearances, coining a line of attack against the Republican ticket that subsequently went viral.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">• In recent days, news reports surfaced a couple potentially damaging stories about Shapiro.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">• Shapiro’s capacity to help Harris in Pennsylvania might be overstated.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">• Shapiro’s selection would have been more divisive within the Democratic coalition and could have jeopardized the spirit of enthusiasm and unity that has prevailed within the party since Biden stepped aside.</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">1. <strong>Walz balances the ticket demographically</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For reasons noted above, Walz does not balance the ticket ideologically as much as Shapiro might have. But he arguably balances it more than the Pennsylvania governor demographically. Unlike Harris and Shapiro (and Joe Biden, Barack Obama, Hillary Clinton, and Bill Clinton), Walz did not go to law school and <em>did</em> serve in the military. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He hails from a tiny town in rural Nebraska, and is an avid hunter and onetime high-school football coach. He therefore has deep roots in the small-town Midwest, an area of deepening weakness for the Democratic Party. In theory, this could render Walz a more effective messenger to swing voters in Wisconsin and Michigan than Shapiro, who was raised in eastern Pennsylvania and spent most of his life on the East Coast.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Granted, Walz <a href="https://x.com/SteveKornacki/status/1820810857716109350">did not perform especially well </a>in rural Minnesota during his 2022 governor run. But during his long tenure in the House, he did unusually well in non-urban areas for a Democrat. Walz knows how to appeal to such voters. To the extent that the Harris campaign believes it needs to reassure voters who are moderate to conservative on some issues, Walz will surely be game to triangulate. Given progressives’ personal affection for and trust in Walz, it is possible that they may give a Harris-Walz ticket greater leeway for pragmatic repositioning than a Harris-Shapiro ticket would have enjoyed.</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">2. <strong>Walz has excelled on television</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A presidential nominee’s running mate is her primary surrogate. And Walz proved himself an able attack dog in recent weeks. During a July 23 appearance by Walz on <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/morning-joe/watch/gov-watz-people-like-jd-vance-know-nothing-about-small-town-america-215470661588">MSNBC’s “Morning Joe,”</a> the governor lamented, “We do not like what has happened, when you can’t even go to Thanksgiving dinner with your uncle because you end up in some weird fight that is unnecessary … Well, it’s true. These guys are just weird.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats both online and off <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/internet/weird-jd-vance-trump-walz-history-kamala-harris-rcna164575">latched onto</a> Walz’s message — that Trump’s GOP had developed a “weird” and off-putting political culture. One <a href="https://www.dataforprogress.org/blog/2024/8/5/voters-think-recent-gop-actions-and-quotes-are-very-weird#:~:text=Democrats%20are%20seen%20as%20more,a%20%2B38%2Dpoint%20margin.">recent poll</a> from a Democratic outfit suggests that this message broke through, with voters saying that the word “weird” better describes Republicans than Democrats by a 47 to 37 percent margin. </p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">3. <strong>Walz is implicated in fewer potential scandals</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Separately, as reporters dug into Harris’s list of VP contenders in recent weeks, they surfaced more potentially damaging stories about Shapiro than about Walz. One of those stories was already well-known, but attained newfound prominence: A top Shapiro aide allegedly subjected one of his office’s employees to persistent sexual harassment last year. The governor’s office reached <a href="https://www.spotlightpa.org/news/2023/10/pennsylvania-josh-shapiro-mike-vereb-sexual-harassment-settlement-amount/">a $295,000 settlement with that employee</a>. Shapiro insists that he had no knowledge of this misconduct until months after the events. Given how close Shapiro was to the aide in question — his secretary of legislative affairs, Mike Vereb — it is not irrational to worry whether that claim would have held up under journalistic scrutiny.<strong> </strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is also the strange and tragic case of Ellen Greenberg. A 27-year-old resident of Philadelphia, Greenberg was found dead of 20 stab wounds in 2011. That case was initially ruled a homicide and then reclassified as a suicide. The seeming improbability of a person successfully stabbing themselves 20<em> </em>times led both Greenberg’s family and the public writ large to find the police’s conclusion outrageous. Nevertheless, when Shapiro was Pennsylvania’s attorney general in 2019, his office upheld the city’s finding of suicide. Recently, the Pennsylvania Supreme Court <a href="https://www.inquirer.com/news/ellen-greenberg-suicide-homicide-appeal-supreme-court-20240731.html">agreed</a> to take up the Greenbergs’ civil case against Philadelphia. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Walz is not wholly devoid of personal scandals; in 1995, he was <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/tim-walz-criminal-record-explored-kamala-harris-vice-president-nominee-1935287">arrested</a> for driving while intoxicated. But his publicly known personal liabilities are less recent and potentially incendiary than Shapiro’s. </p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">4. <strong>Shapiro’s capacity to deliver Pennsylvania may have been overstated</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, presidential candidates have not <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/363899/kamala-harris-vp-pick-josh-shapiro-walz-kelly">consistently performed better</a> in their running mates’ home states. In a 2019 <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/psq.12610">study</a>, the political scientists Christopher J. Devine and Kyle Kopko used large-scale survey data to gauge whether voters who lived in a VP candidate’s home state were more likely to support that candidate’s party than other voters were, after controlling for all other relevant variables (e.g., partisanship, race, age, gender, income, etc.). They found no such effect. And this result was consistent with most other studies on the subject, which have found that vice presidential candidates do not reliably enjoy a “home state advantage.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be sure, there are real limitations to what such research can tell us. Neither party’s presidential nominees have actually tried putting a popular politician from a top-tier swing state onto the ticket in generations. To the contrary, both parties have made a habit of picking VP candidates from completely uncontested red or blue states. Thus, it’s possible that historical data is a poor guide to the actual consequences of elevating Shapiro.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, the fact remains that there is little empirical basis for certainty about Shapiro’s ability to substantially increase Democratic support in Pennsylvania. Political figures’ approval ratings can change dramatically when they join a presidential ticket. Hillary Clinton had <a href="https://www.politifact.com/factchecks/2016/may/22/hillary-clinton/hillary-clintons-approval-rating-secretary-state-w/">a 65 percent approval rating</a> as secretary of state. Not long into her 2016 presidential run, however, she became historically unpopular.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Shapiro ceased to be an inoffensive bipartisan governor and became one of Donald Trump’s leading adversaries, his support with Pennsylvania Republicans could have crashed. Whether his standing with the state’s undecided voters would hold up is impossible to know in advance.</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">5. <strong>Shapiro’s pick could have undermined Democratic unity and enthusiasm (at least, online)</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The second cause for concern about Shapiro’s nomination is its potential to inflame some of the Democratic Party’s internal divisions. Most conspicuously, his selection threatened to heighten the salience of intra-Democratic disputes over US policy toward Israel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From one angle, Shapiro’s views on the Jewish state <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2024/07/josh-shapiro-netanyahu-jewish-vp/679300/">look indistinguishable</a> from those of Walz and other mainstream Democrats. He supports the two-state solution and has called Israel’s Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu “one of the worst leaders of all time.” Meanwhile, Walz <a href="https://x.com/Yair_Rosenberg/status/1820473963958383077">has</a> voiced enthusiastic support of Israel and its right to defend itself, and once took a personal meeting with Netanyahu and posed <a href="https://x.com/Yair_Rosenberg/status/1820474774218572276">for a photograph with him</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This has led some commentators to suggest that progressives’ unique antipathy for Shapiro is informed by antisemitism. Although this is surely true in some individual cases, there is a rational basis for pro-Palestinian Democrats to be particularly distrustful of the Pennsylvania governor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Much of the debate over Shapiro’s posture on Israel-Palestine has focused on an interview he gave to CNN in April. During that <a href="https://transcripts.cnn.com/show/cg/date/2024-04-24/segment/01">conversation</a> with anchor Jake Tapper, Shapiro drew an analogy between the most antisemitic, pro-Palestinian campus protestors and the KKK. Some progressives have suggested that Shapiro was comparing all pro-Palestine demonstrators to klansmen. And his defenders have rightly observed that this is false: Shapiro explicitly defended the legitimacy of peaceful dissent against Israel in the interview, and made clear that he was specifically denouncing those who engaged in the antisemitic harassment of Jewish students. And that is not substantially different from Walz’s own remarks on the subject. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet Shapiro’s hostility toward pro-Palestine advocacy is not limited to some stray remarks on cable news. In 2016, Pennsylvania <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/governor-of-pennsylvania-signs-anti-bds-bill-into-law/">enacted a law</a> that forbade the state from contracting with businesses that boycott Israel. Many legal scholars consider this to be an <a href="https://www.thefire.org/news/unconstitutional-anti-boycott-legislation-should-not-become-law?gad_source=1&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwh7K1BhCZARIsAKOrVqGjI7L7uDBZJWzw0_MhEYcyFR9mF6Vv-PqyuRZ3uSbrZK1zE5ywjCQaAjQhEALw_wcB">unconstitutional abridgment of freedom of speech</a>, as it requires the government to discriminate against business owners on the basis of their political activity. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Shapiro is an avid supporter of the legislation. And as Pennsylvania attorney general in 2021, he <a href="https://delawarevalleyjournal.com/garrity-shapiro-back-anti-bds-action-against-ben-jerrys/">implored the state’s agencies</a> to enforce the law against Ben &amp; Jerry’s, after the ice cream company refused to license its product for sale in the West Bank. Given that Israel’s ongoing occupation of that territory is both a violation of international law and an obstacle to the creation of a Palestinian state, Shapiro’s enthusiasm for punishing an act of protest against that occupation may call his commitment to the two-state solution into question. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The percentage of voters who care deeply about the Israel-Palestine conflict — and believe the Democratic Party is excessively supportive of Israel — <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/06/us/politics/biden-trump-gaza-college-protests.html">is not large</a>. But this contingent is disproportionately influential on social media, and may thus indirectly color the impressions of less politically engaged younger voters. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For much of this year, progressive outrage over American complicity in the devastation of Gaza loomed large on the social media platforms X and TikTok. Following Harris’s replacement of Biden, such discourse was largely displaced by joyful memes highlighting the vice president’s relative youth and vigor. Shapiro’s selection threatened to dampen that mood shift.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, Shapiro’s support for publicly subsidizing <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/elections/veepstakes-puts-spotlight-on-josh-shapiros-support-for-private-school-vouchers-ccd56069">private school attendance</a> has earned him some opposition from the labor movement (public school teachers are typically unionized while private school ones are not). United Auto Workers President Shawn Fain <a href="https://www.detroitnews.com/story/news/politics/2024/08/01/uaw-president-shawn-fain-voices-concerns-about-mark-kelly-josh-shapiro-kamala-harris-vp-andy-beshear/74635714007/">expressed concern</a> about Shapiro’s commitment to labor’s interests last Thursday. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Happily, these days, the bar for running mates is not high</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, Walz was a solid choice. He could plausibly help Harris ingratiate herself to Midwestern voters, enable her to moderate where necessary with only limited intra-party pushback, and, if all goes well, serve as an able governing partner. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, if Democrats wake up on November 6 having narrowly lost Pennsylvania — and thus, the Electoral College — many will surely lament Harris’s failure to tap the popular governor of the most important battleground state. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless, it will be very difficult for Walz to work out much <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/364369/trump-kamala-not-black-indian-vance-childless-cat-ladies">worse than his GOP counterpart</a>.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Rachel M. Cohen</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris’s recent embrace of rent control, explained]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/housing/365063/kamala-harris-housing-rent-control-landlords" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365063</id>
			<updated>2024-08-05T19:31:09Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-06T11:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Housing" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[At her first major campaign rally since becoming the presumptive Democratic presidential nominee, Vice President Kamala Harris made a relatively unexpected promise. Speaking in Atlanta to a crowd of 10,000 supporters, Harris pledged to “take on corporate landlords and cap unfair rent increases.” Harris’s remarks to cap rents echoed a recent proposal from the Biden [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris makes a speech during her presidential campaign rally in Atlanta, Georgia, on July 30, 2024. | Kyle Mazza/Anadolu via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Kyle Mazza/Anadolu via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2163962519_d4c185.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris makes a speech during her presidential campaign rally in Atlanta, Georgia, on July 30, 2024. | Kyle Mazza/Anadolu via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">At her first major campaign rally since becoming the presumptive Democratic presidential nominee, Vice President Kamala Harris made a relatively unexpected promise.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Speaking in Atlanta to a crowd of 10,000 supporters, Harris <a href="https://x.com/KamalaHQ/status/1818428966559944924">pledged</a> to “take on corporate landlords and cap unfair rent increases.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s remarks to cap rents echoed a recent proposal from the Biden administration just two weeks earlier <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/07/16/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-major-new-actions-to-lower-housing-costs-by-limiting-rent-increases-and-building-more-homes/">to limit rent hikes to 5 percent nationwide</a> over the next two years for all landlords who own more than 50 units. (They estimate this would cover over 20 million units across the country.) The Biden plan — which would require congressional approval — would exempt not-yet-built units, so as to not discourage much-needed new housing. The two-year rent cap, Biden officials said, would serve as a way to drive down costs while new housing was under construction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s seeming embrace of the Biden plan isn’t the first time she’s expressed support for rent control. In 2019, after Oregon adopted a then first-of-its-kind statewide rent control measure, she tweeted in praise of the bill signing. “No one should ever have to choose between paying their rent each month or feeding their children,” Harris wrote. As a senator, she also introduced legislation to offer tax relief to renters who earned less than $100,000 if they spent more than 30 percent of their income on rent and utilities. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, it wasn’t clear Harris was going to stick to a pro-renter position on the presidential campaign trail — she’s already abandoned several more left-wing stances she previously embraced while a candidate in 2020. Over the last ten days, Harris has <a href="https://x.com/sahilkapur/status/1818823545650307532">rejected Medicare for All</a>, distanced herself from a <a href="https://x.com/zhalaschak/status/1818733192846737476">federal jobs guarantee</a>, and said she would <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/kamala-harris-fracking-energy-oil-gas-biden-administration-9dd5a023">no longer oppose fracking</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But when it comes to affordable housing, Harris has so far stuck closely with the political playbook of the president, who started <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24113340/biden-housing-2024-election-campaign-renters-tenants-mortgage">campaigning on lowering housing costs</a> more aggressively this year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over <a href="https://www.jchs.harvard.edu/sites/default/files/reports/files/Harvard_JCHS_Americas_Rental_Housing_2024.pdf">22 million households</a> now spend more than a third of their income on rent, and home mortgage rates <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/MORTGAGE30US">have soared since 2022</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Rent caps, however, have <a href="https://www.vox.com/22789296/housing-crisis-rent-relief-control-supply">long been controversial among economists</a>, most of whom argue that the policy hurts housing markets and ultimately limits supply, thus driving costs up further. A <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1051137724000020?via%3Dihub">review</a> of more than 200 empirical rent control studies released in March found a “wide range of adverse effects” for communities with rent caps, and that landlords were more likely to allow rent-capped units to fall into disrepair.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, a growing movement of housing activists has been pressing federal lawmakers to embrace the policy, citing the imminent <a href="https://www.vox.com/23140987/evictions-housing-rent-assistance-erap-tenant">threat of displacement</a> many tenants face. More than 650,000 people in America experience homelessness on any given night, and federal data <a href="https://www.huduser.gov/portal/datasets/ahar/2023-ahar-part-1-pit-estimates-of-homelessness-in-the-us.html">published in late 2023</a> showed a rise in homelessness in most states.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From a campaign perspective, rent caps poll quite well. In <a href="https://navigatorresearch.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Navigator-Update-05.23.2024.pdf">one May survey published by Navigator,</a> a Democratic-aligned research group, pollsters found most voters overwhelmingly support cracking down on rent-gouging by corporate landlords, and cracking down on misleading rental fees. Measures to build more homes as a way to drive affordability were far less popular with voters, by contrast, than providing financial aid to renters and regulating rents.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The rent cap pledge didn’t come out of nowhere</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s announcement in mid-July to embrace rent caps <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/12/2/23485957/housing-banks-corporate-single-family-renters-landlord">on “corporate landlords”</a> came from mounting political pressure, and a sense that he needed to do more to court voters who were feeling badly about the economy and their daunting housing costs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A Redfin-commissioned survey from February <a href="https://spectrumnews1.com/ky/louisville/affordable-housing/2024/03/12/housing-affordabiilty-could-affect-who-voters-pick-for-president--study-says">found almost two-thirds</a> of homeowners and renters said that housing affordability made them feel negatively about the economy. Other <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/05/upshot/polls-biden-trump-2024.html">surveys have suggested</a> that many of the young people and voters of color who helped Biden win in 2020 were now wavering in their support for him, and those voters are more likely to be renters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Activist pressure came largely from the Tenant Union Federation, a national group that seeks to mobilize renters to advocate for higher standards. This group, formerly known as the <a href="https://prospect.org/power/2023-02-09-tenants-rental-housing-policy/">Homes Guarantee Campaign</a>, had successfully pushed the Biden administration to release a non-binding “blueprint” for a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/White-House-Blueprint-for-a-Renters-Bill-of-Rights.pdf">renter’s bill of rights in January 2023</a>, and since turned its sights to rent control. Activists were specifically interested in rent control Biden could enact without going through Congress, and homed in on the <a href="https://www.fhfa.gov/">Federal Housing Finance Agency</a>, which regulates the entities that issue billions in government-backed mortgages every year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In January 2023, these activists helped <a href="https://bowman.house.gov/imo/media/doc/Letter%20to%20Biden%20Admin%20on%20Rent%20Inflation_Warren%20Bowman_01092023.pdf">push a Congressional letter</a>, led by Democrats, asking Biden to take on corporate landlords and end “price gouging in the real estate sector.” The leaders proposed a suite of executive actions the government could take, with their top recommendation to direct the Federal Housing Finance Agency to establish new renter protections, including rent caps.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By July 2023, <a href="https://www.banking.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/brown_letter_to_fhfa_on_tenant_protections.pdf">a new letter from Democratic senators</a> directly urged the Federal Housing Finance Authority to enact “limits against egregious rent hikes” in properties with government-backed mortgages.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While most economists have long warned about negative effects of rent control, tenant activists <a href="https://peoplesaction.org/wp-content/uploads/Economist-Sign-on-Letter_-FHFA-RFI-Response-1.pdf">and their progressive allies in academia and law</a> have been working to challenge perceptions that rent control inevitably hurts housing markets. They point to the debate around the minimum wage, where for decades economists argued that raising the wage would invariably hurt workers and the economy, yet more recently researchers <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w25434/w25434.pdf">have determined</a> that such increases can actually be effective at boosting living standards for low-wage workers with little to no impact on job loss. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Advocates argue that empirical studies are similarly challenging the conventional wisdom that rent control limits new construction or the overall supply of housing, and they point to examples in <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/229489080_Thirty_Years_of_Rent_Control_A_Survey_of_New_Jersey_Cities">New Jersey</a>, <a href="https://economics.mit.edu/sites/default/files/publications/housing%20market%202014.pdf">Massachusetts</a>, <a href="https://www.cura.umn.edu/research/minneapolis-rent-stabilization-study">Minneapolis</a>, and <a href="https://www.urbandisplacement.org/blog/rent-control-the-key-to-neighborhood-stabilization/">California</a> to make their case.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <a href="https://peoplesaction.org/wp-content/uploads/Homes-Guarantee-Memo_-Housing-Supply-_-Case-Studies.pdf">a letter</a> the Tenant Union Federation sent to the Federal Housing Finance Agency last fall, activists noted that 182 cities and municipalities across the country had some form of rent regulation as of 2018, and California, like Oregon, had passed new statewide rent limits in the last five years.<br><br>Despite successfully pushing federal lawmakers to embrace potential new renter protections and even rent control, Biden and, so far, Harris have declined to go as far as the Tenant Union Federation wants. Some activists, for example, oppose the idea that rent caps would be temporary and exempt new units. The president also declined to endorse a plan that relied solely on his own executive power.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The whole fact that [Biden] went to Congress to deal with it is messed up,” Elizabeth Olvera Perez, a tenant and leader in the Louisville Tenants Union, <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/society/biden-rent-cap-organizers-say-whats-next/">told the Nation recently</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tara Raghuveer, the director of the National Tenant Union Federation, praised Harris’s announcement in Atlanta, <a href="https://x.com/taraghuveer/status/1818451482301120678">acknowledging that</a> it had not been a given that it would be a priority for the vice president. “Rent caps are a winning issue,” <a href="https://x.com/taraghuveer/status/1818453997088309521">Raghuveer tweeted</a>. “Candidates up and down ballot should take heed.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Most economists remain against rent control</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Skeptics of rent caps point to St. Paul, Minnesota, as a cautionary tale.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In November 2021, St. Paul voters <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/St._Paul,_Minnesota,_Question_1,_Limits_on_Rent_Increases_Initiative_(November_2021)">approved a ballot measure</a> to cap annual rent increases at 3 percent for most apartments in the city, beginning in May 2022. (The city council loosened this policy in September 2022, to <a href="https://www.twincities.com/2022/09/21/st-paul-city-council-amends-rent-control-exempts-new-construction-exemption-with-5-2-vote/">exempt new development</a> for 20 years.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Developers and investors <a href="https://www.twincities.com/2021/11/09/as-investors-cry-foul-st-paul-mayor-carter-still-bullish-on-altering-not-ending-rent-control-but-city-council-has-its-doubts/">sounded the alarm</a>, and a year into the experiment, the federal housing department reported that new building permits in St. Paul had plummeted nearly 50 percent compared to a year before, while those in nearby Minneapolis were up 16 percent.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">St. Paul planning officials <a href="https://www.twincities.com/2023/04/23/by-hud-counts-st-pauls-apartment-construction-permits-fell-48-after-rent-control-was-it-temporary/">said they weren’t jumping to any conclusions</a> about whether rent control was responsible for the declining construction, and reported their own permitting numbers were somewhat higher. (Tenant activists also argue it’s too soon to legitimately assess the policy’s impact.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, opponents and conservative intellectuals say St. Paul is confirming their worst fears that rent control will make housing more expensive in the aggregate, even if it provides relief to some existing renters in the short term.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Conservatives characterize Biden and Harris’s new embrace of rent control as further evidence that the administration is <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/26/opinion/joe-biden-kamala-harris-push-rent-control-a-great-way-to-destroy-cities/">against landlords</a>. Writing in City Journal,<em> </em>Manhattan Institute senior fellow Judge Glock argued that he doubts the Biden administration’s proposal would actually be limited to just two years. “Almost all rent control laws make such promises; governments often can’t help themselves and keep expanding the laws’ reach anyway,” he said, pointing to <a href="https://www.matthews.com/the-history-and-workings-of-nyc-rent-regulation/">New York City’s experience</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even some prominent liberals have come out against the Biden administration’s new embrace of rent caps.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Rent control has been about as disgraced as any economic policy in the tool kit,” Jason Furman, the top economic adviser to the Obama administration, recently <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/07/15/rent-cap-biden-housing/">told the Washington Post</a>. “The idea we’d be reviving and expanding it will ultimately make our housing supply problems worse, not better.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Colorado’s Democratic governor, Jared Polis, <a href="https://x.com/jaredpolis/status/1812931802899837095">echoed the criticism</a>, saying Biden’s plan “would lead to less affordable housing being built and substantially increase housing costs.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Legislative tea leaves suggest that Congress is likely to move forward with some sort of federal housing package next year. If Democrats sweep in November, and Harris continues to champion rent control, a national rent-cap policy looks a lot more likely. Whether that takes the form of a broad restriction on corporate landlords, or something more targeted to properties with government-backed mortgages is less clear. However, if Republicans retain control of at least the House or Senate, then the odds of rent caps being passed through Congress are virtually nonexistent.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tenant activists, meanwhile, will continue to pressure Biden, and Harris, to use presidential executive authority to limit rent hikes. At this point, it’s unclear whether Harris would embrace such a move if she wins the election, even as her boss has thus demurred. The Harris campaign did not return a request for comment.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Bryan Walsh</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Is there an AI bubble — and is it about to pop?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter/365292/ai-bubble-nvidia-chatgpt-stock-market-crash" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365292</id>
			<updated>2024-08-06T13:46:42Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-06T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Emerging Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained newsletter" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[How much is the future worth?&#160; Usually to answer that question, you’d need to ask philosophers or economists. But if you’re a tech CEO, you have an actual number: about $1 trillion. That’s how much the tech industry as a whole is set to spend building out the artificial intelligence industry over the coming years. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Traders work on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange " data-caption="Wall Street stocks deepened their losses Monday and Tokyo had its worst day in 13 years as panic spread across trading floors over fears of recession in the United States and overvaluation of AI and tech companies. | Charly Triballeau/ AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Charly Triballeau/ AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2164988658.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Wall Street stocks deepened their losses Monday and Tokyo had its worst day in 13 years as panic spread across trading floors over fears of recession in the United States and overvaluation of AI and tech companies. | Charly Triballeau/ AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">How much is the future worth?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Usually to answer that question, you’d need to ask philosophers or economists. But if you’re a tech CEO, you <a href="https://www.goldmansachs.com/insights/articles/will-the-1-trillion-of-generative-ai-investment-pay-off">have an actual number</a>: about $1 trillion.<br><br>That’s how much the tech industry as a whole is set to spend building out the artificial intelligence industry over the coming years. And even in Silicon Valley, where several companies have market capitalizations that start with “T,” a trillion dollars is a lot of money. And while you won’t find more fervent evangelists for AI anywhere than in the C-suite of companies like Google and Microsoft, eventually, all that money has to be recouped. The alternative would be an economic meltdown of the sort we haven’t experienced for years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Which may just well be in the process of happening.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Monday, the stock market continued days of heavy losses, with the S&amp;P down 3 percent by the close of day. The blood-letting was led by many of the same tech companies that had driven the market to record highs in recent months, with AI chip maker Nvidia falling by nearly 7 percent, and Amazon dropping 4 percent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are a lot of reasons why the bottom has at least temporarily fallen out of the market, including the possibility that the Federal Reserve has been too slow to cut interest rates in the face of a weakening US economy. <a href="https://apnews.com/article/stocks-markets-nikkei-economy-c6240977e9482bf7207abc53b2a11e58">Recent data around US hiring and manufacturing activity have come in weaker than expected</a>, helping to fuel this sell-off.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there are real concerns that despite the hundreds of billions that have been spent so far to build up the AI industry, and the hundreds of billions that are projected to be spent in the years to come, AI companies themselves aren’t yet producing much in the way of economic value. And they may not for the foreseeable future.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That sound you hear could be an AI investment bubble going pop. </p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Big AI dreams</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No one spends a trillion dollars on something unless they really, really believe in it — and Silicon Valley really, really believes in the transformative economic potential of AI. Way back in 2018, when ChatGPT was just a twinkle in the eye of OpenAI’s Sam Altman, Google CEO Sundar Pichai <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/1/19/16911180/sundar-pichai-google-fire-electricity-ai">famously told</a> Kara Swisher that “AI is one of the most important things humanity is working on. It’s more profound than, I don’t know, electricity or fire.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fire, I think we can all agree, is pretty important. You might even think of it as humanity’s first breakthrough product. But to tech leaders like Pichai, the possibility of effective, general artificial intelligence was every bit as revolutionary as the day when one of our Paleolithic ancestors rubbed two sticks together. And once OpenAI released ChatGPT in November 2022, exposing the world to the genuine magic that is large language models (LLMs), the race was on to become the company that could capture that fire.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So investors rushed to fund promising LLM startups like OpenAI (currently <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/tech/openai-valued-80-billion-deal-224312281.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly9jaGF0Z3B0LmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAMZ_s3_wCtj-aLk_d9EndIpQLhCJyF9behfY_3PO2jZ564ZiMiKmwzIjKk8C2RbomHsxS1EqBorAgGhwwNZDRMat5OK6nVRMyA4yKWgWBcwkl8Mf46dtCalNL7kOlua0hN3cApYvxJSU6yZG-HABQYXyKAP2fOoLMUZYAHA5JOl0">valued</a> at $80 billion or more) and Anthropic (<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/03/27/amazon-spends-2point7b-on-startup-anthropic-in-largest-venture-investment.html">estimated</a> at $18.4 billion). In the US alone, AI startups <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/ai-robotics/us-startup-funding-doubled-openai-anthropic-2023/">raised</a> $23 billion in capital in 2023, and more than 200 such companies around the world are unicorns — meaning they’re valued at $1 billion or more.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All that money is in part a measure of tech’s confidence that the AI market will eventually prove titanically huge. One <a href="https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/issues/data-and-analytics/publications/artificial-intelligence-study.html">forecast</a> by the consultancy PwC estimated that AI could add nearly $16 trillion — there’s that word again — to the global economy by 2030, chiefly from vastly enhanced labor productivity.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Add in the fact that tech giants have <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/04/05/how-markets-biggest-companies-manage-cash-and-investments.html">plenty of cash on hand</a>, and are <a href="https://www.investors.com/news/technology/artificial-intelligence-stocks/">actively racing</a> against each other to be first past the post when it comes to AI. If you believe the AI industry will be worth trillions — and that the lion’s share of that value will go to the early leaders — then as Pichai <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/02/tech/wall-street-asks-big-tech-will-ai-ever-make-money/index.html">said</a> on a recent earnings call, “the risk of underinvesting is dramatically greater than the risk of overinvesting.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the bill is rising, because generative AI is not cheap — both to build and to run.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">When the bill comes due</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sam Altman himself has <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/openais-losses-doubled-to-540-million-as-it-developed-chatgpt">said</a> that OpenAI is “the most capital intensive startup in history.” That’s because as models get bigger and bigger, they cost more and more to train. And that’s just the cost of making the models — running them is highly expensive as well. One analysis last year estimated that it cost OpenAI $700,000 a day <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/how-much-chatgpt-costs-openai-to-run-estimate-report-2023-4">to run ChatGPT</a>, chiefly in all that compute-intensive server time. And the more ChatGPT and other LLMs are used, the higher those costs rise.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Silicon Valley may not have invented the saying “you have to spend money to make money,” it certainly lives by it. But the revenue these companies are bringing in, chiefly via subscriptions to their premium models, are just a fraction of their costs. The Information <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/why-openai-could-lose-5-billion-this-year">reported recently</a> that OpenAI could lose as much as $5 billion this year, close to 10 times what it lost in 2022. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s not a good trajectory, and neither is ChatGPT’s user numbers. Tech analyst Benedict Evans wrote recently that while many people and companies <a href="https://www.ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2024/7/9/the-ai-summer">try out</a> AI services like ChatGPT, far fewer stick with it. (Notably, ChatGPT’s usage seems to meaningfully dip during school holidays, just in case you were wondering who the power users were.) </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While what LLMs can do is impressive, especially compared to what seemed possible a decade ago, promises of artificial general intelligence that could replace whole classes of workers <a href="https://gigaom.com/2023/11/28/seven-reasons-why-generative-ai-will-fall-short-in-2024/">have yet to come true</a>. As it stands now, the industry as a whole seems to suffer from a classic Silicon Valley problem: It <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/sales/product-market-fit">lacks product-market fit</a>. Chatbots aren’t yet a true product, and it’s not clear yet how big the market is for them. That’s why experts ranging from Wall Street banks <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2024/08/the-generative-ai-revolution-may-be-a-bubble/679345/">like Goldman Sachs</a> to tech VCs <a href="https://www.sequoiacap.com/article/ais-600b-question/">like Sequoia Capital</a> have been throwing up yellow caution flags around the AI industry — and why investors seem to have begun heeding them.<br><br>None of this is to say that AI itself doesn’t still have revolutionary potential, nor that the industry won’t eventually fulfill those dreams. The dot com crash in the early 2000s was in part due to overinvestment and overvaluation of startups of the era, but Evans notes that what was left over set the stage for mega-companies of today like Google and Meta. The same may one day be true for AI companies. But unless the financials improve, it may not be these AI companies. <br><br> <em>This story originally appeared in </em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Today, Explained</a></em></strong><em>, Vox’s flagship daily newsletter. </em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/today-explained-newsletter-signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here for future editions</a></em></strong><em>.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Bangladesh’s prime minister just fled the country in a helicopter. Why?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/365259/bangladesh-sheikh-hasina-awami-protests-bnp" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365259</id>
			<updated>2024-08-06T21:14:12Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-05T22:40:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Economy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="India" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Poverty" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bangladesh’s increasingly autocratic leader, Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, resigned and fled the country Monday following weeks of unrest. Hasina’s exit on an India-bound military helicopter came after crowds broke a curfew and stormed the prime minister’s residence in the capital Dhaka, following weeks of bloody protest.&#160; The movement that ultimately toppled her started with students [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Bangladesh’s prime minister, Sheikh Hasina, speaks to the media during a press conference at Government House. | Peerapon Boonyakiat/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-portal-copyright="Peerapon Boonyakiat/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2149699213.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Bangladesh’s prime minister, Sheikh Hasina, speaks to the media during a press conference at Government House. | Peerapon Boonyakiat/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Bangladesh’s increasingly autocratic leader, Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, resigned and fled the country Monday following weeks of unrest.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hasina’s exit on an India-bound military helicopter <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/8/5/bangladesh-pm-hasina-quits-and-flees-as-protestors-storm-palace-reports">came after crowds broke a curfew and stormed the prime minister’s residence in the capital Dhaka</a>, following weeks of bloody protest.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The movement that ultimately toppled her started with students frustrated at their lack of job prospects and snowballed to include ordinary Bangladeshis facing increasingly tough economic conditions. But the jubilant scenes in the capital Dhaka come at great cost; around 300 people have been killed since the protests started in June, and the country’s future remains uncertain as a military-backed caretaker government steps in.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After a decade and a half in power, Hasina’s legacy is complicated. On the one hand, her government built modern infrastructure and improved development opportunities, especially for the poor. But she also increasingly cracked down on the press, as well as the opposition, and as time went on, many forms of dissent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Army General Waker-uz-Zaman announced Monday that the military had taken control of the government; parliament is being dissolved, and the government is formulating a plan for fresh elections.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The country is going through a revolutionary period,” <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/bangladesh-protesters-call-march-dhaka-defiance-curfew-2024-08-05/">Zaman said</a> in a national television address. “We request you to have faith in the army of the country. Please don’t go back to the path of violence and please return to nonviolent and peaceful ways.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though a people-power movement has won a victory in driving Hasina out, the young democracy is entering a period of major uncertainty; indeed, what happens next for Bangladesh is anyone’s guess.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How Bangladesh got to the breaking point</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hasina belongs to one of Bangladesh’s two political dynasties, which have traded power with each other since the country’s tumultuous and bloody founding in 1971. Her father, Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, was a freedom fighter frequently called the father of Bangladesh. He was assassinated in 1975, forcing Hasina to live in exile in India.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But, boosted by her familial connections, Hasina was first elected prime minister in 1996, serving until 2001, when<strong> </strong>Hasina’s foil, former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia, was elected. Zia <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/bangladesh-protesters-call-march-dhaka-defiance-curfew-2024-08-05/">was released from house arrest Monday at the behest of President Mohammed Shahabuddin</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hasina and Zia, the head of the opposition Bangladeshi Nationalist Party and widow of <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Ziaur-Rahman">former Prime Minister Ziaur Rahman</a>, have been the only two elected leaders in Bangladesh since 1991. Until January, <a href="https://thediplomat.com/2024/01/the-bnps-islamist-dilemma/">the BNP was in a massive coalition against the Awami league with 19 other political parties</a> and boycotted the January 7 elections.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This intense polarization —&nbsp;Awami League versus everyone else —&nbsp;is part of the reason for the protests. Another part is economic. For the country’s many educated young people, a stable path has meant a job with the government, but that has been increasingly impossible. Protesters blame a quota system that reserved up to 30 percent of government jobs for relatives of soldiers from the 1971 war for independence —&nbsp;but which protesters complained benefited Awami League members and allies.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hasina is credited for an economic boom shortly after she took office for the second time in 2008. “The government has had a relatively strong economic record over its 15 years in power,” <a href="https://www.usip.org/people/geoffrey-macdonald-phd">Geoffrey Macdonald</a>, a visiting expert at the US Institute of Peace, told Vox. “There has been rising development, infrastructure developments, [increased] income rates, and a lot of human development indicators outrank many of its neighbors.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But “a lot of Bangladesh’s growth has been in areas like textiles, that are not a big employment stream for university graduates,” <a href="https://political-science.uchicago.edu/directory/Paul-Staniland">Paul Staniland</a>, a political science professor at the University of Chicago, told Vox. “So this quota system was seen as kind of artificially restricting the supply of jobs for educated folks.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But economic problems in Bangladesh are not limited to the middle class;&nbsp; like many other countries in South Asia and around the world, Bengalis are suffering from high inflation —&nbsp;<a href="https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/FP.CPI.TOTL.ZG?locations=BD">around 9.9 percent</a> as of this writing —&nbsp;making it harder for ordinary people to afford the basics.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Politically, Bangladeshis were fed up, too; elections in 2018 and this past January were widely seen as being fraudulent, and people no longer felt that they had a voice in choosing a government that could respond to their needs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This process of an autocratic nation really deepens and lasts five or six years where Sheikh Hasina really goes after a lot of her enemies, whether they’re part of the BNP, whether they’re liberal dissidents, whoever — really kind of solidifying and personalizing her rule,” Stanliand said. “And so that kind of runs through the most recent election, which, you know, is widely viewed as deeply irregular.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those facts, as well as the government’s incredibly violent crackdown against the protesters, ignited a national movement that succeeded in ousting Hasina.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We were expecting some sort of crisis, but I was not thinking that she might leave because she’s a very strong character,” Fabeha Monir, an independent journalist living in Dhaka, told Vox. But the police response, “escalated in a way and then so much that it was intolerable, intolerable for the nation itself.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://apnews.com/article/bangladesh-student-protests-curfew-government-jobs-quota-9af35994b4855ffac9bd962861447cda">In mid-July</a>, crackdowns on the protesters started in earnest, with the police imposing a curfew and shoot-on-sight order. The government also blocked internet and mobile access.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Bangladesh is in a historical transition —&nbsp;but no one knows what comes next</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Along with the founding of the state, the assassination of Hasina’s father, and the 1991 return to democracy, the protest movement and Hasina’s departure will be one of the defining events of Bangladesh’s history.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Details of Hasina’s resignation and exile are still coming to light, but the protests could not have evolved the way they did —&nbsp;with thousands eventually breaching Hasina’s residence —&nbsp;without the military’s tacit agreement, or at least its refusal to crack down as Hasina wished.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“So many unarmed students died, and everybody started blaming our military,” Monir said. “So then they started supporting [the protesters for] a few days now.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The military has historically been powerful in Bangladesh, and though Hasina seemed to have corralled it a bit under her tenure, it still appears to have retained some independence, Staniland said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“My guess is, the military was not willing to kill hundreds or thousands of people to stop this next wave of protest that developed,” he said. “And that was the trigger for her to leave.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though there is genuine excitement about Hasina’s departure, there is also great concern for what happens next. In a best-case scenario for democracy, the caretaker government could ensure elections that lead to real, progressive reforms. That’s far from certain, however. The military could cling to power, or more right-wing, Islamist factions could seize the government.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The great concern for now is the spread of more violence —&nbsp;this time, not just against protesters, but against supporters of the Awami League, particularly those belonging to minority groups.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bangladesh is a multi-ethnic, multi-religious state, <a href="https://thediplomat.com/2023/11/religion-and-bangladeshs-political-parties/">though the BNP</a> tends toward political Islam and is more conservative. The Awami League, which is secular, appeals to religious minorities in a majority Muslim society, as well as ethnic minorities like the Rohingya from Myanmar, which the Hasina administration made an effort to support when they began arriving as refugees in 2017.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think we’re likely to see a lot of retribution being taken out against local Awami League officials — police and security officials who defended the government,” Macdonald said. “Hindus are a historical vote bank of the Awami League. And there’s also just lingering tensions between religious communities in general.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The bizarre RFK Jr. bear incident, briefly explained]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365284/robert-f-kennedy-jr-bear-central-park" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365284</id>
			<updated>2024-08-05T22:26:16Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-05T22:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Robert F. Kennedy Jr., an independent presidential candidate perhaps best known for his anti-vaccine viewpoints and proclivity for spreading conspiracy theories, admitted he dumped a dead bear in New York’s Central Park back in 2014.&#160; In a video Kennedy posted on X on Sunday, he revealed that he’d left a bike and bear carcass in [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kennedy, in a dark blue suit and skinny tie, speaks into a microphone before a black backdrop." data-caption="Independent presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. speaks at the Libertarian National Convention on May 24, 2024 in Washington, DC. | Kevin Dietsch/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Kevin Dietsch/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2154524764.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Independent presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. speaks at the Libertarian National Convention on May 24, 2024 in Washington, DC. | Kevin Dietsch/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/9/7/23862026/robert-f-kennedy-jr-presidential-campaign-republicans">Robert F. Kennedy Jr.,</a> an independent presidential candidate perhaps best known for his anti-vaccine viewpoints and proclivity for spreading conspiracy theories, admitted he dumped a dead bear in New York’s Central Park back in 2014.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://x.com/RobertKennedyJr/status/1820132549798347109">In a video Kennedy posted on X on Sunday,</a> he revealed that he’d left a bike and bear carcass in the park, hoping it would appear that a cyclist had killed the bear, and that it would be “amusing.” It’s a bizarre incident that <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2014/10/08/nyregion/bear-cub-found-dead-in-central-park-was-hit-by-a-car-investigators-say.html">prompted major news coverage</a> at the time — and that spawned a years-long mystery about how the bear even got there. The story was set to become public as part of <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2024/08/12/robert-f-kennedy-jr-profile-presidential-campaign">a long, critical New Yorker profile</a> of Kennedy, which featured the anecdote, and which seemed to have prompted Kennedy to share his side of it.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The bear incident is also only the latest in <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/story/robert-kennedy-jr-shocking-history">myriad problematic acts</a> that Kennedy has been implicated in — including spreading <a href="https://apnews.com/article/rfk-kennedy-election-2024-president-campaign-621c9e9641381a1b2677df9de5a09731">medical misinformation</a> and allegations of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/12/us/politics/kennedy-sexual-assault-accusation.html#:~:text=In%20an%20article%20in%20Vanity,told%20The%20Post%20that%20Mr.">sexual misconduct</a>. He’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/08/us/rfk-jr-brain-health-memory-loss.html">previously made headlines</a>, too, after sharing that a parasitic worm had eaten part of his brain. Collectively, these disclosures have all added to a peculiar persona and haphazard policy positions he’s cultivated.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite his antics and controversial stances, Kennedy has managed to hang on to a <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/04/rfk-jr-2024-election-harris-trump">winnowing base of support</a> that’s attracted to his anti-establishment positions, and that believes he’s the only candidate willing to tell it like it is.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A recent <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/national/">FiveThirtyEight polling aggregation</a> shows Kennedy holding about 5.5 percent support in a general presidential election versus Vice President Kamala Harris and former President Donald Trump. <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/national/biden-trump/">That’s down from the 10.3 percent</a> he received in March in FiveThirtyEight’s roundup, when President Joe Biden was still the presumed Democratic nominee.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With Kennedy, progressive scholar Cornel West, and Green Party candidate Jill Stein all among those running as independent or third-party options, it is possible alternative candidates might help decide what is <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-harris">shaping up to be a close election</a> — especially in key swing states that have historically been <a href="https://www.cnn.com/election/2020/results/president">won by small margins</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The RFK bear incident – and other strange positions – briefly explained</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://x.com/RobertKennedyJr/status/1820132549798347109">In the X video,</a> Kennedy says he was on his way to a falconing trip in the Hudson Valley, when he saw the car in front of him hit and kill a bear cub.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I pulled over and I picked up the bear and put him in the back of my van because I was going to skin the bear,” Kennedy explained. “It was [in] very good condition and I was going to put the meat in my refrigerator.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to Kennedy, the falconing trip went long and he wasn’t able to make it home before having to run to a dinner in New York City. Because that dinner also took longer than expected, he wasn’t able to bring the bear back to his house prior to a flight he had that same evening.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Faced with these time constraints, Kennedy says he — and those around him — felt that his best option was to deposit the bear in Central Park, and make it look like a bike had killed the cub, because that “would be funny for people.” After doing so, Kennedy says he saw an explosion of news coverage about the incident the next day, and grew worried that he’d find himself in trouble with law enforcement, but never came clean about his involvement until now.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The discovery of the bear <a href="https://www.nydailynews.com/2014/10/06/bear-cub-found-dead-in-central-park-police-suspect-death-was-unnatural/">spurred an investigation into animal cruelty</a>, and raised questions about how the animal’s carcass made its way into New York City. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not the only concerning incident that has surfaced about Kennedy in the course of his presidential campaign — others have included everything from <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/02/politics/rfk-jr-eating-dog-vanity-fair/index.html">outrage over him supposedly eating dog</a> to serious allegations of sexual assault. Eliza Cooney, who previously worked as a live-in nanny for his family, alleges that Kennedy groped her in his home and touched her leg in a business meeting. Kennedy has said the piece featuring the sexual assault claim — which <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/story/robert-kennedy-jr-shocking-history">was published in Vanity Fair</a> — was “garbage,” but added that he wasn’t a “church boy.” After the Vanity Fair story published, Cooney shared a text Kennedy <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/07/12/rfk-sexual-assault-apology-eliza-cooney/" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/07/12/rfk-sexual-assault-apology-eliza-cooney/">had sent her with The Washington Post</a>, which stated that he had “no memory of this incident,” but apologized for any actions that may have made her uncomfortable.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That same Vanity Fair story outlines a pattern of strange and disturbing behavior including sending friends nude photos of women and spreading conspiracy theories about everything from Covid-19 to President John F. Kennedy’s assassination, a pattern the New Yorker profile also highlights. “He can say some crazy shit,” his sister Rory Kennedy once said, according to the <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/story/robert-kennedy-jr-shocking-history">Vanity Fair report</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kennedy’s policy platform has focused heavily on incorrect, anti-vaccine statements linking childhood vaccines with autism, which has been widely <a href="https://www.annenbergpublicpolicycenter.org/fact-checking-presidential-candidate-robert-f-kennedy-jr-on-vaccines-autism-and-covid-19/">debunked by physicians and scientists</a>. One of his organizations is also responsible for paying for <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/nov/13/majority-antivaxx-vaccine-ads-facebook-funded-by-two-organizations-study" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/nov/13/majority-antivaxx-vaccine-ads-facebook-funded-by-two-organizations-study">a significant proportion of the ads on Facebook</a> promoting falsehoods about vaccines, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/11/us/robert-f-kennedy-jr-instagram-covid-vaccine.html">the New York Times reports</a>. And his stance has been tied to real damage: In one instance, Kennedy and his nonprofit boosted misinformation in American Samoa about vaccines and likely <a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2024/07/how-rfk-jr-falsely-denied-his-connection-to-a-deadly-measles-outbreak-in-samoa/">contributed to a massive measles outbreak</a> in the region, <a href="https://www.annenbergpublicpolicycenter.org/fact-checking-presidential-candidate-robert-f-kennedy-jr-on-vaccines-autism-and-covid-19/">FactCheck.org notes</a>. Kennedy has also spread conspiracies about Covid-19, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/15/us/politics/rfk-jr-remarks-covid.html">and falsely claimed that it was “ethnically targeted” </a>to avoid harming Ashkenazi Jews and Chinese people. <a href="https://www.kennedy24.com/policies">On the campaign trail</a>, he’s channeled these stances into rhetoric about the importance of protecting people’s “health,” and the need to combat chronic illnesses and get toxins out of food. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Kennedy has a small base of support that could play a role in the election</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The people who’ve supported Kennedy have been drawn to him for the same reasons that critics oppose him.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By and large his backers, who span the ideological spectrum, see him as speaking honestly about issues like vaccines in ways that they don’t see politicians in the two parties doing so. Similarly, they view him as someone who’s willing to call out the political establishment, and cite his past record of taking on big businesses as an environmental lawyer.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“He’s not in that party structure. Those political parties are authoritarian and they don’t allow dissent. Anyone who speaks out against the Democratic orthodox is pushed out,” Kevin Nally, a Kennedy supporter and former Democratic voter, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/rfk-jr-supporters-trump-deserters-ex-democrats-theyre-hungry-change-2024-05-19/">told Reuters</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s also likely that some of his early support was due to the fact that he offered an alternative to Biden and Trump, both of whom came with their own baggage for many voters. Kennedy’s support appears to <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/national/">have declined</a> as Harris has entered the race, though it could still play a role in the election if he’s able to get on key swing state ballots — something his campaign is still working to do in <a href="https://www.spotlightpa.org/news/2024/08/pennsylvania-robert-kennedy-jr-ballot-access-jill-stein-third-parties/">places like Pennsylvania</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Earlier this year, Kennedy’s campaign said that he had been approved to appear on the Michigan ballot, one of a handful of states that will be a crucial battleground. Previously, former President Donald Trump won Michigan in 2016 by just over 10,700 votes, or roughly 0.3 percentage points. And while Biden beat Trump by just over 3 percentage points in 2020, <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-harris">polls suggest</a> the state may look more like 2016 than 2020 this year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Kennedy gets “1 percent in those battleground states that could be decided very narrowly, he could cause one candidate to lose the presidency, or another candidate to win,” University of Virginia political scientist Barbara Perry told Vox.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That dynamic&nbsp; has been evident in the past with third party candidates, including independent businessman Ross Perot in 1992, who was seen as siphoning off support from President George H.W. Bush, and Green Party candidate Jill Stein in 2016, who was seen as cutting into the backing of former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton. (Research suggests that neither <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/23998347/ross-perot-rfj-jr-third-party-indepdendent-2024">Perot</a> nor <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2016/11/11/13576798/jill-stein-third-party-donald-trump-win">Stein</a> actually swung their elections, however.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Polls suggest that Kennedy could actually have an impact on both parties, since his views run the gamut of more conservative ideas like anti-vaccine positions, and more climate-friendly proposals, like calling for companies to cover the costs of pollution. It’s possible, though, that he’s even more harmful to Trump — despite his Democratic roots — because of their shared stances on vaccine mandates and Covid-19 restrictions. And reports suggest that the former president’s <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/05/10/politics/trump-campaign-rfk-jr/index.html">campaign does have some concerns</a> about Kennedy.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What caused the global stock market meltdown]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/money/365271/stocks-dow-nasdaq-recession-us-economy-fed" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365271</id>
			<updated>2024-08-05T21:30:17Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-05T21:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Business &amp; Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Economy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Personal Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Stock market" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Global stocks plunged over the weekend amid fears that the US economy is faltering, and Monday, all three major US stock indexes were down significantly. The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell more than 1,000 points, while the S&#38;P 500 and the Nasdaq were both down more than 3 percent — marking the S&#38;P 550’s biggest [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Stock market numbers are displayed on a screen at the New York Stock Exchange during afternoon trading on August 2, 2024, in New York City. | Michael M. Santiago/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Michael M. Santiago/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2165010509.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Stock market numbers are displayed on a screen at the New York Stock Exchange during afternoon trading on August 2, 2024, in New York City. | Michael M. Santiago/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Global stocks plunged over the weekend amid fears that the US economy is faltering, and Monday, all three major US stock indexes were down significantly.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/livecoverage/stock-market-today-s-p-500-nasdaq-futures-dive-as-buffett-dumps-apple-yen-soars">more than 1,000 points</a>, while the S&amp;P 500 and the Nasdaq were both down more than 3 percent — marking the S&amp;P 550’s <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/live-blog/2024-08-05/asia-market-open">biggest one-day drop </a>since September 2022. The slides came after Japan’s Nikkei index had its <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/05/asia-markets.html">worst day since its “Black Monday” crash of 1987</a>, dropping 12.4 percent, and as <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/05/european-markets-stocks-data-and-earnings-as-volatility-continues.html">European markets</a> struggled as well.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The heavy losses signal that investors are rattled following <a href="https://apnews.com/article/economy-recession-jobs-unemployment-c7f1985b1ab3a7b781920c2693cd0438">reports last week</a> showing that the US had only added 114,000 jobs in July, below expectations of about 150,000, and that unemployment had risen to 4.3 percent — higher than any month since October 2021. These numbers are not in and of themselves a crisis: The unemployment rate is still relatively low, and the underperformance in hiring isn’t catastrophic, but both have been taken as signals that the US economy might be showing some cracks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even though many economists <a href="https://www.bankrate.com/banking/federal-reserve/economic-indicator-survey-recession-risks-april-2024/">projected that the US would avoid a recession</a> after the pandemic-induced economic slump, and despite the fact that it has done so, the reports reignited concerns that a US recession could still happen, wreaking disastrous potential impacts across the global economy. On Monday, Goldman Sachs raised its odds of a recession occurring in the next year from <a href="https://thehill.com/business/4811504-goldman-boosts-recession-odds-but-sees-limited-risk-of-downturn/">15 percent to 25 percent</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s impossible to say now how realistic those recession fears are. But it may be too early for panic. The US economy wasn’t just <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/354969/inflation-cpi-federal-reserve-biden-trump-election">supposed to be good</a> — it actually is in pretty good shape.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There’s certainly some slowing going on,” said Matt Colyar, an economist at Moody’s Analytics. “But the foundational things that made us relatively encouraged about the US economy — those things haven’t changed.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Is a recession coming?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rise in unemployment “spooked a lot of people,” Colyar said, because it triggered what is called the “Sahm Rule,” apparently indicating that a recession may be near.&nbsp; The rule is activated if the three-month average unemployment rate increases by at least half a percentage point from its low over the prior year. It has successfully predicted every US recession since 1970.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, the economist after which the rule is named, Claudia Sahm, isn’t convinced that the Sahm Rule will be a reliable predictor this time. The post-pandemic economy has so far defied other historical recession indicators: For example, most bond strategists polled by Reuters earlier this year said that the patterns they study have been so unusual that they <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/inverted-yield-curve-no-longer-reliable-recession-flag-strategists-say-2024-03-12/">no longer considered bond yield curves</a> to be predictive.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If the Sahm Rule were to trigger, it would join the ever-growing group of indicators, rules of thumb, that weren’t up to the task,” <a href="https://apnews.com/article/economy-recession-jobs-unemployment-c7f1985b1ab3a7b781920c2693cd0438">Sahm told the AP</a> before the jobs report came out last week.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One reason the Sahm rule might not be as useful this time around is that the rise in unemployment isn’t being driven by layoffs but rather more people are entering the labor force. Strong growth in the labor supply isn’t necessarily a signal of a recession, Colyar said. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“[Unemployment] could keep growing,” he said. “But as of right now, the labor market isn&#8217;t flashing red as much as it&#8217;s just slowing down.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But a bad jobs report wasn’t the only thing driving the global market selloff; so-called <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/global-markets-rout-positioning-analysis-pix-2024-08-05/?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;utm_campaign=One-Essential-Read&amp;utm_term=080524&amp;user_email=38572e447ae2b3a943d6423dd3d8ad89c2e154a588929a92468b7914f3f4e88f&amp;lctg=66464e6f30f1bc62c305003b">carry trades</a> may have also played a big role. These trades involve investors borrowing money in currencies that have low interest rates — such as the Japanese yen or Swiss franc — and using it to buy higher-yielding investments, such as US Treasury bonds.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Because the yen has <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-08-05/intensifying-yen-rally-sinks-japan-stocks-rattles-global-market">increased in value by 11 percent against the US dollar</a> in a month, these trades are no longer as advantageous to investors. Though it’s difficult to say for certain in real-time, Colyar said that investors may be “unwinding those bets to minimize their losses” and instead putting that money in safe-haven securities such as US bonds, contributing to the Nikkei index’s crash. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Goldman Sachs has also cautioned about reading too much into recent market volatility. In its Monday analysis, the bank said that it sees recession risk as “limited,” that it does not “see major financial imbalances,” and that though it may have increased its projection on the risk of recession, there is plenty of room for the Federal Reserve to step in to protect the economy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Fed is expected to cut interest rates as early as its September meeting — or unusually, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/us-interest-rate-futures-price-inter-meeting-fed-cut-2024-08-05/">perhaps even before then</a> — and that would provide relief to borrowers and businesses. Now that inflation has come down to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/11/economy/us-cpi-consumer-inflation-june/index.html">near the Fed’s 2 percent target rate</a>, Moody’s Analytics is projecting two rate cuts before the end of the year in September and December, involving a gradual relaxing of high interest rates. That could go a long way in calming the stock market. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Households remain in good shape, and businesses have continued to hire solidly. And businesses and households have handled their debt relatively well,” Colyar said. “So we think that [the Fed] can unwind policy relatively slowly. … There&#8217;s some evidence that there is more resilience there than previously assumed.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Kamala Harris beating Donald Trump in the polls?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365148/kamala-harris-trump-polls-election-2024" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365148</id>
			<updated>2024-08-05T17:27:01Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-05T17:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris entered the presidential race a little over two weeks ago as an underdog. Since then, Democrats’ vibes have been fantastic — and Harris’s polling has gotten better. But it hasn’t improved as much as you might think. At least not yet. Per polls, Trump is no longer the clear favorite to win. But [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris greets the crowd during her presidential campaign rally in Atlanta, Georgia, United States on July 30, 2024. | Kyle Mazza/Anadolu via Getty" data-portal-copyright="Kyle Mazza/Anadolu via Getty" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2163962508_493ec1.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris greets the crowd during her presidential campaign rally in Atlanta, Georgia, United States on July 30, 2024. | Kyle Mazza/Anadolu via Getty</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Kamala Harris entered the presidential race a little over two weeks ago <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/362277/kamala-harris-donald-trump-polling">as an underdog</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since then, Democrats’ vibes have been fantastic — and Harris’s polling has gotten better. But it hasn’t improved as much as you might think. At least not yet.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Per polls, Trump is no longer the clear favorite to win. But Harris hasn’t taken a clear lead either. <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/us/elections/polls-president.html">Polling</a>, particularly in swing states, suggests an extremely close race that could go either way.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear: This is a major improvement for Democrats, as compared to where President Joe Biden’s numbers had been. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Late last year, Trump <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-biden">gained</a> a durable poll lead on Biden nationally and in nearly every swing state. For Democrats, erasing that lead is a very big deal, and it helps explain the Trump campaign’s <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/f511c4ba-a7a6-4007-b91f-79a08f291d1d">flailing</a> of late. The Trump team <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2024/07/trump-campain-election-2024-susie-wiles-chris-lacivita/678806/">thought</a> they were sure to beat Biden, and now they are no longer so sure.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But a Harris win also looks very far from certain. That’s in part because, due to the magic of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/363256/kamala-harris-electoral-college-swing-state-polls">Electoral College</a>, national polls don’t determine the outcome, swing states do. And the state of play in swing states is murky.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last week’s <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2024-07-30/kamala-harris-erases-trump-s-swing-state-lead-in-2024-election-poll?sref=qYiz2hd0">Bloomberg/Morning Consult polls</a> were encouraging for Harris overall, showing her taking a big lead in Michigan and smaller leads in Wisconsin, Arizona, and Nevada. The catch is that they also showed Trump ahead in Pennsylvania and North Carolina, plus a tie in Georgia. If those polls were accurate, the election would come down entirely to Georgia’s outcome.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And other recent swing state polls — from <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4795508-harris-tied-trump-pennsylvania-michigan-wisconsin/">Fox</a>, <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4801296-trump-harris-polls-arizona-pennsylvania-georgia/">Public Policy Polling</a>, and <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4790684-kamala-harris-polls-donald-trump-wisconsin/">Emerson</a> — have shown Trump continuing to hold small leads in most swing states.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is possible that the sparse swing state polling has been slow to catch up to Harris’s improving national vibes — and that a set of new polls showing Harris gaining a clear advantage is right around the corner.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But in both 2016 and 2020, Trump performed significantly better in key Electoral College states than Democrats (and most pollsters) expected — enough to thwart Hillary Clinton’s popular vote win, and to very nearly thwart Biden’s. Harris’s main challenge will be to stop that from happening again.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Harris has been in a honeymoon phase. What will happen after the honeymoon ends?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The past two weeks have gone about as well as could have been expected for Democrats, and far better than many pundits predicted. With the messy process of pushing Biden aside completed, there has been a  joyful embrace of Harris as his replacement. Democrats believe they now have a real chance to win again. Despite being an incumbent vice president, Harris in some ways can be said to embody the new — a 59-year-old woman of color who has not been president before — in contrast to Trump, a 78-year-old former president. She has a claim to being the change candidate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris has also benefited from quite positive media coverage. In part that’s simply because things have, objectively, gone well for her so far. But she’s also benefiting from what’s often called the “<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0301420722000800">honeymoon</a>” phenomenon, in which a newly elevated political leader gets positive press simply because of their newness. And the thing about honeymoons is that they eventually end.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For instance: When Harris was running in the Democratic presidential primary in 2019, her first debate — when she criticized Biden’s 1970s opposition to school desegregation busing in a moment that <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/girl-senator-harris-vice-president-biden-spar-desegregation/story?id=64007842">went viral</a> — was tremendously successful, sending her <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/02/us/politics/kamala-harris-polls.html">surging in the polls</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But as the campaign went on, she struggled to sustain that momentum. Days later, she acknowledged that her views on modern busing policy weren’t any different from Biden’s. Later on, she <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/8/20/20813658/kamala-harris-bernie-sanders-medicare-for-all-2020">struggled to outline</a> a coherent health care policy. And her campaign “became a hotbed of drama and backbiting,” <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/12/03/politics/kamala-harris-2020-campaign/index.html">according to CNN</a>. She eventually dropped out of the race before voting began.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This time around, Harris has masterfully played the inside game in lining up party support for her campaign, she’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/04/us/politics/trump-harris-campaign-crowds.html">drawn enthusiastic crowds</a>, and she’s <a href="https://apnews.com/article/harris-fundraising-democrats-trump-fbc14aa926444b4f961f579c63811766">raised a gargantuan pile of cash</a>. But there are other things she hasn’t done yet. For instance: She hasn’t given an interview or press conference since Biden quit, which is something Republicans <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4806604-kamala-harris-hiding-press-republicans/">are grousing about</a>. Her choice of a running mate could also lead to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/03/us/politics/shapiro-aide-sexual-harassment.html">controversy</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats might hope the honeymoon can be stretched out for three more months. But inevitably, contentious issues will arise for Harris, as they do for all presidential candidates. Media coverage of her will turn at least somewhat less positive. Her campaign’s prospects will depend on how she weathers the storms that are sure to come.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
