<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Automobile Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Automobile articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 08:44:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/automobile.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 08:44:53 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[BAJA SAEINDIA 2025 organises vehicle design competition with Chitkara University, Chandigarh]]></title><description><![CDATA[BAJA SAEINDIA 2025 features engineering students designing, manufacturing, and competing with single-seater ATVs. It includes virtual and physical rounds hosted by various institutes, with events focusing on innovation and sustainability. This season sees increased participation in hydrogen and autonomous vehicle categories, highlighting the competition's role in preparing future mobility engineers.]]></description><link>https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/baja-saeindia-2025-organises-vehicle-design-competition-with-chitkara-university-chandigarh/115863499</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://auto.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/auto-technology/baja-saeindia-2025-organises-vehicle-design-competition-with-chitkara-university-chandigarh/115863499</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 07:50:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cheaper loans on table to urge UK motorists to EVs, plus cuts in fines for firms]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Business secretary Jonathan Reynolds says there is ‘no route to net zero’ that ignores concerns of businesses after wave of closures</p><p>• <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/dec/01/if-we-delay-the-uks-drive-for-electric-vehicles-our-rivals-will-overtake-us">Jonathan Reynolds: If we delay the UK’s drive for electric vehicles, our rivals will overtake us</a></p><p>There is “no route to net zero” that ignores the real concerns of businesses, a cabinet minister has warned, as the government prepares to reduce financial penalties handed to carmakers not selling enough electric cars.</p><p>Ministers are also looking at how cheaper loans could be introduced to help people buy an electric vehicle (EV), after a wave of job losses and closures in which carmakers blamed the onerous fines they were facing.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/dec/01/loans-uk-motorists-electric-ev-fines">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/dec/01/loans-uk-motorists-electric-ev-fines</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/dec/01/loans-uk-motorists-electric-ev-fines</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 07:00:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Claws are out as Jaguar heads down EV rebrand road]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A new electric model will be unveiled this week. Will it turn round the culture war embroiling the marque?</p><p>When German manufacturer BMW took over the Mini brand and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2001/nov/08/carindustry.motoring">launched the Mini Cooper in 2001</a>, some people were outraged. Drivers with previous models even slapped on bumper stickers reading “this is a real Mini”. The BBC reported that executives insisted the car “is not a small BMW”.</p><p>The storm died down, and Mini has gone on to sell more cars each year (about 300,000) than ever before, many of them emblazoned with union jack tail-lights – whatever the ownership of the factory.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2024/dec/01/claws-are-out-as-jaguar-heads-down-ev-rebrand-road">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2024/dec/01/claws-are-out-as-jaguar-heads-down-ev-rebrand-road</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/business/2024/dec/01/claws-are-out-as-jaguar-heads-down-ev-rebrand-road</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 07:00:49 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>