<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Automobile Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Automobile articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 05:32:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/automobile.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 05:32:20 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Driver jailed over wedding bus crash that killed 10]]></title><description><![CDATA[Brett Button has been sentenced to 32 years in prison over the tragedy, which shocked Australia.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/clygey9xyvmo</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/clygey9xyvmo</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 05:23:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[At least 48 dead in Nigeria explosion after fuel tanker collides with truck]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Official says dead given mass burial after after collision in Agaie area of north-central Niger state</p><p>A fuel tanker has collided head on with another truck in Nigeria, causing an explosion that killed at least 48 people, the country’s emergency response agency has said. <br><br>
 The tanker was also carrying cattle in the Agaie area in north-central Niger state, at least 50 of which were burned alive, Abdullahi Baba-Arab, director-general of the Niger State Emergency Management Agency, said. He added that search and rescue operations were under way at the scene of the accident.<br><br>
 Baba-Arab said initially that 30 bodies were found, but in a later statement said an additional 18 bodies of victims who were burned to death in the collision were found. He said the dead had been given a mass burial.<br><br>
 Mohammed Bago, the governor of Niger state, said residents of the affected area should remain calm and asked road users to “always be cautious and abide by road traffic regulations to safeguard lives and property”.<br><br>
 In the absence of an efficient railway system to transport cargo, fatal truck accidents are common along most of the major roads in Nigeria, Africa’s most populous country.<br><br>
 In 2020 alone, there were 1,531 gasoline tanker crashes, resulting in 535 fatalities and 1,142 injuries, according to Nigeria’s Federal Road Safety Corps.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/sep/08/nigeria-dead-after-explosion-fuel-tanker-truck-collision">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/sep/08/nigeria-dead-after-explosion-fuel-tanker-truck-collision</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/sep/08/nigeria-dead-after-explosion-fuel-tanker-truck-collision</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 20:21:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Four Olympic medals stolen from ‘Oarsome Foursome’ rower’s car in Melbourne]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Victoria police launch investigation into theft of Drew Ginn’s medals in Docklands last week</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2024/sep/11/australia-politics-live-dutton-cut-green-tape-miners-mining-king-royal-visit-plans-asylum-seekers-universities-student-caps-vaping">Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates</a></li><li>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl">morning and afternoon news emails</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></li></ul><p>Four Olympic medals – including three gold – belonging to one of the members of Australia’s popular “Oarsome Foursome” rowing team have been stolen from a car in Melbourne.</p><p>Victoria police said Drew Ginn’s medals from four consecutive Olympics were in the back of a Land Rover that was parked on Cumberland Street in Docklands when they were stolen last week.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/sep/11/drew-ginn-olympics-medals-stolen-rower-ntwnfb">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/sep/11/drew-ginn-olympics-medals-stolen-rower-ntwnfb</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/sep/11/drew-ginn-olympics-medals-stolen-rower-ntwnfb</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 01:56:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Driving erratically’: Big rig driver arrested after several calls in Merced County]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/driving-erratically-big-rig-driver-233943218.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/driving-erratically-big-rig-driver-233943218.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 23:39:43 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>