<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:14:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:14:54 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rs 3760 cr! Anil Ambani's 'zero debt' Reliance Group firm bags big financing from THIS Maharatna PSU - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anil Ambani's Reliance Power Secures ₹3760 Crore Financing from Maharatna PSU</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ET Now</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Anil Ambani Reliance Power">
<figcaption>Anil Ambani-led Reliance Power secures financing</figcaption>
<p>Reliance Power, led by Anil Ambani, has secured a significant financing of ₹3760 crore from the Power Finance Corporation (PFC) after recently achieving zero debt status.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The financing will be made available in one or more tranches.</li>
  <li>The funds will be used for general corporate purposes and future investments in renewable energy projects.</li>
  <li>Reliance Power's net worth has increased significantly, reporting ₹14,393 crore for the quarter ending September 2024.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Rosa Power has become a zero-debt company by prepaying ₹485 crore loan to Varde Partners.”</blockquote>
<p>This financing indicates Reliance Power's strategic move towards expanding its renewable energy capabilities while maintaining its commitment to a debt-free operation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/companies/rs-3760-cr-anil-ambanis-zero-debt-reliance-group-firm-bags-big-financing-from-this-maharatna-psu-article-116744338</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/companies/rs-3760-cr-anil-ambanis-zero-debt-reliance-group-firm-bags-big-financing-from-this-maharatna-psu-article-116744338</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:19:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jio Financial Services Share Price: A better stock for long term investment? Market expert Gaurang Shah answers - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is Jio Financial Services a Smart Long-Term Investment? Insights from Market Expert Gaurang Shah</h1><p><strong>Updated Dec 28, 2024</strong> by ET NOW</p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-116744046,updatedat-1735391549682,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/116744046.jpg" alt="jio financial services2"><figcaption>Gaurang Shah of Geojit Financial Services gave an optimistic long-term outlook for Jio Financial Services. (Image: Shutterstock/ET NOW News)</figcaption><p>Market expert Gaurang Shah provides an optimistic perspective on the potential of Jio Financial Services for long-term investors, emphasizing the importance of patience and strategic investment timing.</p><ul><li>Gaurang Shah from Geojit Financial Services shares a positive long-term outlook for Jio Financial Services.</li><li>He stresses a timeframe of 1.5 to 2 years for significant developments due to regulatory processes.</li><li>Investors are advised to hold shares and consider increasing their investments at specific price levels.</li><li>New investors should start accumulating shares for a long-term vision.</li></ul><blockquote>"We do have positive coverage on Jio Financial Services from a long term point of view... our sense is that you need to have at least one and a half, 2 year plus of, kind of time horizon." - Gaurang Shah</blockquote><p>The article highlights Shah's advice for both current and potential investors in Jio Financial Services, focusing on the necessary patience required to see significant impacts from the company's ongoing developments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/jio-financial-services-share-price-a-better-stock-for-long-term-investment-market-expert-gaurang-shah-answers-article-116743962</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/jio-financial-services-share-price-a-better-stock-for-long-term-investment-market-expert-gaurang-shah-answers-article-116743962</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:12:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upcoming IPO: Payments solution provider Seshaasai Technologies files DRHP with SEBI to raise funds via public issue | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Seshaasai Technologies Files IPO to Raise ₹600 Crore</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Seshaasai Technologies Limited, a Mumbai-based payments solutions provider, has submitted its draft red herring prospectus (DRHP) to SEBI to raise funds of ₹600 crore through a public issue.</p><ul><li>The company specializes in technology for contactless payments, customer communication, and smart traceability across various sectors including education and transport.</li><li>Approximately ₹195.328 crore will be used for expanding manufacturing units, while ₹300 crore will be allocated to repay outstanding borrowings.</li><li>The offer includes an offer-for-sale component where two key individuals will sell around 39.37 lakh equity shares each.</li><li>Seshaasai Technologies posted a net profit of ₹40.48 crore for Q1 of FY 2024-25.</li><li>The company reported a profit of ₹169.27 crore for FY 2023, significant growth from previous years.</li></ul><blockquote>"The loss of key customers may adversely affect the company's business," the firm disclosed in its regulatory filings.</blockquote><p>Seshaasai Technologies aims to leverage this public fundraising to bolster its operations and mitigate existing debt, projecting a strong outlook in the competitive payments solutions market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/upcoming-ipo-payments-solution-provider-seshaasai-technologies-files-drhp-with-sebi-to-raise-funds-via-ipo-11735386975014.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/upcoming-ipo-payments-solution-provider-seshaasai-technologies-files-drhp-with-sebi-to-raise-funds-via-ipo-11735386975014.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:56:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telcos investment recovery in limbo as tariff hike backfires, price war with satcom services likely in 202 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telcos investment recovery in limbo as tariff hike backfires, price war with satcom services likely in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>The article discusses the challenges faced by private telecom operators in India as they struggle with investment recovery due to subscriber loss from tariff hikes and competition from satellite broadband services.</p><ul><li>Private telcos invested around Rs 70,000 crore in telecom infrastructure this year.</li><li>Tariff hikes led to a loss of 2 crore subscribers.</li><li>Key players like Reliance Jio, Bharti Airtel, and Vodafone Idea experienced a combined loss of 2.6 crore customers.</li><li>BSNL gained 68 customers while refraining from price hikes.</li><li>The government is considering spectrum allocation to satellite broadband providers without auctions.</li><li>Potential price wars may emerge affecting telecom financial health.</li></ul><blockquote>“5G deployment has been a game-changer... significant surge in 5G base transceiver stations.” - DIPA</blockquote><p>The telecom sector faces various challenges that could affect its growth, with a balance needed between tariff rationalization and maintaining subscriber experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/telecom/telecom-news/telcos-investment-recovery-in-limbo-as-tariff-hike-backfires-price-war-with-satcom-services-likely-in-2025/articleshow/116743630.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/telecom/telecom-news/telcos-investment-recovery-in-limbo-as-tariff-hike-backfires-price-war-with-satcom-services-likely-in-2025/articleshow/116743630.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:51:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telcos investment recovery in limbo as tariff hike backfires, price war with satcom services likely in 2025 | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telcos investment recovery in limbo as tariff hike backfires, price war with satcom services likely in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified&nbsp;|&nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Private telecom operators in India are struggling with recovering investments due to customer losses after tariff hikes and competition from satellite service providers like Starlink.</p><ul><li>Private operators invested around ₹70,000 crore in telecom infrastructure this year.</li><li>Subscriber loss reached about 2.6 crore due to a price increase of 10-26%.</li><li>BSNL gained customers by refraining from tariff increases.</li><li>The push for 5G services highlights the need for operators to attract and maintain customer interest.</li><li>Concerns grow over satellite broadband threatening the market share of existing telecom companies.</li><li>Political implications arise from spectrum allocation controversies.</li></ul><blockquote>“5G deployment has been a game-changer. We've witnessed a significant surge in 5G base transceiver stations.” - DIPA</blockquote><p>The telecom sector faces a critical juncture as it navigates investment recovery, subscriber retention, and emerging competition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/telcos-investment-recovery-in-limbo-as-tariff-hike-backfires-price-war-with-satcom-services-likely-in-2025-11735389471111.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/telcos-investment-recovery-in-limbo-as-tariff-hike-backfires-price-war-with-satcom-services-likely-in-2025-11735389471111.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:37:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PPI interoperability: How RBI’s new UPI rule set to ease digital payments? An explainer | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PPIs Interoperability: How RBI’s New UPI Rule Set to Ease Digital Payments? An Explainer</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has enabled users of prepaid payment instruments (PPIs) to access UPI services through third-party applications, a significant step to enhance the digital payment ecosystem in India.</p><h2>Key Differences: UPI and PPIs</h2><ul><li>UPI allows bank-to-bank money transfers, while PPIs are mobile wallets with pre-loaded funds.</li><li>Interoperability between PPIs and UPI is now permitted, allowing easier transactions across platforms.</li></ul><h2>Current Ecosystem</h2><ul><li>Some PPIs like PhonePe and MobiKwik already had limited UPI access.</li><li>The new rule will expand UPI usage to third-party apps.</li></ul><h2>Users' New Flexibility</h2><ul><li>PPI users can now use any third-party UPI app for transactions.</li><li>This follows the RBI's plan announced in April 2024 for broader PPI integration.</li></ul><blockquote>“UPI’s popularity... will likely encourage more users to adopt digital wallets.” – Ankush Julka, COO, Mufin Pay</blockquote><p>This new rule from RBI aims to significantly boost the ease of digital payments in India, benefiting users with greater flexibility and broader integration with payment systems.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/ppi-interoperability-how-rbi-s-new-upi-rule-set-to-ease-digital-payments-an-explainer-11735386893536.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/ppi-interoperability-how-rbi-s-new-upi-rule-set-to-ease-digital-payments-an-explainer-11735386893536.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:11:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cochin Shipyard bags Adani Ports tug boat order, deal value estimated at ₹450 crore - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cochin Shipyard Wins ₹450 Crore Tug Boat Order from Adani Ports</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, Source: Live Mint</p>
<p>Adani Ports has ordered eight tug boats from Cochin Shipyard Ltd, valued at ₹450 crore, to enhance its maritime infrastructure.</p>
<img src="path_to_image.jpg" alt="Cochin Shipyard" />
<figcaption>Cochin Shipyard's Tug Boat</figcaption>
<p>The order consists of eight 70 T Bollard Pull ASD Tugs, expected to be delivered from December 2026 to August 2028.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Adani Ports and SEZ orders eight tug boats from Cochin Shipyard.</li>
  <li>The deal is valued at ₹450 crore, falling under the “Significant” category of ₹200 to ₹500 crore.</li>
  <li>Tug deliveries are set to begin in December 2026.</li>
  <li>This order will expand Adani's tug boat fleet to 152.</li>
  <li>Adani aims to strengthen local manufacturing with this collaboration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This collaboration signifies our commitment to enhancing maritime infrastructure in India and demonstrates our confidence in our nation's PSUs.” - Ashwani Gupta, CEO of Adani Ports</blockquote>
<p>This significant order highlights the growing cooperation between private companies and public sector units in India’s maritime sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/cochin-shipyard-bags-adani-ports-tug-boat-order-deal-value-estimated-at-rs-450-crore-11735382563877.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/cochin-shipyard-bags-adani-ports-tug-boat-order-deal-value-estimated-at-rs-450-crore-11735382563877.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:26:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cochin Shipyard bags Adani Ports tug boat order, deal value estimated at ₹450 crore | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cochin Shipyard Wins ₹450 Crore Tug Boat Order from Adani Ports</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, Source: Live Mint</p>
<p>Adani Ports has ordered eight tug boats from Cochin Shipyard Ltd, valued at ₹450 crore, to enhance its maritime infrastructure.</p>
<img src="path_to_image.jpg" alt="Cochin Shipyard" />
<figcaption>Cochin Shipyard's Tug Boat</figcaption>
<p>The order consists of eight 70 T Bollard Pull ASD Tugs, expected to be delivered from December 2026 to August 2028.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Adani Ports and SEZ orders eight tug boats from Cochin Shipyard.</li>
  <li>The deal is valued at ₹450 crore, falling under the “Significant” category of ₹200 to ₹500 crore.</li>
  <li>Tug deliveries are set to begin in December 2026.</li>
  <li>This order will expand Adani's tug boat fleet to 152.</li>
  <li>Adani aims to strengthen local manufacturing with this collaboration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This collaboration signifies our commitment to enhancing maritime infrastructure in India and demonstrates our confidence in our nation's PSUs.” - Ashwani Gupta, CEO of Adani Ports</blockquote>
<p>This significant order highlights the growing cooperation between private companies and public sector units in India’s maritime sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/cochin-shipyard-bags-adani-ports-tug-boat-order-deal-value-estimated-at-rs-450-crore-11735382563877.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/cochin-shipyard-bags-adani-ports-tug-boat-order-deal-value-estimated-at-rs-450-crore-11735382563877.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:26:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IPO calendar next week: 2 new issues, 6 listings to close out a robust year of primary market - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IPO Calendar Next Week: 2 New Issues and 6 Listings to End a Strong Year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>It's been a remarkable year for India's IPO market, and as we enter the last week of 2024, two IPOs from Indo Farm Equipment and Technichem Organics will close out what is the most vibrant year for the primary market.</p><ul><li>Two new IPOs are on the table: Indo Farm Equipment and Technichem Organics.</li><li>Indo Farm Equipment's IPO will open on December 31 and conclude on January 2.</li><li>The price band for Indo Farm Equipment is set at Rs 204-215.</li><li>Technichem Organics is available for bidding until January 2, priced at Rs 52-55 per share.</li><li>This year, Indian companies have raised a record Rs 1.3 lakh crore through IPOs.</li><li>Analysts expect the fundraising momentum to continue into 2025, potentially exceeding Rs 2 lakh crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“This year, companies have cumulatively raised a record Rs 1.3 lakh crore,” experts say.</blockquote><p>The IPO landscape is expected to remain vibrant as we transition into the next year, with significant opportunities for investors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/ipos/fpos/ipo-calendar-next-week-2-new-issues-6-listings-to-close-out-a-robust-year-of-primary-market/articleshow/116740426.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/ipos/fpos/ipo-calendar-next-week-2-new-issues-6-listings-to-close-out-a-robust-year-of-primary-market/articleshow/116740426.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:46:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Time To Say Good-Bye To India’s Favourite Brand? - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxPQXpIQ1lUUHY2N3JFR214eUduV0ZFY1FWM3BwWEdWUTFvR2RVd0VVUlJHSmtIOXJTRFBqMWc5cTljUldHSFRrNjV4TmZpNTFmZ0dFT3czVlNTMUR5Z0g3RC1UVFFLemFQUmVMU2JCZFR6Rk55YmZRbU9pLW16ajc1MkhMS2VGc0haNGfSAYoBQVVfeXFMT0F6SENZVFB2NjdyRUdteHlHbldGRWNRVjNwcFhHVlExb0dkVXdFVVJSR0prSDlyU0RQajFnOXE5Y1JXR0hUazY1eE5maTUxZmdHRU93M1ZTUzFEeWdIN0QtVFRRS3phUFJlTFNiQmRUekZOeWJmUW1PaS1temo3NTJITEtlRnNIWjRn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxPQXpIQ1lUUHY2N3JFR214eUduV0ZFY1FWM3BwWEdWUTFvR2RVd0VVUlJHSmtIOXJTRFBqMWc5cTljUldHSFRrNjV4TmZpNTFmZ0dFT3czVlNTMUR5Z0g3RC1UVFFLemFQUmVMU2JCZFR6Rk55YmZRbU9pLW16ajc1MkhMS2VGc0haNGfSAYoBQVVfeXFMT0F6SENZVFB2NjdyRUdteHlHbldGRWNRVjNwcFhHVlExb0dkVXdFVVJSR0prSDlyU0RQajFnOXE5Y1JXR0hUazY1eE5maTUxZmdHRU93M1ZTUzFEeWdIN0QtVFRRS3phUFJlTFNiQmRUekZOeWJmUW1PaS1temo3NTJITEtlRnNIWjRn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:21:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vodafone Group clears about Rs 11,650 cr dues raised against VIL shares - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vodafone Clears Rs 11,650 Crore Dues from VIL Shares</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 28 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Press Trust of India</p>
<img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" title="Vodafone" alt="Vodafone" width="826" height="465">
<figcaption>Vodafone has cleared dues against VIL shares.</figcaption>
<p>UK-based Vodafone Group has successfully cleared dues of approximately Rs 11,650 crore against shares of Vodafone Idea Limited (VIL), reaffirming its financial commitments.</p>
<ul>
<li>Vodafone had pledged nearly its entire stake in VIL to secure the debt.</li>
<li>The dues were cleared as of December 27, 2024, through HSBC Corporate Trustee Company (UK).</li>
<li>The shares in question are valued at around Rs 11,649 crore based on the closing price of Rs 7.41 per share.</li>
<li>Vodafone holds a 22.56% stake in VIL, while Aditya Birla Group and the government hold 14.76% and 23.15% shares respectively.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Consequently, the indirect encumbrance on 15,720,826,860 equity shares... has been released."</blockquote>
<p>This clearance demonstrates Vodafone's ongoing strategy to stabilize its finances and potentially strengthen its position in the Indian telecom market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/vodafone-group-clears-about-rs-11-650-cr-dues-raised-against-vil-shares-124122800394_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/vodafone-group-clears-about-rs-11-650-cr-dues-raised-against-vil-shares-124122800394_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:06:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Greaves Electric Mobility IPO: Rs 1000 cr! Vijay Kedia-backed company's EV arm to list soon - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Greaves Electric Mobility IPO: Rs 1000 crore!</h1>
<p><strong>Updated:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW News</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Greaves Electric Mobility IPO" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Greaves Electric Mobility IPO: Vijay Kedia bought 12 lakh shares for Rs 25 crore via a block deal on December 9.</figcaption>
<p>Greaves Electric Mobility Limited (GEML) has filed a draft red herring prospectus (DRHP) to raise Rs 1,000 crore through an initial public offering (IPO). The company is a subsidiary of Greaves Cotton and manufacturing electric vehicles like Ampere, Eltra, and Ele.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The IPO will consist of a fresh issue of equity shares of up to Rs 1,000 crore.</li>
  <li>Vijay Kedia recently acquired 0.52% stake in Greaves Cotton by purchasing 12 lakh shares for Rs 25 crore.</li>
  <li>Greaves Cotton will sell up to 5.1 crore shares while Abdul Latif Jameel Green Mobility Solutions will sell up to 13.83 crore shares.</li>
  <li>The company may also consider a pre-IPO placement aggregating up to Rs 200 crore before filing of the red herring prospectus.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The average buying price was Rs 208.9 per share. This comes after the company approved an IPO for its subsidiary, GEML."</blockquote>
<p>This IPO represents a significant move for Greaves Electric Mobility as it positions itself within the growing EV market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/greaves-electric-mobility-ipo-rs-1000-cr-vijay-kedia-backed-company-greaves-cotton-share-price-ev-arm-to-list-soon-article-116733464</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/greaves-electric-mobility-ipo-rs-1000-cr-vijay-kedia-backed-company-greaves-cotton-share-price-ev-arm-to-list-soon-article-116733464</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:39:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Mutual Funds: These equity schemes across market cap gave highest returns in the past 1 year. Do you own any? | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Best Mutual Funds: These equity schemes across market cap gave highest returns in the past 1 year. Do you own any?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>This article evaluates the top-performing mutual fund schemes across various market capitalizations, highlighting their past one-year returns and emphasizing the importance of considering additional factors beyond returns when investing.</p>
<h2>Key Points:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The DSP Top 100 Equity Fund reported the highest return of 22.24% among large cap funds.</li>
<li>Nippon India Large Cap Fund has significant assets under management (AUM) of ₹35,779 crore with a return of 19.75%.</li>
<li>In the mid cap segment, Invesco India Mid Cap Fund leads with a return of 44.48%.</li>
<li>The small cap category is topped by Bandhan Small Cap Fund with returns over 44%.</li>
<li>Past performance is not indicative of future results, and investors should always consider a scheme's overall metrics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Past returns give no guarantee of a scheme’s future returns."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while these mutual funds have shown impressive gains, it is essential to conduct thorough research and consider various factors before making investment decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/best-mutual-funds-these-equity-schemes-across-market-cap-gave-highest-returns-in-the-past-1-year-do-you-own-any-11735377183159.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/best-mutual-funds-these-equity-schemes-across-market-cap-gave-highest-returns-in-the-past-1-year-do-you-own-any-11735377183159.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:30:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hit and miss in 2024, but what's the future for India's Rs 8,000 crore-plus IPOs - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxNdVlVMW1kYWVSMUFrMW9XRHFUWWEzV2FPc0ZURVdJNjFBYUFHOWg5SnFxS2lpNGE3YnU2UE9XM2VpWHNWX1ZsRUF5SldpUE5oUWxMM1pzMl9vOWF5TFFITmFITEtkbGgxMTRzXzlmX096eEFGaUNuZHY4aGU2TG1RV2gzQzNITkRpS1BvN3JsT05uOFpLUnd5MEpaZXpsZDNzS1RaQ0ZzOTZBRENEakFkVU9TS3BWQjlPRG8tM1FQeHllbDdWVVYwTDViQkRGVmRnY1Uwd0I3UXctY2w5cFJkVmxaU1nSAeoBQVVfeXFMUElseVVLdkFMRlIwM2RCMTNlQkNYdTI0MVZwd2tiS3B4OGN2TFprSHBXUXhhQ2tqZ2JzQ2NiUGJJSEJtc0tLWUNRNkFIbFRMYlI2Z3hKZVNfWnlzS0pUVXJtRE9aS1V3Y2l3Q1FfVFBLZE5jbVh4cmJZbFFQTW9ydklpdi1GTGp6cXItRklKcHk0NzdtdndaTEdCSEwtclVoelpzWHdrcHZaVDYtWEMxTVNmLVBQVGpKU1dubV9oMmNTbGs5SXhuR0otckNRVy05SXVhMDZlWmNzMko2Y0xlNjFkTTNDM2I1N2ln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxNdVlVMW1kYWVSMUFrMW9XRHFUWWEzV2FPc0ZURVdJNjFBYUFHOWg5SnFxS2lpNGE3YnU2UE9XM2VpWHNWX1ZsRUF5SldpUE5oUWxMM1pzMl9vOWF5TFFITmFITEtkbGgxMTRzXzlmX096eEFGaUNuZHY4aGU2TG1RV2gzQzNITkRpS1BvN3JsT05uOFpLUnd5MEpaZXpsZDNzS1RaQ0ZzOTZBRENEakFkVU9TS3BWQjlPRG8tM1FQeHllbDdWVVYwTDViQkRGVmRnY1Uwd0I3UXctY2w5cFJkVmxaU1nSAeoBQVVfeXFMUElseVVLdkFMRlIwM2RCMTNlQkNYdTI0MVZwd2tiS3B4OGN2TFprSHBXUXhhQ2tqZ2JzQ2NiUGJJSEJtc0tLWUNRNkFIbFRMYlI2Z3hKZVNfWnlzS0pUVXJtRE9aS1V3Y2l3Q1FfVFBLZE5jbVh4cmJZbFFQTW9ydklpdi1GTGp6cXItRklKcHk0NzdtdndaTEdCSEwtclVoelpzWHdrcHZaVDYtWEMxTVNmLVBQVGpKU1dubV9oMmNTbGs5SXhuR0otckNRVy05SXVhMDZlWmNzMko2Y0xlNjFkTTNDM2I1N2ln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:55:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4 SUVs To Buy Instead Of Tata Punch! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>4 SUVs To Consider Instead of Tata Punch</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> MotorOctane</p><img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/twilight-purple-right.webp" alt="Tata Nexon" /><figcaption>Tata Nexon</figcaption><p>The Tata Punch is highly sought after in India due to its value and safety features. However, consumers are exploring alternatives. Here are four SUVs that serve as alternatives to the Tata Punch.</p><ul><li><strong>Tata Nexon:</strong> A larger, safer option priced from Rs 9.40 lakh (on-road, Mumbai).</li><li><strong>Mahindra XUV3XO:</strong> Offers powerful engine options and features starting from Rs 9.16 lakh.</li><li><strong>Skoda Kylaq:</strong> Known for its features and safety, priced from Rs 9.07 lakh.</li><li><strong>Nissan Magnite:</strong> Affordable option starting from Rs 7.04 lakh, providing better features than before.</li></ul><blockquote>“The new Nissan Magnite is now offered with all features that it lacked in its previous iterations.”</blockquote><p>These alternatives provide various features, pricing, and performance capabilities, making them strong competitors against the Tata Punch.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/281549-4-suvs-to-buy-instead-of-tata-punch</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/281549-4-suvs-to-buy-instead-of-tata-punch</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance acquires Karkinos Healthcare for Rs 375 crore - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Reliance Acquires Karkinos Healthcare for Rs 375 Crore</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Saturday</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>The acquisition of Karkinos Healthcare by Reliance Industries marks a significant move in the oncology-focused healthcare sector, aiming to enhance early cancer detection and management.</p><ul><li>Reliance Industries acquired Karkinos Healthcare for Rs 375 crore.</li><li>Karkinos, founded on July 24, 2020, specializes in early cancer detection and treatment solutions.</li><li>The company partnered with around 60 hospitals and is developing a 150-bed cancer hospital in Imphal, Manipur.</li><li>The acquisition enhances Reliance's health services portfolio and was approved by the National Company Law Tribunal (NCLT).</li></ul><blockquote>"The acquisition of Karkinos will help expand the health services business portfolio of the Reliance group," the filing said.</blockquote><p>The acquisition of Karkinos represents a strategic expansion of Reliance's healthcare services, targeting the growing need for cancer care in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/healthcare/biotech/healthcare/reliance-acquires-karkinos-healthcare-for-rs-375-crore/articleshow/116736741.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/healthcare/biotech/healthcare/reliance-acquires-karkinos-healthcare-for-rs-375-crore/articleshow/116736741.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:22:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India begins construction of first AI-enabled semiconductor plant in Gujarat - Communications Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.communicationstoday.co.in/india-begins-construction-of-first-ai-enabled-semiconductor-plant-in-gujarat/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.communicationstoday.co.in/india-begins-construction-of-first-ai-enabled-semiconductor-plant-in-gujarat/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:53:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rs 12468 cr! Largest-ever acquisition by JSW Energy - Details - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rs 12468 cr! Largest-ever acquisition by JSW Energy - Details</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> <strong>Dec 28, 2024</strong> by <strong>ET Now</strong></p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="JSW Energy Largest Acquisition" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>JSW Energy's largest acquisition announcement.</figcaption>
<p>JSW Energy, a leading renewable energy company, has announced its largest-ever acquisition, taking over a 4,696 MW renewable energy platform from O2 Power.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The acquisition is valued at approximately Rs 12,468 crore, subject to CCI approval.</li>
  <li>O2 Power is a partnership between EQT Infrastructure and Temasek.</li>
  <li>The acquisition will increase JSW Energy's generation capacity by 23%, boosting it from 20,012 MW to 24,708 MW.</li>
  <li>2,259 MW of this capacity will be operational by June 2025, with additional capacities scheduled by 2027.</li>
  <li>Shares of JSW Energy saw a slight decline of nearly 2% post-announcement.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This landmark acquisition strengthens our positioning as a leading player in India’s energy sector." - Sharad Mahendra, Managing Director and CEO of JSW Energy</blockquote>
<p>This acquisition marks a significant milestone for JSW Energy, positioning it strategically in the expanding renewable energy sector in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/companies/rs-12468-cr-largest-ever-acquisition-by-jsw-energy-details-article-116734018</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/companies/rs-12468-cr-largest-ever-acquisition-by-jsw-energy-details-article-116734018</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:19:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dhirubhai Ambani birth anniversary: 10 quotes that are important life lessons - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxOem9hdUlEY19aaUtpclgzbmFlT1hXRnNuQmNvcEVmRm9EZm1xcVJSbi1xb1lGRmtmS201ZWtuMVJ0eVZ2MFFqZmxqdHA3czNPQXJhZzhPUlNhT1RkM24tUGVQZ05VMEtaQzZ5ZldnWlFZV3YzclNOUHlfckk2X0NaRzJ4elFETFdlQXhaXy04MHM4ZkVkLUloRkdWWDE1cTZzWW11aks2U1JRdFdKakZUTUx2T3hXbGFyUnJxZXZfV2NMU2JqSXJRTkZ4MDFlVHRCZ0Nra2tycUo5OTNBaUtQN1ZiaG1tWmlZbkZpNGxaZ1JJS2RtNW9ldGt4enplN3huTkhFYtIBhAJBVV95cUxOem9hdUlEY19aaUtpclgzbmFlT1hXRnNuQmNvcEVmRm9EZm1xcVJSbi1xb1lGRmtmS201ZWtuMVJ0eVZ2MFFqZmxqdHA3czNPQXJhZzhPUlNhT1RkM24tUGVQZ05VMEtaQzZ5ZldnWlFZV3YzclNOUHlfckk2X0NaRzJ4elFETFdlQXhaXy04MHM4ZkVkLUloRkdWWDE1cTZzWW11aks2U1JRdFdKakZUTUx2T3hXbGFyUnJxZXZfV2NMU2JqSXJRTkZ4MDFlVHRCZ0Nra2tycUo5OTNBaUtQN1ZiaG1tWmlZbkZpNGxaZ1JJS2RtNW9ldGt4enplN3huTkhFYg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxOem9hdUlEY19aaUtpclgzbmFlT1hXRnNuQmNvcEVmRm9EZm1xcVJSbi1xb1lGRmtmS201ZWtuMVJ0eVZ2MFFqZmxqdHA3czNPQXJhZzhPUlNhT1RkM24tUGVQZ05VMEtaQzZ5ZldnWlFZV3YzclNOUHlfckk2X0NaRzJ4elFETFdlQXhaXy04MHM4ZkVkLUloRkdWWDE1cTZzWW11aks2U1JRdFdKakZUTUx2T3hXbGFyUnJxZXZfV2NMU2JqSXJRTkZ4MDFlVHRCZ0Nra2tycUo5OTNBaUtQN1ZiaG1tWmlZbkZpNGxaZ1JJS2RtNW9ldGt4enplN3huTkhFYtIBhAJBVV95cUxOem9hdUlEY19aaUtpclgzbmFlT1hXRnNuQmNvcEVmRm9EZm1xcVJSbi1xb1lGRmtmS201ZWtuMVJ0eVZ2MFFqZmxqdHA3czNPQXJhZzhPUlNhT1RkM24tUGVQZ05VMEtaQzZ5ZldnWlFZV3YzclNOUHlfckk2X0NaRzJ4elFETFdlQXhaXy04MHM4ZkVkLUloRkdWWDE1cTZzWW11aks2U1JRdFdKakZUTUx2T3hXbGFyUnJxZXZfV2NMU2JqSXJRTkZ4MDFlVHRCZ0Nra2tycUo5OTNBaUtQN1ZiaG1tWmlZbkZpNGxaZ1JJS2RtNW9ldGt4enplN3huTkhFYg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:45:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 stocks with record dates for dividends, bonuses, splits, rights issue next week. Do you own? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>12 stocks with record dates for dividends, bonuses, splits, rights issue next week. Do you own?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><figure><img height="158" width="210" alt="12 stocks with record dates for dividends, bonuses, splits, rights issue next week. Do you own?" src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116733956,width-210,height-158,imgsize-77238,resizemode-75/12-stocks-with-record-dates-for-dividends-bonuses-splits-rights-issue-next-week-do-you-own.jpg"><figcaption>KPI Green Energy and RedTape and several other companies are set to draw attention in the upcoming week.</figcaption></figure><p>Several companies, including KPI Green Energy and RedTape, have upcoming record dates for corporate actions. Investors must hold shares before the ex-date to qualify for dividends, bonuses, or splits. The T+1 settlement system generally aligns record and ex-dates, but exceptions may occur due to market holidays.</p><ul><li>Investors need to ensure shares are in their demat account by the record date.</li><li>If shares are bought on the ex-date, investors do not qualify for benefits.</li><li>Record and ex-dates typically align unless affected by market holidays.</li></ul><blockquote>“The record date is key for identifying shareholders eligible for these benefits.”</blockquote><p>This week's highlighted stocks include Banco Products for a bonus issue, Harshil Agrotech and others for rights issues, along with various stock splits and dividends announced by Surya Roshni and RedTape. Investors should pay attention to these dates to maximize their benefits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/12-stocks-with-record-dates-for-dividends-bonuses-splits-rights-issue-next-week-do-you-own/articleshow/116733929.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/12-stocks-with-record-dates-for-dividends-bonuses-splits-rights-issue-next-week-do-you-own/articleshow/116733929.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:37:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exciting 500 BHP Indian Sports Car Launching Next Month! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxPWDVNUjl0UnNXTm5TdjhTR200WElpZWtKQm92M2MxSklBbWdjSFFUeXBpM29fcEdjRVlZMl82dDJsMzloYjN3c3I5ZmtXZm5vb2lHYUNSQlA4dnpLQzZoNlNBQVhfOUJYWjNhNFZjUnlhMHhjTzE2RVJIb0tNa3BzSTV6ZjQ2cEk0WnFOOTNOUkxsVUp3T2fSAZYBQVVfeXFMT1g1TVI5dFJzV05uU3Y4U0dtNFhJaWVrSkJvdjNjMUpJQW1nY0hRVHlwaTNvX3BHY0VZWTJfNnQybDM5aGIzd3NyOWZrV2Zub29pR2FDUkJQOHZ6S0M2aDZTQUFYXzlCWFozYTRWY1J5YTB4Y08xNkVSSG9LTWtwc0k1emY0NnBJNFpxTjkzTlJMbFVKd09n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxPWDVNUjl0UnNXTm5TdjhTR200WElpZWtKQm92M2MxSklBbWdjSFFUeXBpM29fcEdjRVlZMl82dDJsMzloYjN3c3I5ZmtXZm5vb2lHYUNSQlA4dnpLQzZoNlNBQVhfOUJYWjNhNFZjUnlhMHhjTzE2RVJIb0tNa3BzSTV6ZjQ2cEk0WnFOOTNOUkxsVUp3T2fSAZYBQVVfeXFMT1g1TVI5dFJzV05uU3Y4U0dtNFhJaWVrSkJvdjNjMUpJQW1nY0hRVHlwaTNvX3BHY0VZWTJfNnQybDM5aGIzd3NyOWZrV2Zub29pR2FDUkJQOHZ6S0M2aDZTQUFYXzlCWFozYTRWY1J5YTB4Y08xNkVSSG9LTWtwc0k1emY0NnBJNFpxTjkzTlJMbFVKd09n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:29:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ratan Tata birth anniversary: 10 inspiring quotes by the man who had a heart of gold - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxQOFluYTdvVWJkR19IQ1hWRmx1ZXJFVVNvVXFBb3hmTzBmTmZOZlMyWEJZRllFcnFBS0k4cHN5S1VIazUtQU9fQjAwaHVZQUtvWG1QTDBLbmJJd2diRTBEUkVLZHA3MDhvUklsM1p1STB3Wm8xWmVvT0dNR0dLaFAyOG50eVplRENLNnNaWjBSWUJ0dXAyRS11eFZLeUlfd21zM2FXRzc3MXQ0UEM5QjFOR1dCdXU3UUJDbi1lQVR2Q2ZaR040R3ZJYTlGTEE5UGo5SUhRNHJHb0VsNUM4Y0p2QlpvYjNiT2hRZTVuUU52UVVueXhOd1BheVZyNWdKdGpaQld6anJUbENGQkQ2NWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxQOFluYTdvVWJkR19IQ1hWRmx1ZXJFVVNvVXFBb3hmTzBmTmZOZlMyWEJZRllFcnFBS0k4cHN5S1VIazUtQU9fQjAwaHVZQUtvWG1QTDBLbmJJd2diRTBEUkVLZHA3MDhvUklsM1p1STB3Wm8xWmVvT0dNR0dLaFAyOG50eVplRENLNnNaWjBSWUJ0dXAyRS11eFZLeUlfd21zM2FXRzc3MXQ0UEM5QjFOR1dCdXU3UUJDbi1lQVR2Q2ZaR040R3ZJYTlGTEE5UGo5SUhRNHJHb0VsNUM4Y0p2QlpvYjNiT2hRZTVuUU52UVVueXhOd1BheVZyNWdKdGpaQld6anJUbENGQkQ2NWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:08:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold price decreases by Rs 120 per sovereign, gram costs Rs 7,135 on Dec 28 in Chennai - DTNEXT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxNcFZOSTZDbllkakl3c0tYV0ViWmhrVDRDYkNvY0xBeFd2aUpWdGxKRFdiV3NQdkdFdHU5X1RlWnNPMFpSR1hqWllKTWc1TVJRbXpfaGJDOS1SMnZ0U1JweWZuRC1NaGVVOHU1c19ZcHIwcGczUm1wWUt4LUE4SnR5M2pKamxTOE8xRDc4emJZX2RQUElaN1BrZzlMNnVFdGYxcEVYNXVPaWV2WGFoVGt4VWxxWTVqYTdUUWlvNEdmS05TNmtGblHSAcsBQVVfeXFMUGhoRGl2MjluUFU2MWNIYUx2WWx0WVUyUldibmxtc2czSk9SSURxX2h5VjRjOWhyRXBwQzhDQTdSQzZyTDVmdFdGWU5KQ2c5R2NOclcxQ2tqb0xLaU9uU0Q0aGNzcXdGb3hLUVVrcV8tdHZUR1lzLVZLS0JSWjl1MVNrLXZUVEVhbFBBTWpJVU5SMnlBMmk2eE1NNDdVTU1CMGNEZGZ0LThiYlZYOGFYZGxnRUs1NXFhNlJKZmU5YjRFWTEydkxEdk1CeVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxNcFZOSTZDbllkakl3c0tYV0ViWmhrVDRDYkNvY0xBeFd2aUpWdGxKRFdiV3NQdkdFdHU5X1RlWnNPMFpSR1hqWllKTWc1TVJRbXpfaGJDOS1SMnZ0U1JweWZuRC1NaGVVOHU1c19ZcHIwcGczUm1wWUt4LUE4SnR5M2pKamxTOE8xRDc4emJZX2RQUElaN1BrZzlMNnVFdGYxcEVYNXVPaWV2WGFoVGt4VWxxWTVqYTdUUWlvNEdmS05TNmtGblHSAcsBQVVfeXFMUGhoRGl2MjluUFU2MWNIYUx2WWx0WVUyUldibmxtc2czSk9SSURxX2h5VjRjOWhyRXBwQzhDQTdSQzZyTDVmdFdGWU5KQ2c5R2NOclcxQ2tqb0xLaU9uU0Q0aGNzcXdGb3hLUVVrcV8tdHZUR1lzLVZLS0JSWjl1MVNrLXZUVEVhbFBBTWpJVU5SMnlBMmk2eE1NNDdVTU1CMGNEZGZ0LThiYlZYOGFYZGxnRUs1NXFhNlJKZmU5YjRFWTEydkxEdk1CeVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:59:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CNG Price Hike in Pune from Today - Punekar News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibkFVX3lxTE9lZkFUWnlnbVc5UlNTY29XaWM1dXFSaDFNd0dtVDFVM1k4bVk3ZFFaZjRlak9PcTcyb1V0MF9zcEZMNU53WndDRVVMLUZyRjFTMC1oazlPR0wzbURxaFJEMTZBSUo1UFNtdkFBM193?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibkFVX3lxTE9lZkFUWnlnbVc5UlNTY29XaWM1dXFSaDFNd0dtVDFVM1k4bVk3ZFFaZjRlak9PcTcyb1V0MF9zcEZMNU53WndDRVVMLUZyRjFTMC1oazlPR0wzbURxaFJEMTZBSUo1UFNtdkFBM193?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:54:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025 stock picks from Religare Broking with up to 29% upside potential - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2025 Stock Picks from Religare Broking with Up to 29% Upside Potential</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116732538,width-640,resizemode-4,imgsize-33044/stock-picks.jpg" alt="Stock Picks"><figcaption>The Indian stock market has delivered a strong performance in 2024, with notable gains across major indices. Both Nifty and Sensex have risen for the ninth consecutive year, recording an approximate 9% growth year-to-date.</figcaption><p>As we enter 2025, global markets may be shaped by shifts in U.S. trade policies, geopolitical resolutions, and a recovery in corporate earnings, supported by increased government spending and easing inflation, says a report by domestic brokerage firm Religare Broking. These factors set the stage for opportunities and challenges. Religare has identified 6 fundamentally strong stocks across various sectors poised for robust performance in 2025 with up to 29% upside:</p><ul><li><strong>HDFC Bank:</strong> Buy range: 1,720-1,810 | Target: Rs 1,920-2,008 | Upside: 11%</li><li><strong>LIC:</strong> Buy range: Rs 840-900 | Target: Rs 1,045-1,160 | Upside: 29%</li><li><strong>DLF:</strong> Buy range: Rs 800-850 | Target: Rs 960-1,050 | Upside: 23.5%</li><li><strong>Samvardhana Motherson:</strong> Buy range: Rs 145-160 | Target: Rs 175-195 | Upside: 22%</li><li><strong>Amara Raja:</strong> Buy range: 1,080-1,200 | Target: Rs 1,350-1,440 | Upside: 20%</li><li><strong>Senco Gold:</strong> Buy range: Rs 1,010-1,080 | Target: Rs 1,200-1,330 | Upside: 23%</li></ul><blockquote>“Recommendations, suggestions, views, and opinions given by the experts are their own. These do not represent the views of The Economic Times.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the identifiable stocks by Religare Broking present potential for investors as 2025 approaches, leveraging the anticipated improvements in the global economy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/2025-stock-picks-from-religare-broking-with-up-to-29-upside-potential/slideshow/116732538.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/2025-stock-picks-from-religare-broking-with-up-to-29-upside-potential/slideshow/116732538.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:39:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 5 small cap mutual funds which performed better than their benchmark in 3 years - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxONlZzLXNnODVMZHl0VXdHVW1SOGlONGN4NlI4RUE0MmR3a3R6YzZIV1FXVTk3U2xUejVCUkxvNzFtSTVFa0Uwb3ZMSXFCb3FIYVl6VlhWSDV2M1kyUDh5RVkxaF92NEh6QjU3Mkdka3BxVmRPV2tDQlljdnM2WFYyQzBTcHF5ejFpWlIyVnM5VDhycGpfa1ZubDBUNkNSTThXNU1WeTNva3JzcWxEU2Jrcm0tdnhndldCcExpRGsxWDNDamR5MElFclREZFp2SG4zSTkwdzVmRU9nVGd2TjBxQXpCcnPSAeQBQVVfeXFMTjZWcy1zZzg1TGR5dFV3R1VtUjhpTjRjeDZSOEVBNDJkd2t0emM2SFdRV1U5N1NsVHo1QlJMbzcxbUk1RWtFMG92TElxQm9xSGFZelZYVkg1djNZMlA4eUVZMWhfdjRIekI1NzJHZGtwcVZkT1drQ0JZY3ZzNlhWMkMwU3BxeXoxaVpSMlZzOVQ4cnBqX2tWbmwwVDZDUk04VzVNVnkzb2tyc3FsRFNia3JtLXZ4Z3ZXQnBMaURrMVgzQ2pkeTBJRXJURGRadkhuM0k5MHc1ZkVPZ1Rndk4wcUF6QnJz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxONlZzLXNnODVMZHl0VXdHVW1SOGlONGN4NlI4RUE0MmR3a3R6YzZIV1FXVTk3U2xUejVCUkxvNzFtSTVFa0Uwb3ZMSXFCb3FIYVl6VlhWSDV2M1kyUDh5RVkxaF92NEh6QjU3Mkdka3BxVmRPV2tDQlljdnM2WFYyQzBTcHF5ejFpWlIyVnM5VDhycGpfa1ZubDBUNkNSTThXNU1WeTNva3JzcWxEU2Jrcm0tdnhndldCcExpRGsxWDNDamR5MElFclREZFp2SG4zSTkwdzVmRU9nVGd2TjBxQXpCcnPSAeQBQVVfeXFMTjZWcy1zZzg1TGR5dFV3R1VtUjhpTjRjeDZSOEVBNDJkd2t0emM2SFdRV1U5N1NsVHo1QlJMbzcxbUk1RWtFMG92TElxQm9xSGFZelZYVkg1djNZMlA4eUVZMWhfdjRIekI1NzJHZGtwcVZkT1drQ0JZY3ZzNlhWMkMwU3BxeXoxaVpSMlZzOVQ4cnBqX2tWbmwwVDZDUk04VzVNVnkzb2tyc3FsRFNia3JtLXZ4Z3ZXQnBMaURrMVgzQ2pkeTBJRXJURGRadkhuM0k5MHc1ZkVPZ1Rndk4wcUF6QnJz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:39:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Picks for 2025: DOMS, Prestige, Ethos, Fortis, Cipla and more | Axis Securities recommendations - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/stock-picks-for-2025-doms-prestige-ethos-fortis-cipla-and-more-axis-securities-recommendations-article-116731331</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/stock-picks-for-2025-doms-prestige-ethos-fortis-cipla-and-more-axis-securities-recommendations-article-116731331</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:35:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 high growth sectors to watch for maximum investment returns in 2025 - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 High Growth Sectors to Watch for Maximum Investment Returns in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p><p>The world is rapidly going digital, creating fresh opportunities for innovation and growth. In October 2024, India saw 7.42 billion UPI transactions, highlighting the country's shift towards digital services. Financial literacy and inclusion have increased access to formal financial services, making India an attractive market for global investors.</p><ul><li><strong>Banking & Financial Services:</strong> The fintech market in India is expected to grow at a CAGR of 20% by 2030, with a focus on mid-sized private banks.</li><li><strong>Information Technology:</strong> Indian IT firms are essential to global digital transformation with a market size of $245 billion.</li><li><strong>Consumer Goods:</strong> The FMCG market is projected to reach $220 billion by 2025, driven by the middle class's spending power.</li><li><strong>Healthcare & Pharmaceuticals:</strong> India holds 20% of the global generic drug market, with potential for growth in biotechnology and telemedicine.</li><li><strong>Infrastructure & Capital Goods:</strong> With a government investment plan of ₹111 lakh crore, the infrastructure sector is geared for growth.</li><li><strong>Real Estate:</strong> Demand for luxury properties is rising, especially in key urban regions.</li></ul><blockquote>“By aligning your portfolio with these growth-driving sectors, you can capitalize on opportunities shaping India’s economic future.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, keeping an eye on these sectors can help investors leverage potential growth areas as India moves towards a more digitally-savvy economy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/money/6-high-growth-sectors-to-watch-for-maximum-investment-returns-in-2025-3702037/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/money/6-high-growth-sectors-to-watch-for-maximum-investment-returns-in-2025-3702037/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:13:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's car race: How far EVs went in 2024 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Car Race: Electric Vehicle Sales Surge in 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<p>The automobile industry in India experienced modest growth in 2024, but electric vehicles saw a substantial increase in sales, marking a significant shift towards EV adoption.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Overall automobile sales grew by just 0.5% in the April-September quarter.</li>
    <li>Electric vehicle sales increased by over 25% compared to the previous fiscal year.</li>
    <li>From April 1 to November 30, 2024, 1.3 million EVs were registered in India.</li>
    <li>Electric two-wheelers accounted for 60% of total EV sales.</li>
    <li>The government launched the PM E-Drive scheme to incentivize EV adoption with a budget of Rs 10,900 crore.</li>
    <li>Major new EV models were launched by companies such as Tata, Mahindra, and MG in 2024.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The Minister of State for Heavy Industries stated, "13.06 lakh EVs were registered in the country from April to November 2024."</blockquote>
<p>In summary, 2024 saw a notable rise in electric vehicle adoption in India driven by consumer demand and government initiatives, highlighting a transition towards more sustainable transportation options.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/renewables/year-ender-2024-indias-car-race-how-far-evs-went-in-2024/articleshow/116731428.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/renewables/year-ender-2024-indias-car-race-how-far-evs-went-in-2024/articleshow/116731428.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 04:55:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Kia Sonet surpasses 1 lakh sales in 11 months - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Kia Sonet Surpasses 1 Lakh Sales in 11 Months</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> February 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p><p>Kia's new Sonet has achieved remarkable sales, surpassing the 1 lakh mark in just 11 months since its launch in January 2024, averaging nearly 10,000 sales per month.</p><ul><li>The Sonet is available in a lineup of 22 variants with 6 powertrain options.</li><li>76% of sales come from petrol variants, while diesel comprises 24%.</li><li>34% of total sales are from automatic transmissions.</li><li>A notable 79% of purchased variants are equipped with sunroofs.</li></ul><blockquote>“When we introduced the New Sonet, it came with several best in segment features, premiumizing the segment. These features have significantly enhanced the value proposition of the New Sonet, contributing to strong sales performance.” - Hardeep Singh Brar, Sr. VP and Head of Sales and Marketing</blockquote><p>This achievement highlights the market's positive reception of the Kia Sonet, driven by its competitive pricing and feature-rich offerings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/auto/car-news/new-kia-sonet-surpasses-1-lakh-sales-in-11-months/3702028/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/auto/car-news/new-kia-sonet-surpasses-1-lakh-sales-in-11-months/3702028/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 04:45:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>