<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 22:17:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 22:17:03 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why the US dollar is so strong to start the year - ForexLive]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why the US dollar is so strong to start the year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Forexlive</p><img src="https://images.financemagnates.com/user-profiles/c97fe488-0a4b-4549-9382-1fe0b770a597_size50.jpeg" alt="Adam Button"><figcaption>Adam Button</figcaption><p>The US dollar is the top performer as it surges at the start of 2025, outperforming major currencies like the euro and pound. This performance is driven by strong capital flows toward US assets, with US equity markets vastly outperforming others.</p><ul><li>The US dollar is up more than 1% against the euro and pound.</li><li>The recent economic news included initial jobless claims and soft data on construction spending and manufacturing sentiment.</li><li>Capital flows are the main driver of the dollar's strength, with significant investment occurring in US markets.</li><li>There are risks such as tariffs and fiscal policies that could affect the markets.</li><li>Investors see a big opportunity when markets shift, similar to Argentina's market performance after political changes.</li></ul><blockquote>“The short answer is that right now the US and US companies are not just winning, but they're running up the score.”</blockquote><p>The US dollar's strong performance is a result of sustained capital flows and market dynamics, with potential risks ahead that could impact the trend.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forexlive.com/news/why-the-us-dollar-is-so-strong-to-start-the-year-20250102/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forexlive.com/news/why-the-us-dollar-is-so-strong-to-start-the-year-20250102/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee to marginally depreciate against USD in CY25, outperform many of its peers: Report - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee to marginally depreciate against USD in CY25, outperform many of its peers: Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>The article analyzes the forecast for the Indian Rupee, indicating a slight depreciation against the US Dollar in the calendar year 2025, while also projecting better performance compared to other currencies.</p><ul><li>Forecasted depreciation of Rupee against USD.</li><li>Expected to outperform many peer currencies.</li><li>Factors influencing the currency movements are discussed.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/rupee-to-marginally-depreciate-against-usd-in-cy25-outperform-many-of-its-peers-report/articleshow/116891990.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/rupee-to-marginally-depreciate-against-usd-in-cy25-outperform-many-of-its-peers-report/articleshow/116891990.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to Watch on January 3: Varun Beverages, NHPC, Hindustan Zinc, Wockhardt and more - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to Watch on January 3: Varun Beverages, NHPC, Hindustan Zinc, Wockhardt and More</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="Stock market overview" title="Stocks to Watch" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Overview of key stocks to monitor today</figcaption><p>This article discusses stocks to watch today, including Varun Beverages and NHPC, alongside their recent developments and financial performance.</p><ul><li><strong>Varun Beverages:</strong> Announced a ₹413 crore investment in South African subsidiary Bevco, acquiring an additional 2.42% shareholding.</li><li><strong>NHPC:</strong> Received a ₹250 crore payment under its Mega Insurance Policy following business interruption losses due to a flash flood.</li><li><strong>Hindustan Zinc:</strong> Reported a 2% decrease in mined metal production year-on-year but a 3% increase compared to the previous quarter.</li><li><strong>Wockhardt:</strong> Received CDSCO approval for Miqnaf, a new treatment for Community-Acquired Bacterial Pneumonia.</li><li><strong>Biocon:</strong> Secured approval from the NMPA in China for Tacrolimus capsules used in organ transplant patients.</li><li><strong>Avenue Supermarts:</strong> Reported a 17.5% year-on-year increase in standalone revenue to ₹15,565.23 crore.</li><li><strong>RITES:</strong> Awarded a ₹69.78 crore contract by SAIL for repairs of locomotives.</li><li><strong>Bank of Maharashtra:</strong> Announced a 16.9% year-on-year increase in total business to ₹5.08 lakh crore.</li><li><strong>Pricol:</strong> Approved divestment of its wiping business to Auto Ignition Ltd for ₹20 crore.</li><li><strong>Honasa Consumer:</strong> Chief Business Officer Master Zairus resigned effective February 28, 2025.</li><li><strong>Capital Small Finance Bank:</strong> Reported a 12% increase in total deposits to ₹8,384 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“We aim to strengthen our balance sheet and support future growth,” said Varun Beverages regarding their recent investment.</blockquote><p>This article highlights significant stock movements and news that investors should monitor for informed decision-making in the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/stocks/stocks-to-watch-on-january-3-varun-beverages-nhpc-hindustan-zinc-wockhardt-and-more-19533721.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/stocks/stocks-to-watch-on-january-3-varun-beverages-nhpc-hindustan-zinc-wockhardt-and-more-19533721.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:15:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trade setup for January 3: Top 15 things to know before the opening bell - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trade setup for January 3: Top 15 things to know before the opening bell</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 / 21:52 IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250102155937_Image102012025.jpg" alt="Nifty Trade Setup" title="Nifty Trade Setup" width="770" height="431"></p><figcaption>Nifty Trade Setup</figcaption><p>Bulls staged a strong performance on January 2, helping the Nifty 50 surpass the psychological 24,000 mark with a 446-point gain, marking the biggest single-day gain in the last six weeks.</p><ul><li>Short-term moving averages (10-day and 20-day EMAs) are climbing.</li><li>The Nifty may face resistance at the 24,200-24,250 zone.</li><li>Immediate support levels are at 24,900 and 24,700.</li><li>Overall momentum has strengthened, but some consolidation may occur before further gains.</li></ul><blockquote>“The momentum has definitely strengthened.”</blockquote><p>The article highlights key levels to watch for potential profitable trades in the Nifty 50.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/trade-setup-for-january-3-top-15-things-to-know-before-the-opening-bell-12902426.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/trade-setup-for-january-3-top-15-things-to-know-before-the-opening-bell-12902426.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:06:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hindenburg Research claims used-car dealer Carvana's involvement in $800 million loan sales undisclosed transactions | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hindenburg Research Accuses Carvana of $800 Million Loan Misconduct</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 2, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>US-based short seller Hindenburg Research has alleged that Carvana Co., an online car dealer, engaged in $800 million of loan sales involving undisclosed related party transactions. Following the report's release, Carvana's stock dropped nearly 5%.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Hindenburg's report claims $800 million in undisclosed loan sales by Carvana.</li><li>The report suggests accounting manipulation and lax underwriting practices.</li><li>Despite bankruptcy risks in previous years, Carvana's stock surged 284% in 2024.</li><li>Used vehicle prices have dropped 20.3% over the past three years, creating significant headwinds for Carvana.</li><li>The company's solvency is questioned due to insider stock unloading.</li></ul><blockquote>“For every $1 in net income it reported, the company has added $139 in market cap – a $34 billion market cap increase,” Hindenburg alleged.</blockquote><p>Hindenburg Research has established a short position in Carvana shares, projecting serious concerns regarding the company's financial practices and future viability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/hindenburg-research-alleges-800-million-loan-sales-by-carvana-to-undisclosed-related-party-11735832465065.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/hindenburg-research-alleges-800-million-loan-sales-by-carvana-to-undisclosed-related-party-11735832465065.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:48:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sebi bans Ketan Parekh, 2 others from markets in front-running scam, impounds Rs 65 crore - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sebi Bans Ketan Parekh and Associates in Front-Running Scam, Seizes ₹65 Crore</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Thursday | <strong>Source:</strong> The Economic Times</p><figure><img height="158" width="210" alt="Sebi bans Ketan Parekh, 2 others from markets in front-running scam, impounds Rs 65 crore" src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116891308,width-210,height-158,imgsize-27670,resizemode-75/sebi-bans-ketan-parekh-2-others-from-markets-in-front-running-scam-impounds-rs-65-crore.jpg"><figcaption>ET Bureau &amp; Agencies</figcaption></figure><p>The Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi) has barred Ketan Parekh and Rohit Salgaocar from the Indian capital markets due to their involvement in a front-running scam, resulting in the impounding of ₹65.77 crore.</p><ul><li>Ketan Parekh, known for his role in the 2001 stock scam, faces renewed restrictions.</li><li>Sebi's investigation revealed unlawful gains earned through front-running activities.</li><li>The accused exploited non-public information related to a foreign portfolio investment.</li></ul><blockquote>"Noticees no. 1 and 2 i.e. Rohit Salgaocar and Ketan Parekh devised the entire scheme to unjustly enrich from the NPI pertaining to the Big Client by orchestrating front running activities." - Sebi's Order</blockquote><p>The ruling emphasizes the importance of regulatory oversight in preventing similar fraudulent activities in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/sebi-bans-ketan-parekh-2-others-from-markets-in-front-running-scam-impounds-rs-65-crore/articleshow/116891317.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/sebi-bans-ketan-parekh-2-others-from-markets-in-front-running-scam-impounds-rs-65-crore/articleshow/116891317.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:47:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NHPC gets ₹250 crore payment under Mega Insurance Policy for Teesta-V power station loss - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/stocks/nhpc-share-price-gets-rs-250-crore-payment-under-mega-insurance-policy-for-teesta-v-power-station-loss-19533680.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/stocks/nhpc-share-price-gets-rs-250-crore-payment-under-mega-insurance-policy-for-teesta-v-power-station-loss-19533680.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:10:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video | Asia Shares Fall | Maruti, Mahindra Boost December Car Sales In India| The World Report - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxOeEtBWEJVUU43Ty0wR1Y4bEZ6VloteEFMRXpidl9meGVKRzdHN1h0RjVlRDdFTnllTFJDWE5RVUlwaF9MRVQ0WG9PTW0wSEozbXEwVGVVUDJjUURhOE1UZ0pmT003M21ldFdDMnFOT2FGbncwRDByWkVoV3JIUXRiTnZkenh2eGpIZ2g0ZjRRSldoWEVwVmpwT0s1NkI4Zlp5RDE2QkdEQUR6eUxQRVl6WnVqUWJFRjhM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxOeEtBWEJVUU43Ty0wR1Y4bEZ6VloteEFMRXpidl9meGVKRzdHN1h0RjVlRDdFTnllTFJDWE5RVUlwaF9MRVQ0WG9PTW0wSEozbXEwVGVVUDJjUURhOE1UZ0pmT003M21ldFdDMnFOT2FGbncwRDByWkVoV3JIUXRiTnZkenh2eGpIZ2g0ZjRRSldoWEVwVmpwT0s1NkI4Zlp5RDE2QkdEQUR6eUxQRVl6WnVqUWJFRjhM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tesla deliveries miss expectations, stock drops - Investing.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tesla Stock Falls 7% Following Lower-Than-Expected Q4 Deliveries</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Investing.com</p>
<p>Tesla reported record vehicle deliveries but fell short of market expectations, leading to a significant drop in stock prices.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Tesla delivered 495,570 vehicles in Q4, below the expected 512,277.</li>
  <li>Shares fell over 7% at market open after the announcement.</li>
  <li>In 2023, Tesla delivered a total of 1.79 million vehicles, marking a decline in annual EV sales for the first time in over a decade.</li>
  <li>Energy storage deployments reached a total of 31.4 GWh for the year.</li>
  <li>Tesla plans to release its Q4 2024 financial results on January 29, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Overall, we would characterize this is a respectable delivery number although the Street and bulls wanted to see a 500k+ number and the stock will be a bit weak on the knee-jerk reaction." - Wedbush</blockquote>
<p>The report highlights challenges Tesla faces in meeting investor expectations despite strong overall performance and ambitious growth plans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/tesla-deliveries-miss-expectations-stock-drops-3794114</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/tesla-deliveries-miss-expectations-stock-drops-3794114</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:38:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sebi clubs fund diversion, disclosure violation probes against ZEE, Punit Goenka and Subhash Chandra | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sebi Combines Probes Against ZEE, Punit Goenka, and Subhash Chandra</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi) has consolidated ongoing investigations into Zee Entertainment Enterprises Ltd (ZEEL) and its executives over allegations of fund diversion and disclosure violations.</p><ul><li>Sebi has clubbed investigations against ZEEL, CEO Punit Goenka, and former chairman Subhash Chandra.</li><li>Allegations include failure to comply with listing regulations and corporate governance violations.</li><li>A show-cause notice was issued in July 2022, questioning the actions of the involved parties.</li><li>Settlement applications filed by Zee and Goenka were rejected in April 2023, leading to further investigations.</li><li>An interim order barred Chandra and Goenka from holding key positions in listed companies amid the allegations.</li><li>Sebi's investigations into LODR violations will now be included in the funds diversion probe.</li><li>The proceeding against the company and executives were dropped to avoid multiplicity of cases.</li></ul><blockquote>“The allegations in the show-cause notice of 6 July 2022 issued by the adjudicating officer are to be subsumed with the findings of the further investigation carried out by SEBI in the instant (funds diversion) matter.”</blockquote><p>This development is significant as it centralizes the investigation process and streamlines legal proceedings within the corporate governance framework.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/sebi-zee-punit-goenka-subhash-chandra-fund-diversion-disclosure-violation-investigations-11735824784831.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/sebi-zee-punit-goenka-subhash-chandra-fund-diversion-disclosure-violation-investigations-11735824784831.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:22:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Indian CEO Is The Highest-Paid Employee In The World; This Is His Salary... - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jagdeep Singh: The Highest-Paid CEO in the World</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2025/01/untitled-design-40-2025-01-413fbbd5fa3cff053e46553e9c804c93.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Jagdeep Singh founded Quantumscape, a leading electric car battery developer." />
<figcaption>Jagdeep Singh founded Quantumscape, a leading electric car battery developer.</figcaption>
<p>Jagdeep Singh holds the title for the highest annual salary in the world at Rs 17,500 crore, with earnings that reflect his significant impact on the evolving landscape of wealth and technology.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Singh earns an astonishing Rs 48 crore per day, surpassing the annual revenue of many corporations.</li>
  <li>He is the founder of Quantumscape, a leader in electric car battery technology.</li>
  <li>Singh's monthly income stands at Rs 1,459 crore, setting a new benchmark for salary globally.</li>
  <li>His academic background includes a B.Tech from Stanford University and an MBA from the University of California.</li>
  <li>Quantumscape is driving innovations in electric vehicle technology, contributing to sustainable transportation.</li>
  <li>Singh's journey from an employee to a CEO exemplifies the potential of entrepreneurship and innovation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Singh is King,” reflecting the pride in his achievement as the highest-paid employee worldwide.</blockquote>
<p>Jagdeep Singh’s story serves as an inspiration for aspiring entrepreneurs, highlighting the intersection of technology, opportunity, and financial success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/this-indian-ceo-is-the-highest-paid-employee-in-the-world-this-is-his-salary-ws-ab-9175104.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/this-indian-ceo-is-the-highest-paid-employee-in-the-world-this-is-his-salary-ws-ab-9175104.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:09:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indo Farm Equipment IPO Day 3 Live Updates: Issue subscribed 229.68 times on third day; check latest GMP | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indo Farm Equipment IPO Day 3 Live Updates: Issue Subscribed 229.68 Times</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 02 Jan, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> LiveMint</p><figure><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2025/01/02/600x338/pexels-photo-8064065_1735288947424_1735783688453.jpeg" alt="Indo Farm Equipment IPO Day 3 Live Updates" title="Indo Farm Equipment IPO enters the third and last day of the bidding process today."><figcaption>Indo Farm Equipment IPO enters the third and last day of the bidding process today.</figcaption></figure><p>The Indo Farm Equipment IPO saw exceptional demand, closing with an oversubscription of over 229 times on the final day of bidding. This article provides the details and implications of the IPO, which aims to raise significant capital for business expansion and debt reduction.</p><ul><li>IPO subscription was strong, with bids for 1.94 billion shares against 847,000 shares on offer.</li><li>The price band for the IPO is set between ₹204 and ₹215 per share, targeting to raise ₹260.15 crore.</li><li>The QIB segment attracted a subscription of 242.40 times, while NII was subscribed 503.83 times.</li><li>Indo Farm Equipment's strategic plans include expanding production capacity and reducing debt.</li></ul><blockquote>“At the upper end of the price band, the company aims to raise ₹260.15 crore from the book-built issue.”</blockquote><p>This IPO is seen as a strong investment opportunity, backed by the company’s growth strategy and market position.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-day-3-live-updates-indo-farm-equipment-ipo-gmp-subscription-status-price-band-apply-or-not-11735783633123.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-day-3-live-updates-indo-farm-equipment-ipo-gmp-subscription-status-price-band-apply-or-not-11735783633123.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:53:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blinkit launches 10-minute ambulance service in Gurugram, to expand across major cities in 2 years - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Blinkit Launches 10-Minute Ambulance Service in Gurugram</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Thursday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Blinkit</p>
<p>Blinkit has introduced a 10-minute ambulance service in select areas of Gurugram, marking its entry into the healthcare space.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Five ambulances equipped with Basic Life Support (BLS) systems deployed.</li>
  <li>Users can book ambulances via the Blinkit app.</li>
  <li>The service is designed to be affordable and not profit-driven.</li>
  <li>Company aims to expand to all major cities in the next two years.</li>
  <li>Ambulances are equipped with essential life-saving equipment and staffed for emergency care.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Profit is not a goal here. We will operate this service at an affordable cost for customers.” - Albinder Dhindsa</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Blinkit's new ambulance service aims to address a critical urban challenge while ensuring quick and reliable emergency healthcare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/business-news/latest-updates/zomato-s-blinkit-launches-10-minute-ambulance-service-in-gurugram/article-138496/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/business-news/latest-updates/zomato-s-blinkit-launches-10-minute-ambulance-service-in-gurugram/article-138496/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:22:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indo Farm Equipment IPO subscribed 229.31x on Day 3; Check latest GMP, subscription status, other details | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indo Farm Equipment IPO Subscribed 229.31x on Final Day</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>The initial public offering (IPO) of Indo Farm Equipment witnessed an extraordinary response, being oversubscribed by 229.31 times on its final bidding day.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The IPO opened on December 31 and closed on January 2, 2023.</li>
  <li>Investors bid for 194,221,841 shares against 8,470,000 shares available.</li>
  <li>Non-Institutional Investors led the subscriptions at 503.39 times, followed by Qualified Institutional Buyers at 242.40 times, and Retail Investors at 104.36 times.</li>
  <li>The IPO raised ₹78 crore from anchor investors prior to the public issue.</li>
  <li>The grey market premium (GMP) is currently ₹96 per share.</li>
  <li>Proceeds will be used for loan repayment, expansion of manufacturing capacity, and investment in their NBFC subsidiary.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Indo Farm Equipment IPO Latest GMP</h2>
<p>The grey market premium (GMP) reflects investor sentiment, indicating a listing price around ₹311, representing a premium of 44.65% over the upper price band of ₹215.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“As of January 2, the grey market premium (GMP) of Indo Farm Equipment stands at ₹96 per share.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This IPO is expected to list on the stock market on January 7, 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> The views and recommendations given in this article are those of individual analysts and do not represent the views of Mint. Consult certified experts before making investment decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-subscribed-229-31-times-check-latest-gmp-subscription-status-other-details-11735822685562.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-subscribed-229-31-times-check-latest-gmp-subscription-status-other-details-11735822685562.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:19:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ketan Parekh strikes again! SEBI unearths unusual front-running scam, impounds Rs 65.77 crore - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ketan Parekh strikes again! SEBI unearths unusual front-running scam, impounds Rs 65.77 crore</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2022/11/gavel-3575414_960_720-770x424.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431' alt='SEBI Investigation' width='770' height='431'><figcaption>In an order issued on January 2, the Securities and Exchange Board of India detailed the investigation that spanned over 20 locations</figcaption><p>The market regulator has uncovered a significant front-running scam involving Ketan Parekh, leading to the impounding of Rs 65.77 crore.</p><ul><li>SEBI issued an interim order detailing the investigation conducted across over 20 locations.</li><li>The order was passed against 22 involved entities.</li><li>Ketan Parekh, previously imprisoned for a similar scam, is involved along with trader Rohit Salgaocar.</li><li>The investigation revealed tactics to unjustly enrich from trading activities.</li><li>Individuals involved have been previously prohibited from trading in securities.</li></ul><blockquote>“Noticees no. 1 and 2 ... devised the entire scheme to unjustly enrich from the NPI pertaining to the Big Client by orchestrating front running activities.” - SEBI's Whole-time Member Kamlesh Varshney</blockquote><p>This investigation marks another chapter in Ketan Parekh's controversial history in the Indian securities market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/ketan-parekh-strikes-again-sebi-unearths-unusual-front-running-scam-impounds-rs-65-77-crore-12902368.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/ketan-parekh-strikes-again-sebi-unearths-unusual-front-running-scam-impounds-rs-65-77-crore-12902368.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:14:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyundai Creta Electric With 473KM Claimed Range, Active Air Flaps Unveiled in India: Features, Launch Dat... - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQcU1WeTU4LXJmLUtLQUlsaWFaUG9HRjViRjZCZzQwajFZV3NIWWhMZ0V5X052T0p2dVRmQWFDMk84SmNCaW5ocWo0Y2RVSnBXTWd5MG1kNHNrMEdQdjJUazMzcVM0dnoxLUdHdk54eThURVlha25Bbm4zWWdlMUdEWEIxTDlWSG5TN1pqcE0wS1JnN3BmQTZ1LU54N3RBVE1nQlQ4RlZ3MNIBrAFBVV95cUxNY0VZQTl4NFlwUXVFTnljRmE2MWpvNm1ydElBZ1B4T0RSTnZ4dEV2N1MxMWZQNS1Vb04tSzZ3eDJSbF9SSG85MHhuazYtcjlaZEliX1BGUlVNaHJaLWxhc2JGT1ByOUtueU93MFIwYUpnS1E5cVE2UGpsem9fYlE4Y25DaG8yaWZTWVNlWWNEcmtKSGZqNUVURHk4MUNVMEp5VXBzX1hTOVRWa3Nf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQcU1WeTU4LXJmLUtLQUlsaWFaUG9HRjViRjZCZzQwajFZV3NIWWhMZ0V5X052T0p2dVRmQWFDMk84SmNCaW5ocWo0Y2RVSnBXTWd5MG1kNHNrMEdQdjJUazMzcVM0dnoxLUdHdk54eThURVlha25Bbm4zWWdlMUdEWEIxTDlWSG5TN1pqcE0wS1JnN3BmQTZ1LU54N3RBVE1nQlQ4RlZ3MNIBrAFBVV95cUxNY0VZQTl4NFlwUXVFTnljRmE2MWpvNm1ydElBZ1B4T0RSTnZ4dEV2N1MxMWZQNS1Vb04tSzZ3eDJSbF9SSG85MHhuazYtcjlaZEliX1BGUlVNaHJaLWxhc2JGT1ByOUtueU93MFIwYUpnS1E5cVE2UGpsem9fYlE4Y25DaG8yaWZTWVNlWWNEcmtKSGZqNUVURHk4MUNVMEp5VXBzX1hTOVRWa3Nf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:53:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avenue Supermarts reports 17.5% growth in Q3 revenue - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Avenue Supermarts Reports 17.5% Revenue Growth in Q3 FY25</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Avenue Supermarts reports 17.5% growth in Q3 revenue" title="Avenue Supermarts reports 17.5% growth in Q3 revenue" width="640" height="360" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Avenue Supermarts reports 17.5% growth in Q3 revenue</figcaption><p>Avenue Supermarts Ltd, which operates the D-Mart retail chain, has reported significant growth in its third-quarter revenues, highlighting strong operational performance.</p><ul><li>Standalone revenue for Q3 FY25 reached ₹15,565.23 crore, a 17.5% increase year-on-year.</li><li>The company had 387 stores operational as of December 31, 2024.</li><li>Net profit in Q2 FY25 was ₹710 crore, representing a 7.9% increase over last year.</li><li>EBITDA for Q2 FY25 was ₹1,105 crore with a margin of 7.9%.</li><li>Basic earnings per share for Q2 FY25 were ₹10.92, compared to ₹10.12 in Q2 FY24.</li></ul><blockquote>“The firm's total revenue for the first six months of FY25 has risen to ₹27,762 crore, up from ₹23,892 crore last year.”</blockquote><p>The financial results demonstrate Avenue Supermarts' resilience and growth, positioning it strongly in the competitive retail sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/stocks/d-mart-avenue-supermarts-share-price-reports-17-5-growth-in-q3-revenue-19533561.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/stocks/d-mart-avenue-supermarts-share-price-reports-17-5-growth-in-q3-revenue-19533561.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:43:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blinkit Launches 10-Minute Ambulance Service In Gurugram - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Blinkit Launches 10-Minute Ambulance Service In Gurugram</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified <strong>Source: </strong>Blinkit</p>
<img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2025-01-02%2F0sxj0z96%2FGgSHvr3bEAEQm-r.jpeg?rect=0%2C231%2C3869%2C2176&amp;w=1200" alt="Blinkit's 10-minute ambulance service in Gurugram"/>
<figcaption>Blinkit's 10-minute ambulance service in Gurugram marks the beginning of its plan to expand emergency medical assistance to major cities across India over the next two years. (Representative Image: Photo source: Freepik)</figcaption>
<p>Blinkit has introduced a 10-minute ambulance service in Gurugram to enhance emergency medical assistance in urban areas, with plans to expand across India over the next two years.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The service launches with five ambulances equipped with critical life-saving tools.</li>
  <li>Available for booking through the Blinkit app.</li>
  <li>Service staffed by trained personnel including a paramedic, an assistant, and a driver.</li>
  <li>Focus on affordability and quality care instead of profit.</li>
  <li>Part of Blinkit's broader strategy to provide diversified services beyond grocery delivery.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This initiative is a long-term solution to a critical problem,” said Albinder Dhindsa, CEO of Blinkit.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Blinkit's initiative aims to fill a significant gap in emergency medical services, reflecting its commitment to improving healthcare accessibility in Indian cities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/business/blinkit-10-minute-ambulance-service-gurugram-launch</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/business/blinkit-10-minute-ambulance-service-gurugram-launch</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:32:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DMart battles quick commerce, grows revenue by 17% on year to Rs 15,565 crore - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>DMart Battles Quick Commerce with 17% Revenue Growth</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2021/12/Avenue_Supermarts2_dmart.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="DMart Image" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>During the September quarter, DMart parent Avenue Supermarts' revenue and net profit fell below expectations, sparking a sharp selloff in the share prices.</figcaption><p>DMart-owner Avenue Supermarts reported a standalone revenue of Rs 15,565.23 crore for the September quarter, marking a 17.5% year-on-year increase. The company continues to face pressures from online grocery competitors.</p><ul><li>Revenue from operations reached Rs 15,565 crore, a 17.5% increase compared to the same period last year.</li><li>Total store count as of December was 387, with the addition of 10 new stores in the third quarter.</li><li>Shares of Avenue Supermarts saw a 1.4% increase on January 2.</li><li>Despite growth, the company faced challenges from quick commerce and online grocery formats influencing operations.</li></ul><blockquote>“The operations were impacted by online grocery format players, including the rapid growth of quick commerce as a delivery model.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while DMart shows resilient revenue growth, the company's performance indicates a competitive landscape influenced by the rapid rise of quick commerce.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/dmart-battles-quick-commerce-grows-revenue-by-17-on-year-to-rs-15-565-crore-12902323.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/dmart-battles-quick-commerce-grows-revenue-by-17-on-year-to-rs-15-565-crore-12902323.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:29:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Ambulance In 10 Minutes': Blinkit Rolls Out Services In Gurugram, Says 'Profit Is Not A Goal' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/blinkit-rolls-out-ambulance-in-10-minutes-services-in-gurugram-major-cities-soon-albinder-dhindsa-viral-news-9175484.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/blinkit-rolls-out-ambulance-in-10-minutes-services-in-gurugram-major-cities-soon-albinder-dhindsa-viral-news-9175484.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:27:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sebi rejects Zee, Punit Goenka's settlement applications, orders further probe - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sebi Rejects Settlement Applications from Zee Entertainment and Punit Goenka</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<p>The Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi) has dismissed the settlement applications filed by Zee Entertainment Enterprises and its CEO Punit Goenka, ordering further investigation into the matter.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sebi's decision followed the review of show cause notices against Zee and its executives for alleged violations.</li>
  <li>The ongoing investigation will now include previously issued allegations as part of its broader inquiry.</li>
  <li>Shares of Zee have significantly declined, down nearly 60% in the past year following a terminated deal with Sony.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The allegations in the SCN dated July 06, 2022 issued by AO are to be subsumed with the findings of the further investigation carried out by SEBI in the instant matter." - Sebi Order</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, with the rejection of settlement applications, the investigation into Zee Entertainment and its executives will continue, potentially leading to further regulatory actions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/sebi-rejects-zee-punit-goenkas-settlement-applications-orders-further-probe/articleshow/116887188.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/sebi-rejects-zee-punit-goenkas-settlement-applications-orders-further-probe/articleshow/116887188.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:24:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indo Farm Equipment IPO Day 3 Live Updates: Issue subscribed 227.57 times on third day; check latest GMP | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxQOF90VHhQQXFkdWV5NmxkQldSLTc5NC1oSVFNb1pHTzREVURHSy14eE4wajBCNU8zQnNOMUVNZ1hObmNPZEd2bzFodzR1VlhNRzJ2ajc0N1RVak9UVTFTVU1kVW1zanBQMTVKNXdoSU5lRXlzNUpKNGwzQ0FVT0RRS3M1cUNvbFJyTXhsX3NhMDZpcXpTTTRPbXhMY2tlbVN3NDZJbnlFWXFEa0dJaHlWaXRqZTMwT3JlZ1FucXRPRGJHci1XcXNuYVFPQkQ0c2s1c2dtVU9IUEdXTVVJVlhzV1BBdnBMRDE2T1o0a2VfUlJWckJ3amsyTlEtQW94eTTSAYQCQVVfeXFMTzVOMzlmR1hJQV8tVVBITTJsdHJoNHRRZFVwRXIyRUtkOUl4eGxCcXJ2di1YUjlrcFhwUGFlTDFvVEdEbkVYZHo3MDFJZVYxRkduWDQ1aHVqV2FpSVJyaEFqX09jVWdoM2tCMm1YeDlDWUNMcl9EcEY5UjdqUXo4MWFEVkdhUUVMaFpoWXBBS2xyS3R2U2QwVnNrRkk0XzFNdHhCeUFCTTdfNU9mMzFnVDl6djRGc1NJWjVjQkxuTHpWTGEtb2lzZXpBOENYQmtxWmc4U0d2eW5kcjNPNE1pczBqMUZCeF82STZocXBEYVlHTlVhRVVnR2ZTNU1aeE1ET3hCSUs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxQOF90VHhQQXFkdWV5NmxkQldSLTc5NC1oSVFNb1pHTzREVURHSy14eE4wajBCNU8zQnNOMUVNZ1hObmNPZEd2bzFodzR1VlhNRzJ2ajc0N1RVak9UVTFTVU1kVW1zanBQMTVKNXdoSU5lRXlzNUpKNGwzQ0FVT0RRS3M1cUNvbFJyTXhsX3NhMDZpcXpTTTRPbXhMY2tlbVN3NDZJbnlFWXFEa0dJaHlWaXRqZTMwT3JlZ1FucXRPRGJHci1XcXNuYVFPQkQ0c2s1c2dtVU9IUEdXTVVJVlhzV1BBdnBMRDE2T1o0a2VfUlJWckJ3amsyTlEtQW94eTTSAYQCQVVfeXFMTzVOMzlmR1hJQV8tVVBITTJsdHJoNHRRZFVwRXIyRUtkOUl4eGxCcXJ2di1YUjlrcFhwUGFlTDFvVEdEbkVYZHo3MDFJZVYxRkduWDQ1aHVqV2FpSVJyaEFqX09jVWdoM2tCMm1YeDlDWUNMcl9EcEY5UjdqUXo4MWFEVkdhUUVMaFpoWXBBS2xyS3R2U2QwVnNrRkk0XzFNdHhCeUFCTTdfNU9mMzFnVDl6djRGc1NJWjVjQkxuTHpWTGEtb2lzZXpBOENYQmtxWmc4U0d2eW5kcjNPNE1pczBqMUZCeF82STZocXBEYVlHTlVhRVVnR2ZTNU1aeE1ET3hCSUs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:15:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Ambani's son Akash Ambani makes big announcement about Jamnagar, not related to refinery but... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Akash Ambani's Bold Move to Develop AI Infrastructure in Jamnagar</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> October 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><figure><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Untitled-design-66.png?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Mukesh Ambani's son Akash Ambani makes big announcement about Jamnagar, not related to refinery but..."><figcaption>Mukesh Ambani and Akash Ambani</figcaption></figure><p>In a significant step that could change the future of technology development in India, Akash Ambani, the elder son of Mukesh Ambani, announced plans to develop AI infrastructure in Jamnagar, aiming to make it a global leader in technology.</p><ul><li>Akash Ambani stated a commitment to develop AI infrastructure in Jamnagar.</li><li>The project is expected to be completed within 24 months.</li><li>This announcement coincided with the 25th anniversary of Reliance’s Jamnagar refinery.</li><li>Ambani emphasized the importance of the project for the future of technology in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“AI infrastructure that we have commenced working in Jamnagar will not only make Jamnagar a leader in AI infrastructure, but will also place it amongst the top rank in the world.”</blockquote><p>The Ambani family has expressed their commitment to grow Reliance together, ensuring Jamnagar remains a jewel of the Reliance family.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/business/mukesh-ambanis-son-akash-ambani-makes-big-announcement-about-jamnagar-not-related-to-refinery-but-7509875/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/business/mukesh-ambanis-son-akash-ambani-makes-big-announcement-about-jamnagar-not-related-to-refinery-but-7509875/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:54:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘The best is behind us…’: Zerodha's Nithin Kamath flags SEBI's F&O regulations' ripple effect on brokerage platforms | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zerodha's Nithin Kamath Discusses SEBI's F&O Regulations and Their Impact on Brokerage Platforms</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Nithin Kamath, the co-founder and CEO of Zerodha, reflects on the brokerage industry's performance, indicating that the peak was in 2024, which may now be a thing of the past due to new regulations.</p>
<blockquote>“Looking back, 2024 was probably the best year for the brokerage industry, and it's starting to look like the best is behind us, at least for the foreseeable future.” — Nithin Kamath</blockquote>
<ul>
  <li>Kamath warns that the best days for brokerage platforms may be over.</li>
  <li>The futures and options (F&O) regulations imposed by SEBI have led to a 20-30% drop in F&O activities across brokers.</li>
  <li>SEBI's regulations include several key changes aimed to curb excessive speculative trading.</li>
</ul>
<p>Key changes include limiting weekly expiry contracts, increasing lot sizes effective January 2025, and requiring option buyers to pay premiums upfront.</p>
<p>The implications of these regulations are expected to deepen in the following year, impacting market dynamics significantly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/the-best-is-behind-us-zerodhas-nithin-kamath-flags-sebis-f-o-regulations-ripple-effect-on-brokerage-platforms-11735812813297.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/the-best-is-behind-us-zerodhas-nithin-kamath-flags-sebis-f-o-regulations-ripple-effect-on-brokerage-platforms-11735812813297.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:51:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India’s economic outlook for 2025: Navigating slowdown, structural challenges and global uncertainty - Business Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxPZmdPRWYxUFd2ekNKSDE1Y0EzaGNaVzBtamloZTVqUU9QWnBKZ3RpdE11NkFJaGt3UjRjbTJ2QW1YQ2hHNWc1T3Q0QVUyeHZ5VHRuTmpISFZ0RzVKbS1nUTZKcmNDV0ZFakppYmZCbms0cmJuSjJvRHR1Mm5KVHNwSnJkVDJqUWpEYzhVS3I4a3pxV3JLcWZ6djRjNnlNV0hxWDA1bFZIakdkRGk4R2NORE1WTEpOSE93WTFkX3MyNGJqanR5dGw1WDJOVHBUdE9vdE5pbGo0aVNXVGJMTF9rTlJmVjBvcExkR2FtUA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxPZmdPRWYxUFd2ekNKSDE1Y0EzaGNaVzBtamloZTVqUU9QWnBKZ3RpdE11NkFJaGt3UjRjbTJ2QW1YQ2hHNWc1T3Q0QVUyeHZ5VHRuTmpISFZ0RzVKbS1nUTZKcmNDV0ZFakppYmZCbms0cmJuSjJvRHR1Mm5KVHNwSnJkVDJqUWpEYzhVS3I4a3pxV3JLcWZ6djRjNnlNV0hxWDA1bFZIakdkRGk4R2NORE1WTEpOSE93WTFkX3MyNGJqanR5dGw1WDJOVHBUdE9vdE5pbGo0aVNXVGJMTF9rTlJmVjBvcExkR2FtUA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:36:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indo Farm Equipment IPO Day 3 Live Updates: Issue subscribed over 227 times so far; check GMP. Apply or not? | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxQOF90VHhQQXFkdWV5NmxkQldSLTc5NC1oSVFNb1pHTzREVURHSy14eE4wajBCNU8zQnNOMUVNZ1hObmNPZEd2bzFodzR1VlhNRzJ2ajc0N1RVak9UVTFTVU1kVW1zanBQMTVKNXdoSU5lRXlzNUpKNGwzQ0FVT0RRS3M1cUNvbFJyTXhsX3NhMDZpcXpTTTRPbXhMY2tlbVN3NDZJbnlFWXFEa0dJaHlWaXRqZTMwT3JlZ1FucXRPRGJHci1XcXNuYVFPQkQ0c2s1c2dtVU9IUEdXTVVJVlhzV1BBdnBMRDE2T1o0a2VfUlJWckJ3amsyTlEtQW94eTTSAYQCQVVfeXFMTzVOMzlmR1hJQV8tVVBITTJsdHJoNHRRZFVwRXIyRUtkOUl4eGxCcXJ2di1YUjlrcFhwUGFlTDFvVEdEbkVYZHo3MDFJZVYxRkduWDQ1aHVqV2FpSVJyaEFqX09jVWdoM2tCMm1YeDlDWUNMcl9EcEY5UjdqUXo4MWFEVkdhUUVMaFpoWXBBS2xyS3R2U2QwVnNrRkk0XzFNdHhCeUFCTTdfNU9mMzFnVDl6djRGc1NJWjVjQkxuTHpWTGEtb2lzZXpBOENYQmtxWmc4U0d2eW5kcjNPNE1pczBqMUZCeF82STZocXBEYVlHTlVhRVVnR2ZTNU1aeE1ET3hCSUs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxQOF90VHhQQXFkdWV5NmxkQldSLTc5NC1oSVFNb1pHTzREVURHSy14eE4wajBCNU8zQnNOMUVNZ1hObmNPZEd2bzFodzR1VlhNRzJ2ajc0N1RVak9UVTFTVU1kVW1zanBQMTVKNXdoSU5lRXlzNUpKNGwzQ0FVT0RRS3M1cUNvbFJyTXhsX3NhMDZpcXpTTTRPbXhMY2tlbVN3NDZJbnlFWXFEa0dJaHlWaXRqZTMwT3JlZ1FucXRPRGJHci1XcXNuYVFPQkQ0c2s1c2dtVU9IUEdXTVVJVlhzV1BBdnBMRDE2T1o0a2VfUlJWckJ3amsyTlEtQW94eTTSAYQCQVVfeXFMTzVOMzlmR1hJQV8tVVBITTJsdHJoNHRRZFVwRXIyRUtkOUl4eGxCcXJ2di1YUjlrcFhwUGFlTDFvVEdEbkVYZHo3MDFJZVYxRkduWDQ1aHVqV2FpSVJyaEFqX09jVWdoM2tCMm1YeDlDWUNMcl9EcEY5UjdqUXo4MWFEVkdhUUVMaFpoWXBBS2xyS3R2U2QwVnNrRkk0XzFNdHhCeUFCTTdfNU9mMzFnVDl6djRGc1NJWjVjQkxuTHpWTGEtb2lzZXpBOENYQmtxWmc4U0d2eW5kcjNPNE1pczBqMUZCeF82STZocXBEYVlHTlVhRVVnR2ZTNU1aeE1ET3hCSUs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:28:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jefferies Budget 2025 picks: Siemens, HAL, and more poised for up to 49% gains - Zee Business]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxQMFhWZDFraHAza214WUc4V1ltZFpEUl9RQUtwc09MZG5lSjlFOWluUXFOZVh2Uzk2RUNsLUptczRTVjlkTmZ3S2xHQTc0NXJSSDZmR05pMmtXLVVZeXZoWFMwYnZqSHBJQW04NjNIRlN5UGR2S09RVTJpWnBVRk43Y0lKR1VIRDZvNm1SU3RKdV8yRGc1SG1reVdZcDJhckpZOERHNEIwZzBkSkJFSDhkWTBQTXpUWWJuWEFCTkRrWWZYUdIBxwFBVV95cUxQRGM4ekZWc2xQOXNlTjM3cmZXdE9VMVhDazFaR0FRaUFsb2RQSTZQTU1aUS1NTXQ4ZENTRENFcGFzUm1XbjB3QzRxamZGQVF1Zi1WTXFMUm1mc2oydjRqUmU0RmlhdTN1bjlxd25teHhQaWtsLWdjNXNGdjNLZEE4LTJwUGlOOGdEb1RIMGNkZ1BIYXo1X1RfMHNmUTVvRURsYU9UNjJqb3hvdUtETDdQRS1HVmJHdEdyOUptTHRlTHJ1b25qd0RJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxQMFhWZDFraHAza214WUc4V1ltZFpEUl9RQUtwc09MZG5lSjlFOWluUXFOZVh2Uzk2RUNsLUptczRTVjlkTmZ3S2xHQTc0NXJSSDZmR05pMmtXLVVZeXZoWFMwYnZqSHBJQW04NjNIRlN5UGR2S09RVTJpWnBVRk43Y0lKR1VIRDZvNm1SU3RKdV8yRGc1SG1reVdZcDJhckpZOERHNEIwZzBkSkJFSDhkWTBQTXpUWWJuWEFCTkRrWWZYUdIBxwFBVV95cUxQRGM4ekZWc2xQOXNlTjM3cmZXdE9VMVhDazFaR0FRaUFsb2RQSTZQTU1aUS1NTXQ4ZENTRENFcGFzUm1XbjB3QzRxamZGQVF1Zi1WTXFMUm1mc2oydjRqUmU0RmlhdTN1bjlxd25teHhQaWtsLWdjNXNGdjNLZEE4LTJwUGlOOGdEb1RIMGNkZ1BIYXo1X1RfMHNmUTVvRURsYU9UNjJqb3hvdUtETDdQRS1HVmJHdEdyOUptTHRlTHJ1b25qd0RJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:19:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SEBI rejects ZEEL's, Punit Goenka's settlement applications; to probe further - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNZXJWcXRmZ29VNGt1eGVmLW9nV0tXbXhOSlRHNmduUlBXVktlWGJ4OTFNendyQkUyckRWYjZxakd1aTNSTFI1bFZ1ZEl4VlAzZkhJYi12dmNGSWs5c3oyR0liWWtOS3RKb1o3YklVVUFaMXJuLUh6Q0xSTi02Qm1oWDRIR2ZLRkV3WkdnN1o1MktSZ3NVWUM0TjdkUFJwY3AzRHVtNnlmcFpXaDhGa0dtQnhVLVFRNUhWS09YSUhpV3BSajU4cDhOOTZwcEtyVlp6eDVMV0tTUdIB3AFBVV95cUxPRkl0YTZMZGZMS0ZPdFM3X3lydHhJZVM1NGR3b0ZDVTA0UkwtdXEtcHN4VkJfd1BrWmY4TGZTV1lSNENPUjVFczBpbGxVRWxhazBqczRicnMyTG9XN0FwaVI0b2o2Y1lTYlJWdGhxVTZsd2dueXpsT09rOU1hR1A3b0xRVWg3ZndscHE5U3FjSWNfTWI4QzluX2plS2t0YlR4cjBPcHhjWnRpY2tIbk5oWjBKcDlvS3RFdnFhdkwxN2NfRklvcTgzamxIbThlY2hhSVNlWFBpb3Q2alU0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNZXJWcXRmZ29VNGt1eGVmLW9nV0tXbXhOSlRHNmduUlBXVktlWGJ4OTFNendyQkUyckRWYjZxakd1aTNSTFI1bFZ1ZEl4VlAzZkhJYi12dmNGSWs5c3oyR0liWWtOS3RKb1o3YklVVUFaMXJuLUh6Q0xSTi02Qm1oWDRIR2ZLRkV3WkdnN1o1MktSZ3NVWUM0TjdkUFJwY3AzRHVtNnlmcFpXaDhGa0dtQnhVLVFRNUhWS09YSUhpV3BSajU4cDhOOTZwcEtyVlp6eDVMV0tTUdIB3AFBVV95cUxPRkl0YTZMZGZMS0ZPdFM3X3lydHhJZVM1NGR3b0ZDVTA0UkwtdXEtcHN4VkJfd1BrWmY4TGZTV1lSNENPUjVFczBpbGxVRWxhazBqczRicnMyTG9XN0FwaVI0b2o2Y1lTYlJWdGhxVTZsd2dueXpsT09rOU1hR1A3b0xRVWg3ZndscHE5U3FjSWNfTWI4QzluX2plS2t0YlR4cjBPcHhjWnRpY2tIbk5oWjBKcDlvS3RFdnFhdkwxN2NfRklvcTgzamxIbThlY2hhSVNlWFBpb3Q2alU0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:19:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Waaree Energies to NTPC Green: Check how renewable energy stocks performed in 2024 and the sector outlook for 2025 - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Performance of Renewable Energy Stocks in India: 2024 Insights and 2025 Outlook</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><p>As India aims to enhance its green energy capacity, renewable energy stocks witnessed varied performances in 2024, with significant implications for 2025's outlook.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li><strong>Adani Green Energy:</strong> Shares dropped 35% due to allegations against chairman Gautam Adani, closing 2024 at ₹1,040.7.</li><li><strong>Suzlon Energy:</strong> Shares rose 61.6%, bolstered by strong order flows, closing at ₹62.22.</li><li><strong>Waaree Energies:</strong> Strong orders led to an 89% increase since listing, closing at ₹2,854.6.</li><li><strong>Premier Energies:</strong> Jumped over 60%, closing at ₹1,353.1, backed by substantial contracts.</li><li><strong>NTPC Green Energy:</strong> Rose 14.5% since listing, reaching ₹127.67 with significant project bids.</li><li><strong>KPI Green Energy:</strong> Increased over 66%, closing at ₹815.15, projecting 10GW capacity by 2030.</li></ul><h2>Key Sector Triggers</h2><ul><li>Renewable energy capacity additions reached 24.72 GW in 2024, led by solar power.</li><li>The government pledged ₹32.45 lakh crore for renewable energy projects.</li><li>Growth factors include emerging technologies and rising demand for solar components.</li></ul><h2>Outlook for 2025</h2><ul><li>Projected capacity addition of 35 GW in 2025.</li><li>Government initiatives like PM Surya Ghar Muft Bijli Yojana to support solar projects.</li><li>Wind energy sector expected to see double-digit growth.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/waaree-energies-to-ntpc-green-check-how-renewable-energy-stock-performed-in-2024-and-the-sector-outlook-for-2025/article-138428/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/waaree-energies-to-ntpc-green-check-how-renewable-energy-stock-performed-in-2024-and-the-sector-outlook-for-2025/article-138428/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:14:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Europe and Asia's factories end 2024 on weak footing as Trump 2.0 risks mount - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Europe and Asia's factories end 2024 on weak footing as Trump 2.0 risks mount</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/D5UK4WJG5FN3HGEGF5KD7CQLDU.jpg?auth=e409296b14eb3f92675af01a9116465a53759a1958e48471767fbbcba0421471&amp;width=5500&amp;quality=80" alt="China’s BYD opens its first electric vehicle (EV) factory in Southeast Asia, in Rayong"><figcaption>A worker assembles an EV car inside BYD's first electric vehicle (EV) factory in Southeast Asia.</figcaption><p>Factory activity in Asia and Europe ended 2024 on a soft note due to rising trade tensions linked to a possible second term for Donald Trump and the ongoing economic struggles in China.</p><ul><li>European manufacturing activity fell sharply in December.</li><li>Asia's factory activity slows amid weak Chinese demand.</li><li>Trump's tariff threats are impacting major trading partners.</li><li>Taiwan sees growth, while South Korea and Japan face declines.</li></ul><blockquote>“Output in the euro zone remained under pressure at the end of 2024, held back by a continued slide in new orders in both the domestic market and in exports.” - Claus Vistesen, chief euro zone economist at Pantheon.</blockquote><p>The decline in factory activity points to a challenging economic landscape as stakeholders brace for potential tariff increases and slow recovery in major economies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asias-factories-end-2024-weak-footing-trump-20-risks-mount-2025-01-02/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/asias-factories-end-2024-weak-footing-trump-20-risks-mount-2025-01-02/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>