<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 23:18:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 23:18:25 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unimech Aerospace IPO Listing On Tuesday: GMP At 91.08% Indicates Robust Gains For Investors - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unimech Aerospace IPO Listing On Tuesday: GMP At 91.08% Indicates Robust Gains For Investors</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Unimech Aerospace IPO Listing Date." title="Unimech Aerospace IPO Listing Date.">
<figcaption>Unimech Aerospace IPO Listing Date.</figcaption>
<p>The Unimech Aerospace IPO is set to list on December 31, showing a 91.08% premium over its issue price of Rs 785, indicating significant investor interest.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The IPO received a remarkable 184.34 times subscription.</li>
  <li>Unimech Aerospace shares are currently trading at Rs 1,500 in the grey market.</li>
  <li>The listing will take place on both BSE and NSE.</li>
  <li>The price band of the IPO was between Rs 745 and 785.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Grey market premium indicates investors’ readiness to pay more than the issue price.”</blockquote>
<p>This IPO is significant for its robust subscription figures and the expectation of solid gains for investors on its upcoming listing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/ipo/unimech-aerospace-ipo-listing-on-tuesday-gmp-at-91-08-indicates-robust-gains-for-investors-9170963.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/ipo/unimech-aerospace-ipo-listing-on-tuesday-gmp-at-91-08-indicates-robust-gains-for-investors-9170963.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 21:23:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Government Waives Bank Guarantees; Vodafone Idea Sees Boost for 4G, 5G Investments - TelecomTalk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxNTlN6UTM3Tjh2cUl5enlLLW05SzRDWktwWldoelFrVFVHYUp6elA5LUlQenIwOEk3MThQUG9RbFNiSV81MDhQSWdGVG5hZ1c2MWVvektrek5ycEllQ2czRXFjd2ZING12RXBWV21TRjBWZDhzUjYwLVRHUVB1MkV0UURDaG1BOGlhbXR4UnJn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxNTlN6UTM3Tjh2cUl5enlLLW05SzRDWktwWldoelFrVFVHYUp6elA5LUlQenIwOEk3MThQUG9RbFNiSV81MDhQSWdGVG5hZ1c2MWVvektrek5ycEllQ2czRXFjd2ZING12RXBWV21TRjBWZDhzUjYwLVRHUVB1MkV0UURDaG1BOGlhbXR4UnJn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:05:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vodafone Group clears Rs 11,650 cr dues, releases pledged shares in Vodafone Idea - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vodafone Group Settles ₹11,650 Crore Dues, Releases Shares in Vodafone Idea</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>Vodafone Group has cleared outstanding dues of ₹11,650 crore, releasing its pledged shares in Vodafone Idea.</p><ul><li>The group settled dues secured against its shares in Vodafone Idea.</li><li>Funds were raised through a debt arrangement involving HSBC Corporate Trustee Company (UK).</li><li>Vodafone Group had previously pledged its stake in Indus Towers to fund its rights issue in 2019.</li><li>HSBC released the shares upon repayment of the outstanding dues.</li><li>The Vodafone Group's stake in Vodafone Idea stands at 22.56% post-clearance.</li></ul><blockquote>“On 27 December 2024, HSBC Corporate Trustee Company (UK) Limited acting as the security trustee for the lenders has released the pledges pursuant to repayment of the outstanding dues owed to the lenders by the Vodafone Promoter Shareholders.”</blockquote><p>This settlement allows Vodafone Group to regain its shareholding, enabling potential future investments in the growing Indian telecom market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/telecom/telecom-news/vodafone-group-clears-rs-11650-cr-dues-releases-pledged-shares-in-vodafone-idea/articleshow/116747332.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/telecom/telecom-news/vodafone-group-clears-rs-11650-cr-dues-releases-pledged-shares-in-vodafone-idea/articleshow/116747332.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:54:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Picks for 2025: HDFC Bank to Senco Gold— Religare Broking suggests THESE six stocks to ‘accumulate’ for long-term | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Picks for 2025: HDFC Bank to Senco Gold— Religare Broking suggests THESE six stocks to ‘accumulate’ for long-term</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>Live Mint</p><p>The Indian stock market showed positive performance in 2024 with significant gains, but faced challenges in the second half. Analysts from Religare Broking advise accumulating fundamentally strong stocks for 2025 as several trends could impact markets.</p><ul><li>2024 saw sustained growth in major indices, with Nifty 50 and Sensex reaching new highs.</li><li>Challenges included weak corporate earnings and elevated inflation.</li><li>Key trends for 2025 involve shifts in US trade policies and geopolitical conflicts.</li><li>Analysts recommend focusing on stocks with solid balance sheets during market dips.</li><li>HDFC Bank identified as a key stock due to improvements in its credit-to-deposit ratio.</li></ul><blockquote>“Investors are advised to focus on accumulating fundamentally strong stocks during market dips.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, investors are presented with both opportunities and challenges as they navigate the markets in 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stock-picks-for-2025-hdfc-bank-to-senco-gold-religare-broking-suggests-these-six-stocks-to-accumulate-for-longterm-11735397911523.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stock-picks-for-2025-hdfc-bank-to-senco-gold-religare-broking-suggests-these-six-stocks-to-accumulate-for-longterm-11735397911523.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:06:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rs 20 Lakh Daily To Wipe-Out: Startup Founder Blames Amazon For Running Him Out Of Business - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rs 20 Lakh Daily To Wipe-Out: Startup Founder Blames Amazon For Running Him Out Of Business</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg Quint</p>
<img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2024-12-28%2Fsmb1fst2%2Fheadway-5QgIuuBxKwM-unsplash.jpg?w=1200" alt="The story of the startup founder's rise and fall was shared by Saumil Tripathi, the founder of Grapevine. (Photo source: Unsplash)" />
<figcaption>The story of the startup founder's rise and fall was shared by Saumil Tripathi, the founder of Grapevine. (Photo source: Unsplash)</figcaption>
<p>An Indian entrepreneur's story of how his thriving business was allegedly destroyed by e-commerce giant Amazon has gone viral on social media, shedding light on the challenges faced by small businesses competing against the dominance of larger corporations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The founder, Saumil Tripathi, of Grapevine, shared the story of a startup that made Rs 20 lakh daily before its downfall.</li>
  <li>The startup offered affordable home storage solutions, sourcing products that were significantly cheaper than those on Amazon.</li>
  <li>After declining a nine-figure acquisition offer from Amazon, the startup faced fierce competition when Amazon launched a competing private-label brand.</li>
  <li>The entrepreneur's efforts to cut prices were ineffective against Amazon's ability to undercut further, leading to financial losses.</li>
  <li>Despite challenges, the founder retains financial security but has lost his vision of creating generational wealth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I went from selling 20L of products per day to watching my generational-wealth dream crumble." — Saumil Tripathi</blockquote>
<p>The narrative illustrates the overwhelming challenges small businesses face in the e-commerce landscape dominated by giants like Amazon, raising questions about fair competition and market practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/business/rs-20-lakh-daily-to-wipe-out-startup-founder-blames-amazon-for-running-him-out-of-business</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/business/rs-20-lakh-daily-to-wipe-out-startup-founder-blames-amazon-for-running-him-out-of-business</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:28:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rs 3760 cr! Anil Ambani's 'zero debt' Reliance Group firm bags big financing from THIS Maharatna PSU - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anil Ambani's Reliance Power Secures ₹3760 Crore Financing from Maharatna PSU</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ET Now</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Anil Ambani Reliance Power">
<figcaption>Anil Ambani-led Reliance Power secures financing</figcaption>
<p>Reliance Power, led by Anil Ambani, has secured a significant financing of ₹3760 crore from the Power Finance Corporation (PFC) after recently achieving zero debt status.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The financing will be made available in one or more tranches.</li>
  <li>The funds will be used for general corporate purposes and future investments in renewable energy projects.</li>
  <li>Reliance Power's net worth has increased significantly, reporting ₹14,393 crore for the quarter ending September 2024.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Rosa Power has become a zero-debt company by prepaying ₹485 crore loan to Varde Partners.”</blockquote>
<p>This financing indicates Reliance Power's strategic move towards expanding its renewable energy capabilities while maintaining its commitment to a debt-free operation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/companies/rs-3760-cr-anil-ambanis-zero-debt-reliance-group-firm-bags-big-financing-from-this-maharatna-psu-article-116744338</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/companies/rs-3760-cr-anil-ambanis-zero-debt-reliance-group-firm-bags-big-financing-from-this-maharatna-psu-article-116744338</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:19:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jio Financial Services Share Price: A better stock for long term investment? Market expert Gaurang Shah answers - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is Jio Financial Services a Smart Long-Term Investment? Insights from Market Expert Gaurang Shah</h1><p><strong>Updated Dec 28, 2024</strong> by ET NOW</p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-116744046,updatedat-1735391549682,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/116744046.jpg" alt="jio financial services2"><figcaption>Gaurang Shah of Geojit Financial Services gave an optimistic long-term outlook for Jio Financial Services. (Image: Shutterstock/ET NOW News)</figcaption><p>Market expert Gaurang Shah provides an optimistic perspective on the potential of Jio Financial Services for long-term investors, emphasizing the importance of patience and strategic investment timing.</p><ul><li>Gaurang Shah from Geojit Financial Services shares a positive long-term outlook for Jio Financial Services.</li><li>He stresses a timeframe of 1.5 to 2 years for significant developments due to regulatory processes.</li><li>Investors are advised to hold shares and consider increasing their investments at specific price levels.</li><li>New investors should start accumulating shares for a long-term vision.</li></ul><blockquote>"We do have positive coverage on Jio Financial Services from a long term point of view... our sense is that you need to have at least one and a half, 2 year plus of, kind of time horizon." - Gaurang Shah</blockquote><p>The article highlights Shah's advice for both current and potential investors in Jio Financial Services, focusing on the necessary patience required to see significant impacts from the company's ongoing developments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/jio-financial-services-share-price-a-better-stock-for-long-term-investment-market-expert-gaurang-shah-answers-article-116743962</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/jio-financial-services-share-price-a-better-stock-for-long-term-investment-market-expert-gaurang-shah-answers-article-116743962</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:12:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 New Skoda Cars Confirmed For Debut Next Month In India - GaadiWaadi.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 New Skoda Cars Confirmed For Debut Next Month In India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Gaadi Waadi</p>
<img src="https://gaadiwaadi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/New-Gen-Skoda-Kodiaq-1068x600.jpg" alt="New Gen Skoda Kodiaq">
<figcaption>New Gen Skoda Kodiaq</figcaption>
<p>Skoda India is set to debut five new cars at the Bharat Mobility Global Expo 2025 in New Delhi. This includes two electric vehicles and a high-performance sedan, highlighting the brand's ongoing expansion in the Indian market.</p>
<ul>
<li>New-Gen Skoda Superb, powered by a 2.0L turbocharged petrol engine.</li>
<li>New Skoda Kodiaq with a 7-seater configuration and advanced tech features.</li>
<li>Skoda Octavia RS, featuring a powerful 2.0L turbocharged TSI engine with 265 bhp.</li>
<li>Skoda Elroq EV, an all-electric SUV with multiple battery options and a range of 560 km.</li>
<li>Skoda Enyaq iV, Skoda's first electric car in India with a battery promising 513 km range.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Bharat Mobility Global Expo 2025 will showcase the latest from Skoda as it aligns with the growing demand for electric vehicles in India."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this event marks a significant step for Skoda as it aims to capture the growing Indian automotive market, showcasing a blend of traditional and electric vehicles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://gaadiwaadi.com/5-new-skoda-cars-confirmed-for-debut-next-month-in-india/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gaadiwaadi.com/5-new-skoda-cars-confirmed-for-debut-next-month-in-india/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:00:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upcoming IPO: Payments solution provider Seshaasai Technologies files DRHP with SEBI to raise funds via public issue | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Seshaasai Technologies Files IPO to Raise ₹600 Crore</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Seshaasai Technologies Limited, a Mumbai-based payments solutions provider, has submitted its draft red herring prospectus (DRHP) to SEBI to raise funds of ₹600 crore through a public issue.</p><ul><li>The company specializes in technology for contactless payments, customer communication, and smart traceability across various sectors including education and transport.</li><li>Approximately ₹195.328 crore will be used for expanding manufacturing units, while ₹300 crore will be allocated to repay outstanding borrowings.</li><li>The offer includes an offer-for-sale component where two key individuals will sell around 39.37 lakh equity shares each.</li><li>Seshaasai Technologies posted a net profit of ₹40.48 crore for Q1 of FY 2024-25.</li><li>The company reported a profit of ₹169.27 crore for FY 2023, significant growth from previous years.</li></ul><blockquote>"The loss of key customers may adversely affect the company's business," the firm disclosed in its regulatory filings.</blockquote><p>Seshaasai Technologies aims to leverage this public fundraising to bolster its operations and mitigate existing debt, projecting a strong outlook in the competitive payments solutions market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/upcoming-ipo-payments-solution-provider-seshaasai-technologies-files-drhp-with-sebi-to-raise-funds-via-ipo-11735386975014.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/upcoming-ipo-payments-solution-provider-seshaasai-technologies-files-drhp-with-sebi-to-raise-funds-via-ipo-11735386975014.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:56:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telcos investment recovery in limbo as tariff hike backfires, price war with satcom services likely in 202 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telcos investment recovery in limbo as tariff hike backfires, price war with satcom services likely in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>The article discusses the challenges faced by private telecom operators in India as they struggle with investment recovery due to subscriber loss from tariff hikes and competition from satellite broadband services.</p><ul><li>Private telcos invested around Rs 70,000 crore in telecom infrastructure this year.</li><li>Tariff hikes led to a loss of 2 crore subscribers.</li><li>Key players like Reliance Jio, Bharti Airtel, and Vodafone Idea experienced a combined loss of 2.6 crore customers.</li><li>BSNL gained 68 customers while refraining from price hikes.</li><li>The government is considering spectrum allocation to satellite broadband providers without auctions.</li><li>Potential price wars may emerge affecting telecom financial health.</li></ul><blockquote>“5G deployment has been a game-changer... significant surge in 5G base transceiver stations.” - DIPA</blockquote><p>The telecom sector faces various challenges that could affect its growth, with a balance needed between tariff rationalization and maintaining subscriber experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/telecom/telecom-news/telcos-investment-recovery-in-limbo-as-tariff-hike-backfires-price-war-with-satcom-services-likely-in-2025/articleshow/116743630.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/telecom/telecom-news/telcos-investment-recovery-in-limbo-as-tariff-hike-backfires-price-war-with-satcom-services-likely-in-2025/articleshow/116743630.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:51:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telcos investment recovery in limbo as tariff hike backfires, price war with satcom services likely in 2025 | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telcos investment recovery in limbo as tariff hike backfires, price war with satcom services likely in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified&nbsp;|&nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Private telecom operators in India are struggling with recovering investments due to customer losses after tariff hikes and competition from satellite service providers like Starlink.</p><ul><li>Private operators invested around ₹70,000 crore in telecom infrastructure this year.</li><li>Subscriber loss reached about 2.6 crore due to a price increase of 10-26%.</li><li>BSNL gained customers by refraining from tariff increases.</li><li>The push for 5G services highlights the need for operators to attract and maintain customer interest.</li><li>Concerns grow over satellite broadband threatening the market share of existing telecom companies.</li><li>Political implications arise from spectrum allocation controversies.</li></ul><blockquote>“5G deployment has been a game-changer. We've witnessed a significant surge in 5G base transceiver stations.” - DIPA</blockquote><p>The telecom sector faces a critical juncture as it navigates investment recovery, subscriber retention, and emerging competition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/telcos-investment-recovery-in-limbo-as-tariff-hike-backfires-price-war-with-satcom-services-likely-in-2025-11735389471111.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/telcos-investment-recovery-in-limbo-as-tariff-hike-backfires-price-war-with-satcom-services-likely-in-2025-11735389471111.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:37:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PPI interoperability: How RBI’s new UPI rule set to ease digital payments? An explainer | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PPIs Interoperability: How RBI’s New UPI Rule Set to Ease Digital Payments? An Explainer</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has enabled users of prepaid payment instruments (PPIs) to access UPI services through third-party applications, a significant step to enhance the digital payment ecosystem in India.</p><h2>Key Differences: UPI and PPIs</h2><ul><li>UPI allows bank-to-bank money transfers, while PPIs are mobile wallets with pre-loaded funds.</li><li>Interoperability between PPIs and UPI is now permitted, allowing easier transactions across platforms.</li></ul><h2>Current Ecosystem</h2><ul><li>Some PPIs like PhonePe and MobiKwik already had limited UPI access.</li><li>The new rule will expand UPI usage to third-party apps.</li></ul><h2>Users' New Flexibility</h2><ul><li>PPI users can now use any third-party UPI app for transactions.</li><li>This follows the RBI's plan announced in April 2024 for broader PPI integration.</li></ul><blockquote>“UPI’s popularity... will likely encourage more users to adopt digital wallets.” – Ankush Julka, COO, Mufin Pay</blockquote><p>This new rule from RBI aims to significantly boost the ease of digital payments in India, benefiting users with greater flexibility and broader integration with payment systems.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/ppi-interoperability-how-rbi-s-new-upi-rule-set-to-ease-digital-payments-an-explainer-11735386893536.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/ppi-interoperability-how-rbi-s-new-upi-rule-set-to-ease-digital-payments-an-explainer-11735386893536.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:11:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cochin Shipyard bags Adani Ports tug boat order, deal value estimated at ₹450 crore - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cochin Shipyard Wins ₹450 Crore Tug Boat Order from Adani Ports</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, Source: Live Mint</p>
<p>Adani Ports has ordered eight tug boats from Cochin Shipyard Ltd, valued at ₹450 crore, to enhance its maritime infrastructure.</p>
<img src="path_to_image.jpg" alt="Cochin Shipyard" />
<figcaption>Cochin Shipyard's Tug Boat</figcaption>
<p>The order consists of eight 70 T Bollard Pull ASD Tugs, expected to be delivered from December 2026 to August 2028.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Adani Ports and SEZ orders eight tug boats from Cochin Shipyard.</li>
  <li>The deal is valued at ₹450 crore, falling under the “Significant” category of ₹200 to ₹500 crore.</li>
  <li>Tug deliveries are set to begin in December 2026.</li>
  <li>This order will expand Adani's tug boat fleet to 152.</li>
  <li>Adani aims to strengthen local manufacturing with this collaboration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This collaboration signifies our commitment to enhancing maritime infrastructure in India and demonstrates our confidence in our nation's PSUs.” - Ashwani Gupta, CEO of Adani Ports</blockquote>
<p>This significant order highlights the growing cooperation between private companies and public sector units in India’s maritime sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/cochin-shipyard-bags-adani-ports-tug-boat-order-deal-value-estimated-at-rs-450-crore-11735382563877.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/cochin-shipyard-bags-adani-ports-tug-boat-order-deal-value-estimated-at-rs-450-crore-11735382563877.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:26:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cochin Shipyard bags Adani Ports tug boat order, deal value estimated at ₹450 crore | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cochin Shipyard Wins ₹450 Crore Tug Boat Order from Adani Ports</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, Source: Live Mint</p>
<p>Adani Ports has ordered eight tug boats from Cochin Shipyard Ltd, valued at ₹450 crore, to enhance its maritime infrastructure.</p>
<img src="path_to_image.jpg" alt="Cochin Shipyard" />
<figcaption>Cochin Shipyard's Tug Boat</figcaption>
<p>The order consists of eight 70 T Bollard Pull ASD Tugs, expected to be delivered from December 2026 to August 2028.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Adani Ports and SEZ orders eight tug boats from Cochin Shipyard.</li>
  <li>The deal is valued at ₹450 crore, falling under the “Significant” category of ₹200 to ₹500 crore.</li>
  <li>Tug deliveries are set to begin in December 2026.</li>
  <li>This order will expand Adani's tug boat fleet to 152.</li>
  <li>Adani aims to strengthen local manufacturing with this collaboration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This collaboration signifies our commitment to enhancing maritime infrastructure in India and demonstrates our confidence in our nation's PSUs.” - Ashwani Gupta, CEO of Adani Ports</blockquote>
<p>This significant order highlights the growing cooperation between private companies and public sector units in India’s maritime sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/cochin-shipyard-bags-adani-ports-tug-boat-order-deal-value-estimated-at-rs-450-crore-11735382563877.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/cochin-shipyard-bags-adani-ports-tug-boat-order-deal-value-estimated-at-rs-450-crore-11735382563877.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:26:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vodafone Group clears about Rs 11,650 cr dues to lenders raised against VIL shares - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6wFBVV95cUxQaUdObzI4M05NMVJvVFlaWUxKcE1lZ0hIOXhBOHJxQVluV01CVWZnMVR5RThENHJYeVpTTWZ0SFMxTzRkMGZKQzUwaXNQVkxFYnBFcEJ1eksyT2prVlR6ZFA1U1otZ2pHZ25idlFxT0pzOWVqaG5wQ3h3cEpESm41Z0piY3ZzV1dvaE45OGxZTDUxejktOVNZaTNpZkRTX1BiVl9uZy03LWd1endJc2NaWDFUdmU3ZnNCY09LTXZyUGtHM1VpOXpSU1RheHBlck9MYXNHTEh5bmk5VFJsbmNJaXdhZUo3dkVCOUhr0gHwAUFVX3lxTFBKYkpQUkpOTXQ3OU1MUi03eGdpVm1xZnViTjJJVGwxd0RXZ1JyRGFLUU1IVHlmWENYZGFsQzNvUUtNR2ZGSkxYY3JrYWZrREpBQ0QxNDZDQ3FnX2tpUTlMWDdBT1dIME96eHFaSmRRR1BsbUE4VHhEc2Rocmpzd0JwZnBPQmJHWlJOaFdFSWF0Ynlaa2lxVTV2RU5WTW5FaTBJbi0wVGJLQWxyTlFCSlVkQVo3YTNwWEc1Z2otTXpGRzVfSmdUVW90SFhQSmo2QnFLczVpS2dBaU1VZ0xDd20xMXdOdjRZSXdGcXpITF9Faw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6wFBVV95cUxQaUdObzI4M05NMVJvVFlaWUxKcE1lZ0hIOXhBOHJxQVluV01CVWZnMVR5RThENHJYeVpTTWZ0SFMxTzRkMGZKQzUwaXNQVkxFYnBFcEJ1eksyT2prVlR6ZFA1U1otZ2pHZ25idlFxT0pzOWVqaG5wQ3h3cEpESm41Z0piY3ZzV1dvaE45OGxZTDUxejktOVNZaTNpZkRTX1BiVl9uZy03LWd1endJc2NaWDFUdmU3ZnNCY09LTXZyUGtHM1VpOXpSU1RheHBlck9MYXNHTEh5bmk5VFJsbmNJaXdhZUo3dkVCOUhr0gHwAUFVX3lxTFBKYkpQUkpOTXQ3OU1MUi03eGdpVm1xZnViTjJJVGwxd0RXZ1JyRGFLUU1IVHlmWENYZGFsQzNvUUtNR2ZGSkxYY3JrYWZrREpBQ0QxNDZDQ3FnX2tpUTlMWDdBT1dIME96eHFaSmRRR1BsbUE4VHhEc2Rocmpzd0JwZnBPQmJHWlJOaFdFSWF0Ynlaa2lxVTV2RU5WTW5FaTBJbi0wVGJLQWxyTlFCSlVkQVo3YTNwWEc1Z2otTXpGRzVfSmdUVW90SFhQSmo2QnFLczVpS2dBaU1VZ0xDd20xMXdOdjRZSXdGcXpITF9Faw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:46:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IPO calendar next week: 2 new issues, 6 listings to close out a robust year of primary market - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IPO Calendar Next Week: 2 New Issues and 6 Listings to End a Strong Year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>It's been a remarkable year for India's IPO market, and as we enter the last week of 2024, two IPOs from Indo Farm Equipment and Technichem Organics will close out what is the most vibrant year for the primary market.</p><ul><li>Two new IPOs are on the table: Indo Farm Equipment and Technichem Organics.</li><li>Indo Farm Equipment's IPO will open on December 31 and conclude on January 2.</li><li>The price band for Indo Farm Equipment is set at Rs 204-215.</li><li>Technichem Organics is available for bidding until January 2, priced at Rs 52-55 per share.</li><li>This year, Indian companies have raised a record Rs 1.3 lakh crore through IPOs.</li><li>Analysts expect the fundraising momentum to continue into 2025, potentially exceeding Rs 2 lakh crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“This year, companies have cumulatively raised a record Rs 1.3 lakh crore,” experts say.</blockquote><p>The IPO landscape is expected to remain vibrant as we transition into the next year, with significant opportunities for investors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/ipos/fpos/ipo-calendar-next-week-2-new-issues-6-listings-to-close-out-a-robust-year-of-primary-market/articleshow/116740426.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/ipos/fpos/ipo-calendar-next-week-2-new-issues-6-listings-to-close-out-a-robust-year-of-primary-market/articleshow/116740426.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:46:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Time To Say Good-Bye To India’s Favourite Brand? - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxPQXpIQ1lUUHY2N3JFR214eUduV0ZFY1FWM3BwWEdWUTFvR2RVd0VVUlJHSmtIOXJTRFBqMWc5cTljUldHSFRrNjV4TmZpNTFmZ0dFT3czVlNTMUR5Z0g3RC1UVFFLemFQUmVMU2JCZFR6Rk55YmZRbU9pLW16ajc1MkhMS2VGc0haNGfSAYoBQVVfeXFMT0F6SENZVFB2NjdyRUdteHlHbldGRWNRVjNwcFhHVlExb0dkVXdFVVJSR0prSDlyU0RQajFnOXE5Y1JXR0hUazY1eE5maTUxZmdHRU93M1ZTUzFEeWdIN0QtVFRRS3phUFJlTFNiQmRUekZOeWJmUW1PaS1temo3NTJITEtlRnNIWjRn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxPQXpIQ1lUUHY2N3JFR214eUduV0ZFY1FWM3BwWEdWUTFvR2RVd0VVUlJHSmtIOXJTRFBqMWc5cTljUldHSFRrNjV4TmZpNTFmZ0dFT3czVlNTMUR5Z0g3RC1UVFFLemFQUmVMU2JCZFR6Rk55YmZRbU9pLW16ajc1MkhMS2VGc0haNGfSAYoBQVVfeXFMT0F6SENZVFB2NjdyRUdteHlHbldGRWNRVjNwcFhHVlExb0dkVXdFVVJSR0prSDlyU0RQajFnOXE5Y1JXR0hUazY1eE5maTUxZmdHRU93M1ZTUzFEeWdIN0QtVFRRS3phUFJlTFNiQmRUekZOeWJmUW1PaS1temo3NTJITEtlRnNIWjRn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:21:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vodafone Group clears about Rs 11,650 cr dues raised against VIL shares - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vodafone Clears Rs 11,650 Crore Dues from VIL Shares</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 28 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Press Trust of India</p>
<img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" title="Vodafone" alt="Vodafone" width="826" height="465">
<figcaption>Vodafone has cleared dues against VIL shares.</figcaption>
<p>UK-based Vodafone Group has successfully cleared dues of approximately Rs 11,650 crore against shares of Vodafone Idea Limited (VIL), reaffirming its financial commitments.</p>
<ul>
<li>Vodafone had pledged nearly its entire stake in VIL to secure the debt.</li>
<li>The dues were cleared as of December 27, 2024, through HSBC Corporate Trustee Company (UK).</li>
<li>The shares in question are valued at around Rs 11,649 crore based on the closing price of Rs 7.41 per share.</li>
<li>Vodafone holds a 22.56% stake in VIL, while Aditya Birla Group and the government hold 14.76% and 23.15% shares respectively.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Consequently, the indirect encumbrance on 15,720,826,860 equity shares... has been released."</blockquote>
<p>This clearance demonstrates Vodafone's ongoing strategy to stabilize its finances and potentially strengthen its position in the Indian telecom market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/vodafone-group-clears-about-rs-11-650-cr-dues-raised-against-vil-shares-124122800394_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/vodafone-group-clears-about-rs-11-650-cr-dues-raised-against-vil-shares-124122800394_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:06:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Market Holiday On New Year? NSE, BSE open or closed on January 1, Wednesday? Check here - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Holiday On New Year - NSE and BSE Open on January 1, 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW</p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="stock market holiday on new year"><figcaption>Stock market holiday on New Year (Pic: ET NOW)</figcaption><p>The National Stock Exchange (NSE) and BSE confirm that the stock market will be open on January 1, 2025, despite it being a public holiday.</p><ul><li>The stock market will operate normally on January 1, with trading hours from 9:15 AM to 3:30 PM.</li><li>The NSE and BSE have listed 14 holidays for the year 2025, with January 1 not included.</li><li>January 2025 will see the stock market closed on 8 days, all Saturdays and Sundays.</li><li>February 1, the Budget Day, will also see regular trading hours at the stock exchanges.</li></ul><blockquote>“Trading on January 1, 2025 will be as usual in the equity, equity derivatives segment and Securities Lending and Borrowing (SLB) segments.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, traders can expect the stock market to function as normal on New Year's Day, providing clarity for traders looking ahead to the start of 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/stock-market-holiday-on-new-year-nse-bse-open-or-closed-on-january-1-wednesday-check-here-article-116738886</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/stock-market-holiday-on-new-year-nse-bse-open-or-closed-on-january-1-wednesday-check-here-article-116738886</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:04:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Multibagger stock to buy now: Ventura Securities sees 110% upside in Adani Energy Solutions share price | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwJBVV95cUxOQndTVkl4RkRmdTh6Q0o1ZXFuZGNGZG1JNC14Y3VEaE9zd2RIR21GMGk4Qk5NTTNleEphYlZGT09jR2R6MTFiWTJxZ2VBNTFNVnR3bzFQcVhkM2dhcnN4Nm9IWXBkdDhJaFQwZEN5UVNUejBMWHNXendENVg0bjU3ZDdYOVhuYU92NktMWmRTNVhUblZyMi0zYmI3eFo2V2Z3RzlabGpiRzkyU2hnZWhFd1N5VkY0SFAtbVI4SHBsRGxZbGRxME9fT3pmUFlMTXpNZzZKdUozaEhjbjkzdkY0cm5PX3BCY0d3TDlJSl8wYkR5TWpnbmlwYVBvZWppYkZtVUdR0gGIAkFVX3lxTE42cDYyX0o3c0Y5cVpyR0JTZWtzMF9iWEt3N1g2b0JqLXpzcjg1ZmJqdzJjNmlZeFlwNFFLc2J3cTJLd0VSSmIteDdsSGpwcmpMUXpxRFYzMlFEc0RFTzh6bHlIbUNGdlg1elVpN3NEdzFwejNpQlNyUktDbV93Wk1PNEt4OGwyUXRyb0N2Y3d0ZzdWcFR1aW5Na1Vna1lTLWZ2V1ZHNUw4S1Fmbkk0cWNfZzV3MUFOTTBHazhRSF8xbmJyVWJKLXZOZTBCS0dJSkJHeWZsd3I0elVOd0pIcUlKSFRKYWxqUk9sSVV4MFJfVHlaaEs1UDJqcms0WmhFVWtObUtzMXpqOQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwJBVV95cUxOQndTVkl4RkRmdTh6Q0o1ZXFuZGNGZG1JNC14Y3VEaE9zd2RIR21GMGk4Qk5NTTNleEphYlZGT09jR2R6MTFiWTJxZ2VBNTFNVnR3bzFQcVhkM2dhcnN4Nm9IWXBkdDhJaFQwZEN5UVNUejBMWHNXendENVg0bjU3ZDdYOVhuYU92NktMWmRTNVhUblZyMi0zYmI3eFo2V2Z3RzlabGpiRzkyU2hnZWhFd1N5VkY0SFAtbVI4SHBsRGxZbGRxME9fT3pmUFlMTXpNZzZKdUozaEhjbjkzdkY0cm5PX3BCY0d3TDlJSl8wYkR5TWpnbmlwYVBvZWppYkZtVUdR0gGIAkFVX3lxTE42cDYyX0o3c0Y5cVpyR0JTZWtzMF9iWEt3N1g2b0JqLXpzcjg1ZmJqdzJjNmlZeFlwNFFLc2J3cTJLd0VSSmIteDdsSGpwcmpMUXpxRFYzMlFEc0RFTzh6bHlIbUNGdlg1elVpN3NEdzFwejNpQlNyUktDbV93Wk1PNEt4OGwyUXRyb0N2Y3d0ZzdWcFR1aW5Na1Vna1lTLWZ2V1ZHNUw4S1Fmbkk0cWNfZzV3MUFOTTBHazhRSF8xbmJyVWJKLXZOZTBCS0dJSkJHeWZsd3I0elVOd0pIcUlKSFRKYWxqUk9sSVV4MFJfVHlaaEs1UDJqcms0WmhFVWtObUtzMXpqOQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:45:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Greaves Electric Mobility IPO: Rs 1000 cr! Vijay Kedia-backed company's EV arm to list soon - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Greaves Electric Mobility IPO: Rs 1000 crore!</h1>
<p><strong>Updated:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW News</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Greaves Electric Mobility IPO" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Greaves Electric Mobility IPO: Vijay Kedia bought 12 lakh shares for Rs 25 crore via a block deal on December 9.</figcaption>
<p>Greaves Electric Mobility Limited (GEML) has filed a draft red herring prospectus (DRHP) to raise Rs 1,000 crore through an initial public offering (IPO). The company is a subsidiary of Greaves Cotton and manufacturing electric vehicles like Ampere, Eltra, and Ele.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The IPO will consist of a fresh issue of equity shares of up to Rs 1,000 crore.</li>
  <li>Vijay Kedia recently acquired 0.52% stake in Greaves Cotton by purchasing 12 lakh shares for Rs 25 crore.</li>
  <li>Greaves Cotton will sell up to 5.1 crore shares while Abdul Latif Jameel Green Mobility Solutions will sell up to 13.83 crore shares.</li>
  <li>The company may also consider a pre-IPO placement aggregating up to Rs 200 crore before filing of the red herring prospectus.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The average buying price was Rs 208.9 per share. This comes after the company approved an IPO for its subsidiary, GEML."</blockquote>
<p>This IPO represents a significant move for Greaves Electric Mobility as it positions itself within the growing EV market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/greaves-electric-mobility-ipo-rs-1000-cr-vijay-kedia-backed-company-greaves-cotton-share-price-ev-arm-to-list-soon-article-116733464</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/greaves-electric-mobility-ipo-rs-1000-cr-vijay-kedia-backed-company-greaves-cotton-share-price-ev-arm-to-list-soon-article-116733464</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:39:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Mutual Funds: These equity schemes across market cap gave highest returns in the past 1 year. Do you own any? | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Best Mutual Funds: These equity schemes across market cap gave highest returns in the past 1 year. Do you own any?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>This article evaluates the top-performing mutual fund schemes across various market capitalizations, highlighting their past one-year returns and emphasizing the importance of considering additional factors beyond returns when investing.</p>
<h2>Key Points:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The DSP Top 100 Equity Fund reported the highest return of 22.24% among large cap funds.</li>
<li>Nippon India Large Cap Fund has significant assets under management (AUM) of ₹35,779 crore with a return of 19.75%.</li>
<li>In the mid cap segment, Invesco India Mid Cap Fund leads with a return of 44.48%.</li>
<li>The small cap category is topped by Bandhan Small Cap Fund with returns over 44%.</li>
<li>Past performance is not indicative of future results, and investors should always consider a scheme's overall metrics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Past returns give no guarantee of a scheme’s future returns."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while these mutual funds have shown impressive gains, it is essential to conduct thorough research and consider various factors before making investment decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/best-mutual-funds-these-equity-schemes-across-market-cap-gave-highest-returns-in-the-past-1-year-do-you-own-any-11735377183159.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/best-mutual-funds-these-equity-schemes-across-market-cap-gave-highest-returns-in-the-past-1-year-do-you-own-any-11735377183159.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:30:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai mother buys ₹27.5 lakh mini Kelly bag for daughter to ‘carry lipstick’ during honeymoon; netizens shocked | Video | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxON3Nwc0xJbEZ6ZDZUQS1LOGp1T2d5UUZqaFhtYW9kam52andqd0hjV3JzLXFLNzF5NzkxRUQzZkluSm0wZ0ZMMXJqWk96VkVQUmJacHNfRmpkVFhGQ3ktRzNVaFlwb3BhYXFqa2lTckhRaDlva3hkSHlJeS0xc2FPRXpCYTdMMG5DdWZ0UEJKd1JBZzVWbFZOUmlGUnAzQ2pvUmUzbC1JM2ZsYk43bzBQbGtuVHdfZFZEUUtxb0Q1M214YUE1c1JvMjZkOUxlanM5bmtoLUhUNmpNNHNpOTExZ21RdlFpWFhBUDZvUG1IalZIQTNmSEZPQWlpRHdXczdw0gGGAkFVX3lxTFBBMkgzWTJZZGRlLTFmSktJWEJkNWNVVHBIMHVqa0ZTeFp1RnVLMjlTWU5kZXFkNzByWlRkeEQwYzJLVHc5OEIteE00YW9RcVdsa0NkTkJ6NHlkazMxQTRRWm1tZk4wS2tlZmp5U1N1dFphYWd4azRiYUhrUFBXOUk1N3dnZjNVT2puX0hscFVDeGdmS1FzNlN1dVBhTGI4anEwbTZHU1VoakVtSE1MbVBqSHIxYXR3YTRYZkZ0eEtYeVZRRTBQSXhmanhIRjZHV285amxMU01MQlVvaWNhLU5ydDUxVkgtaTByY3VLVU1ZVGwxbzdZVGg1QU1YU21fenBESWFHY0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxON3Nwc0xJbEZ6ZDZUQS1LOGp1T2d5UUZqaFhtYW9kam52andqd0hjV3JzLXFLNzF5NzkxRUQzZkluSm0wZ0ZMMXJqWk96VkVQUmJacHNfRmpkVFhGQ3ktRzNVaFlwb3BhYXFqa2lTckhRaDlva3hkSHlJeS0xc2FPRXpCYTdMMG5DdWZ0UEJKd1JBZzVWbFZOUmlGUnAzQ2pvUmUzbC1JM2ZsYk43bzBQbGtuVHdfZFZEUUtxb0Q1M214YUE1c1JvMjZkOUxlanM5bmtoLUhUNmpNNHNpOTExZ21RdlFpWFhBUDZvUG1IalZIQTNmSEZPQWlpRHdXczdw0gGGAkFVX3lxTFBBMkgzWTJZZGRlLTFmSktJWEJkNWNVVHBIMHVqa0ZTeFp1RnVLMjlTWU5kZXFkNzByWlRkeEQwYzJLVHc5OEIteE00YW9RcVdsa0NkTkJ6NHlkazMxQTRRWm1tZk4wS2tlZmp5U1N1dFphYWd4azRiYUhrUFBXOUk1N3dnZjNVT2puX0hscFVDeGdmS1FzNlN1dVBhTGI4anEwbTZHU1VoakVtSE1MbVBqSHIxYXR3YTRYZkZ0eEtYeVZRRTBQSXhmanhIRjZHV285amxMU01MQlVvaWNhLU5ydDUxVkgtaTByY3VLVU1ZVGwxbzdZVGg1QU1YU21fenBESWFHY0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:24:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RIL acquires healthcare startup Karkinos for Rs 375 cr in all-cash deal - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RIL acquires healthcare startup Karkinos for Rs 375 cr in all-cash deal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Saturday, <strong>Source:</strong> Reliance Industries</p><p>Reliance Industries, led by billionaire Mukesh Ambani, has acquired Karkinos Healthcare for Rs 375 crore, aiming to enhance its healthcare services through innovative cancer solutions.</p><ul><li>Acquisition completed by Reliance Strategic Business Ventures (RSBVL).</li><li>Karkinos specializes in early detection and management of cancer.</li><li>Karkinos had a turnover of about Rs 22 crore in FY 2022-23.</li><li>The company has partnered with around 60 hospitals and is setting up a 150-bed cancer hospital in Imphal, Manipur.</li><li>Previous investors included Tata Sons, Reliance Digital Health, and Mayo Clinic.</li></ul><blockquote>“The acquisition of Karkinos will help expand the health services business portfolio of the Reliance group,” the filing said.</blockquote><p>The acquisition reflects Reliance's strategic move to diversify into healthcare, particularly oncology services, which are in high demand.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/reliance-acquires-startup-karkinos-with-1-cr-shares-ofcds-for-rs-375-cr-124122800308_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/reliance-acquires-startup-karkinos-with-1-cr-shares-ofcds-for-rs-375-cr-124122800308_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:04:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hit and miss in 2024, but what's the future for India's Rs 8,000 crore-plus IPOs - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxNdVlVMW1kYWVSMUFrMW9XRHFUWWEzV2FPc0ZURVdJNjFBYUFHOWg5SnFxS2lpNGE3YnU2UE9XM2VpWHNWX1ZsRUF5SldpUE5oUWxMM1pzMl9vOWF5TFFITmFITEtkbGgxMTRzXzlmX096eEFGaUNuZHY4aGU2TG1RV2gzQzNITkRpS1BvN3JsT05uOFpLUnd5MEpaZXpsZDNzS1RaQ0ZzOTZBRENEakFkVU9TS3BWQjlPRG8tM1FQeHllbDdWVVYwTDViQkRGVmRnY1Uwd0I3UXctY2w5cFJkVmxaU1nSAeoBQVVfeXFMUElseVVLdkFMRlIwM2RCMTNlQkNYdTI0MVZwd2tiS3B4OGN2TFprSHBXUXhhQ2tqZ2JzQ2NiUGJJSEJtc0tLWUNRNkFIbFRMYlI2Z3hKZVNfWnlzS0pUVXJtRE9aS1V3Y2l3Q1FfVFBLZE5jbVh4cmJZbFFQTW9ydklpdi1GTGp6cXItRklKcHk0NzdtdndaTEdCSEwtclVoelpzWHdrcHZaVDYtWEMxTVNmLVBQVGpKU1dubV9oMmNTbGs5SXhuR0otckNRVy05SXVhMDZlWmNzMko2Y0xlNjFkTTNDM2I1N2ln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxNdVlVMW1kYWVSMUFrMW9XRHFUWWEzV2FPc0ZURVdJNjFBYUFHOWg5SnFxS2lpNGE3YnU2UE9XM2VpWHNWX1ZsRUF5SldpUE5oUWxMM1pzMl9vOWF5TFFITmFITEtkbGgxMTRzXzlmX096eEFGaUNuZHY4aGU2TG1RV2gzQzNITkRpS1BvN3JsT05uOFpLUnd5MEpaZXpsZDNzS1RaQ0ZzOTZBRENEakFkVU9TS3BWQjlPRG8tM1FQeHllbDdWVVYwTDViQkRGVmRnY1Uwd0I3UXctY2w5cFJkVmxaU1nSAeoBQVVfeXFMUElseVVLdkFMRlIwM2RCMTNlQkNYdTI0MVZwd2tiS3B4OGN2TFprSHBXUXhhQ2tqZ2JzQ2NiUGJJSEJtc0tLWUNRNkFIbFRMYlI2Z3hKZVNfWnlzS0pUVXJtRE9aS1V3Y2l3Q1FfVFBLZE5jbVh4cmJZbFFQTW9ydklpdi1GTGp6cXItRklKcHk0NzdtdndaTEdCSEwtclVoelpzWHdrcHZaVDYtWEMxTVNmLVBQVGpKU1dubV9oMmNTbGs5SXhuR0otckNRVy05SXVhMDZlWmNzMko2Y0xlNjFkTTNDM2I1N2ln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:55:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Buy or sell: Sumeet Bagadia recommends three stocks to buy on Monday — 30 December 2024 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sumeet Bagadia's Stock Recommendations for December 30, 2024</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Indian stock markets traded sideways as the Nifty 50 index struggled against a major resistance level. Sumeet Bagadia from Choice Broking has suggested three stocks for investors to consider buying next week.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>The Nifty 50 index closed at 23,832, failing to break the resistance at 23,850.</li><li>Bagadia recommends purchasing Can Fin Homes, Dr Reddy's Laboratories, and Mahindra & Mahindra.</li><li>The stocks show consolidating price patterns with specific buy targets and stop-loss levels.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes</h2><blockquote>"The current range of the Nifty 50 index is 23,200 to 23,850, and a bullish or bearish trend can be assumed on the breakage of either side of the range."</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>Investors looking to leverage potential market movements should consider the suggested stocks, keeping an eye on their respective support and resistance levels.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/buy-or-sell-sumeet-bagadia-recommends-three-stocks-to-buy-on-monday-30-december-2024-11735374697985.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/buy-or-sell-sumeet-bagadia-recommends-three-stocks-to-buy-on-monday-30-december-2024-11735374697985.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:52:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4 SUVs To Buy Instead Of Tata Punch! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>4 SUVs To Consider Instead of Tata Punch</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> MotorOctane</p><img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/twilight-purple-right.webp" alt="Tata Nexon" /><figcaption>Tata Nexon</figcaption><p>The Tata Punch is highly sought after in India due to its value and safety features. However, consumers are exploring alternatives. Here are four SUVs that serve as alternatives to the Tata Punch.</p><ul><li><strong>Tata Nexon:</strong> A larger, safer option priced from Rs 9.40 lakh (on-road, Mumbai).</li><li><strong>Mahindra XUV3XO:</strong> Offers powerful engine options and features starting from Rs 9.16 lakh.</li><li><strong>Skoda Kylaq:</strong> Known for its features and safety, priced from Rs 9.07 lakh.</li><li><strong>Nissan Magnite:</strong> Affordable option starting from Rs 7.04 lakh, providing better features than before.</li></ul><blockquote>“The new Nissan Magnite is now offered with all features that it lacked in its previous iterations.”</blockquote><p>These alternatives provide various features, pricing, and performance capabilities, making them strong competitors against the Tata Punch.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/281549-4-suvs-to-buy-instead-of-tata-punch</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/281549-4-suvs-to-buy-instead-of-tata-punch</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PF rules change in 2025: Key EPFO rule changes to expect in 2025 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxQOU5XNUdZbTQ4Wm5oTENXQ2VwY0tkVVQtZE52WVROZjlOUUxrX3dFeXhWRHRicG4xN1diVlhsMWV1Zjc2c09jaS1KbTV6TlNBTWVBdmgyeEtrVDZrLVBIYzVkdEVtb3FjdmRDckctM3ZrSVhOSmQxT0hsSEdPbXlXWGZhRDRzRFZrQ1NHdnRQVXRtZjRmQXNDbENCSUU4a0NEQzBudEFZdVpGT3dmYjBieU9fSTQ0UGs2T0lUdmJlR1ZGSDhzXzVIQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxQOU5XNUdZbTQ4Wm5oTENXQ2VwY0tkVVQtZE52WVROZjlOUUxrX3dFeXhWRHRicG4xN1diVlhsMWV1Zjc2c09jaS1KbTV6TlNBTWVBdmgyeEtrVDZrLVBIYzVkdEVtb3FjdmRDckctM3ZrSVhOSmQxT0hsSEdPbXlXWGZhRDRzRFZrQ1NHdnRQVXRtZjRmQXNDbENCSUU4a0NEQzBudEFZdVpGT3dmYjBieU9fSTQ0UGs2T0lUdmJlR1ZGSDhzXzVIQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:36:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI announces significant changes in its structure - Softonic EN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://en.softonic.com/articles/openai-announces-significant-changes-in-its-structure</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.softonic.com/articles/openai-announces-significant-changes-in-its-structure</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:36:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance acquires Karkinos Healthcare for Rs 375 crore - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Reliance Acquires Karkinos Healthcare for Rs 375 Crore</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Saturday</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>The acquisition of Karkinos Healthcare by Reliance Industries marks a significant move in the oncology-focused healthcare sector, aiming to enhance early cancer detection and management.</p><ul><li>Reliance Industries acquired Karkinos Healthcare for Rs 375 crore.</li><li>Karkinos, founded on July 24, 2020, specializes in early cancer detection and treatment solutions.</li><li>The company partnered with around 60 hospitals and is developing a 150-bed cancer hospital in Imphal, Manipur.</li><li>The acquisition enhances Reliance's health services portfolio and was approved by the National Company Law Tribunal (NCLT).</li></ul><blockquote>"The acquisition of Karkinos will help expand the health services business portfolio of the Reliance group," the filing said.</blockquote><p>The acquisition of Karkinos represents a strategic expansion of Reliance's healthcare services, targeting the growing need for cancer care in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/healthcare/biotech/healthcare/reliance-acquires-karkinos-healthcare-for-rs-375-crore/articleshow/116736741.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/healthcare/biotech/healthcare/reliance-acquires-karkinos-healthcare-for-rs-375-crore/articleshow/116736741.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:22:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>