<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 12:34:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 12:34:38 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NTPC Green Energy Share Price: 1000MW solar project from UPPCL! Time to BUY shares? Check target - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NTPC Green Energy's 1000MW Solar Project: A Strong Investment Opportunity?</h1>
<p><strong>Updated:</strong> January 5, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW News</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-116939515,updatedat-1735984285674,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/116939515.jpg" alt="ntpc green 2" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>NTPC REL secured a capacity of 1000 MW at an impressive tariff of Rs 2.56/kWh.</figcaption>
<p>NTPC Renewable Energy Limited has emerged as a successful bidder for a 1000 MW solar power project, securing a competitive tariff while awaiting the letter of award from UPPCL.</p>
<ul>
<li>NTPC REL secured a capacity of 1000 MW at Rs 2.56/kWh.</li>
<li>Share price closed at Rs 128.35, showing a 0.35% increase on the BSE.</li>
<li>NTPC Renewable Energy began commercial delivery of 30 MW from its 150 MW solar plant in Gujarat.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The market expert has given a BUY rating to the stock, with a target range of Rs 134-Rs 139 at the stop loss of Rs 120."</blockquote>
<p>This significant project highlights NTPC's commitment to renewable energy and presents a promising investment opportunity in the changing energy landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/ntpc-green-energy-share-price-1000mw-solar-project-from-uppcl-time-to-buy-shares-check-target-article-116939481</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/ntpc-green-energy-share-price-1000mw-solar-project-from-uppcl-time-to-buy-shares-check-target-article-116939481</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 11:53:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to buy under ₹100: Sumeet Bagadia recommends three shares to buy tomorrow — 6 January 2025 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to buy under ₹100: Sumeet Bagadia recommends three shares to buy tomorrow — 6 January 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 6 January 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The domestic stock market faced significant losses on 3 January due to profit booking, but remains cautiously optimistic according to stock analyst Sumeet Bagadia. Despite the drop, the Nifty 50 index sustained above important support levels.</p><h2>Sumeet Bagadia's stock recommendations</h2><ul><li><strong>South Indian Bank Ltd. (SOUTHBANK)</strong>: Buy at ₹26.96; Target at ₹29; Stop Loss at ₹26.</li><li><strong>Lloyds Engineering Works Ltd. (LLOYDSENGG)</strong>: Buy at ₹85.29; Target at ₹92; Stop Loss at ₹82.</li><li><strong>Paramount Communications Ltd. (PARACABLES)</strong>: Buy at ₹85.1; Target at ₹91; Stop Loss at ₹82.5.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite a heavy sell-off on Friday, the Indian stock market bias is cautiously optimistic.” - Sumeet Bagadia</blockquote><p>Investors are advised to consult certified experts before making investment decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stocks-to-buy-under-rs-100-sumeet-bagadia-recommends-three-shares-to-buy-tomorrow-6-january-2025-11736070343552.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stocks-to-buy-under-rs-100-sumeet-bagadia-recommends-three-shares-to-buy-tomorrow-6-january-2025-11736070343552.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 10:32:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foreign investors pull out Rs 4,285 crore from Indian equities amid high valuations, global headwinds - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Foreign Investors Withdraw ₹4,285 Crore from Indian Equities Amid High Valuations and Global Challenges</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>Foreign investors have pulled out ₹4,285 crore from Indian equities due to high valuations and global headwinds, reflecting a significant shift in market dynamics.</p>
<ul>
<li>The outflow is attributed to rising global inflation and interest rates.</li>
<li>Investors are concerned about the sustainability of high valuations in Indian markets.</li>
<li>This marks a notable trend of foreign exit amidst a generally bullish domestic market.</li>
<li>Experts warn that continued outflows could impact market stability.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The current environment of high valuations combined with global uncertainties is making foreign investors cautious," an analyst noted.</blockquote>
<p>This trend indicates a need for the Indian market to reassess its positioning in the face of global financial challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/foreign-investors-pull-out-rs-4285-crore-from-indian-equities-amid-high-valuations-global-headwinds/articleshow/116964463.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/foreign-investors-pull-out-rs-4285-crore-from-indian-equities-amid-high-valuations-global-headwinds/articleshow/116964463.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 10:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New York imposes first ever congestion pricing plan in US.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New York Implements First Congestion Pricing Plan in the US</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date Not Specified <strong>Source:</strong> Xinhua News Agency</p>
<img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/newyork11736072256.jpg" alt="New York imposes first ever congestion pricing plan in US">
<figcaption>A congestion pricing plan covering Lower and Midtown Manhattan took effect on Sunday.</figcaption>
<p>A congestion pricing plan has been initiated in Manhattan, making New York City the first in the United States to adopt such a system.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Vehicles entering the congestion relief zone will be tolled based on vehicle type, time of day, and payment method.</li>
  <li>This plan aims to reduce the number of vehicles in the zone by an estimated 10%.</li>
  <li>The Metropolitan Transportation Authority (MTA) anticipates generating $1 billion annually from this plan.</li>
  <li>Controversy surrounding the plan has resulted in multiple lawsuits, though implementation proceeded.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The tolls would be adjusted upward in 2028 and 2031, phasing out 40% of initial discounts."</blockquote>
<p>This congestion pricing initiative marks a significant shift in urban traffic management and aims to fund public transportation while reducing congestion in Manhattan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/articles/special-articles/new-york-imposes-first-ever-congestion-pricing-plan-in-us-143221</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/articles/special-articles/new-york-imposes-first-ever-congestion-pricing-plan-in-us-143221</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 10:17:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IndiGo Airlines CEO Pieter Elbers Salary in 2025 - Aviation A2z]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE5zVWxBUTBWSEtRT3lSejk3VGFta1VtZzE4OThvRWhfNkJ6SHVBcDU0MUlkSlliOU9MaVotT1p3TXF5NkV5b1dSNUE5TE5zSk16c1BkQU96bUdvYnI0RDUzRTJCMWQ0Nk1CT3JhMWtZMTRlQ2Vzc2N0SzJHQUU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE5zVWxBUTBWSEtRT3lSejk3VGFta1VtZzE4OThvRWhfNkJ6SHVBcDU0MUlkSlliOU9MaVotT1p3TXF5NkV5b1dSNUE5TE5zSk16c1BkQU96bUdvYnI0RDUzRTJCMWQ0Nk1CT3JhMWtZMTRlQ2Vzc2N0SzJHQUU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 09:40:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ITC-ITC Hotels Demerger: Share price, listing date, F&O contracts - Things to know before Jan 6 record date - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ITC-ITC Hotels Demerger: Share price, listing date, F&amp;O contracts - Things to know before Jan 6 record date</h1><p><strong>Updated:</strong> January 5, 2025</p><p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="ITC Hotels Demerger" loading="lazy"><figcaption>ITC Hotels Demerger Overview</figcaption></p><p>The highly anticipated demerger of ITC Hotels from ITC Limited will take place on January 6, 2025, determining the eligibility for shareholders to receive shares of the newly formed entity.</p><ul><li>ITC will retain 40% ownership while distributing 60% to existing shareholders.</li><li>Shareholders will receive one share of ITC Hotels for every 10 shares held in ITC.</li><li>The stock is expected to list on NSE and BSE within 60 days of receiving the NCLT order dated December 16, 2024.</li><li>Market valuation of ITC Hotels is estimated between Rs 42,500 to Rs 62,000 crore.</li><li>ITC F&amp;O contracts will be introduced again on January 6, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>"We believe the listing of ITC Hotels shares will be in the range of Rs 200-300 per share at a market cap of Rs 42,500-62,000 crore." - Mihir P Shah, Nomura</blockquote><p>This demerger is crucial as it is expected to unlock significant shareholder value and allow focused growth in the luxury hospitality sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/itc-itc-hotels-demerger-share-price-listing-date-fo-contracts-things-to-know-before-jan-6-record-date-article-116962077</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/itc-itc-hotels-demerger-share-price-listing-date-fo-contracts-things-to-know-before-jan-6-record-date-article-116962077</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 08:46:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FPIs withdraw ₹4,285 crore in 3 trading sessions amid high valuations, global headwinds | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FPIs Withdraw ₹4,285 Crore in 3 Trading Sessions Amid High Valuations, Global Headwinds</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>In the first three trading days of January, foreign investors withdrew ₹4,285 crore from Indian equities amidst concerns over upcoming earnings and high stock valuations. This marks a significant trend away from Indian investments following a net inflow of ₹15,446 crore in December.</p><ul><li>Foreign Portfolio Investors (FPIs) pulled out ₹4,285 crore during January 1-3.</li><li>Investor sentiment is cautious due to a strong dollar and high US bond yields.</li><li>FPIs are reassessing investments ahead of the Q3FY25 earnings season.</li><li>The depreciating rupee is impacting the attractiveness of Indian equities.</li><li>Net inflows for 2024 stand at only ₹427 crore, a stark contrast to the ₹1.71 lakh crore in 2023.</li></ul><blockquote>"FPIs selling is due to high valuations in the secondary market... in the primary market where the valuations are fair, FPIs have been sustained investors." - V K Vijayakumar, Chief Investment Strategist at Geojit Financial Services</blockquote><p>The outflows highlight a cautious stance from foreign investors, reflecting broader economic concerns and valuation challenges in the Indian market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/fpis-withdraw-4-285-crore-in-3-trading-sessions-amid-high-valuations-global-headwinds-11736059305534.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/fpis-withdraw-4-285-crore-in-3-trading-sessions-amid-high-valuations-global-headwinds-11736059305534.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:41:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Shock For Hyundai Creta? - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 2024 Car Sales: Key Highlights and Trends</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> MotorOctane</p><img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Hyundai-Creta-3-1200x675.webp" alt="Hyundai Creta"><figcaption>Hyundai Creta, a notable model in December 2024 sales.</figcaption><p>As 2024 comes to a close, car manufacturers are offering significant discounts while reviewing their best-sold models. December saw impressive sales figures across several brands.</p><ul><li><strong>Maruti Brezza:</strong> Topped the sales with 17,300 units, compared to 12,844 last year.</li><li><strong>Maruti WagonR:</strong> Sold 17,300 units, a constant favorite in the hatchback segment.</li><li><strong>Maruti Dzire:</strong> Returned to the top-10 list with 16,573 units sold.</li><li><strong>Hyundai Creta:</strong> Sold over 12,600 units, maintaining its position in the market.</li><li><strong>Mahindra Scorpio:</strong> The only proper SUV in the list with over 12,100 units sold.</li></ul><blockquote>Maruti Brezza achieved over 17,300 units in December.</blockquote><p>This month highlights the competitive landscape of the automotive market, with several familiar names leading the charts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/281739-big-shock-for-hyundai-creta</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/281739-big-shock-for-hyundai-creta</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyundai Creta Electric unveiled: All you need to know - CarWale]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hyundai Creta Electric unveiled: All you need to know</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CarWale</p>
<img src="https://imgd.aeplcdn.com/642x361/n/cw/ec/194947/creta-ev-exterior-left-rear-three-quarter.jpeg?isig=0&amp;wm=1&amp;q=75" alt="Hyundai Creta EV Left Rear Three Quarter" />
<figcaption>Hyundai Creta EV Left Rear Three Quarter</figcaption>
<p>After months of anticipation, the Hyundai Creta Electric has been revealed, marking the South Korean automaker’s first locally made SUV.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Creta Electric will offer two battery pack options: a 42kWh pack with a range of 390km and a 51.4kWh pack with a range of 473km.</li>
  <li>Charging times are 58 minutes with a DC fast charger and four hours with an 11kWh AC wall box charger.</li>
  <li>It will be available in four variants: Executive, Smart, Premium, and Excellence.</li>
  <li>Design cues are taken from the regular Creta with specific enhancements for the electric model.</li>
  <li>Inside, expect advanced features akin to the ICE version including dual digital displays, ADAS, and a panoramic sunroof.</li>
  <li>Pricing is expected to be between Rs. 22 lakh to Rs. 26 lakh.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Creta Electric is now a large piece of the puzzle that has been revealed, this puzzle being a new electric SUV D-segment battle.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the Hyundai Creta Electric represents a significant step in the electric SUV market, promising innovative technology and competitive pricing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.carwale.com/news/hyundai-creta-electric-unveiled-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.carwale.com/news/hyundai-creta-electric-unveiled-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:25:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mcap of 4 of top-10 most valued firms fall by ₹96,606 crore; HDFC Bank biggest hit | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mcap of 4 of top-10 most valued firms fall by ₹96,606 crore; HDFC Bank biggest hit</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The combined market capitalisation of four of the top 10 most valuable companies in India saw a decline last week, with HDFC Bank experiencing the largest drop.</p><ul><li>The overall market cap decline amounted to ₹96,605.66 crore.</li><li>HDFC Bank's valuation decreased by ₹37,025.46 crore to ₹13,37,919.84 crore.</li><li>ICICI Bank's valuation fell by ₹29,324.55 crore to ₹8,93,378.50 crore.</li><li>Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) saw a decline of ₹24,856.26 crore to ₹14,83,144.53 crore.</li><li>State Bank of India lost ₹5,399.39 crore, reducing its valuation to ₹7,08,168.60 crore.</li><li>In contrast, Reliance Industries gained ₹41,138.41 crore, becoming more valuable at ₹16,93,373.48 crore.</li><li>Other companies like Hindustan Unilever and LIC also recorded gains in their market valuations.</li></ul><blockquote>“During the same period, the BSE benchmark index climbed 524.04 points (0.66%).”</blockquote><p>While four firms struggled, several others managed to increase their market capitalisation, showing mixed fortunes in the stock market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/mcap-of-4-of-top-10-most-valued-firms-falls-by-96-606-crore-hdfc-bank-biggest-hit-11736059196645.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/mcap-of-4-of-top-10-most-valued-firms-falls-by-96-606-crore-hdfc-bank-biggest-hit-11736059196645.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:14:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance, Asian Paints, and DMART: Is it the right time to buy them as they underperform the Nifty50? - Trade Brains]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxPVk5xV0xfWU5MTl9hcmJ0Q1lxQm1LNmZ0NjZ0RlI4TW1VNks1ZENUNGxqVVY4OVRhU2RXX2l4VU9ZanRJaHpzWFFLVUs2N3dnOTlvblVkMmprYWE1d3JXM0V4dDNVZjFiWklaTFZ3LTVLUlA2cHI2ZXRHUWpjSmJKbE91enRJc0JXajdSbEdXUnlXYUpUZFRZNTJNeHNOVEFCaHNuaUNYaWxwR21vSlNua21wWEE3bFFaS2dsMklWM1Y3bkdwcWdULTZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxPVk5xV0xfWU5MTl9hcmJ0Q1lxQm1LNmZ0NjZ0RlI4TW1VNks1ZENUNGxqVVY4OVRhU2RXX2l4VU9ZanRJaHpzWFFLVUs2N3dnOTlvblVkMmprYWE1d3JXM0V4dDNVZjFiWklaTFZ3LTVLUlA2cHI2ZXRHUWpjSmJKbE91enRJc0JXajdSbEdXUnlXYUpUZFRZNTJNeHNOVEFCaHNuaUNYaWxwR21vSlNua21wWEE3bFFaS2dsMklWM1Y3bkdwcWdULTZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small cap mutual funds: 3 MF schemes - Rs 10k SIP to Rs 1 crore corpus - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Small cap mutual funds: 3 MF schemes - Rs 10k SIP to Rs 1 crore corpus</h1>
<p><strong>Updated:</strong> Jan 5, 2025 11:50 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW Digital</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Small cap mutual funds" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Small cap mutual funds</figcaption>
<p>Small cap mutual funds have potential to deliver significant returns and help investors build wealth over time. This article analyzes a few mutual fund schemes that have successfully transformed a Rs 10,000 monthly SIP into a corpus exceeding Rs 1 crore.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Kotak Small Cap Fund:</strong> Launched in February 2005, it has yielded 18.23% returns, making the corpus grow to Rs 1.02 crore from Rs 10,000 SIP over 15 years.</li>
<li><strong>SBI Small Cap Fund:</strong> Initiated in September 2009, it delivered 20.74% returns, allowing an investment of Rs 10,000 per month to reach Rs 1.25 crore over 15 years.</li>
<li><strong>Nippon India Small Cap Fund:</strong> Starting in September 2010, this scheme provided 22.22% returns, growing the investment to Rs 1.27 crore over nearly 14 years.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"All mutual fund investments are subject to market risks; it's essential to consult financial advisors before making investment decisions."</blockquote>
<p>These small cap mutual fund schemes demonstrate substantial potential for investors looking to build wealth through systematic investments over time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/mutual-funds/small-cap-mutual-funds-3-mf-schemes-rs-10k-sip-to-rs-1-crore-corpus-article-116959212</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/mutual-funds/small-cap-mutual-funds-3-mf-schemes-rs-10k-sip-to-rs-1-crore-corpus-article-116959212</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 06:20:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FPIs net sell domestic equities worth Rs 4,285 crore in first 3 sessions in January. What lies ahead? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxPWTV0eGo1TUNDMXlqUFh0ck1CZjJtbTNSMkNZRE5jN2VyWS1GSXF1RnFjaTdQSnhuSi1UNEc4Q0YzQ1U2cnF5RVo1NU5nSmRvU2tWTUk5bUQ4OGVHbk80X192TDQzSWpzNWttempvLVg3SWE3Y3Y3c1ZNN3pRMkFTclMtdzI4dWpNRFlLUHZlRzFNUXN4SnJ0MlNneF84YXdoRTZoeG1qWEZkRjRtT0I4aURjNElrTVc0ZTJMRWtQbHQ1SFplWlpnUnNtWC1Xc2tTQjN2MnlydmtITk5GUlY4eUlNZkI5QlRMX2ZHZURBd0gyOUlGMEpoYTVyVG1ORFBCYXfSAYcCQVVfeXFMUHJTRko1V25VQTkwbFIyWnhkZTJoWExDYV9ldUppSC0yem10Mm1vcHlkWDNCVUkwS0ZnMmRVTUhMem9uTmZ4NDF0R2F1akY2cUhwZmkxZ2YxZ2JKOWtIcEhJUmR0cUh6Sll1VTJ5STBvRGFpV1lZc21KQXpTQ19ILW5zMzZ3bnRyVFpmazRtOWg2LS1fTlVERTVSa0c0SkFVWXJXUDMwZkVjdW9KQmdCQjQ4SFZqWGNKbzZraFZmSmhqOHRZeXlIMFBUT3dhREhQeklFWEIzTzk2Wl95QkVZX2d3YVVZZWZZNV93MkcxNU5pcmotTlVJeWRPYVdkS0lGRUJGcjdoTXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxPWTV0eGo1TUNDMXlqUFh0ck1CZjJtbTNSMkNZRE5jN2VyWS1GSXF1RnFjaTdQSnhuSi1UNEc4Q0YzQ1U2cnF5RVo1NU5nSmRvU2tWTUk5bUQ4OGVHbk80X192TDQzSWpzNWttempvLVg3SWE3Y3Y3c1ZNN3pRMkFTclMtdzI4dWpNRFlLUHZlRzFNUXN4SnJ0MlNneF84YXdoRTZoeG1qWEZkRjRtT0I4aURjNElrTVc0ZTJMRWtQbHQ1SFplWlpnUnNtWC1Xc2tTQjN2MnlydmtITk5GUlY4eUlNZkI5QlRMX2ZHZURBd0gyOUlGMEpoYTVyVG1ORFBCYXfSAYcCQVVfeXFMUHJTRko1V25VQTkwbFIyWnhkZTJoWExDYV9ldUppSC0yem10Mm1vcHlkWDNCVUkwS0ZnMmRVTUhMem9uTmZ4NDF0R2F1akY2cUhwZmkxZ2YxZ2JKOWtIcEhJUmR0cUh6Sll1VTJ5STBvRGFpV1lZc21KQXpTQ19ILW5zMzZ3bnRyVFpmazRtOWg2LS1fTlVERTVSa0c0SkFVWXJXUDMwZkVjdW9KQmdCQjQ4SFZqWGNKbzZraFZmSmhqOHRZeXlIMFBUT3dhREhQeklFWEIzTzk2Wl95QkVZX2d3YVVZZWZZNV93MkcxNU5pcmotTlVJeWRPYVdkS0lGRUJGcjdoTXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:50:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Months after Ratan Tata's death, THIS move by Noel Tata shocks Elon Musk, it is... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Air India Becomes First Airline in India to Offer In-Flight Wi-Fi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><figure><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/noel-tata.png?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="noel tata"><figcaption>Noel Tata’s big move shocks Elon Musk, Ratan Tata's company becomes first company in India to...., the name of company is...</figcaption></figure><p>In a major move, Air India has started offering internet on its flights, fulfilling a long-standing demand from passengers. The Wi-Fi service is available on both domestic and international flights.</p><ul><li>Air India has become the first airline in India to offer Wi-Fi on domestic flights.</li><li>The Wi-Fi will be available on Airbus A350, Boeing 787-9, and select Airbus A321neo aircraft.</li><li>Initially, the Wi-Fi service will be available for free.</li><li>Passengers can access social media and messaging apps on laptops, tablets, and smartphones.</li></ul><blockquote>“The service depends on factors like satellite connectivity and government regulations.”</blockquote><p>Air India will begin a gradual rollout of Wi-Fi on its other aircraft.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/business/noel-tatas-big-move-shocks-elon-musk-ratan-tatas-company-becomes-first-company-in-india-to-the-name-of-company-is-7515376/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/business/noel-tatas-big-move-shocks-elon-musk-ratan-tatas-company-becomes-first-company-in-india-to-the-name-of-company-is-7515376/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:33:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Noel Tata’s big move shocks Elon Musk, Ratan Tata's company becomes first company in India to...., the name o - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxORlNFN3N4U3FrRU8wV0tia1V2aUxJNVNSTU1tRmpMTDQwdGg1Z1dOSVVueDdvMVM3VmVVd0tpeHYtdE5MNU1XS0oybDhXX1JRMmhZZWxlT09fUXMyZ083X3VHOTNPZzRNNjZmWVdYdkxDRG5Ma0JSUEktb0RibXpEUFJMS0MybzN2WDg1SzB2Q2ZxNHVmeGFULVJYYVM3Z25udVl5VHd5QlI2Qk4zUERVOEd1SWl6ZnFiYXJjTzRkaEZWY0JDS1lVLW5MdGltMUhHTDY3SVlZOS1oaVRKazk4amgtTnZIenBy0gHuAUFVX3lxTE9ENzRKMC1BQ1ZMMWRFYnZMRVhWaGlyMkxCRVF5NktnVUE3czBoNzY4SldyWWlwTTNyTDBJMGJJWUllVU1MbFRHRWxWNVVWZkpjNUU4ZlVqai1KYXlCTnI0M1R4Vkp3cUZZU3FJSlJpd0tFMmN6NEpjSWx5N0dBV0M2SzV3TC1pSXA5aXFJeUZLY0FROERoT2dqV01UVWVZdmozUzYyM1B0alZKbVFfSm9KZGxfRkhqTzVFLXJ0bTFhRXlfSXhFQVMyUzlLMHJlRXQzTUNELV9OOThzb0NPYWc5UXBlRWNVZzVPNC10MXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxORlNFN3N4U3FrRU8wV0tia1V2aUxJNVNSTU1tRmpMTDQwdGg1Z1dOSVVueDdvMVM3VmVVd0tpeHYtdE5MNU1XS0oybDhXX1JRMmhZZWxlT09fUXMyZ083X3VHOTNPZzRNNjZmWVdYdkxDRG5Ma0JSUEktb0RibXpEUFJMS0MybzN2WDg1SzB2Q2ZxNHVmeGFULVJYYVM3Z25udVl5VHd5QlI2Qk4zUERVOEd1SWl6ZnFiYXJjTzRkaEZWY0JDS1lVLW5MdGltMUhHTDY3SVlZOS1oaVRKazk4amgtTnZIenBy0gHuAUFVX3lxTE9ENzRKMC1BQ1ZMMWRFYnZMRVhWaGlyMkxCRVF5NktnVUE3czBoNzY4SldyWWlwTTNyTDBJMGJJWUllVU1MbFRHRWxWNVVWZkpjNUU4ZlVqai1KYXlCTnI0M1R4Vkp3cUZZU3FJSlJpd0tFMmN6NEpjSWx5N0dBV0M2SzV3TC1pSXA5aXFJeUZLY0FROERoT2dqV01UVWVZdmozUzYyM1B0alZKbVFfSm9KZGxfRkhqTzVFLXJ0bTFhRXlfSXhFQVMyUzlLMHJlRXQzTUNELV9OOThzb0NPYWc5UXBlRWNVZzVPNC10MXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:33:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weaker Rupee Benefits Companies Like Infosys? - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weaker Rupee Benefits Companies Like Infosys?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/Rupee11736054917.jpg" alt="Weaker Rupee Benefits Companies Like Infosys?"><figcaption>Weaker Rupee Benefits Companies Like Infosys?</figcaption><p>Veteran investor Mark Mobius sees India as a strong investment hub due to its growth, reforms, and China’s declining favor under Trump 2.0.</p><ul><li>A weaker rupee benefits export-oriented companies like Infosys, enhancing global competitiveness.</li><li>Many Indian firms with earnings in US dollars are expected to thrive.</li><li>Mobius predicts the rupee may weaken further to 86 by year-end, influenced by a strong dollar and India’s trade deficit.</li><li>He remains optimistic about India’s economic potential and market opportunities.</li><li>Mobius recommends investment in export-driven sectors and consumption industries.</li></ul><blockquote>“India is a natural choice for manufacturing after China,” says Mobius.</blockquote><p>Mobius aims for a 50% investment allocation in India, highlighting the growth potential.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/india-news/weaker-rupee-benefits-companies-like-infosys-143214</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/india-news/weaker-rupee-benefits-companies-like-infosys-143214</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:29:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weaker Rupee Benefits Companies Like Infosys?.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weaker Rupee Benefits Companies Like Infosys?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/Rupee11736054917.jpg" alt="Weaker Rupee Benefits Companies Like Infosys?"><figcaption>Weaker Rupee Benefits Companies Like Infosys?</figcaption><p>Veteran investor Mark Mobius sees India as a strong investment hub due to its growth, reforms, and China’s declining favor under Trump 2.0.</p><ul><li>A weaker rupee benefits export-oriented companies like Infosys, enhancing global competitiveness.</li><li>Many Indian firms with earnings in US dollars are expected to thrive.</li><li>Mobius predicts the rupee may weaken further to 86 by year-end, influenced by a strong dollar and India’s trade deficit.</li><li>He remains optimistic about India’s economic potential and market opportunities.</li><li>Mobius recommends investment in export-driven sectors and consumption industries.</li></ul><blockquote>“India is a natural choice for manufacturing after China,” says Mobius.</blockquote><p>Mobius aims for a 50% investment allocation in India, highlighting the growth potential.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/india-news/weaker-rupee-benefits-companies-like-infosys-143214</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/india-news/weaker-rupee-benefits-companies-like-infosys-143214</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:29:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is Indian-origin Kevan Parekh’s salary as Apple’s new CFO? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What is Indian-origin Kevan Parekh’s salary as Apple’s new CFO?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 05, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/GV9SzR-aoAEH0_e_1736053309136_1736053317262.jpg" alt="Indian-origin Kevan Parekh, who has been appointed as the new chief financial officer of Apple Inc." title="Indian-origin Kevan Parekh, who has been appointed as the new chief financial officer of Apple Inc.">
<figcaption>Indian-origin Kevan Parekh, who has been appointed as the new chief financial officer of Apple Inc.</figcaption>
<p>Indian-origin Kevan Parekh, appointed as the CFO of Apple effective January 1, 2025, will receive an annual salary of $1 million (₹8.57 crore).</p>
<ul>
  <li>Parekh joined Apple in June 2013 and has significant experience in finance roles.</li>
  <li>He previously held leadership positions at Thomson Reuters and General Motors.</li>
  <li>Parekh succeeds Luca Maestri in Apple's CFO transition plan.</li>
  <li>Tim Cook praised Parekh's intelligence and judgment in his new role.</li>
  <li>His annual compensation includes participation in Apple’s Executive Cash Incentive Plan with a target opportunity of 175% of base salary.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“For more than a decade, Kevan has been an indispensable member of Apple's finance leadership team.” – Tim Cook</blockquote>
<p>This appointment highlights Apple’s commitment to maintaining strong financial leadership during a key transition period.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/what-is-indian-origin-kevan-parekh-s-salary-as-apple-s-new-cfo-101736050627448.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/what-is-indian-origin-kevan-parekh-s-salary-as-apple-s-new-cfo-101736050627448.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:18:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian-origin CEO is world's highest paid person, earns Rs 48 crore per day - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian-origin CEO is world's highest paid person, earns Rs 48 crore per day</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <em>Publication date not available</em> | <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p>
<p>Jagdeep Singh, the founder and former CEO of Quantumscape, has made headlines with an annual salary of Rs 17,500 crore ($2.06 billion), earning an average of Rs 48 crore daily, which sets a new record for executive compensation globally.</p>
<ul>
<li>Singh's remarkable salary exceeds that of several large corporations.</li>
<li>He holds degrees from prestigious institutions such as Stanford and UC Berkeley.</li>
<li>Quantumscape, founded in 2010, focuses on innovative battery technology that enhances electric vehicle performance.</li>
<li>Singh recently stepped down as CEO but continues to influence the company as a board member.</li>
<li>Quantumscape aims to develop solid-state batteries for a sustainable energy future.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Quantumscape's advanced technology is set to revolutionize energy storage and support a decarbonized future.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Jagdeep Singh's unprecedented earnings reflect both his personal achievements and the transformative potential of the technologies developed at Quantumscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/companies/people/jagdeep-singh-quantumscape-salary-package-rs-17500-crore-electric-vehicles-125010500132_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/companies/people/jagdeep-singh-quantumscape-salary-package-rs-17500-crore-electric-vehicles-125010500132_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:03:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian CEO is highest paid person in the world, earns Rs 48 crore per day - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jagdeep Singh Named Highest Paid CEO in the World with Earnings of Rs 48 Crore per Day</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p><p>Jagdeep Singh, founder and former CEO of Quantumscape, has made headlines with his astronomical earnings totaling Rs 17,500 crore annually, averaging Rs 48 crore per day, making him the highest-paid individual globally.</p><ul><li>Singh's compensation surpasses many large corporations’ revenues.</li><li>He holds degrees from prestigious institutions, including Stanford and UC Berkeley.</li><li>Quantumscape, founded by Singh, focuses on advanced battery technology for EVs.</li><li>He has contributed significantly to the EV battery revolution with innovative solid-state solutions.</li><li>In February 2024, Singh transitioned from CEO to take on a new role within Quantumscape.</li></ul><blockquote>"Singh's profile as a visionary entrepreneur highlights the intersection of technology and sustainable energy."</blockquote><p>Singh's remarkable journey and achievements not only set a new benchmark for executive pay but also emphasize the evolving landscape of sustainable energy and innovation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/companies/people/jagdeep-singh-quantumscape-salary-package-rs-17500-crore-electric-vehicles-125010500132_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/companies/people/jagdeep-singh-quantumscape-salary-package-rs-17500-crore-electric-vehicles-125010500132_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold Rate And Silver Price Today on January 5, 2025: Check latest Rates in India | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Rate And Silver Price Today on January 5, 2025: Check latest Rates in India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Livemint</p><p>Gold prices experienced a modest decrease on January 5, 2025, with significant changes in gold and silver rates across major cities in India.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The cost of 24 carat gold in India is Rs.7888.3 per gram, down by ₹500.0.</li><li>The cost of 22 carat gold is Rs.7232.3 per gram, down by ₹460.0.</li><li>The current price of silver in India is ₹94600.0 per kg, reflecting a decrease of ₹1100.0.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“The prices of gold and silver constantly fluctuate due to various factors, both domestic and international.”</p></blockquote><h2>Price Summary in South Cities:</h2><ul><li>Chennai: Gold Rate ₹78731.0/10 grams</li><li>Bangalore: Gold Rate ₹78725.0/10 grams</li><li>Hyderabad: Gold Rate ₹78739.0/10 grams</li><li>Visakhapatnam: Gold Rate ₹78747.0/10 grams</li><li>Vijayawada: Gold Rate ₹78745.0/10 grams</li></ul><h2>Factors Affecting Prices:</h2><ul><li>Global Demand</li><li>Currency Fluctuations</li><li>Interest Rates</li><li>Government Regulations</li><li>World Events</li></ul><p>This is an AI-generated story and has not been edited by Livemint staff.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/commodities/gold-rate-and-silver-price-today-on-january-5-2025-check-latest-rates-in-india-11736053202785.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/commodities/gold-rate-and-silver-price-today-on-january-5-2025-check-latest-rates-in-india-11736053202785.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Exciting Skoda Cars Confirmed For This Month! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>3 Exciting Skoda Cars Confirmed For This Month!</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> MotorOctane</p>
<img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/6672cb99b95db.webp" alt="Upcoming Skoda Cars – Skoda Kodiaq">
<figcaption>Upcoming Skoda Cars – Skoda Kodiaq</figcaption>
<p>As the Auto Expo approaches, Skoda confirms three new models set to launch in India, showcasing significant design updates and advanced features.</p>
<ul>
  <li>New Skoda Kodiaq to receive major design updates including a new touchscreen and instrument cluster.</li>
  <li>Skoda Octavia VRS to feature a 2.0-litre turbo petrol engine producing 260 bhp.</li>
  <li>Skoda Superb to return with an updated design and improved interior features.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The new Kodiaq will be priced around Rs 50 lakh (on-road, Mumbai).”</blockquote>
<p>This month is pivotal for Skoda as it aims to capture market attention with these exciting releases in the Indian automotive landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/281733-3-exciting-skoda-cars-confirmed-for-this-month</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/281733-3-exciting-skoda-cars-confirmed-for-this-month</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Chinese brand that has become a 'headache' for Zara, H&M in Europe and Amazon in the US is coming to - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Chinese brand that has become a 'headache' for Zara, H&M in Europe and Amazon in the US is coming to Reliance's Ajio website</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Publication Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/109343604.cms' alt='TOI logo' width='300' height='45'><figcaption>Source: Times of India</figcaption><p>This article discusses how a Chinese brand is increasingly challenging major retailers like Zara, H&M, and Amazon, and its upcoming launch on Reliance's Ajio platform.</p><ul><li>The Chinese brand is gaining traction in the European and US markets.</li><li>It poses significant competition to established brands like Zara and H&M.</li><li>Expansion into India through Reliance's Ajio platform indicates its growth strategy.</li></ul><blockquote>"The market is evolving rapidly, and new entrants pose unique challenges to traditional players."</blockquote><p>The arrival of this brand on Ajio is expected to stir competition in the Indian fashion retail space, signaling changing consumer preferences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/the-chinese-brand-that-has-become-a-headache-for-zara-hm-in-europe-and-amazon-in-the-us-is-coming-to-reliances-ajio-website/articleshow/116925266.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/the-chinese-brand-that-has-become-a-headache-for-zara-hm-in-europe-and-amazon-in-the-us-is-coming-to-reliances-ajio-website/articleshow/116925266.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025 Ather 450X: What is new? - BikeWale]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2025 Ather 450X: What is new?</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> October 2023, BikeWale</p><img src="https://imgd.aeplcdn.com/642x361/n/cw/ec/195109/450x-left-side-view-6.jpeg?isig=0&amp;q=75" alt="Ather 450X Left Side View" title="Ather 450X Left Side View"><figcaption>Ather 450X Left Side View</figcaption><p>The 2025 Ather 450X electric scooter has launched in India priced at Rs 1.47 lakh, featuring new enhancements and technologies aimed at improving rider experience and safety.</p><ul><li>Introduction of a new traction control system with three modes: Rain, Road, and Rally.</li><li>Launch of the Ather Magic Twist, allowing riders to counter-rotate the throttle to decelerate without using brakes.</li><li>New low resistance tyres that can improve the scooter's range by 25%.</li><li>Expanded battery options with a 105km range for the 2.9kWh version and a 130km range for the 3.7kWh version.</li><li>New color options added: Hyper Sand and Stealth Blue, alongside existing colors.</li><li>Increased pricing reflective of added features; 450X 2.9kWh at Rs. 1.47 lakh and 3.7kWh at Rs. 1.57 lakh.</li></ul><blockquote>“The traction control system adds a layer of safety, particularly important for new, inexperienced riders.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the 2025 Ather 450X offers significant upgrades aimed not only at performance but also at enhancing the safety and overall riding experience for users.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bikewale.com/news/2025-ather-450x-what-is-new/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bikewale.com/news/2025-ather-450x-what-is-new/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:48:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk donates Tesla shares worth $112 million to charities that have 'no current intention to ...' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-donates-tesla-shares-worth-112-million-what-the-regulatory-filing-said/articleshow/116935264.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-donates-tesla-shares-worth-112-million-what-the-regulatory-filing-said/articleshow/116935264.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian-origin CEO sparks debate with viral post: 'haven't done dishes in 4 years' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian-origin CEO sparks debate with viral post: 'haven't done dishes in 4 years'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 05, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/dish_1736050902073_1736050906530.png" alt="He said delegating tasks like washing dishes, which can be outsourced for $15/hour, allows him to focus on work worth $5,000/hour.(Pexel)"><figcaption>He said delegating tasks like washing dishes, which can be outsourced for $15/hour, allows him to focus on work worth $5,000/hour.(Pexel)</figcaption></figure><p>An Indian-origin CEO’s LinkedIn post sparked a debate about productivity, delegation, and the value of time. The entrepreneur shared how he prioritises high-value tasks over household chores, claiming he hasn’t done the dishes in four years.</p><ul><li>The CEO stated that delegating chores allows him to focus on work worth $5,000/hour.</li><li>He emphasized the importance of task prioritization in scaling productivity.</li><li>Critics pointed out that outsourcing is not feasible for everyone, highlighting privilege.</li><li>Many users reacted humorously and critically to the CEO's stance on productivity.</li></ul><blockquote>“Stop doing $15/hour tasks. Start doing $5,000/hour work. That’s how you scale.”</blockquote><p>This post has raised questions about the practicality of such approaches for ordinary professionals and sparked discussions on the value of time management.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/indianorigin-ceo-sparks-debate-with-viral-post-havent-done-dishes-in-4-years-101736050141219.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/indianorigin-ceo-sparks-debate-with-viral-post-havent-done-dishes-in-4-years-101736050141219.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:28:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TCS Q3 results, FII action among 8 factors that could keep D-Street on toes this week - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>TCS Q3 results, FII action among 8 factors that could keep D-Street on toes this week</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>Nifty ended with weekly gains of 0.80% aided by auto and health stocks, but the markets are likely to be impacted by various key factors when they resume trading.</p><ul><li><strong>Q3FY25 Earnings:</strong> The earnings season starts with TCS results followed by important updates from several top companies.</li><li><strong>US Markets:</strong> US stocks rebounded with expectations surrounding the Trump administration.</li><li><strong>FII/DII Action:</strong> FIIs were net sellers while DIIs were net buyers recently, raising questions on future market movements.</li><li><strong>Technical Factors:</strong> Market trends indicate a potential rise for Nifty, dependent on crossing key resistance levels.</li><li><strong>Upcoming IPOs:</strong> A busy IPO week with several issues launching, signaling strong market momentum.</li><li><strong>Rupee vs Dollar:</strong> The rupee hit a record low against the dollar, affecting market sentiment.</li><li><strong>Crude Oil Prices:</strong> Rising oil prices raise concerns over inflation and market stability.</li><li><strong>Corporate Action:</strong> Several stocks will be in focus due to corporate actions scheduled for the week.</li></ul><blockquote>“The RSI shows a bullish crossover. On the upside, the index may rise towards 24,200–24,220,” - Rupak De, Senior Technical Analyst.</blockquote><p>The week ahead will be crucial as various factors, including earnings reports and foreign investment activity, could dictate market dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/-fii-action-among-8-factors-that-could-keep-d-street-on-toes-this-week/articleshow/116957819.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/-fii-action-among-8-factors-that-could-keep-d-street-on-toes-this-week/articleshow/116957819.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:08:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to buy under ₹100: Experts recommend six shares to buy tomorrow j— 6 January 2025 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to buy under ₹100: Experts recommend six shares to buy tomorrow</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> LiveMint</p><p>Following weak global market cues, the Indian stock market experienced a downturn but shows signs of resilience. Experts have recommended six stocks under ₹100 for potential buyers.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The Nifty 50 index closed at 24,043, down 183 points.</li><li>The BSE Sensex dropped 773 points, closing at 79,170.</li><li>Key sectors showing gains included Media, Oil & Gas, and Consumer Durables.</li><li>Market experts recommend six stocks to buy: Yes Bank, Aartech Solonics, IDFC First Bank, Bank of Maharashtra, Manaksia Steels, and AMD Industries.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes:</h2><blockquote>“The near-term uptrend remains intact for Nifty.” - Nagaraj Shetti, HDFC Securities</blockquote><blockquote>“Ongoing consolidation will continue.” - Hrishikesh Yedve, Asit C Mehta</blockquote><p><strong>Recommended Stocks:</strong></p><ul><li>Yes Bank: Buy at ₹19.40-₹19.60, target ₹21.20</li><li>Aartech Solonics: Buy at ₹88.50, target ₹94</li><li>IDFC First Bank: Buy at ₹64-₹65.50, multiple targets</li><li>Bank of Maharashtra: Buy at ₹54-₹55, multiple targets</li><li>Manaksia Steels: Buy at ₹62.40, target ₹65</li><li>AMD Industries: Buy at ₹66.50, target ₹70.50</li></ul><p><i><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> Views expressed are those of individual analysts; investors are advised to seek certified expert opinions.</i></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stocks-to-buy-under-rs-100-experts-recommend-six-shares-to-buy-on-monday-6-january-2025-11735964240595.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stocks-to-buy-under-rs-100-experts-recommend-six-shares-to-buy-on-monday-6-january-2025-11735964240595.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 03:59:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold Rate Today Rises In India: Check 22, 24 Carat Prices In Your City On January 05 - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Rate Today In India: Check 22 and 24 Carat Prices In Your City On January 05, 2025</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 05, 2025, 14:59 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Check Gold Prices Today On January 5, 2025." title="Check Gold Prices Today On January 5, 2025." loading="eager"><figcaption>Check Gold Prices Today On January 5, 2025.</figcaption></figure><p>On January 5, 2025, gold prices in India stayed high due to strong demand and current market trends. 24-carat gold continued to be popular for its unmatched purity, while 22-carat gold remained a top choice for jewellery buyers because of its strength and elegant look—perfect for those looking for long-lasting investment pieces.</p><h2><strong>Gold Prices</strong>: Retail Rates on January 05 Across Major Cities in India</h2><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>City</strong></td><td><strong>22 Carat Gold Rate Today</strong></td><td><strong>24 Carat Gold Rate Today</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Delhi</td><td>72,300</td><td>78,860</td></tr><tr><td>Mumbai</td><td>72,150</td><td>78,710</td></tr><tr><td>Ahmedabad</td><td>72,200</td><td>78,760</td></tr><tr><td>Chennai</td><td>72,150</td><td>78,710</td></tr><tr><td>Kolkata</td><td>72,150</td><td>78,710</td></tr><tr><td>Pune</td><td>72,150</td><td>78,710</td></tr><tr><td>Lucknow</td><td>72,300</td><td>78,860</td></tr><tr><td>Bengaluru</td><td>72,150</td><td>78,710</td></tr><tr><td>Jaipur</td><td>72,300</td><td>78,860</td></tr><tr><td>Patna</td><td>72,200</td><td>78,760</td></tr><tr><td>Bhubaneshwar</td><td>72,150</td><td>78,710</td></tr><tr><td>Hyderabad</td><td>72,150</td><td>78,710</td></tr></tbody></table><p><strong>Retail Gold Prices in India</strong>: The price of 24-carat gold stood at Rs 78,710 per 10 grams. Meanwhile, 22-carat gold was available at Rs 72,150 per 10 grams.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/savings-and-investments/gold-rate-today-mumbai-22-carat-10-gram-9177505.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/savings-and-investments/gold-rate-today-mumbai-22-carat-10-gram-9177505.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 03:52:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New UPI features to use in 2025: UPI One World wallet, payment delegation, foreign travel, link WhatsApp &more | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New UPI Features for 2025: Enhancements for Global Payments</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>UPI payments are set to expand with new features for an enhanced user experience, including international transactions and integration with popular messaging platforms.</p>
<ul>
<li>WhatsApp users can now make UPI payments as NPCI lifts the user onboarding limit.</li>
<li>UPI will be accepted in foreign countries, starting with select locations like France in July 2024.</li>
<li>Cashback offers are available for RuPay cardholders on international transactions.</li>
<li>International numbers can be linked to UPI accounts for NRIs.</li>
<li>The UPI One World wallet will assist international travellers visiting India.</li>
<li>UPI Circle allows delegation of transactions to family members.</li>
<li>Personal accident policies are now available for RuPay cardholders.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) has removed the UPI user onboarding limit for WhatsApp Pay... This allows WhatsApp Pay to extend UPI services to its entire user base in India,” NPCI stated.</blockquote>
<p>This evolution in UPI technology promises greater convenience for users both domestically and abroad, fostering a more connected and accessible payment landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/new-upi-features-to-use-in-2025-upi-one-world-wallet-payment-delegation-foreign-travel-link-whatsapp-more-11736043000339.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/new-upi-features-to-use-in-2025-upi-one-world-wallet-payment-delegation-foreign-travel-link-whatsapp-more-11736043000339.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 03:32:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>