<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:20:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:20:03 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PSU Bank Stake Sale: Government approves ₹10,000 crore QIP plan for five lenders — Exclusive - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Government Greenlights ₹10,000 Crore Fundraising for Five PSU Banks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 14, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC-TV18</p><img alt="PSU Bank Stake Sale: Government approves ₹10,000 crore QIP plan for five lenders — Exclusive" title="PSU Bank Stake Sale: Government approves ₹10,000 crore QIP plan for five lenders — Exclusive" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" decoding="async" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Government's approval for fundraising plan for PSU banks.</figcaption><p>The government has approved a ₹10,000 crore fundraising plan for five state-run lenders through the Qualified Institutional Placement (QIP) route.</p><ul><li>Five banks approved include Bank of Maharashtra, Punjab & Sind Bank, Indian Overseas Bank, UCO Bank, and Central Bank of India.</li><li>The fundraising may commence in small tranches starting from Q4 of FY 2025.</li><li>The government aims to meet 25% minimum public shareholding norms by August 2026.</li><li>The government holds substantial stakes in these banks, with Bank of Maharashtra at 79.6% and Punjab & Sind Bank at 98.25%.</li><li>The current excess government stake in these banks is nearly ₹50,000 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“The government holds a significant stake across these five banks, with intentions to enhance public shareholding.”</blockquote><p>This approval is part of the government's strategy to bolster the financial status of PSU banks and meet regulatory requirements for shareholding.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/psu-bank-stake-sale-qip-ofs-10000-crore-iob-uco-punjab-sind-central-bank-bom-share-price-19539806.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/psu-bank-stake-sale-qip-ofs-10000-crore-iob-uco-punjab-sind-central-bank-bom-share-price-19539806.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:25:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why rupee breached 86 against US dollar: strengthening dollar, weak FII inflows - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why Rupee Breached 86 Against US Dollar: Strengthening Dollar and Weak FII Inflows</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>The rupee fell past 86 against the US dollar driven by a strong dollar and weak foreign institutional investor (FII) inflows. This depreciation comes after positive US jobs data and rising crude oil prices.</p><ul><li>The rupee opened at a record low of 86.12 and hit 86.31 against the dollar.</li><li>Factors contributing to the fall include a strong dollar, higher crude oil prices, and selling by foreign investors.</li><li>US jobs report showed an increase in Non-farm Payrolls, higher than expected, influencing market outlook.</li><li>Approximately $4.2 billion has exited Indian markets in January alone, driven by higher US yields.</li><li>The outlook predicts the rupee will trade within 85.80–86.50 range in the near term with volatility anticipated.</li></ul><blockquote>“This sustained decline reflects a combination of global and domestic pressures.” - Amit Pabari, Managing Director CR Forex Advisors</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/rupee-us-dollar-weak-fii-inflows-9775948/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/rupee-us-dollar-weak-fii-inflows-9775948/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ola Electric stock bounces back with 4.5% gain after 3-day slump, still down 15% in January | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ola Electric Stock Rebounds 4.5% After Three-Day Decline</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Ola Electric Mobility's shares gained 4.5% today, recovering from a three-day slump despite being down 15% for the month so far.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The stock opened at ₹71.50 and peaked at ₹73.46.</li>
  <li>Shares faced selling pressure due to negative developments and slipped below the IPO price of ₹76.</li>
  <li>SEBI warned the company for sharing expansion plans on social media before informing stock exchanges.</li>
  <li>The Karnataka High Court granted a six-week extension for Ola to respond to CCPA's request for documents.</li>
  <li>Ola sold over 407,547 electric vehicles in 2024, a 52% increase compared to the previous year.</li>
  <li>Citi Research initiated coverage with a 'buy' rating and a target price of ₹90 per share.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“By leveraging its direct-to-consumer (D2C) model, Ola is ensuring that EV ownership becomes a reality for every household.” - Ola Electric</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, after a challenging period, Ola Electric is taking steps to recover and expand its market presence while navigating regulatory challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/ola-electric-stock-bounces-back-with-4-5-gain-after-3-day-slump-still-down-15-in-january-11736834647724.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/ola-electric-stock-bounces-back-with-4-5-gain-after-3-day-slump-still-down-15-in-january-11736834647724.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 07:36:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[United Spirits, Adani Green Energy, Adani Power, JSW Energy, NTPC Green Energy, HCLTech: Check top buzzing stocks of the day - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/united-spirits-adani-green-energy-adani-power-jsw-energy-ntpc-green-energy-hcl-tech-check-top-buzzing-stocks-of-the-day/article-140292/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/united-spirits-adani-green-energy-adani-power-jsw-energy-ntpc-green-energy-hcl-tech-check-top-buzzing-stocks-of-the-day/article-140292/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 07:12:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[United Spirits, Adani Green Energy, Adani Power, JSW Energy, NTPC Green Energy, HCLTech: Check top buzzing stocks of the day - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/united-spirits-adani-green-energy-adani-power-jsw-energy-ntpc-green-energy-hcl-tech-check-top-buzzing-stocks-of-the-day/article-140292/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/united-spirits-adani-green-energy-adani-power-jsw-energy-ntpc-green-energy-hcl-tech-check-top-buzzing-stocks-of-the-day/article-140292/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 07:12:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025 Tata Nexon Launched At Rs 7.99 Lakh; New Trims, Features Added - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2025 Tata Nexon Launched At Rs 7.99 Lakh; New Trims, Features Added</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/h6b81u88_2025-nexon-screen_625x300_14_January_25.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=800" alt="Tata Nexon 2025" />
<figcaption>2025 Tata Nexon Showcase</figcaption>
<p>Tata Motors has launched the 2025 Tata Nexon in the Indian market, introducing new trims, colors, and features while maintaining the existing powertrain options.</p>
<ul>
  <li>New exterior colors: Carbon Black, Creative Blue, Royal Blue, Grassland Beige, and others.</li>
  <li>Discontinued trims: Pure, Pure S, Creative Plus, Fearless; New trims include Pure Plus and Pure Plus S.</li>
  <li>New features in trims: updated touchscreen, rain-sensing wipers, panoramic sunroof, 360-degree camera.</li>
  <li>No changes to powertrain: 1.2-litre turbo petrol, 1.5-litre diesel, and a CNG option remain unchanged.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The new top-spec Fearless Plus PS comes equipped with a panoramic sunroof, 10.25-inch digital instrument cluster, and connected tech.”</blockquote>
<p>The launch of the 2025 Tata Nexon represents Tata Motors' continued effort to enhance its vehicle offerings in response to consumer demand while ensuring reliability in performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/auto/2025-tata-nexon-launched-at-rs-7-99-lakh-new-trims-features-added-7469693</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/auto/2025-tata-nexon-launched-at-rs-7-99-lakh-new-trims-features-added-7469693</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 06:47:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amara Raja, BEL to Bharat Forge: Why are EV stocks rising today? Experts link it to this TCS study | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amara Raja, BEL to Bharat Forge: Why EV Stocks are Rising Today</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 14, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> LiveMint</p>
<p>Electric vehicle (EV) stocks like Amara Raja, BEL, Bharat Forge and Minda Corporation gained up to 6% on January 14, driven by a TCS study indicating strong consumer interest in EVs.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Over 64% of consumers are likely to consider an EV for their next purchase.</li>
  <li>60% view charging infrastructure as a key hurdle, yet 56% are willing to invest up to $40,000 for an EV.</li>
  <li>The study surveyed 1,300 respondents across regions including North America, Europe, and APAC.</li>
  <li>53% of commercial fleet operators cite reduced operational costs as a primary motivation for EV adoption.</li>
  <li>Notable stocks witnessing gains include Minda Corporation which rose over 6%.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“EV stocks are rising on improved business buzz in the year 2025... 64% of consumers will likely choose EVs as their next vehicle.” - Avinash Gorakshkar, Head of Research, Profitmart Securities</blockquote>
<p>The TCS study suggests a promising future for EV adoption, indicating that 2025 could be pivotal for the electric vehicle market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/amara-raja-bel-to-bharat-forge-why-are-ev-stocks-rising-today-experts-link-it-to-this-tcs-study-11736834951373.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/amara-raja-bel-to-bharat-forge-why-are-ev-stocks-rising-today-experts-link-it-to-this-tcs-study-11736834951373.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 06:13:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani Energy Solutions shares jump 12% after firm posts strong Q3 business growth - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Adani Energy Solutions Sees 12% Share Surge Following Strong Q3 Growth</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/08/20240815090929_adanirtr.png?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Adani Group" title="Adani Group" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Adani Group</figcaption><p>Adani Energy Solutions' shares jumped over 12% after the company reported significant growth in its Q3 operational metrics.</p><ul><li>Transmission network length increased to 26,485 ckm, up nearly 23% year-over-year.</li><li>Power transmission capacity rose by 54% to 84,286 MVA.</li><li>The company secured two new projects with substantial investments.</li><li>Distribution losses were reduced, and units sold increased by 3% year-over-year.</li></ul><blockquote>“Fully commissioned MP Package-2 transmission line which will strengthen transmission system in the eastern region of Madhya Pradesh by adding 1,088 ckm to the transmission network,” the company stated.</blockquote><p>The solid financial results and expansion efforts position Adani Energy Solutions as a key player in the energy sector, indicating robust growth potential moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/adani-energy-solutions-shares-jump-12-after-firm-announces-strong-q3-business-growth-12910003.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/adani-energy-solutions-shares-jump-12-after-firm-announces-strong-q3-business-growth-12910003.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 05:38:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani Power, Adani Green to Adani Enterprises — Why are Adani group shares skyrocketing? EXPLAINED | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxNcmg1ZHYxR3hRZnRFNEVFUDZDYkRRcFIyY1ZPTEhMcmFmZ2FZcXR4THFDZEp4c2pNTHE3bVUzLTc0ZDFVSUZ4Z0FobTRwMlU2elFoa0N5blpwbUtWTUN6NEx4QUtMUUM0MVJGaUNIZ0kyWk9ka2NKRWdDZGVzbVZaRnU4VkN6UGVFRmNxd2E3alBYLXo3ZHZJUUxXVU9ES2hQai1OQ1NMTEdWYTZIXzVxS1dWS01NcVFIbzRHcFFMZlNRdW9JSDdoaXN3UDhZaUJtSnNfSllHc3prMUhmZlV6bVFXOG1YdklUSzFyWHUtUXVESk5Yem1n0gH8AUFVX3lxTE0zcXc5N3VQSFRWWE5kX1JtMDRvTmdlNl84QWFHcTlYZUxfOWJVd3VqeFZsV25VQW1ITjNXN0phRUtFdTJMZUVqenBhWUY4SnM0SzRLMlZPQlJSVndMTXJrQlNINUwwelRwN2JsWkZPV0lEZ2dBbmhaT2IzQzdMaG43NFRKUVV6VHdBTUNOS05CVUdaU1JrMl9EV0dZMkRhUlA3VTY4SThkbEZ1RVd1UzBNcU1mMENQY1B3UnFpQVZZaEVmeHBmcXFlT29hZ1JUWTdNU2FPNDJkTG5maUFSSWJjRGNIcjdrQjFOM1laZV9CUnR5X3QwV3ZjWjhHNw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxNcmg1ZHYxR3hRZnRFNEVFUDZDYkRRcFIyY1ZPTEhMcmFmZ2FZcXR4THFDZEp4c2pNTHE3bVUzLTc0ZDFVSUZ4Z0FobTRwMlU2elFoa0N5blpwbUtWTUN6NEx4QUtMUUM0MVJGaUNIZ0kyWk9ka2NKRWdDZGVzbVZaRnU4VkN6UGVFRmNxd2E3alBYLXo3ZHZJUUxXVU9ES2hQai1OQ1NMTEdWYTZIXzVxS1dWS01NcVFIbzRHcFFMZlNRdW9JSDdoaXN3UDhZaUJtSnNfSllHc3prMUhmZlV6bVFXOG1YdklUSzFyWHUtUXVESk5Yem1n0gH8AUFVX3lxTE0zcXc5N3VQSFRWWE5kX1JtMDRvTmdlNl84QWFHcTlYZUxfOWJVd3VqeFZsV25VQW1ITjNXN0phRUtFdTJMZUVqenBhWUY4SnM0SzRLMlZPQlJSVndMTXJrQlNINUwwelRwN2JsWkZPV0lEZ2dBbmhaT2IzQzdMaG43NFRKUVV6VHdBTUNOS05CVUdaU1JrMl9EV0dZMkRhUlA3VTY4SThkbEZ1RVd1UzBNcU1mMENQY1B3UnFpQVZZaEVmeHBmcXFlT29hZ1JUWTdNU2FPNDJkTG5maUFSSWJjRGNIcjdrQjFOM1laZV9CUnR5X3QwV3ZjWjhHNw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 05:26:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk to buy TikTok from China, here’s what the company has to say - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk to Buy TikTok from China: Here’s What the Company Has to Say</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here], <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>Elon Musk's potential acquisition of TikTok has sparked significant interest, with the company responding to inquiries about the deal.</p><ul><li>Musk is reportedly interested in acquiring TikTok to bolster his influence in social media.</li><li>Concerns have been raised regarding data privacy and national security implications of such a purchase.</li><li>The company emphasizes its commitment to user trust and data protection.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are focused on maintaining the integrity and safety of our user base across all platforms." - TikTok Representative</blockquote><p>This acquisition could have far-reaching implications in the tech industry and social media landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/social/elon-musk-to-buy-tiktok-from-china-heres-what-the-company-has-to-say/articleshow/117221985.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/social/elon-musk-to-buy-tiktok-from-china-heres-what-the-company-has-to-say/articleshow/117221985.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple iPhone sales drop 5% globally after AI rollout disappoints, Chinese competition grows - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple's global iPhone sales declined by about 5% globally during the final quarter of 2024, due to underwhelming upgrades and rising Chinese competition</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/APPLE-CHINA--1_1736820423331_1736820503969.JPG" alt="A man checks an iPhone 16 Pro Max as the new iPhone 16 series smartphones go on sale at an Apple store in Beijing, China September 20, 2024. REUTERS//File Photo(Florence Lo/Reuters)" title="A man checks an iPhone 16 Pro Max as the new iPhone 16 series smartphones go on sale at an Apple store in Beijing, China September 20, 2024. REUTERS//File Photo(Florence Lo/Reuters)"/><figcaption>A man checks an iPhone 16 Pro Max as the new iPhone 16 series smartphones go on sale at an Apple store in Beijing, China September 20, 2024. REUTERS//File Photo(Florence Lo/Reuters)</figcaption><p>In the final quarter of 2024, Apple Inc. saw a 5% drop in global iPhone sales, attributed to disappointing upgrades and increasing competition from Chinese brands.</p><ul><li>Global iPhone sales dropped by 5% and 2% for the entire year while the industry grew by 4%.</li><li>Apple's market share fell to 18%, with Chinese competitors like Xiaomi and Vivo gaining ground.</li><li>Chinese smartphone vendors achieved record shipments, accounting for 56% of the global market.</li><li>Apple’s AI features lag behind competitors, particularly in China, Apple’s major market outside the US and Europe.</li></ul><blockquote>“This past quarter was particularly remarkable for the largest Chinese smartphone vendors,” said IDC analyst Francisco Jeronimo.</blockquote><p>Although Apple’s overall sales were down, there was a noted increase in the sales of higher-end iPhone models in China, representing over half of its shipments there.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/apple-iphone-sales-drop-5-globally-after-ai-rollout-disappoints-chinese-competition-grows-101736819320746.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/apple-iphone-sales-drop-5-globally-after-ai-rollout-disappoints-chinese-competition-grows-101736819320746.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:12:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HCLTech stock nosedives 9% after marginal guidance upgrade hints at weaker Q4 - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HCLTech stock nosedives 9% after marginal guidance upgrade hints at weaker Q4</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/09/20240919093212_HCL-Tech.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="HCL" title="HCL" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>HCL stock performance chart</figcaption>
<p>Shares of India's third largest IT company, HCLTech plummeted over 9 percent on January 14, driven by updated revenue guidance indicating weaker growth for Q4, revealing a surprising shift in market sentiment.</p>
<ul>
  <li>HCLTech shares fell 9% following the release of its Q3 performance.</li>
  <li>The company's earnings were in-line, but the guidance hinted at a weaker performance for Q4.</li>
  <li>Current share price stands at Rs 1,804.65, marking the biggest single-day decline in nearly a decade.</li>
  <li>Revenue growth guidance for fiscal year 2025 was adjusted to 4.5-5%, an upgrade of 100 basis points on the lower end.</li>
  <li>CEO C Vijayakumar noted challenges including a telecom deal scale-down and delays in project ramp-ups.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Brokerages pointed out that the updated guidance suggested weaker growth for Q4, which came as a disappointment, especially with improved discretionary demand.”</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights the volatility of the tech stock market and investor reactions to earnings forecasts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/hcltech-stock-nosedives-9-after-marginal-guidance-upgrade-hints-weaker-q4-12909914.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/hcltech-stock-nosedives-9-after-marginal-guidance-upgrade-hints-weaker-q4-12909914.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:10:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[L&T HR head Sonica Muraleedharan addresses backlash over chairmans 90-hour work week row - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQQTBVLTNNUW1DZ3Nlc1BNdFBQY0ZydURRcXpHSERpV0EteWdxdWs0SWp3V191RTZScjI3bUFFUzRjYlU5TW1rWjJZWmNjWVNLeW01RjlCX3RWM0ZIc0FfcnozclNaMlFDWFlLTXFJQVJ6czRCRDlzZWwzbHdBYTZRNm9BZmpWdl80c29zNHZuVVpjelZndENaTE9UeWxTZ2JvWDY4clZodEpMOXFjSjBBVkpOQi1pODVWV3RmQXdGVktFb0NCUHJn0gHLAUFVX3lxTE0zMUpRa1JSZnZPaG1DQ2hsdTRpRl9pVlRheldrV01uZnFkMkl5X2d5d2JJaG5TZFF6SnBTeDc1Yi1qRXJpQlRoUXUxZlUyUWhLMWo0cHNGWWQtOXNBZDg5ZWgyLTJiM0kxcUhhOHhyY3JzdmhLNzQ5RFRUa1d2a1RHZFVVQjJaYlo1ZzJDZzBHZjBncHN4NzhrS3pYdmtKcUVjUFJsRDNzejJ4b1hCWktKTjF6ZG03U1RkTEx2dHFQclhMcEFOclNKeG1V?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQQTBVLTNNUW1DZ3Nlc1BNdFBQY0ZydURRcXpHSERpV0EteWdxdWs0SWp3V191RTZScjI3bUFFUzRjYlU5TW1rWjJZWmNjWVNLeW01RjlCX3RWM0ZIc0FfcnozclNaMlFDWFlLTXFJQVJ6czRCRDlzZWwzbHdBYTZRNm9BZmpWdl80c29zNHZuVVpjelZndENaTE9UeWxTZ2JvWDY4clZodEpMOXFjSjBBVkpOQi1pODVWV3RmQXdGVktFb0NCUHJn0gHLAUFVX3lxTE0zMUpRa1JSZnZPaG1DQ2hsdTRpRl9pVlRheldrV01uZnFkMkl5X2d5d2JJaG5TZFF6SnBTeDc1Yi1qRXJpQlRoUXUxZlUyUWhLMWo0cHNGWWQtOXNBZDg5ZWgyLTJiM0kxcUhhOHhyY3JzdmhLNzQ5RFRUa1d2a1RHZFVVQjJaYlo1ZzJDZzBHZjBncHN4NzhrS3pYdmtKcUVjUFJsRDNzejJ4b1hCWktKTjF6ZG03U1RkTEx2dHFQclhMcEFOclNKeG1V?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:06:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold Rate Rises In India: Check 22 Carat Price In Your City On January 14 - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/savings-and-investments/gold-rate-today-mumbai-18-carat-24-carat-22k-9187873.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/savings-and-investments/gold-rate-today-mumbai-18-carat-24-carat-22k-9187873.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:53:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold Rate Rises In India: Check 22 Carat Price In Your City On January 14 - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/savings-and-investments/gold-rate-today-mumbai-18-carat-24-carat-22k-9187873.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/savings-and-investments/gold-rate-today-mumbai-18-carat-24-carat-22k-9187873.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:53:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China slows supply chain shifts by Apple, others as Trump 2.0 looms - Nikkei Asia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOejZlWXVyLWxrejZwWUprdFhSa25HdWtPeVdFeXFVLTZiV203TTZTakh2MG5QTlZyaEw2ZlFZN3loSmRSLVdqcXJNLWVWSlEzUHpKTFpiSVZpVnAyVkJmdTkzcUMteHBKWjdQbUdPRFVaOXdLZGYtWkNVblRCdzZPMWwxajJCTk9idGx2MDdVT2wtazNlaXN4UFBWeTY4engxb3VCdVJLRU45dVQtUzRacUZ0Zw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOejZlWXVyLWxrejZwWUprdFhSa25HdWtPeVdFeXFVLTZiV203TTZTakh2MG5QTlZyaEw2ZlFZN3loSmRSLVdqcXJNLWVWSlEzUHpKTFpiSVZpVnAyVkJmdTkzcUMteHBKWjdQbUdPRFVaOXdLZGYtWkNVblRCdzZPMWwxajJCTk9idGx2MDdVT2wtazNlaXN4UFBWeTY4engxb3VCdVJLRU45dVQtUzRacUZ0Zw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Chinese delay’ make Apple and Foxconn seek government help - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chinese Delay Forces Apple and Foxconn to Request Government Assistance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Apple and Foxconn are seeking help from the government due to delays attributed to China.</p><ul><li>Chinese manufacturing delays are impacting production schedules for Apple and Foxconn.</li><li>Both companies are exploring government assistance to mitigate the situation.</li></ul><p>The ongoing situation highlights the vulnerabilities in global supply chains, especially in tech manufacturing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/chinese-delay-make-apple-and-foxconn-seek-government-help/articleshow/117220984.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/chinese-delay-make-apple-and-foxconn-seek-government-help/articleshow/117220984.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This analyst expects MGL to benefit from Mumbai's Tesla-like moment - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This analyst expects MGL to benefit from Mumbai's Tesla-like moment</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBCTV18</p><img alt="This analyst expects MGL to benefit from Mumbai's Tesla-like moment" title="This analyst expects MGL to benefit from Mumbai's Tesla-like moment" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" decoding="async" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>An analyst believes MGL will capitalize on Mumbai's burgeoning natural gas market.</figcaption><p>The article discusses how Morgan Stanley has initiated coverage of Mahanagar Gas Ltd. (MGL) with an 'Overweight' rating, highlighting the city's expanding energy needs and the role of natural gas.</p><ul><li>MGL is expected to benefit from a growing market for natural gas in Mumbai.</li><li>The brokerage projected a price target of ₹1,606, indicating a potential upside of over 30% from the current levels.</li><li>One-fifth of MGL's gas sourcing is linked to LNG, which could impact margins positively.</li><li>The article describes this expansion as MGL's “Tesla-like moment” in the gas market.</li><li>A weak third quarter is anticipated, but improvements may come in the fourth quarter FY25.</li><li>MGL shares decreased by 4.37% on Monday, settling at ₹1,229.90.</li></ul><blockquote>“Natural gas is considered the fuel of the future for Mumbai.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, MGL is positioned well to capitalize on the growth in Mumbai’s natural gas market, even amid challenges in the short term.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/mahanagar-gas-share-price-this-analyst-expects-mgl-to-benefit-from-mumbai-tesla-like-moment-19539537.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/mahanagar-gas-share-price-this-analyst-expects-mgl-to-benefit-from-mumbai-tesla-like-moment-19539537.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:35:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vishal Mega Mart shares emerge as a Mutual Fund favourite post listing - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vishal Mega Mart Shares Become a Favorite Among Mutual Funds Post-Listing</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 14, 2025 8:44 AM IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p>
<img alt="Vishal Mega Mart shares emerge as a Mutual Fund favourite post listing" title="Vishal Mega Mart shares emerge as a Mutual Fund favourite post listing" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360">
<figcaption>Vishal Mega Mart shares have garnered significant interest from domestic mutual funds post-listing.</figcaption>
<p>Newly listed Vishal Mega Mart Ltd. has attracted considerable interest from India's domestic mutual funds, reflected in its shareholding pattern.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Domestic Mutual Funds own an 8.66% stake in Vishal Mega Mart.</li>
  <li>Nippon India AMC has a 3.08% stake in the company.</li>
  <li>Aditya Birla Sun Life Mutual Fund purchased shares worth ₹250 crore.</li>
  <li>Axis Mutual Fund bought shares worth ₹380 crore.</li>
  <li>Total retail investor stake stands at 4.52%, with 9.13 lakh retail shareholders.</li>
  <li>The stock closed 4% lower at ₹104 but trades above its IPO price of ₹79.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Foreign Portfolio Investors (FPIs) held a 6.47% stake as of December, with the Government of Singapore notably holding 1.67%.”</blockquote>
<p>Vishal Mega Mart's listing has seen strong support from mutual funds, showcasing investor confidence in the company.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/vishal-mega-mart-share-price-mutual-funds-buy-post-listing-fpi-retail-ipo-returns-19539535.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/vishal-mega-mart-share-price-mutual-funds-buy-post-listing-fpi-retail-ipo-returns-19539535.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:14:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shares to buy or sell: Chandan Taparia recommends three stocks to buy and sell today | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxNV2NhMjVVdnhJTWtDUFJoUWh1bHFHVDNTYXFGdV80RFM3MG94RmtfYk45MXhZTWdDYXdJcTlVZXVwc1lKMGFUZXJVczVRSVozVXU5aGJQdDZYNW9UYkZOWmJteVE3cTg4STNrWHRJZ2wxMHAyejR2cTVOeldydWpBT2dBM1NYeGtYd1Y1eGd0VVlvaGg4MzNfNlN0Vi1odGZpdFVDcG84Tzd4M2JrUGxnVzFYRk5xaEdVdkRaN2QyeGZOZi1uT3psR1AtQzFrbzd6TkY0d2VVUURpc1VhWWNxUGk5cGxuMW9q0gHuAUFVX3lxTE5iVzI2XzRLNmFaTWJuYlU0VGpidGptUWpiOVlGci1KNXMyRFF0a3JCT2pUdFhXWk5JSTVBUUd3Y1c1ZlR6Mk9SdGdKMWZZRnFJb004Z2kxcnZHZHVOcW1iY20xSjBoQWtjTy1kTVp1Qk5xWnVRdVByMkpDSF82Z3lzdzVSQy1WNmo5X3JHVVE5ZmtPYm95NnJxQWNBVlJOczY5N3dTN2tIVGtHTU9vbkthVGhJUjZ5UGZkbnZ6MjQ0TTFXd2lGUjBVblNwVFoxVXNpdXdZOG1rZnBreFQ4Ym5mNEswNi01Z1FuRTJGN3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxNV2NhMjVVdnhJTWtDUFJoUWh1bHFHVDNTYXFGdV80RFM3MG94RmtfYk45MXhZTWdDYXdJcTlVZXVwc1lKMGFUZXJVczVRSVozVXU5aGJQdDZYNW9UYkZOWmJteVE3cTg4STNrWHRJZ2wxMHAyejR2cTVOeldydWpBT2dBM1NYeGtYd1Y1eGd0VVlvaGg4MzNfNlN0Vi1odGZpdFVDcG84Tzd4M2JrUGxnVzFYRk5xaEdVdkRaN2QyeGZOZi1uT3psR1AtQzFrbzd6TkY0d2VVUURpc1VhWWNxUGk5cGxuMW9q0gHuAUFVX3lxTE5iVzI2XzRLNmFaTWJuYlU0VGpidGptUWpiOVlGci1KNXMyRFF0a3JCT2pUdFhXWk5JSTVBUUd3Y1c1ZlR6Mk9SdGdKMWZZRnFJb004Z2kxcnZHZHVOcW1iY20xSjBoQWtjTy1kTVp1Qk5xWnVRdVByMkpDSF82Z3lzdzVSQy1WNmo5X3JHVVE5ZmtPYm95NnJxQWNBVlJOczY5N3dTN2tIVGtHTU9vbkthVGhJUjZ5UGZkbnZ6MjQ0TTFXd2lGUjBVblNwVFoxVXNpdXdZOG1rZnBreFQ4Ym5mNEswNi01Z1FuRTJGN3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:05:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HCLTech shares tumble 10% on no big positive announcements in Q3 FY25 earnings; check key numbers - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxNS3FuY1dndVRvNDE2NVpUZEFYMnFQOWxCYV9UcllUdnJ6QlRYczF6RE1VbnNXTld1ajBXTW5Oc0k0VXBVR0JYc0tfUHZuLUlCa2w1dFVwekpYUC1QbUJ5OHY2M0FWYjFDUzlZV2RjdW41S1I1ank3UzJQVE1wd3ZlRDZneUI0bnA5RmJQN0FFTU5uSDAyS1dnOF96UDAyRzBTZHc5TF94UTRidHZvSHplam42dFExV1lMUGwtc3BXQU1QU2ozRkpWWmU5ckp3VXBFTU9rSFJkeUl1N3dOS1dPZl9vdzdDekNfUDV6clBWWjM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxNS3FuY1dndVRvNDE2NVpUZEFYMnFQOWxCYV9UcllUdnJ6QlRYczF6RE1VbnNXTld1ajBXTW5Oc0k0VXBVR0JYc0tfUHZuLUlCa2w1dFVwekpYUC1QbUJ5OHY2M0FWYjFDUzlZV2RjdW41S1I1ank3UzJQVE1wd3ZlRDZneUI0bnA5RmJQN0FFTU5uSDAyS1dnOF96UDAyRzBTZHc5TF94UTRidHZvSHplam42dFExV1lMUGwtc3BXQU1QU2ozRkpWWmU5ckp3VXBFTU9rSFJkeUl1N3dOS1dPZl9vdzdDekNfUDV6clBWWjM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:03:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Recognise efforts rather than misinterpret them': L&T HR head defends chairman’s 90-hour workweek remark - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Recognise efforts rather than misinterpret them': L&T HR head defends chairman’s 90-hour workweek remark</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Not Provided]</p><p>The HR head of L&T has defended the chairman's recent remark regarding his 90-hour workweek, emphasizing the importance of recognizing efforts rather than misinterpretations.</p><ul><li>The chairman received backlash for discussing his long working hours.</li><li>The HR head highlighted the need for a fair understanding of employee dedication.</li><li>The conversation touches on work-life balance concerns in modern workplaces.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is crucial to appreciate the commitment individuals show without misinterpretations.”</blockquote><p>This article sheds light on the ongoing discussion around work hours and employee recognition in the corporate world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/recognise-efforts-rather-than-misinterpret-them-lt-hr-head-defends-chairmans-90-hour-workweek-remark/articleshow/117221241.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/recognise-efforts-rather-than-misinterpret-them-lt-hr-head-defends-chairmans-90-hour-workweek-remark/articleshow/117221241.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China discusses sale of TikTok US to Elon Musk as one possible option - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China discusses sale of TikTok US to Elon Musk as one possible option</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p>
<p>China is reportedly considering the option of selling TikTok's US operations to Elon Musk amid ongoing concerns about data privacy and security.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The discussions arise as tensions between the U.S. and China escalate over technology and trade.</li>
  <li>Elon Musk's interest in acquiring TikTok could reshape the social media landscape.</li>
  <li>This potential sale is framed within broader efforts to address regulatory scrutiny facing TikTok.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The sale could provide a new path forward for TikTok amid regulatory challenges in the U.S.”</blockquote>
<p>This potential sale is a significant development in the ongoing saga of data privacy and tech company regulations, with implications for users and the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/international-business/china-discusses-sale-of-tiktok-us-to-elon-musk-as-one-possible-option/articleshow/117219501.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/international-business/china-discusses-sale-of-tiktok-us-to-elon-musk-as-one-possible-option/articleshow/117219501.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to watch, January 14: JSW Energy, HCLTech, Shoppers Stop, HDFC AMC, Himadri Speciality, Delta Corp, and more - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to Watch, January 14: JSW Energy, HCLTech, Shoppers Stop, and More</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Unspecified Financial News Source</p>
<p>In today’s stock market update, major companies such as HCLTech and JSW Energy are in focus as several firms prepare to release their financial results.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>NIFTY50 Opening:</strong> Expected to open 114 points higher at 23,276.50.</li>
  <li><strong>HCL Technologies:</strong> Reported a 5.54% growth in net profit to ₹4,591 crore for Q3 FY25.</li>
  <li><strong>JSW Energy:</strong> Acquired KSK Mahanadi Power Company under insolvency proceedings.</li>
  <li><strong>Delta Corp:</strong> Net profit increased by 3.62% to ₹35.73 crore.</li>
  <li><strong>Other Earnings:</strong> Companies like HDFC AMC and Shoppers Stop set to announce Q3 results.</li>
  <li><strong>Den Networks:</strong> Experienced a YoY net profit decline of 14.6%.</li>
  <li><strong>Himadri Speciality:</strong> Reported a 31.55% jump in net profit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“JSW Energy emerged as a successful applicant to acquire KSK Mahanadi Power Company.”</blockquote>
<p>This trading day focuses on earnings results and market indicators, emphasizing shifts in major technology and energy sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/stocks-to-watch-january-14-jsw-energy-hcl-tech-shoppers-stop-hdfc-amc-himadri-speciality-delta-corp-and-more/article-140188/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/stocks-to-watch-january-14-jsw-energy-hcl-tech-shoppers-stop-hdfc-amc-himadri-speciality-delta-corp-and-more/article-140188/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:08:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ITC Hotels shares credited to Demat accounts after allotment; ITC investors get THIS special message - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ITC Hotels Shares Credited to Investors' Demat Accounts After Allotment</h1>
<p><strong>Updated:</strong> <strong>January 14, 2025</strong> - <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="ITC Hotels shares credited allotment listing" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>ITC Hotels shares credited to Demat accounts after allotment (Pic: ET NOW)</figcaption>
<p>ITC Hotels shares have been credited to the Demat accounts of eligible ITC shareholders following the allotment announced on January 11, with shares credited on January 13.</p>
<ul>
<li>Eligible shareholders received an SMS confirming the credit of ITC Hotels shares to their accounts.</li>
<li>A total of 125.11 crore equity shares have been allotted to ITC shareholders based on their holdings as of January 6.</li>
<li>The shares carry no value at the moment and are currently represented as a dummy ticker in Demat accounts.</li>
<li>ITC Hotels shares will be listed on NSE and BSE, with trading set to start after the listing.</li>
<li>Shares will be included in Nifty 50 and BSE Sensex as a dummy ticker before their official listing.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Consequent to the above, ITCHL has ceased to be a subsidiary of the Company effective 11th January, 2025," ITC stated.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, ITC Hotels shares are now available in shareholders' Demat accounts, ready for future trading post-listing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/itc-hotels-shares-credited-to-demat-accounts-after-allotment-message-sms-itc-hotels-listing-date-price-prediction-nse-bse-article-117218965</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/itc-hotels-shares-credited-to-demat-accounts-after-allotment-message-sms-itc-hotels-listing-date-price-prediction-nse-bse-article-117218965</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:08:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[D-Street's $556 billion equity rout seen worsening as growth cools - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQdW84M3VIRkJzamg3OGdTd25qWk9tZlRqQTF1Qml1YUY3Z0NoYUhoR1ZJTnl2Z2dsTGIxcHVrT0d1bVZXc3g4OWdKZXU4cjVRODRpaGdRazhWa0pqVlp1dGZoaV9oUEF2ekYyTDVjTjlxNThsazZGd1N5Skgwb3UxalJ6OFJDU3BPTTZWTEJ4c3cxLWpqYlN0c2J3Q3MyV0pTYmlUY2tud1pVYlJqX2REcVhIZFJTQlh4Rld3MGh6RUhQaERmR05IVmFGcTFPMTJLSnJCSA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQdW84M3VIRkJzamg3OGdTd25qWk9tZlRqQTF1Qml1YUY3Z0NoYUhoR1ZJTnl2Z2dsTGIxcHVrT0d1bVZXc3g4OWdKZXU4cjVRODRpaGdRazhWa0pqVlp1dGZoaV9oUEF2ekYyTDVjTjlxNThsazZGd1N5Skgwb3UxalJ6OFJDU3BPTTZWTEJ4c3cxLWpqYlN0c2J3Q3MyV0pTYmlUY2tud1pVYlJqX2REcVhIZFJTQlh4Rld3MGh6RUhQaERmR05IVmFGcTFPMTJLSnJCSA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:06:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China considering TikTok US sale to Elon Musk if company fails to fend off potential ban: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Considering Selling TikTok to Elon Musk Amid U.S. Ban Threat</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/FRANCE-TECHNOLOGY-AI-GROK-5_1736816980536_1736817013231.jpg" alt="Screens displaying the logo of Grok, a generative artificial intelligence chatbot developed by xAI, the American company specializing in artificial intelligence and its founder Elon Musk.(AFP)" />
<figcaption>Screens displaying the logo of Grok, a generative artificial intelligence chatbot developed by xAI, the American company specializing in artificial intelligence and its founder Elon Musk.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>China is contemplating selling TikTok's U.S. operations to Elon Musk if the company fails to prevent a proposed ban by U.S. authorities.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Chinese officials prefer TikTok to remain with parent company ByteDance.</li>
  <li>A potential ban on TikTok is expected as President-elect Trump assumes office, raising national security concerns.</li>
  <li>Musk, a supporter of Trump, has been appointed co-chair of the Department of Government Efficiency.</li>
  <li>ByteDance is contesting the impending ban in the U.S. Supreme Court, which has set a deadline of January 19 for a sale.</li>
  <li>About half of the U.S. population uses TikTok, which has raised data privacy concerns among lawmakers.</li>
  <li>A sale to Musk might align TikTok's operations more closely with his management style of Twitter, now rebranded as “X.”</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>TikTok is used by roughly half of the US population, catering to around 170 million users.</blockquote>
<p>The situation surrounding TikTok continues to evolve, with significant implications for its future in the U.S. market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/china-considering-tiktok-us-sale-to-elon-musk-if-company-fails-to-fend-off-potential-ban-report-101736816819501.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/china-considering-tiktok-us-sale-to-elon-musk-if-company-fails-to-fend-off-potential-ban-report-101736816819501.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:35:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian stock market: 7 key things that changed for market overnight - Gift Nifty, CPI inflation to HCL Tech Q3 Results | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian stock market: 7 key things that changed for market overnight - Gift Nifty, CPI inflation to HCL Tech Q3 Results</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The domestic equity market indices, Sensex and Nifty 50, are expected to open higher on Tuesday amid mixed global cues, following a significant crash on Monday.</p><ul><li>On Monday, the Sensex and Nifty suffered substantial declines of 1.36% and 1.47%, respectively.</li><li>Rising crude oil prices, a depreciating rupee, and foreign capital outflows were primary contributors to the sell-off.</li><li>Asian markets showed a mixed response, with Japan's Nikkei down while South Korea's Kospi rose.</li><li>The Gift Nifty suggests a gap-up start, trading at around 23,280.</li><li>HCL Technologies reported an 8.4% QoQ increase in net profit for Q3, showing strong performance amidst market fluctuations.</li><li>Retail inflation in India eased to a four-month low at 5.22%, which may ease concerns for rate cuts from the RBI.</li><li>Strong direct tax collection growth indicates robust economic activity despite market volatility.</li></ul><blockquote>“Wide-spread selling across the sectors fuelled along with massive exits in mid and small-cap stocks further worsened the sentiment.” - Prashanth Tapse, Senior VP (Research), Mehta Equities Ltd.</blockquote><p>This market turbulence reflects ongoing global trends and highlights the complexities of the current economic landscape, as various factors are contributing to the risk and resilience of the Indian stock market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/indian-stock-market-7-key-things-that-changed-for-market-overnight-gift-nifty-cpi-inflation-to-hcl-tech-q3-results-11736790154753.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/indian-stock-market-7-key-things-that-changed-for-market-overnight-gift-nifty-cpi-inflation-to-hcl-tech-q3-results-11736790154753.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:27:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GIFT Nifty up 150 points; here's the trading setup for today's session - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GIFT Nifty up 150 points; here's the trading setup for today's session</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today<br><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>Indian markets experienced a sell-off due to strong US payroll data, leading to expectations of volatility. The GIFT Nifty indicates a gap-up start for Dalal Street.</p><img src='image_url.jpg' alt='GIFT Nifty Trend'><figcaption>GIFT Nifty trading trends</figcaption><p>Key factors influencing the market include the upcoming 2025 budget, Q3 results, RBI policy, and global political events.</p><ul><li>GIFT Nifty traded up by 152.50 points, indicating a positive start.</li><li>India VIX rose 7.2% to 16 levels, reflecting increased market fear.</li><li>Foreign portfolio investors were net sellers, while domestic institutional investors bought shares worth Rs 8,066 crore.</li><li>The rupee declined sharply, hitting a historic low of 86.62 against the US dollar.</li></ul><blockquote>“Any pullback up to 23,350 could be a sell-on-rise opportunity.” - Nagaraj Shetti, HDFC Securities</blockquote><p>The market is expected to remain volatile as key economic and political factors unfold.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/pre-market-action-heres-the-trade-setup-for-todays-session/articleshow/117211167.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/pre-market-action-heres-the-trade-setup-for-todays-session/articleshow/117211167.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China's export curbs: Hi-tech machinery supply faces major hit - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's Export Curbs: Hi-Tech Machinery Supply Faces Major Hit</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<div><img src="https://img.etimg.com/photo/msid-117214239/1.jpg" alt="" title="1">
<figcaption>Chinese government halts capital equipment exports impacting Indian manufacturing.</figcaption></div>
<p>China's tightening of export regulations is dramatically affecting sectors reliant on hi-tech machinery, particularly in electronics and electric vehicles, with industry leaders warning of severe manufacturing setbacks in India.</p>
<ul>
  <li>China has almost halted exports of critical industrial machinery needed for production.</li>
  <li>Firms like Foxconn, BYD, and Lenovo face challenges in scaling up operations in India.</li>
  <li>The Indian government is considering measures to mitigate the impact on manufacturing.</li>
  <li>The restrictions are seen as a protectionist move by Beijing amid geopolitical tensions.</li>
  <li>India's domestic manufacturing ecosystem is underdeveloped compared to other countries such as Vietnam.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Chinese government is stopping capital equipment exports from China which are critical to the manufacturing of various products, especially electronics, EVs and solar panels.” - Anonymous executive</blockquote>
<p>China's export restrictions could hurt evolving manufacturing ecosystems in India, compelling the government to rethink strategies to support domestic industries reliant on Chinese machinery.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/foreign-trade/chinas-export-curbs-hi-tech-machinery-supply-faces-major-hit/articleshow/117214222.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/foreign-trade/chinas-export-curbs-hi-tech-machinery-supply-faces-major-hit/articleshow/117214222.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>