<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:16:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:16:49 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Great Republic Day Sale begins on January 13, Prime members to get 12-hour early access - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amazon Great Republic Day Sale Begins on January 13, Prime Members to Get 12-Hour Early Access</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Amazon_Great_Republic_Day_Sale_1736323715522_1736323720287.png" alt="Get ready for amazing deals! The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale starts January 13, with exclusive early access for Prime members. Don’t miss it!" title="Get ready for amazing deals! The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale starts January 13, with exclusive early access for Prime members. Don’t miss it!">
<figcaption>Get ready for amazing deals! The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale starts January 13, with exclusive early access for Prime members. Don’t miss it!</figcaption>
<p>The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale is set to commence on January 13, providing Prime members with an exclusive 12-hour early access to amazing discounts across various categories.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Deals on washing machines, saving up to 65%.</li>
  <li>Smart TVs available at discounts up to 65%.</li>
  <li>Refrigerators discounted by up to 65%.</li>
  <li>Excellent promotions on laptops catering to various needs.</li>
  <li>Significant bank offers for additional savings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale ensures significant savings for every shopper.”</blockquote>
<p>This upcoming sale promises an extensive range of discounted items, making it a great opportunity to snag some incredible deals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-begins-on-january-13-prime-members-to-get-12-hour-early-access-101736323669229.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-begins-on-january-13-prime-members-to-get-12-hour-early-access-101736323669229.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:45:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quadrant Future Tek IPO Day 2: Issue booked over 40 times so far; check offer size, price band and more - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxOeHFwSDd0WFFzRXJXM01qTnJIel82cTJwdEZqQWVnMWxFeGRBWU1fYTBTcHZEbW9ENS1YM1lYSFZhQlRwdzRnTXJjVS1YdkozMUlIZWNoLXpVV3VHRmU4QzZPUVdNLTM4YkZTbWc3b0Y2SzZueHZEUW5SZk40cXZzT3dFemtXdmhNZDFnZ1M3Q1p3a3k3dVVZRVA1eDhfaHRobW1IeWEwa18yTHpjVEhsM2hNNXZPOGdVRnRoT2JJZUVhZVQxTnVqWjVDdjFUOEc3WFFaWjg4VEtwRkJ2bHdYU3RuSmk5OVlDVGZVWg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxOeHFwSDd0WFFzRXJXM01qTnJIel82cTJwdEZqQWVnMWxFeGRBWU1fYTBTcHZEbW9ENS1YM1lYSFZhQlRwdzRnTXJjVS1YdkozMUlIZWNoLXpVV3VHRmU4QzZPUVdNLTM4YkZTbWc3b0Y2SzZueHZEUW5SZk40cXZzT3dFemtXdmhNZDFnZ1M3Q1p3a3k3dVVZRVA1eDhfaHRobW1IeWEwa18yTHpjVEhsM2hNNXZPOGdVRnRoT2JJZUVhZVQxTnVqWjVDdjFUOEc3WFFaWjg4VEtwRkJ2bHdYU3RuSmk5OVlDVGZVWg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:35:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market crash: IRCTC along with 2 other stocks hit 52-week low; here’s why - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxOOENQYWpfN2QzSjFTYVdITWJvZ2JQaWVGLTdSUnBnTHJfZ2ZPcHFTallJRHZCUHZpc3ItVk5KS1VkbkRGZGpIaU1TSUFqLWZTbnNNemVBWTg2U29TWTRYdEIwWmhLeURjcHFQTGVIV2JiRVhiMkx4T2wyOWxWWFRQcHZGcU1XNGY3eTR5VktDSXo3SVVKakR3bXlaYnM4ZVR4NHA3NWZFQTJaMjVJUzRsMzhBY2pEWkxGU0xSNjV1czdEbmVKQ0Z0TnVSTWh5ekdIcEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxOOENQYWpfN2QzSjFTYVdITWJvZ2JQaWVGLTdSUnBnTHJfZ2ZPcHFTallJRHZCUHZpc3ItVk5KS1VkbkRGZGpIaU1TSUFqLWZTbnNNemVBWTg2U29TWTRYdEIwWmhLeURjcHFQTGVIV2JiRVhiMkx4T2wyOWxWWFRQcHZGcU1XNGY3eTR5VktDSXo3SVVKakR3bXlaYnM4ZVR4NHA3NWZFQTJaMjVJUzRsMzhBY2pEWkxGU0xSNjV1czdEbmVKQ0Z0TnVSTWh5ekdIcEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:31:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sensex crashes over 600 points: What's behind the fall in Indian stock market & how to trade now? | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sensex Crashes Over 600 Points: What’s Behind the Fall in Indian Stock Market & How to Trade Now?</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>January 8, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source: </strong>Live Mint</p><p>The Indian stock market faced a significant downturn today, with the Sensex crashing over 700 points amid global weakness and increased selling pressure from foreign investors. The Nifty 50 also recorded a notable decline.</p><img src='link-to-image.jpg' alt='Sensex Downfall' /><figcaption>A visual representation of the market decline</figcaption><p>The following key factors have contributed to the market's drop:</p><ul><li>Weak global cues affecting domestic sentiment.</li><li>Waning hopes for a US Federal Reserve rate cut.</li><li>Caution ahead of expected Q3 earnings season.</li><li>Poor performance from major IT and banking stocks.</li><li>Sustained foreign capital outflows impacting market stability.</li></ul><blockquote>"The trend of strong US macros weakening emerging markets is continuing." - V K Vijayakumar, Chief Investment Strategist at Geojit Financial Services</blockquote><p>Investors are encouraged to consider a long-term perspective, targeting large-cap stocks in financials and pharmaceuticals as potential recovery plays.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/sensex-crashes-over-600-points-whats-behind-the-fall-in-indian-stock-market-how-to-trade-now-11736319472533.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/sensex-crashes-over-600-points-whats-behind-the-fall-in-indian-stock-market-how-to-trade-now-11736319472533.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:08:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why are shares of Dixon Technologies, CG Power and peers witnessing a sharp fall? - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why are shares of Dixon Technologies, CG Power and peers witnessing a sharp fall?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="Why are shares of Dixon Technologies, CG Power and peers witnessing a sharp fall?" title="Why are shares of Dixon Technologies, CG Power and peers witnessing a sharp fall?" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" decoding="async" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Shares of Dixon Technologies and others are seeing significant declines.</figcaption><p>The stocks of Dixon Technologies and other Electronic Manufacturing Companies have experienced sharp declines, leading to a loss of up to 8% in daily trading. This follows Tata Group's announcement of a $18 billion investment in electronics and semiconductor production.</p><ul><li>Dixon Technologies sees an 8% drop in share price.</li><li>Other companies such as Kaynes Tech and CG Power also report losses of 4% to 8%.</li><li>The Tata Group's planned $18 billion investment aims to open nine new factories over two years.</li><li>Nomura recently labeled Dixon a top pick in the EMS sector, with a target price of ₹22,256.</li><li>A significant increase in mobile exports is projected, benefiting Dixon Technologies.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tata Group Chairman N Chandrasekaran called this field a 'long game'.”</blockquote><p>The recent downturn in shares contrasts sharply with the substantial gains these companies made over the past year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/dixon-technologies-share-price-crash-kaynes-cg-power-pg-electroplast-stock-tata-electronics-18-billion-19536450.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/dixon-technologies-share-price-crash-kaynes-cg-power-pg-electroplast-stock-tata-electronics-18-billion-19536450.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:21:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kalyan Jewellers share price slumps 6% on profit booking post Q3 update; Should you buy or sell? | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kalyan Jewellers Share Price Slumps 6% on Profit Booking Post Q3 Update</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Kalyan Jewellers shares fell by 6.2% after a Q3 update indicated significant revenue growth driven by festive demand.</p><ul><li>The stock dropped to ₹677.55 following investor profit booking.</li><li>Q3 revenue grew nearly 41% year-on-year, with a same-store sales increase of 24%.</li><li>The company launched 24 new showrooms in India during the quarter.</li><li>Revenue from the Middle East increased by approximately 22% compared to the previous year.</li><li>Kalyan's digital brand, Candere, saw an 89% revenue growth and opened 23 new showrooms.</li><li>The firm inaugurated its first COCO showroom in the U.S.</li><li>Motilal Oswal issued a 'buy' rating for Kalyan Jewellers stock with a target price of ₹850.</li></ul><blockquote>“The stock is in strong uptrend and forming higher lows on monthly scale from last few months,” Motilal Oswal reported.</blockquote><p>This downward movement in share price comes despite robust overall business performance, leaving investors considering future actions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/kalyan-jewellers-share-price-slumps-6-on-profit-booking-post-q3-update-should-you-buy-or-sell-11736318873803.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/kalyan-jewellers-share-price-slumps-6-on-profit-booking-post-q3-update-should-you-buy-or-sell-11736318873803.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:20:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft inks strategic partnerships to make India’s core sectors AI-first - Microsoft]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Microsoft inks strategic partnerships to make India’s core sectors AI-first</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Source India</p>
<img src="https://pub-c2c1d9230f0b4abb9b0d2d95e06fd4ef.r2.dev/sites/45/2025/01/Satya-ND-FINAL--960x640.jpg" alt="Person on stage, speaking at Microsoft event">
<figcaption>Microsoft chairman and CEO, Satya Nadella, on stage at the Microsoft AI Tour in New Delhi.</figcaption>
<p>Microsoft has announced several strategic partnerships with key sectors in India to enhance cloud and AI initiatives, aiming to build a robust AI ecosystem in the country.</p>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft has formed alliances with RailTel, Apollo Hospitals, Bajaj Finserv, Mahindra Group, and upGrad to advance AI adoption in their operations.</li>
<li>The company signed an MoU with India AI to support AI innovation, establish AI Centers of Excellence, and promote inclusive growth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The world is looking to India’s leadership in AI, and our partners are helping the country move forward with AI.” - Puneet Chandok, Microsoft India</blockquote>
<p>Microsoft is committed to investing $3 billion in AI and cloud infrastructure in India, fostering innovation across various sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.microsoft.com/en-in/microsoft-inks-strategic-partnerships-to-make-indias-core-sectors-ai-first/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.microsoft.com/en-in/microsoft-inks-strategic-partnerships-to-make-indias-core-sectors-ai-first/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:20:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RIL, Kalyan Jewellers, MMTC, Spandana Sphoorty, Paytm, Dixon Technologies, KEC International: Check top buzzing stocks of the day - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Buzzing Stocks of the Day: RIL, Kalyan Jewellers, and More</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Upstox</p><p>Domestic shares were generally in negative territory in the afternoon deals, with significant movement among various stocks.</p><ul><li><strong>Kalyan Jewellers:</strong> Shares dropped 7.5% despite a 39% revenue growth in Q3.</li><li><strong>Reliance Industries (RIL):</strong> The stock rose nearly 2% with analysts predicting up to 36% upside.</li><li><strong>Dixon Technologies:</strong> Stock fell 7.8% but remains up 171% over the past year.</li><li><strong>Zomato:</strong> Shares declined 2.73% amid competition concerns.</li><li><strong>Ola Electric Mobility:</strong> Stock dropped over 5% after receiving a SEBI warning.</li><li><strong>Tata Technologies:</strong> Shares rose 3.4% after a new partnership announcement.</li><li><strong>Dr Reddy's:</strong> Stock climbed 3.99% following a subsidiary's sale announcement.</li><li><strong>ONGC:</strong> Shares up over 2% as crude oil prices rise.</li><li><strong>MMTC:</strong> Stock trading over 12% higher.</li><li><strong>Spandana Sphoorty:</strong> Stock rose over 14%, showcasing positive performance in microfinance.</li><li><strong>Paytm:</strong> Shares dropped 5.75% following the sale of a stake in PayPay Corporation.</li><li><strong>KEC International:</strong> Stock was down 6.81% post-initial gains from securing new orders.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/kalyan-jewellers-mmtc-spandana-sphoorty-paytm-dixon-technologies-kec-international-check-top-buzzing-stocks-of-the-day/article-139451/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/kalyan-jewellers-mmtc-spandana-sphoorty-paytm-dixon-technologies-kec-international-check-top-buzzing-stocks-of-the-day/article-139451/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:19:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 Announced: Check Expected Deals On Smartphones, Exchange Offers, And Bank Discounts - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 Announced: Check Expected Deals On Smartphones, Exchange Offers, And Bank Discounts</h1><p><strong>Date: January 13, 2025</strong> - <strong>Source: Zee News</strong></p><p>The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 is set to begin on January 13 at 12 PM, offering shoppers exciting discounts and exchange offers on a wide range of products.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>The sale kicks off with early access at midnight on January 13.</li><li>Exchange offers include up to Rs 45,000 off on smartphones and discounts on other electronics.</li><li>Bank offers include a 10% discount for SBI Credit Card users and 5% cashback for ICICI Amazon Pay Credit Card users.</li><li>Major smartphone brands like OnePlus, Motorola, and Samsung are expected to feature heavily in the sale.</li></ul><blockquote>"Consumers can avail of exchange discounts of up to Rs 45,000 on smartphones, Rs 7,000 on laptops, and Rs 15,000 on home appliances."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Amazon Great Republic Day Sale promises significant savings for consumers looking to upgrade their gadgets and enjoy various deals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/technology/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-2025-announced-check-expected-deals-on-smartphone-exchange-offers-and-bank-discounts-2840930.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/technology/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-2025-announced-check-expected-deals-on-smartphone-exchange-offers-and-bank-discounts-2840930.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:08:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sam Altman reacts to his sister’s allegations of financial, sexual abuse; “untrue”, says OpenAI CEO - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sam Altman reacts to his sister’s allegations of financial, sexual abuse; “untrue”, says OpenAI CEO</h1><p><strong>Published: January 08, 2025 12:37 pm IST</strong></p><p><strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ehtfxa/article69075350.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-09-26T202811Z_1785427284_RC2AK5APDFNE_RTRMADP_3_OPENAI-ALTMAN-PAY.JPG" alt="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI" title="Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI" /><figcaption>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, pictured above [File] | Photo Credit: REUTERS</figcaption><p>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman has denied allegations of sexual abuse made by his sister, labeling them as “untrue” and attributing her claims to mental health challenges.</p><ul><li>Altman responded to a lawsuit filed by his sister alleging sexual abuse that began when she was three years old.</li><li>He emphasized the emotional toll on their family due to these allegations.</li><li>Altman claimed that the family has financially and medically supported his sister, who has publicly accused them multiple times before.</li><li>Amidst these claims, he mentioned that she has made various accusations against family members regarding money and privacy issues.</li></ul><blockquote>“All of these claims are utterly untrue,” said Altman. “This situation causes immense pain to our entire family.”</blockquote><p>Altman reiterated that the accusations had evolved over time, intensifying with the recent lawsuit filed against him.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/openai-ceo-sam-altman-says-sisters-allegations-of-financial-sexual-abuse-are-utterly-untrue/article69075392.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/openai-ceo-sam-altman-says-sisters-allegations-of-financial-sexual-abuse-are-utterly-untrue/article69075392.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[L&T Heavy Engineering Wins (Significant*) Orders in India and Abroad - L&T]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxOS0g0RWpUbTNtMkp5ZzdCRFZSU3ZnMXBFcGQ5ZDhsM3NHbi02LXcyN1g0UGNfUFBiMFNJNVFBd3Zwc05ZYlRUOEIwZlJjM3p5SWM5NjdZeVZDLUEzVzhYTy1IZHJNMXRCWFprNnp1ZTFnYVdyZXRZRFZtUjJEOVppWWlNVXVMXzE5b01EckFwZ3dSekxsMzVrTmpUTmNZSXpVYThaNDJ0UjNuSzBXa05JcUExbVhoTkVFcmhN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxOS0g0RWpUbTNtMkp5ZzdCRFZSU3ZnMXBFcGQ5ZDhsM3NHbi02LXcyN1g0UGNfUFBiMFNJNVFBd3Zwc05ZYlRUOEIwZlJjM3p5SWM5NjdZeVZDLUEzVzhYTy1IZHJNMXRCWFprNnp1ZTFnYVdyZXRZRFZtUjJEOVppWWlNVXVMXzE5b01EckFwZ3dSekxsMzVrTmpUTmNZSXpVYThaNDJ0UjNuSzBXa05JcUExbVhoTkVFcmhN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:00:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Cement Stock Picks: These shares offer upside of up to 30%, as per CLSA - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Cement Stock Picks: These shares offer upside of up to 30%, as per CLSA</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Cement Stocks" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Cement Stocks Overview</figcaption><p>Brokerage firm CLSA has turned constructive on the cement sector as earnings visibility improves and opportunities arise for companies.</p><ul><li>CLSA forecasts a demand recovery in the cement sector.</li><li>Consolidation and capacity expansion are expected to continue.</li><li>Profitability is aided by low base and cost savings.</li><li>Significant upgrades and price target changes for leading cement stocks.</li></ul><blockquote>“CLSA has upgraded ACC and Dalmia Bharat to 'outperform'. Ambuja Cements holds a potential upside of 19%.”</blockquote><p>This renewed optimism in the cement sector suggests a positive outlook for investors, with potential upsides in multiple stocks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/top-cement-stock-picks-clsa-constructive-2025-themes-acc-ambuja-dalmia-bharat-ultratech-share-price-upside-19536420.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/top-cement-stock-picks-clsa-constructive-2025-themes-acc-ambuja-dalmia-bharat-ultratech-share-price-upside-19536420.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:21:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ola Electric Shares Dip 4% After SEBI Warning - Indiainfoline]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPNm5NMFlKSGNyNTAzNnNvcjJDdUI5dGFKX3BsZDhBdjNiQXo0c1BieUxaZTJFT29UdnJNMXZpNElkeVVPQ3pSU2tZTjVYS2loNHdxX3VvRGhDV1J0bnFMal9pQ1NPME9xSFE5UWZRVDBBekc1SFVVNFhSbi1OeVJCd0tYaWRxUUM1cjZiZVBnd1BOam8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPNm5NMFlKSGNyNTAzNnNvcjJDdUI5dGFKX3BsZDhBdjNiQXo0c1BieUxaZTJFT29UdnJNMXZpNElkeVVPQ3pSU2tZTjVYS2loNHdxX3VvRGhDV1J0bnFMal9pQ1NPME9xSFE5UWZRVDBBekc1SFVVNFhSbi1OeVJCd0tYaWRxUUM1cjZiZVBnd1BOam8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paytm shares plunge over 7% after NPCI data suggests no UPI share gain in December - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/paytm-share-price-npci-data-no-upi-share-gain-december-ubs-target-below-ipo-levels-19536393.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/paytm-share-price-npci-data-no-upi-share-gain-december-ubs-target-below-ipo-levels-19536393.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:56:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paytm shares plunge 5% after NPCI data suggests no UPI share gain in December - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/paytm-share-price-npci-data-no-upi-share-gain-december-ubs-target-below-ipo-levels-19536393.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/paytm-share-price-npci-data-no-upi-share-gain-december-ubs-target-below-ipo-levels-19536393.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:56:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explained — Why Spandana Sphoorty, CreditAccess Grameen shares surged up to 16% - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Explained — Why Spandana Sphoorty, CreditAccess Grameen shares surged up to 16%</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="Explained — Why Spandana Sphoorty, CreditAccess Grameen shares surged up to 16%" title="Explained — Why Spandana Sphoorty, CreditAccess Grameen shares surged up to 16%" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Image illustrating the surge in stock prices.</figcaption><p>Shares of Spandana Sphoorty and CreditAccess Grameen have surged significantly, with Spandana experiencing a gain of 35% in the last two trading sessions and CreditAccess snapping a three-day losing streak.</p><ul><li>Spandana Sphoorty shares have gained up to 35% recently.</li><li>CreditAccess Grameen shares have increased by 11% to 15% as of January 8.</li><li>The Department of Financial Services is hosting consultative meetings for the industry between January 7 to January 16.</li><li>Key players discuss easing repayment schedules and enhancing borrowing rates.</li><li>Analyst Sushil Kedia predicts Spandana's stock could reach ₹1,800.</li><li>Current trading prices: Spandana at ₹453.7 and CreditAccess at ₹995.7.</li></ul><blockquote>Sushil Kedia stated, "The stock may surge to levels of ₹1,800, which is a return of nearly 6x from Monday's closing levels."</blockquote><p>The recent surge in share prices reflects investor optimism amid upcoming discussions on industry challenges and potential regulatory support.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/spandana-sphoorty-creditaccess-grameen-share-price-dfs-meeting-mfi-players-fintech-concerns-leverage-agenda-outlook-19536368.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/spandana-sphoorty-creditaccess-grameen-share-price-dfs-meeting-mfi-players-fintech-concerns-leverage-agenda-outlook-19536368.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:43:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Flying car' at CES 2025 leaves Indians in splits: ‘Will bounce like a rabbit on our roads’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/flying-car-at-ces-2025-leaves-indians-in-splits-it-ll-bounce-like-a-rabbit-on-our-roads-101736311935678.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/flying-car-at-ces-2025-leaves-indians-in-splits-it-ll-bounce-like-a-rabbit-on-our-roads-101736311935678.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:36:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kalyan Jewellers shares slide 6% amid profit booking a day after Q3 update - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AFBVV95cUxQem1oMm9iODltOU80bDd0MFpzUlFSM0xwc1V0WVZrMXVFSVN2dGtJR19ra2VtRGNsLTI3bFd2cjRXTFUyZ0drTW9jYzdzSEU5SUZQc2d1dk92NTUxeU5LdnVDanlRRmlLZFdkUnM4MmozbmZiY3hKMmFpRWRVTnI2QURGMzZ1R0RtVFBSQ0hKYUN4VllFcFp0cGhZYnVwS3pjOEF3cmFFcTB6UjQzUHBNdXVMT20xQkdESDJVTjFWaDNkbFRYdnZxVlZtSl9sQVIyY0J2bzFzeXNLQ0todVJwONIB5gFBVV95cUxPMUlDcXBSaUdmeVUxYXZMZ05uUzhCQXBacnVQRmx1UnlBWFJMTjZRS2xYMUwwVnVwdE9ZRGFOY1VUVVFsaUFHZFpMMlVUbk5xVFlOeXA2emFJTkMxYmFZQnF3ZmlBbE1tX3F1VlIyWGRfSFJEX19ZeGVpUnpKdFI4VVdYYnQ0a1YyRHRxSW1Ta004U1ZIVG9uNk5WTDNteUt5Q2hrME1uSmVHSWVMa0F0YlpjSmpjTFl3bFhibk9Ld0JmWTNmMlZiVWlKLVVjbkVJUnRGMGQ3eU0tcmh2VXdycW5nWklQZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AFBVV95cUxQem1oMm9iODltOU80bDd0MFpzUlFSM0xwc1V0WVZrMXVFSVN2dGtJR19ra2VtRGNsLTI3bFd2cjRXTFUyZ0drTW9jYzdzSEU5SUZQc2d1dk92NTUxeU5LdnVDanlRRmlLZFdkUnM4MmozbmZiY3hKMmFpRWRVTnI2QURGMzZ1R0RtVFBSQ0hKYUN4VllFcFp0cGhZYnVwS3pjOEF3cmFFcTB6UjQzUHBNdXVMT20xQkdESDJVTjFWaDNkbFRYdnZxVlZtSl9sQVIyY0J2bzFzeXNLQ0todVJwONIB5gFBVV95cUxPMUlDcXBSaUdmeVUxYXZMZ05uUzhCQXBacnVQRmx1UnlBWFJMTjZRS2xYMUwwVnVwdE9ZRGFOY1VUVVFsaUFHZFpMMlVUbk5xVFlOeXA2emFJTkMxYmFZQnF3ZmlBbE1tX3F1VlIyWGRfSFJEX19ZeGVpUnpKdFI4VVdYYnQ0a1YyRHRxSW1Ta004U1ZIVG9uNk5WTDNteUt5Q2hrME1uSmVHSWVMa0F0YlpjSmpjTFl3bFhibk9Ld0JmWTNmMlZiVWlKLVVjbkVJUnRGMGQ3eU0tcmh2VXdycW5nWklQZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:12:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zomato enters 15 minutes delivery battle, app shows new tab for customers | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zomato Launches 15-Minute Delivery Option in App</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><figure><img src="https://www.example.com/image.jpg" alt="Zomato 15 minute delivery tab can be seen in the Explore section"><figcaption>Zomato 15 minute delivery tab can be seen in the Explore section</figcaption></figure><p>Zomato has introduced a new '15 minutes delivery' option in its app, allowing customers to see food options that can be delivered quickly from restaurants within a 1.5 km radius of their location, further intensifying the competition in quick delivery services.</p><ul><li>Zomato's app now features a '15 mins delivery' tab in the Explore section.</li><li>The delivery option is currently limited to restaurants within a 1.5 km distance.</li><li>This move follows Swiggy's launch of a 10-minute delivery service called 'Bolt'.</li><li>Zomato's previous attempt at a quick delivery service, Zomato Instant, came amid customer backlash in 2022.</li></ul><blockquote>“Will be for specific nearby locations, popular and standardised items only.” - Deepinder Goyal, CEO of Zomato</blockquote><p>The launch of Zomato's 15-minute delivery service indicates a competitive thrust into the quick delivery segment, possibly leading to a revised approach to their earlier quick-service initiatives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/zomato-enters-15-minutes-food-delivery-battle-app-shows-new-tab-for-customers-india-news-company-swiggy-bolt-zepto-cafe-11736311979109.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/zomato-enters-15-minutes-food-delivery-battle-app-shows-new-tab-for-customers-india-news-company-swiggy-bolt-zepto-cafe-11736311979109.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:01:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here is why Reliance Industries share price has a potential upside of 36% - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Here is why Reliance Industries share price has a potential upside of 36%</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBCTV18</p><p>Brokerage firm Jefferies has reviewed Reliance Industries Ltd’s share price and indicates a potential upside of 36%, reiterating its 'buy' recommendation.</p><ul><li>Jefferies sets a price target of ₹1,690, indicating a 36% upside from Tuesday's closing price.</li><li>Reliance Industries recently underperformed the Nifty 50 index by 15% in 2024.</li><li>Concerns over growth prospects in the retail sector and lower earnings growth impacted share performance.</li><li>Growth restoration in the retail business and profit improvements in the Oil-To-Chemicals sector are expected by FY2026.</li><li>Reliance's current valuations are the cheapest since March 2020.</li><li>Bernstein also projects a recovery cycle in 2025, targeting ₹1,520 per share for Reliance Industries.</li><li>Out of 39 analysts, 33 recommend 'buy', with the highest target being ₹1,950.</li></ul><blockquote>“Risk-reward for the stock is attractive as valuations are at a three-year low.” - Bernstein</blockquote><p>The overall market sentiment indicates optimism for Reliance Industries as it trades at ₹1,263, showing a modest gain.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/reliance-industries-share-price-valuations-risk-reward-favourable-jefferies-buy-target-upside-nifty-50-19536321.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/reliance-industries-share-price-valuations-risk-reward-favourable-jefferies-buy-target-upside-nifty-50-19536321.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:39:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RBI Guv Malhotra faces calls to unshackle rupee amid surging dollar - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Calls for RBI Governor Malhotra to Allow Rupee Flexibility Amid Dollar Surge</h1><p><strong>Date: Unknown | Source: Unknown</strong></p><div><img alt='Chart' src='data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7'><figcaption>Chart demonstrating currency fluctuations.</figcaption></div><p>The new Governor of the Reserve Bank of India, Sanjay Malhotra, faces pressure to change the current exchange rate policy favored by his predecessor amidst a strong dollar and increasing rupee volatility.</p><ul><li>Former RBI Governor Shaktikanta Das focused on stabilizing the rupee to attract foreign investments.</li><li>Critics argue that the fixed approach has weakened India’s export competitiveness.</li><li>Malhotra has not yet communicated his policy intentions, but signs suggest a shift towards allowing the rupee to fluctuate more.</li><li>Key economic advisors advocate for a more flexible exchange rate to improve competitiveness.</li><li>The rupee's real effective exchange rate indicates an overvaluation, requiring a depreciation of 2-3% to align with fundamentals.</li></ul><blockquote>“India’s external account has shifted from comfort to caution.” - Namrata Mittal, Chief Economist at SBI Mutual Fund</blockquote><p>This article emphasizes the evolving challenges for the RBI in managing the rupee's value amidst global economic pressures, highlighting the need for potential policy changes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/finance/news/rbi-guv-malhotra-faces-calls-to-unshackle-rupee-amid-surging-dollar-125010800221_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/finance/news/rbi-guv-malhotra-faces-calls-to-unshackle-rupee-amid-surging-dollar-125010800221_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:24:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's Modi looks to new economic playbook as risks mount - Reuters India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/india/indias-modi-looks-new-economic-playbook-risks-mount-2025-01-08/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/india/indias-modi-looks-new-economic-playbook-risks-mount-2025-01-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SEBI ‘warning’ letter on social media to Ola CEO Bhavish Aggarwal: You have failed to … - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SEBI Cautions Ola CEO Bhavish Aggarwal Over Social Media Conduct</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 23, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>In a recent communication, the Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) has issued a warning letter to Ola's CEO, Bhavish Aggarwal, citing concerns over his activities on social media which may be in violation of securities laws.</p><ul><li>The warning highlights specific posts made by Aggarwal that could mislead investors.</li><li>SEBI emphasizes the importance of transparency and ethical conduct in financial communications.</li><li>This comes amid increased scrutiny of leaders in the tech industry regarding their public statements.</li></ul><blockquote>"We expect all market participants to adhere strictly to disclosure norms and avoid any statements that could mislead stakeholders," stated a SEBI official.</blockquote><p>This warning serves as a reminder of the regulatory obligations that CEOs have towards their public communications, especially in volatile markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/sebi-warning-letter-on-social-media-to-ola-ceo-bhavish-aggarwal-you-have-failed-to-/articleshow/117040668.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/sebi-warning-letter-on-social-media-to-ola-ceo-bhavish-aggarwal-you-have-failed-to-/articleshow/117040668.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold Rate Falls In India: Check 22 Carat Price In Your City On January 08 - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Rate Today In India: Check 22 Carat Price In Your City On January 08</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 08, 2025, 14:55 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Gold and silver prices in India on January 06, 2025." title="Gold and silver prices in India on January 06, 2025."><figcaption>Gold and silver prices in India on January 06, 2025.</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Gold Rate Today In India:</strong> On January 08, 2025, gold prices in India held steady, reflecting current market trends. The 24-carat gold continued to attract buyers for its unmatched purity. In contrast, 22-carat gold remained the preferred choice for jewellery enthusiasts due to its durability and timeless elegance, making it an ideal option for long-term investments.</p><p>The price of 24-carat gold was Rs 78,700 for 10 grams, while 22-carat gold was Rs 72,140 for 10 grams. Silver was trading at Rs 91,400 per kilogram.</p><h2><strong>Today’s Gold Prices:</strong> Retail Rates on January 08 Across Major Cities in India (Rs per 10 grams):</h2><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>City</strong></td><td><strong>22 Carat Gold Rate Today</strong></td><td><strong>24 Carat Gold Rate Today</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Delhi</td><td>72,290</td><td>78,850</td></tr><tr><td>Mumbai</td><td>72,140</td><td>78,700</td></tr><tr><td>Ahmedabad</td><td>72,190</td><td>78,750</td></tr><tr><td>Chennai</td><td>72,140</td><td>78,700</td></tr><tr><td>Kolkata</td><td>72,140</td><td>78,700</td></tr><tr><td>Pune</td><td>72,140</td><td>78,700</td></tr><tr><td>Lucknow</td><td>72,290</td><td>78,850</td></tr><tr><td>Bengaluru</td><td>72,140</td><td>78,700</td></tr><tr><td>Jaipur</td><td>72,290</td><td>78,850</td></tr><tr><td>Patna</td><td>72,190</td><td>78,750</td></tr><tr><td>Bhubaneshwar</td><td>72,140</td><td>78,700</td></tr><tr><td>Hyderabad</td><td>72,140</td><td>78,700</td></tr></tbody></table><p><strong>Retail Gold Prices in India</strong></p><p>Gold holds immense cultural and financial significance in India. It remains a favoured investment and is pivotal in celebrations, especially during weddings and festivals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/savings-and-investments/gold-rate-today-mumbai-24-carat-10-gram-22k-47-9181489.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/savings-and-investments/gold-rate-today-mumbai-24-carat-10-gram-22k-47-9181489.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:50:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Sell Premier Energies, Waaree' shares advises this analyst, with a downside of up to 41% - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sell Premier Energies, Waaree' shares advises this analyst, with a downside of up to 41%</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 8, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="'Sell Premier Energies, Waaree' shares advises this analyst, with a downside of up to 41%" title="'Sell Premier Energies, Waaree' shares advises this analyst, with a downside of up to 41%" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Image depicting stock analysis advisory</figcaption><p>Kotak Institutional Equities has issued a 'sell' recommendation for the stocks of Premier Energies and Waaree Energies, forecasting significant potential downsides for both.</p><ul><li>Kotak has set a price target of ₹770 for Premier Energies, suggesting a potential downside of 41% from current levels.</li><li>For Waaree Energies, the price target is ₹2,550, indicating an 8% downside.</li><li>Despite the downside projections, Premier Energies is expected to achieve a 44% CAGR from 2024 to 2030.</li><li>The solar sector in India is anticipated to grow at an 18% CAGR until 2030.</li><li>This is the first 'sell' rating for Premier Energies, coinciding with a 'hold' from JPMorgan.</li></ul><blockquote>“India's solar sector is primed for growth with a 18% CAGR in utility scale solar capacity additions until financial year 2030.”</blockquote><p>The advisory indicates caution for investors in the renewable energy sectors defined by high valuations, with a potential for losses despite promising growth forecasts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/premier-energies-waaree-share-price-kotak-instl-equities-sell-target-downside-renewable-ipo-returns-19536281.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/premier-energies-waaree-share-price-kotak-instl-equities-sell-target-downside-renewable-ipo-returns-19536281.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:43:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These Auto Stocks Are Jefferies Top Picks In 2025 Sector Outlook - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>These Auto Stocks Are Jefferies' Top Picks In 2025 Sector Outlook</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>08 Jan 2025, <strong>Source: </strong>NDTV Profit</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2024-10-31%2F7endowdh%2FAuto-sectorEnvato.jpg?w=1200" alt="Jefferies has identified Mahindra and Mahindra Ltd., Eicher Motors Ltd., and TVS Motor Co. as its top picks for 2025. (Photo source: Envato)">
<figcaption>Jefferies has identified Mahindra and Mahindra Ltd., Eicher Motors Ltd., and TVS Motor Co. as its top picks for 2025. (Photo source: Envato)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The outlook for India's auto industry reveals growth divergence among key sectors, with two-wheelers and tractors expected to lead growth compared to passenger vehicles and trucks.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jefferies forecasts a 13-15% compound annual growth rate (CAGR) for two-wheelers and tractors for FY25-27.</li>
  <li>Passenger vehicles and trucks are projected at a CAGR of 5-8% during the same period.</li>
  <li>Top picks include Mahindra and Mahindra, Eicher Motors, and TVS Motor, expected to outperform the market.</li>
  <li>Mahindra's passenger vehicle market share is forecasted to increase, positioning it as a strong Hyundai competitor by FY27.</li>
  <li>TVS Motor has seen its domestic two-wheeler market share rise to 17%.</li>
  <li>Eicher Motors is projected to benefit from demand for premium motorcycles with a 16% earnings growth forecast.</li>
  <li>Electric vehicle (EV) adoption is slow, with expectations of gradual growth in the two-wheeler segment's EV share.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Jefferies remains positive on the Indian auto sector, with a focus on two-wheelers and tractors over passenger vehicles and trucks.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the brokerage highlights opportunities in the two-wheeler and tractor markets while cautiously evaluating traditional segments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/mahindra-tvs-eicher-are-jefferies-top-pick-in-auto-sector-in-2025-outlook</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/mahindra-tvs-eicher-are-jefferies-top-pick-in-auto-sector-in-2025-outlook</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:41:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These Auto Stocks Are Jefferies' Top Picks In 2025 Sector Outlook - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxPLVZiZ1loLVNMNnBiQjBhcUdweU5zbXdfM1VsS1hGSDVyaGhacFJVT0tkWXpWZF9OdWhUY0hjRGNWYVNuU1dqNG5JY2RBYjk0ZjB0aWZMaWlYZFlfMWI2SkpQZ0tYaUI4YVpRVU9PbVFKQVdKWmNLZDJPYXF3VnROaDF2YllBOTRRclAtWUdydnp3QkFsdkFJbFZNUlhhbDhZT0d3b2ZSNHQ2WUln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxPLVZiZ1loLVNMNnBiQjBhcUdweU5zbXdfM1VsS1hGSDVyaGhacFJVT0tkWXpWZF9OdWhUY0hjRGNWYVNuU1dqNG5JY2RBYjk0ZjB0aWZMaWlYZFlfMWI2SkpQZ0tYaUI4YVpRVU9PbVFKQVdKWmNLZDJPYXF3VnROaDF2YllBOTRRclAtWUdydnp3QkFsdkFJbFZNUlhhbDhZT0d3b2ZSNHQ2WUln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:41:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[KEC International share price climbs nearly 4% on winning new orders worth ₹1,136 crore - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxQbVRhdjg5ZDd3clpqSjNqUl81RjhJMDhwQXJENE5kNzNoOWc4NkNEbEVKUS1RenZYSDRRMkZRVS1sUDFSTVhGRzg3N2FnUkd2ZFZpM3RCVHNoT2tNMHlaQklhZVZZWHgzZW5oaWVLQ002TGJvTHRaV3pXa3pTa3FybzFsLWdlYk1mVmpjY3ByN1BFVnM4R1cwQnZpckt2NC1QZGRKTTNVWWpnTEFDd0tXUDVHajI5bnJJb3RxMnhzZ3J4Z1doS3EzbEhONEdJT0UwaUMw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxQbVRhdjg5ZDd3clpqSjNqUl81RjhJMDhwQXJENE5kNzNoOWc4NkNEbEVKUS1RenZYSDRRMkZRVS1sUDFSTVhGRzg3N2FnUkd2ZFZpM3RCVHNoT2tNMHlaQklhZVZZWHgzZW5oaWVLQ002TGJvTHRaV3pXa3pTa3FybzFsLWdlYk1mVmpjY3ByN1BFVnM4R1cwQnZpckt2NC1QZGRKTTNVWWpnTEFDd0tXUDVHajI5bnJJb3RxMnhzZ3J4Z1doS3EzbEhONEdJT0UwaUMw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:23:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ola Electric shares in focus after SEBI warns of disclosure norm violations - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ola Electric Shares Drop 4% After Sebi Warning Over Disclosure Violations</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><figure><img height="158" width="210" alt="Ola Electric shares in focus after SEBI warns of disclosure norm violations" src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-117039309,width-210,height-158,imgsize-29044,resizemode-75/ola-electric-shares-in-focus-after-sebi-warns-of-disclosure-norm-violations.jpg"><figcaption>Ola Electric Mobility received an administrative warning from SEBI for breaching disclosure norms.</figcaption></figure><p>Ola Electric Mobility shares fell 3.8% after SEBI issued a warning for violating disclosure norms regarding the early announcement of a planned store network expansion. The Karnataka High Court also granted Ola an extension to respond to the CCPA.</p><ul><li>Ola Electric shares dropped to Rs 76.12 on January 8, following an administrative warning from SEBI.</li><li>SEBI cited violations related to early announcements made by the company’s Chairman.</li><li>Ola Electric clarified that there are no financial implications from this warning.</li><li>The Karnataka High Court granted a six-week extension for Ola to respond to the CCPA's notice.</li><li>The average target price for Ola Electric shares is Rs 97, suggesting a potential upside of 22%.</li></ul><blockquote>"You are hereby warned and advised to be careful in the future and to improve your compliance standards." - SEBI</blockquote><p>The incident highlights the importance of compliance with disclosure norms in the industry, and it remains to be seen how Ola Electric will navigate these challenges moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/ola-electric-shares-in-focus-after-sebi-warns-of-disclosure-norm-violations/articleshow/117039343.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/ola-electric-shares-in-focus-after-sebi-warns-of-disclosure-norm-violations/articleshow/117039343.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:13:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tata Steel reports 6% YoY rise in crude steel production during Q3 FY25; check details, and how shares are performing - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tata Steel Reports 6% Yearly Growth in Crude Steel Production in Q3 FY25</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><p>Tata Steel has announced a year-on-year rise of 6% in crude steel production, reaching 5.68 million tonnes in Q3 FY25.</p><ol><li>Crude steel production increased from 5.35 million tonnes in Q3 FY24.</li><li>Quarter-on-quarter, production saw an 8% increase.</li><li>Steel deliveries in India rose by 8.4% year-on-year to 5.29 million tonnes.</li><li>Tata Steel Netherlands reported liquid steel production of 1.76 million tonnes.</li><li>UK operations saw a significant drop with output at zero due to blast furnace closures.</li><li>CEO TV Narendran discussed challenges including China's pricing and global recovery issues.</li></ol><blockquote>“Despite challenges, Tata Steel is well-positioned and profitable in India due to growing demand.” - TV Narendran</blockquote><p>The rise in production and deliveries indicates Tata Steel's robust position in the market despite global challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/tata-steel-shares-in-focus-as-company-reports-6-yo-y-rise-in-crude-steel-production-during-q3-fy-25-check-details/article-139361/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/tata-steel-shares-in-focus-as-company-reports-6-yo-y-rise-in-crude-steel-production-during-q3-fy-25-check-details/article-139361/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:06:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>