<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 20:19:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 20:19:22 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-Infosys CFO Mohandas Pai Slams IndiGo Over Bengaluru Incident: ‘Left Without Air Conditioning’ - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ex-Infosys CFO Mohandas Pai Slams IndiGo Over Bengaluru Incident: ‘Left Without Air Conditioning’</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Former Infosys CFO Mohandas Pai was travelling from Bengaluru to Coimbatore when the incident happened."/>
<figcaption>Former Infosys CFO Mohandas Pai was travelling from Bengaluru to Coimbatore when the incident happened.</figcaption>
<p>Former Infosys CFO Mohandas Pai expressed his discontent with IndiGo's service after being left waiting on the tarmac in Bengaluru without air conditioning.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Passengers were left on the hot tarmac in Bengaluru, with the air conditioning reportedly non-operational.</li>
  <li>Pai shared his experience on social media, prompting others to share similar complaints.</li>
  <li>After a passenger protest, IndiGo staff used a generator to power the air conditioning.</li>
  <li>Pai called on IndiGo to change their protocols to prevent future incidents.</li>
  <li>IndiGo responded to his post, assuring that customer comfort is a priority and that they value feedback.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Indigo treats its passengers badly. Sitting in 6E 7407 without AC on hot tarmac in Bengaluru. No way to treat passengers. Only after protest staff using tarmac generator for AC...” — Mohandas Pai</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights ongoing issues with passenger treatment in airlines and brings attention to the need for better customer service practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/ex-infosys-cfo-mohandas-pai-slams-indigo-over-bengaluru-incident-left-without-air-conditioning-9172544.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/ex-infosys-cfo-mohandas-pai-slams-indigo-over-bengaluru-incident-left-without-air-conditioning-9172544.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 18:43:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wall St slides to 1-week low on thin trading, elevated yields - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/wall-st-futures-slip-elevated-treasury-yields-2024-12-30/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/wall-st-futures-slip-elevated-treasury-yields-2024-12-30/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:28:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SBI Life picks up 10% stake in Bima Sugam India Federation | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SBI Life Acquires 10% Stake in Bima Sugam India Federation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>SBI Life has announced its decision to acquire a 10% stake in Bima Sugam India Federation for ₹6.6 crore, aiming to enhance the insurance product marketplace.</p><ul><li>SBI Life's board approved an investment not exceeding 10% of Bima Sugam's paid-up equity share capital.</li><li>Bima Sugam India Federation is set to create a centralized marketplace for insurance products and services.</li><li>The company will invest ₹6.6 crore to purchase 66 lakh equity shares at a face value of ₹10 each.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/sbi-life-picks-up-10-stake-in-bima-sugam-india-federation-11735578939988.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/sbi-life-picks-up-10-stake-in-bima-sugam-india-federation-11735578939988.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:24:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JSW Energy Jumps 8% Amid O2 Power Acquisition; Motilal Oswal Shares Target Price - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JSW Energy Shares Rise 8% Following O2 Power Acquisition Announcement</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='JSW Energy Share Price' title='JSW Energy Share Price'><figcaption>JSW Energy Share Price</figcaption><p>JSW Energy's stock surged by 8% after the announcement of its acquisition of O2 Power, a renewable energy platform, reflecting strong investor confidence.</p><ul><li>JSW Energy’s subsidiary, JSW Neo Energy, will acquire O2 Power, valued at Rs 12,468 crore ($1.47 billion).</li><li>The deal includes acquiring O2 Power Midco Holdings and O2 Energy SG, pending regulatory approval.</li><li>Post-announcement, shares of JSW Energy reached Rs 673.05, marking a 7.67% increase.</li><li>Motilal Oswal has set a target price of Rs 810 per share for JSW Energy.</li><li>The stock has seen a 67% increase from its 52-week low, although it's down 17% from its high.</li></ul><blockquote>“Motilal Oswal Financial Services has a favorable outlook on JSW Energy, indicating strong operational performance.”</blockquote><p>The increase in JSW Energy's shares indicates positive market sentiment regarding its expansion into renewable energy, showcasing the potential for future growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/markets/jsw-energy-jumps-8-amid-o2-power-acquisition-motilal-oswal-shares-target-price-9172342.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/markets/jsw-energy-jumps-8-amid-o2-power-acquisition-motilal-oswal-shares-target-price-9172342.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:22:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Rupee 58.58 against Dollar in 2014, it's 85.27 now': Congress recalls PM Modi's 2013 remarks on deprecia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Rupee 58.58 against Dollar in 2014, it's 85.27 now': Congress recalls PM Modi's 2013 remarks on depreciating currency during UPA government</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Congress has referenced past remarks made by Prime Minister Modi regarding the depreciation of the Indian Rupee, contrasting them with the current exchange rate of 85.27 against the dollar.</p><ul><li>The Rupee was valued at 58.58 against the dollar in 2014.</li><li>Current statistics show a significant depreciation with the Rupee now at 85.27.</li><li>Congress has criticized the government's handling of the economy.</li></ul><blockquote>“In 2013, Modi warned against the falling currency, but now his government is facing the same issue.”</blockquote><p>The ongoing depreciation of the Rupee raises concerns regarding the economic policies of the current administration and its implications for ordinary citizens.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/rupee-58-58-against-dollar-in-2014-its-85-27-now-congress-recalls-pm-modis-2013-remarks-on-depreciating-currency-during-upa-government/articleshow/116805578.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/rupee-58-58-against-dollar-in-2014-its-85-27-now-congress-recalls-pm-modis-2013-remarks-on-depreciating-currency-during-upa-government/articleshow/116805578.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks decline as yields remain elevated - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks Decline as Yields Remain Elevated</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 30, 2024, Reuters</p><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resource/latest/2024-12-30T185327Z_154496335_RC26V89E02B0_RTRMADP_3_NYSE-STOCKS-U.S-STOCKS.jpg" alt="Traders work on the floor at the New York Stock Exchange" width="600"><figcaption>Traders work on the floor at the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City, U.S., December 10, 2024.</figcaption><p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Global stocks fell for a third straight session on Monday, with Wall Street tumbling, as recent elevated U.S. Treasury yields prompted profit taking at the end of a strong year for equities.</p><ol><li>U.S., European stocks fall</li><li>Dollar up broadly but weaker vs yen</li><li>10-year U.S. Treasury yield falls but holds above 4.5%</li></ol><blockquote>The benchmark 10-year U.S. Treasury yield's recent push above the 4.5% mark... will be a strong headwind for equity prices.</blockquote><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> Stock markets in several countries were closed or had abbreviated trading sessions ahead of the New Year holiday.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-wrapup-1-2024-12-30/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-wrapup-1-2024-12-30/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:58:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Boss Called Me A**hole’: Intern, 21, Opens Up About Toxic Workplace In India - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Intern Reveals Toxic Work Environment After Being Insulted by Boss in India</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="An Indian boss recently abused a 21-year-old intern over a 'minor error' in a draft." />
<figcaption>An Indian boss recently abused a 21-year-old intern over a 'minor error' in a draft. (Representative image)</figcaption>
<p>A 21-year-old intern shared his distressing experience of workplace bullying on Reddit, revealing how his boss verbally assaulted him over a minor mistake in his work.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The intern was called an “a**hole” by his boss over a simple error in a draft.</li>
  <li>He expressed his concerns on Reddit, seeking advice on whether to report the issue.</li>
  <li>This incident highlights the toxic work culture present in some corporate environments in India.</li>
  <li>The intern worried about possible repercussions of escalating the issue.</li>
  <li>Reddit users encouraged him to address the situation and not remain silent.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“To say I was shocked would be an understatement. I’m genuinely frustrated and this isn’t the first time.”</blockquote>
<p>This unfortunate incident raises awareness about bullying and the need for healthier workplace environments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/boss-called-me-ahole-over-minor-error-intern-21-opens-up-about-toxic-workplace-9172278.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/boss-called-me-ahole-over-minor-error-intern-21-opens-up-about-toxic-workplace-9172278.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:55:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold prices dip as markets await fresh catalysts - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Prices Dip as Markets Await Fresh Catalysts</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 30</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/TEHTFKMZTNIAVLBCWRWL2ZL4UY.jpg?auth=5c303d585dc134137743f3fa0863f6af2b3a700ab9dd0485734a98a8c51326bd&amp;width=5500&amp;quality=80" alt="Production at Krastsvetmet precious metals plant in Krasnoyarsk"/><figcaption>A view shows granules of 99.99 percent pure gold in a workroom during production at Krastsvetmet precious metals plant in the Siberian city of Krasnoyarsk, Russia, May 23, 2024.</figcaption><p>Gold prices dipped as traders awaited fresh catalysts, including upcoming U.S. economic data that could influence the Federal Reserve's interest-rate outlook and policies from incoming President Trump.</p><ul><li>Gold has gained nearly 27% this year.</li><li>U.S. jobs data and December Fed meeting minutes are expected next week.</li><li>Platinum hit over a three-month low on Friday.</li></ul><blockquote>“I think it's just the holiday thin trade. Perhaps some squaring of the books before year-end,” said Peter Grant, vice president and senior metals strategist at Zaner Metals.</blockquote><p>Geopolitical tensions are expected to remain high, with central banks continuing to buy gold, as the U.S. debt situation worsens, fueling ongoing safe-haven demand.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/gold-edges-up-focus-shifts-incoming-trump-administration-2024-12-30/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/gold-edges-up-focus-shifts-incoming-trump-administration-2024-12-30/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:39:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold prices dip as markets await fresh catalysts - Reuters.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/gold-edges-up-focus-shifts-incoming-trump-administration-2024-12-30/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/gold-edges-up-focus-shifts-incoming-trump-administration-2024-12-30/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:39:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Private Banks Grapple With 25% Attrition Rate, Operational Risks Loom: RBI - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Private Banks Face 25% Employee Attrition Amid Operational Risks, Says RBI</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='Employee attrition rates are high across select private sector banks and small finance banks ' /><figcaption>Employee attrition rates are high across select private sector banks and small finance banks.</figcaption><p>The Reserve Bank of India's latest report highlights a troubling rise in employee attrition rates within private sector banks, which have reached approximately 25%. This poses serious operational risks for these financial institutions.</p><ul><li>Employee attrition in private banks has increased to about 25%.</li><li>This trend brings significant operational risks related to customer service and loss of institutional knowledge.</li><li>The report indicates that the total count of employees in private banks has eclipsed that of public sector banks.</li><li>Strategies recommended to reduce turnover include better onboarding, career development, and supportive workplace cultures.</li><li>The RBI urged banks to review their gold loan policies due to observed irregularities.</li><li>Climate change risks are projected to negatively influence the financial stability of institutions.</li></ul><blockquote>“High attrition and employee turnover rate pose significant operational risks, including disruption in customer services, besides leading to loss of institutional knowledge and increased recruitment costs.” - RBI Report</blockquote><p>This rising attrition rate signifies a critical challenge for private banks that requires immediate and effective strategic responses to safeguard operational efficiency and ensure long-term stability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/banking-finance/private-banks-grapple-with-25-attrition-rate-operational-risks-loom-rbi-9172426.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/banking-finance/private-banks-grapple-with-25-attrition-rate-operational-risks-loom-rbi-9172426.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:31:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wall St hits 1-week low in thin trading, elevated yields add pressure - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/wall-st-futures-slip-elevated-treasury-yields-2024-12-30/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/wall-st-futures-slip-elevated-treasury-yields-2024-12-30/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:23:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unimech Aerospace IPO GMP today signals at gains ahead of listing date? - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unimech Aerospace IPO GMP Today Signals Gains Ahead of Listing Date</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW DIGITAL</p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Unimech Aerospace IPO GMP" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Unimech Aerospace IPO GMP</figcaption><p>Unimech Aerospace's IPO is generating significant investor interest as reflected in impressive subscription numbers during the bidding period.</p><ul><li>Unimech Aerospace and Manufacturing Ltd's IPO was subscribed 174.93 times on the final day of bidding.</li><li>Bidding for the IPO took place from December 23 to December 26, 2024.</li><li>Qualified Institutional Buyers (QIBs) had a subscription rate of 317.63 times.</li><li>Non-institutional investors subscribed 263.40 times.</li><li>The IPO's last GMP is Rs 675, with an expected gain per share of 85.99%.</li><li>The expected listing price is around Rs 1460, based on the cap price and current GMP.</li></ul><blockquote>"Unimech Aerospace is a high-precision engineering solutions company specializing in complex manufacturing solutions for the aerospace, defence, energy, and semiconductor industries."</blockquote><p>This IPO reflects a high level of market interest and could indicate a positive listing experience based on its current GMP.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/unimech-aerospace-ipo-gmp-today-signals-at-gains-ahead-of-listing-date-article-116804496</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/unimech-aerospace-ipo-gmp-today-signals-at-gains-ahead-of-listing-date-article-116804496</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:07:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Market Trading Guide: Lupin, Apollo Micro Systems are stock recommendations for Tuesday - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxQMTM0dGxnaWRrajZGMUtTTk9mYkhFVVdBeFZiY0wyaWd6emVKSDN2M2VzT3l5eld4LTRfRkFLbEhyRDlxTVIyMlE2aERDR0VsVDYyTnFDczAyc1hHYl8zQTA1UHBocERtSDl4YmNROE5SaTdCY1lBQkoyeno3QVNkRmlPbTJEX29sUk85MUViTGpZUU5sWllPNW4wcl9OWUpmZmhVeDhWNjlYSnR6X2ZQeVdYWTBpMHYyTVFEVF8zTkVvS3YxNFJhTGdVcl9OWG5fU3RNVE5uOUxaa2hseHZCcktFMHpGZE9nSGN2cjFmbjJRRlduaXZnbGRHVEEzdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxQMTM0dGxnaWRrajZGMUtTTk9mYkhFVVdBeFZiY0wyaWd6emVKSDN2M2VzT3l5eld4LTRfRkFLbEhyRDlxTVIyMlE2aERDR0VsVDYyTnFDczAyc1hHYl8zQTA1UHBocERtSDl4YmNROE5SaTdCY1lBQkoyeno3QVNkRmlPbTJEX29sUk85MUViTGpZUU5sWllPNW4wcl9OWUpmZmhVeDhWNjlYSnR6X2ZQeVdYWTBpMHYyTVFEVF8zTkVvS3YxNFJhTGdVcl9OWG5fU3RNVE5uOUxaa2hseHZCcktFMHpGZE9nSGN2cjFmbjJRRlduaXZnbGRHVEEzdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Types Of Bank Accounts To Be Closed From January 1: Is Yours One Of Them? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>3 Types Of Bank Accounts To Be Closed From January 1: Is Yours One Of Them?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Accounts that maintain a zero balance for an extended period will also be subject to closure." /><figcaption>Accounts that maintain a zero balance for an extended period will also be subject to closure.</figcaption><p>Starting January 1, 2025, the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) will implement rule changes affecting numerous bank accounts across the country. It is crucial for customers to understand these changes and how they may impact their accounts.</p><ul><li>Dormant accounts (inactive for over two years) will be closed.</li><li>Inactive accounts (no transaction for 12 months or more) will also face closure.</li><li>Zero balance accounts maintained for an extended period risk being closed.</li></ul><blockquote>“To safeguard customers and the banking system, the RBI has decided to close such accounts.”</blockquote><p>Customers must take immediate action to reactivate dormant accounts by completing necessary KYC processes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/3-types-of-bank-accounts-to-be-closed-from-january-1-is-yours-one-of-them-ws-ab-9172381.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/3-types-of-bank-accounts-to-be-closed-from-january-1-is-yours-one-of-them-ws-ab-9172381.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:52:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SNAPSHOT Wall St opens lower on pressure from elevated Treasury yields - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wall Street Opens Lower Amid Rising Treasury Yields</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p>
<img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/24Q7772NNRJG3PRRERIMKWXT3E.jpg?auth=a9dfc4296a57849348528be324f6805b60ea24bd18f8741356952e3473e2c89a&amp;width=4278&amp;quality=80" alt="A Wall Street sign hangs in front of a U.S. Flag outside the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE)">
<figcaption>A Wall Street sign hangs in front of a U.S. Flag outside the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City, U.S., September 18, 2024. REUTERS/Andrew Kelly/File Photo</figcaption>
<p>The U.S. main stock indexes opened lower as the impact of rising Treasury yields influenced market trading.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell 128.3 points, or 0.30%, to 42,863.86.</li>
<li>The S&P 500 decreased by 50.2 points, or 0.84%, to 5,920.67.</li>
<li>The Nasdaq Composite dropped 261.6 points, or 1.33%, to 19,460.413.</li>
<li>Sparse trading volumes contributed to the downward pressure.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The traditionally strong year-end rally for equities is under threat from the specter of rising Treasury yields.</blockquote>
<p>This opening dip reflects market apprehensions ahead of the New Year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/wall-st-futures-slip-elevated-treasury-yields-2024-12-30/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/wall-st-futures-slip-elevated-treasury-yields-2024-12-30/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:33:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to Watch on December 31: Mazagon Dock Shipbuilders, ITC, EaseMyTrip, Hindalco Industries and more - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to Watch on December 31: Mazagon Dock Shipbuilders, ITC, EaseMyTrip, Hindalco Industries and more</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 31, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC-TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Stocks to Watch" title="Stocks to Watch" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360"><figcaption></figcaption><p>This article outlines key stocks to monitor on December 31, including updates from Mazagon Dock Shipbuilders, ITC, EaseMyTrip, Hindalco Industries, and more.</p><ul><li><strong>Mazagon Dock Shipbuilders:</strong> Secured a contract worth ₹1,990 crore from MoD for advanced submarine technology.</li><li><strong>ITC:</strong> Plans to list ITC Hotels on stock exchanges following a successful demerger announcement.</li><li><strong>EaseMyTrip:</strong> Co-founder to sell a 14.21% stake for ₹780 crore through a block deal.</li><li><strong>Hindalco Industries:</strong> Awarded Meenakshi coal mine in Odisha, enhancing resource capabilities.</li><li><strong>Shriram Properties:</strong> Announced sale of land in Chennai to a major healthcare group.</li><li><strong>RVNL:</strong> Declared lowest bidder for a rail project contract in Central Railway.</li></ul><blockquote>“This strategic sale reflects our commitment to diversifying our assets for sustainable growth.” - Shriram Properties spokesman.</blockquote><p>The developments in these companies reflect significant movements in the stock market, providing investors with potential opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/stocks/stocks-to-watch-to-on-december-31-mazagon-dock-shipbuilders-itc-easemytrip-hindalco-industries-and-more-19532015.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/stocks/stocks-to-watch-to-on-december-31-mazagon-dock-shipbuilders-itc-easemytrip-hindalco-industries-and-more-19532015.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:29:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How High Wil Pi Network Price Rise After Mainnet Launch? - CoinGape]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How High Will Pi Network Price Rise After Mainnet Launch?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified <strong>Source: </strong>CoinGape</p><figure id="attachment_231393" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-231393"><img decoding="async" src="https://coingape.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Pi-Network-price-5.png" alt="Pi Network price" width="3574" height="1982"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-231393">Pi Network price chart</figcaption></figure><p>Pi Network price has been consolidating this week, mirroring other cryptocurrencies. The anticipated mainnet launch could significantly impact the price by allowing users to convert their tokens into fiat.</p><ul><li>The Pi Network's mainnet launch is expected in Q1 2025, originally planned for December but postponed for user onboarding.</li><li>About 18 million users have completed KYC; roughly 8 million have moved their tokens to the new mainnet.</li><li>The price has dropped to around $50, down from nearly $100 in November, but shows support above crucial trendlines.</li><li>Prediction suggests a potential price target of $100 or even $121 in 2024 after the mainnet launch.</li></ul><blockquote>The bullish outlook would be negated if prices fall below $37.21.</blockquote><p>In summary, the upcoming mainnet launch is seen as a major positive catalyst for Pi Network's price trajectory.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://coingape.com/markets/how-high-wil-pi-network-price-rise-after-mainnet-launch/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coingape.com/markets/how-high-wil-pi-network-price-rise-after-mainnet-launch/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:28:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GG Story of the Year 2024: Telegram Tap-to-Earn Gaming Explodes, Then Implodes - Decrypt]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GG Story of the Year 2024: Telegram Tap-to-Earn Gaming Explodes, Then Implodes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Decrypt</p><p>At the start of 2024, Telegram tap-to-earn games emerged as a unique trend, drawing millions of players. However, by the end of the year, the initial excitement quickly faded as players became disillusioned with disappointing rewards and game complications.</p><ul><li>The tap-to-earn game Notcoin attracted over 35 million players shortly after its launch.</li><li>Hamster Kombat saw a rapid rise to 300 million players but faced backlash after its airdrop led to many receiving minimal benefits.</li><li>Despite initial success, players became frustrated with complicated token launches and unmet expectations.</li><li>Experts have mixed opinions on the future of tap-to-earn games, questioning their sustainability and engagement levels.</li></ul><blockquote>“Is the next Notcoin just around the corner in 2025? Perhaps.”</blockquote><p>The year showcased the volatility of the gaming cryptocurrency landscape, leaving players and developers reconsidering the future of tap-to-earn models.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://decrypt.co/298895/gg-story-year-2024-telegram-tap-to-earn-gaming</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://decrypt.co/298895/gg-story-year-2024-telegram-tap-to-earn-gaming</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:04:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shriram Properties sells mall land in Chennai for ₹93 crore - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shriram Properties sells mall land in Chennai for ₹93 crore</h1><p><strong>Updated - December 30, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: The Hindu Business Line</strong></p><img src="https://bl-i.thgim.com/public/todays-paper/tp-others/tp-states/dklwo9/article68683683.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Shriram-PropertGFGDCK0VG.5.jpg.jpg" alt="Shriram Properties land sale" /><figcaption>Shriram Properties sells a land parcel in Chennai</figcaption><p>Shriram Properties Limited has sold a 3.9 acre land parcel in Chennai for ₹93 crore to a large healthcare and educational group. The sale is part of the company’s strategy to unlock value from non-core assets and focus on residential development.</p><ul><li>Shriram Properties sold 3.9 acres of land in Chennai.</li><li>The sale amount is ₹93 crore.</li><li>The land is approved for development of retail space.</li><li>The decision aligns with SPL's focus on residential real estate.</li><li>CEO M Murali commented on the transaction as a significant step for the company's growth funding needs.</li></ul><blockquote>“This transaction marks a significant step in the Company’s plan to unlock value from existing non-core land parcels and redeploy capital for growth funding needs.” - M Murali, CMD of SPL</blockquote><p>This strategic move reflects Shriram Properties' commitment to prudent financial management and its intent to enhance its growth in residential projects across its operational markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/news/real-estate/shriram-properties-sells-mall-land-in-chennai-for-93-crore/article69043589.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/news/real-estate/shriram-properties-sells-mall-land-in-chennai-for-93-crore/article69043589.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:51:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ashwin Sheth aims to launch over 10 housing projects in 2025, enter Bengaluru | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/ashwin-sheth-real-estate-luxury-projects-residential-project-housing-rebranding-premium-segment-11735468938280.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/ashwin-sheth-real-estate-luxury-projects-residential-project-housing-rebranding-premium-segment-11735468938280.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:49:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpiceJet to operationalize 30 grounded planes, resume delivery talks with Boeing | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpiceJet to Operationalize 30 Grounded Planes and Resume Delivery Talks with Boeing</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Budget carrier SpiceJet plans to operationalize 30 Boeing 737 MAX aircraft that have been grounded for various reasons within the next 12-15 months and aims to resume delivery talks with Boeing.</p><ul><li>SpiceJet's Chairman Ajay Singh announced plans at the annual general meeting.</li><li>The airline had previously ordered 200 B737 MAX aircraft from Boeing.</li><li>Currently, the airline operates only 28 aircraft.</li><li>SpiceJet aims to expand its fleet to 100 aircraft by the end of 2026.</li><li>Industry experts view this move as critical for breaking the duopoly in India's aviation sector.</li></ul><blockquote>“The announcement by the CMD is a bold move in the strangled Indian aviation market.” - Sanjay Lazar, CEO of Avialaz Consultants</blockquote><p>SpiceJet is also focusing on improving customer services and operational efficiency to regain consumer trust.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/spicejet-to-operationalize-30-grounded-planes-resume-delivery-talks-with-boeing-11735560758146.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/spicejet-to-operationalize-30-grounded-planes-resume-delivery-talks-with-boeing-11735560758146.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:33:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024 in review: From General Elections to Yen carry trade unwind — 5 key events that impacted stock market investors | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2024 in Review: Key Events Impacting Stock Market Investors</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The year 2024 was marked by significant events that shaped the Indian stock market, with a notable rise in the first half followed by a decline in the latter half, culminating in a modest annual return of 9%.</p><ul><li><h2>1. Lok Sabha Elections 2024</h2><p>The General Elections led to Narendra Modi's return as Prime Minister, causing a significant sell-off in the stock market, particularly after disappointing election results.</p></li><li><h2>2. Yen Carry Trade Unwinding</h2><p>The Bank of Japan's interest rate hike created volatility in global markets, negatively impacting investor sentiment.</p></li><li><h2>3. Weak Earnings Outcome</h2><p>Corporate India's performance deteriorated in the July-September quarter, resulting in significant losses in market indices.</p></li><li><h2>4. Middle-East Crisis</h2><p>Tensions escalated with missile launches by Iran, impacting investor confidence in the Indian stock market.</p></li><li><h2>5. US Elections Outcome</h2><p>Donald Trump's victory in the US led to a surge in the cryptocurrency market but further declines in Indian stock indices due to foreign outflows.</p></li></ul><blockquote>“The overall sentiment among investors turned negative as uncertainty regarding US economic conditions and Japanese monetary policy persisted, leading to heightened volatility and sharp losses.” - Satish Chandra Aluri</blockquote><p>The events of 2024 illustrate the interconnectedness of global happenings and their significant impacts on the Indian stock market, providing investors with crucial lessons for the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/2024-in-review-from-general-elections-to-yen-carry-trade-unwind-five-key-events-that-impacted-stock-market-investors-11735559003910.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/2024-in-review-from-general-elections-to-yen-carry-trade-unwind-five-key-events-that-impacted-stock-market-investors-11735559003910.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:28:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Teen forced to endure 16-hr flight with stranger's toddler in her lap - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Teen Endures 16-Hour Flight With Stranger's Toddler</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Not Provided]</p><p>A teenager faced an unusual and challenging situation during a long flight, having to care for a stranger's toddler sitting in her lap for 16 hours.</p><ul><li>The incident highlights issues of passenger responsibility and comfort.</li><li>The girl had to manage the comfort of the child as well as her own throughout the extended flight.</li><li>This scenario raises questions about airline policies regarding children and seating arrangements.</li></ul><blockquote>“I never expected my flight to turn into a babysitting job.”</blockquote><p>This unique ordeal has sparked discussions among travelers regarding the need for clearer policies on flying with children and the responsibilities of adult passengers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/teen-forced-to-endure-16-hr-flight-with-strangers-toddler-in-her-lap/articleshow/116802015.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/teen-forced-to-endure-16-hr-flight-with-strangers-toddler-in-her-lap/articleshow/116802015.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RBI introduces name lookup for RTGS and NEFT - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RBI Introduces Name Lookup for RTGS and NEFT</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> March 2024, CNBC TV18</p>
<img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg" alt="RBI introduces name lookup for RTGS and NEFT" width="640" height="360">
<img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg" alt="RBI introduces name lookup for RTGS and NEFT" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>RBI introduces name lookup for RTGS and NEFT</figcaption>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has launched a new beneficiary bank account name verification feature for Real Time Gross Settlement (RTGS) and National Electronic Funds Transfer (NEFT) systems.</p>
<ol>
<li>Allows remitters to verify beneficiary's name before initiating a transaction.</li>
<li>Reduces risk of errors and fraudulent transfers.</li>
<li>Available through internet, mobile banking, and bank branches.</li>
<li>Tasked to NPCI for development and implementation.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Key Benefits:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Enhanced transaction accuracy</li>
<li>Improved security</li>
<li>Streamlined payment processes</li>
<li>Reduced operational risks</li>
<li>Faster resolution of payment issues</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The new feature strengthens security, accuracy, and efficiency of RTGS and NEFT transactions, promoting digital payment systems and minimizing potential risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/economy/rbi-introduces-name-lookup-for-rtgs-and-neft-19531928.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/economy/rbi-introduces-name-lookup-for-rtgs-and-neft-19531928.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:15:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nearly 20 Lakh Electric Vehicles Sold In 2024 With Huge Growth - GaadiWaadi.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Record Sales of Electric Vehicles in India: Nearly 20 Lakh in 2024</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> 2024, Gaadi Waadi</p><img src="https://gaadiwaadi.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG-windsor-EV-10-1068x624.jpg" alt="MG windsor EV-10"><figcaption>MG Windsor EV-10</figcaption><p>The electric vehicle (EV) market in India has witnessed remarkable growth in 2024, with total sales hitting 1.94 million units, marking a 26.5% increase from the previous year.</p><ul><li>EV penetration in India has increased to 7.46% from 6.39% in 2023.</li><li>The introduction of the E-DRIVE scheme has significantly contributed to this growth.</li><li>October 2024 reported the highest sales with 219,482 units sold.</li><li>Domestic vehicle sales showed a total of 26.04 million, with petrol variants still dominating at 73.69%.</li></ul><blockquote>“For every EV sold in 2024, about 12.43 vehicles powered by petrol or diesel were purchased.”</blockquote><p>The Indian EV industry is on a path toward further growth with new models expected to be released in 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://gaadiwaadi.com/nearly-20-lakh-electric-vehicles-sold-in-2024-with-huge-growth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gaadiwaadi.com/nearly-20-lakh-electric-vehicles-sold-in-2024-with-huge-growth/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:00:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From LPG to PF: Major Rule Changes Effective From January 1, 2025 - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Major Rule Changes Coming in 2025: Impact on LPG and PF Regulations</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024<br/><strong>Source:</strong> News18 Hindi</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Prices for the 14 kg domestic cylinders have remained steady for a prolonged period. (News18 Hindi)" />
<figcaption>Prices for the 14 kg domestic cylinders have remained steady for a prolonged period. (News18 Hindi)</figcaption>
<p>As 2024 comes to a close, several key rule changes are set to take effect from January 1, 2025, impacting various sectors including LPG pricing and EPFO regulations.</p>
<ul>
<li>Adjustments to LPG prices anticipated.</li>
<li>EPFO account holders will have new withdrawal options from ATMs.</li>
<li>UPI payment limits increased for feature phones.</li>
<li>Loan limits for farmers raised to Rs 2 lakh.</li>
<li>Expiry of contracts on NSE changed to the last Thursday of the month.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We aim to streamline PF withdrawals and enhance service quality through technological advancements.” - Labour Secretary Sumita Dawra</blockquote>
<p>These changes are expected to have significant implications across various sectors, indicating a foundational shift in policies as the new year approaches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/from-lpg-to-pf-major-rule-changes-effective-from-january-1-2025-ws-ab-9172806.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/from-lpg-to-pf-major-rule-changes-effective-from-january-1-2025-ws-ab-9172806.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:21:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jefferies turns positive on HDFC Bank; reveals 22 stocks of its India long-only equity portfolio | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jefferies turns positive on HDFC Bank; reveals 22 stocks of its India long-only equity portfolio</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><figure><img src='image_url_here' alt='Jefferies' India long-only equity portfolio' /><figcaption>Jefferies' India long-only equity portfolio</figcaption></figure><p>Global brokerage firm Jefferies has brought back HDFC Bank to its Asia ex-Japan long-only portfolio, reducing stakes in several other banks.</p><ul><li>Investment in HDFC Bank will have a 4% weighting in the portfolio.</li><li>Investments in Macrotech Developers, L&T, ICICI Bank, and Axis Bank reduced by 1% each.</li><li>New investment in Siemens initiated with a 4% weighting, funded by the removal of Samsung Electronics Pref.</li><li>Jefferies' India long-only equity portfolio includes 22 stocks across various sectors.</li><li>Projected 10% rise in Nifty 50 by the end of 2025, with a target of 26,000.</li></ul><blockquote>"At 20.5 times one-year forward PE, Nifty's valuation is nearly 6% above the past five-year average."</blockquote><p>This reallocation reflects Jefferies' confidence in HDFC Bank while also balancing their portfolio across different sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/jefferies-turns-positive-on-hdfc-bank-reveals-22-stocks-of-its-india-long-only-equity-portfolio-11735560646975.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/jefferies-turns-positive-on-hdfc-bank-reveals-22-stocks-of-its-india-long-only-equity-portfolio-11735560646975.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:21:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RBI Financial Stability Report: Three Banks Continue To Display Risky Metrics - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RBI Financial Stability Report: Three Banks Continue To Display Risky Metrics</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> September 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Profit</p>
<img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2022-08%2F8ba4334c-4bed-4bc6-b231-0ff4129db268%2FRBI__1_.jpg?rect=0%2C0%2C1200%2C675&amp;w=1200" alt="New Risk Metrics of Banks" />
<figcaption>RBI's September 2024 report highlights three banks underperforming in risk metrics, including capital adequacy, asset quality, and earnings. (Photo source: NDTV Profit)</figcaption>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has released its Financial Stability Report indicating that three banks demonstrate insufficient risk metrics despite improvements across the sector.</p>
<ul>
<li>Three banks account for 15% of banking system assets and fail to meet key risk indicators.</li>
<li>Most banks show significant improvements; only three banks were found deficient in risk metrics as of September 2024.</li>
<li>The KRI framework integrates traditional CAMELS metrics with market-based indicators to assess bank vulnerability.</li>
<li>The report highlights a reduction in monetary fines and a notable increase in bank profits contributing to capital growth.</li>
<li>Bank reliance on borrowing has increased due to rising loan growth outpacing deposit growth, affecting the loan-deposit ratio.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Only three banks forming 15 percent of total banking system assets have been found to be deficient in three KRIs." - RBI Financial Stability Report</blockquote>
<p>In summary, while the overall banking sector exhibits positive trends, these identified banks require close monitoring to prevent potential risks from escalating in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/economy-finance/rbi-financial-stability-report-three-banks-risk-metrics-september-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/economy-finance/rbi-financial-stability-report-three-banks-risk-metrics-september-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:15:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samhi Hotels bets on converting old office buildings into luxury hotels | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samhi Hotels Pioneers Office-to-Hotel Conversion</h1><p><strong>Date: November, Source: Company Business News</strong></p><p>Samhi Hotels Ltd has initiated a unique project in Hyderabad, converting an empty office building into a 170-175 room luxury hotel under the W Hotel brand, managed by Marriott International. This is the first-of-its-kind initiative in the country, aiming to launch by FY27.</p><p><img src='https://example.com/hotel_construction.jpg' alt='Hotel Construction' width='200px'><figcaption>Artist's impression of the hotel under construction</figcaption></p><p>Gurugram-based Samhi Hotels, led by Ashish Jakhanwala, is bucking the trend of new constructions by repurposing existing office spaces, expediting the hotel development process.</p><ol><li>The converted office building will be transformed into a luxury hotel in Hitech City, Hyderabad.</li><li>The hotel will be operated under the W Hotel brand, managed by Marriott International.</li><li>The project is expected to be launched by FY27.</li></ol><blockquote>Ashish Jakhanwala, chairman, managing director, and CEO of Samhi Hotels Ltd, claimed that this will be the first-ever initiative of converting an office building into a hotel in the country.</blockquote><p>This innovative approach by Samhi Hotels could set a precedent for the hospitality industry, streamlining the hotel development process and potentially reducing costs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/samhi-hotels-bets-on-converting-old-office-buildings-into-luxury-hotels-11735448969114.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/samhi-hotels-bets-on-converting-old-office-buildings-into-luxury-hotels-11735448969114.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:04:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From costlier cars, GST updates to US visa fees: What’s all changing from January 1, 2025? - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Upcoming Changes in India: GST, Car Prices, Visas, and More from January 1, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 31, 2024, <em>Economic Times</em></p>
<img src="https://example.com/image.jpg" alt="A graph showing various changes" width="500" height="300"><figcaption>Graph showing the various changes coming into effect on January 1, 2025</figcaption>
<p>As the calendar turns to 2025, India is set to witness a range of changes in regulations and rules impacting businesses, consumers, and the economy. From higher car prices to stricter GST compliance, here's an overview of what's changing in the new year.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>GST Compliance:</strong> Mandatory Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) will be required for accessing the GST portal, and E-Way Bill restrictions will be imposed to streamline logistics.</li>
  <li><strong>Car Prices:</strong> Major automakers are set to increase prices due to rising input costs and inflation.</li>
  <li><strong>Visa Processes:</strong> Thailand is expanding its e-visa system, and the US is introducing more flexible visa appointment rules and changes to the H-1B visa process.</li>
  <li><strong>Telecom Regulations:</strong> The government has updated Right of Way (RoW) rules to boost infrastructure development and simplify the process for telecom providers.</li>
  <li><strong>RBI Rules for Fixed Deposits:</strong> The Reserve Bank of India has introduced new guidelines for fixed deposits with NBFCs and HFCs, allowing premature withdrawals without interest for small deposits.</li>
  <li><strong>UPI Limit Extension:</strong> The transaction limit for UPI 123Pay users has been doubled, allowing feature phone users to make payments of up to ₹10,000 without an internet connection.</li>
</ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/business-news/latest-updates/from-costlier-cars-gst-updates-to-us-visa-fees-what-s-all-changing-from-january-1-2025/article-137578/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/business-news/latest-updates/from-costlier-cars-gst-updates-to-us-visa-fees-what-s-all-changing-from-january-1-2025/article-137578/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:41:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>