<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 08:23:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 08:23:46 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025 Tata Nexon Launched At Rs 7.99 Lakh; New Trims, Features Added - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2025 Tata Nexon Launched At Rs 7.99 Lakh; New Trims, Features Added</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/h6b81u88_2025-nexon-screen_625x300_14_January_25.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=800" alt="Tata Nexon 2025" />
<figcaption>2025 Tata Nexon Showcase</figcaption>
<p>Tata Motors has launched the 2025 Tata Nexon in the Indian market, introducing new trims, colors, and features while maintaining the existing powertrain options.</p>
<ul>
  <li>New exterior colors: Carbon Black, Creative Blue, Royal Blue, Grassland Beige, and others.</li>
  <li>Discontinued trims: Pure, Pure S, Creative Plus, Fearless; New trims include Pure Plus and Pure Plus S.</li>
  <li>New features in trims: updated touchscreen, rain-sensing wipers, panoramic sunroof, 360-degree camera.</li>
  <li>No changes to powertrain: 1.2-litre turbo petrol, 1.5-litre diesel, and a CNG option remain unchanged.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The new top-spec Fearless Plus PS comes equipped with a panoramic sunroof, 10.25-inch digital instrument cluster, and connected tech.”</blockquote>
<p>The launch of the 2025 Tata Nexon represents Tata Motors' continued effort to enhance its vehicle offerings in response to consumer demand while ensuring reliability in performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/auto/2025-tata-nexon-launched-at-rs-7-99-lakh-new-trims-features-added-7469693</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/auto/2025-tata-nexon-launched-at-rs-7-99-lakh-new-trims-features-added-7469693</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 06:47:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani Energy Solutions shares jump 12% after firm posts strong Q3 business growth - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Adani Energy Solutions Sees 12% Share Surge Following Strong Q3 Growth</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/08/20240815090929_adanirtr.png?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Adani Group" title="Adani Group" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Adani Group</figcaption><p>Adani Energy Solutions' shares jumped over 12% after the company reported significant growth in its Q3 operational metrics.</p><ul><li>Transmission network length increased to 26,485 ckm, up nearly 23% year-over-year.</li><li>Power transmission capacity rose by 54% to 84,286 MVA.</li><li>The company secured two new projects with substantial investments.</li><li>Distribution losses were reduced, and units sold increased by 3% year-over-year.</li></ul><blockquote>“Fully commissioned MP Package-2 transmission line which will strengthen transmission system in the eastern region of Madhya Pradesh by adding 1,088 ckm to the transmission network,” the company stated.</blockquote><p>The solid financial results and expansion efforts position Adani Energy Solutions as a key player in the energy sector, indicating robust growth potential moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/adani-energy-solutions-shares-jump-12-after-firm-announces-strong-q3-business-growth-12910003.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/adani-energy-solutions-shares-jump-12-after-firm-announces-strong-q3-business-growth-12910003.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 05:38:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani Power, Adani Green to Adani Enterprises — Why are Adani group shares skyrocketing? EXPLAINED | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxNcmg1ZHYxR3hRZnRFNEVFUDZDYkRRcFIyY1ZPTEhMcmFmZ2FZcXR4THFDZEp4c2pNTHE3bVUzLTc0ZDFVSUZ4Z0FobTRwMlU2elFoa0N5blpwbUtWTUN6NEx4QUtMUUM0MVJGaUNIZ0kyWk9ka2NKRWdDZGVzbVZaRnU4VkN6UGVFRmNxd2E3alBYLXo3ZHZJUUxXVU9ES2hQai1OQ1NMTEdWYTZIXzVxS1dWS01NcVFIbzRHcFFMZlNRdW9JSDdoaXN3UDhZaUJtSnNfSllHc3prMUhmZlV6bVFXOG1YdklUSzFyWHUtUXVESk5Yem1n0gH8AUFVX3lxTE0zcXc5N3VQSFRWWE5kX1JtMDRvTmdlNl84QWFHcTlYZUxfOWJVd3VqeFZsV25VQW1ITjNXN0phRUtFdTJMZUVqenBhWUY4SnM0SzRLMlZPQlJSVndMTXJrQlNINUwwelRwN2JsWkZPV0lEZ2dBbmhaT2IzQzdMaG43NFRKUVV6VHdBTUNOS05CVUdaU1JrMl9EV0dZMkRhUlA3VTY4SThkbEZ1RVd1UzBNcU1mMENQY1B3UnFpQVZZaEVmeHBmcXFlT29hZ1JUWTdNU2FPNDJkTG5maUFSSWJjRGNIcjdrQjFOM1laZV9CUnR5X3QwV3ZjWjhHNw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxNcmg1ZHYxR3hRZnRFNEVFUDZDYkRRcFIyY1ZPTEhMcmFmZ2FZcXR4THFDZEp4c2pNTHE3bVUzLTc0ZDFVSUZ4Z0FobTRwMlU2elFoa0N5blpwbUtWTUN6NEx4QUtMUUM0MVJGaUNIZ0kyWk9ka2NKRWdDZGVzbVZaRnU4VkN6UGVFRmNxd2E3alBYLXo3ZHZJUUxXVU9ES2hQai1OQ1NMTEdWYTZIXzVxS1dWS01NcVFIbzRHcFFMZlNRdW9JSDdoaXN3UDhZaUJtSnNfSllHc3prMUhmZlV6bVFXOG1YdklUSzFyWHUtUXVESk5Yem1n0gH8AUFVX3lxTE0zcXc5N3VQSFRWWE5kX1JtMDRvTmdlNl84QWFHcTlYZUxfOWJVd3VqeFZsV25VQW1ITjNXN0phRUtFdTJMZUVqenBhWUY4SnM0SzRLMlZPQlJSVndMTXJrQlNINUwwelRwN2JsWkZPV0lEZ2dBbmhaT2IzQzdMaG43NFRKUVV6VHdBTUNOS05CVUdaU1JrMl9EV0dZMkRhUlA3VTY4SThkbEZ1RVd1UzBNcU1mMENQY1B3UnFpQVZZaEVmeHBmcXFlT29hZ1JUWTdNU2FPNDJkTG5maUFSSWJjRGNIcjdrQjFOM1laZV9CUnR5X3QwV3ZjWjhHNw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 05:26:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk to buy TikTok from China, here’s what the company has to say - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk to Buy TikTok from China: Here’s What the Company Has to Say</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here], <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>Elon Musk's potential acquisition of TikTok has sparked significant interest, with the company responding to inquiries about the deal.</p><ul><li>Musk is reportedly interested in acquiring TikTok to bolster his influence in social media.</li><li>Concerns have been raised regarding data privacy and national security implications of such a purchase.</li><li>The company emphasizes its commitment to user trust and data protection.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are focused on maintaining the integrity and safety of our user base across all platforms." - TikTok Representative</blockquote><p>This acquisition could have far-reaching implications in the tech industry and social media landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/social/elon-musk-to-buy-tiktok-from-china-heres-what-the-company-has-to-say/articleshow/117221985.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/social/elon-musk-to-buy-tiktok-from-china-heres-what-the-company-has-to-say/articleshow/117221985.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple iPhone sales drop 5% globally after AI rollout disappoints, Chinese competition grows - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple's global iPhone sales declined by about 5% globally during the final quarter of 2024, due to underwhelming upgrades and rising Chinese competition</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/APPLE-CHINA--1_1736820423331_1736820503969.JPG" alt="A man checks an iPhone 16 Pro Max as the new iPhone 16 series smartphones go on sale at an Apple store in Beijing, China September 20, 2024. REUTERS//File Photo(Florence Lo/Reuters)" title="A man checks an iPhone 16 Pro Max as the new iPhone 16 series smartphones go on sale at an Apple store in Beijing, China September 20, 2024. REUTERS//File Photo(Florence Lo/Reuters)"/><figcaption>A man checks an iPhone 16 Pro Max as the new iPhone 16 series smartphones go on sale at an Apple store in Beijing, China September 20, 2024. REUTERS//File Photo(Florence Lo/Reuters)</figcaption><p>In the final quarter of 2024, Apple Inc. saw a 5% drop in global iPhone sales, attributed to disappointing upgrades and increasing competition from Chinese brands.</p><ul><li>Global iPhone sales dropped by 5% and 2% for the entire year while the industry grew by 4%.</li><li>Apple's market share fell to 18%, with Chinese competitors like Xiaomi and Vivo gaining ground.</li><li>Chinese smartphone vendors achieved record shipments, accounting for 56% of the global market.</li><li>Apple’s AI features lag behind competitors, particularly in China, Apple’s major market outside the US and Europe.</li></ul><blockquote>“This past quarter was particularly remarkable for the largest Chinese smartphone vendors,” said IDC analyst Francisco Jeronimo.</blockquote><p>Although Apple’s overall sales were down, there was a noted increase in the sales of higher-end iPhone models in China, representing over half of its shipments there.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/apple-iphone-sales-drop-5-globally-after-ai-rollout-disappoints-chinese-competition-grows-101736819320746.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/apple-iphone-sales-drop-5-globally-after-ai-rollout-disappoints-chinese-competition-grows-101736819320746.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:12:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HCLTech stock nosedives 9% after marginal guidance upgrade hints at weaker Q4 - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HCLTech stock nosedives 9% after marginal guidance upgrade hints at weaker Q4</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/09/20240919093212_HCL-Tech.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="HCL" title="HCL" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>HCL stock performance chart</figcaption>
<p>Shares of India's third largest IT company, HCLTech plummeted over 9 percent on January 14, driven by updated revenue guidance indicating weaker growth for Q4, revealing a surprising shift in market sentiment.</p>
<ul>
  <li>HCLTech shares fell 9% following the release of its Q3 performance.</li>
  <li>The company's earnings were in-line, but the guidance hinted at a weaker performance for Q4.</li>
  <li>Current share price stands at Rs 1,804.65, marking the biggest single-day decline in nearly a decade.</li>
  <li>Revenue growth guidance for fiscal year 2025 was adjusted to 4.5-5%, an upgrade of 100 basis points on the lower end.</li>
  <li>CEO C Vijayakumar noted challenges including a telecom deal scale-down and delays in project ramp-ups.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Brokerages pointed out that the updated guidance suggested weaker growth for Q4, which came as a disappointment, especially with improved discretionary demand.”</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights the volatility of the tech stock market and investor reactions to earnings forecasts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/hcltech-stock-nosedives-9-after-marginal-guidance-upgrade-hints-weaker-q4-12909914.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/hcltech-stock-nosedives-9-after-marginal-guidance-upgrade-hints-weaker-q4-12909914.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:10:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[L&T HR head Sonica Muraleedharan addresses backlash over chairmans 90-hour work week row - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQQTBVLTNNUW1DZ3Nlc1BNdFBQY0ZydURRcXpHSERpV0EteWdxdWs0SWp3V191RTZScjI3bUFFUzRjYlU5TW1rWjJZWmNjWVNLeW01RjlCX3RWM0ZIc0FfcnozclNaMlFDWFlLTXFJQVJ6czRCRDlzZWwzbHdBYTZRNm9BZmpWdl80c29zNHZuVVpjelZndENaTE9UeWxTZ2JvWDY4clZodEpMOXFjSjBBVkpOQi1pODVWV3RmQXdGVktFb0NCUHJn0gHLAUFVX3lxTE0zMUpRa1JSZnZPaG1DQ2hsdTRpRl9pVlRheldrV01uZnFkMkl5X2d5d2JJaG5TZFF6SnBTeDc1Yi1qRXJpQlRoUXUxZlUyUWhLMWo0cHNGWWQtOXNBZDg5ZWgyLTJiM0kxcUhhOHhyY3JzdmhLNzQ5RFRUa1d2a1RHZFVVQjJaYlo1ZzJDZzBHZjBncHN4NzhrS3pYdmtKcUVjUFJsRDNzejJ4b1hCWktKTjF6ZG03U1RkTEx2dHFQclhMcEFOclNKeG1V?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQQTBVLTNNUW1DZ3Nlc1BNdFBQY0ZydURRcXpHSERpV0EteWdxdWs0SWp3V191RTZScjI3bUFFUzRjYlU5TW1rWjJZWmNjWVNLeW01RjlCX3RWM0ZIc0FfcnozclNaMlFDWFlLTXFJQVJ6czRCRDlzZWwzbHdBYTZRNm9BZmpWdl80c29zNHZuVVpjelZndENaTE9UeWxTZ2JvWDY4clZodEpMOXFjSjBBVkpOQi1pODVWV3RmQXdGVktFb0NCUHJn0gHLAUFVX3lxTE0zMUpRa1JSZnZPaG1DQ2hsdTRpRl9pVlRheldrV01uZnFkMkl5X2d5d2JJaG5TZFF6SnBTeDc1Yi1qRXJpQlRoUXUxZlUyUWhLMWo0cHNGWWQtOXNBZDg5ZWgyLTJiM0kxcUhhOHhyY3JzdmhLNzQ5RFRUa1d2a1RHZFVVQjJaYlo1ZzJDZzBHZjBncHN4NzhrS3pYdmtKcUVjUFJsRDNzejJ4b1hCWktKTjF6ZG03U1RkTEx2dHFQclhMcEFOclNKeG1V?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:06:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Chinese delay’ make Apple and Foxconn seek government help - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chinese Delay Forces Apple and Foxconn to Request Government Assistance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Apple and Foxconn are seeking help from the government due to delays attributed to China.</p><ul><li>Chinese manufacturing delays are impacting production schedules for Apple and Foxconn.</li><li>Both companies are exploring government assistance to mitigate the situation.</li></ul><p>The ongoing situation highlights the vulnerabilities in global supply chains, especially in tech manufacturing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/chinese-delay-make-apple-and-foxconn-seek-government-help/articleshow/117220984.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/chinese-delay-make-apple-and-foxconn-seek-government-help/articleshow/117220984.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This analyst expects MGL to benefit from Mumbai's Tesla-like moment - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This analyst expects MGL to benefit from Mumbai's Tesla-like moment</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBCTV18</p><img alt="This analyst expects MGL to benefit from Mumbai's Tesla-like moment" title="This analyst expects MGL to benefit from Mumbai's Tesla-like moment" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" decoding="async" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>An analyst believes MGL will capitalize on Mumbai's burgeoning natural gas market.</figcaption><p>The article discusses how Morgan Stanley has initiated coverage of Mahanagar Gas Ltd. (MGL) with an 'Overweight' rating, highlighting the city's expanding energy needs and the role of natural gas.</p><ul><li>MGL is expected to benefit from a growing market for natural gas in Mumbai.</li><li>The brokerage projected a price target of ₹1,606, indicating a potential upside of over 30% from the current levels.</li><li>One-fifth of MGL's gas sourcing is linked to LNG, which could impact margins positively.</li><li>The article describes this expansion as MGL's “Tesla-like moment” in the gas market.</li><li>A weak third quarter is anticipated, but improvements may come in the fourth quarter FY25.</li><li>MGL shares decreased by 4.37% on Monday, settling at ₹1,229.90.</li></ul><blockquote>“Natural gas is considered the fuel of the future for Mumbai.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, MGL is positioned well to capitalize on the growth in Mumbai’s natural gas market, even amid challenges in the short term.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/mahanagar-gas-share-price-this-analyst-expects-mgl-to-benefit-from-mumbai-tesla-like-moment-19539537.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/mahanagar-gas-share-price-this-analyst-expects-mgl-to-benefit-from-mumbai-tesla-like-moment-19539537.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:35:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vishal Mega Mart shares emerge as a Mutual Fund favourite post listing - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vishal Mega Mart Shares Become a Favorite Among Mutual Funds Post-Listing</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 14, 2025 8:44 AM IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p>
<img alt="Vishal Mega Mart shares emerge as a Mutual Fund favourite post listing" title="Vishal Mega Mart shares emerge as a Mutual Fund favourite post listing" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360">
<figcaption>Vishal Mega Mart shares have garnered significant interest from domestic mutual funds post-listing.</figcaption>
<p>Newly listed Vishal Mega Mart Ltd. has attracted considerable interest from India's domestic mutual funds, reflected in its shareholding pattern.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Domestic Mutual Funds own an 8.66% stake in Vishal Mega Mart.</li>
  <li>Nippon India AMC has a 3.08% stake in the company.</li>
  <li>Aditya Birla Sun Life Mutual Fund purchased shares worth ₹250 crore.</li>
  <li>Axis Mutual Fund bought shares worth ₹380 crore.</li>
  <li>Total retail investor stake stands at 4.52%, with 9.13 lakh retail shareholders.</li>
  <li>The stock closed 4% lower at ₹104 but trades above its IPO price of ₹79.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Foreign Portfolio Investors (FPIs) held a 6.47% stake as of December, with the Government of Singapore notably holding 1.67%.”</blockquote>
<p>Vishal Mega Mart's listing has seen strong support from mutual funds, showcasing investor confidence in the company.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/vishal-mega-mart-share-price-mutual-funds-buy-post-listing-fpi-retail-ipo-returns-19539535.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/vishal-mega-mart-share-price-mutual-funds-buy-post-listing-fpi-retail-ipo-returns-19539535.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:14:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shares to buy or sell: Chandan Taparia recommends three stocks to buy and sell today | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxNV2NhMjVVdnhJTWtDUFJoUWh1bHFHVDNTYXFGdV80RFM3MG94RmtfYk45MXhZTWdDYXdJcTlVZXVwc1lKMGFUZXJVczVRSVozVXU5aGJQdDZYNW9UYkZOWmJteVE3cTg4STNrWHRJZ2wxMHAyejR2cTVOeldydWpBT2dBM1NYeGtYd1Y1eGd0VVlvaGg4MzNfNlN0Vi1odGZpdFVDcG84Tzd4M2JrUGxnVzFYRk5xaEdVdkRaN2QyeGZOZi1uT3psR1AtQzFrbzd6TkY0d2VVUURpc1VhWWNxUGk5cGxuMW9q0gHuAUFVX3lxTE5iVzI2XzRLNmFaTWJuYlU0VGpidGptUWpiOVlGci1KNXMyRFF0a3JCT2pUdFhXWk5JSTVBUUd3Y1c1ZlR6Mk9SdGdKMWZZRnFJb004Z2kxcnZHZHVOcW1iY20xSjBoQWtjTy1kTVp1Qk5xWnVRdVByMkpDSF82Z3lzdzVSQy1WNmo5X3JHVVE5ZmtPYm95NnJxQWNBVlJOczY5N3dTN2tIVGtHTU9vbkthVGhJUjZ5UGZkbnZ6MjQ0TTFXd2lGUjBVblNwVFoxVXNpdXdZOG1rZnBreFQ4Ym5mNEswNi01Z1FuRTJGN3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxNV2NhMjVVdnhJTWtDUFJoUWh1bHFHVDNTYXFGdV80RFM3MG94RmtfYk45MXhZTWdDYXdJcTlVZXVwc1lKMGFUZXJVczVRSVozVXU5aGJQdDZYNW9UYkZOWmJteVE3cTg4STNrWHRJZ2wxMHAyejR2cTVOeldydWpBT2dBM1NYeGtYd1Y1eGd0VVlvaGg4MzNfNlN0Vi1odGZpdFVDcG84Tzd4M2JrUGxnVzFYRk5xaEdVdkRaN2QyeGZOZi1uT3psR1AtQzFrbzd6TkY0d2VVUURpc1VhWWNxUGk5cGxuMW9q0gHuAUFVX3lxTE5iVzI2XzRLNmFaTWJuYlU0VGpidGptUWpiOVlGci1KNXMyRFF0a3JCT2pUdFhXWk5JSTVBUUd3Y1c1ZlR6Mk9SdGdKMWZZRnFJb004Z2kxcnZHZHVOcW1iY20xSjBoQWtjTy1kTVp1Qk5xWnVRdVByMkpDSF82Z3lzdzVSQy1WNmo5X3JHVVE5ZmtPYm95NnJxQWNBVlJOczY5N3dTN2tIVGtHTU9vbkthVGhJUjZ5UGZkbnZ6MjQ0TTFXd2lGUjBVblNwVFoxVXNpdXdZOG1rZnBreFQ4Ym5mNEswNi01Z1FuRTJGN3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:05:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HCLTech shares tumble 10% on no big positive announcements in Q3 FY25 earnings; check key numbers - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxNS3FuY1dndVRvNDE2NVpUZEFYMnFQOWxCYV9UcllUdnJ6QlRYczF6RE1VbnNXTld1ajBXTW5Oc0k0VXBVR0JYc0tfUHZuLUlCa2w1dFVwekpYUC1QbUJ5OHY2M0FWYjFDUzlZV2RjdW41S1I1ank3UzJQVE1wd3ZlRDZneUI0bnA5RmJQN0FFTU5uSDAyS1dnOF96UDAyRzBTZHc5TF94UTRidHZvSHplam42dFExV1lMUGwtc3BXQU1QU2ozRkpWWmU5ckp3VXBFTU9rSFJkeUl1N3dOS1dPZl9vdzdDekNfUDV6clBWWjM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxNS3FuY1dndVRvNDE2NVpUZEFYMnFQOWxCYV9UcllUdnJ6QlRYczF6RE1VbnNXTld1ajBXTW5Oc0k0VXBVR0JYc0tfUHZuLUlCa2w1dFVwekpYUC1QbUJ5OHY2M0FWYjFDUzlZV2RjdW41S1I1ank3UzJQVE1wd3ZlRDZneUI0bnA5RmJQN0FFTU5uSDAyS1dnOF96UDAyRzBTZHc5TF94UTRidHZvSHplam42dFExV1lMUGwtc3BXQU1QU2ozRkpWWmU5ckp3VXBFTU9rSFJkeUl1N3dOS1dPZl9vdzdDekNfUDV6clBWWjM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:03:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Recognise efforts rather than misinterpret them': L&T HR head defends chairman’s 90-hour workweek remark - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Recognise efforts rather than misinterpret them': L&T HR head defends chairman’s 90-hour workweek remark</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Not Provided]</p><p>The HR head of L&T has defended the chairman's recent remark regarding his 90-hour workweek, emphasizing the importance of recognizing efforts rather than misinterpretations.</p><ul><li>The chairman received backlash for discussing his long working hours.</li><li>The HR head highlighted the need for a fair understanding of employee dedication.</li><li>The conversation touches on work-life balance concerns in modern workplaces.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is crucial to appreciate the commitment individuals show without misinterpretations.”</blockquote><p>This article sheds light on the ongoing discussion around work hours and employee recognition in the corporate world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/recognise-efforts-rather-than-misinterpret-them-lt-hr-head-defends-chairmans-90-hour-workweek-remark/articleshow/117221241.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/recognise-efforts-rather-than-misinterpret-them-lt-hr-head-defends-chairmans-90-hour-workweek-remark/articleshow/117221241.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China discusses sale of TikTok US to Elon Musk as one possible option - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China discusses sale of TikTok US to Elon Musk as one possible option</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p>
<p>China is reportedly considering the option of selling TikTok's US operations to Elon Musk amid ongoing concerns about data privacy and security.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The discussions arise as tensions between the U.S. and China escalate over technology and trade.</li>
  <li>Elon Musk's interest in acquiring TikTok could reshape the social media landscape.</li>
  <li>This potential sale is framed within broader efforts to address regulatory scrutiny facing TikTok.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The sale could provide a new path forward for TikTok amid regulatory challenges in the U.S.”</blockquote>
<p>This potential sale is a significant development in the ongoing saga of data privacy and tech company regulations, with implications for users and the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/international-business/china-discusses-sale-of-tiktok-us-to-elon-musk-as-one-possible-option/articleshow/117219501.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/international-business/china-discusses-sale-of-tiktok-us-to-elon-musk-as-one-possible-option/articleshow/117219501.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to watch, January 14: JSW Energy, HCLTech, Shoppers Stop, HDFC AMC, Himadri Speciality, Delta Corp, and more - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to Watch, January 14: JSW Energy, HCLTech, Shoppers Stop, and More</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Unspecified Financial News Source</p>
<p>In today’s stock market update, major companies such as HCLTech and JSW Energy are in focus as several firms prepare to release their financial results.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>NIFTY50 Opening:</strong> Expected to open 114 points higher at 23,276.50.</li>
  <li><strong>HCL Technologies:</strong> Reported a 5.54% growth in net profit to ₹4,591 crore for Q3 FY25.</li>
  <li><strong>JSW Energy:</strong> Acquired KSK Mahanadi Power Company under insolvency proceedings.</li>
  <li><strong>Delta Corp:</strong> Net profit increased by 3.62% to ₹35.73 crore.</li>
  <li><strong>Other Earnings:</strong> Companies like HDFC AMC and Shoppers Stop set to announce Q3 results.</li>
  <li><strong>Den Networks:</strong> Experienced a YoY net profit decline of 14.6%.</li>
  <li><strong>Himadri Speciality:</strong> Reported a 31.55% jump in net profit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“JSW Energy emerged as a successful applicant to acquire KSK Mahanadi Power Company.”</blockquote>
<p>This trading day focuses on earnings results and market indicators, emphasizing shifts in major technology and energy sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/stocks-to-watch-january-14-jsw-energy-hcl-tech-shoppers-stop-hdfc-amc-himadri-speciality-delta-corp-and-more/article-140188/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/stocks-to-watch-january-14-jsw-energy-hcl-tech-shoppers-stop-hdfc-amc-himadri-speciality-delta-corp-and-more/article-140188/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:08:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ITC Hotels shares credited to Demat accounts after allotment; ITC investors get THIS special message - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ITC Hotels Shares Credited to Investors' Demat Accounts After Allotment</h1>
<p><strong>Updated:</strong> <strong>January 14, 2025</strong> - <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="ITC Hotels shares credited allotment listing" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>ITC Hotels shares credited to Demat accounts after allotment (Pic: ET NOW)</figcaption>
<p>ITC Hotels shares have been credited to the Demat accounts of eligible ITC shareholders following the allotment announced on January 11, with shares credited on January 13.</p>
<ul>
<li>Eligible shareholders received an SMS confirming the credit of ITC Hotels shares to their accounts.</li>
<li>A total of 125.11 crore equity shares have been allotted to ITC shareholders based on their holdings as of January 6.</li>
<li>The shares carry no value at the moment and are currently represented as a dummy ticker in Demat accounts.</li>
<li>ITC Hotels shares will be listed on NSE and BSE, with trading set to start after the listing.</li>
<li>Shares will be included in Nifty 50 and BSE Sensex as a dummy ticker before their official listing.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Consequent to the above, ITCHL has ceased to be a subsidiary of the Company effective 11th January, 2025," ITC stated.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, ITC Hotels shares are now available in shareholders' Demat accounts, ready for future trading post-listing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/itc-hotels-shares-credited-to-demat-accounts-after-allotment-message-sms-itc-hotels-listing-date-price-prediction-nse-bse-article-117218965</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/itc-hotels-shares-credited-to-demat-accounts-after-allotment-message-sms-itc-hotels-listing-date-price-prediction-nse-bse-article-117218965</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:08:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[D-Street's $556 billion equity rout seen worsening as growth cools - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQdW84M3VIRkJzamg3OGdTd25qWk9tZlRqQTF1Qml1YUY3Z0NoYUhoR1ZJTnl2Z2dsTGIxcHVrT0d1bVZXc3g4OWdKZXU4cjVRODRpaGdRazhWa0pqVlp1dGZoaV9oUEF2ekYyTDVjTjlxNThsazZGd1N5Skgwb3UxalJ6OFJDU3BPTTZWTEJ4c3cxLWpqYlN0c2J3Q3MyV0pTYmlUY2tud1pVYlJqX2REcVhIZFJTQlh4Rld3MGh6RUhQaERmR05IVmFGcTFPMTJLSnJCSA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQdW84M3VIRkJzamg3OGdTd25qWk9tZlRqQTF1Qml1YUY3Z0NoYUhoR1ZJTnl2Z2dsTGIxcHVrT0d1bVZXc3g4OWdKZXU4cjVRODRpaGdRazhWa0pqVlp1dGZoaV9oUEF2ekYyTDVjTjlxNThsazZGd1N5Skgwb3UxalJ6OFJDU3BPTTZWTEJ4c3cxLWpqYlN0c2J3Q3MyV0pTYmlUY2tud1pVYlJqX2REcVhIZFJTQlh4Rld3MGh6RUhQaERmR05IVmFGcTFPMTJLSnJCSA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:06:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China considering TikTok US sale to Elon Musk if company fails to fend off potential ban: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Considering Selling TikTok to Elon Musk Amid U.S. Ban Threat</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/FRANCE-TECHNOLOGY-AI-GROK-5_1736816980536_1736817013231.jpg" alt="Screens displaying the logo of Grok, a generative artificial intelligence chatbot developed by xAI, the American company specializing in artificial intelligence and its founder Elon Musk.(AFP)" />
<figcaption>Screens displaying the logo of Grok, a generative artificial intelligence chatbot developed by xAI, the American company specializing in artificial intelligence and its founder Elon Musk.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>China is contemplating selling TikTok's U.S. operations to Elon Musk if the company fails to prevent a proposed ban by U.S. authorities.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Chinese officials prefer TikTok to remain with parent company ByteDance.</li>
  <li>A potential ban on TikTok is expected as President-elect Trump assumes office, raising national security concerns.</li>
  <li>Musk, a supporter of Trump, has been appointed co-chair of the Department of Government Efficiency.</li>
  <li>ByteDance is contesting the impending ban in the U.S. Supreme Court, which has set a deadline of January 19 for a sale.</li>
  <li>About half of the U.S. population uses TikTok, which has raised data privacy concerns among lawmakers.</li>
  <li>A sale to Musk might align TikTok's operations more closely with his management style of Twitter, now rebranded as “X.”</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>TikTok is used by roughly half of the US population, catering to around 170 million users.</blockquote>
<p>The situation surrounding TikTok continues to evolve, with significant implications for its future in the U.S. market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/china-considering-tiktok-us-sale-to-elon-musk-if-company-fails-to-fend-off-potential-ban-report-101736816819501.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/china-considering-tiktok-us-sale-to-elon-musk-if-company-fails-to-fend-off-potential-ban-report-101736816819501.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:35:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian stock market: 7 key things that changed for market overnight - Gift Nifty, CPI inflation to HCL Tech Q3 Results | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian stock market: 7 key things that changed for market overnight - Gift Nifty, CPI inflation to HCL Tech Q3 Results</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The domestic equity market indices, Sensex and Nifty 50, are expected to open higher on Tuesday amid mixed global cues, following a significant crash on Monday.</p><ul><li>On Monday, the Sensex and Nifty suffered substantial declines of 1.36% and 1.47%, respectively.</li><li>Rising crude oil prices, a depreciating rupee, and foreign capital outflows were primary contributors to the sell-off.</li><li>Asian markets showed a mixed response, with Japan's Nikkei down while South Korea's Kospi rose.</li><li>The Gift Nifty suggests a gap-up start, trading at around 23,280.</li><li>HCL Technologies reported an 8.4% QoQ increase in net profit for Q3, showing strong performance amidst market fluctuations.</li><li>Retail inflation in India eased to a four-month low at 5.22%, which may ease concerns for rate cuts from the RBI.</li><li>Strong direct tax collection growth indicates robust economic activity despite market volatility.</li></ul><blockquote>“Wide-spread selling across the sectors fuelled along with massive exits in mid and small-cap stocks further worsened the sentiment.” - Prashanth Tapse, Senior VP (Research), Mehta Equities Ltd.</blockquote><p>This market turbulence reflects ongoing global trends and highlights the complexities of the current economic landscape, as various factors are contributing to the risk and resilience of the Indian stock market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/indian-stock-market-7-key-things-that-changed-for-market-overnight-gift-nifty-cpi-inflation-to-hcl-tech-q3-results-11736790154753.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/indian-stock-market-7-key-things-that-changed-for-market-overnight-gift-nifty-cpi-inflation-to-hcl-tech-q3-results-11736790154753.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:27:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GIFT Nifty up 150 points; here's the trading setup for today's session - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GIFT Nifty up 150 points; here's the trading setup for today's session</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today<br><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>Indian markets experienced a sell-off due to strong US payroll data, leading to expectations of volatility. The GIFT Nifty indicates a gap-up start for Dalal Street.</p><img src='image_url.jpg' alt='GIFT Nifty Trend'><figcaption>GIFT Nifty trading trends</figcaption><p>Key factors influencing the market include the upcoming 2025 budget, Q3 results, RBI policy, and global political events.</p><ul><li>GIFT Nifty traded up by 152.50 points, indicating a positive start.</li><li>India VIX rose 7.2% to 16 levels, reflecting increased market fear.</li><li>Foreign portfolio investors were net sellers, while domestic institutional investors bought shares worth Rs 8,066 crore.</li><li>The rupee declined sharply, hitting a historic low of 86.62 against the US dollar.</li></ul><blockquote>“Any pullback up to 23,350 could be a sell-on-rise opportunity.” - Nagaraj Shetti, HDFC Securities</blockquote><p>The market is expected to remain volatile as key economic and political factors unfold.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/pre-market-action-heres-the-trade-setup-for-todays-session/articleshow/117211167.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/pre-market-action-heres-the-trade-setup-for-todays-session/articleshow/117211167.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China's export curbs: Hi-tech machinery supply faces major hit - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's Export Curbs: Hi-Tech Machinery Supply Faces Major Hit</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<div><img src="https://img.etimg.com/photo/msid-117214239/1.jpg" alt="" title="1">
<figcaption>Chinese government halts capital equipment exports impacting Indian manufacturing.</figcaption></div>
<p>China's tightening of export regulations is dramatically affecting sectors reliant on hi-tech machinery, particularly in electronics and electric vehicles, with industry leaders warning of severe manufacturing setbacks in India.</p>
<ul>
  <li>China has almost halted exports of critical industrial machinery needed for production.</li>
  <li>Firms like Foxconn, BYD, and Lenovo face challenges in scaling up operations in India.</li>
  <li>The Indian government is considering measures to mitigate the impact on manufacturing.</li>
  <li>The restrictions are seen as a protectionist move by Beijing amid geopolitical tensions.</li>
  <li>India's domestic manufacturing ecosystem is underdeveloped compared to other countries such as Vietnam.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Chinese government is stopping capital equipment exports from China which are critical to the manufacturing of various products, especially electronics, EVs and solar panels.” - Anonymous executive</blockquote>
<p>China's export restrictions could hurt evolving manufacturing ecosystems in India, compelling the government to rethink strategies to support domestic industries reliant on Chinese machinery.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/foreign-trade/chinas-export-curbs-hi-tech-machinery-supply-faces-major-hit/articleshow/117214222.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/foreign-trade/chinas-export-curbs-hi-tech-machinery-supply-faces-major-hit/articleshow/117214222.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trading Plan: Can Nifty rebound to 23,200, Bank Nifty climb towards 49,000? - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxOT0c3RE9FWF9yVEl5ZVFMaGVVRDVDQjFnY1p2by1UUHdtTm5FYldMRGhNbXVscVMzT1FGb3hsa2YwY2FDM3lIeEZFTWJ4dHQ0QXJTTW9SVThEaG8xNnB3LVFnVzJja1RSMHU2ZUd1LUI2VGRQYkt6WXpBUUFyOC01UFRfT3NjU1JCbk5FRXQ3VW1vejhDTzlFdmNkNkxXR3RxRDNnNUt0RmpkYjVlc1RlN3Mzd1hDYUtIb0J3VUNjanJXalNkNER3ek1TMTdfdlJKZHdn0gHYAUFVX3lxTE83VzhsbnlQRi1nNVA5UjVSOFJMRnctOHQ4NEg1QlpMTDFIeDFDamN5SHRkLWhvbWZMelFkaGg5aDRzNEtnRWFKZVhSanlocTF0aU82aElaYW9CZVBMVDI1R3FrQngzM0dvX3hRbkl3bEp5TG1YSEEyeFVxRnNyRmFWX0RHSzNWNTNFZWFsNHVvN1NVS2NmVzByNzZEWlp0cFExNnZYZENVVFkwS29oUnYtVElKN3pRRzVvVG1YY2RyeEc5RDd3anR5bXJQcjVqMGxhODlzaktscw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxOT0c3RE9FWF9yVEl5ZVFMaGVVRDVDQjFnY1p2by1UUHdtTm5FYldMRGhNbXVscVMzT1FGb3hsa2YwY2FDM3lIeEZFTWJ4dHQ0QXJTTW9SVThEaG8xNnB3LVFnVzJja1RSMHU2ZUd1LUI2VGRQYkt6WXpBUUFyOC01UFRfT3NjU1JCbk5FRXQ3VW1vejhDTzlFdmNkNkxXR3RxRDNnNUt0RmpkYjVlc1RlN3Mzd1hDYUtIb0J3VUNjanJXalNkNER3ek1TMTdfdlJKZHdn0gHYAUFVX3lxTE83VzhsbnlQRi1nNVA5UjVSOFJMRnctOHQ4NEg1QlpMTDFIeDFDamN5SHRkLWhvbWZMelFkaGg5aDRzNEtnRWFKZVhSanlocTF0aU82aElaYW9CZVBMVDI1R3FrQngzM0dvX3hRbkl3bEp5TG1YSEEyeFVxRnNyRmFWX0RHSzNWNTNFZWFsNHVvN1NVS2NmVzByNzZEWlp0cFExNnZYZENVVFkwS29oUnYtVElKN3pRRzVvVG1YY2RyeEc5RDd3anR5bXJQcjVqMGxhODlzaktscw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 22:12:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Retail inflation dips to 4-month low of 5.2% in Dec - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Retail inflation dips to 4-month low of 5.2% in Dec</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Data not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Retail Inflation" />
<figcaption>Retail inflation trends in recent months</figcaption>
<p>The retail inflation rate in India has dropped to its lowest level in four months, settling at 5.2% for December. This significant decrease is attributed to lower prices in various sectors.</p>
<ul>
<li>The inflation rate is a key indicator of the economic health, affecting monetary policy and purchasing power.</li>
<li>This is the lowest inflation rate reported since August of the previous year.</li>
<li>Factors contributing to this decline include decreased food prices and stabilizing crude oil prices.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This decline in inflation is a positive sign for economic recovery as it provides more room for policy adjustments." - Economic Analyst</blockquote>
<p>This decrease in retail inflation signals potential economic stability, providing hope for consumers and policymakers alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/retail-inflation-dips-to-4-mth-low-of-5-2-in-dec/articleshow/117215809.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/retail-inflation-dips-to-4-mth-low-of-5-2-in-dec/articleshow/117215809.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 21:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tether will relocate HQ to El Salvador after securing license - Cointelegraph]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxNNElPc2lYVlhjS1cwcVZIUGw2ZnFNVUpIcnMxY2w2NXRFMmJ6UHhEV0FmSkpPMW5xeWg5eHRkaWtld0ZhLWFTcjhRZlpYZGhvWnFUb2dCNHlZSWlJa0p2NkFMb1ZBZFR5a0d0OVpCR1Y1bEkxU1dFVUYxYTZhcFJFSw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxNNElPc2lYVlhjS1cwcVZIUGw2ZnFNVUpIcnMxY2w2NXRFMmJ6UHhEV0FmSkpPMW5xeWg5eHRkaWtld0ZhLWFTcjhRZlpYZGhvWnFUb2dCNHlZSWlJa0p2NkFMb1ZBZFR5a0d0OVpCR1Y1bEkxU1dFVUYxYTZhcFJFSw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:47:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DMart Shares Tank 6% As Q3 Earnings Fail To Impress D-Street; Should You Invest? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>DMart Shares Tank 6% As Q3 Earnings Fail To Impress D-Street; Should You Invest?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="DMart shares"><figcaption>DMart shares</figcaption></figure><p>Avenue Supermarts, the operator of the DMart retail chain, reported disappointing Q3 results leading to a significant drop in share prices. Investors are left questioning whether to buy, sell, or hold.</p><ul><li>Avenue Supermarts shares fell by 5.7%, reaching Rs 3,474.</li><li>Q3FY25 revenue increased by 17.5% YoY, totaling Rs 15,565 crore.</li><li>Net profit rose 6.5% YoY to Rs 785 crore, but margins are under pressure.</li><li>EBITDA margin dropped to 7.9% from 8.5% YoY.</li><li>Same-store sales growth was reported at 8.3%.</li><li>The company will focus on both home delivery and pick-up services.</li><li>Analysts have adjusted their earnings projections downwards and have mixed ratings on DMart’s stock.</li><li>Management changes announced with a new CEO effective March 15, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“While discounting in the FMCG category remained intense, the impact on high-turnover stores in metro towns was lower than in the previous quarter.” - Neville Noronha, CEO</blockquote><p>Investors are advised to closely monitor the company’s strategic changes and market performance amidst competitive pressures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/markets/dmart-shares-tank-6-as-q3-earnings-fail-to-impress-d-street-should-you-invest-9186890.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/markets/dmart-shares-tank-6-as-q3-earnings-fail-to-impress-d-street-should-you-invest-9186890.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:20:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trade setup for January 14: Top 15 things to know before the opening bell - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxNT0lxWmVDUUpPVXdQcXpsQWlwS094TFZzQnZXWWNoa0REYXR3Z19TRlh6ME9MYzUxZ1FMTnRhOXpFSmRFaUlSbDNldFFTM2xXY2M3YktMN1Z5bVRhdEd6WXhVN3ctMmJWeW5ENDVsZG5wUXRRbEJYR3QzcXU4YVpmbVRydWR3MzFpWS1GMVl0c2hkUmYwXzdiSmhsamVhUjE1bHVtSGdmMEFqLXNtRWRHc2QwXzNia2hKdmlxNXRDbWdlRmk2WTJwNTQ3c0VldEtxeFlj0gHYAUFVX3lxTE9SUzl3cS14WlNGSml4RFRBb2JWb1JQYzFNN3pwaGxoX0lzWFNFdEJUdTdjZlo5dl9mT2dEb085SFc5eFdiWEw1VHVhNjhSaFhOX0VZbUNRMzM3WWV1cmkzb01XSjk0bEhIN1NmY0NXSHdnRk5sc01ibUZCeEg0QVFsUWJjQnFYZkJCblNHYzk4bzNsdEhvblhwNXY2d1ZXeVZqcGdTM3h5WXZnVE13dVRCWm1HTk5EN3ZyU3k3UHNKOU5KSGU3Zll2TTZXQTJ5aHJCMVo3dGRZbQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxNT0lxWmVDUUpPVXdQcXpsQWlwS094TFZzQnZXWWNoa0REYXR3Z19TRlh6ME9MYzUxZ1FMTnRhOXpFSmRFaUlSbDNldFFTM2xXY2M3YktMN1Z5bVRhdEd6WXhVN3ctMmJWeW5ENDVsZG5wUXRRbEJYR3QzcXU4YVpmbVRydWR3MzFpWS1GMVl0c2hkUmYwXzdiSmhsamVhUjE1bHVtSGdmMEFqLXNtRWRHc2QwXzNia2hKdmlxNXRDbWdlRmk2WTJwNTQ3c0VldEtxeFlj0gHYAUFVX3lxTE9SUzl3cS14WlNGSml4RFRBb2JWb1JQYzFNN3pwaGxoX0lzWFNFdEJUdTdjZlo5dl9mT2dEb085SFc5eFdiWEw1VHVhNjhSaFhOX0VZbUNRMzM3WWV1cmkzb01XSjk0bEhIN1NmY0NXSHdnRk5sc01ibUZCeEg0QVFsUWJjQnFYZkJCblNHYzk4bzNsdEhvblhwNXY2d1ZXeVZqcGdTM3h5WXZnVE13dVRCWm1HTk5EN3ZyU3k3UHNKOU5KSGU3Zll2TTZXQTJ5aHJCMVo3dGRZbQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:35:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MicroStrategy Buys $243 Million More Bitcoin - Decrypt]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE12UUJfaWkxYURQM3JiX3BqUGV6NjlMdXFoRlI4Y3lhRVA5RVVvd1kyMkdJU1pvaUhFcnpZbFEweHJnZF9zYzF3aWVZWXZ1aVdqelRMbFNvS3dOazlBNHEySlJlNTd4WkJuSTl3NG9ieHpCODBCWGlsMtIBgAFBVV95cUxPWVJKMzNzaV90Qy1KWXVfQ1BSQ2hhZG5qTk9hTU15c3pwaUZ1ZXFHSHFyd2tuc0tXS2hwSFZ5dkZ0NXlHSUxJTVdQR3pWeXJ1R0JXckxTcmY4cVdtWEdvRy1NU1VQQjdlZ3c3LXZlYllLcVk3aXNOS0JNcXUzTWI4cg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE12UUJfaWkxYURQM3JiX3BqUGV6NjlMdXFoRlI4Y3lhRVA5RVVvd1kyMkdJU1pvaUhFcnpZbFEweHJnZF9zYzF3aWVZWXZ1aVdqelRMbFNvS3dOazlBNHEySlJlNTd4WkJuSTl3NG9ieHpCODBCWGlsMtIBgAFBVV95cUxPWVJKMzNzaV90Qy1KWXVfQ1BSQ2hhZG5qTk9hTU15c3pwaUZ1ZXFHSHFyd2tuc0tXS2hwSFZ5dkZ0NXlHSUxJTVdQR3pWeXJ1R0JXckxTcmY4cVdtWEdvRy1NU1VQQjdlZ3c3LXZlYllLcVk3aXNOS0JNcXUzTWI4cg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:47:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's retail inflation eases to 4-month low of 5.22% in December 2024 | Dec is 4th month with retail inflation over 5% | Inshorts - Inshorts]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Heavy Rainfall and Very Dense Fog Warnings Issued for Several States</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Monday 13 January, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Inshorts</p><p>The India Meteorological Department (IMD) has issued warnings for heavy rainfall and dense fog affecting multiple states in India. These warnings are particularly significant for the coming day.</p><ul><li>Heavy rainfall is expected over Tamil Nadu and Puducherry.</li><li>Very dense fog warnings are issued for Punjab, Haryana, Chandigarh and Uttar Pradesh.</li><li>Dense fog is also likely over additional states including Himachal Pradesh, Uttarakhand, and West Bengal among others.</li></ul><blockquote>IMD warns that conditions may lead to travel disruptions and safety concerns due to low visibility.</blockquote><p>These weather conditions highlight the ongoing impact of the winter season in India, requiring public awareness and preparedness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://inshorts.com/en/news/india-s-retail-inflation-eases-to-4-month-low-of-5-22--in-december-2024-1736773784715</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inshorts.com/en/news/india-s-retail-inflation-eases-to-4-month-low-of-5-22--in-december-2024-1736773784715</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:44:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market crash: Investors lose ₹25 lakh crore in four days of slump - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock market crash: Investors lose ₹25 lakh crore in four days of slump</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/ANI-20230920248-0_1698062650494_1736777436195.jpg" alt="A share broker reacts as Sensex and Nifty prices plummet in Kolkata. (ANI/File Photo)"><figcaption>A share broker reacts as Sensex and Nifty prices plummet in Kolkata. (ANI/File Photo)</figcaption><p>Investments worth nearly ₹25 lakh crore in market valuation have been lost in the past four days of a severe drubbing in the equity market.</p><ul><li>The market capitalisation of BSE-listed firms dropped to ₹4,17,05,906.74 crore ($4.82 trillion), a fall of ₹24,69,243.3 crore.</li><li>On Monday alone, investors' wealth dropped ₹12.61 lakh crore.</li><li>Continued foreign institutional investor selling crossed ₹20,000 crore this month, contributing to negative sentiments.</li><li>The Indian rupee touched a fresh low against the dollar during the session.</li><li>Oil prices reached their highest level in over three months due to expanded US sanctions disrupting Russian crude supplies.</li><li>Over the previous four sessions, BSE Sensex has tanked 1,869.1 points (2.39%).</li><li>3,562 stocks declined, while 555 advanced and 131 remained unchanged on the BSE.</li><li>508 stocks registered their 52-week lows.</li></ul><blockquote>“Continued foreign institutional investor selling crossed ₹20,000 crore this month, contributing to the negative sentiments.” - Siddhartha Khemka, Head - Research, Wealth Management, Motilal Oswal Financial Services Ltd.</blockquote><p>This stock market slump highlights the growing concerns among investors and the impact of global economic factors on local markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/stock-market-crash-investors-lose-rs-25-lakh-crore-in-four-days-of-slump-101736777283739.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/stock-market-crash-investors-lose-rs-25-lakh-crore-in-four-days-of-slump-101736777283739.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:38:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hiremath claims a third of Baba Kalyani family fortune including Bharat Forge shares | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hiremath Claims a Third of Baba Kalyani Family Fortune Including Bharat Forge Shares</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>In a new development in the ongoing family feud, Sugandha Hiremath has filed a petition claiming a third of the Kalyani family assets, including a significant stake in Bharat Forge.</p><ul><li>Hiremath's petition was filed on 28 September in the Pune Civil Court.</li><li>She claims to have discovered an ancestral Kalyani Hindu Undivided Family (HUF) that owns the family's business assets.</li><li>The combined market capitalisation of Kalyani group companies exceeds ₹70,000 crore.</li><li>Hiremath’s previous suit in 2012 sought a share in the family HUF.</li><li>Both parties have made conflicting claims regarding agreements about Hikal shares.</li><li>The feud has turned complex, involving multiple legal proceedings regarding family asset distribution.</li></ul><blockquote>“Willful suppression of this letter of Mr. N. Vaghul by Mr. & Mrs. Hiremath is done with a sole intention to create false market in the securities of our Company...”</blockquote><p>The dispute highlights the intertwining of family and corporate governance, with significant implications for investor confidence and market transparency.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/hiremath-baba-kalyani-bharat-forge-hindu-undivided-family-icici-bank-supreme-court-legal-struggle-asahi-legal-11736777720545.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/hiremath-baba-kalyani-bharat-forge-hindu-undivided-family-icici-bank-supreme-court-legal-struggle-asahi-legal-11736777720545.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:34:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>