<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:22:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mutual fund SIP inflow at record high, but why is Nifty down 10% from peak? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxQZlduLS1sb1gyblQ4YVgwZEtVYVdhYXFWTWNmUmt1TDMxeWRhNkVxVDNPY0NUd1VoTjBHc1NEbkVXZEwtYXdZdmVhLTJoQ245eHZaV2Vfd3ZhOVBTZ2lKaFQ3bDdnSDQ5NUlkXzUyX2hmMml3ZzlTNHRrVUdiOVJLbUc1TWVVNVJGTFl0M2tFVzFiekRGWm1ybTBkdHNGVGxObmJGTTlsNloxOVdDTU9adW5NN3FlM05WdGpadFNqeTlTMVZ2ZGlZQVNfTGJJRkxOSkE0ZGFJTGlCVnNMaGZV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxQZlduLS1sb1gyblQ4YVgwZEtVYVdhYXFWTWNmUmt1TDMxeWRhNkVxVDNPY0NUd1VoTjBHc1NEbkVXZEwtYXdZdmVhLTJoQ245eHZaV2Vfd3ZhOVBTZ2lKaFQ3bDdnSDQ5NUlkXzUyX2hmMml3ZzlTNHRrVUdiOVJLbUc1TWVVNVJGTFl0M2tFVzFiekRGWm1ybTBkdHNGVGxObmJGTTlsNloxOVdDTU9adW5NN3FlM05WdGpadFNqeTlTMVZ2ZGlZQVNfTGJJRkxOSkE0ZGFJTGlCVnNMaGZV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infosys files counterclaim against Cognizant, accuses CEO Ravi Kumar of misusing sensitive information,... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Infosys Accuses Cognizant of Anticompetitive Practices in Counterclaim</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2022/10/INFY.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="The suit, filed in the Northern District of Texas, comes months after Cognizant’s subsidiary Cognizant TriZetto alleged that Infosys had stolen trade secrets related to its healthcare insurance software" title="The suit, filed in the Northern District of Texas, comes months after Cognizant’s subsidiary Cognizant TriZetto alleged that Infosys had stolen trade secrets related to its healthcare insurance software" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>The suit, filed in the Northern District of Texas, comes months after Cognizant’s subsidiary Cognizant TriZetto alleged that Infosys had stolen trade secrets related to its healthcare insurance software.</figcaption><p>India’s second largest software exporter, Infosys, has filed a counterclaim against Cognizant, alleging that the company indulged in anticompetitive tactics to hinder the growth of its healthcare platform, Infosys Helix.</p><ul><li>Infosys filed the counterclaim on January 10, 2025, in a US Court.</li><li>The lawsuit arises amid a backdrop of allegations from Cognizant’s subsidiary that Infosys stole trade secrets.</li><li>Infosys is requesting a jury trial and seeks to invalidate Cognizant’s Non-Disclosure Agreements.</li><li>The counterclaim includes a request for triple damages and attorney's fees.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will vigorously defend the lawsuit in court.”</blockquote><p>This counterclaim highlights the competitive tensions in the IT sector at a time of economic uncertainty.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/infosys-files-counterclaim-against-cognizant-accuses-ceo-ravi-kumar-of-misusing-sensitive-information-anticompetitive-practices-article-12907483.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/infosys-files-counterclaim-against-cognizant-accuses-ceo-ravi-kumar-of-misusing-sensitive-information-anticompetitive-practices-article-12907483.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:01:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tata Shocks Maruti Dzire & Honda Amaze With This New Feature! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tata Shocks Maruti Dzire & Honda Amaze With This New Feature!</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent updates<br><strong>Source:</strong> MotorOctane</p><figure><img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/ezgif.com-resize-5-2025-01-e9c8e8075bec55c4d7137d8bc507277a-900x506-1.jpg" alt="Affordable Tata Cars"><figcaption>Affordable Tata Cars</figcaption></figure><p>Tata recently announced updates to its most affordable cars, introducing new features that may challenge competitors like Maruti and Honda.</p><ul><li>The Tigor receives exterior design updates and interior tech enhancements.</li><li>New features on the Tigor include a 10.25-inch touchscreen, wireless connectivity, and a 360-degree camera.</li><li>The Tiago also benefits from similar updates but lacks some features like the 360-degree camera.</li><li>The price hike for the Tigor ranges from Rs 6.90 lakh to Rs 9.77 lakh, while the Tiago is priced between Rs 5.73 lakh and Rs 8.40 lakh.</li></ul><blockquote>"The new Tigor and Tiago are aimed at enhancing the value proposition for customers in the affordable segment."</blockquote><p>The enhancements in Tata's models demonstrate the brand's commitment to staying competitive in a crowded market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/281926-tata-shocks-maruti-dzire-honda-amaze-with-this-new-feature</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/281926-tata-shocks-maruti-dzire-honda-amaze-with-this-new-feature</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:40:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Four consultancies ask employees to go slow on work travel, use public transport - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Big Four consultancies ask employees to go slow on work travel, use public transport</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/01/Tech.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Consultancy Firms" title="Consultancy Firms" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>Deloitte, PWC, EY, and KPMG aim to cut costs and reduce carbon footprints.</figcaption>
<p>The Big Four consultancies have implemented measures to limit work-related travel, encouraging employees to utilize virtual meetings and public transportation to reduce costs and support sustainability goals.</p>
<ul>
<li>Employees are encouraged to minimize travel for client visits.</li>
<li>When travel is necessary, public transport is recommended.</li>
<li>These directives have been issued in the past few months in response to carbon footprint targets.</li>
<li>Recent client engagements have seen fewer employees traveling, advocating for remote coordination instead.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“But the firm took a view that it was sufficient for one partner to travel, and the rest could be coordinated online.”</blockquote>
<p>This move reflects the consultancies' commitment to environmental responsibility while balancing operational effectiveness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/big-four-consultancies-ask-employees-to-go-slow-on-work-travel-use-public-transport-12907407.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/big-four-consultancies-ask-employees-to-go-slow-on-work-travel-use-public-transport-12907407.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:23:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vodafone Increases Stake in Vi to 24.39 Percent After Completing Share Placing in Indus - TelecomTalk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vodafone Boosts Stake in Vi to 24.39% with Indus Towers Share Placing</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Telecom Talk</p><img src="https://telecomtalk.info/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/vodafone-completes-share-placing-in-indus-towers.jpg.webp" alt="Vodafone Completes Share Placing in Indus Towers" width="1200" height="800"><figcaption>Vodafone Completes Share Placing in Indus Towers</figcaption><p>Vodafone Group Plc announced it has increased its stake in Vodafone Idea Limited (Vi) following a financial transaction involving Indus Towers that secured Vodafone's obligations.</p><ul><li>Vodafone invested Rs 19.1 billion to raise its stake in Vi to 24.39 percent.</li><li>Rs 8.9 billion was allocated to repay borrowings and transaction fees.</li><li>The funds enabled Vi to settle its Master Service Agreement dues with Indus Towers.</li></ul><blockquote>"Vi have used the proceeds from this Capital Raise to pay outstanding Master Service Agreement (MSA) dues to Indus. Following this, Vodafone's obligations to Indus under the Security Arrangements have now been satisfied in full," Vodafone stated.</blockquote><p>This strategic move allows Vodafone to enhance its stake in the competitive telecom market while fulfilling financial commitments to Indus Towers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://telecomtalk.info/vodafone-increases-stake-in-vi-2439percent-indus/987711/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://telecomtalk.info/vodafone-increases-stake-in-vi-2439percent-indus/987711/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:38:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tata Steel, SAIL, Coal India among others hit 52-week low in weak market today, check full list - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tata Steel, SAIL, Coal India Among Stocks Hitting 52-Week Low in Weak Market</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Benchmark indices witnessed losses mainly in banks, energy, and FMCG stocks despite an initial rise, with IT stocks remaining resilient.</p><ul><li>Tata Elxsi Ltd hit a 52-week low of ₹5,921 after an 8% decline.</li><li>Tata Steel Ltd fell to ₹126.70, down 2.5%, marking a third consecutive session of decline.</li><li>Steel Authority of India Ltd (SAIL) dropped to ₹104.80, with concerns over entering a trading ban.</li><li>Coal India Ltd shares fell 2% to ₹364.70 amidst collaborations for critical minerals.</li><li>Additional stocks hitting 52-week lows include Bajaj Housing Finance, IRCTC, and Yes Bank among others.</li></ul><blockquote>“The cautious approach among investors is impacting market sentiment due to global economic uncertainties.”</blockquote><p>The downturn in the market is attributed to global factors and declining performances of major stocks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/tata-steel-sail-coal-india-among-others-hit-52-week-low-in-weak-market-today-check-full-list/article-139831/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/tata-steel-sail-coal-india-among-others-hit-52-week-low-in-weak-market-today-check-full-list/article-139831/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:35:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Defence stock Apollo Micro Systems declares preferential issue at ₹114 per share. Details here | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apollo Micro Systems Announces Preferential Issue at ₹114 per Share</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 09 January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Apollo Micro Systems has declared the issuance of a preferential issue at ₹114 per share to raise funds, aiming to increase its paid-up capital.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The company plans to raise its paid-up capital from ₹36 crores to ₹45 crores.</li>
  <li>Out of the additional ₹9 crores, ₹3.34 crores will be raised through preferential shares.</li>
  <li>The issuance will consist of up to 3,34,18,806 equity shares at a price of ₹114 each.</li>
  <li>The funds will be allocated to a select group of investors outside the promoter group.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Authorized capital of Apollo Micro Systems has been increased from ₹36 crores to ₹45 crores,” the company stated.</blockquote>
<p>This preferential issue signifies Apollo Micro Systems' efforts to enhance its financial standing and support future growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/apollo-micro-systems-share-price-crashes-over-5-despite-fundraise-move-11736490322402.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/apollo-micro-systems-share-price-crashes-over-5-despite-fundraise-move-11736490322402.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:19:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Market Live: Nifty, Sensex Flat As Surge In IT Stocks Offset Decline In Financials, Pharma, Energy - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Today: Sensex and Nifty End Week With 2% Decline</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg Quint</p>
<img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2025-01-10%2Fiwcsb42t%2FSENSEX-1.png?w=1200" alt="Stock Market Today: Sensex, Nifty End Week With 2% Decline; PSU Banks, Realty, Drag While IT Bucks Trend">
<figcaption>Intraday, Nifty fell 0.77% and Sensex declined 0.67%</figcaption>
<p>Indian equities saw gains and losses but closed lower for the second consecutive session as financial, pharma, and energy stocks weighed. Gains in information technology stocks helped offset the wider decline. The NSE Nifty 50 ended 95 points or 0.4% lower, while the BSE Sensex lost 241.3 points or 0.31%.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nifty declined as much as 0.78% to an intraday low of 23,503.</li>
<li>Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) was the top gainer on the Nifty, rising 5.6% after impressive earnings.</li>
<li>PSU banks and overall broader markets underperformed.</li>
<li>The US futures declined leading into jobs data.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>The rupee weakened to a record low of 85.95 against the US dollar, indicating ongoing concerns about currency stability.</p></blockquote>
<p>This week's performance shows a significant decline in broader indices, indicating a trend that investors should keep an eye on.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/stock-market-live-updates-nse-nifty-50-bse-sensex-nifty-bank-gift-nifty-trading-levels-10-01-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/stock-market-live-updates-nse-nifty-50-bse-sensex-nifty-bank-gift-nifty-trading-levels-10-01-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:03:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IREDA Profit Soars, Shares Dip - Indiainfoline]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMif0FVX3lxTFByMXFicFdHYUNReFhrSVRPV0hFaS1NYnNGb2tFQnJOU1JKbnRNSl8yZGFpQWV4R0dZdmxySzg2OFgxTkZZWU5UR3BYb3NVR2V5dnJrcDlmTnZRTnlsLUo0U3hsTVBYY0JjbXZNNnk3dDJMT05iSDBCR3ZTUkRIa00?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMif0FVX3lxTFByMXFicFdHYUNReFhrSVRPV0hFaS1NYnNGb2tFQnJOU1JKbnRNSl8yZGFpQWV4R0dZdmxySzg2OFgxTkZZWU5UR3BYb3NVR2V5dnJrcDlmTnZRTnlsLUo0U3hsTVBYY0JjbXZNNnk3dDJMT05iSDBCR3ZTUkRIa00?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Decoding India’s growth slowdown - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Decoding India’s growth slowdown</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 10, 2025 08:30 am IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/2n1g11/article69082175.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/Chart%201%203.jpg" alt="Economic Chart" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Chart 1: Volatility of WPI over the past decade.</figcaption><p>The first advance estimate of India’s GDP for 2024-25 reveals a decline in real GDP growth rate to 6.4% from 8.2% in 2023-24, which challenges previous projections. Concerns are raised regarding potential underestimation of the GDP growth rate as discrepancies in data collection methods are highlighted.</p><ul><li>India's GDP growth rate projected to decline significantly in 2024-25.</li><li>Concerns about the reliability of official GDP estimates due to data collection issues.</li><li>Private sector investment is not responding positively to government tax cuts, affecting overall economic growth.</li><li>Public spending remains crucial in sustaining economic growth amidst a slowdown.</li><li>The economic slowdown risks disrupting the Union Budget's fiscal targets.</li></ul><blockquote>“A reworking of the revenue mobilisation strategy is required to enhance capex and welfare spending.”</blockquote><p>The analysis indicates the need for structural changes and improved data reliability to accurately reflect the economic landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/business/Economy/decoding-indias-growth-slowdown/article69080910.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/business/Economy/decoding-indias-growth-slowdown/article69080910.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SC stays GST show cause notices to online gaming companies; Delta Corp, Nazara Tech shares surge up to 7% - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SC stays GST show cause notices to online gaming companies; Delta Corp, Nazara Tech shares surge up to 7%</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250110063353_online-gaming.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="SC stays GST show cause notices to online gaming companies; Delta Corp, Nazara Tech shares surge up to 7%" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>SC stays GST show cause notices to online gaming companies; Delta Corp, Nazara Tech shares surge up to 7%</figcaption>
<p>The Supreme Court has stayed the GST show cause notices amounting to Rs 1.12 lakh crore to online gaming companies, causing shares of Delta Corp and Nazara Tech to surge.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Supreme Court stayed all proceedings until the case is resolved, with a final hearing scheduled for March 18.</li>
  <li>Delta Corp shares rose over 4% while Nazara Tech shares saw a modest decline.</li>
  <li>The apex court's decision halts significant financial pressures on the online gaming sector.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“All further proceedings shall remain stayed till the case is decided,” said the apex court.</blockquote>
<p>This ruling is significant for the online gaming industry and could shape future regulations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/delta-corp-nazara-shares-surge-up-to-7-amid-sc-stays-gst-show-cause-notices-to-online-gaming-companies-12907302.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/delta-corp-nazara-shares-surge-up-to-7-amid-sc-stays-gst-show-cause-notices-to-online-gaming-companies-12907302.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:25:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delta Corp, Nazara Tech shares surge over 15% after big relief from Supreme Court - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delta Corp, Nazara Tech shares surge over 15% after big relief from Supreme Court</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="Delta Corp, Nazara Tech shares surge over 15% after big relief from Supreme Court" title="Delta Corp, Nazara Tech shares surge over 15% after big relief from Supreme Court" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Delta Corp and Nazara Tech stocks responded positively to the Supreme Court's ruling.</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court provided relief to online gaming companies by staying GST show cause notices worth ₹1.12 lakh crore, resulting in a significant uptick in stock prices for Delta Corp and Nazara Tech.</p><ul><li>Delta Corp shares surged by 14%, while Nazara Tech shares increased by 7% after the news broke.</li><li>The stock gains were fueled by concerns over possible coercive actions by tax authorities.</li><li>The court ruling has stayed all further proceedings under the challenged GST notices until a final decision is made.</li><li>The larger tax demand from the DGGI against 71 gaming companies could total ₹2.3 lakh crore including penalties.</li><li>Shares cooled off from initial highs, with Delta Corp trading 4.5% higher later in the day.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Supreme Court has directed that all further proceedings under the show cause notice will remain stayed till the case is finally decided."</blockquote><p>The court's intervention indicates ongoing legal challenges within the gaming industry, highlighting the significance of regulatory clarity for market participants.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/delta-corp-nazara-tech-share-price-supreme-court-gst-relief-timeline-online-gaming-new-date-reaction-19537869.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/delta-corp-nazara-tech-share-price-supreme-court-gst-relief-timeline-online-gaming-new-date-reaction-19537869.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:21:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Market Live: Nifty, Sensex Rise As TCS, Infosys Share Prices Lead; Nifty IT Surges 3% - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Live: Nifty, Sensex Flat As Surge In IT Stocks Offset Decline In Financials, Pharma, Energy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Profit</p><figure><img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2023-07%2F04ff454a-e4d3-4e92-8e14-9ca73183de34%2FA_bronze_bull_statue_stands_at_the_entrance_to_the_Bombay_Stock_Exchange_building_in_Mumbai____Sourc.jpg?rect=0%2C193%2C4032%2C2268&amp;w=1200" alt="Bronze bull statue at the Bombay Stock Exchange" /><figcaption>Sensex is around 77,600 level. A bronze bull statue stands at the entrance to the BSE building in Mumbai. (Source: Vijay Sartape / NDTV Profit)</figcaption></figure><p>Both the Nifty 50 and Sensex recovered from day's low to trade flat. A surge in IT stocks made up for losses in financials, pharma, and auto.</p><h2>Key Highlights</h2><ul><li>Sensex and Nifty displayed flat trading.</li><li>Recovery aided by IT sector performance.</li><li>Financials, pharma, and auto sectors experienced declines.</li><li>Union Bank's shares hit a 52-week low.</li><li>Syrma SGS Technologies secured a deal to manufacture laptops for MSI.</li></ul><blockquote>"IT stocks are proving resilient amidst declines in other sectors."</blockquote><p>The market's flat performance indicates a mixed sentiment, driven largely by the fluctuation in IT stocks countering losses in other industries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/stock-market-live-updates-nse-nifty-50-bse-sensex-nifty-bank-gift-nifty-trading-levels-10-01-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/stock-market-live-updates-nse-nifty-50-bse-sensex-nifty-bank-gift-nifty-trading-levels-10-01-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:06:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Enough To Devastate Every U.S Navy Warship At Norfolk”: China’s “Shadow Fleet” Raises Alarm In Washington - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's 'Shadow Fleet' Raises Alarm in Washington</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> EurAsian Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Su-57-1290-x-650-px-11.png" alt="Cosco Shipping" width="1290" height="650"><figcaption>Cosco Shipping. Image Credits Cosco shipping. Edited Image.</figcaption></figure><p>The U.S. has blacklisted China's largest shipping company, Cosco Shipping Holdings Co., along with major shipbuilders for their alleged ties to the People’s Liberation Army (PLA), escalating geopolitical tensions.</p><ul><li>Cosco Shipping is now listed on the U.S. Federal Register blacklist.</li><li>This blacklisting extends to major players in tech and energy sectors in China.</li><li>Past sanctions on Cosco included penalties for transporting Iranian oil.</li><li>The blacklisting serves as a deterrent to U.S. businesses from engaging with these companies.</li><li>Concerns are raised about China’s use of merchant ships to support military operations, namely the civil-military fusion strategy.</li><li>A notable incident involved the COSCO Sakura ship docking near the Norfolk Naval Station.</li><li>Experts warn about the potential of using commercial vessels for military logistics.</li><li>China's maritime militia strategy is drawing significant attention and concern.</li></ul><blockquote>“If only, say, 10% of those containers were used for munitions, they could, for example, field 144 cruise missiles and 252 quadcopters, more than enough to devastate every warship at Norfolk...” - Thomas Shugart</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the implications of China's military shipping strategies and the ongoing U.S.-China maritime competition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/chinas-shadow-fleet-on-us-radar-inside/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/chinas-shadow-fleet-on-us-radar-inside/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:33:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Bucks: L&T Chairman SN Subrahmanyan who wants 90-hr workweek earns ₹51cr—whopping 535x more than average employee! | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>L&T Chairman SN Subrahmanyan Earns ₹51 Crore, Advocates 90-Hour Workweek</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 9, 2025&nbsp;|&nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Larsen & Toubro (L&T) Chairman SN Subrahmanyan is under scrutiny for advocating a 90-hour workweek while earning ₹51 crore a year, 535 times more than the average employee salary.</p><ul><li>Subrahmanyan's total earnings for 2023-24 include a base salary of ₹3.6 crore, perks worth ₹1.67 crore, commission of ₹35.28 crore, and retirement benefits of ₹10.5 crore.</li><li>The median salary of L&T employees is ₹9.55 lakh.</li><li>L&T issued a clarification on Subrahmanyan’s statement, stating it reflected a vision for extraordinary outcomes through hard work.</li><li>Public reactions highlight concerns over work-life balance and the high demands of such work expectations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Let your young employees enjoy family life. Family life and leisure time is as important as work life and money.” — Dr. Poornima</blockquote><p>L&T's remarks indicate a commitment to national progress while raising questions about employee welfare amidst high executive compensation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/big-bucks-l-t-chairman-sn-subrahmanyan-wants-90-hour-workweek-earns-rs-51-crore-whopping-535x-more-than-average-employee-11736485319752.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/big-bucks-l-t-chairman-sn-subrahmanyan-wants-90-hour-workweek-earns-rs-51-crore-whopping-535x-more-than-average-employee-11736485319752.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:17:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kalyan Jewellers shares decline for sixth consecutive day - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kalyan Jewellers Shares Decline for Sixth Consecutive Day</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2023/02/Kalyan-Jewellers.png?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Kalyan Jewellers" title="Kalyan Jewellers"><figcaption>Kalyan Jewellers shares continue to fall</figcaption><p>Kalyan Jewellers India Ltd. shares have fallen for the sixth consecutive day, with a decline of 3.34 percent on January 10, trading at Rs 651.45. The company recently announced a potential net revenue growth of 39% for Q3 FY25.</p><ul><li>Shares fell 3.34% on January 10.</li><li>Current trading price: Rs 651.45.</li><li>Net revenue expected to grow by 39%.</li><li>India business surge reported at 41% due to festive and wedding demand.</li><li>Same-store-sales growth recorded at 24%.</li><li>24 new Kalyan showrooms were launched in the previous quarter.</li><li>Plans to open 30 more Kalyan showrooms and 15 Candere showrooms this quarter.</li></ul><blockquote>“The quarter also witnessed growth in same-store-sales, close to 24 percent.”</blockquote><p>The ongoing decline in share prices prompts a closer look at the company's performance amidst strong revenue growth projections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/stocks/kalyan-jewellers-shares-extend-fall-on-fifth-day-12906328.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/stocks/kalyan-jewellers-shares-extend-fall-on-fifth-day-12906328.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IREDA Q3FY25 net profit jumps 27% YoY to ₹425 crore; shares trade lower - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IREDA Q3FY25 net profit jumps 27% YoY to ₹425 crore; shares trade lower</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>IREDA has reported a significant increase in net profit and revenue from operations for the third quarter of FY25, indicating strong growth in the renewable energy sector.</p><ul><li>Revenue from operations rose 36% YoY to ₹1,698 crore.</li><li>Net profit jumped 27% YoY to ₹426 crore.</li><li>Non-fossil fuel capacity increased to 200 GW, aiming for 500 GW by 2030.</li><li>Operating income increased by 51% YoY to ₹652 crore.</li><li>GNPA improved to 2.68% from 2.90% YoY.</li><li>Loan book expanded to ₹68,960 crore from ₹50,580 crore YoY.</li><li>Shares recorded nearly 5% negative returns for Q3FY25, although they more than doubled in 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>"The renewable energy sector witnessed strong growth..."</blockquote><p>The results reflect IREDA's strong performance amidst challenges in share prices, showcasing the resilience of the renewable energy sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/ireda-q3-fy-25-net-profit-jumps-27-yo-y-to-425-crore-shares-trade-lower/article-139807/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/ireda-q3-fy-25-net-profit-jumps-27-yo-y-to-425-crore-shares-trade-lower/article-139807/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:07:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tata Tiago, Tiago EV And Tigor Variant And Features Rejigged, Prices Hiked By Up To Rs 30,000 - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tata Updates Tiago, Tiago EV, and Tigor with New Features and Pricing</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> CarDekho.com</p><img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/6780b0d894667.jpg" alt="Model year updates introduced to Tata Tiago, Tiago EV and Tigor"><figcaption>Model year updates introduced to Tata Tiago, Tiago EV and Tigor</figcaption><p>Tata Motors has introduced model year updates for its entry-level models, Tiago, Tiago EV, and Tigor, enhancing their features and adjusting pricing.</p><ul><li>Tata Tiago receives a bigger 10.25-inch touchscreen and updated driver’s display.</li><li>New variants and pricing adjustments have been made across the models.</li><li>Feature upgrades include wireless Android Auto, Apple CarPlay, and LED headlights.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tata has yet to disclose the revised prices of the AMT variants.”</blockquote><p>The updated Tata models aim to provide modern features while competing effectively in the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/tata-tiago-tiago-ev-and-tigor-variant-and-features-rejigged-prices-hiked-by-up-to-rs-30000-33801.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/tata-tiago-tiago-ev-and-tigor-variant-and-features-rejigged-prices-hiked-by-up-to-rs-30000-33801.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani Wilmar shares crash 9% as promoter looks to sell up to 20% stake via OFS - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxPaDhSSThYZVdtYVQxNmN5WEZYUmxELXlBdG9uQnAweXRCMkUtRm5uZkotYlB1V3QtRzFGRWJuazlWZFNLNW1EOHI4c01wZEpnS1JVdVZWcVdJMHlRdXFfd3FaX2Z0Rm9aZHppM2UxVHFBcXJIMl9vd2VuZldhVnFnYi1oYXJrQWZYcWlkQ2QxdmtBcjVJTXZpb1BXc1BON3Rkd3BGbXdhaFh4T3lsRDV6ZHh1c1BydVJQOTJtZXFZSjkyOEppNENkVF9WMWJkdTVYaUZDWV9OSHXSAd4BQVVfeXFMUHRpaVdpbjJVTjZ5X0ppT3NoQlU5d3BzVWpEZFdhXzZicUMwaWc1OXRMbzJLOENWMTRJaGs1YXAzanI4bUFTM1FfZk1MSHl4SG5SQjBERFczd3RVYUtuMGhlY3BNOXZJRmpseDA1M281TDNLMFpzVTdVNW1YcDFyOHd5WkZodFItZUNRZDZxbnhiWnZ6STlaVDlyS1g2X2pqLTB4NkJ4Tm9NZDlnSE9QYXFXNnViaDhXWkxjeEpVNGs4WkdxLUJadkZmSXhiTkpNSEJlUmZqOFlDM1dIenJR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxPaDhSSThYZVdtYVQxNmN5WEZYUmxELXlBdG9uQnAweXRCMkUtRm5uZkotYlB1V3QtRzFGRWJuazlWZFNLNW1EOHI4c01wZEpnS1JVdVZWcVdJMHlRdXFfd3FaX2Z0Rm9aZHppM2UxVHFBcXJIMl9vd2VuZldhVnFnYi1oYXJrQWZYcWlkQ2QxdmtBcjVJTXZpb1BXc1BON3Rkd3BGbXdhaFh4T3lsRDV6ZHh1c1BydVJQOTJtZXFZSjkyOEppNENkVF9WMWJkdTVYaUZDWV9OSHXSAd4BQVVfeXFMUHRpaVdpbjJVTjZ5X0ppT3NoQlU5d3BzVWpEZFdhXzZicUMwaWc1OXRMbzJLOENWMTRJaGs1YXAzanI4bUFTM1FfZk1MSHl4SG5SQjBERFczd3RVYUtuMGhlY3BNOXZJRmpseDA1M281TDNLMFpzVTdVNW1YcDFyOHd5WkZodFItZUNRZDZxbnhiWnZ6STlaVDlyS1g2X2pqLTB4NkJ4Tm9NZDlnSE9QYXFXNnViaDhXWkxjeEpVNGs4WkdxLUJadkZmSXhiTkpNSEJlUmZqOFlDM1dIenJR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 04:54:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani Wilmar shares slide 9% as promoter looks to divest 20% stake via OFS | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Adani Wilmar Shares Drop 9% as Promoter Plans to Divest 20% Stake</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><img src="" alt=""/><p>Adani Wilmar's shares plummeted by 9.5% following the announcement of a plan by its promoter to divest up to 20% stake through an Offer For Sale (OFS).</p><ul><li>The promoter, Adani Commodities LLP, will sell up to 17,54,56,612 equity shares, representing 13.5% of the company's total equity.</li><li>The OFS begins for non-retail investors on January 10 and for retail investors on January 13.</li><li>Adani Enterprises plans to exit its joint venture stake in Adani Wilmar, affecting the company's shareholding structure.</li><li>The company's revenue saw a 33% YoY increase in Q3 FY25, despite challenges in the market.</li></ul><blockquote>“The value of Adani Enterprises' current stake in Adani Wilmar is estimated at ₹18,500 crore, equivalent to over $2 billion.”</blockquote><p>The stock's decline and the ongoing divestment plan highlight significant market shifts and challenges ahead for Adani Wilmar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/adani-wilmar-shares-slide-9-as-promoter-looks-to-divest-20-stake-via-ofs-11736481107846.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/adani-wilmar-shares-slide-9-as-promoter-looks-to-divest-20-stake-via-ofs-11736481107846.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 04:31:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bears grip D-Street! Sensex extends decline to 3rd day, Nifty below 23,400; broader markets fall 2% - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxPRmRURTBOdURTcVkxRGZQZ0hhRFBDLWExNmJjS0g1eGN4WkttVnZfOERmbGNvdUFESGp4azY1cU5jdXNla1J1eFJnS2d2TDhnZ1FZTDVZcUNrMU5iZDA1OFRDSzB5MkNmRktHOWtZZ3pQS3Juel8tY1l0N1FwT0NkdGtBREs4T0ZPVkFRVUNtbWhGYnhILTNYdW92US1WUGZoTnlicnVDeHozbkZxa1ZJOEtQUTJ6WjFGdUZ5M0tGVzJqY2lETEpzbkVTSThnLWtTdEdLeDRRWjFXTnRPUG5FbXk0dTNWUVBqOVBZbEpyWVNWTnA10gH6AUFVX3lxTE5telVyUFRyMEVSX1hwMjd0TTg5UHU0aFJLYk5MRElWeTVzN3VjV0laUDVoWFpmVzdRMnVUYnViVVdQQWFhSU9lMXJGRXFNeTIxX1I2Mk1QZE43ZVZUNGR0YVFBUDg4Y1VkZDh6SjAxNlBoQVNsTm5XT2NRdzhaNlBFbVE4aVJKb1BMTmx6RTM3aWNtR3ltNS1QRUdQeGRFVGgwalJ1YnVDZkZFVGtUUmxkbEc4aGo5bXZoZ0x4R2lTbXhnejVNVFZvYl9QWk1JeEpsOXVRVHQxS2pESE1MRmZrNXNaLWM4SFNkZ3dKOHl0dVNiV2hOR05lZHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxPRmRURTBOdURTcVkxRGZQZ0hhRFBDLWExNmJjS0g1eGN4WkttVnZfOERmbGNvdUFESGp4azY1cU5jdXNla1J1eFJnS2d2TDhnZ1FZTDVZcUNrMU5iZDA1OFRDSzB5MkNmRktHOWtZZ3pQS3Juel8tY1l0N1FwT0NkdGtBREs4T0ZPVkFRVUNtbWhGYnhILTNYdW92US1WUGZoTnlicnVDeHozbkZxa1ZJOEtQUTJ6WjFGdUZ5M0tGVzJqY2lETEpzbkVTSThnLWtTdEdLeDRRWjFXTnRPUG5FbXk0dTNWUVBqOVBZbEpyWVNWTnA10gH6AUFVX3lxTE5telVyUFRyMEVSX1hwMjd0TTg5UHU0aFJLYk5MRElWeTVzN3VjV0laUDVoWFpmVzdRMnVUYnViVVdQQWFhSU9lMXJGRXFNeTIxX1I2Mk1QZE43ZVZUNGR0YVFBUDg4Y1VkZDh6SjAxNlBoQVNsTm5XT2NRdzhaNlBFbVE4aVJKb1BMTmx6RTM3aWNtR3ltNS1QRUdQeGRFVGgwalJ1YnVDZkZFVGtUUmxkbEc4aGo5bXZoZ0x4R2lTbXhnejVNVFZvYl9QWk1JeEpsOXVRVHQxS2pESE1MRmZrNXNaLWM4SFNkZ3dKOHl0dVNiV2hOR05lZHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 04:16:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Market Live: Nifty Enters Correction Zone; Nifty IT Surges 2% After TCS Q3 Result - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Live: Nifty In Correction Zone; Nifty IT Bucks Trend To Surge 2%, PSU Banks Under Pressure</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2024-01%2Fd723f55b-de7a-40cc-a5e5-8fe94c753fb1%2FNSE_Vijay_Sartape_1.jfif?rect=0%2C0%2C3353%2C1886&amp;w=1200" alt="The Nifty 50 is down nearly 0.5%. (Photographer: Vijay Sartape/NDTV Profit)" /><figcaption>The Nifty 50 is down nearly 0.5%. (Photographer: Vijay Sartape/NDTV Profit)</figcaption><p>Nifty has fallen into a correction zone, indicating a decline of over 10% from its 52-week high, as Sensex decreases by 0.4%.</p><ul><li>Nifty faces challenges as it drops to correction levels, raising concerns for investors.</li><li>Nifty IT sector shows resilience with a 2% increase amid broader market declines.</li><li>Pressure on PSU banks is evident, with significant drop in stock prices among major players.</li></ul><blockquote>"The market is currently experiencing significant volatility, which may lead to a reevaluation of investment strategies among traders."</blockquote><p>This market phase highlights the tension between sector performance, particularly the strength of IT stocks compared to the broader market instabilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/stock-market-live-updates-nse-nifty-50-bse-sensex-nifty-bank-gift-nifty-trading-levels-10-01-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/stock-market-live-updates-nse-nifty-50-bse-sensex-nifty-bank-gift-nifty-trading-levels-10-01-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 04:12:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TCS share price soars over 6% on robust Q3 results, $10.2 billion order book and dividend announcement - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>TCS Shares Surge Over 6% Following Strong Q3 Results and Dividend Announcement</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p>
<p>TCS share price experienced a significant increase after the announcement of its Q3 results and dividends, reflecting strong financial performance and a healthy order book.</p>
<ul>
  <li>TCS share price rose by 6.28% to ₹4,292.65 on the NSE.</li>
  <li>The company's market capitalization is ₹15,48,830.90 crore.</li>
  <li>Q3 net profit reached ₹12,380 crore, an increase of 11.95% YoY.</li>
  <li>Revenue from operations was ₹63,973 crore, a 5.59% increase YoY.</li>
  <li>New order bookings amounted to USD 10.2 billion.</li>
  <li>The company announced a dividend of ₹76 per equity share.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We are pleased with the excellent TCV performance in Q3 which was well-rounded across industries, geographies and service lines lending good visibility to long-term growth," K Krithivasan, CEO of TCS.</blockquote>
<p>The IT services sector is showing signs of recovery, with positive indications in various verticals, and TCS's strong performance contributes to a favorable outlook.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/tcs-share-price-soars-over-4-on-robust-q3-results-10-2-billion-order-book-and-dividend-announcement/article-139803/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/tcs-share-price-soars-over-4-on-robust-q3-results-10-2-billion-order-book-and-dividend-announcement/article-139803/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 04:08:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FIIs begin 2025 with $2 billion selloff in 7 days. 6 reasons driving the exodus - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FIIs Begin 2025 with $2 Billion Selloff in 7 Days: 6 Reasons Driving the Exodus</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ETMarkets.com</p>
<img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-117104362,width-650,height-488,imgsize-2163039,resizemode-75/.jpg" alt="Foreign Institutional Investors Selloff" />
<figcaption>Foreign Institutional Investors Bring in Selloff amid Various Economic Concerns</figcaption>
<p>Foreign institutional investors (FIIs) have sold nearly $2 billion worth of Indian stocks in the first seven trading days of 2025 due to multiple factors impacting market confidence.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Earnings Downgrades:</strong> India Inc is facing downgrades in earnings after years of robust growth.</li>
  <li><strong>Weaker Macroeconomics:</strong> The Indian GDP growth is projected to slow down significantly.</li>
  <li><strong>Record Low Rupee:</strong> The Indian rupee is at a lifetime low against the dollar, affecting FII confidence.</li>
  <li><strong>US Bond Yields:</strong> Rising US Treasury yields are diverting investments from India.</li>
  <li><strong>Tariff Fears:</strong> Uncertainty about US trade policies post-Trump's inauguration is causing apprehensions.</li>
  <li><strong>Competition from the US Market:</strong> The dominance of the US market is attracting global capital away from emerging markets.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>This will have many ramifications for consumer and business confidence, wage growth, corporate revenues, consumption, investment, credit demand and, most importantly, the fiscal arithmetic. - Rahul Bajoria, BofA Securities India</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the substantial selloff reflects concerns among foreign investors about the Indian market's immediate prospects and macroeconomic stability amidst global uncertainties.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/fiis-begin-2025-with-2-billion-selloff-in-7-days-6-reasons-driving-the-exodus/articleshow/117104362.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/fiis-begin-2025-with-2-billion-selloff-in-7-days-6-reasons-driving-the-exodus/articleshow/117104362.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 04:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Industries share selling is 'overdone', says Goldman Sachs, sees 27% upside - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/reliance-industries-share-price-selling-overdone-says-goldman-sachs-target-ebitda-jio-retail-outlook-19537701.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/reliance-industries-share-price-selling-overdone-says-goldman-sachs-target-ebitda-jio-retail-outlook-19537701.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 03:33:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Industries share selling is 'overdone', says Goldman Sachs, sees 27% upside - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/reliance-industries-share-price-selling-overdone-says-goldman-sachs-target-ebitda-jio-retail-outlook-19537701.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/reliance-industries-share-price-selling-overdone-says-goldman-sachs-target-ebitda-jio-retail-outlook-19537701.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 03:33:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tata Elxsi shares fall 8% after Street expects shares to continue underperforming - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tata Elxsi shares fall 8% after Street expects shares to continue underperforming</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Tata Elxsi shares fall 8%" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Tata Elxsi shares fall 8% after Street expects shares to continue underperforming.</figcaption><p>Shares of Tata Elxsi Ltd. declined by 8% following disappointing quarterly results and lower price targets set by analysts.</p><ul><li>Tata Elxsi's December quarter results fell short of expectations due to a slowdown in communications and automotive segments.</li><li>The company reported a 13% decline in net profit quarter-on-quarter, totaling ₹199 crore.</li><li>Revenue decreased by 1.7% QoQ to ₹939 crore, with significant drops in the media and communications unit.</li><li>Morgan Stanley and JP Morgan have both downgraded their ratings and price targets for the stock.</li><li>Shares have dropped over 25% in the last year, reflecting ongoing challenges in the market.</li></ul><blockquote>Morgan Stanley noted, "Tata Elxsi's Q3 results missed expectations. Weakness in European transportation continues, and a significant recovery in media and healthcare remains elusive."</blockquote><p>The continued decline in share prices indicates challenges within Tata Elxsi's business segments and a cautious outlook from analysts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/tata-elxsi-share-price-may-continue-to-underperform-says-this-analyst-post-q3-results-19537690.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/tata-elxsi-share-price-may-continue-to-underperform-says-this-analyst-post-q3-results-19537690.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 03:23:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Q3 results today: Just Dial, PCBL, GNA Axles, Equinox India, others to announce earnings on January 10; check list - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Q3 Results 2023: Companies Announcing Earnings Today</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Upstox</p><p>Today, 15 companies, including Just Dial, PCBL, and GNA Axles, will announce their financial results for Q3 2023.</p><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Image of financial report' /><figcaption>Financial report image</figcaption><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Companies reporting include: Just Dial, PCBL, GNA Axles, Equinox India, and others.</li><li>Tata Consultancy Services reported an 11.95% increase in Q3 FY25 profits.</li><li>Q3 results encompass the period of October to December 2023.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are pleased with the excellent TCV performance in Q3 which was well-rounded across industries...” - K Krithivasan, CEO of TCS</blockquote><p>Overall, the earnings announcements today will provide insights into various sectors and their financial health amid ongoing economic fluctuations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/earnings/q3-results-just-dial-pcbl-gna-axles-equinox-india-others-to-announce-earnings-on-january-10-2025-check-list/article-139796/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/earnings/q3-results-just-dial-pcbl-gna-axles-equinox-india-others-to-announce-earnings-on-january-10-2025-check-list/article-139796/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 02:57:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fastest growing and declining job roles by 2030 as per WEF, all you need to know - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fastest Growing and Declining Job Roles by 2030 as per WEF</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 10, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/ant-rozetsky-HXOllTSwrpM-unsplash_1661928374899_1736338930657.jpg' alt='The Future of Jobs Report 2025' title='The Future of Jobs Report 2025'><figcaption>The Future of Jobs Report 2025 brings together the perspective of over 1,000 leading global employers(Photo by Ant Rozetsky on Unsplash)</figcaption><p>The World Economic Forum (WEF) has released the Future of Jobs Report 2025, highlighting significant changes in the global labor market by 2030.</p><ul><li>170 million new jobs will be created, with 92 million jobs displaced, leading to a net increase of 78 million jobs.</li><li>Big data specialists, FinTech engineers, and AI & machine learning specialists are predicted to be the fastest growing job roles.</li><li>The fastest declining roles include postal service clerks, bank tellers, and data entry clerks, primarily driven by technological advancements.</li><li>Farmworkers are expected to see a major increase, with 35 million more jobs anticipated by 2030 due to green transition trends.</li></ul><blockquote>“Farmworkers top the list of the largest growing job roles in the next five years…”</blockquote><p>The report emphasizes the necessity of adapting to changing job landscapes and preparing for future opportunities in the workforce.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/education/features/fastest-growing-and-declining-job-roles-by-2030-as-per-wef-all-you-need-to-know-101736337094261.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/education/features/fastest-growing-and-declining-job-roles-by-2030-as-per-wef-all-you-need-to-know-101736337094261.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 02:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahindra XEV 9e And BE 6 Top-end Pack 3 Variant To Be Available With A Much More Affordable Price Tag - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahindra XEV 9e And BE 6 Top-end Pack 3 Variant To Be Available With Smaller 59 kWh Battery Pack Too</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Recent<br><strong>Source: </strong>CarDekho.com</p>
<img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/677fc5d6b4f9b.jpg" alt="Mahindra BE6 and XEV 9e">
<figcaption>Mahindra BE6 and XEV 9e</figcaption>
<p>Mahindra confirms that the top-end variants of the BE 6 and XEV 9e will now also be available with a smaller 59 kWh battery pack, making them more affordable.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The BE 6 and XEV 9e are the first products under Mahindra’s new EV sub-brands.</li>
  <li>Both models will be offered with 59 kWh and 79 kWh battery packs, claiming ranges over 600 km.</li>
  <li>Notable features include multi-zone AC, panoramic sunroof, and ADAS.</li>
  <li>Current prices for the top-end variants with the larger 79 kWh pack are Rs 30.5 lakh for XEV 9e and Rs 26.9 lakh for BE 6.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Powertrain Options</h2>
<p>Specifications reveal the two battery packs available, with different power outputs for both models. The smaller battery option is expected to offer a more economical choice.</p>
<blockquote>"The battery packs support fast charging capabilities with speeds up to 175 kW, allowing you to top up from 20 to 80 percent in just 20 minutes."</blockquote>
<p>With the addition of the smaller battery pack option, Mahindra aims to broaden its customer base for its electric vehicles, making them accessible at a lower price point.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/mahindra-xev-9e-and-be-6-topend-pack-3-variant-to-be-available-with-a-much-more-affordable-price-tag-33809.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/mahindra-xev-9e-and-be-6-topend-pack-3-variant-to-be-available-with-a-much-more-affordable-price-tag-33809.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 02:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>