<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 04:23:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 04:23:50 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A.P. to get ₹14,000-crore semiconductor manufacturing facility in Orvakal Mega Industrial Hub - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxNX3VYUWhXdDhneXBWNlFreElWUHQ0TEFRM1djTjE5ODRNT3RyX2xNNkpuZEg2eFhiV2tjMVM0bHJvcDNGZkNWUUYyRW1pOEw5d0RuUW5id3Q5VUEyTTQ3S2tmTUY2ZU1SMjVRMEpoamlJZ0s5dG1QOEU4QTBWRVZmNGRlSlRsMWNUVWwxT2RzekFrckk4NHN3T2ZwSEUxcHJRc1pibFdsWVRpcGhra0RibnFUd01xa1U0SG5oaG1zc0VYVTJsRGphNWdfdDE0Um1CdFZkSTdrWGF4MFVESmRENk92ZllMVVZBV1JfRjhlV0NDM0JMSEHSAfwBQVVfeXFMUGZwNnp5a3FURTFrU3VXWl9Ya3VfaVdDOHc5OGlabXJsNUlXQWJ6VDdrUkN3WmVKSTFjcjh3aUdTcFRjTlhmcWs1U3VhVzZhakNPNEZndUM1OEUtSWxqdDEtdG0zYkNhQXFBZU9tUU1fNVNuRl9HMXdqU191T0w1TFZ1bUM5X2xwSkh0VDRSSUJadV96ZmhzbTF6dy1vandGbG42Yjlpa1B1aGlkSVlZVFVUMzZacHpFemE2Ui1XaWJ1eElWU3lGMlQ1SzRVbU9TcG85ZHNwZEFRSnVQMXc4QWplWEFTRG02OXNHVlYzV2hqQnhXS1AyMEptMXJu?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxNX3VYUWhXdDhneXBWNlFreElWUHQ0TEFRM1djTjE5ODRNT3RyX2xNNkpuZEg2eFhiV2tjMVM0bHJvcDNGZkNWUUYyRW1pOEw5d0RuUW5id3Q5VUEyTTQ3S2tmTUY2ZU1SMjVRMEpoamlJZ0s5dG1QOEU4QTBWRVZmNGRlSlRsMWNUVWwxT2RzekFrckk4NHN3T2ZwSEUxcHJRc1pibFdsWVRpcGhra0RibnFUd01xa1U0SG5oaG1zc0VYVTJsRGphNWdfdDE0Um1CdFZkSTdrWGF4MFVESmRENk92ZllMVVZBV1JfRjhlV0NDM0JMSEHSAfwBQVVfeXFMUGZwNnp5a3FURTFrU3VXWl9Ya3VfaVdDOHc5OGlabXJsNUlXQWJ6VDdrUkN3WmVKSTFjcjh3aUdTcFRjTlhmcWs1U3VhVzZhakNPNEZndUM1OEUtSWxqdDEtdG0zYkNhQXFBZU9tUU1fNVNuRl9HMXdqU191T0w1TFZ1bUM5X2xwSkh0VDRSSUJadV96ZmhzbTF6dy1vandGbG42Yjlpa1B1aGlkSVlZVFVUMzZacHpFemE2Ui1XaWJ1eElWU3lGMlQ1SzRVbU9TcG85ZHNwZEFRSnVQMXc4QWplWEFTRG02OXNHVlYzV2hqQnhXS1AyMEptMXJu?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 23:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anand Mahindra weighs in on 90-hour work week: ‘My wife is wonderful, I love staring at her’ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/anand-mahindra-weighs-in-on-90-hour-work-week-my-wife-is-wonderful-i-love-staring-at-her/articleshow/117155705.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/anand-mahindra-weighs-in-on-90-hour-work-week-my-wife-is-wonderful-i-love-staring-at-her/articleshow/117155705.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jio offers YouTube Premium free for 2 years with JioFiber and AirFiber: Check out plans - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jio offers YouTube Premium free for 2 years with JioFiber and AirFiber: Check out plans</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Jio-YouTube-Premium-Free-Plan.jpg?w=640" alt="YouTube Premium offers a seamless ad-free viewing experience." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>YouTube Premium offers a seamless ad-free viewing experience. (Express: Image/Youtube)</figcaption><p>Jio is back with a bumper offer, providing YouTube Premium for free with JioFiber and AirFiber postpaid plans for two years.</p><ul><li>Users can enjoy an ad-free experience on YouTube.</li><li>YouTube Premium allows playback in the background and offline downloads.</li><li>The offer caters to heavy consumers of video content on smartphones and smart TVs.</li><li>Current pricing for YouTube Premium plans includes monthly rates of ₹89 for students, ₹149 for individuals, and ₹299 for families.</li></ul><blockquote>"With this, Jio aims to enhance the experience of Jio’s broadband and postpaid services by offering YouTube Premium which is among the most popular entertainment subscriptions."</blockquote><p>This initiative is part of Jio's strategy to provide added value to its broadband services.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/jio-offers-youtube-premium-free-for-2-years-with-jiofiber-and-airfiber-check-out-plans-9772817/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/jio-offers-youtube-premium-free-for-2-years-with-jiofiber-and-airfiber-check-out-plans-9772817/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 16:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[D-Mart Shake-Up! Neville Noronha steps down after 20 years; HUL's Anshul Asawa to become new CEO - Full profile - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>D-Mart Shake-Up: Neville Noronha Steps Down as CEO, Anshul Asawa Takes Over</h1>
<p><strong>Updated:</strong> January 11, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW News</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Neville Noronha" />
<figcaption>Neville Noronha (Left), one of the richest CEOs in India, and Anshul Asawa (Right), who will succeed him as CEO. (Image: BCCL/LinkedIn/Asawa/ET NOW News)</figcaption>
<p>Neville Noronha, after over 20 years of leadership at Avenue Supermarts, has decided not to extend his contract, paving the way for Anshul Asawa of Unilever to become the new CEO.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Neville Noronha will not extend his term as CEO of Avenue Supermarts after more than 20 years.</li>
    <li>Anshul Asawa from Unilever is appointed as CEO Designate, effective March 15th, 2025.</li>
    <li>Noronha has led the company since January 2004, owning around 1.95% of DMart, valued at over Rs 4,700 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Board has appointed Anshul Asawa as the CEO Designate, effective March 15th, 2025, honoring Neville's decision after his exceptional leadership tenure.”</blockquote>
<p>Noronha's leadership has been marked by significant achievements, including expanding DMart from 5 to over 380 outlets, significantly increasing annual revenue.</p>
<blockquote>“Under Neville's stewardship, DMart has reached significant milestones, including surpassing the Rs.50,000 Crore annual turnover mark” - Avenue Supermarts</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Neville Noronha's impactful tenure has set the stage for Anshul Asawa, who brings extensive leadership experience from Unilever, to further enhance DMart's growth trajectory.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/companies/d-mart-shake-up-neville-noronha-steps-down-after-20-years-huls-anshul-asawa-to-become-new-ceo-full-profile-article-117153783</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/companies/d-mart-shake-up-neville-noronha-steps-down-after-20-years-huls-anshul-asawa-to-become-new-ceo-full-profile-article-117153783</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:56:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neville Noronha to step down as Avenue Supermarts MD-CEO, Unilever's Anshul Asawa to take over - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Neville Noronha to step down as Avenue Supermarts MD-CEO, Unilever's Anshul Asawa to take over</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/05/20240516072427_neville-noronha.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Neville Noronha," title="Neville Noronha," width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Avenue Supermarts CEO Neville Noronha</figcaption><p>Neville Noronha, CEO of Avenue Supermarts, is set to step down as Managing Director and CEO after a notable tenure. Anshul Asawa from Unilever will take over in March 2025.</p><ul><li>Neville Noronha has led Avenue Supermarts for over two decades.</li><li>Anshul Asawa has a 30-year experience at Unilever and has held various leadership roles in Asia and Europe.</li><li>The transition is aimed to be smooth with Neville supporting Anshul during the changeover.</li><li>Anshul led digitization efforts and product innovations during his tenure at Unilever.</li></ul><blockquote>Neville has chosen not to extend his contract after more than two decades of exceptional leadership.</blockquote><p>This leadership change highlights the evolving landscape of retail leadership in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings/neville-noronha-to-step-down-as-avenue-supermarts-md-ceo-unilever-s-anshul-asawa-to-take-over-12908129.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings/neville-noronha-to-step-down-as-avenue-supermarts-md-ceo-unilever-s-anshul-asawa-to-take-over-12908129.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:43:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hundreds of excess pilots grounded at Akasa as plane deliveries retard - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Grounding of Excess Pilots at Akasa Air Amid Aircraft Delivery Delays</h1><p><strong>Published on January 11, 2025, by The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/3j3o6l/article69089691.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_FILE_PHOTO__An_Akasa_2_1_DODECEL2.jpg" alt="An Akasa Air passenger aircraft."><figcaption>An Akasa Air passenger aircraft. File | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>The global shortage of new aircraft has led to an oversupply of pilots at Akasa Air, causing anxiety among the grounded cockpit crew. With 850 pilots on staff for a fleet of only 26 aircraft, many are waiting long periods to start flying.</p><ul><li>Akasa Air has 850 pilots, while only 468 are needed based on a standard aircraft-crew ratio.</li><li>Approximately 400 pilots have not yet flown since being hired, awaiting lengthy training completion.</li><li>Salary compensation for grounded pilots is significantly lower, creating financial strain.</li><li>The airline's ambitious growth plans have been disrupted due to delays in Boeing 737 MAX deliveries.</li><li>The global aircraft delivery issues affect airlines worldwide, leading to operational challenges.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite the changes in the aircraft delivery schedules, more than 60% of our pilots have begun to accumulate flying hours.” - Akasa Air Spokesperson</blockquote><p>The situation illustrates the challenges airlines face due to supply chain disruptions and the need for adequate pilot management amidst growth ambitions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/hundreds-of-excess-pilots-grounded-at-akasa-as-plane-deliveries-retard/article69088613.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/hundreds-of-excess-pilots-grounded-at-akasa-as-plane-deliveries-retard/article69088613.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avenue Supermarts CEO Neville Noronha steps down after 20-year stint at DMart, Unilever's Anshul Asawa to be new chief | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwJBVV95cUxONzhrMUF1cGlqSzFzMUM3em1vM2ZSaU9vYXZpSEwzVUp2ZmgxWE1aNkphbUhuVVBKeW1vOFZKRlJyT1NPalgyaE1RN2FDclFHWVdqSVpLMmN4VzBwTXhzZlJyVjdDU0ZTOFRGTS0yS0RyczRGWldtRXZrUV9xYjRsS0tsLVh0NzFJeVFkclFUT1JBTnNQTXg1OFV4OWpGWUNWLUc5b3lGcGtGa1NmU2RoUVNjc01Ea1QxZGFLdlJKOGMyQUVBcXp0QWNiS0Z5RU5keHUwSWpvMGJFdFBxWlBZR3pCUTEwUENweHlFdjJ2ZFFHZzZVazZrVldLTEs5VU9PVVBtQlJUd9IBjAJBVV95cUxQWnZvc3NqbUllNjlQWDlWeFE5dUQ5WjFmVVhpZWVsbXFaenRmOV80VldHVGEzei1zUHF0TGh3SDRLLVMyVkR1SmFBaWNBS2hpcVk4N001c0ZoeHFNZUVPa1dLa0daWGhtZXg0WlNQTkVZTDVFX3daTG1CY1ZvTV8zalN0ME1nWkJtQ1Zsbl9VRElvbUNwZWlkaGd3OEVBOVBVUW5ra0ZoWk5yR0FBRDVzWnJNLVJCeUtzdGdoX2l5NVd4ZE9yb3hsbmFVR0d1VGx2aU5iWFhMSnJEWUlpQXY3WndTbGxhZTNTckNtNTRXYzZ5em5fRGExRFRrUUN0QWF5M0hldnNvRXl6Mjc3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwJBVV95cUxONzhrMUF1cGlqSzFzMUM3em1vM2ZSaU9vYXZpSEwzVUp2ZmgxWE1aNkphbUhuVVBKeW1vOFZKRlJyT1NPalgyaE1RN2FDclFHWVdqSVpLMmN4VzBwTXhzZlJyVjdDU0ZTOFRGTS0yS0RyczRGWldtRXZrUV9xYjRsS0tsLVh0NzFJeVFkclFUT1JBTnNQTXg1OFV4OWpGWUNWLUc5b3lGcGtGa1NmU2RoUVNjc01Ea1QxZGFLdlJKOGMyQUVBcXp0QWNiS0Z5RU5keHUwSWpvMGJFdFBxWlBZR3pCUTEwUENweHlFdjJ2ZFFHZzZVazZrVldLTEs5VU9PVVBtQlJUd9IBjAJBVV95cUxQWnZvc3NqbUllNjlQWDlWeFE5dUQ5WjFmVVhpZWVsbXFaenRmOV80VldHVGEzei1zUHF0TGh3SDRLLVMyVkR1SmFBaWNBS2hpcVk4N001c0ZoeHFNZUVPa1dLa0daWGhtZXg0WlNQTkVZTDVFX3daTG1CY1ZvTV8zalN0ME1nWkJtQ1Zsbl9VRElvbUNwZWlkaGd3OEVBOVBVUW5ra0ZoWk5yR0FBRDVzWnJNLVJCeUtzdGdoX2l5NVd4ZE9yb3hsbmFVR0d1VGx2aU5iWFhMSnJEWUlpQXY3WndTbGxhZTNTckNtNTRXYzZ5em5fRGExRFRrUUN0QWF5M0hldnNvRXl6Mjc3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:35:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trade unions condemn L&T CEO’s statement on work hours - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trade Unions Condemn L&T CEO’s Statement on Work Hours</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/h5v1c4/article69089583.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/S%20N%20Subrahmanyan.jpg" alt="File picture of S.N. Subrahmanyan, CEO & MD, L&T." title="File picture of S.N. Subrahmanyan, CEO & MD, L&T."><figcaption>File picture of S.N. Subrahmanyan,&nbsp;CEO &amp; MD, L&amp;T. | Photo Credit: Special Arrangement</figcaption><p>The central trade unions have condemned the statement made by S.N. Subrahmanyan, the chairman and managing director of Larsen & Toubro, suggesting that employees should work 90 hours per week. His words drew backlash from various sectors of society, emphasizing the need for a better work-life balance.</p><ul><li>Subrahmanyan proposed a drastic increase in work hours to 90 per week, suggesting workers should come to the office even on Sundays.</li><li>Trade unions likened his remarks to past statements made by corporate leaders advocating for longer working hours.</li><li>Critics argue that extended hours negatively impact workers' health and social lives, creating a divide between corporate objectives and worker welfare.</li><li>Many unions highlighted the increasing unemployment rates and warned against policies that prioritize corporate profits over workers' rights.</li></ul><blockquote>“Advocating such a policy contradicts the principles of quality of life and human dignity that are fundamental to a progressive society.” - Virjesh Upadhyay, labour studies think tank head</blockquote><p>The trade unions' strong response reflects a broader concern over labor rights and the working conditions in India, highlighting the need for a balanced approach to work hours that respects workers' dignity and health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/business/Industry/trade-unions-condemn-lt-ceos-statement-on-work-hours/article69089126.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/business/Industry/trade-unions-condemn-lt-ceos-statement-on-work-hours/article69089126.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sebi may revise ₹500 cr derivative exposure limit for institutional investors | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sebi May Revise ₹500 Cr Derivative Exposure Limit for Institutional Investors</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>The Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi) is contemplating changes to the ₹500-crore exposure limit for institutional investors in derivatives, which was implemented post the COVID-19 outbreak in March 2020. The proposed revisions aim to refine how open interest is measured and link market-wide position limits to actual delivery volumes of stocks.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sebi is considering revising the exposure limit for foreign portfolio investors and mutual funds.</li>
<li>The changes address market manipulation risks and excessive volatility in derivatives trading.</li>
<li>Current limits include a cumulative cap of ₹7,500 crore on index futures and options trades.</li>
<li>Following a study, individual traders reportedly lost ₹1.8 trillion trading index options.</li>
<li>The new methodology will focus on a delta-based metric for measuring open interest, aligning with global best practices.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Moving to a delta-based metric would ensure that we are actually measuring risk the correct way,” - Ananth Narayan, Sebi Whole-Time Member.</blockquote>
<p>The adjustments are set to enhance market stability and better reflect actual trading risks, ensuring investor protection and more informed trading practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/sebi-derivatives-f-o-position-exposure-open-interest-limits-institutional-investors-ananth-narayan-samvad-nifty-11736598211026.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/sebi-derivatives-f-o-position-exposure-open-interest-limits-institutional-investors-ananth-narayan-samvad-nifty-11736598211026.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neville Noronha quits Avenue Supermarts, Unilever's Anshul Asawa to be new CEO - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Neville Noronha Quits Avenue Supermarts, Unilever's Anshul Asawa to be New CEO</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><figure><img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-117152758,width-210,height-158,imgsize-28402,resizemode-75/neville-noronha-1200-.jpg" alt="Neville Noronha" height="158" width="210"><figcaption>The company's board has appointed Anshul Asawa as the CEO Designate, effective March 15th, 2025.</figcaption></figure><p>Neville Noronha, CEO of Avenue Supermarts, will not renew his contract ending in January 2026 after leading the company for over two decades. Anshul Asawa from Unilever will take over as CEO Designate from March 2025 and assume full CEO responsibilities in February 2026.</p><ul><li>Noronha has led Avenue Supermarts for over 20 years.</li><li>Anshul Asawa is the new CEO Designate, starting March 15, 2025.</li><li>Noronha leaves a legacy of significant growth, expanding DMart to over 380 stores.</li></ul><blockquote>"A hallmark of Neville's leadership is his conviction that while business strategy is evolved out of a complex metrics of ideas and competing claims, competent execution requires that it is articulated in simple and precise terms."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the transition marks a significant change in leadership for Avenue Supermarts, emphasizing their ongoing growth strategy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/neville-noronha-quits-avenue-supermarts-unilevers-anshul-asawa-to-be-new-ceo/articleshow/117152693.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/neville-noronha-quits-avenue-supermarts-unilevers-anshul-asawa-to-be-new-ceo/articleshow/117152693.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:02:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Love Staring at Wife, She's Wonderful': Anand Mahindra Weighs in 90-Hour Workweek Debate - Republic World]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anand Mahindra Advocates Quality over Quantity in 90-Hour Workweek Debate</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Republic World</p><img src="https://www.republicworld.com/_app/immutable/assets/16-9-placeholder.ylpwvwO6.jpg" alt="Anand Mahindra" width="800" height="450"><figcaption>Anand Mahindra emphasizes the importance of quality work at a media event.</figcaption><p>Anand Mahindra recently addressed the 90-hour workweek debate, emphasizing the necessity to prioritize the quality of work rather than the quantity of hours worked. He shared personal insights and made a case for a balanced approach to work and life, referencing his own commitment to family and personal well-being.</p><ul><li>Mahindra noted that true productivity is defined by output, not hours logged.</li><li>He criticized the ongoing debate as being misguided, focusing instead on holistic thinking and personal experiences.</li><li>Anand Mahindra championed exposure to liberal arts and culture as essential for better decision-making in business.</li><li>He reflected on the automotive industry, arguing that understanding customer needs requires time spent outside the office.</li></ul><blockquote>“What output are you doing even if it's 10 hours? You can change the world in 10 hours.” - Anand Mahindra</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Anand Mahindra’s remarks highlight a shift in workplace culture, advocating for balance between work and life, and the value of understanding personal connections in crafting effective business strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.republicworld.com/india/love-staring-at-wife-she-s-wonderful-anand-mahindra-takes-on-90-hour-work-week-debate</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.republicworld.com/india/love-staring-at-wife-she-s-wonderful-anand-mahindra-takes-on-90-hour-work-week-debate</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:52:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DMart Q3 Results: Standalone profit up 6.5% to Rs 785 crore, revenue jumps 17.5% - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>DMart Q3 Results: Standalone profit up 6.5% to Rs 785 crore, revenue jumps 17.5%</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recently Published | <strong>Source:</strong> ETMarkets.com</p><figure><img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-117152175,width-210,height-158,imgsize-46262,resizemode-75/dmart.jpg" alt="DMart"><figcaption>Avenue Supermarts, which operates the retail chain of DMart, on Saturday announced that its standalone Q3 revenue jumped 17.5% year-on-year (YoY) to Rs 15,565 crore while profit rose 6.5% YoY to Rs 785 crore.</figcaption></figure><p>Avenue Supermarts reported strong quarterly results with significant revenue growth, although both EBITDA and PAT margins have decreased compared to the previous year.</p><ul><li>Standalone Q3 revenue increased by 17.5% YoY to Rs 15,565 crore.</li><li>Profit after tax (PAT) saw a rise of 6.5% YoY to Rs 785 crore.</li><li>EBITDA margin dropped to 7.9% from 8.5% in Q3FY24.</li><li>PAT margin decreased to 5% from 5.5% YoY.</li><li>Same store revenue growth for established stores was 8.3%.</li><li>DMart Ready experienced a 21.5% growth in demand for home delivery services.</li></ul><blockquote>"Our home delivery business now far exceeds our pick-up point sales contribution." - Neville Noronha, MD and CEO</blockquote><p>The leadership of Avenue Supermarts is transitioning as CEO Neville Noronha announces he will not renew his term. Anshul Asawa has been appointed as the new CEO effective March 15, 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/earnings/dmart-q3-results-standalone-profit-up-6-5-to-rs-785-crore-revenue-jumps-17-5/articleshow/117152200.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/earnings/dmart-q3-results-standalone-profit-up-6-5-to-rs-785-crore-revenue-jumps-17-5/articleshow/117152200.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:38:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DMart Q3 results: Net profit up nearly 5% at Rs 724 crore; Revenue up 17.6% - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>DMart Q3 results: Net profit up nearly 5% at Rs 724 crore; Revenue up 17.6%</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2022/12/Avenue_Supermarts2_dmart.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Dmart" title="Dmart" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Dmart</figcaption><p>Avenue Supermarts, which operates the retail chain DMart, reported a 4.9% increase in consolidated net profit for Q3 FY25.</p><ul><li>Net profit stood at Rs 723.54 crore.</li><li>Consolidated revenue grew 17.6% to Rs 15,973 crore compared to Rs 13,572 crore in the same quarter last year.</li><li>EBITDA margin decreased to 7.6% from 8.3% YoY.</li><li>PAT margin also fell to 5.0% from 5.5% YoY.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our consolidated revenue grew 17.6 percent at Rs 15,973 cr vs Rs 13,572 in the corresponding quarter.”</blockquote><p>The growth in revenue indicates strong consumer demand and effective business strategies, despite a decrease in margins.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings/dmart-q3-results-net-profit-up-5-at-rs-724-crore-revenue-at-rs-15-973-cr-12908050.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings/dmart-q3-results-net-profit-up-5-at-rs-724-crore-revenue-at-rs-15-973-cr-12908050.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:38:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DMart Q3 Results: Avenue Supermarts net profit rises 4.7% to ₹723 crore, revenue up 17.6% YoY | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>DMart Q3 Results: Avenue Supermarts net profit rises 4.7% to ₹723 crore, revenue up 17.6% YoY</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Avenue Supermarts, the operator of DMart, reported its Q3FY25 results, showing a 4.79% increase in consolidated net profit and a significant growth in revenue year over year.</p><ul><li>Net profit reached ₹723.72 crore, up from ₹690.61 crore in Q3FY24.</li><li>Revenue from operations increased by 17.68% to ₹15,972.55 crore.</li><li>Total income, including other income, rose 17.57% to ₹15,996.69 crore.</li><li>EBITDA increased by 8.7% to ₹1,217.3 crore, with an EBITDA margin of 7.6%.</li><li>Basic Earnings per Share (EPS) rose to ₹11.12.</li><li>Avenue Supermarts plans to adapt its home delivery services in response to increasing demand.</li><li>CEO Neville Noronha announced his departure after 20 years, with Anshul Asawa appointed as CEO Designate.</li><li>DMart opened 10 new stores in the December quarter, reaching a total of 387 stores.</li></ul><blockquote>“After more than two decades of exceptional leadership... Neville has chosen not to extend his contract.” - Avenue Supermarts</blockquote><p>This quarter's results indicate continuous growth for DMart, along with innovative adjustments to meet market demands.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/company-results/dmart-q3-results-avenue-supermarts-net-profit-rises-4-7-to-rs-723-crore-revenue-up-17-6-yoy-11736547378518.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/company-results/dmart-q3-results-avenue-supermarts-net-profit-rises-4-7-to-rs-723-crore-revenue-up-17-6-yoy-11736547378518.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:35:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I love staring at my wife': Anand Mahindra takes a swipe at L&T chairman’s 90-hour workweek call - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anand Mahindra Responds to L&T Chairman's 90-Hour Workweek Suggestion</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/ANI-20241209205-0_1736602660003_1736602667773.jpg" alt="Anand Mahindra shared that he uses social media as a powerful business tool to gather feedback from 11 million people.(Video Grab)" title="Anand Mahindra shared that he uses social media as a powerful business tool to gather feedback from 11 million people.(Video Grab)">
<figcaption>Anand Mahindra shared that he uses social media as a powerful business tool to gather feedback from 11 million people.(Video Grab)</figcaption>
<p>Industrialist Anand Mahindra offered insights on balancing his work and personal life while responding to L&T Chairman's controversial suggestion of a 90-hour workweek.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Mahindra expressed his affection for his wife, stating he enjoys spending time at home, contrasting with the L&T chairman's remarks.</li>
  <li>He emphasized the importance of quality over quantity in terms of work hours.</li>
  <li>Mahindra highlighted that social media provides him feedback from a vast audience of 11 million.</li>
  <li>The discussion was prompted by comments from L&T Chairman SN Subrahmanyan about work-life balance and leisure time.</li>
  <li>L&T clarified that the Chairman's comments reflect a commitment to national progress and infrastructure development.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I am on social media because it is an amazing business tool. On one platform, I get feedback from 11 million people.” - Anand Mahindra</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Mahindra's statements underscore the value of personal time and quality work-life balance amid growing workplace demands.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/anand-mahindra-opens-up-about-his-social-media-usage-i-love-staring-at-my-wife-101736601959688.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/anand-mahindra-opens-up-about-his-social-media-usage-i-love-staring-at-my-wife-101736601959688.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:07:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[#e4mBreaking: HT Media appoints TikTok’s Sameer Singh as Group CEO - Exchange4Media]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.exchange4media.com/people-movement-news/ht-media-appoints-tiktoks-sameer-singh-as-group-ceo-140018.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.exchange4media.com/people-movement-news/ht-media-appoints-tiktoks-sameer-singh-as-group-ceo-140018.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:55:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ITC Hotels Allots 125.11 Crore Shares to ITC Shareholders, Ceases To Be A Subsidiary - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ITC Hotels Allocates 125.11 Crore Shares to ITC Shareholders, Ceases To Be A Subsidiary</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 11 Jan 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Profit</p><figure><img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2023-07%2F24386f0a-eeb3-4a51-b572-8ae1eae48b9c%2Fpool_long_dusk.png?rect=0%2C0%2C1200%2C675&amp;w=1200" alt="Eligible shareholders will get one share of the ITC Hotels Ltd. for every 10 shares held in ITC Ltd."/><figcaption>Eligible shareholders will get one share of ITC Hotels for every 10 shares held in ITC Ltd. (Photo source: ITC Hotels website)</figcaption></figure><p>ITC Hotels Ltd. allotted 125.11 crore equity shares to its shareholders during a Board meeting on January 11, 2025, as part of a restructuring effort following a Scheme of Arrangement between ITC Ltd. and ITCHL.</p><ul><li>Shares were allocated to shareholders of ITC Ltd. as of January 6, 2025.</li><li>The move aims to demerge and reorganize both ITC Ltd. and ITC Hotels.</li><li>ITC Hotels will no longer be a subsidiary of ITC Limited starting January 11, 2025.</li><li>ITC Hotels plans to list the newly allotted shares, which will remain frozen until permissions are obtained.</li><li>This demerger aligns with ITC's strategy to segregate its hotels business, with ITC Hotels anticipated to become India's second-largest hotel chain.</li></ul><blockquote>"The demerger has been structured as part of ITC's strategy to separate its hotels business."</blockquote><p>This significant restructuring allows ITC Hotels to establish itself independently, highlighting ITC Ltd.'s strategic initiative to enhance its operational focus within the hospitality sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/itc-hotels-allots-12511-crore-shares-to-itc-shareholders-ceases-to-be-a-subsidiary</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/itc-hotels-allots-12511-crore-shares-to-itc-shareholders-ceases-to-be-a-subsidiary</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Priyanka Gandhi demands answers from PM Narendra Modi over falling value of rupee, reminds of his attacks on UPA - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Priyanka Gandhi demands answers from PM Narendra Modi over falling value of rupee, reminds of his attacks on UPA</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/Priyanka_Gandhi_Narendra_Modi_1736600390330_1736600445769.jpg" alt="Priyanka Gandhi Vadra pointed out at PM Modi's attacks on the then UPA government a decade earlier." title="Priyanka Gandhi Vadra pointed out at PM Modi's attacks on the then UPA government a decade earlier." />
<figcaption>Priyanka Gandhi Vadra pointed out at PM Modi's attacks on the then UPA government a decade earlier.(X/Priyanka Gandhi, ANI)</figcaption>
<p>Congress leader Priyanka Gandhi Vadra criticized the current government for the rupee reaching its lowest value against the US dollar, demanding accountability from Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The rupee declined 18 paise to settle at 86.04 against the US dollar.</li>
  <li>Priyanka recalled PM Modi's past statements during UPA's tenure linking rupee value with government prestige.</li>
  <li>She emphasized that Modi should explain the current situation to the public.</li>
  <li>Contributing factors include global crude oil prices and foreign funds outflow.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Today he himself is the prime minister and all the records on the fall of the rupee have been broken. He should answer to the people of the country," Priyanka Gandhi stated.</blockquote>
<p>This situation emphasizes the need for the government to respond effectively to economic challenges amidst changing global dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/priyanka-gandhi-demands-answers-from-pm-narendra-modi-over-falling-value-of-rupee-reminds-of-his-attacks-on-upa-101736599532730.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/priyanka-gandhi-demands-answers-from-pm-narendra-modi-over-falling-value-of-rupee-reminds-of-his-attacks-on-upa-101736599532730.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:26:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic Of Long-Term Investing: These Equity Schemes Made ₹5,000 Per Month SIP Up To ₹5 Crore In 25 Years - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Magic Of Long-Term Investing: These Equity Schemes Made ₹5,000 Per Month SIP Up To ₹5 Crore In 25 Years</h1><p><strong>Updated - January 11, 2025</strong></p><img src="https://bl-i.thgim.com/public/news/86gki6/article69088908.ece/alternates/FREE_660/PO12_FI_Graphic_1.jpg" alt="" /><figcaption>Top-performing equity schemes in the mutual fund sector</figcaption><p>This article discusses how systematic investment plans (SIPs) can help in achieving long-term financial goals like retirement and education, highlighting that a monthly investment of ₹5,000 in select equity schemes could grow to ₹5 crore over 25 years.</p><ul><li>Mutual funds are essential for long-term investment success.</li><li>Top schemes, like Nippon India Growth Fund, yielded impressive returns.</li><li>Monthly SIP contributions exceeded ₹25,000 crore across India.</li><li>Step-up SIPs can significantly enhance savings.</li><li>Long-term investors should avoid reacting to market fluctuations.</li></ul><blockquote>The regular SIP of ₹5,000 per month in Nippon India growth fund fetched you a corpus of ₹4.98 crore in 25 years. But with a 10% annual step-up, it would grow to ₹7.6 crore.</blockquote><p>Investing through SIPs can provide substantial financial growth over time, making it a robust approach for building wealth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/portfolio/mutual-funds/magic-of-long-term-investing-these-equity-schemes-made-5000-per-month-sip-up-to-5-crore-in-25-years/article69080506.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/portfolio/mutual-funds/magic-of-long-term-investing-these-equity-schemes-made-5000-per-month-sip-up-to-5-crore-in-25-years/article69080506.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:26:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vodafone Idea 5G: An Overview of Key Vi 5G Announcements as of January 2025 - TelecomTalk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNTndRbVVLVERkS2J0UGxLZHE2OFd5YWRGQkVmQUxCeEg0VlJaWHVhQW5UQjVVd09UTjNMREZuQ09UakdReEFkTEtCclhnbEliT1ZITmoxNXlvUWVGNlVkNlNCUzBQWU55bGlid0hlRUcwVmhwc2Q2dDVYX1VLRngyejhGMWU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNTndRbVVLVERkS2J0UGxLZHE2OFd5YWRGQkVmQUxCeEg0VlJaWHVhQW5UQjVVd09UTjNMREZuQ09UakdReEFkTEtCclhnbEliT1ZITmoxNXlvUWVGNlVkNlNCUzBQWU55bGlid0hlRUcwVmhwc2Q2dDVYX1VLRngyejhGMWU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:22:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[55 Upcoming Cars In 2025 In India Detailed - Big Launches Happening! - GaadiWaadi.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>55 Upcoming Cars In 2025 In India Detailed - Big Launches Happening!</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Gaadi Waadi</p>
<img src="https://gaadiwaadi.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/upcoming-cars-2025-india--1068x610.jpg" alt="upcoming cars 2025" width="1068" height="610">
<figcaption>Upcoming Cars in 2025</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the 55 upcoming cars set to launch in India in 2025, highlighting major launches at the Bharat Mobility Global Expo 2025.</p>
<ul>
  <li>2025 expected to see many new passenger vehicles launched in India.</li>
  <li>The Bharat Mobility Global Expo 2025 will feature major brands unveiling new vehicles and technologies.</li>
  <li>Key launches include the Maruti Suzuki e Vitara and Hyundai Creta EV.</li>
  <li>Hyundai Creta Electric will offer a range up to 473 km on a single charge.</li>
  <li>Mahindra's XUV 3XO EV is anticipated to be showcased.</li>
  <li>Kia plans to introduce updated models like the facelifted EV6 and new electric RVs.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>India’s top four carmakers recorded their best-ever yearly volume sales in 2024.</blockquote>
<p>This overview shows the increasing focus on electric vehicles and SUVs in the Indian market, setting a strong stage for the upcoming launches in 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://gaadiwaadi.com/55-upcoming-cars-in-2025-in-india-detailed-big-launches-happening/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gaadiwaadi.com/55-upcoming-cars-in-2025-in-india-detailed-big-launches-happening/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:00:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Laxmi Dental IPO: OrbiMed-backed ₹698-crore IPO mobilises ₹314 crore from anchor investors ahead of subscription | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Laxmi Dental IPO: OrbiMed-backed ₹698-crore IPO mobilises ₹314 crore from anchor investors ahead of subscription</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 2023, Live Mint</p><p>OrbiMed-backed Laxmi Dental has raised ₹314 crore from anchor investors prior to its initial public offering (IPO) which opens for subscription on January 13.</p><img src='URL_TO_IMAGE_IF_AVAILABLE' alt='Laxmi Dental IPO Image'><figcaption>Laxmi Dental IPO Announcement</figcaption><p>The initial share sale will conclude on January 15, with shares priced between ₹407-428.</p><ul><li>Laxmi Dental allocated 73.39 lakh shares to 31 entities at ₹428 each.</li><li>The IPO includes a fresh issue of equity shares worth up to ₹138 crore and an offer for sale (OFS) worth ₹560 crore.</li><li>The company's shares will be listed on the BSE and NSE.</li><li>Proceeds from the fresh issue will be used to repay debt, fund capital expenditures, and invest in its subsidiary.</li></ul><blockquote>“Laxmi Dental is an end-to-end integrated dental products company with a comprehensive portfolio.”</blockquote><p>The Laxmi Dental IPO is significant as it taps into the growing demand for dental products and is backed by strong investor interest from various entities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/laxmi-dental-ipo-orbimed-backed-rs-698-crore-ipo-mobilises-rs-314-crore-from-anchor-investors-ahead-of-subscription-11736597646529.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/laxmi-dental-ipo-orbimed-backed-rs-698-crore-ipo-mobilises-rs-314-crore-from-anchor-investors-ahead-of-subscription-11736597646529.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 12:16:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quadrant Future Tek IPO Allotment Highlights: Check GMP, listing, and key details - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Quadrant Future Tek IPO Allotment Status Highlights</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 10, 2025 - Financial Express</p><img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/IPO-edited_20250110084715.jpg?w=300" alt="Quadrant Future Tek IPO allotment today, January 10"><figcaption>Quadrant Future Tek IPO allotment today: Here’s how to check status online on NSE and Link Intime</figcaption><p>Quadrant Future Tek's IPO, with a total worth of Rs 290 crores, was opened for bidding from January 7 to January 9. The IPO comprises a fresh issue of 1 crore equity shares priced between Rs 275 to Rs 290 each, with Sundae Capital Advisors as the book-running manager. The allotment is set to be finalized today, with the company’s listing on BSE and NSE scheduled for January 14.</p><ul><li>The company has a market capitalization of ₹1160.00 crore.</li><li>Key performance indicators include an ROE of 33.41% and a Debt-to-Equity ratio of 1.86.</li><li>The latest GMP for the IPO is Rs 152, indicating an estimated listing price of Rs 442.</li><li>Subscription details reveal an overwhelming response, with the issue subscribed 195.96 times overall.</li></ul><blockquote>Gaurav Garg, Research Analyst: “The Indian Specialty Cable and Train Control System market is expected to witness significant growth.”</blockquote><p>This new IPO is poised to make a substantial impact in the rail industry, enhancing safety features with innovative technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/market/ipo-news-quadrant-future-tek-ipo-allotment-live-updates-listing-gmp-price-band-subscription-status-ipo-news-3711654/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/market/ipo-news-quadrant-future-tek-ipo-allotment-live-updates-listing-gmp-price-band-subscription-status-ipo-news-3711654/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:58:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Market Next Week: From TCS dividend record date to HCLTech, RIL, Infosys, Axis Bank Q3 results – Cues to watch - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Next Week: From TCS dividend record date to HCLTech, RIL, Infosys, Axis Bank Q3 results – Cues to watch</h1><p><strong>Updated:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 17:23 IST</p><p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Stock Market Next Week" loading="lazy"></p><figcaption>Stock Market Next Week</figcaption></p><p>The Indian benchmark indices ended on a negative note last week, with several key events on the horizon that may influence the market's performance in the upcoming week.</p><ul><li>Indian benchmark indices continued to decline, recording their third consecutive day of losses.</li><li>IT stocks played a significant role in mitigating losses in Sensex and Nifty.</li><li>Nifty closed at 23,431.50, down by 95 points or 0.4%.</li></ul><p>Investors experienced a significant loss, with the market capitalization of BSE-listed firms dropping to Rs 429.68 lakh crore.</p><h2>Cues for the upcoming week (Jan 11-17)</h2><ul><li><strong>India:</strong> CPI on Jan 13, WPI on Jan 14</li><li><strong>Global:</strong></li><ul><li>U.S.: PPI on Jan 14, CPI on Jan 15, Initial jobless claims and retail sales on Jan 16, Industrial production on Jan 17</li><li>U.K.: CPI on Jan 15, Industrial production on Jan 16</li><li>China: Trade data on Jan 13, GDP on Jan 17</li></ul></li></ul><h2>Q3 Earnings</h2><ul><li>Jan 13: HCLTech</li><li>Jan 16: RIL, Infosys, Axis Bank</li></ul><h2>Corporate Actions</h2><p>Jan 15: Last day to buy shares of PCBL, CESC for interim dividend eligibility. </p><p>Jan 16: Last day to buy shares of TCS for interim and special dividend eligibility.</p><blockquote>Disclaimer: The above article is meant for informational purposes only, and should not be considered as investment advice.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, monitoring the upcoming economic indicators and corporate earnings will be crucial for investors next week.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/stock-market-next-week-from-tcs-dividend-record-date-to-hcltech-ril-infosys-axis-bank-q3-results-cues-to-watch-article-117146134</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/stock-market-next-week-from-tcs-dividend-record-date-to-hcltech-ril-infosys-axis-bank-q3-results-cues-to-watch-article-117146134</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:53:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No more actions on derivatives on anvil: Sebi's Ananth Narayan - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>No More Actions on Derivatives: Insights from Sebi's Ananth Narayan</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/08/20240803175206_jpgtopngconverter-com-6.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431' alt='Sebi's Ananth Narayan on derivatives market' /><figcaption>Sebi's Ananth Narayan emphasizing the importance of derivatives in market pricing.</figcaption><p>The Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi) is not planning any additional restrictions on derivatives, according to Sebi's Wholetime Member Ananth Narayan. Sebi is focusing on improving the system without further constraints.</p><ul><li>Sebi assures that no further actions will be taken against derivatives trading.</li><li>An expert group is working on measures to enhance business practices and risk management in the derivatives market.</li><li>Recent restrictions imposed in November aimed at curbing speculative trades after poor performance data for retail investors.</li><li>Discussions within Sebi include measures to improve risk assessment in the derivatives market.</li></ul><blockquote>“At this point in time, there is no thought of Sebi taking any further steps in this particular regard.” - Ananth Narayan</blockquote><p>This stance demonstrates Sebi's commitment to maintain the integrity and trust of the derivatives market while exploring avenues for enhancements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/no-more-actions-on-derivatives-on-anvil-sebi-s-ananth-narayan-12908086.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/no-more-actions-on-derivatives-on-anvil-sebi-s-ananth-narayan-12908086.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:51:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foxconn halts Chinese workers' deployment to India, sends Taiwanese staff - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Foxconn Halts Chinese Workers' Deployment to India and Sends Taiwanese Staff</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Rest of World</p><p>Foxconn, a major partner for Apple, has ceased sending Chinese workers to its Indian factories and is replacing them with Taiwanese workers amid critical equipment shipment delays.</p><ul><li>Foxconn's shift threatens Apple's production strategy in India.</li><li>Delays in the shipment of vital manufacturing equipment may hinder Apple's plans to diversify production away from China.</li><li>Chinese workers were asked to cancel travel to India, leading to a scramble for replacements.</li><li>Geopolitical tensions between China and India may be influencing this decision.</li></ul><blockquote>“Currently, the equipment and manpower are not allowed to go over [to India],” a source told Rest of World.</blockquote><p>The situation highlights the challenges Apple faces in its manufacturing shift to India and underscores the complexities of global supply chains.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/foxconn-halts-chinese-workers-deployment-to-india-sends-taiwanese-staff-125011100497_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/foxconn-halts-chinese-workers-deployment-to-india-sends-taiwanese-staff-125011100497_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:27:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cognizant Hike 2025: IT company's new 'Hike' scheme! Retirement age raised for employees - Details - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/companies/cognizant-hike-2025-it-companys-new-hike-scheme-retirement-age-raised-from-58-to-for-it-employees-details-article-117143914</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/companies/cognizant-hike-2025-it-companys-new-hike-scheme-retirement-age-raised-from-58-to-for-it-employees-details-article-117143914</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 10:04:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google CEO Sundar Pichai to employees: As we start the year, I have been reviewing... - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Google CEO Sundar Pichai to Employees: As We Start the Year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Google News</p><p>As the new year begins, Google CEO Sundar Pichai addressed employees, sharing insights into the company's goals and reflections on the past year.</p><ul><li>Pichai emphasized the importance of innovation and teamwork.</li><li>He discussed the challenges faced by the company in the previous year.</li><li>The CEO highlighted strategic plans for upcoming projects and initiatives.</li></ul><blockquote>“Innovation thrives when we work together,” said Pichai, reinforcing team collaboration.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Pichai's message focused on resilience and collective effort as key to navigating the upcoming year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-to-employees-as-we-start-the-year-i-have-been-reviewing-/articleshow/117114841.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-to-employees-as-we-start-the-year-i-have-been-reviewing-/articleshow/117114841.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 09:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BEL Q3 Results FY 2025 date, time: Quarterly earnings announcement schedule FIXED – Defence PSU stock to register profit? - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BEL Q3 Results FY 2025 Announcement Schedule Set for January 30, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="BEL Q3 Results 2025 date and time">
<figcaption>BEL Q3 Results 2025 date and time</figcaption>
<p>Government-owned Bharat Electronic Ltd (BEL) has scheduled the announcement for its October-December quarter earnings on January 30, 2025. The firm recently reported a significant profit increase for the previous quarter.</p>
<ul>
  <li>BEL specializes in manufacturing advanced electronic products and systems for military branches.</li>
  <li>The Board of Directors meeting is set for January 30, 2025, to discuss the financial results.</li>
  <li>BEL's standalone net profit for Q2 FY25 rose by 34% to Rs 1,091 crore compared to Rs 812 crore in the same quarter last year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We wish to inform that a meeting of the Board of Directors of the Company is scheduled to be held on Thursday, the 30th January, 2025 to consider and approve, inter alia, Unaudited Standalone & Consolidated Financial Results for the quarter and nine months ended 31st December, 2024.”</blockquote>
<p>With a strong performance last quarter, BEL is expected to deliver favorable Q3 results.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/bel-q3-results-fy-2025-date-time-quarterly-earnings-announcement-schedule-fixed-defence-psu-stock-to-register-profit-article-117143499</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/bel-q3-results-fy-2025-date-time-quarterly-earnings-announcement-schedule-fixed-defence-psu-stock-to-register-profit-article-117143499</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 09:48:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IREDA, PFC, REC: How to trade 3 PSU power stocks in market crash? - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IREDA, PFC, REC: How to trade 3 PSU power stocks in market crash?</h1><p><strong>Updated:</strong> <strong>Jan 11, 2025</strong> 16:02 IST</p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="IREDA PFC REC"><figcaption>IREDA, PFC, REC: How to trade 3 PSU power stocks in market crash? (Pic: Shutterstock/ ET NOW)</figcaption><p>The PSU power stocks have suffered a significant decline due to recent market sell-offs, with many losing over 30% from their peak values.</p><ul><li>The BSE Power index dropped by 27% from its peak.</li><li>REC shares fell 29%, closing at Rs 459.65.</li><li>PFC shares dropped 30%, closing at Rs 404.20.</li><li>IREDA shares lost 35%, closing at Rs 201.15.</li></ul><blockquote>“The rally in IREDA shares couldn't sustain due to profit booking. I would recommend to exit,” said Jatin Gedia, Technical Research Analyst at Mirae Asset Sharekhan.</blockquote><p>IREDA's shares are up more than 500% from its IPO price of Rs 32 launched in November 2024, while REC and PFC shares have shown modest performances.</p><p>Recommendation: Investors are advised to exit their positions or hold for the long term in PFC and REC.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/ireda-pfc-rec-how-to-trade-3-psu-power-stocks-in-market-crash-article-117144521</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/ireda-pfc-rec-how-to-trade-3-psu-power-stocks-in-market-crash-article-117144521</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 09:16:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>