<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:15:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:15:38 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take A Look At All The Tata Cars That Could Go On Sale In 2025 - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>All New Tata Cars Expected To Be Launched In 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> CarDekho.com</p>
<img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/676e636943501.png" alt="Upcoming Tata Cars in 2025">
<figcaption>Upcoming Tata Cars in 2025</figcaption>
<p>Tata Motors is preparing for an exciting launch lineup in 2025, featuring electric versions of popular models and the return of the Tata Sierra SUV.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sierra and Harrier EVs to debut alongside other models.</li>
<li>Sierra expected to launch on January 17, 2025, with ICE and EV variants.</li>
<li>Harrier EV to feature all-wheel drive and is expected to launch by March 2025.</li>
<li>Safari EV set to debut in February 2025 with a range similar to the Harrier EV.</li>
<li>Punch facelift projected for September 2025, retaining its 1.2-litre engine.</li>
<li>Harrier petrol variant expected in June 2025 with a new engine option.</li>
<li>Tiago and Tigor facelifts anticipated in December 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Which of these Tata cars are you most excited about?"</blockquote>
<p>In summary, 2025 holds significant promise for Tata Motors with their electrification efforts and revamping existing models.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/take-a-look-at-all-the-tata-cars-that-could-go-on-sale-in-2025-33731.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/take-a-look-at-all-the-tata-cars-that-could-go-on-sale-in-2025-33731.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Osamu Suzuki, who led Japanese automaker into India, dies at 94 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Osamu Suzuki, Pioneer of Suzuki Motor and Indian Auto Market, Dies at 94</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/business/Industry/d38bq3/article68855305.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/SwiftDzire.jpg" alt="Suzuki Swift" />
<figcaption>Suzuki Swift - The affordable car innovation.</figcaption>
<p>Osamu Suzuki, a legendary figure in the automotive industry and former chairman of Suzuki Motor Corporation, passed away at the age of 94 on Christmas Day due to lymphoma. He was instrumental in transforming the Indian auto market and expanding Suzuki's global reach.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Suzuki led Suzuki Motor for over 40 years, significantly impacting the automotive landscape.</li>
  <li>He focused on cost efficiency, which shaped the company's operations, including lowering factory ceilings for savings.</li>
  <li>Under his leadership, Suzuki launched the Maruti 800, revolutionizing the Indian car market.</li>
  <li>Suzuki played a key role in establishing a partnership with Maruti at a time when India had limited car production.</li>
  <li>His quirky personality and humor were noted, often playfully stating he would stay with the company 'forever.'</li>
  <li>The company he built retains about 40% of the Indian car market today.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“To be number one somewhere in the world” was his motivation for investing in India.</blockquote>
<p>Osamu Suzuki’s legacy will continue through the ongoing success of Maruti Suzuki, marking a significant chapter in automotive history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/business/osamu-suzuki-who-led-japanese-automaker-into-india-dies-at-94/article69032945.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/business/osamu-suzuki-who-led-japanese-automaker-into-india-dies-at-94/article69032945.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SaaS fintech Zaggle plans at least 2 acquisitions next fiscal to drive growth | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SaaS fintech Zaggle plans at least 2 acquisitions next fiscal to drive growth</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><p>Zaggle Prepaid Ocean Services Ltd, a SaaS fintech platform, aims to acquire at least two companies in the next financial year to stimulate growth. The company recently raised ₹595 crore through a qualified institutional placement to support this initiative.</p><ul><li>The fintech is assessing 5 to 6 potential acquisition targets, focusing on merchant card software, accounts receivables, and FASTag solutions.</li><li>Founder Raj Narayanam mentioned a goal of reaching a billion-dollar revenue target within the next 5 to 6 years.</li><li>Zaggle has previously invested ₹48 crore to acquire stakes in Span Across IT Solutions and Mobileware Technologies.</li><li>The latest funding round attracted major institutional investors and involved the allotment of 1.13 crore equity shares.</li><li>For the July-September quarter, Zaggle reported a three-fold increase in net profit, amounting to ₹20.3 crore and a 64.22% year-over-year revenue growth to ₹302.5 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are aiming for a billion-dollar revenue target within the next 5 to 6 years,” - Raj Narayanam</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Zaggle is strategically positioning itself for growth through timely acquisitions and financial investments, which could significantly enhance its market presence in the fintech industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/saas-fintech-zaggle-plans-at-least-2-acquisitions-next-fiscal-to-drive-growth-11735290026913.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/saas-fintech-zaggle-plans-at-least-2-acquisitions-next-fiscal-to-drive-growth-11735290026913.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:00:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Transrail Lighting Share Price: Stock down 2.9% after listing at 36.57% premium over IPO price on NSE - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Transrail Lighting Share Price: Stock down 2.9% after listing at 36.57% premium over IPO price on NSE</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27<br><strong>Source:</strong> Upstox</p><p>Shares of Transrail Lighting were listed at ₹590 on the NSE on December 27, a 36.57% premium over the IPO price of ₹432. However, the stock experienced fluctuations, ending the trading day 2.9% lower.</p><figure><img src='image_url_here' alt='Transrail Lighting Logo'><figcaption>Transrail Lighting Logo</figcaption></figure><p>Despite a strong debut, the stock has seen a decline post-listing due to various market factors.</p><ul><li>IPO subscription was 80.80 times oversubscribed.</li><li>Initial high of ₹605 was recorded during trading.</li><li>The company's market cap reached ₹7,663.33 crore.</li><li>Shares traded as low as ₹544.50 shortly after listing.</li></ul><blockquote>“Shares jumped nearly 37% on debut trade, showing strong market interest.”</blockquote><p>The fluctuations in the share price indicate the volatile nature of the market and investor sentiment around new listings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/transrail-lighting-ipo-listing-share-price-live-shares-list-premium-nse-bse-stock-news-review-all-you-need-to-know/article-137129/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/transrail-lighting-ipo-listing-share-price-live-shares-list-premium-nse-bse-stock-news-review-all-you-need-to-know/article-137129/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:52:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explained | Why rupee is in a free fall against the US Dollar - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why the Rupee is Plummeting Against the US Dollar</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV 18</p><img alt="Explained | Why rupee is in a free fall against the US Dollar" title="Explained | Why rupee is in a free fall against the US Dollar" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" decoding="async" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>The rupee has hit a record low against the US dollar.</figcaption><p>The Indian rupee has recently seen a sharp decline, hitting a record low of 85.81 against the US dollar. Key factors contributing to this drop include a strengthening dollar, increased demand from importers, and potential policy shifts by the Reserve Bank of India.</p><ul><li>The US Dollar has strengthened due to market expectations of the Trump administration's policies and a hawkish Federal Reserve.</li><li>The rupee's significant single-day fall was noted on December 27, reaching an all-time low.</li><li>Increased demand for dollars, particularly from oil importers, is exerting pressure on the rupee.</li><li>The Reserve Bank of India's policy may be adjusting to allow a more free-market determination of the rupee's value.</li><li>Despite this, the rupee has remained relatively strong compared to other emerging market currencies year-to-date.</li></ul><blockquote>Mitul Kotecha, Head of FX and EM Macro Strategy Asia at Barclays, stated, "the rupee is likely to weaken further, reaching 87 against the dollar by the end of next year, despite temporary measures to slow its fall. However, it is expected to outperform its Asian peers."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while the rupee faces challenges in the current market context, its long-term performance relative to other currencies remains to be closely monitored.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/currency/rupee-at-record-low-vs-usd-explained-inr-dollar-index-greenback-crude-oil-brent-wti-19530563.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/currency/rupee-at-record-low-vs-usd-explained-inr-dollar-index-greenback-crude-oil-brent-wti-19530563.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:25:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tata Capital IPO: Listing Date, Valuation And Ownership — All You Need To Know - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tata Capital IPO: Listing Date, Valuation And Ownership — All You Need To Know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Profit</p><img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2024-09-02%2Fnnp9an0i%2FIPO%20Ahead.webp?rect=0%2C0%2C499%2C281&amp;w=1200" alt="Tata Capital IPO Image"><figcaption>(Representative image. Photo source: Unspash)</figcaption><p>Tata Capital Ltd., the financial services arm of Tata Group, is preparing for a public listing by September 2025 after its merger with Tata Motor Finance.</p><ul><li>The merger will be voted on by unsecured creditors on January 17, 2025.</li><li>Tata Capital is classified as an upper-layer systemically important non-banking financial company (NBFC), which mandates a listing within three years.</li><li>For FY2024, Tata Capital reported a profit after tax of Rs 3,327 crore.</li><li>The merged entity will have assets under management of Rs 2.30 lakh crore as of March 31, 2024.</li><li>The RBI approved the merger of Tata Capital and Tata Motor Finance in October 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>The proforma book value of the merged NBFC stood at Rs 31,603 crore at the end of September 2024, thereby valuing the company at three times book value.</blockquote><p>The upcoming IPO of Tata Capital is significant as it represents a consolidation in the Tata Group's financial services sector, positioning it for growth in a competitive market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/ipos/tata-capital-ipo-listing-date-valuation-and-ownership-all-you-need-to-know</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/ipos/tata-capital-ipo-listing-date-valuation-and-ownership-all-you-need-to-know</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:23:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Could See These Tata Cars Go On Sale In 2025 - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>All New Tata Cars Expected To Be Launched In 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> CarDekho.com</p>
<img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/676e636943501.png" alt="Upcoming Tata Cars in 2025">
<figcaption>Upcoming Tata Cars in 2025</figcaption>
<p>Tata Motors is preparing for an exciting launch lineup in 2025, featuring electric versions of popular models and the return of the Tata Sierra SUV.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sierra and Harrier EVs to debut alongside other models.</li>
<li>Sierra expected to launch on January 17, 2025, with ICE and EV variants.</li>
<li>Harrier EV to feature all-wheel drive and is expected to launch by March 2025.</li>
<li>Safari EV set to debut in February 2025 with a range similar to the Harrier EV.</li>
<li>Punch facelift projected for September 2025, retaining its 1.2-litre engine.</li>
<li>Harrier petrol variant expected in June 2025 with a new engine option.</li>
<li>Tiago and Tigor facelifts anticipated in December 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Which of these Tata cars are you most excited about?"</blockquote>
<p>In summary, 2025 holds significant promise for Tata Motors with their electrification efforts and revamping existing models.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/we-could-see-these-tata-cars-go-on-sale-in-2025-33731.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/we-could-see-these-tata-cars-go-on-sale-in-2025-33731.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finolex Industries, Religare Enterprises, Greaves Cotton, Mamata Machinery, Star Cement, Sagility India: Check top buzzing stocks of the day - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingJBVV95cUxQZmk5UUo1cXYtM1NSMkNQbm1qN3hhNzd3UHN4YUtXQ0pfN0Fzdkh6eUFfQU8tS0w5djg5c3J1ZHFKZFkybzBUbFdHeHF1eEZvSkpCelM4ZTExQUhibVZDczR3LXNLbXkxV05Hb3Y0VEowSU9Bams1dUx0eWlhM19qWkNVbG5kRGM5ZzYxRWswZzltY3BaS19sZzRUUGZzbEZFbXJaMEtJLXBGNFlaRzg3Wm85d0ZiQ2gxcmFSd050blp4VWY4SW5yVXdZRlU5WkdGN2N6SXhqemZlQnhCTlhKM3ViTmFyX2NMTktTZ1VrM0ZiVTVGajRpeWs0VXY3b0J0Z3ZVZU5DYXZ6Q2lSZGluZm9PVkJLQTgtdjNCWkxB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingJBVV95cUxQZmk5UUo1cXYtM1NSMkNQbm1qN3hhNzd3UHN4YUtXQ0pfN0Fzdkh6eUFfQU8tS0w5djg5c3J1ZHFKZFkybzBUbFdHeHF1eEZvSkpCelM4ZTExQUhibVZDczR3LXNLbXkxV05Hb3Y0VEowSU9Bams1dUx0eWlhM19qWkNVbG5kRGM5ZzYxRWswZzltY3BaS19sZzRUUGZzbEZFbXJaMEtJLXBGNFlaRzg3Wm85d0ZiQ2gxcmFSd050blp4VWY4SW5yVXdZRlU5WkdGN2N6SXhqemZlQnhCTlhKM3ViTmFyX2NMTktTZ1VrM0ZiVTVGajRpeWs0VXY3b0J0Z3ZVZU5DYXZ6Q2lSZGluZm9PVkJLQTgtdjNCWkxB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:00:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee's fall worsens as it hits 85.80 against dollar, set for worst month in two years - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee Hits 85.80 Against Dollar, Facing Worst Month in Two Years</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/12/20241216070038_Market_down1.jpeg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Rupee has extended the fall for a ninth day in a row, on Friday, breaching the psychologically key level of 85.50 for the first time." title="Rupee has extended the fall for a ninth day in a row, on Friday, breaching the psychologically key level of 85.50 for the first time."><figcaption>Rupee has extended the fall for a ninth day in a row, breaching the key level of 85.50 for the first time.</figcaption>
<p>The Indian Rupee has hit a fresh low of 85.80 against the US dollar, marking the worst expected month in two years, driven by strong demand for dollars in the non-deliverable forwards (NDF) market.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Rupee has weakened by 3% against the US dollar for the year.</li>
<li>This marks the Rupee's seventh consecutive year of annual losses.</li>
<li>Analysts project the Rupee could reach 86 against the dollar by the end of March.</li>
<li>The RBI has not indicated any changes in intervention strategy under the new governor.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Nuvama Institutional has projected that the Rupee could hit 86 against the dollar by end of March.</blockquote>
<p>This continuing depreciation raises concerns regarding economic stability and the effectiveness of current forex strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/currency/rupee-hits-record-low-against-us-dollar-weakens-past-85-50-mark-12898750.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/currency/rupee-hits-record-low-against-us-dollar-weakens-past-85-50-mark-12898750.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:57:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Suzuki Motor Chairman Osamu Suzuki, who led company for 40 years, dies at 94 - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Former Suzuki Motor Chairman Osamu Suzuki, Who Led Company for 40 Years, Dies at 94</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 25, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="Former Suzuki Motor Chairman Osamu Suzuki" title="Former Suzuki Motor Chairman Osamu Suzuki, who led company for 40 years, dies at 94" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Former Suzuki Motor Chairman Osamu Suzuki, who led company for 40 years, dies at 94</figcaption><p>Osamu Suzuki, former chairman of Japan's Suzuki Motor, has died at the age of 94. He led the company for over 40 years, transforming it into a global automaker.</p><ul><li>Born on January 30, 1930, in Gero, Gifu Prefecture, Japan.</li><li>Led Suzuki as president from 1978, significantly expanding its global presence.</li><li>Strategically formed alliances with General Motors and Volkswagen.</li><li>Pioneered the company’s success in affordable small vehicles in India.</li><li>Stepped down as CEO amidst a fuel efficiency testing scandal in 2016.</li><li>Returned as president during the 2008 financial crisis to stabilize the company.</li><li>Passed away due to lymphoma on December 25, 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>“If I were to listen to everybody, it would make things too slow,” Osamu Suzuki wrote in his memoir.</blockquote><p>Osamu Suzuki's leadership was marked by a relentless drive for progress and decisiveness, influencing the automotive industry significantly over his lengthy career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/auto/former-suzuki-motor-chairman-osamu-suzuki-who-led-company-for-40-years-dies-at-94-19530571.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/auto/former-suzuki-motor-chairman-osamu-suzuki-who-led-company-for-40-years-dies-at-94-19530571.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:43:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why NTPC Green Energy shares gained on Friday — Explained - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why NTPC Green Energy shares gained on Friday — Explained</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="Why NTPC Green Energy shares gained on Friday — Explained" title="Why NTPC Green Energy shares gained on Friday — Explained" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" decoding="async" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Shares of NTPC Green Energy Ltd. rallied after new project operations commenced.</figcaption><p>The stock of NTPC Green Energy Ltd. rose significantly after the announcement of the start of commercial operations for its solar project in Gujarat, increasing shareholder interest.</p><ul><li>NTPC Green Energy shares increased by 6% after announcing the start of commercial operations for a 200 MW solar project.</li><li>The first phase of the project, with a capacity of 37.5 MW, was launched based on a certificate received on December 26.</li><li>The project contributes to the NTPC group's total capacity, which now stands at 76,598.18 MW.</li><li>The stock reached an intraday high of ₹133.35 and ended the day at ₹129.58, a noteworthy rise since its IPO.</li><li>There were significant trading activities due to the conclusion of the lock-in period for anchor investors.</li></ul><blockquote>“With this milestone, the total installed and commercial capacity of the NTPC group has increased to 76,598.18 MW.”</blockquote><p>This increase in operations for NTPC Green Energy reflects the growing interest and development in renewable energy projects, positioning the company favorably in the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/ntpc-green-energy-shares-gain-commercialisation-of-new-plant-gujarat-group-capacity-ipo-returns-19530551.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/ntpc-green-energy-shares-gain-commercialisation-of-new-plant-gujarat-group-capacity-ipo-returns-19530551.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:39:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Osamu Suzuki, former president of Suzuki Motor, dies at 94 - The Japan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Osamu Suzuki, Longtime Leader of Suzuki Motor, Passes Away at 94</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Wednesday, December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Japan Times</p><div><img src="https://cdn4.premiumread.com/?url=https://www.japantimes.co.jp/japantimes/uploads/images/2024/12/27/442956.jpg?v=3.1&amp;q=100&amp;f=jpg&amp;t=1.51" alt="Suzuki" title="Suzuki"><figcaption>Suzuki | JIJI</figcaption></div><p>Osamu Suzuki, who played a pivotal role in expanding Suzuki Motor and was known for his leadership style, has died at the age of 94. He was instrumental in the company’s successes in both the global and Indian markets.</p><ul><li>Osamu Suzuki died of lymphoma, as confirmed by the company.</li><li>He was married into the Suzuki family and became a key figure in the automotive industry.</li><li>He formed important partnerships with General Motors and Volkswagen during his tenure.</li><li>Under his leadership, Suzuki Motor gained significant market share in India, particularly through the Maruti brand.</li><li>Suzuki served as president of Suzuki Motor for over 28 years, making him the longest-standing head of a global automaker.</li><li>He faced challenges, including controversies surrounding fuel-economy testing methods which impacted the company’s stock.</li></ul><blockquote>“If I were to listen to everybody, it would make things too slow. Never stop, or else you lose.” - Osamu Suzuki</blockquote><p>Osamu Suzuki's legacy will continue to influence the automotive industry, especially through his contributions to the expansion of Suzuki Motor in international markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.japantimes.co.jp/business/2024/12/27/companies/osamu-suzuki-obituary/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.japantimes.co.jp/business/2024/12/27/companies/osamu-suzuki-obituary/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shares to buy: Prashanth Tapse of Mehta Equities suggests these three stocks to buy in the short term | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shares to buy: Prashanth Tapse of Mehta Equities suggests these three stocks to buy in the short term</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The domestic stock market is showing signs of an upward trend, with optimism for a year-end rally. Analysts predict that while selling pressure from foreign investors persists, the market is expected to provide superior returns in the long term.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The Nifty 50 index opened at 23,801.40, up 0.22%.</li><li>The Sensex index rose by 0.17%, starting at 78,607.58.</li><li>Foreign institutional investor selling remains a concern, tied to strong dollar performance.</li><li>Prashanth Tapse, a senior VP at Mehta Equities, gives three stock recommendations for short-term investors.</li></ul><h2>Stock Recommendations:</h2><ol><li><strong>Bharat Electronics Ltd (BEL)</strong><br> Buy at: ₹295 | Stop Loss: ₹285 | Targets: ₹310 and ₹315</li><li><strong>Himadri Speciality Chemical Ltd (HSCL)</strong><br> Buy at: ₹583 | Stop Loss: ₹560 | Targets: ₹625 and ₹650</li><li><strong>Mahindra & Mahindra (M&M)</strong><br> Buy at: ₹3,052 | Stop Loss: ₹2,990 | Target: ₹3,200</li></ol><blockquote>"The market is expected to continue offering superior returns to investors in the coming years, as the India Growth Story remains strong."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, investors are advised to consider these stocks based on their market position and positive technical indicators.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/shares-to-buy-prashanth-tapse-of-mehta-equities-suggests-these-three-stocks-to-buy-in-the-short-term-11735281809194.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/shares-to-buy-prashanth-tapse-of-mehta-equities-suggests-these-three-stocks-to-buy-in-the-short-term-11735281809194.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:14:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee recovers after testing new low of 85.81, set for worst month in two years - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee recovers after testing new low of 85.81, set for worst month in two years</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/12/20241216070038_Market_down1.jpeg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Rupee has extended the fall for a ninth day in a row, on Friday, breaching the psychologically key level of 85.50 for the first time." title="Rupee has extended the fall for a ninth day in a row, on Friday, breaching the psychologically key level of 85.50 for the first time." width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Rupee has extended the fall for a ninth day in a row, breaching a key level.</figcaption><p>The Rupee partially recovered from a fresh low of 85.81 against the dollar, marking a significant drop and ongoing challenges in the forex market as it faces its worst month in two years.</p><ul><li>The Rupee has weakened by 3% against the USD this year, set for annual losses for the seventh year in a row.</li><li>It broke below the key level of 85.50 for the first time, primarily due to month-end dollar demand.</li><li>Nuvama Institutional predicts the Rupee may hit 86 against the dollar by March 2025.</li><li>Market participants highlighted a liquidity shortfall in the banking system as a contributing factor to the Rupee's fall.</li></ul><blockquote>“Intervention in such an environment can only slow the pace of currency depreciation.” - Christopher Wong, Oversea-Chinese Banking Corp</blockquote><p>The ongoing economic adjustments and geopolitical tensions continue to exert pressure on the Indian Rupee, impacting its performance against multiple currencies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/currency/rupee-hits-record-low-against-us-dollar-weakens-past-85-50-mark-12898750.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/currency/rupee-hits-record-low-against-us-dollar-weakens-past-85-50-mark-12898750.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:24:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee recovers after testing new low of 85.81, set to end 2024 with 3% weakness - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQYXc1OWkxelloc2F4NUF3bnhDV1VnakZ5VjhZWllLV1BHbGhlMVY5aW1aaW9sV19vUXhQSUVXUXVHQUtleENMY1V4LTNYSjBVN0JaX0o5ZFQyazVyUzg1eDV0dnpIS2xnd3pKMWprTWYyX1ZXOFJOeDdGcGZlbHNMSDI0N3dhRVQ3VDZubTVpaXNMa3hIeUo4SW1pY1d4Uk83OEZRS1FhVmhabmstcGRKM0ZSUVVVR0VOcHhUU9IBwgFBVV95cUxOcmF3UThhU1dqYllodmR4NXJjTGxJOFRBYm1PZjRZN2l5ZndJYlRzb2JYUVVXX0hZUmNOYjBvV3Zzd0FuajdIMWlGQ01HRXBjRHROVUhvUkdzaUdWQXVOMnBFM1huVXdHdHFNeE5yODd1R1QwSFpBdTJ4aTRESm9HOVNlVFM4YWVYU0dldmE1b0drTm1mbno5ekhIS1hwVl9vRUVDTHZldDlMVUo3cFRSQjAwZG0td04ySllXdnExOTF4UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQYXc1OWkxelloc2F4NUF3bnhDV1VnakZ5VjhZWllLV1BHbGhlMVY5aW1aaW9sV19vUXhQSUVXUXVHQUtleENMY1V4LTNYSjBVN0JaX0o5ZFQyazVyUzg1eDV0dnpIS2xnd3pKMWprTWYyX1ZXOFJOeDdGcGZlbHNMSDI0N3dhRVQ3VDZubTVpaXNMa3hIeUo4SW1pY1d4Uk83OEZRS1FhVmhabmstcGRKM0ZSUVVVR0VOcHhUU9IBwgFBVV95cUxOcmF3UThhU1dqYllodmR4NXJjTGxJOFRBYm1PZjRZN2l5ZndJYlRzb2JYUVVXX0hZUmNOYjBvV3Zzd0FuajdIMWlGQ01HRXBjRHROVUhvUkdzaUdWQXVOMnBFM1huVXdHdHFNeE5yODd1R1QwSFpBdTJ4aTRESm9HOVNlVFM4YWVYU0dldmE1b0drTm1mbno5ekhIS1hwVl9vRUVDTHZldDlMVUo3cFRSQjAwZG0td04ySllXdnExOTF4UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:24:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee hits record low against US Dollar, weakens past 85.50 mark - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee's fall worsens as it breaches 85.70 against dollar, set for worst month in two years</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/12/20241216070038_Market_down1.jpeg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Rupee has extended the fall for a ninth day in a row, on Friday, breaching the psychologically key level of 85.50 for the first time." title="Rupee has extended the fall for a ninth day in a row, on Friday, breaching the psychologically key level of 85.50 for the first time."><figcaption>Rupee has extended the fall for a ninth day in a row, breaching the psychologically key level of 85.50.</figcaption><p>The Rupee hit a fresh low of 85.73 against the US dollar, marking a continuous decline driven by strong demand for the dollar. It is projected to experience its worst month in two years.</p><ul><li>The Rupee has weakened by 3% against the US dollar for the year.</li><li>It is set to post annual losses for the seventh consecutive year.</li><li>Analysts attribute the fall to the December currency futures expiry and increased demand from importers.</li><li>The November trade deficit reached a record high of $37.8 billion.</li><li>India's export growth has been negatively influenced by weakening global demand.</li></ul><blockquote>"Expected higher activity from importers at this time of the month." - Forex trader</blockquote><p>The current trends indicate significant challenges for the Indian economy as the Rupee continues to struggle against the US dollar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/currency/rupee-hits-record-low-against-us-dollar-weakens-past-85-50-mark-12898750.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/currency/rupee-hits-record-low-against-us-dollar-weakens-past-85-50-mark-12898750.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:24:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bank of Baroda SO Online Form 2025 - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTE9wMk55TXVtV3BEVkdBS0EtU19VQTRYdjhCVGVOZFN4Ui1BMkdqakZ6NS1UMU8zenZJWXV5LTVhQUlkZXlVdWRaSkwwaDAyaXBaaWVDTWc2RTBVb3BQeDBEeUtjMHJlTjBlS2RLM3R5dGE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTE9wMk55TXVtV3BEVkdBS0EtU19VQTRYdjhCVGVOZFN4Ui1BMkdqakZ6NS1UMU8zenZJWXV5LTVhQUlkZXlVdWRaSkwwaDAyaXBaaWVDTWc2RTBVb3BQeDBEeUtjMHJlTjBlS2RLM3R5dGE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:15:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold price holds losses despite safe-haven demand amid market caution - FXStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Price Declines Despite Safe-Haven Demand Amid Market Caution</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Currently Unavailable <strong>Source:</strong> FXStreet</p>
<img src="https://editorial.fxsstatic.com/miscelaneous/image-638708606600940092.png" alt="Gold Price Daily Chart">
<figcaption>Gold Price Daily Chart</figcaption>
<p>Gold prices are experiencing a decline despite safe-haven demand as traders anticipate signals from the US economy.</p>
<ul>
<li>Gold price decreases as traders await clues about the US economy.</li>
<li>The metal finds support from increased expectations of Fed rate cuts due to US PCE inflation data.</li>
<li>The ongoing geopolitical tensions may further boost gold prices.</li>
<li>Gold has a remarkable 27% annual gain, its best performance since 2010.</li>
<li>Gold's price remains under pressure from a strengthening US dollar.</li>
<li>Geopolitical developments, such as the Russia-Ukraine conflict and recent airstrikes in Gaza, are impacting prices.</li>
<li>The Federal Reserve's cautious stance on rate cuts also influences market sentiment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Gold is often viewed as a safe-haven asset during turbulent times.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while gold faces downward pressure from a strong dollar, its safe-haven appeal remains significant amid geopolitical uncertainties and potential monetary easing from the Federal Reserve.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-depreciates-amid-light-trading-downside-seems-limited-due-to-safe-haven-demand-202412270147</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-depreciates-amid-light-trading-downside-seems-limited-due-to-safe-haven-demand-202412270147</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Incremental investment in cement sector will come only when profitability improves: Report | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNYmhOcXY0OC0yREtxSHFhMk9aNWs2NUlHWURqMjR2cjNoTVZUTEtRcG9kU0E3TllOOG41Qnc5cnJTLVJUdVNIWnR4aC1JeDRDZzNwcHA0RjlQV3puWldxSUdpSjVReFZ0ZncwSDhnYmNwRkZQWXc2VGUySzI4RDRKeVpBeTdPSmZWZDRTZWQwZXBjTFlZc3VObEVLeTc0SjBzeFpjWXA2aXN6R19qMXVVV2hndVltdmgzVGdIT2dDMFZhajZlLURRb1Q5MlBiUVY2S3RremlyR2M2NHZzQjczVlZ6b9IB6AFBVV95cUxQN2ttdkFTd2Rac1hrQ1dPNDl0ZndlOThVdFk5a29yVFIwdHAwMmVTUmhqUFdXN1VNT3NIc1NRU3ctR2w0MWVxaktaaTl1VThKVHYxTWpVc1U3R3VYcWJoRGx3OTNiOEdfRkktSFhxdVl1NlZGaDcyNkJDcFVUWThVeW9LQUZ6WDVQV0tLSEoxSFVMdV82MmxoR19PYWJ3bjNHZTdlV2p2N0ZKMm8yUHRHWVBJSy1idHRxclJIZWFORHduMlVObzNVeE5XNW0yUG5kbHhkRkVMRFlQbXZiVTZwd3h4dVpVMTl3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNYmhOcXY0OC0yREtxSHFhMk9aNWs2NUlHWURqMjR2cjNoTVZUTEtRcG9kU0E3TllOOG41Qnc5cnJTLVJUdVNIWnR4aC1JeDRDZzNwcHA0RjlQV3puWldxSUdpSjVReFZ0ZncwSDhnYmNwRkZQWXc2VGUySzI4RDRKeVpBeTdPSmZWZDRTZWQwZXBjTFlZc3VObEVLeTc0SjBzeFpjWXA2aXN6R19qMXVVV2hndVltdmgzVGdIT2dDMFZhajZlLURRb1Q5MlBiUVY2S3RremlyR2M2NHZzQjczVlZ6b9IB6AFBVV95cUxQN2ttdkFTd2Rac1hrQ1dPNDl0ZndlOThVdFk5a29yVFIwdHAwMmVTUmhqUFdXN1VNT3NIc1NRU3ctR2w0MWVxaktaaTl1VThKVHYxTWpVc1U3R3VYcWJoRGx3OTNiOEdfRkktSFhxdVl1NlZGaDcyNkJDcFVUWThVeW9LQUZ6WDVQV0tLSEoxSFVMdV82MmxoR19PYWJ3bjNHZTdlV2p2N0ZKMm8yUHRHWVBJSy1idHRxclJIZWFORHduMlVObzNVeE5XNW0yUG5kbHhkRkVMRFlQbXZiVTZwd3h4dVpVMTl3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:55:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru foodie spends ₹5 lakh on a single restaurant visit, gets shout-out from Zomato - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru foodie spends ₹5 lakh on a single restaurant visit, gets shout-out from Zomato</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/pexels-olly-3907161_1735278127739_1735278133479.jpg" alt="A Bengaluru foodie spent over ₹5 lakh on a single bill while eating out" title="A Bengaluru foodie spent over ₹5 lakh on a single bill while eating out"><figcaption>A Bengaluru foodie spent over ₹5 lakh on a single bill while eating out</figcaption><p>This article highlights a foodie in Bengaluru who spent an outrageous ₹5 lakh on a single restaurant visit, as reported by Zomato in its year-end statistics report for 2024.</p><ul><li>A Bengaluru food lover spent ₹5,13,733 on one restaurant bill.</li><li>Zomato revealed that 2024 saw more than 9 crore biryani orders in India.</li><li>Indians reserved over 1 crore tables through Zomato between January 1 and December 6, 2024.</li><li>Delhi residents saved ₹195 crore on dining out bills, making it the most budget-friendly city.</li><li>For the ninth consecutive year, biryani was the most-ordered dish in India.</li><li>Tea emerged as the most-ordered beverage, surpassing coffee.</li></ul><blockquote>Zomato stated, 'A nation of biryani lovers, for sure.'</blockquote><p>The takeaway is that food trends in India continue to thrive, with considerable spending on dining out and biryani maintaining its popularity among Indians.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/bengaluru-foodie-spends-rs-5-lakh-on-single-restaurant-visit-gets-shout-out-from-zomato-101735277916389.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/bengaluru-foodie-spends-rs-5-lakh-on-single-restaurant-visit-gets-shout-out-from-zomato-101735277916389.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:43:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NMDC share price: Stock trades ex-date for issuance of 2:1 bonus shares | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNWjE1YlM3TVpMSmNnODNzV085cVBnWXBzZ0lQSWhjRXg4dm0yRUljX1UwTnZvX043blpYS2F4ckFobTA4R3FFeGkzM3JsemNvTTd2WFp3M1NuN3d5Zm0wUF9sSGVNcFV6cmU3X1VzVkl1OWl1WDJrczlXQV9DaThDVHVzOU9PVy1Zdkw4SUJRNnh2dlkteVlCYWdpMFZPWllRRi1COFVucWVWT0lOY1JiNlBmNjVMV2duOWoxNkk2X0FUY3F3ZTVJR2ZyQlJENDZqWmo0NFk2VdIB3AFBVV95cUxQcjM3TmxYVmZaN2djRUFET2lrZDR4eWVMa2VOVWFibzZqekw3WEQtb1h3aVBHaUxfdmdlelRzdlpRZkNwVU5hXzdob3lnMUhFRzVDQjNhaHRvUGtBTU5UekxqUWdtLWo3YmRhMldqQVdSak1SOVJJZXhnbWZibUl2Y1gxOTdYZFEydGM2ampBcmVjZUJSelctbW5fWjRmOHIwMkJmUlFkS0I2TlJvNlVBOHdTWFBhNmVFWVpEOHlyNFQyR3JmY0sxVXFGTnBDYlpWTkFJRDBVcDhJOVVm?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNWjE1YlM3TVpMSmNnODNzV085cVBnWXBzZ0lQSWhjRXg4dm0yRUljX1UwTnZvX043blpYS2F4ckFobTA4R3FFeGkzM3JsemNvTTd2WFp3M1NuN3d5Zm0wUF9sSGVNcFV6cmU3X1VzVkl1OWl1WDJrczlXQV9DaThDVHVzOU9PVy1Zdkw4SUJRNnh2dlkteVlCYWdpMFZPWllRRi1COFVucWVWT0lOY1JiNlBmNjVMV2duOWoxNkk2X0FUY3F3ZTVJR2ZyQlJENDZqWmo0NFk2VdIB3AFBVV95cUxQcjM3TmxYVmZaN2djRUFET2lrZDR4eWVMa2VOVWFibzZqekw3WEQtb1h3aVBHaUxfdmdlelRzdlpRZkNwVU5hXzdob3lnMUhFRzVDQjNhaHRvUGtBTU5UekxqUWdtLWo3YmRhMldqQVdSak1SOVJJZXhnbWZibUl2Y1gxOTdYZFEydGM2ampBcmVjZUJSelctbW5fWjRmOHIwMkJmUlFkS0I2TlJvNlVBOHdTWFBhNmVFWVpEOHlyNFQyR3JmY0sxVXFGTnBDYlpWTkFJRDBVcDhJOVVm?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:43:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCLT admits Hero Electric to insolvency process over unpaid dues of ₹1.8 crore - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hero Electric Admitted to Insolvency by NCLT Over ₹1.8 Crore Dues</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 27 Dec 2024, 5:37 am</p><p>The National Company Law Tribunal (NCLT) in Delhi has initiated the Corporate Insolvency Resolution Process (CIRP) for Hero Electric following a petition from Metro Tyres over unpaid dues amounting to ₹1.8 crore.</p><ul><li>The petition was filed by Metro Tyres Ltd regarding unpaid dues from goods supplied between August and December 2022.</li><li>Hero Electric disputed the petition, citing quality issues with the supplied goods and discrepancies in account reconciliation.</li><li>The NCLT found Hero Electric's claims unconvincing, labeling them 'moonshine defence' and 'afterthought'.</li><li>Bhoopesh Gupta has been appointed as the Interim Resolution Professional to oversee operations of Hero Electric.</li><li>Hero Electric has been instructed to deposit ₹2,00,000 with the IRP for initial expenses.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Corporate Debtor has not been able to raise a plausible contention regarding the pre-existence of 'dispute' between the parties.”</blockquote><p>The NCLT's decision marks a significant step towards resolving the financial irregularities faced by Hero Electric, signaling a focus on creditor interests and accountability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/nclt-admits-hero-electric-insolvency-process-unpaid-dues-18-crore</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/nclt-admits-hero-electric-insolvency-process-unpaid-dues-18-crore</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:37:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IPO listings: With 147% premium, Mamata Machinery dazzles; other four issues also see decent listings - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IPO listings: With 147% premium, Mamata Machinery dazzles; other four issues also see decent listings</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p>
<p>This year has marked a record-breaking period for IPOs in India, with a total fundraising of ₹1.6 lakh crore. Mamata Machinery notably listed with a premium of 147%, alongside other companies that also saw positive market responses.</p>
<ul>
<li>Mamata Machinery listed with a 146.91% premium at ₹600, significantly oversubscribed 195 times.</li>
<li>Transrail Lighting listed at ₹590, a premium of 36.57% over the issue price.</li>
<li>DAM Capital Advisors had a listing premium of 38.8% at ₹393.</li>
<li>Sanathan Textiles debuted at ₹422.3, reflecting a 31.56% premium.</li>
<li>Concord Enviro Systems listed at ₹826, a 17.8% premium.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The primary market in 2024 has been characterized by substantial economic growth and favorable market conditions."</blockquote>
<p>The remarkable performance of these IPOs indicates a healthy sentiment in the Indian equity market, laying a strong foundation for future listings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/ipo-listings-with-147-premium-mamata-machinery-dazzles-other-four-issues-also-see-decent-listings/article-137187/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/ipo-listings-with-147-premium-mamata-machinery-dazzles-other-four-issues-also-see-decent-listings/article-137187/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:36:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PSU banks to cross ₹1.5 lakh cr profit in FY'25, low deposit mobilisation concern | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Public Sector Banks Expected to Surpass ₹1.5 Lakh Crore Profit in FY’25 Amid Deposit Concerns</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><p>Public sector banks (PSBs) are projected to exceed profits of ₹1.5 lakh crore in the fiscal year 2024-25, driven by low non-performing assets (NPAs) and strong credit growth.</p><ul><li>PSBs reported a 25% increase in net profit to ₹85,520 crore in H1’FY25.</li><li>The highest-ever net profit recorded was ₹1.41 lakh crore in FY24.</li><li>Gross NPA ratio improved to 3.12% as of September 2024, down from 14.58% in March 2018.</li><li>CRAR rose to 15.43%, exceeding RBI’s minimum requirement.</li><li>Challenges include slower deposit growth compared to credit growth and rising digital fraud incidents.</li></ul><blockquote>“We expect deposit rates to decline with a lag even if the rate cuts were to start from the upcoming MPC meeting.” - Sachin Sachdeva, ICRA Vice President</blockquote><p>Despite facing challenges like slower deposit growth and digital fraud, the banking sector's profitability is forecasted to remain strong as it continues to support economic growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/company-results/psu-banks-to-cross-rs-1-5-lakh-cr-profit-in-fy-25-low-deposit-mobilisation-concern-11735277583212.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/company-results/psu-banks-to-cross-rs-1-5-lakh-cr-profit-in-fy-25-low-deposit-mobilisation-concern-11735277583212.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:33:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unimech Aerospace IPO allotment on December 27: Steps to check status online - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unimech Aerospace IPO allotment on December 27: Steps to check status online</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBCTV18</p><img alt="Unimech Aerospace IPO allotment on December 27: Steps to check status online" title="Unimech Aerospace IPO allotment on December 27: Steps to check status online" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Unimech Aerospace IPO allotment on December 27: Steps to check status online</figcaption><p>The ₹500-crore IPO of Unimech Aerospace, which was open for subscription from December 23 to December 26, saw an overwhelming response, being oversubscribed by 175 times.</p><ul><li>IPO allotment will be finalised on December 27.</li><li>Shares will debut on the BSE and NSE on December 31.</li><li>Qualified Institutional Buyers subscribed 317.63 times, Non-Institutional Investors 264 times, and retail investors 56.74 times their allocation.</li><li>Steps to check allotment status are provided via the BSE and KFin Technologies websites.</li></ul><blockquote>“The price band for the issue was set between ₹745 and ₹785 per share.”</blockquote><p>Proceeds from the IPO will be used for various corporate purposes, including acquiring machinery and repaying borrowings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/unimech-aerospace-ipo-allotment-december-27-gmp-latest-steps-to-check-status-online-19530421.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/unimech-aerospace-ipo-allotment-december-27-gmp-latest-steps-to-check-status-online-19530421.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:26:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four AI predictions for 2025 - Financial Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Four AI Predictions for 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Financial Times</p>
<p>This article explores the future of AI development as we head into 2025, discussing potential obstacles, the emergence of 'killer apps', Nvidia's dominance in chip manufacturing, and the ongoing AI boom in the stock market.</p>
<ul>
<li>AI development may slow down, yielding diminishing returns from larger models.</li>
<li>New AI models aim to reason better by refining their responses through multiple steps.</li>
<li>Generative AI tools are expected to improve, but true 'killer apps' may remain elusive.</li>
<li>Nvidia faces competition in the chip market but maintains a significant lead due to its software capabilities.</li>
<li>The stock market may continue to exhibit volatile reactions to AI advancements amidst varying economic factors.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Even some of the tech industry’s biggest optimists have conceded...that simply throwing more data and computing power into training ever-larger AI models...is starting to yield diminishing returns."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while AI shows promise for the future, challenges persist, and the landscape remains dynamic and uncertain as technology continues to evolve.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ft.com/content/9978baaf-1f48-4e2c-bcfc-dc34d48e6e4c</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ft.com/content/9978baaf-1f48-4e2c-bcfc-dc34d48e6e4c</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Newmalayalam Steel shares list flat at ₹90 apiece on NSE SME, decline 5% to hit lower circuit - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Newmalayalam Steel Shares Debut Flat on NSE, Hit Lower Circuit</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Upstox</p>
<p>Newmalayalam Steel Ltd made a muted debut on the NSE SME platform, listing flat at ₹90 per share before declining to hit the lower circuit.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shares began trading at ₹90 and fell 5% to ₹85.5.</li>
  <li>Over 3.82 lakh shares were traded, totaling ₹3.44 crore in value.</li>
  <li>The company's market capitalization reached ₹147.81 crore.</li>
  <li>IPO auction was open from December 19 to December 23, raising ₹41.76 crore.</li>
  <li>IPO heavily oversubscribed at 50.73 times with strong demand from retail investors.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"IPO investors who bagged shares in the allotment would not have made any gains after listing of the stock."</blockquote>
<p>The company aims to use IPO proceeds for technological upgrades and expanding solar facilities, which signifies an intent to enhance operational efficiency.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/newmalayalam-steel-shares-list-flat-at-90-apiece-on-nse-sme-decline-5-to-hit-lower-circuit/article-137182/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/newmalayalam-steel-shares-list-flat-at-90-apiece-on-nse-sme-decline-5-to-hit-lower-circuit/article-137182/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:55:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UltraTech acquires 8.7% stake in Star Cement for ₹851 crore; shares surge 7% - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UltraTech Acquires 8.7% Stake in Star Cement for ₹851 Crore; Shares Surge 7%</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>UltraTech Cement has acquired an 8.7% stake in Star Cement for ₹851 crore. Following this announcement, shares of Star Cement increased by over 7%.</p><img src="path_to_image.jpg" alt="UltraTech Cement Logo"><figcaption>UltraTech Cement Logo</figcaption><p>The acquisition involves the purchase of 3.70 crore equity shares at a maximum price of ₹235 each. This non-controlling stake reflects UltraTech's growing influence in the cement market.</p><ul><li>UltraTech Cement purchases an 8.7% stake in Star Cement.</li><li>The total investment is ₹851 crore.</li><li>Star Cement's shares surged 7% post-announcement.</li><li>The acquisition was approved by UltraTech’s Board of Directors.</li><li>Star Cement is a leading manufacturer in northeast India.</li></ul><blockquote>“Some promoter and promoter group entities of Star Cement propose to sell their equity holding…”</blockquote><p>This acquisition is part of UltraTech's recent expansion efforts, which also include a majority stake in India Cements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/latest-updates/ultra-tech-acquires-8-7-stake-in-star-cement-for-851-crore-shares-surge-7/article-137184/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/latest-updates/ultra-tech-acquires-8-7-stake-in-star-cement-for-851-crore-shares-surge-7/article-137184/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:54:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 big-bang policy moves Modi government made in 2024 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQUmRpSG1KSm5WMlkyTERQT1ZyRlpLZ3J4c1IxVGRINlRQQTNuOXRTbGRKZklNTV9GNDFScWsxbnF6NlAyMWdwRnBuWEdzMmVjaTltRmdCYU0xZ1dlMzVfZUFLUFp1dGtRVllQaURmZkhKX2tpN25lTnRNU2hveDFpQS0ycThGcmVOREsxckZleDB6WE9EN1lLVnhRZ3pSanZRS0YydkhMeWg1dVNnQmt2YUg3MmRITXdRUXlDbUhDNmdBamFMamfSAcsBQVVfeXFMTm0yYkhubjlMUndEM3VUUzE3QlJ0TjZqRTQ4Z2xEemNkYmlMSFVia2NWSXhDUWFHUDZqVFBBaGxaTUxCd3ppQ1I4ZlRMUDNMZk5NTzdUM2NScGR2RkNNTEJsVFl4R2pvZWZYNU9CV09DOXByall0MnMtcW8zOVNha28tWGRTYmlhWXpGdFhXUmZSTV9tckFOckVDamJQa0tjZHVQcnRoTlZpR3RNOE9iRGw1UzBXLXYtNzQzVktEbXNxbEI3YmltRGNvTG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQUmRpSG1KSm5WMlkyTERQT1ZyRlpLZ3J4c1IxVGRINlRQQTNuOXRTbGRKZklNTV9GNDFScWsxbnF6NlAyMWdwRnBuWEdzMmVjaTltRmdCYU0xZ1dlMzVfZUFLUFp1dGtRVllQaURmZkhKX2tpN25lTnRNU2hveDFpQS0ycThGcmVOREsxckZleDB6WE9EN1lLVnhRZ3pSanZRS0YydkhMeWg1dVNnQmt2YUg3MmRITXdRUXlDbUhDNmdBamFMamfSAcsBQVVfeXFMTm0yYkhubjlMUndEM3VUUzE3QlJ0TjZqRTQ4Z2xEemNkYmlMSFVia2NWSXhDUWFHUDZqVFBBaGxaTUxCd3ppQ1I4ZlRMUDNMZk5NTzdUM2NScGR2RkNNTEJsVFl4R2pvZWZYNU9CV09DOXByall0MnMtcW8zOVNha28tWGRTYmlhWXpGdFhXUmZSTV9tckFOckVDamJQa0tjZHVQcnRoTlZpR3RNOE9iRGw1UzBXLXYtNzQzVktEbXNxbEI3YmltRGNvTG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:53:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee hits record low on strong NDF dollar bids; RBI likely steps in - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee hits record low on strong NDF dollar bids; RBI likely steps in</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img decoding="async" src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/12/20241216070038_Market_down1.jpeg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="The dollar index was a tad higher at 108.1, while Asian currencies were down between 0.1% and 1%." title="The dollar index was a tad higher at 108.1, while Asian currencies were down between 0.1% and 1%."><figcaption>The dollar index was a tad higher at 108.1, while Asian currencies were down between 0.1% and 1%.</figcaption><p>The Indian rupee has fallen to a record low, reaching 85.3950 against the dollar as strong demand in the non-deliverable forwards market persists. The Reserve Bank of India is expected to intervene to support the currency.</p><ul><li>The rupee reached an all-time low of 85.3950, surpassing the previous low of 85.2825.</li><li>This decline is attributed to strong dollar demand and India's widening trade deficit.</li><li>Amit Pabari of CR Forex suggests that pressure on the rupee may continue, predicting it will trade between 85 and 85.50 in the near term.</li></ul><blockquote>“The pressure on the currency is likely to persist, driven by month-end dollar demand from local oil companies.”</blockquote><p>This significant drop in the value of the rupee underscores ongoing economic challenges in India, with potential implications for both domestic and international markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/currency/rupee-hits-record-low-on-strong-ndf-dollar-bids-rbi-likely-steps-in-12898677.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/currency/rupee-hits-record-low-on-strong-ndf-dollar-bids-rbi-likely-steps-in-12898677.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:33:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>