<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:17:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:17:40 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Axes Diversity Initiatives Before Trump's Return, Meta Orders Tampon Removal From Men's Bathrooms - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amazon Cuts Diversity Programs and Meta Removes Tampons from Men's Bathrooms Ahead of Trump's Return</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Mark Zuckerberg (AP Image)"><figcaption>Mark Zuckerberg (AP Image)</figcaption></figure><p>Ahead of Donald Trump’s return as the US President, Amazon.com is scaling back its diversity programmes amid rising conservative criticism, while Meta has decided to remove tampons from men’s bathrooms as part of a broader rollback of diversity initiatives.</p><ul><li>Amazon announces the phase-out of outdated diversity and inclusion programmes by the end of 2024.</li><li>Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg orders the removal of sanitary products provided for non-binary and transgender employees.</li><li>These changes come amid a backlash against diversity initiatives following conservative critiques and a US Supreme Court ruling on affirmative action.</li><li>Amazon’s founder Jeff Bezos donated $1 million to Trump’s inaugural committee.</li><li>Meta's internal memo indicates a significant shift in how DEI efforts are perceived in a changing legal landscape.</li></ul><blockquote>“The legal and policy landscape surrounding diversity, equity, and inclusion efforts in the United States is changing.” - Janelle Gale, Meta’s VP of HR</blockquote><p>The decisions by Amazon and Meta illustrate the growing tension surrounding DEI programs in corporate America, highlighting a shift in company policies influenced by political pressures. The future of such initiatives remains uncertain as companies respond to shifting social perspectives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/amazon-axes-diversity-programmes-before-trumps-return-meta-orders-tampon-removal-from-bathrooms-9185264.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/amazon-axes-diversity-programmes-before-trumps-return-meta-orders-tampon-removal-from-bathrooms-9185264.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 09:01:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Perplexity AI CEO Aravind Srinivas announces hiring plans to expand operations in India - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Perplexity AI CEO Aravind Srinivas Unveils Hiring Plans for Expansion in India</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250107080119_perplexity-ai-bbo.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Founded in August 2022 by Srinivas, Denis Yarats, Johnny Ho, and Andy Konwinski, Perplexity AI launched its answer engine in December 2022." title="Founded in August 2022 by Srinivas, Denis Yarats, Johnny Ho, and Andy Konwinski, Perplexity AI launched its answer engine in December 2022.">
<figcaption>Founded in August 2022 by Srinivas, Denis Yarats, Johnny Ho, and Andy Konwinski, Perplexity AI launched its answer engine in December 2022.</figcaption>
<p>Artificial Intelligence (AI)-powered search startup Perplexity AI is looking to hire a candidate to help expand its operations in India.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The role requires candidates to be based in India, work in a startup environment, and travel to meet strategic partners and institutions.</li>
  <li>This hiring initiative comes as Perplexity AI has gained popularity, amassing over a million users in India.</li>
  <li>Founded in August 2022, the company recently closed a $500 million funding round, increasing its valuation to $9 billion.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Perplexity AI has garnered more than a million users in India, reflecting the growing popularity of the service.”</blockquote>
<p>This expansion signifies a crucial step for Perplexity AI as it aims to strengthen its market presence in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/startup/perplexity-ai-ceo-aravind-srinivas-announces-hiring-plans-to-expand-operations-in-india-12907952.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/startup/perplexity-ai-ceo-aravind-srinivas-announces-hiring-plans-to-expand-operations-in-india-12907952.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 06:19:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to buy under ₹100: Experts recommend three shares to buy on Monday — 13 January 2025 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to buy under ₹100: Experts recommend three shares to buy on Monday — 13 January 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 13 January 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><div><p>The Indian stock market continues to show bearish trends despite recent activity in IT stocks. With the Nifty 50 and BSE Sensex experiencing significant declines, experts recommend three shares to consider buying under ₹100 in the upcoming week.</p></div><ul><li>Ola Electric: Buy at ₹72, target ₹77, stop loss at ₹69.80.</li><li>Jayaswal Neco Industries: Buy between ₹37.50 - ₹39, with targets of ₹41.50, ₹44, and ₹47; stop loss at ₹35.</li><li>BMW Industries: Buy at ₹51, target ₹55, stop loss at ₹49.</li></ul><blockquote>“India's GDP growth is expected to fall to a four-year low of 6.4% in 2025” - Siddhartha Khemka, Motilal Oswal</blockquote><p>Experts suggest caution in the market due to ongoing negative trends, with critical indicators to watch in the coming days.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stocks-to-buy-under-rs-100-experts-recommend-three-shares-to-buy-on-monday-13-january-2025-11736573520703.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stocks-to-buy-under-rs-100-experts-recommend-three-shares-to-buy-on-monday-13-january-2025-11736573520703.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:43:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rs 770 DIVIDEND paid in 2024; next announcement on Feb 5 - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rs 770 Dividend Paid in 2024; Next Announcement on Feb 5</h1>
<p><strong>Updated Jan 11, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW News</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Dividend stock" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Dividend stock: The company has paid total Rs 770 dividend in CY 2024. (Image: Shutterstock/ iStock/ ET NOW News)</figcaption>
<p>A BSE 200-listed company has paid a cumulative dividend of Rs 770 in CY 2024 and will announce its next dividend during a board meeting on February 5, 2025.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The company declared dividends on four occasions in CY 2024: Rs 100, Rs 120, Rs 300, and Rs 250.</li>
  <li>Current dividend yield stands at 1.65% at the market price.</li>
  <li>The stock discussed is Page Industries, the exclusive seller of Jockey International in several regions.</li>
  <li>The board meeting will also announce the unaudited financial results for the quarter ended December 31, 2024.</li>
  <li>Record date for the upcoming dividend is set as February 13, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Page Industries has posted an 18.5% return over the past six months and a 24.8% return in the last year, compared to a negative return of 3.2% for the Sensex over the same period."</blockquote>
<p>This announcement signifies the company's ongoing commitment to returning value to its shareholders amid market fluctuations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/rs-770-dividend-paid-in-2024-next-announcement-by-page-industries-on-feb-5-article-117138275</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/rs-770-dividend-paid-in-2024-next-announcement-by-page-industries-on-feb-5-article-117138275</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:43:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rs 76 DIVIDEND Stock - Tata company fixes ex-date, RECORD date, payment date - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>TCS Announces Rs 76 Dividend: Key Dates and Details</h1><p><strong>Updated on:</strong> <strong>Jan 11, 2025</strong> by <strong>ET NOW</strong></p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="tcs dividend 2025"><figcaption>Tata Consultancy Services announces Rs 76 dividend for shareholders.</figcaption><p>Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) is set to reward its shareholders with a significant dividend of Rs 76, following the announcement in its Q3 results.</p><ul><li>TCS will pay an interim dividend of Rs 10 and a special dividend of Rs 66.</li><li>The record date for receiving the dividend is set for January 17, 2025.</li><li>The payment date for the dividend is February 3, 2025.</li><li>TCS shares will trade ex-dividend on January 17, 2025.</li><li>The company's dividend history includes previous payments of Rs 75, Rs 117, and Rs 45 in the past three years.</li></ul><blockquote>“We would like to inform you that at the Board Meeting held today, the Directors have declared a third interim dividend of Rs 10 and a special dividend of Rs 66 per Equity Share,” TCS reported.</blockquote><p>This announcement reflects TCS's commitment to its investors, continuing its history of strong dividend payments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/rs-76-dividend-stock-tata-company-fixes-ex-date-record-date-payment-date-article-117138469</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/rs-76-dividend-stock-tata-company-fixes-ex-date-record-date-payment-date-article-117138469</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:18:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian economy likely to be 'a little weaker' in 2025: IMF MD - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IMF Projects Slight Weakness in Indian Economy for 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 11, 2025</strong> / <strong>Source: Moneycontrol</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/02/IMF-Managing-Director-Kristalina-Georgieva.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="IMF Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>IMF Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva</figcaption>
<p>The Indian economy is expected to be "a little weaker" in 2025, as per IMF Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva, who attributes this forecast to uncertainty in global trade policies, particularly from the US.</p>
<ul>
  <li>IMF MD Kristalina Georgieva stated the Indian economy's anticipated weakness despite global growth.</li>
  <li>Concerns raised about regional divergence in economic performance globally.</li>
  <li>Georgieva cited rising long-term interest rates as a global challenge.</li>
  <li>The US economy is performing better than earlier projections, while the EU is experiencing stagnation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The US is doing quite a bit better than we expected before, the EU is somewhat stalling, (and) India a little weaker," said Kristalina Georgieva.</blockquote>
<p>Moving forward, details regarding the Indian economy's trajectory will be further elaborated during the upcoming World Economy Outlook update week.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/indian-economy-likely-to-be-a-little-weaker-in-2025-imf-md-12907905.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/indian-economy-likely-to-be-a-little-weaker-in-2025-imf-md-12907905.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:13:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quadrant Future Tek IPO Allotment Live Updates: Check GMP, listing, and key details - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Quadrant Future Tek IPO Allotment Live Updates</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-11T11:38:41+05:30">January 11, 2025</time></p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p>
<img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-17.jpg?w=1024" alt="Quadrant Future Tek IPO Allotment Status Live: GMP, price band, listing" width="670" height="377">
<figcaption>Quadrant Future Tek IPO Allotment Status Live Updates: The price band of the issue is set between Rs 275 to Rs 290 per share (Image: Canva)</figcaption>
<p>The Quadrant Future Tek IPO, worth Rs 290 crores, was open for bidding from January 7 to January 9. The allotment of shares is likely to be finalized today, January 10, with a debut on BSE and NSE scheduled for January 14.</p>
<ul>
<li>Price band set between Rs 275 to Rs 290 per share.</li>
<li>IPO consists of a fresh issue of 1 crore equity shares.</li>
<li>The minimum investment for retail investors is Rs 14,500 for 50 shares.</li>
<li>Overall subscription rate reached 195.96 times by the third day.</li>
<li>Shares trading at a grey market premium estimating a listing price around Rs 480.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Indian Specialty Cable and Train Control System market is expected to witness significant growth.” - Gaurav Garg, Research Analyst.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the Quadrant Future Tek IPO receives a strong response, with high subscription rates and anticipated listing gains.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/market/ipo-news-quadrant-future-tek-ipo-allotment-live-updates-listing-gmp-price-band-subscription-status-ipo-news-3711654/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/market/ipo-news-quadrant-future-tek-ipo-allotment-live-updates-listing-gmp-price-band-subscription-status-ipo-news-3711654/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:01:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dividend 2025: Rs 105 paid in 2024; ANNOUNCEMENT again on Jan 30 - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dividend Announcement for Shree Cement Scheduled for January 30, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date Updated:</strong> January 11, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW News</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Dividend 2025" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Dividend 2025: At the current market price, the stock's dividend yield stands at 0.41%. (Image: iStock/ET NOW News)</figcaption>
<p>Shree Cement is set to announce its interim dividend for the financial year 2024-25 on January 30, 2025, after previously paying Rs 105 in dividends during 2024.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The previous dividends included Rs 50 interim and Rs 55 final dividends.</li>
    <li>Shree Cement's total dividend in CY 2023 was Rs 100, an increase from Rs 90 in CY 2022.</li>
    <li>The stock has a market cap of Rs 92,837.57 crore and trades on BSE 100.</li>
    <li>The record date to determine eligible shareholders for the dividend is February 5, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>A steady or growing dividend payout is often seen as a sign that a company is financially healthy and optimistic about its future profits.</blockquote>
<p>Shree Cement continues to show a commitment to rewarding shareholders, underscoring its strong market position and operational performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/dividend-2025-rs-105-paid-in-2024-announcement-again-on-jan-30-shree-cement-article-117136891</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/dividend-2025-rs-105-paid-in-2024-announcement-again-on-jan-30-shree-cement-article-117136891</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:33:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg claims Biden officials ‘screamed’ and ‘cursed’ at Meta execs over Covid vaccine posts, ‘It was brutal’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zuckerberg Claims Biden Officials Pressured Meta on Vaccine Posts</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/FILES-US-TECH-MEDIA-0_1736569214701_1736569244550.jpg" alt="Mark Zuckerberg alleges Biden officials ‘screamed’ and ‘cursed’ at Meta execs remove Covid vaccine posts (Photo by ANDREW CABALLERO-REYNOLDS / AFP)(AFP)"><figcaption>Mark Zuckerberg alleges Biden officials ‘screamed’ and ‘cursed’ at Meta execs remove Covid vaccine posts (Photo by ANDREW CABALLERO-REYNOLDS / AFP)(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>In a recent interview with Joe Rogan, Mark Zuckerberg claimed that officials from the Biden administration pressured Meta executives to remove posts regarding the COVID-19 vaccine. He described the conversations as “brutal” and criticized the government's approach towards tech companies.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Zuckerberg alleges Biden officials “screamed” at Meta, demanding the removal of negative vaccine posts.</li>
  <li>He stated that they also pressured Meta to censor accurate information about vaccine side effects.</li>
  <li>Zuckerberg expressed regret over past decisions made under government pressure.</li>
  <li>He noted a shift in Meta's fact-checking policy to a user-driven “community notes” system.</li>
  <li>Biden previously criticized Meta's decision not to fact-check under its new policy.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The US government should be defending its companies, not be at the tip of the spear attacking its companies.” - Mark Zuckerberg</blockquote>
<p>This controversy underscores ongoing tensions between government authorities and social media platforms regarding the management of public health information.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/mark-zuckerberg-alleges-biden-officials-screamed-and-cursed-at-meta-execs-remove-covid-vaccine-posts-101736568887669.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/mark-zuckerberg-alleges-biden-officials-screamed-and-cursed-at-meta-execs-remove-covid-vaccine-posts-101736568887669.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:26:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HDFC Bank revises fixed deposit (FD) interest rates: A comparison with SBI, Axis, and Punjab National Bank | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/hdfc-bank-revises-fixed-deposit-fd-interest-rates-a-comparison-with-sbi-axis-and-punjab-national-bank-11736563396112.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/hdfc-bank-revises-fixed-deposit-fd-interest-rates-a-comparison-with-sbi-axis-and-punjab-national-bank-11736563396112.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:21:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HDFC Bank revises fixed deposit (FD) interest rates: A comparison with SBI, Axis, and Punjab National Bank | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/hdfc-bank-revises-fixed-deposit-fd-interest-rates-a-comparison-with-sbi-axis-and-punjab-national-bank-11736563396112.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/hdfc-bank-revises-fixed-deposit-fd-interest-rates-a-comparison-with-sbi-axis-and-punjab-national-bank-11736563396112.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:21:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cognizant gives a different hike as IT co changes retirement age from 58 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxONDNadDFYdWJ4dkFscG5RNlpseW5OZlpZLTJVRDEzeGlRRjZhVVZSQ3FuclF2aXZROGI3SUFidUNRYkJnb0hsZ3NweDgxT19HSURiWW9BcVh1R0x3MGRKXzg4LUxJQzRpNGg1RTJubFA3aXVPQjEtQU5DYXJWalhKaFNITk1wOEZ4WXZBa2t4VU5EWmlQZnpjczk3Um9CZUdyUkhNeldjalZnTzluWi11TGRxekZkdDU5MWRwWFVhR2VtZmJMeVlnR29QSjAxYTFPZENpZEp4bS11dnJMZkVkZmdsTW5fYnhaQjRiRDdn0gHzAUFVX3lxTE1NVEpqRDRtMG4zWWI3V0oyOGtUR0l3NEd1ZHJPYzBUOW5GM0FrN0gzYlVSLWlrZnQtWkQwMEFzN3JzZjhObmxwVloxaklNSFp6X0NscDVUMHVCM0hGWC1CX2JDRFlMcU40UkctYUZtS1ItandmQ04wOVVVOWllUHhDS1FrRzBPOEhFTDdlQ09PYi01akcxQzhlb01VTXpHa2g5eWVPalU4aTBCY3h0RVZhcy12dm52N0F1YjZNNkRtTVEwTFJhaHZfMFc0QktzRGpuVTlnNXN1V0lISzJ1S1IyUjBOd0V0X0daTTlMb2JOemFiOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxONDNadDFYdWJ4dkFscG5RNlpseW5OZlpZLTJVRDEzeGlRRjZhVVZSQ3FuclF2aXZROGI3SUFidUNRYkJnb0hsZ3NweDgxT19HSURiWW9BcVh1R0x3MGRKXzg4LUxJQzRpNGg1RTJubFA3aXVPQjEtQU5DYXJWalhKaFNITk1wOEZ4WXZBa2t4VU5EWmlQZnpjczk3Um9CZUdyUkhNeldjalZnTzluWi11TGRxekZkdDU5MWRwWFVhR2VtZmJMeVlnR29QSjAxYTFPZENpZEp4bS11dnJMZkVkZmdsTW5fYnhaQjRiRDdn0gHzAUFVX3lxTE1NVEpqRDRtMG4zWWI3V0oyOGtUR0l3NEd1ZHJPYzBUOW5GM0FrN0gzYlVSLWlrZnQtWkQwMEFzN3JzZjhObmxwVloxaklNSFp6X0NscDVUMHVCM0hGWC1CX2JDRFlMcU40UkctYUZtS1ItandmQ04wOVVVOWllUHhDS1FrRzBPOEhFTDdlQ09PYi01akcxQzhlb01VTXpHa2g5eWVPalU4aTBCY3h0RVZhcy12dm52N0F1YjZNNkRtTVEwTFJhaHZfMFc0QktzRGpuVTlnNXN1V0lISzJ1S1IyUjBOd0V0X0daTTlMb2JOemFiOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:19:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top India Car News Of The Week (January 6-10): Hyundai Creta Electric New Details Revealed, Tata Tiago, Tiago EV, And Tigor Get Model Year Updates, Mahindra BE 6 And XEV 9e Prices Out, And More - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxNVjlpMmIyaU9PTXp5RWNEYzhnb3YtQ2pMYXhRcEJqS1ZqeU9LeW41VWJQUHFLdlNmclRVckxONm5rU3l6ODVRcjRrZWFMT3YtVUFuSXhrTWJ1dUtzUWVudUw2RlZORmVTTWVKMFEzWUl1UDlCb1VlMnp1bGtGZ18zd0FzcllvaTdEVHlVQnF5dUppODZjbUFvNWI4U3VBZ2cybnVmTEJrV0JGQ2xmQU1HNjJLUUpkdVVqdFNHNzhDdlo4TmxVZ3E0aFlaVWNWdmpFelExNU9UeFpFb1c2aHFYTEJUNjBWT012cXV4TGYzMWxZUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxNVjlpMmIyaU9PTXp5RWNEYzhnb3YtQ2pMYXhRcEJqS1ZqeU9LeW41VWJQUHFLdlNmclRVckxONm5rU3l6ODVRcjRrZWFMT3YtVUFuSXhrTWJ1dUtzUWVudUw2RlZORmVTTWVKMFEzWUl1UDlCb1VlMnp1bGtGZ18zd0FzcllvaTdEVHlVQnF5dUppODZjbUFvNWI4U3VBZ2cybnVmTEJrV0JGQ2xmQU1HNjJLUUpkdVVqdFNHNzhDdlo4TmxVZ3E0aFlaVWNWdmpFelExNU9UeFpFb1c2aHFYTEJUNjBWT012cXV4TGYzMWxZUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian economy likely to be 'a little weaker' in 2025: IMF MD - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxOWGltc1czTmFleG1mRFo5Qmt6LWZOQzR1dDI5SFBfc1RVRDdXT2ZMV0NvZjBHeVBiaVpOYTRaUk5BelZhOHViODQtbmxTZmdRNGZQTDBIS1hHTVR2ZlVBZFZiUWxNWlJOVFNGVXhBWURDdWVJSklBaEdlVTh2eUhIWWN6d2ZxaUVfVWw3ZTZleUpEZ0lPdGdfeUxtMmVJZi1VWkFEUVhIUkdNWHB3enZSWHh2RHdUR2pXNnNVOHhVamlfNVpBQ3hVS3hncVIwYlR2bmfSAdcBQVVfeXFMUDZobTRMVHNKdFI1S2NzXzZHV2RuSVpZVXhzNUd2YkJvNEc3VTlmOWJGMldybE9zQkprMHM5TVk3eEdrZFpYSDRsSTJPTjVJU1FYeGNIUEczUW9GZl9ocE9abW9IM1dNR2xOMk1jbGxLcndQYXFxS3ZLT1BoR1lrWEhpV1hjaUZJUEFQNm5faWNfbk00X0VQdVVoNGFCUnNWZGE4SkUyT3NTRlVwa3FtOFpTZXpORmNvWG02cGYyVFpDaDZDRzB5WEk1aGpJS1R0d3JCSFZxUzA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxOWGltc1czTmFleG1mRFo5Qmt6LWZOQzR1dDI5SFBfc1RVRDdXT2ZMV0NvZjBHeVBiaVpOYTRaUk5BelZhOHViODQtbmxTZmdRNGZQTDBIS1hHTVR2ZlVBZFZiUWxNWlJOVFNGVXhBWURDdWVJSklBaEdlVTh2eUhIWWN6d2ZxaUVfVWw3ZTZleUpEZ0lPdGdfeUxtMmVJZi1VWkFEUVhIUkdNWHB3enZSWHh2RHdUR2pXNnNVOHhVamlfNVpBQ3hVS3hncVIwYlR2bmfSAdcBQVVfeXFMUDZobTRMVHNKdFI1S2NzXzZHV2RuSVpZVXhzNUd2YkJvNEc3VTlmOWJGMldybE9zQkprMHM5TVk3eEdrZFpYSDRsSTJPTjVJU1FYeGNIUEczUW9GZl9ocE9abW9IM1dNR2xOMk1jbGxLcndQYXFxS3ZLT1BoR1lrWEhpV1hjaUZJUEFQNm5faWNfbk00X0VQdVVoNGFCUnNWZGE4SkUyT3NTRlVwa3FtOFpTZXpORmNvWG02cGYyVFpDaDZDRzB5WEk1aGpJS1R0d3JCSFZxUzA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:12:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[90-hr work week debate: 'Been at work for 100 hrs, but not productive,' Radhika Gupta shares why she felt 'miserable | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>90-hr work week debate: ’Been at work for 100 hrs, but not productive,’ Radhika Gupta shares why she felt ’miserable</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>In her insightful post, Radhika Gupta, CEO of Edelweiss Mutual Fund, reflects on the implications of extreme work hours, sharing her personal experience with a 100-hour work week and advocating for a balanced approach to work and life.</p><ul><li>Gupta participated in the debate sparked by L&T Chairman SN Subrahmanyan about long working hours.</li><li>She recalls that despite working nearly 100 hours, she felt unproductive and miserable.</li><li>Gupta emphasizes that hard work should not be equated with long hours, advocating for sustainable work practices.</li><li>She discusses the importance of work-life balance, family, and mental health in achieving true success.</li></ul><blockquote>“Hard work is not equal to hours worked. Many of those hours in entry-level careers were pure facetime.” — Radhika Gupta</blockquote><p>Gupta points out the risks of compromising personal well-being for career ambitions, particularly for women. She encourages creating a workplace culture that motivates employees rather than imposing rigid hour requirements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/90hr-work-week-debate-been-at-work-for-100-hrs-but-not-productive-radhika-gupta-shares-why-she-felt-miserable-11736567544991.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/90hr-work-week-debate-been-at-work-for-100-hrs-but-not-productive-radhika-gupta-shares-why-she-felt-miserable-11736567544991.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maruti Suzuki Model Wise Sales December 2024 – Dzire, Vitara, Brezza, Baleno - GaadiWaadi.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maruti Suzuki Model Wise Sales December 2024 - Dzire, Vitara, Brezza, Baleno</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> GaadiWaadi</p><figure><img src="https://gaadiwaadi.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/New-Dzire-1068x661.jpg" alt="New Dzire" title="New Dzire" width="1068" height="661"><figcaption>Pic Source: Sreedev S S</figcaption></figure><p>Maruti Suzuki India Limited (MSIL) sold a total of 1,30,115 units in December 2024, marking a 24% year-over-year growth. The Brezza topped sales with 17,336 units, followed closely by the Wagon R and Dzire.</p><ul><li>Total sales in December 2024: 1,30,115 units</li><li>YOY growth compared to December 2023: 24%</li><li>Top-selling models in December 2024:</li><ol><li>Brezza: 17,336 units (35% YOY growth)</li><li>Wagon R: 17,303 units (102% YOY growth)</li><li>Dzire: 16,573 units (18% YOY growth)</li><li>Ertiga: 16,056 units (24% YOY growth)</li></ol><li>Other notable mentions: Jimny saw 51% YOY growth with 1,100 units sold.</li></ul><blockquote><p>The company recorded an 8% decline from November 2024 where it sold 1,41,312 units.</p></blockquote><p>In conclusion, the results for December 2024 reflect strong year-over-year gains for several models, indicating a positive market response for Maruti Suzuki's offerings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://gaadiwaadi.com/maruti-suzuki-model-wise-sales-december-2024-dzire-vitara-brezza-baleno/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gaadiwaadi.com/maruti-suzuki-model-wise-sales-december-2024-dzire-vitara-brezza-baleno/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:00:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[176 smallcap stocks fell in double-digits in a rough week for markets - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>176 Smallcap Stocks Fell in Double-Digits in a Rough Week for Markets</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> Not specified | <strong>Source: </strong> Economic Times</p><figure><img height="158" width="210" alt="176 smallcap stocks fell in double-digits in a rough week for markets" src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-117137035,width-210,height-158,imgsize-115266,resizemode-75/176-smallcap-stocks-fell-in-double-digits-in-a-rough-week-for-markets.jpg"><figcaption>On the contrary, as many as 176 stocks fell in double-digits. Some of the biggest losers were Jai Corp, KEC International, Inox Wind, Skipper, Oriental Rail Infrastructure among others.</figcaption></figure><p>The Indian markets faced substantial selling pressure over the last week due to modest GDP and corporate earnings estimates, resulting in a substantial decline in small-cap stocks.</p><ul><li>Only four smallcap stocks posted double-digit weekly returns.</li><li>Foreign investors sold nearly $2 billion, contributing to negative market sentiment.</li><li>Rising US bond yields continued to influence investor confidence negatively.</li><li>Key macroeconomic indicators, including CPI, will guide future market direction.</li></ul><blockquote>"A spike in crude oil prices will add inflationary pressure. Overall, market volatility is expected to remain as investors react to a mix of earnings, macroeconomic data, and global cues," said Vinod Nair, Head of Research at Geojit Financial.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the upcoming week is critical as corporate earnings and macro data will significantly impact market trends.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/176-smallcap-stocks-fell-in-double-digits-in-a-rough-week-for-markets/articleshow/117137051.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/176-smallcap-stocks-fell-in-double-digits-in-a-rough-week-for-markets/articleshow/117137051.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:59:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zomato share price down 18% in 1 week; what chart suggests? - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/zomato-share-price-down-18-in-1-week-what-chart-suggests-article-117136803</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/zomato-share-price-down-18-in-1-week-what-chart-suggests-article-117136803</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:49:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zomato share price down 18% in 1 week; what chart suggests? - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/zomato-share-price-down-18-in-1-week-what-chart-suggests-article-117136803</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/zomato-share-price-down-18-in-1-week-what-chart-suggests-article-117136803</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:49:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian refiners shift crude strategy amid fears of Russian oil supply shocks - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxOQ2ttYmtpNUkzSXFjZ0t6d2pnd1o5OTRjZXlFQWkxQ1hKZW9VcWMwZktpZ21WTUdoeENZcTctUVl2ZUFBczExMElhNm9VV2piRkRuUjhXUGxQZS13YVp2UkRYNFZpSG1zVGE1ckNVdkJQUEl2WklPRUF4YjNRaU9heFFpcWZwT0RrMTFtX2dMOW9wR2JpT09lbWxYNEFUVVZWVmh0NkIydlR3ajJvTTQwbzFvNENRS3hWX3lPdjU1eEJTTFFWWlNadXhSZlBPdGd2Y19lUFR6eW9mT09Fa2kyZWhfdmJCcFFN0gHuAUFVX3lxTFB3ekZHdy1kVG56LU11ZFpmUWFseE1rUFB0NTdEMlltMWo2TW82cUFob1ZZSWxlaUZMMFo3Wmt6cEpNbVFVZG9KbktkTkVYRmROenZsVjJBSlR4YTAxSldqc3ZPZDQycjZ1QlFmTHlOeU5DR0tJSGlHbVpwVmdMTEFfR3dVTlF3ZzRoZWtwS2E4WVV1cmJJcjNURlI5d3BQdXF3djlnWFR6by1tV2l6WW1hVWdENzBOSEhiTlM2RW5oZGVwZEVJMnpQOG11WDF0dVRocDAzVVhGdjVrdGNqd0ZzRTQ1SlJqRnRMdHpidVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxOQ2ttYmtpNUkzSXFjZ0t6d2pnd1o5OTRjZXlFQWkxQ1hKZW9VcWMwZktpZ21WTUdoeENZcTctUVl2ZUFBczExMElhNm9VV2piRkRuUjhXUGxQZS13YVp2UkRYNFZpSG1zVGE1ckNVdkJQUEl2WklPRUF4YjNRaU9heFFpcWZwT0RrMTFtX2dMOW9wR2JpT09lbWxYNEFUVVZWVmh0NkIydlR3ajJvTTQwbzFvNENRS3hWX3lPdjU1eEJTTFFWWlNadXhSZlBPdGd2Y19lUFR6eW9mT09Fa2kyZWhfdmJCcFFN0gHuAUFVX3lxTFB3ekZHdy1kVG56LU11ZFpmUWFseE1rUFB0NTdEMlltMWo2TW82cUFob1ZZSWxlaUZMMFo3Wmt6cEpNbVFVZG9KbktkTkVYRmROenZsVjJBSlR4YTAxSldqc3ZPZDQycjZ1QlFmTHlOeU5DR0tJSGlHbVpwVmdMTEFfR3dVTlF3ZzRoZWtwS2E4WVV1cmJJcjNURlI5d3BQdXF3djlnWFR6by1tV2l6WW1hVWdENzBOSEhiTlM2RW5oZGVwZEVJMnpQOG11WDF0dVRocDAzVVhGdjVrdGNqd0ZzRTQ1SlJqRnRMdHpidVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:39:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian refiners shift cude strategy amid fears of Russian oil supply shocks - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian Refiners Adjust Crude Strategy Amid Russian Oil Supply Concerns</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>Oil refiners in India and China are increasing crude purchases from the Middle East and Atlantic Basin due to concerns over potential restrictions on Russian and Iranian oil imports.</p><ul><li>Indian state refiners have bought 6 million barrels of Oman and Abu Dhabi's Murban crude.</li><li>Indian Oil Corp. purchased 2 million barrels of WTI Midland crude.</li><li>Chinese buyers are increasing imports of Angolan and Abu Dhabi oil.</li><li>Concerns over potential sanctions have driven the shift in purchasing patterns.</li><li>Global crude futures are rising as trade restrictions tighten on Tehran and Moscow.</li></ul><blockquote>“The surge in buying interest from Indian and Chinese buyers has stemmed not only from fewer and pricier offers of Urals, ESPO and Iranian Light crude...”</blockquote><p>The shift in crude procurement strategies reflects the uncertainties in the global oil supply landscape, particularly regarding Russian and Iranian oil.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/energy/oil-gas/indian-refiners-shift-cude-strategy-amid-fears-of-russian-oil-supply-shocks/articleshow/117136665.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/energy/oil-gas/indian-refiners-shift-cude-strategy-amid-fears-of-russian-oil-supply-shocks/articleshow/117136665.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:39:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nifty Prediction January 2025: RSI in negative crossover; selling to continue? Check support, resistance levels by experts - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nifty Prediction January 2025: RSI in negative crossover; selling to continue?</h1><p><strong>Updated:</strong> January 11, 2025 09:13 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW News</p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Nifty Prediction January 2025"><figcaption>Investors have lost Rs 13.51 lakh crore in the past three days of constant selling.</figcaption><p>The Indian stock market is experiencing a significant downturn as investors react to sustained foreign fund outflows and downward revisions of GDP growth forecasts. The Sensex and Nifty indices have seen considerable declines over the past few days.</p><ul><li>The Sensex has decreased by 8,600 points (10%) from its record high.</li><li>The Nifty 50 index has dropped 2,850 points (10.8%) from its peak.</li><li>Technical analysts indicate a bearish continuation pattern and broken support levels.</li><li>Concerns over economic growth and corporate earnings projections weigh heavily on investor sentiment.</li></ul><blockquote>“The bearish pressure continues to intensify as the index closed below 23,500 for the first time in several days,” - Rupak De, Senior Technical Analyst.</blockquote><p>Looking ahead, corporate earnings and macroeconomic indicators are expected to influence market direction, with analysts advising caution as volatility remains high.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/nifty-prediction-january-2025-rsi-in-negative-crossover-selling-to-continue-check-support-resistance-levels-by-experts-article-117136073</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/nifty-prediction-january-2025-rsi-in-negative-crossover-selling-to-continue-check-support-resistance-levels-by-experts-article-117136073</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:16:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mega Acquisition! JSW Paints, Berger Paints in race for Dulux seller Akzo Nobel's India business - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JSW Paints and Berger Paints Compete to Acquire Akzo Nobel's India Business</h1><p><strong>Updated: Jan 11, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: ET NOW</strong></p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="JSW Paints Berger Paints Akzo Nobel"><figcaption>JSW Paints, Berger Paints in race to acquire Dulux-seller Akzo Nobel (Pic: Shutterstock/ ET NOW)</figcaption><p>JSW Paints and Berger Paints are exploring opportunities to acquire Akzo Nobel's operations in India, as the Dutch multinational conducts a strategic review of its business in South Asia.</p><ul><li>JSW Paints is looking into both organic and inorganic growth options.</li><li>Berger Paints is interested in Akzo Nobel's decorative business but stresses the importance of a fair valuation.</li><li>Sundaresan AS, CEO of JSW Paints, confirmed the interest in potential acquisitions that offer synergies.</li><li>JSW Paints plans to invest Rs 1,000 crore over the next 3-5 years for its growth.</li></ul><blockquote>“As a group, we are open to exploring opportunities for inorganic growth. Akzo Nobel has announced a process, and we will certainly look into it,” - Sundaresan AS, Joint Managing Director and CEO, JSW Paints</blockquote><p>The potential acquisition represents a significant move in the Indian paint industry, as companies vie for market dominance in an evolving landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/companies/mega-acquisition-jsw-paints-berger-paints-in-race-for-dulux-seller-akzo-nobel-article-117136133</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/companies/mega-acquisition-jsw-paints-berger-paints-in-race-for-dulux-seller-akzo-nobel-article-117136133</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:03:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Bucks: L&T Chairman SN Subrahmanyan who wants 90-hr workweek earns ₹51cr—whopping 535x than average employee! | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>L&T Chairman SN Subrahmanyan's 90-Hour Workweek Advocacies and His ₹51 Crore Salary</h1><p><strong>Date Published:</strong> January 9, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>SN Subrahmanyan, Chairman of L&T, has proposed 90-hour workweeks for employees while earning ₹51 crore annually, which is significantly higher than the average employee's salary.</p><img src='image_url' alt='L&T Chairman SN Subrahmanyan' /><figcaption>SN Subrahmanyan, Chairman of L&T</figcaption><p>This article discusses the disparity in pay between Subrahmanyan and the average employee, as well as the implications of his remarks regarding work hours.</p><ul><li>Subrahmanyan's annual salary for 2023-24 is ₹51 crore, 535 times the median employee salary of ₹9.55 lakh.</li><li>In FY23, he earned ₹35.67 crore; in FY22, ₹61.27 crore, not including stock options.</li><li>L&T's employee-related expenses grew at an average of 11% from FY22 to FY24.</li><li>Subrahmanyan's comments have sparked significant public discussion on work-life balance.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dear sir, after one or two years of marriage... Family life and leisure time is as important as work life and money.” - A netizen's response regarding the 90-hour workweek proposal.</blockquote><p>The contrast between Subrahmanyan's salary and that of L&T employees highlights ongoing discussions about executive compensation and employee welfare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/big-bucks-l-t-chairman-sn-subrahmanyan-wants-90-hour-workweek-earns-rs-51-crore-whopping-535x-more-than-average-employee-11736485319752.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/big-bucks-l-t-chairman-sn-subrahmanyan-wants-90-hour-workweek-earns-rs-51-crore-whopping-535x-more-than-average-employee-11736485319752.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:32:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IMF chief sees steady world growth in 2025, continuing disinflation - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPay04UThzNi1oWXhTRlhibUtHZkdIaWJaVkZ6VklHR1dGSEJTbndabkFkWjdiWThnaDFtZmh3OGZiN29UVU5HMm5JNFZYU0Y4S0VKVkJvNmotcU9xVVNMSXFnUXloakE0cXRhY1lrMzFCOHVjQjhfaWJtdFdGYnl3Sm90b1BCRWlqUFZRNXdDT1JJcXVlTVJad2hVcE84UVZqcll0dkhXZjE5R2hORTNORmxPN2NSS1BQVlZtaNIBwgFBVV95cUxQZlNqZDByUDd1bnQxRFYxMmNuU2Z4Y0lCLTBWbU4zNFBPeGE2Q0VWSFV1Q3pUX1ROa2tLVUl0WEE4YXFHazJBZzdiY1dXOVgxQTlVb0ZaNER2RVZBLWpGUG8tc2ZkRzNJWTgtNm9OU1IxeXhuanJBYllXbFV0eU14a3ZYMF9KWUxxY2F5T3VoRHZ0TUVPS1ZUeGt5U3M0NzZDS3lLTkxOXzVvZkFGQ0dLWGxnUDZmS2tIQ0liMXpmS1VLQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPay04UThzNi1oWXhTRlhibUtHZkdIaWJaVkZ6VklHR1dGSEJTbndabkFkWjdiWThnaDFtZmh3OGZiN29UVU5HMm5JNFZYU0Y4S0VKVkJvNmotcU9xVVNMSXFnUXloakE0cXRhY1lrMzFCOHVjQjhfaWJtdFdGYnl3Sm90b1BCRWlqUFZRNXdDT1JJcXVlTVJad2hVcE84UVZqcll0dkhXZjE5R2hORTNORmxPN2NSS1BQVlZtaNIBwgFBVV95cUxQZlNqZDByUDd1bnQxRFYxMmNuU2Z4Y0lCLTBWbU4zNFBPeGE2Q0VWSFV1Q3pUX1ROa2tLVUl0WEE4YXFHazJBZzdiY1dXOVgxQTlVb0ZaNER2RVZBLWpGUG8tc2ZkRzNJWTgtNm9OU1IxeXhuanJBYllXbFV0eU14a3ZYMF9KWUxxY2F5T3VoRHZ0TUVPS1ZUeGt5U3M0NzZDS3lLTkxOXzVvZkFGQ0dLWGxnUDZmS2tIQ0liMXpmS1VLQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:06:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple CEO pay rises 18%; company opposes anti-diversity measure - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple CEO Tim Cook's Pay Increases by 18% Amid Opposition to Diversity Measure</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250111015626_Tim-Cook.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="While Cook’s pay is up significantly from last year, it’s still a far cry from his total compensation in 2022, which reached nearly $100 million thanks to stock awards. Bloomberg" title="While Cook’s pay is up significantly from last year, it’s still a far cry from his total compensation in 2022, which reached nearly $100 million thanks to stock awards. Bloomberg"><figcaption>While Cook’s pay is up significantly from last year, it’s still a far cry from his total compensation in 2022, which reached nearly $100 million thanks to stock awards. Bloomberg</figcaption><p>Apple Inc. has reported an 18% increase in the compensation of CEO Tim Cook ahead of its annual shareholder meeting. The rise in pay has sparked discussions on the company's stance regarding its diversity initiatives.</p><ul><li>Tim Cook's total compensation for 2024 is $74.6 million, up from $63.2 million the previous year.</li><li>The compensation includes a $3 million base salary, $58.1 million in stock awards, and about $13.5 million in additional compensation.</li><li>Apple has opposed a shareholder measure aiming to end its diversity programs, claiming they are crucial for business operations and compliance.</li><li>The upcoming meeting on February 25 will also address other proposals opposed by the company.</li></ul><blockquote>“The proposal was an inappropriate attempt to restrict Apple’s business operations.” - Apple Inc.</blockquote><p>The increase in Cook's pay is primarily driven by the heightened value of stock awards, raising questions about corporate compensation in relation to broader company policies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/apple-ceo-pay-rises-18-company-opposes-anti-diversity-measure-article-12907851.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/apple-ceo-pay-rises-18-company-opposes-anti-diversity-measure-article-12907851.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:57:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ITC Hotels share price listing prediction by top brokerages - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ITC Hotels Share Price Listing Predictions by Top Brokerages</h1>
<p><strong>Updated on:</strong> <strong>Jan 11, 2025</strong> by ET Now</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="ITC Hotels Listing Date" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>ITC Hotels listing date prediction (Pic: ET NOW)</figcaption>
<p>The demerger of ITC Hotels from ITC Limited has been completed, and the listing date for ITC Hotels shares on NSE and BSE is anticipated before mid-February.</p>
<ul>
  <li>ITC shareholders on January 6 will receive one share of ITC Hotels for every 10 shares of ITC.</li>
  <li>ITC Hotels shares are expected to be credited to eligible shareholders' Demat accounts soon.</li>
  <li>Nomura predicts a listing range of Rs 200 to Rs 300, while Nuvama estimates Rs 150 to Rs 175, and SBI Securities predicts Rs 113 to Rs 170.</li>
  <li>ITC Hotels will be part of Sensex and Nifty50, with specific exclusion rules on indices post-listing.</li>
  <li>The demerger is projected to unlock significant shareholder value, focusing on the luxury hospitality sector.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>As per Nomura, ITC Hotels shares could list in the range of Rs 200 to Rs 300, which would reflect a market valuation of Rs 42,500 to Rs 60,000 crore.</blockquote>
<p>This prediction is vital for investors as they await the final listing price and the impacts of the demerger on shareholder value.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/itc-hotels-share-price-listing-prediction-by-top-brokerages-article-117135268</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/itc-hotels-share-price-listing-prediction-by-top-brokerages-article-117135268</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:42:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bad news for Infosys employees as Narayan Murthy’s company takes big decision to..., set to affect... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/business/bad-news-for-infosys-employees-as-narayan-murthys-company-takes-big-decision-to-set-to-affect-7529957/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/business/bad-news-for-infosys-employees-as-narayan-murthys-company-takes-big-decision-to-set-to-affect-7529957/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:40:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bad news for Infosys employees as Narayan Murthy’s company takes big decision to..., set to affect... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/business/bad-news-for-infosys-employees-as-narayan-murthys-company-takes-big-decision-to-set-to-affect-7529957/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/business/bad-news-for-infosys-employees-as-narayan-murthys-company-takes-big-decision-to-set-to-affect-7529957/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:40:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[President Biden says Meta scrapping fact-checking in US is ‘really shameful’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Criticizes Meta's End of Fact-Checking as Shameful</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/Biden-12_1736557029020_1736557078622.jpg" alt="President Joe Biden speaks in the Roosevelt Room at the White House in Washington, Friday, Jan. 10, 2025.(AP)" title="President Joe Biden speaks in the Roosevelt Room at the White House in Washington, Friday, Jan. 10, 2025.(AP)">
<figcaption>President Joe Biden speaks in the Roosevelt Room at the White House in Washington, Friday, Jan. 10, 2025.(AP)</figcaption>
<p>US President Joe Biden has condemned Meta's decision to scrap a stringent fact-checking program, stating it goes against American values.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Biden described the change as “really shameful” and emphasized the importance of truth.</li>
  <li>The International Fact-Checking Network warns that such a policy change could cause “real-world harm” globally.</li>
  <li>Meta's CEO Zuckerberg defended the decision, suggesting the program is outdated and controversially claimed it has eroded trust.</li>
  <li>The United Nations and Brazil have expressed concerns, calling for regulation of harmful content on social media.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Telling the truth matters,” said President Biden.</blockquote>
<p>This controversy highlights the tension between social media policies and the impact of misinformation, drawing responses from multiple international bodies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/president-biden-says-meta-scrapping-fact-checking-in-us-is-really-shameful-101736554811443.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/president-biden-says-meta-scrapping-fact-checking-in-us-is-really-shameful-101736554811443.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:24:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>