<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:19:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:19:07 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wall St slides at end of strong holiday-shortened week - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wall St slides at end of strong holiday-shortened week</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27 | <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p>
<img src='https://www.reutersagency.com/en/licensereuterscontent/?utm_medium=rcom-article-media&utm_campaign=rcom-rcp-lead' alt='A street sign for Wall Street' />
<figcaption>A street sign for Wall Street is seen outside the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City.</figcaption>
<p>Tech and growth stocks pulled Wall Street's main indexes lower on Friday, capping a strong holiday-shortened week.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Amedisys gains after extending merger deadline with UnitedHealth.</li>
  <li>All three major indexes poised for weekly gains.</li>
  <li>Dow down 0.76%, S&P 500 down 1.16%, Nasdaq down 1.77%.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Tech, which has had a tremendous run, is starting to pull back. It is the beginning of a healthy correction that will get focused in on over the next four to eight weeks." - Jay Woods, Chief Global Strategist at Freedom Capital Markets</blockquote>
<p>After a stellar November fueled by pro-business optimism under a new administration, traders proceed with caution into the end of the year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/wall-st-futures-ease-strong-holiday-shortened-week-draws-close-2024-12-27/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/wall-st-futures-ease-strong-holiday-shortened-week-draws-close-2024-12-27/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:32:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Terra Luna Founder Do Kwon to be Extradited to the US - Watcher Guru]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Do Kwon, Founder of Terra Luna, Extradited to the US</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Watcher Guru</p><figure><img src="https://watcher.guru/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/230323185328-do-kwon-terraform-file-2022-restricted-1-1024x576.jpg" alt="Terra's Do Kwon Faces Fake Passport Charges From Montenegro"/><figcaption>Source: CNN</figcaption></figure><p>In a major update on the ongoing legal situation, Do Kwon, the founder of Terra Luna, is set to be extradited to the United States after lengthy court deliberations in Montenegro.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court of Montenegro has approved the extradition to the US, citing fulfillment of legal conditions from both South Korea and the US.</li><li>Kwon was previously arrested in Montenegro in March 2023, and his extradition decision indicates a significant turning point in his legal battles.</li><li>The fall of TerraUSD and Luna caused a $40 billion market wipeout, with Kwon being identified as a major figure behind the financial collapse.</li></ul><blockquote>"JUST IN: Terra Luna Founder Do Kwon to be extradited to the United States." — Watcher.Guru</blockquote><p>The extradition of Do Kwon, amid his controversial past and the recent recovery within the cryptocurrency market, marks a significant moment for both law enforcement and the crypto industry as a whole.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://watcher.guru/news/terra-luna-founder-do-kwon-to-be-extradited-to-the-us</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://watcher.guru/news/terra-luna-founder-do-kwon-to-be-extradited-to-the-us</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:49:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JSW Neo Energy to acquire O2 Power at enterprise value of $1.47 billion | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JSW Neo Energy to Acquire O2 Power for $1.47 Billion</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>JSW Neo Energy, a subsidiary of JSW Energy Ltd, is set to acquire O2 Power at an enterprise value of $1.47 billion, subject to necessary approvals.</p>
<ul>
  <li>O2 Power has a capacity of 4.7 GW in renewable energy.</li>
  <li>The ownership of O2 Power is currently held by EQT and Temasek, who will exit after the acquisition.</li>
  <li>This acquisition will increase JSW Neo Energy's planned generation capacity by 23%.</li>
  <li>JSW Energy aims to strengthen its position in the Indian energy sector with this deal.</li>
  <li>CEO Parag Sharma expressed excitement about the new partnership and focus on renewable energy goals.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This marks the beginning of the next phase for O2 Power... We look forward to working with JSW Neo Energy for the next phase.” - Parag Sharma, CEO of O2 Power</blockquote>
<p>The acquisition signifies a strategic expansion for JSW Neo Energy in the renewable sector, aligning with India's energy goals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/jsw-neo-energy-o2-power-acquisition-renewable-energy-thermal-power-power-generation-capacity-cci-11735306895620.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/jsw-neo-energy-o2-power-acquisition-renewable-energy-thermal-power-power-generation-capacity-cci-11735306895620.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:55:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI lays out its for-profit transition plans - TechCrunch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OpenAI lays out its for-profit transition plans</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> TechCrunch</p><p>OpenAI is transitioning its corporate structure to a Delaware Public Benefit Corporation (PBC) to further its mission of ensuring artificial general intelligence (AGI) benefits all of humanity. This move aims to balance shareholder interests with public benefits.</p><ul><li>OpenAI currently operates as a for-profit controlled by a nonprofit with capped profits for investors.</li><li>The transition aims to allow OpenAI to raise necessary capital under conventional terms.</li><li>OpenAI's existing nonprofit would receive shares in the new PBC at fair valuation.</li><li>Elon Musk has filed for an injunction against this transition, claiming it undermines OpenAI's philanthropic mission.</li><li>Meta has also expressed concerns over the implications of this shift on Silicon Valley.</li></ul><blockquote>“As we enter 2025, we will have to become more than a lab and a startup — we have to become an enduring company,” OpenAI stated in its memo.</blockquote><p>This transition illustrates OpenAI's evolution and the challenges it faces in balancing profit and public good.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/27/openai-lays-out-its-for-profit-transition-plans/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/27/openai-lays-out-its-for-profit-transition-plans/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:33:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Personal Loan: How AI is boosting the lending ecosystem – 6 key points to know | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Personal Loan: How AI is boosting the lending ecosystem – 6 key points to know</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Artificial intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing the lending ecosystem, making the process of obtaining personal loans simpler and more convenient. This article outlines six ways in which AI has enhanced personal loan management.</p><ol><li><strong>Loan approvals:</strong> AI algorithms speed up eligibility evaluations by analyzing credit scores, income data, and spending patterns, allowing for approvals in minutes.</li><li><strong>Personalized offers:</strong> Machine learning models provide tailored loan terms and interest rates, adjusting to a borrower’s financial profile and market trends.</li><li><strong>Customer experience:</strong> AI-driven tools offer 24/7 support, helping borrowers with queries and tracking repayments.</li><li><strong>Behavioral Analysis:</strong> AI can detect unusual activities to prevent fraud, protecting both borrowers and lenders.</li><li><strong>Smarter credit scoring:</strong> AI utilizes unconventional data points to assess creditworthiness, promoting financial inclusion.</li><li><strong>Probability of defaults:</strong> AI predicts repayment probabilities, assisting lenders in managing portfolios effectively.</li></ol><p>AI is not just streamlining processes but also enhancing security and ensuring better financial inclusion for borrowers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/personal-loan-how-ai-is-giving-an-impetus-to-lending-ecosystem-6-key-points-to-know-artificial-intelligence-11735306023386.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/personal-loan-how-ai-is-giving-an-impetus-to-lending-ecosystem-6-key-points-to-know-artificial-intelligence-11735306023386.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:10:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ola Electric’s CTO, CMO quit adding to top-level exodus - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ola Electric Faces Leadership Challenges as CTO and CMO Resign</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><figure><img height="488" width="650" alt="Ola" src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116719359,width-650,height-488,imgsize-34286,resizemode-75/ola.jpg"><figcaption>CMO Anshul Khandelwal (left) and CTO Suvonil Chatterjee, Ola Electric</figcaption></figure><p>Two senior executives at Ola Electric, Suvonil Chatterjee and Anshul Khandelwal, have resigned, contributing to a larger trend of top-level resignations at the company amidst struggles in market performance.</p><ul><li>Suvonil Chatterjee and Anshul Khandelwal have stepped down citing personal reasons.</li><li>The resignations are part of a wave of high-level exits from the Ola group.</li><li>Ola Electric has faced market share decline and employee attrition rates as high as 44.25% this fiscal year.</li><li>Chatterjee and Khandelwal had been with Ola since 2017 and 2018, respectively.</li><li>Employee layoffs and a fall in stock price have added to the challenges facing Ola Electric.</li></ul><blockquote>“It has been an incredible journey, and I am grateful for the opportunities to contribute to Ola’s inspiring vision.” - Anshul Khandelwal</blockquote><p>Ola Electric continues to navigate significant leadership changes and market pressures as it aims to stabilize its operations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/technology/ola-electrics-cto-cmo-quit-adding-to-top-level-exodus/articleshow/116718241.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/technology/ola-electrics-cto-cmo-quit-adding-to-top-level-exodus/articleshow/116718241.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:10:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JSW Neo Energy to Acquire O2 Power for ₹125 Billion - Mercom India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JSW Neo Energy to Acquire O2 Power for ₹125 Billion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Mercom India</p><img alt="thumbnail" src="https://d382rz2cea0pah.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/JSW-Neo-Energy-to-Acquire-O2-Power-for-%E2%82%B9125-Billion.jpg" decoding="async"><figcaption>JSW Neo Energy to Acquire O2 Power for ₹125 Billion</figcaption><p>JSW Neo Energy has entered into a definitive agreement to acquire a 4,696 MW renewable energy platform from O2 Power Pooling.</p><ul><li>The enterprise valuation of the platform is approximately ₹124.68 billion (~$1.46 billion).</li><li>The acquisition includes O2 Power Midco Holdings and O2 Energy SG, pending regulatory approvals.</li><li>O2 Power operates a renewable energy platform with 4,696 MW capacity, with 2,259 MW expected operational by June 2025.</li><li>JSW’s generation capacity will increase by 23% from 20,012 MW to 24,708 MW.</li></ul><blockquote>“The platform offers a blended average tariff of ₹3.37 (~$0.039)/kWh and an average operational life of approximately 23 years.”</blockquote><p>This acquisition enhances JSW Energy's position in the renewable energy sector, positioning it for future growth in clean energy generation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mercomindia.com/jsw-neo-acquire-o2-power-125-billion</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mercomindia.com/jsw-neo-acquire-o2-power-125-billion</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:07:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech View: Nifty forms Doji candle but crosses 200-DMA? What traders should do on Monday - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxPUFJnQlNJNXMzc180STB6ZF8ySHRBNWVLOVI2aEx1ZTRoYkZmUFJ4bU9wVHdSeGFGMlJlU2E3QktGYXBGaFRvMWVLR1NPb0FyQWN0TFYySWxQS2pWZ09ZRzBITm1nN2RDVHJJSUJxT3MyV3dUdkF3SF94dmd3YVgyNHBRWmpKbGVzTXJhRm5GSU15U2tBR1E0ak5veXdfZzRhUldJd0h6MDdPaUhhZ3R3dzVTTEItQi1vSktnb2lHcjJsaWg1bkhxYk9rUjZtT1duWkFXR2tLY01qbEpXcm02VjljejhGYVVBcHlWNjdYZ05nUdIB9wFBVV95cUxNQzBEYkdhVWx5THpNaHRjRGZzMVlxRXhiaENHNFNuYWc0VmRwSlR2WGxJUFhzT0pzYnZnSGNzSk5NTWxzYXlGZHlZbU44cTlMc28wZW5lNUtHdExWTGgxVlRMMEJ3aVp6LTZhN3g1NjJqOG5RNU5EaUVFbDNEaE8tR2Rkc1ZQYXl3VF90RDgtNGxveUdJaW15Q2U2cVF4YVlreGZIWWVZWnZVS2xzUm16UGN6aEE4VTRDR0tyZER3c3dwbElOVWdCMVo0UXhpOUk5VGNFRVRQdHVFZ1M1aEhkSDlnVmdHeVlFTkFoc1dEUlpGVDl2RDNZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxPUFJnQlNJNXMzc180STB6ZF8ySHRBNWVLOVI2aEx1ZTRoYkZmUFJ4bU9wVHdSeGFGMlJlU2E3QktGYXBGaFRvMWVLR1NPb0FyQWN0TFYySWxQS2pWZ09ZRzBITm1nN2RDVHJJSUJxT3MyV3dUdkF3SF94dmd3YVgyNHBRWmpKbGVzTXJhRm5GSU15U2tBR1E0ak5veXdfZzRhUldJd0h6MDdPaUhhZ3R3dzVTTEItQi1vSktnb2lHcjJsaWg1bkhxYk9rUjZtT1duWkFXR2tLY01qbEpXcm02VjljejhGYVVBcHlWNjdYZ05nUdIB9wFBVV95cUxNQzBEYkdhVWx5THpNaHRjRGZzMVlxRXhiaENHNFNuYWc0VmRwSlR2WGxJUFhzT0pzYnZnSGNzSk5NTWxzYXlGZHlZbU44cTlMc28wZW5lNUtHdExWTGgxVlRMMEJ3aVp6LTZhN3g1NjJqOG5RNU5EaUVFbDNEaE8tR2Rkc1ZQYXl3VF90RDgtNGxveUdJaW15Q2U2cVF4YVlreGZIWWVZWnZVS2xzUm16UGN6aEE4VTRDR0tyZER3c3dwbElOVWdCMVo0UXhpOUk5VGNFRVRQdHVFZ1M1aEhkSDlnVmdHeVlFTkFoc1dEUlpGVDl2RDNZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICICI Bank, L&T to Mastek: SMC Global Securities suggests THESE 10 stocks to buy for long-term with 15-30% upside | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICICI Bank, L&T to Mastek: SMC Global Securities suggests THESE 10 stocks to buy for long-term with 15-30% upside</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>This article discusses the significant growth observed in the Indian stock market and highlights key sectors expected to thrive as investment opportunities for 2025.</p><ul><li>The Indian stock market saw Nifty 50 and Sensex gaining 8-10%.</li><li>Domestic Institutional Investors (DIIs) are increasingly confident in India's economic growth.</li><li>India's GDP is projected to grow by 6.3% for FY25.</li><li>Key factors for growth include private investment, domestic consumption, and government initiatives.</li><li>The financial sector experienced a 15% rise in credit growth.</li><li>Technology, healthcare, and manufacturing sectors are expected to drive growth.</li><li>Investment risks include geopolitical tensions and economic slowdowns in other regions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite challenges, India’s long-term growth potential presents significant investment opportunities.”</blockquote><p>Investors are encouraged to adopt a strategic, staggered investment approach to capitalize on the promising market in 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/icici-bank-l-t-to-mastek-smc-global-securities-suggests-these-10-stocks-to-buy-for-long-term-with-15-30-upside-11735303387981.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/icici-bank-l-t-to-mastek-smc-global-securities-suggests-these-10-stocks-to-buy-for-long-term-with-15-30-upside-11735303387981.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:58:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple poised to cross $4 trillion threshold - Fortune]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Poised to Cross $4 Trillion Market Cap Threshold</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Fortune</p><p>Apple is on track to become the first company with a market cap exceeding $4 trillion, currently valued at $3.92 trillion. Stock growth has been fueled by optimism around AI advancements in iPhones and other devices.</p><ul><li>Apple's current valuation is $3.92 trillion.</li><li>The stock has risen 40% this year due to AI improvements.</li><li>Analysts predict future growth from the new Apple Intelligence initiative.</li><li>Wedbush analyst Daniel Ives has raised the price target for Apple stocks to $325.</li></ul><blockquote>“We believe Apple is heading into a multi-year AI driven iPhone upgrade cycle that is still being underestimated by the Street.” - Daniel Ives</blockquote><p>Analysts from JPMorgan also foresee potential growth driven by upcoming iPhone releases and a focus on services.</p><p>In conclusion, Apple is set to reach a significant milestone, potentially transforming the consumer technology landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://fortune.com/2024/12/27/apple-ai-4-trillion-market-cap/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fortune.com/2024/12/27/apple-ai-4-trillion-market-cap/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RBI permits UPI transactions via PPI wallets using third-party apps - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RBI Permits UPI Transactions via PPI Wallets Using Third-Party Apps</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has approved the use of third-party applications for UPI transactions facilitated through Prepaid Payment Instruments (PPI) wallets. This move aims to increase the accessibility and usability of UPI services for consumers.</p><ul><li>RBI's new directive enables an increased number of digital wallet providers to facilitate UPI transactions.</li><li>This decision is expected to enhance the financial inclusion landscape in India.</li><li>The RBI ensures that transactions remain secure while introducing convenience for users.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a significant advancement towards enhancing digital payment systems in India.”</blockquote><p>This development is expected to foster competition among digital payment platforms and improve user experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/rbi-permits-upi-transactions-via-ppi-wallets-using-third-party-apps/articleshow/116714193.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/rbi-permits-upi-transactions-via-ppi-wallets-using-third-party-apps/articleshow/116714193.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bank of Baroda SO Online Form 2025 - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTE9wMk55TXVtV3BEVkdBS0EtU19VQTRYdjhCVGVOZFN4Ui1BMkdqakZ6NS1UMU8zenZJWXV5LTVhQUlkZXlVdWRaSkwwaDAyaXBaaWVDTWc2RTBVb3BQeDBEeUtjMHJlTjBlS2RLM3R5dGE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTE9wMk55TXVtV3BEVkdBS0EtU19VQTRYdjhCVGVOZFN4Ui1BMkdqakZ6NS1UMU8zenZJWXV5LTVhQUlkZXlVdWRaSkwwaDAyaXBaaWVDTWc2RTBVb3BQeDBEeUtjMHJlTjBlS2RLM3R5dGE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kia Sonet Facelift Crosses 1 Lakh Sales Since Its Launch In January - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2024 Kia Sonet Achieves 1 Lakh Sales Milestone in Less Than a Year</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CarDekho.com</p> <img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/676e9d31a5a55.jpg" alt="Kia Sonet Facelift Crosses 1 Lakh Sales Since Its Launch In January"> <figcaption>Kia Sonet Facelift Crosses 1 Lakh Sales Since Its Launch In January</figcaption> <p>The 2024 Kia Sonet has crossed 1 lakh sales in just 11 months since its launch in January, showcasing its popularity in the subcompact SUV segment.</p> <ul> <li>79% of total sales are from variants equipped with a sunroof.</li> <li>76% of sales are from petrol-powered variants.</li> <li>34% of customers prefer automatic and iMT transmission variants.</li> <li>Features include dual 10.25-inch screens, ventilated front seats, and advanced safety features.</li> <li>Offers three engine options: 1.2-litre naturally aspirated petrol, 1-litre turbo-petrol, and 1.5-litre diesel.</li> <li>Priced from Rs 8 lakh to Rs 15.77 lakh (ex-showroom Delhi).</li> </ul> <blockquote>“At Kia, our continuous focus is on understanding customer needs and creating solutions that meet them.” - Mr. Hardeep Singh Brar, Sr. VP and Head of Sales and Marketing</blockquote> <p>This achievement highlights the growing trust among consumers and reinforces Kia's commitment to delivering innovative products that exceed customer expectations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/kia-sonet-facelift-crosses-1-lakh-sales-since-its-launch-in-january-33734.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/kia-sonet-facelift-crosses-1-lakh-sales-since-its-launch-in-january-33734.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Current account deficit narrows to $11.2 billion in Q2FY25 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Current account deficit at $11.2 billion in July-September</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Economic Times</p><p>The current account deficit for the July-September quarter stood at $11.2 billion, representing 1.2% of GDP, slightly lower than the revised figure of $11.3 billion for the same period last year.</p><ul><li>The deficit was $9.7 billion, or 1.1% of GDP, in the preceding quarter.</li><li>The figures are reported by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI).</li></ul><blockquote>“The current account deficit was $11.2 billion in the reporting quarter.”</blockquote><p>This slight reduction in the deficit indicates a marginal improvement in the balance of payments situation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/indicators/current-account-deficit-at-11-2-billion-in-july-september/articleshow/116714960.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/indicators/current-account-deficit-at-11-2-billion-in-july-september/articleshow/116714960.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:52:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Applied? Unimech Aerospace IPO Expected Listing Price, GMP Today - What grey market signals - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unimech Aerospace IPO Expected Listing Price and Grey Market Signals</h1>
<p><strong>Updated Dec 27, 2024 - Source: ET NOW</strong></p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Unimech Aerospace IPO" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Unimech Aerospace is a high-precision engineering solutions company. (Image: Freepik/ET NOW News)</figcaption>
<p>The article discusses the impressive subscription rates for the Unimech Aerospace IPO, highlighting its significant interest from various investor categories.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The IPO received 174.93 times subscription on the final bidding day.</li>
    <li>It raised Rs 500 crore with bids for over 82 million shares against 47,04,028 shares available.</li>
    <li>Institutional investors showed high interest with QIBs subscribing 317.63 times.</li>
    <li>The expected listing price of the IPO is estimated at Rs 1451.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The expected percentage gain per share is 84.84 percent.</blockquote>
<p>This IPO indicates robust market interest and potential for significant returns, showcasing the growing demand in the aerospace sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/applied-unimech-aerospace-ipo-expected-listing-price-gmp-today-what-grey-market-signals-article-116714737</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/applied-unimech-aerospace-ipo-expected-listing-price-gmp-today-what-grey-market-signals-article-116714737</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:46:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Rs 20 Lakh A Day To Zero, Startup Founder Shares How Amazon Ended His Dream - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Startup Founder Shares Journey from Rs 20 Lakh A Day to Zero Due to Amazon Competition</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Just when the business was growing, Amazon launched a competing brand." title="Just when the business was growing, Amazon launched a competing brand."><figcaption>Just when the business was growing, Amazon launched a competing brand.</figcaption></figure><p>An Indian startup founder recently shared his heartbreaking journey of business downfall, which used to generate Rs 20 lakh per day. His home organiser company faced a sudden crash when Amazon launched a competing brand, wiping out his revenue.</p><ul><li>The founder started his business in 2017, finding an opportunity in overpriced storage products on Amazon.</li><li>After initial success, Amazon's launch of similar products severely impacted his sales.</li><li>The founder shared insights on the risks of relying solely on one platform like Amazon.</li><li>He emphasized the importance of building a strong brand and diversifying sales channels.</li></ul><blockquote>“I went from selling 20L of products per day to watching my generational-wealth dream crumble under Amazon.”</blockquote><p>This experience highlights the challenges faced by small businesses in competitive environments, particularly against large corporations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/from-rs-20-lakh-a-day-to-zero-startup-founder-shares-how-amazon-ended-his-dream-aa-9169634.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/from-rs-20-lakh-a-day-to-zero-startup-founder-shares-how-amazon-ended-his-dream-aa-9169634.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:36:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24: Non-food items lead household spending trends; rent major contributor - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24: Non-food items lead household spending trends; rent major contributor</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Ministry of Statistics and Programme Implementation</p> <p>The 2023-24 Consumption Expenditure Survey reveals a narrowing urban-rural gap in consumption expenditure, with non-food items dominating household spending.</p> <ul> <li>The urban-rural gap in monthly per capita consumption expenditure (MPCE) decreased to 70% in 2023-24.</li> <li>Average MPCE was ₹4,122 in rural and ₹6,996 in urban areas, rising to ₹4,247 and ₹7,078 when including government welfare benefits.</li> <li>Sikkim had the highest MPCE, while Chhattisgarh recorded the lowest.</li> <li>Non-food items account for 53% of rural and 60% of urban household expenditures.</li> <li>The Gini coefficient for inequality declined in both rural (0.237) and urban (0.284) areas.</li> <li>Rent constitutes around 7% of urban non-food expenditure.</li></ul> <blockquote>“Rent with a share of around 7% is another major constituent of households’ non-food expenditure in urban India.”</blockquote> <p>Overall, the survey highlights significant trends in consumption patterns and a decrease in inequality, impacting economic indicators such as GDP and CPI.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/business-news/economy/consumption-expenditure-survey-2023-24-non-food-items-lead-household-spending-trends-rent-major-contributor/article-137312/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/business-news/economy/consumption-expenditure-survey-2023-24-non-food-items-lead-household-spending-trends-rent-major-contributor/article-137312/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:22:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold set for weekly gains amid geopolitical uncertainty | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxPWnNpbzZtaVZDa0Nsa0ZPcHZyWnJoOXpFUmxwenU5bHN1REV2MFhubFVfRDJWcnMyb09ZLXhTZ2RVMFVfckdUSk85dXNsa3pGaGMwVVhmZnRiYlZHOVp3Wk1BekdWRlB1NnZ3MjJYNkJsN3dib3dhRTB0NkZhbkRkX0k4S1ZXY3Y5eXlFOXh5TjQwMDZWdVBSQ3lFU1djbHgwcS1fS3dHdi1MTVd0bVRFb3JBOGVkWnZicDZR0gHAAUFVX3lxTE45TXpDdlBsdzZHbEFtc2xfYlNEdmlSdExvckY2dDRFa21LbEVvbUlSdzR6dGNzRGd4NzNUdHZQTlBDVklBdnRSeFdxeTRWeTJTVVRyZXNQcWJJR0hZOWprdjA5OElpeGtzNnNtUTB6Y2lHQVliNjA2VVpXT2VidEEtZGVLWDU0c3o2S2JLLWQyOVd1VGphMTE5Tk9oS1ZwMFB5TGpUZ1VLVWpaaDl1M3JoOXZDODh4OEtOeGVpd0dSbQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxPWnNpbzZtaVZDa0Nsa0ZPcHZyWnJoOXpFUmxwenU5bHN1REV2MFhubFVfRDJWcnMyb09ZLXhTZ2RVMFVfckdUSk85dXNsa3pGaGMwVVhmZnRiYlZHOVp3Wk1BekdWRlB1NnZ3MjJYNkJsN3dib3dhRTB0NkZhbkRkX0k4S1ZXY3Y5eXlFOXh5TjQwMDZWdVBSQ3lFU1djbHgwcS1fS3dHdi1MTVd0bVRFb3JBOGVkWnZicDZR0gHAAUFVX3lxTE45TXpDdlBsdzZHbEFtc2xfYlNEdmlSdExvckY2dDRFa21LbEVvbUlSdzR6dGNzRGd4NzNUdHZQTlBDVklBdnRSeFdxeTRWeTJTVVRyZXNQcWJJR0hZOWprdjA5OElpeGtzNnNtUTB6Y2lHQVliNjA2VVpXT2VidEEtZGVLWDU0c3o2S2JLLWQyOVd1VGphMTE5Tk9oS1ZwMFB5TGpUZ1VLVWpaaDl1M3JoOXZDODh4OEtOeGVpd0dSbQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:17:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Market Wrap, December 27: SENSEX, NIFTY50 gain 1% this week; auto, healthcare stocks rally - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Market Wrap, December 27: SENSEX, NIFTY50 gain 1% this week; auto, healthcare stocks rally</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Stock Market News</p><p>The bulls maintained an upper hand in the stock market as both the S&P BSE SENSEX and NSE's NIFTY50 gained approximately 1% this week after previous declines.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>S&P BSE SENSEX closed at 78,699.07, up 0.29%.</li><li>NSE NIFTY50 index settled at 23,813.40, up 0.27%.</li><li>Major buying observed in auto and healthcare sectors.</li><li>This week’s gains follow a 5% drop last week, influenced by US Federal Reserve's rate projections.</li><li>Top gainers included Dr Reddy's, IndusInd Bank, and M&M.</li><li>Top losers included Hindalco Industries and SBI.</li></ul><h2>Market Statistics:</h2><ul><li>4,087 stocks traded on BSE; 2,026 fell while 1,948 advanced.</li><li>155 stocks hit 52-week highs; 72 hit one-year lows.</li></ul><h2>Buzzing Stocks:</h2><ul><li>Greaves Cotton shares reached 20% upper circuit limit due to IPO fundraising plans.</li><li>Mamata Machinery listed at a 146.91% premium.</li><li>Sagility India shares rose to an all-time high after 9 consecutive sessions of growth.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/market-wrap-december-27-sensex-nifty-50-gain-1-this-week-auto-healthcare-stocks-rally/article-137311/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/market-wrap-december-27-sensex-nifty-50-gain-1-this-week-auto-healthcare-stocks-rally/article-137311/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:16:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025 Honda Unicorn launched at Rs 1.19 lakh; check whats new - Zee Business]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxPQ25DdExibzVIYTRSOElUdW5jMkppZWx2eENMc3N3b0U5S245UmxYZU5nZ3g3UE1GdVljWkJVMkk4OHFJNTg1WEE5NVJsODgyTDlodUZ2b2EtbEI4ZDFQaTVqX283RHV0cTJoQ2ozXy1WdmJSVVNVSWJOamVuRFUyeHRKektWZ3FUbXVhYV9iUzJDdnRiNFdCd2tFWGJsX3UtSjJvdHhfMldsTVVwZHN6UlBPaFMwbU8yYno5alV1QmZoX09IOVVxTy04WUJ5cEJnT2txZUI3cmhyd9IB3wFBVV95cUxQNWxBZERpZ0d4dmtoTHU4Sy1welpGbzlONmRMd2xhN21lMFROS250VkNLQ044UE9tNUZXTlluNU5QSlJrbFg5Ylg5WUdrZ0VrTmRNRVhvSk95dGlyck9OUE15S05IYktTMDFPV1ZxdmdTTkdUUDFXZ2VNdm03bDEtQzc2N2h0ZXlreEdNbXhHU2hEWTQ0Z0MtYVJqcTVvMDUzX2duWDczdUhIN3c4cTZLZEtWcVhKNGg0ZTIwX3VzTFVib285UENqRXhBd0tDOC1Ia3B3dm1fRzdFbDRHZjBn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxPQ25DdExibzVIYTRSOElUdW5jMkppZWx2eENMc3N3b0U5S245UmxYZU5nZ3g3UE1GdVljWkJVMkk4OHFJNTg1WEE5NVJsODgyTDlodUZ2b2EtbEI4ZDFQaTVqX283RHV0cTJoQ2ozXy1WdmJSVVNVSWJOamVuRFUyeHRKektWZ3FUbXVhYV9iUzJDdnRiNFdCd2tFWGJsX3UtSjJvdHhfMldsTVVwZHN6UlBPaFMwbU8yYno5alV1QmZoX09IOVVxTy04WUJ5cEJnT2txZUI3cmhyd9IB3wFBVV95cUxQNWxBZERpZ0d4dmtoTHU4Sy1welpGbzlONmRMd2xhN21lMFROS250VkNLQ044UE9tNUZXTlluNU5QSlJrbFg5Ylg5WUdrZ0VrTmRNRVhvSk95dGlyck9OUE15S05IYktTMDFPV1ZxdmdTTkdUUDFXZ2VNdm03bDEtQzc2N2h0ZXlreEdNbXhHU2hEWTQ0Z0MtYVJqcTVvMDUzX2duWDczdUhIN3c4cTZLZEtWcVhKNGg0ZTIwX3VzTFVib285UENqRXhBd0tDOC1Ia3B3dm1fRzdFbDRHZjBn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:13:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take A Look At All The Tata Cars That Could Go On Sale In 2025 - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>All New Tata Cars Expected To Be Launched In 2025: Tata Sierra, Tata Harrier EV, Tata Safari EV, Tata Punch Facelift, And More</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> CarDekho.com</p>
<img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/676e921a185a7.jpg" alt="Upcoming Tata Cars in 2025">
<figcaption>Upcoming Tata Cars in 2025</figcaption>
<p>Tata Motors is set for an exciting 2025 with the launch of seven new models, including electric versions of popular cars and the return of the iconic Tata Sierra SUV.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Tata Sierra (ICE + EV):</strong> Launch expected on January 17, 2025. Prices expected at Rs 11 lakh (ICE) and Rs 20 lakh (EV).</li>
  <li><strong>Tata Harrier EV:</strong> Expected launch in January 2025 with a price tag of Rs 25 lakh.</li>
  <li><strong>Tata Safari EV:</strong> Set to debut in February 2025 with an expected price of Rs 32 lakh.</li>
  <li><strong>Tata Punch Facelift:</strong> Anticipated launch in September 2025, expected price of Rs 6 lakh.</li>
  <li><strong>Tata Harrier Petrol:</strong> Launch expected in June 2025 at Rs 14 lakh.</li>
  <li><strong>Tata Tiago and Tigor Facelifts:</strong> Expected in December 2025, with prices projected at Rs 5.2 lakh (Tiago) and Rs 6.2 lakh (Tigor).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Follow the CarDekho WhatsApp channel to get instant updates from the automotive world."</blockquote>
<p>This lineup showcases Tata's commitment to expanding their electric vehicle offerings, along with refreshing their current models for the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/take-a-look-at-all-the-tata-cars-that-could-go-on-sale-in-2025-33731.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/take-a-look-at-all-the-tata-cars-that-could-go-on-sale-in-2025-33731.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mamata Machinery Share Price, IPO Listing Highlights: IPO lists at 147% premium on NSE, shares up lock in upper circuit - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mamata Machinery Share Price, IPO listing Highlights: IPO lists at 147% premium on NSE, shares up lock in upper circuit</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p><figure><img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Mamata-Machinery-website-1.jpg?w=1024" alt="Mamata Machinery Share Price, IPO GMP listing live updates:" width="670" height="377"><figcaption>Mamata Machinery Share Price, IPO listing live: The company raised Rs 53.56 crore from anchor investors. (Image: Company's website)</figcaption></figure><p>The IPO of Mamata Machinery was listed at a remarkable 147% premium on the National Stock Exchange (NSE) today, reflecting overwhelming market response with a total oversubscription of 194.95 times.</p><ul><li>The IPO was subscribed 138.08 times by retail investors.</li><li>Qualified Institutional Buyers (QIBs) subscribed 235.88 times.</li><li>The company raised Rs 179.39 crore by selling 74 lakh shares.</li><li>Stock closed at Rs 629.95 on BSE, gaining 4.99%.</li></ul><blockquote>“At the upper price band company is valued at a P/E of 16.6x,” said Anand Rathi Research.</blockquote><p>This strong listing is backed by Mamata Machinery's robust positioning in the packaging machinery sector and positive market sentiments surrounding the IPO.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/market/mamata-machinery-share-price-ipo-listing-live-updates-date-time-share-price-allotment-listing-status-gmp-price-subscription-status-allotment-status-ipo-news-3701159/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/market/mamata-machinery-share-price-ipo-listing-live-updates-date-time-share-price-allotment-listing-status-gmp-price-subscription-status-allotment-status-ipo-news-3701159/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:07:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leadership exodus at Ola Electric as technology and marketing heads quit - The Arc]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxNVk95S1p1UDB3MWh5QVRHQWliemNFYzY1dElzTXlRcTg2bE5jalZCYzY5ekU0a0RSeHM3Q2I1bDJpYUQ5QmNId1l0ZFozZWVQNFhaSkRiczJ6Y05RMEE1NDNmak50V3ctakNLbmZKVmZkUVczWW4tZEV4cW4yemhYbzNBLVZGNk91STVEMjdsMURMNEpycXNlNkNqclFuWkwwWFdEeDlfVUgtdXprR1JiTEhBUGE3NFlVX1FPX0l3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxNVk95S1p1UDB3MWh5QVRHQWliemNFYzY1dElzTXlRcTg2bE5jalZCYzY5ekU0a0RSeHM3Q2I1bDJpYUQ5QmNId1l0ZFozZWVQNFhaSkRiczJ6Y05RMEE1NDNmak50V3ctakNLbmZKVmZkUVczWW4tZEV4cW4yemhYbzNBLVZGNk91STVEMjdsMURMNEpycXNlNkNqclFuWkwwWFdEeDlfVUgtdXprR1JiTEhBUGE3NFlVX1FPX0l3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:07:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swiggy-ing it! Bengaluru user spent over Rs 11 lakh on Instamart in 2024; milk, onion and curd among top buys in city - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru User Spends Over ₹11 Lakh on Swiggy Instamart in 2024</h1><p><strong>Published: 27 December 2024, Source: Deccan Herald</strong></p><p>The quick-commerce sector in India, particularly in Bengaluru, has witnessed a remarkable rise, with one user spending over ₹11 lakh on Swiggy Instamart in 2024.</p><ul><li>Bengaluru ranked as the most convenience-oriented city in India.</li><li>A single user in Bengaluru spent ₹11,70,077 on groceries and essentials this year.</li><li>Top purchases included milk, onion, curd, and tomatoes.</li><li>Residents spent more on self-care than on electronics, with beauty products seeing a 40% higher expenditure.</li><li>The fastest delivery recorded was in Kochi, covering 180 metres in just 89 seconds.</li><li>The 'Incognito Mode' feature saw significant use, with late-night orders for items like masala chips and flavored condoms.</li></ul><blockquote>"Since launching in August 2020, we've seen Bangaloreans increasingly turn to the convenience of quick commerce," said Amitesh Jha, CEO of Swiggy Instamart.</blockquote><p>The rise in quick-commerce usage reflects the changing consumer behavior in urban India, indicating a growing reliance on instant delivery services.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/business/companies/swiggy-ing-it-bengaluru-user-spent-over-rs-11-lakh-on-instamart-in-2024-milk-onion-and-curd-among-top-buys-in-city-3333850</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/business/companies/swiggy-ing-it-bengaluru-user-spent-over-rs-11-lakh-on-instamart-in-2024-milk-onion-and-curd-among-top-buys-in-city-3333850</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:06:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ark's Cathie Wood calls for tax clarity as she rides 'Trump bump' | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cathie Wood Urges Tax Clarity from Trump's Administration</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27<br><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><p>Cathie Wood, a prominent U.S. tech investor, is advocating for clarity on tax policies from Donald Trump's incoming administration. She believes backdating tax cuts to January 1, 2025, would stimulate economic growth.</p><ul><li>Wood's ARK Innovation ETF has surged 17% post-Trump's victory, outperforming the S&P500.</li><li>Key holdings Tesla and Coinbase have seen significant increases in their stock prices since November.</li><li>Wood supports Trump's economic platform, advocating for reduced tariffs and tax cuts.</li><li>Analysts expect a push for tax reform by the new Congress, with Trump poised to use executive orders to implement policies.</li><li>Wood has not financially supported Trump but maintains contact with key figures like Elon Musk and Senator Cynthia Lummis.</li></ul><blockquote>“I see them saying, okay, we're going to cut taxes but we will make them retroactive to Jan. 1, 2025. That would be very helpful, I think, in terms of providing certainty for the markets.” - Cathie Wood</blockquote><p>Wood believes that while the market's initial excitement may fade, innovation-driven sectors will benefit in the long run.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/arks-cathie-wood-calls-for-tax-clarity-as-she-rides-trump-bump-11735297280849.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/arks-cathie-wood-calls-for-tax-clarity-as-she-rides-trump-bump-11735297280849.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:01:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian airlines to follow BCAS's new 7kg, one-baggage rule from January 2025: What you need to know | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian Airlines to Implement New 7kg One-Baggage Rule Starting January 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>December 25, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Mint</p><p>The Bureau of Civil Aviation (BCAS) has revised hand baggage guidelines allowing passengers to carry only one piece of hand baggage on flights starting January 2025.</p><ul><li>Passengers must check in any additional baggage before boarding.</li><li>Hand baggage weight limit is 7kg for economy and premium class, and 10kg for business class.</li><li>Baggage dimensions must be below 55 cm x 40 cm x 20 cm.</li><li>Tickets booked before May 4, 2024, are exempt from the new guidelines.</li></ul><h2>Statistics</h2><p>In November 2024, Indian flights carried approximately 1.42 crore passengers, a 12% increase from the previous year.</p><blockquote>“Passengers carried by domestic airlines during January-November 2024 were 1,464.02 lakh, registering an annual growth of 5.91%.”</blockquote><p>This new rule is expected to streamline baggage handling and improve boarding efficiency.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/india/indian-airlines-new-7kg-baggage-limit-starts-from-january-2025-what-you-need-to-know-11735292639560.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/india/indian-airlines-new-7kg-baggage-limit-starts-from-january-2025-what-you-need-to-know-11735292639560.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:35:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Gainers and Losers today on 27 December, 2024: Dr Reddys Laboratories, Mahindra & Mahindra, Hindalco Industries, State Bank Of India among most active stocks; Check full list here | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Gainers and Losers today on 27 December, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>The Nifty index saw a rise of 0.27%, ending at 23,750.2. The report highlights the top gainers and losers of the Nifty index and provides an overview of market performance including the Sensex and Midcap stocks.</p>

<h2>Nifty Index Top Gainers and Losers Today</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Top Gainers:</strong> Dr. Reddy's Laboratories (up 2.53%), Mahindra &amp; Mahindra (up 2.48%), IndusInd Bank (up 2.30%).</li>
<li><strong>Top Losers:</strong> Hindalco Industries (down 1.81%), State Bank of India (down 1.58%), Coal India (down 1.58%).</li>
</ul>

<h2>Market Overview</h2>
<ul>
<li>Nifty closed at 23,750.2, reaching a peak of 23,938.85.</li>
<li>Sensex closed at 78,472.48, up 0.29%.</li>
<li>The Midcap index underperformed, finishing 0.27% lower.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics</h2>
<blockquote>"The Nifty has given returns of 9.94% in the last year."
</blockquote>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>The market showed a positive trend on December 27, 2024, with significant movements in the Nifty and Sensex indices, highlighting key stocks to watch moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/top-gainers-and-losers-today-on-27-december-2024-dr-reddys-laboratories-mahindra-mahindra-hindalco-industries-state-bank-of-india-among-most-active-stocks-check-full-list-here-11735295592808.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/top-gainers-and-losers-today-on-27-december-2024-dr-reddys-laboratories-mahindra-mahindra-hindalco-industries-state-bank-of-india-among-most-active-stocks-check-full-list-here-11735295592808.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:33:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asian Paints, Indigo Paints, Berger & others: CareEdge expects further dip in profitability by FY26 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CareEdge Expects Further Profitability Dip for Paint Companies by FY26</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>Share prices of major paint companies like Asian Paints, Berger Paints, and Indigo Paints are under pressure, reflecting concerns over profitability due to the depreciation of the rupee impacting raw material costs.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Paint companies have seen share prices drop up to 7% recently.</li><li>Growth rates for leading players have moderated to mid-single digits, with a shift to negative growth anticipated in H1FY25.</li><li>CareEdge forecasts a revenue rebound in H2 FY25 thanks to price hikes from July-August 2024.</li><li>Intensifying competition from new entrants is leading to increased expenditures in advertising and sales.</li><li>Operating profit margins are projected to decline to 14% by FY26, from 20% in FY24.</li><li>Organised players are expected to capture about 80% market share in the medium term.</li></ul><blockquote>“Operating profitability margin, which reduced to 16% in H1FY25 from 20% in FY24, is expected to further moderate to 14% by FY26.”</blockquote><p>This outlook indicates significant challenges for established and new players alike in the paint industry, highlighting the need for strategic adjustments in a competitive landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/asian-paints-berger-indigo-others-careedge-expects-further-dip-in-profitabiity-by-fy26-11735291822089.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/asian-paints-berger-indigo-others-careedge-expects-further-dip-in-profitabiity-by-fy26-11735291822089.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:32:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Volkswagen Polo India Comeback Confirmed! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Volkswagen Polo India Comeback Confirmed!</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> MotorOctane</p><img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/20241227030609_Volkswagen_Golf_GTI_2025_front.jpg" alt="Volkswagen Golf GTI 2025" /><figcaption>Upcoming Volkswagen Golf GTI for India</figcaption><p>Volkswagen has confirmed the launch of the Golf GTI in India, set to occur by August 2025.</p><ul><li>The Golf GTI will be launched via the CBU route and priced under Rs 45 lakh (on-road, Mumbai).</li><li>It will compete with premium brands such as Mini Cooper and XEV 9e.</li><li>The car is powered by a 2.0-litre turbo petrol engine creating 265 bhp and 370 Nm of torque.</li><li>The vehicle can accelerate from 0-100 km/h in 5.9 seconds.</li><li>A variety of high-tech features will be available, including a 12.9-inch touchscreen and matrix LED headlights.</li></ul><blockquote>Volkswagen is renewing its presence in India with promising models after its Polo GTI.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Volkswagen's Golf GTI is set to make a significant impact in the Indian automotive market, promising exciting features and performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/281512-volkswagen-polo-india-comeback-confirmed</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/281512-volkswagen-polo-india-comeback-confirmed</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:20:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IPOs worth Rs 2 lakh crore expected to hit primary market in 2025; NSDL, Avanse Financial among others in p... - Zee Business]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxQYVNRVUZKdmktQnRFTEJzTC10ZlI4NTRzQjJ1amRjS2hMM2lCRVo3S3d4NXgyT0h0MTUtUGdoTjhDSDFsR0ZIa2NlX2FGLWJ4bGpEbEN6d0Vna3JiOHB4YTVodE5CWFhOTC1GTV9ITnE3QkFKMzdvTkxyRm1SWXNhMDJIVWpQQ09XWFlWOUZ0dHdyeVZVN3Y5QXdXdDd4NXIwYTB3ZGJuZkF5Mmd2MkpJNWtLbm4ybzZKUm92a3ZPbFN3UnhadXRiSVlGNGJ6Z055S0tHdWRMdS1aS0Fldkt1emtCMmx0Y2V5TGxrQlZfSENEeHhPUkRCYTVXX3psclV2dEHSAYcCQVVfeXFMT0RRVk1MbFh4RkdZeDZweC1Jc3gyVnJGaUxRTnJsV2xsMzJYSE1WS01mZGpOMnE1NDNGQU1fWmZOLXI3VnBTZ1FBZnk4OTZlQjlRY1gyYzFnc0M0b3RyeV9pSklWemRVUmE2elZRdEppTkdidUNZbG0tVWFkOXF2YzV3RXBvYzlPWmtpSG4xMFpVSWp2RmkyQ1BLbGtNZ01KdWtMRkVKbzZURTk1SVdObmRJbTNjVWZpYndxbHVxZjZuU284YkdCRUY3dHVOUC1uRFR3eG1lX0VWYlpXaUNlMllqMzF4UlJXNmwyYU0wbmVGOEo1NVNpcFE5Qnc5R0daM0tmY1BPcTg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxQYVNRVUZKdmktQnRFTEJzTC10ZlI4NTRzQjJ1amRjS2hMM2lCRVo3S3d4NXgyT0h0MTUtUGdoTjhDSDFsR0ZIa2NlX2FGLWJ4bGpEbEN6d0Vna3JiOHB4YTVodE5CWFhOTC1GTV9ITnE3QkFKMzdvTkxyRm1SWXNhMDJIVWpQQ09XWFlWOUZ0dHdyeVZVN3Y5QXdXdDd4NXIwYTB3ZGJuZkF5Mmd2MkpJNWtLbm4ybzZKUm92a3ZPbFN3UnhadXRiSVlGNGJ6Z055S0tHdWRMdS1aS0Fldkt1emtCMmx0Y2V5TGxrQlZfSENEeHhPUkRCYTVXX3psclV2dEHSAYcCQVVfeXFMT0RRVk1MbFh4RkdZeDZweC1Jc3gyVnJGaUxRTnJsV2xsMzJYSE1WS01mZGpOMnE1NDNGQU1fWmZOLXI3VnBTZ1FBZnk4OTZlQjlRY1gyYzFnc0M0b3RyeV9pSklWemRVUmE2elZRdEppTkdidUNZbG0tVWFkOXF2YzV3RXBvYzlPWmtpSG4xMFpVSWp2RmkyQ1BLbGtNZ01KdWtMRkVKbzZURTk1SVdObmRJbTNjVWZpYndxbHVxZjZuU284YkdCRUY3dHVOUC1uRFR3eG1lX0VWYlpXaUNlMllqMzF4UlJXNmwyYU0wbmVGOEo1NVNpcFE5Qnc5R0daM0tmY1BPcTg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:20:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>