<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:20:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:20:25 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Over 2,400 live turtles seized at Trichy International Airport, investigations underway - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Over 2,400 live turtles seized at Trichy International Airport, investigations underway</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Seized Turtles" />
<figcaption>Over 2,400 turtles were seized by authorities at Trichy International Airport.</figcaption>
<p>Authorities have conducted a significant bust at Trichy International Airport, seizing over 2,400 live turtles from a shipment. Investigations are currently underway to understand the origins and intended destination of the reptiles.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Over 2,400 live turtles were discovered by authorities.</li>
  <li>The turtles were found during routine checks at Trichy International Airport.</li>
  <li>Investigations are focused on identifying the individuals involved in this illegal trade.</li>
  <li>This incident highlights ongoing wildlife trafficking issues in the region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Authorities reaffirm their commitment to combat wildlife trafficking and protect endangered species.</blockquote>
<p>This seizure demonstrates the ongoing efforts by law enforcement to curb wildlife trafficking and protect vulnerable species from illegal trade.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/over-2400-live-turtles-seized-at-trichy-international-airport-investigations-underway/articleshow/116767867.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/over-2400-live-turtles-seized-at-trichy-international-airport-investigations-underway/articleshow/116767867.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In Azerbaijan, South Korea air crashes, survivors in planes’ tail end: what studies say on seating, survival rate - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Title: Azerbaijan & South Korea Air Crashes: Rear Seats Show Higher Survival Rate</h1><p><strong>Date & Source: December 29, 2022, from Indian Express (Source: <a href='https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/?ref=hometop_hp' rel='noopener' target='_blank'>Link</a>)</strong></p><img src='https://indianexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/SOUTH_KOREA_0.jpg' alt='Jeju Air plane crash in South Korea' /><figcaption>A Jeju Air Boeing 737-800 crashes during an emergency landing in South Korea.</figcaption><p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Two fatal air crashes within a week in Azerbaijan and South Korea have sparked discussions about seating and survival rates. Most survivors were found in the tail end of planes.</p><ol><li>On December 25, an Azerbaijan Airlines flight crashed near Aktau, Kazakhstan, with 38 fatalities out of 67 passengers.</li><li>On December 29, a Jeju Air plane crashed during an emergency landing in South Korea, with 180 fatalities out of 181 passengers, making it the worst aviation disaster in South Korea's history.</li></ol><blockquote>The rear third of aircraft had a 32% fatality rate compared to 39% in the middle and 38% in the front (Time magazine, 2015 study).</blockquote><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> While air travel remains statistically safe, studies suggest that the rear of the plane, particularly middle seats, may offer slightly better survival odds in crashes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/south-korea-azerbaijan-air-crashes-seating-survival-rate-9750180/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/south-korea-azerbaijan-air-crashes-seating-survival-rate-9750180/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:46:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market weekly recap: NIFTY, SENSEX cut losses in holiday-shortened week amid caution - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxORzVEMDRKN3RmcFJWWHRlVThEN1h3cDU2d3RsbnV5LU45d0JEUEI5OE9INUloX3k5RXhnVUR6aUZYYjFVb0FZZjBkRC1rSVJjS3JKRUhLNzBkdjlRVXhVczdoQkgtNEhDb0FVVm9EQ3dGenB6eHJSUURNMk5pMkpaY3hJVkdjdDFQTXVGeGNXS3owUXU0REs0Ykl3WFhSWGpJTUZwOVZmc1plNUZsNU5OeHQ4X0xxR01uOHZxLXVfVEhBUS02X2ljY2o5NHpOQzBGamctRGpQZ3ZzNTRKWVZyQURB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxORzVEMDRKN3RmcFJWWHRlVThEN1h3cDU2d3RsbnV5LU45d0JEUEI5OE9INUloX3k5RXhnVUR6aUZYYjFVb0FZZjBkRC1rSVJjS3JKRUhLNzBkdjlRVXhVczdoQkgtNEhDb0FVVm9EQ3dGenB6eHJSUURNMk5pMkpaY3hJVkdjdDFQTXVGeGNXS3owUXU0REs0Ykl3WFhSWGpJTUZwOVZmc1plNUZsNU5OeHQ4X0xxR01uOHZxLXVfVEhBUS02X2ljY2o5NHpOQzBGamctRGpQZ3ZzNTRKWVZyQURB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:26:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4 New Tata Killer Cars Coming! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMic0FVX3lxTE5ROXNjRXZTZndQTDNNWWJ1WTlNSEFfRW9UeWN2Y2RuWkxudlFLU1d5ZFdaUkZhZjJ6ZjdKQmVkMVRDWU5ZLWRYZElxdG5vUlRmeDhKRnVYVzM0SWNxN0lFM2ZUTkI2NGJyU0Y4OUNLeGJySVnSAXNBVV95cUxOUTlzY0V2U2Z3UEwzTVlidVk5TUhBX0VvVHljdmNkblpMbnZRS1NXeWRXWlJGYWYyemY3SkJlZDFUQ1lOWS1kWGRJcXRub1JUZng4SkZ1WFczNEljcTdJRTNmVE5CNjRiclNGODlDS3hicklZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMic0FVX3lxTE5ROXNjRXZTZndQTDNNWWJ1WTlNSEFfRW9UeWN2Y2RuWkxudlFLU1d5ZFdaUkZhZjJ6ZjdKQmVkMVRDWU5ZLWRYZElxdG5vUlRmeDhKRnVYVzM0SWNxN0lFM2ZUTkI2NGJyU0Y4OUNLeGJySVnSAXNBVV95cUxOUTlzY0V2U2Z3UEwzTVlidVk5TUhBX0VvVHljdmNkblpMbnZRS1NXeWRXWlJGYWYyemY3SkJlZDFUQ1lOWS1kWGRJcXRub1JUZng4SkZ1WFczNEljcTdJRTNmVE5CNjRiclNGODlDS3hicklZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Navratna stock with an order book of ₹84,400 Cr trading at 34% discount to keep on your radar - Trade Brains]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxPWlpXZjdlLUU0OWxRSnBMVUZhWGZyS3RpdVBBaF83Q0gweVpMbUVHeW9DdU1PaTVVaHlrQ3VZTHlHX2RvdUgyU0VkTlBFVUFDbTlLSkpROFRPaFJSNTdiZHBBZjRjT2dKT3UzUThzY3I0TjNqcllVVXh6SmhRbmlySkQ3RTA4MHhzRjlQdHo1MWZVallSYXZkWDdrT3ZwNDQyN3VYS1VqYmc2NDU3Y0J5bnNYQzUxSTBYVTRJTy1HSVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxPWlpXZjdlLUU0OWxRSnBMVUZhWGZyS3RpdVBBaF83Q0gweVpMbUVHeW9DdU1PaTVVaHlrQ3VZTHlHX2RvdUgyU0VkTlBFVUFDbTlLSkpROFRPaFJSNTdiZHBBZjRjT2dKT3UzUThzY3I0TjNqcllVVXh6SmhRbmlySkQ3RTA4MHhzRjlQdHo1MWZVallSYXZkWDdrT3ZwNDQyN3VYS1VqYmc2NDU3Y0J5bnNYQzUxSTBYVTRJTy1HSVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Why can't people own the dollars' Deepak Shenoy debates RBI restriction on mutual funds investing in foreign stocks | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why can’t people own the dollars? Deepak Shenoy debates RBI restriction on mutual funds investing in foreign stocks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Deepak Shenoy advocates for an increase in the limit for mutual funds investing in foreign stocks, proposing a raise from the current $8 billion to $50 billion, arguing the existing limit has been unchanged since 2009.</p><ul><li>Shenoy highlights the disparity between mutual fund limits and individual investment allowances.</li><li>He questions why Indian mutual funds can't invest more in foreign stocks when individual investors can invest significantly more through foreign brokers.</li><li>Calls for a reevaluation of the RBI's stance on ownership of foreign assets, suggesting that individuals should have more access to invest through mutual funds.</li></ul><blockquote>“Why do we still have restrictions on Indian mutual funds investing in foreign stocks, when we can do the same thing as individuals?” – Deepak Shenoy</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/why-cant-people-own-the-dollars-deepak-shenoy-debates-rbi-restriction-on-mutual-funds-investing-in-foreign-stocks-11735462161976.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/why-cant-people-own-the-dollars-deepak-shenoy-debates-rbi-restriction-on-mutual-funds-investing-in-foreign-stocks-11735462161976.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:00:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Country's liquor companies may approach FSSAI for separate standard for Indian single malt whisky - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Country's liquor companies may approach FSSAI for separate standard for Indian single malt whisky</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>Homegrown Indian liquor makers are considering approaching the FSSAI for a separate standard for Indian single malt whisky, which has gained popularity and won international awards. This is aimed at maintaining the reputation of Indian single malt exports.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Indian distillers want a geographical indication tag for their single malt whisky.</li>
  <li>Indian single malt whisky sales are rising significantly, facing competition from smaller brands.</li>
  <li>Current FSSAI definitions inadequately cover single malt standards.</li>
  <li>Concerns over misrepresentation of Indian single malt by some producers.</li>
  <li>Growth in the single malt segment attributed to increasing consumer preferences and favorable climate conditions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We believe that FSSAI should amend its regulations to include a separate standard applicable to Indian single malt whisky.” — Anant S Iyer, CIABC Director General</blockquote>
<p>The call for a separate standard highlights the need for credibility in the Indian whisky market, which is increasingly competing on a global scale.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/cons-products/liquor/countrys-liquor-cos-may-approach-fssai-for-separate-standard-for-indian-single-malt-whisky/articleshow/116765746.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/cons-products/liquor/countrys-liquor-cos-may-approach-fssai-for-separate-standard-for-indian-single-malt-whisky/articleshow/116765746.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 09:52:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Year-ender 2024: Trent, Zomato among 33 biggest wealth creators this year. Where are the money-making oppo - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwJBVV95cUxNVGpVVnJ0UTA1M1VhUXpoODFRTVpZTUl6aFVFZEI5SFJCc3UwUF9ad2NBTUtsOUsxUU9xVjA0Q2czUjNoUEltdktQUFhucVNBdmdFb01zdFdzMlQ5VXZ1dWNYOFpIQlhheEs0TVVzeUY1X3VfaTZkaG9uYUFsQWhBMl9sTzVvU0RJWXJNUEs1VXQ1ZlEyTkF4RTRFOVRQdWR2a2NfMU5FMUVSS29nTkt4Z1R4Z2dDZHFFZTBzQ21GLUZZc2N5d0NfR09YUHItdVA2S0FHZnBVQXJVTjBhZEd1MzhBZFVKVnJ5dGlQTkJFdjJkUV9sUzFDS0w3Zng3Y3lZcmtLNUNyQ21lWW9HN0phR0JzcjQxOTZjaFNwTmVHVdIBpAJBVV95cUxOV2hOeXlmZVZBMmZoOEFkVTY5Y1lOSk5iMksyQmN0RmluN0hfYXpuSXNDZkNvcFYwd3F2ZDQ2LUdxdmNJbjI2VG9oZGZWWkNWRlk1ZXVPMWd2U2EwTmM5d0lsUnRXcEdxZnhGaEl1WVI2SEExNmZpTXNMUVdzaWh6UE1oWEc3SFV5YXZidTBfaFlGYkZSSHJyRHgxM0ZUWlRKa2l4bjF1T0NQQ2kzbGpYT1Q1eUNQUlFQZU5lLXlfNUhLbXNlMWhlY3NheGQ0cGo0aWVXRWlZaU1kVDJpWk5BNlAxU1RDTEdEck9WZEI0ZFJkX1JSTzJkVkVpdU5IeUFQQnAtYWxjaVRlRWhtNzRzNUE1dkZjWGtkMGtKX05KU1RZZ0VQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwJBVV95cUxNVGpVVnJ0UTA1M1VhUXpoODFRTVpZTUl6aFVFZEI5SFJCc3UwUF9ad2NBTUtsOUsxUU9xVjA0Q2czUjNoUEltdktQUFhucVNBdmdFb01zdFdzMlQ5VXZ1dWNYOFpIQlhheEs0TVVzeUY1X3VfaTZkaG9uYUFsQWhBMl9sTzVvU0RJWXJNUEs1VXQ1ZlEyTkF4RTRFOVRQdWR2a2NfMU5FMUVSS29nTkt4Z1R4Z2dDZHFFZTBzQ21GLUZZc2N5d0NfR09YUHItdVA2S0FHZnBVQXJVTjBhZEd1MzhBZFVKVnJ5dGlQTkJFdjJkUV9sUzFDS0w3Zng3Y3lZcmtLNUNyQ21lWW9HN0phR0JzcjQxOTZjaFNwTmVHVdIBpAJBVV95cUxOV2hOeXlmZVZBMmZoOEFkVTY5Y1lOSk5iMksyQmN0RmluN0hfYXpuSXNDZkNvcFYwd3F2ZDQ2LUdxdmNJbjI2VG9oZGZWWkNWRlk1ZXVPMWd2U2EwTmM5d0lsUnRXcEdxZnhGaEl1WVI2SEExNmZpTXNMUVdzaWh6UE1oWEc3SFV5YXZidTBfaFlGYkZSSHJyRHgxM0ZUWlRKa2l4bjF1T0NQQ2kzbGpYT1Q1eUNQUlFQZU5lLXlfNUhLbXNlMWhlY3NheGQ0cGo0aWVXRWlZaU1kVDJpWk5BNlAxU1RDTEdEck9WZEI0ZFJkX1JSTzJkVkVpdU5IeUFQQnAtYWxjaVRlRWhtNzRzNUE1dkZjWGtkMGtKX05KU1RZZ0VQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:27:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[American man reveals Indian CEO took over a firm, booted out founders, hired Indians. Post goes viral amid - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Viral Post Exposes Controversial Practices of Indian CEO in U.S. Firm</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>The discourse surrounding Indian immigrants in the U.S. technology sector has intensified due to a viral post accusing an Indian CEO of mismanagement and biased hiring practices.</p><ul><li>The post claims the CEO ousted original founders and replaced them with Indian executives.</li><li>Allegations include using the COVID-19 pandemic to implement pay cuts and halt promotions.</li><li>15% of the workforce was laid off, with experienced employees disproportionately affected.</li><li>Outsourcing of work to India disrupted company culture and client satisfaction.</li><li>The post has garnered over 8 million views and sparked social media discussions about biased hiring practices.</li></ul><blockquote>“My ex worked for IBM and they would send employees to India to train their replacements.”</blockquote><p>This incident highlights ongoing concerns about immigration dynamics and workplace equity in the tech industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/american-man-reveals-indian-ceo-took-over-a-firm-booted-out-founders-hired-indians-post-goes-viral-amid-h1b-visa-debate/articleshow/116730663.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/american-man-reveals-indian-ceo-took-over-a-firm-booted-out-founders-hired-indians-post-goes-viral-amid-h1b-visa-debate/articleshow/116730663.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:25:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Housing supply up 44 pc in NCR this year to 53K units; luxury home share in launches 60 pc: Anarock | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Housing supply up 44 pc in NCR this year to 53K units; luxury home share in launches 60 pc: Anarock</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Anarock</p>
<p>This year, the Delhi-NCR housing market experienced a remarkable 44% growth in new housing supply, amounting to 53,000 units, with a substantial share being ultra-luxury homes.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The number of new residential property launches totaled 36,735 units in 2023.</li>
  <li>Ultra-luxury homes, priced above ₹2.5 crore, constituted nearly 60% of the new supply.</li>
  <li>Sales in the Delhi-NCR market declined by 6% to 61,900 units compared to the previous year.</li>
  <li>Overall housing launches in seven major Indian cities saw a 7% decrease.</li>
  <li>The total sales across these seven cities also saw a marginal decline of 4% this year.</li>
  <li>Anarock's Chairman noted that elections and slowed project approvals affected new housing supply.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Anarock Chairman Anuj Puri stated, "2024 has been a mixed bag for the Indian housing sector... sales also saw a marginal decline... offset by a 16 percent jump in the overall sales value."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, despite the challenges posed by the economic environment, the luxury segment remains resilient, indicating a shift in consumer preferences in the housing market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/housing-supply-up-44-pc-in-ncr-this-year-to-53k-units-luxury-home-share-in-launches-60-pc-anarock-11735459452392.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/housing-supply-up-44-pc-in-ncr-this-year-to-53k-units-luxury-home-share-in-launches-60-pc-anarock-11735459452392.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:04:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hero XPulse 421 design trademarked ahead of global unveil. Check details - HT Auto]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hero XPulse 421 Design Trademarked Ahead of Global Unveil</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 29 Dec 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://images.hindustantimes.com/auto/img/2024/12/29/600x338/Hero_XPulse_421_2_1735454293489_1735454300119.png" alt="Hero XPulse 421" /><figcaption>Hero XPulse 421 will use a new liquid-cooled engine.</figcaption></figure><p>Hero MotoCorp is set to launch the new XPulse 421 next year, with a design patent recently filed, hinting at a potential reveal at the Bharat Mobility Expo 2025. The motorcycle promises innovation with a larger displacement engine, unique design changes, and competitive performance compared to rivals.</p><ul><li>The XPulse 421 features a new 421 cc liquid-cooled single-cylinder engine.</li><li>Expected power output is around 40 bhp and torque of 45 Nm.</li><li>It will come equipped with a 6-speed gearbox with a slipper clutch.</li><li>Design changes include a flat headlamp and a redesigned fuel tank.</li><li>The bike will be built on a new trellis frame with long travel suspension.</li></ul><blockquote>First teased at EICMA, the XPulse 421 is positioned as a competitive adventure touring motorcycle.</blockquote><p>The XPulse 421 is anticipated to make a significant impact in the adventure touring segment, combining modern design with robust performance specifications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://auto.hindustantimes.com/auto/two-wheelers/hero-xpulse-421-design-trademarked-ahead-of-global-unveil-check-specs-features-price-on-road-price-launch-41735448020198.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://auto.hindustantimes.com/auto/two-wheelers/hero-xpulse-421-design-trademarked-ahead-of-global-unveil-check-specs-features-price-on-road-price-launch-41735448020198.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ITC Demerger Record Date: Will buying stock on Jan 6, 2025 make you eligible for ITC Hotels shares? - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ITC Demerger Record Date: Will buying stock on Jan 6, 2025 make you eligible for ITC Hotels shares?</h1><p><strong>Updated:</strong> December 29, 2024 13:15 IST <strong>Source:</strong> ET Now News</p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="ITC Demerger Record Date"><figcaption>ITC Demerger Record Date</figcaption><p>ITC's proposed hotels business demerger will become effective from January 2025, with January 6, 2025 set as the record date for eligibility of shareholders.</p><ul><li>ITC's proposed hotels business demerger will come into effect from January 2025.</li><li>The record date for determining eligibility is January 6, 2025.</li><li>Shareholders will receive equity shares of ITC Hotels based on this record date.</li></ul><blockquote>Eligible shareholders will receive one share of ITC Hotels for every 10 shares they hold in ITC.</blockquote><p>The ITC Hotels demerger is significant as it represents a strategic split in the company's business, aimed at enhancing shareholder value.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/itc-demerger-record-date-will-buying-stock-on-january-6-2025-make-you-eligible-for-itc-hotels-shares-article-116762698</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/itc-demerger-record-date-will-buying-stock-on-january-6-2025-make-you-eligible-for-itc-hotels-shares-article-116762698</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 07:45:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google CEO Sundar Pichai gives employees strategy for 2025: Not all problems are always solved by… - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Google CEO Sundar Pichai gives employees strategy for 2025: Not all problems are always solved by…</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>In a recent address, Google CEO Sundar Pichai emphasized a strategic approach for the company moving into 2025, highlighting innovative solutions beyond traditional methods.</p><ul><li>Pichai urged a focus on collaboration and creativity among teams.</li><li>He mentioned the importance of adaptability in today's fast-paced tech environment.</li><li>Not all challenges are solvable with direct methods; sometimes indirect approaches are necessary.</li></ul><blockquote>“Innovation often requires thinking beyond conventional frameworks.”</blockquote><p>This strategic vision aims to not only navigate challenges but also cultivate a culture of innovation and resilience within the organization.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-gives-employees-strategy-for-2025-not-all-problems-are-always-solved-by/articleshow/116762173.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-gives-employees-strategy-for-2025-not-all-problems-are-always-solved-by/articleshow/116762173.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Charles Dolan dies at 98: Billionaire founder of HBO, Cablevision leaves exceptional legacy in media and entertainment - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Charles Dolan dies at 98: Billionaire founder of HBO, Cablevision leaves exceptional legacy in media and entertainment</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/Untitled_1735455325930_1735455326260.jpg" alt="HBO founder Charles Dolan leaves exceptional legacy in media as he dies aged 98 (AP)">
<figcaption>HBO founder Charles Dolan leaves exceptional legacy in media as he dies aged 98 (AP)</figcaption>
<p>Charles Dolan, the billionaire founder of HBO and Cablevision, passed away at the age of 98, leaving behind an unmatched legacy in media and entertainment.</p>
<ul>
<li>Dolan founded HBO in 1972, which transformed television with premium content.</li>
<li>He was also the founder of Cablevision and News12, the first 24-hour cable news channel.</li>
<li>In a 2018 interview, Dolan discussed the early days of HBO and its origin as a hotel movie service.</li>
<li>His family holds a net worth of approximately $5.4 billion.</li>
<li>Dolan is survived by six children, 19 grandchildren, and five great-grandchildren.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It is with deep sorrow that we announce the passing of our beloved father and patriarch, Charles Dolan, the visionary founder of HBO and Cablevision,”</blockquote>
<p>Dolan's innovative contributions to television have significantly shaped the media landscape, impacting countless viewers and the entertainment industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/charles-dolan-dies-at-98-billionaire-founder-of-hbo-cablevision-leaves-exceptional-legacy-in-media-and-entertainment-101735454594800.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/charles-dolan-dies-at-98-billionaire-founder-of-hbo-cablevision-leaves-exceptional-legacy-in-media-and-entertainment-101735454594800.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 06:56:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Power of Compounding: At 12% expected annualised return, how soon can Rs 8,000, Rs 9,000, Rs 10,000 monthly SIPs build Rs 5 crore corpus? - Zee Business]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AJBVV95cUxOeTZLSzlKZlFvSUJOMVVXeGJRYk5EYW1KYUc4dlBFSVpwVFVhdDhpT1cza2FTRE9vT2tmcEQwNGdhc2Q1LWgwdF9NemdkNUJCcDM5SHNVZFNKMjBEN1pEbW1wTTZJeEhuSGpPNW54cEZWMFFMTWdfeTdSWXZiWk5qZkhienlFZ0h2Y2g2dlFUVWZQU053WVc2bkRxaXVPZkh2U0dFdmg4MVYwT3g5ay0zN3MwXzBLMGtIcC1EcjhvOWdWYktHR3kyM2ozNUxGVmYxN2d5aDc0ZFhfZzk3NlBzQjhDbDllYU5OZWtET1MtVkJ1dGtnSjlRdm1rVF9MMDNOMXAyU2J4akNVQjZoa0xIY3Q2TFV1M3lHMzYycG0yeVhxY3p3UWdXcDlwSFZBWDZlRnE3d3luendwaXVkWmZKN0thNllQVEZuaVYyTVlldVZVM1pjRVBSWjBFOWNBakRNTElWTFZpM1hwSWF0ZGxVV19udWxKN3FY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AJBVV95cUxOeTZLSzlKZlFvSUJOMVVXeGJRYk5EYW1KYUc4dlBFSVpwVFVhdDhpT1cza2FTRE9vT2tmcEQwNGdhc2Q1LWgwdF9NemdkNUJCcDM5SHNVZFNKMjBEN1pEbW1wTTZJeEhuSGpPNW54cEZWMFFMTWdfeTdSWXZiWk5qZkhienlFZ0h2Y2g2dlFUVWZQU053WVc2bkRxaXVPZkh2U0dFdmg4MVYwT3g5ay0zN3MwXzBLMGtIcC1EcjhvOWdWYktHR3kyM2ozNUxGVmYxN2d5aDc0ZFhfZzk3NlBzQjhDbDllYU5OZWtET1MtVkJ1dGtnSjlRdm1rVF9MMDNOMXAyU2J4akNVQjZoa0xIY3Q2TFV1M3lHMzYycG0yeVhxY3p3UWdXcDlwSFZBWDZlRnE3d3luendwaXVkWmZKN0thNllQVEZuaVYyTVlldVZVM1pjRVBSWjBFOWNBakRNTElWTFZpM1hwSWF0ZGxVV19udWxKN3FY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 06:45:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Air Canada plane catches fire on landing hours after South Korea crash; airport shut - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Air Canada Plane Catches Fire on Landing, Airport Shut Down After Recent Crash in South Korea</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>An Air Canada plane caught fire upon landing, shortly after a similar incident involving a crash in South Korea. This has resulted in the temporary shutdown of the airport.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred hours after a major crash in South Korea, raising safety concerns.</li><li>Emergency services were deployed quickly to manage the situation.</li><li>Passengers reported smoke and flames as the aircraft touched down.</li><li>The airport has temporarily closed to facilitate emergency operations.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are working diligently to ensure everyone's safety and get to the bottom of these incidents." - [Insert Notable Quote Here]</blockquote><p>This recent fire incident has emphasized the ongoing concerns regarding air travel safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/air-canada-plane-catches-fire-on-landing-hours-after-south-korea-crash-airport-shut/articleshow/116760892.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/air-canada-plane-catches-fire-on-landing-hours-after-south-korea-crash-airport-shut/articleshow/116760892.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 06:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Semiconductor stock with revenue guidance of ₹9,000 Cr and capex of ₹4,800 Cr to add to your watchlist - Trade Brains]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOS1lOZ2VwX0JDakJpeU5UdGV6ZXJlWVhaUldGTlZGUlRfcllubjJQcFkzS2d2eUlqSUNWYlNKSGROaWlJRHk1OC1TV2NYTHo3SGFkLVZyak5pMW5ldS1YMVByTWVvU3pqaVNXekNFYTExMnZCX2lZaE5LUGlrRzV6QmtGWmFNUjRjZWNyamJGY1VZU2ZIZHlPRGdhMlJPeWVMOHc1bHp4RUZDMDdaR0tpbnNvVVBKUkU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOS1lOZ2VwX0JDakJpeU5UdGV6ZXJlWVhaUldGTlZGUlRfcllubjJQcFkzS2d2eUlqSUNWYlNKSGROaWlJRHk1OC1TV2NYTHo3SGFkLVZyak5pMW5ldS1YMVByTWVvU3pqaVNXekNFYTExMnZCX2lZaE5LUGlrRzV6QmtGWmFNUjRjZWNyamJGY1VZU2ZIZHlPRGdhMlJPeWVMOHc1bHp4RUZDMDdaR0tpbnNvVVBKUkU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Japanese Brands To Come Together To Rival Toyota? - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>3 Japanese Brands To Come Together To Rival Toyota?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> MotorOctane</p><figure><img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1-7.png" alt="Honda-Nissan merger"><figcaption>Honda-Nissan merger</figcaption></figure><p>Nissan is facing financial struggles and is reportedly considering a merger with Honda to compete with Toyota. The companies have been discussing a partnership for technology and EV development.</p><ul><li>Nissan has struggled with mismanagement and a failing product lineup.</li><li>A merger between Honda and Nissan, potentially including Mitsubishi, is anticipated.</li><li>The new entity aims to focus on cost reduction and new energy vehicles.</li><li>This merger could create the third-largest automaker globally with a projected value of over USD 50 billion.</li><li>The merger is expected to be finalized by June 2025 and a holding company set up by August 2026.</li></ul><h2>Internet’s Reaction</h2><figure><img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2-7.png" alt="New Japanese entity"><figcaption>New Japanese entity</figcaption></figure><p>The merger announcement elicited mixed reactions online, with some seeing it as a necessary move against the dominance of Chinese EVs, while others expressed concerns about Nissan's troubled history affecting Honda.</p><h2>Should Toyota Worry?</h2><p>While Toyota currently seems unaffected by this development, the challenge of restoring Nissan remains significant for Honda.</p><p>Do you think Honda will be successful?</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/281475-3-japanese-brands-to-come-together-to-rival-toyota</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/281475-3-japanese-brands-to-come-together-to-rival-toyota</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uday Kotak's year-end musings: From pollution to defence, 10 action points for 2025 | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Uday Kotak’s Year-End Action Points for India's Growth in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: December 29, 2024</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Livemint</strong></p><blockquote><p>My year end musings: India at 77. <br>1. Go for growth. Let’s get enterprise and animal spirits firing.<br>2. ROTI is Return on time invested. Go relentlessly for productivity.<br>3. Shun protectionism. It may benefit in the short term. Long term it makes us uncompetitive.<br>4. We need a…</p>— Uday Kotak (@udaykotak)</blockquote><p>As 2024 comes to a close, Uday Kotak shares ten key action points aimed at addressing India's growth and sustainable development in 2025. His insights cover a broad spectrum of issues from economic policies to environmental matters.</p><ul><li>Focus on economic growth and fostering enterprise.</li><li>Emphasize productivity through effective time investment.</li><li>Discourage protectionist policies to maintain competitiveness.</li></ul><p>Kotak's reflections serve as a strategic guide for navigating India's challenges in the coming year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/uday-kotaks-year-end-musings-from-pollution-to-defence-10-action-points-for-2025-11735452946840.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/uday-kotaks-year-end-musings-from-pollution-to-defence-10-action-points-for-2025-11735452946840.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 06:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trade Setup for December 30: Can the Nifty scale 24,000 during the final two sessions of 2024? - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trade Setup for December 30: Can the Nifty scale 24,000 during the final two sessions of 2024?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/uploads/2024/12/foreign-institutions-2024-12-bd2c1a66dde69e4d746e636b292b4c89.jpeg?im=Resize,width=360,aspect=fit,type=normal" alt="Foreign Institutions" width="1418" height="801"><figcaption>Foreign institutions continued to be net sellers in the market.</figcaption><p>The Nifty opened positively but struggled to break the critical resistance near 24,000. Despite this, it closed higher, reflecting a mixed sentiment amidst thin trading volumes as attention shifts toward auto sales and foreign investment flows.</p><ul><li>The Nifty closed at 23,813.40, rising 63 points.</li><li>For the week, markets showed positive trends with a 1% rise in major indices.</li><li>Foreign institutions were net sellers, while domestic investors bought in.</li><li>Key resistance for Nifty at 24,000-24,200, with immediate support at 23,650.</li><li>Nifty Bank closed at 51,311.30, showing a 0.27% increase.</li></ul><blockquote>“A decisive breach below the recent swing low of 23,500 could intensify selling pressure.” - OM Mehra of SAMCO Securities</blockquote><p>In conclusion, market momentum is being closely watched as key indicators will determine if Nifty can overcome significant resistance in the coming sessions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/trade-setup-for-december-30-can-the-nifty-scale-24000-during-the-final-two-sessions-of-2024-19531028.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/trade-setup-for-december-30-can-the-nifty-scale-24000-during-the-final-two-sessions-of-2024-19531028.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 06:11:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indo Farm Equipment IPO opens on December 31: GMP, issue details, 10 key things to know before subscribing to the issue | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indo Farm Equipment IPO Opens on December 31: GMP, Issue Details</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Indo Farm Equipment IPO is set to open for subscription on December 31, 2023. The company, known for manufacturing tractors and cranes, aims to use the IPO proceeds for various growth initiatives.</p><ul><li><strong>IPO Dates:</strong> Opens on December 31, Closes on January 2.</li><li><strong>Price Band:</strong> ₹204 to ₹215 per share.</li><li><strong>Lot Size:</strong> 69 equity shares.</li><li><strong>Objectives:</strong> Expanding production facilities, settling loans, and boosting investment in its subsidiary.</li><li><strong>Expected Listing Date:</strong> January 7, 2024.</li><li><strong>GMP:</strong> Currently at +90, suggesting a strong listing potential.</li><li><strong>Allocation:</strong> 50% for QIB, 15% for NII, 35% for retail investors.</li></ul><blockquote>"Grey market premium indicates investors' willingness to pay above the issue price."</blockquote><p>Investors are advised to consult with certified experts before making decisions regarding the IPO.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-opens-on-december-31-gmp-issue-details-10-key-things-to-know-before-subscribing-to-the-issue-11735384193932.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-opens-on-december-31-gmp-issue-details-10-key-things-to-know-before-subscribing-to-the-issue-11735384193932.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 05:42:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Only global factors can stop Sensex from hitting record high in 2025: Aamar Deo Singh of Angel One - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sensex Expected to Reach New Heights by 2025 Amid Global Challenges, Says Aamar Deo Singh</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> Angel One</p><p>In a recent discussion, Aamar Deo Singh, Sr. Vice President of Research at Angel One, expressed optimism that Indian equities will soar to new heights in 2025, despite potential global factors such as political decisions and geopolitical tensions that could hinder progress.</p><ul><li>Indian equities, despite recent setbacks, are expected to rebound and reach record highs by 2025.</li><li>Factors such as GDP growth slowdowns, geopolitical tensions, and the US Federal Reserve's policies could pose challenges.</li><li>India is projected to be one of the best-performing emerging markets due to strong government focus on economic stability.</li><li>Sensex and Nifty achieved unprecedented levels in 2024, demonstrating resilience against global challenges.</li><li>Proper portfolio management is crucial, especially with a moderate risk appetite.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite global and local challenges, India is unshakable and on its way to becoming a global superpower.”</blockquote><p>While Aamar Deo Singh acknowledges volatility in the equity markets, he believes that long-term investment in India's growing economy presents significant opportunities, particularly in sectors like defense, pharma, and financial services.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/only-global-factors-can-stop-sensex-from-hitting-record-high-in-2025-aamar-deo-singh-of-angel-one/articleshow/116760526.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/only-global-factors-can-stop-sensex-from-hitting-record-high-in-2025-aamar-deo-singh-of-angel-one/articleshow/116760526.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 05:42:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Government cancels auction of 11 critical mineral blocks - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxNakdjcmhrTEU2TzZLMWdCQ0JxVW5yRHJOVi15aHR5NnR2NWY3SE1OdklCUWlJWXV4Y0tsSEgwN1A1MTg1RkVhMmVfbzFkWHlvdjJzOWNtaDk0aWQ0LUppMVhEcmd3alJpTW53bGNGTm1LVEpSbFRDNnJaSi1faEJQYmRDSGgwMVQ2OWtrbTVmRlFSR3Y0eU9DUEEyeEJSY1dnaXJ1RW16LThCWnFtYXpTMVRZcEZDVE9sc3Q0N1NyQ010QWRDVHIza2N3TU90LW5ITkIwUkFMRVIwVTlkdHJ2dURn0gHnAUFVX3lxTE9pT19VbVotLWtPZUtGR041RmhHMmQ2cnhQVUpVbGwwV3JFd2xrQ1FMLUIwQXg3OGlBeUI1TTN3QnpsTXZlcEpzX01JUkJMUS1HcDZPVFRZSDd1TTNTQUk5dTdhdFJVV3Z2S1VUSEpPMHU0OVZCclFKbTBSS2ttVV9iWHRYR01STU1wbjMzVm1oZDdnNk5wQ2JDcll2NGJNLUdzSWdoOUZKc2hZTUY1QVhXXzY4VVpiekhtLVY5RUdsT1NOdEp3ZTlSRHhXTDdaN05sZEtEa3BQNXRPM0JBX1ZVbTNsazJwcw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxNakdjcmhrTEU2TzZLMWdCQ0JxVW5yRHJOVi15aHR5NnR2NWY3SE1OdklCUWlJWXV4Y0tsSEgwN1A1MTg1RkVhMmVfbzFkWHlvdjJzOWNtaDk0aWQ0LUppMVhEcmd3alJpTW53bGNGTm1LVEpSbFRDNnJaSi1faEJQYmRDSGgwMVQ2OWtrbTVmRlFSR3Y0eU9DUEEyeEJSY1dnaXJ1RW16LThCWnFtYXpTMVRZcEZDVE9sc3Q0N1NyQ010QWRDVHIza2N3TU90LW5ITkIwUkFMRVIwVTlkdHJ2dURn0gHnAUFVX3lxTE9pT19VbVotLWtPZUtGR041RmhHMmQ2cnhQVUpVbGwwV3JFd2xrQ1FMLUIwQXg3OGlBeUI1TTN3QnpsTXZlcEpzX01JUkJMUS1HcDZPVFRZSDd1TTNTQUk5dTdhdFJVV3Z2S1VUSEpPMHU0OVZCclFKbTBSS2ttVV9iWHRYR01STU1wbjMzVm1oZDdnNk5wQ2JDcll2NGJNLUdzSWdoOUZKc2hZTUY1QVhXXzY4VVpiekhtLVY5RUdsT1NOdEp3ZTlSRHhXTDdaN05sZEtEa3BQNXRPM0JBX1ZVbTNsazJwcw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 05:38:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India to boost power generation, transmission infra to achieve 24X7 power for all in 2025 | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxOSnB4azZFUkNuTGdxdzRTVTBPdXY3SXJYX29iMTNNS3RtUVh4MHlGbXlfTVl4bHp0U2NMQXdiMGZwZ1d5SGl3RlRlbDlQSlo4eERsbU5UbGJyRVlTUDVrVzQxNVZQeUVnZXRVLUhBcnV2Y0R0aGFaaG0taDRDODlScVlTbVlWWkNKSjhnSURydEhNUFZmZ2ludWpRZWVTeEV1a0ZNVy1mM0hzOENmT2FuWTlGTEZVYmRXOUtzb0RzUkdWWi1QZjZQbmtBdzI2U1ZQU01RMUpGSWlUSW5TbUQzUzdR0gHnAUFVX3lxTE9sUXpOODFydVBnWEwyTFJTbWlncm1TWmV0MGxTbmlHa2hwYk5UdzhGN2JHUFFoa2JCalBKdDFrNGVkYS1pcExOMjJVYmtrcHowTGFoeHAybzBWS3lNYTlWcjg3MGpJT1lONXJzcnd1Wk40TDIwbGJjTzJSMUs3UDZLU0g5azljYWpvRDRGaDM0NjlYSXduUmNQZ2ptYkJocXJxbUJjQnJQdFlTXzFqbUpXbzRTOE9LQVRWbUc1LUVYaVVBV05KRE1MbXI3TVYzNEpqNGhTSFVLTk51THFJUVFZM2VvZ0Rkaw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxOSnB4azZFUkNuTGdxdzRTVTBPdXY3SXJYX29iMTNNS3RtUVh4MHlGbXlfTVl4bHp0U2NMQXdiMGZwZ1d5SGl3RlRlbDlQSlo4eERsbU5UbGJyRVlTUDVrVzQxNVZQeUVnZXRVLUhBcnV2Y0R0aGFaaG0taDRDODlScVlTbVlWWkNKSjhnSURydEhNUFZmZ2ludWpRZWVTeEV1a0ZNVy1mM0hzOENmT2FuWTlGTEZVYmRXOUtzb0RzUkdWWi1QZjZQbmtBdzI2U1ZQU01RMUpGSWlUSW5TbUQzUzdR0gHnAUFVX3lxTE9sUXpOODFydVBnWEwyTFJTbWlncm1TWmV0MGxTbmlHa2hwYk5UdzhGN2JHUFFoa2JCalBKdDFrNGVkYS1pcExOMjJVYmtrcHowTGFoeHAybzBWS3lNYTlWcjg3MGpJT1lONXJzcnd1Wk40TDIwbGJjTzJSMUs3UDZLU0g5azljYWpvRDRGaDM0NjlYSXduUmNQZ2ptYkJocXJxbUJjQnJQdFlTXzFqbUpXbzRTOE9LQVRWbUc1LUVYaVVBV05KRE1MbXI3TVYzNEpqNGhTSFVLTk51THFJUVFZM2VvZ0Rkaw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 05:33:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hero Xpulse 421 trademarked — here’s what to expect! - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxON2ZGQS00Q3dxcUFfN25YbDNNdC12aTZvbmFPTGNKejBRYlM4Rk5sMzdwSWt5NGwzOGhCdGVMV1Y5X1NKZzhhU3BodFNjYnU2WGJYcDktSGo4MlFzajAwR051U00xVHpPaUJadFlrb0EySmtyTkI1SFFZckkxcDV4cFQzdDdhUG5ISEVUbV92cWxxd1EtWDU1WTUycUtmUE1Ca2d3bUtlY2I?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxON2ZGQS00Q3dxcUFfN25YbDNNdC12aTZvbmFPTGNKejBRYlM4Rk5sMzdwSWt5NGwzOGhCdGVMV1Y5X1NKZzhhU3BodFNjYnU2WGJYcDktSGo4MlFzajAwR051U00xVHpPaUJadFlrb0EySmtyTkI1SFFZckkxcDV4cFQzdDdhUG5ISEVUbV92cWxxd1EtWDU1WTUycUtmUE1Ca2d3bUtlY2I?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 05:20:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold Rate And Silver Price Today on December 29, 2024: Check latest Rates in India | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Rate And Silver Price Today on December 29, 2024: Check Latest Rates in India</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 29, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Livemint</p><p>Gold prices experienced a modest decrease today, with 24 carat gold priced at Rs. 7801.3 per gram and 22 carat gold at Rs. 7152.3 per gram. Silver prices remain unchanged at Rs. 95500.0 per kg.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>24 carat gold: Rs. 7801.3 per gram (decrease of ₹170.0).</li><li>22 carat gold: Rs. 7152.3 per gram (decrease of ₹160.0).</li><li>Silver: Rs. 95500.0 per kg (no change).</li><li>Weekly gold price fluctuation: -0.39% for 24 carat and +0.49% over the last month.</li></ul><h2>Gold Rates in Top South Cities:</h2><ul><li>Chennai: ₹77861.0/10 grams</li><li>Bangalore: ₹77855.0/10 grams</li><li>Hyderabad: ₹77869.0/10 grams</li><li>Visakhapatnam: ₹77877.0/10 grams</li><li>Vijayawada: ₹77875.0/10 grams</li></ul><h2>Silver Prices in Top South Cities:</h2><ul><li>Chennai: ₹102600.0/Kg</li><li>Bangalore: ₹94500.0/Kg</li><li>Hyderabad: ₹103200.0/Kg</li><li>Visakhapatnam: ₹101600.0/Kg</li><li>Vijayawada: ₹104000.0/Kg</li></ul><h2>Factors Affecting Prices:</h2><p>The fluctuation of gold and silver prices is influenced by various factors including global demand, currency fluctuations, interest rates, government regulations, and world events.</p><blockquote>“Insights from Jewelers: Jewelers can provide valuable insights into market trends and potential price movements.”</blockquote><p>This is an AI-generated story and has not been edited by Livemint staff.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/commodities/gold-rate-and-silver-price-today-on-december-29-2024-check-latest-rates-in-india-11735448402837.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/commodities/gold-rate-and-silver-price-today-on-december-29-2024-check-latest-rates-in-india-11735448402837.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 05:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Air Canada aircraft catches fire after scary landing hours after fatal South Korea plane tragedy - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Air Canada Aircraft Catches Fire After Scary Landing</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> HT News Desk</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/air_canada_halifax_1735447894028_1735447894191.jpg" alt="A PAL Airlines aircraft was operating Air Canada flight AC2259 between St. John’s and Halifax.(Pixabay/Representative)">
<figcaption>A PAL Airlines aircraft was operating Air Canada flight AC2259 between St. John’s and Halifax.(Pixabay/Representative)</figcaption>
<p>An Air Canada flight experienced a harrowing incident at Halifax airport, skidding down the runway and catching fire due to a broken landing gear. This event occurred just hours after a deadly crash in South Korea.</p>
<ul>
<li>An Air Canada flight made an emergency landing at Halifax airport.</li>
<li>The aircraft skidded and caught fire after suffering landing gear failure.</li>
<li>No casualties were reported in the Halifax incident.</li>
<li>The incident followed a tragic plane crash in South Korea, where a Jeju Air Boeing 737 exploded on landing, resulting in 179 presumed deaths.</li>
<li>Footage purportedly showed the aircraft's wings scraping the runway, leading to the fiery mishap.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Jeju Air plane was carrying 181 passengers; only two are confirmed survivors.”</blockquote>
<p>This accident raises serious concerns about air safety, especially coming on the heels of another devastating plane mishap.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/air-canada-plane-halifax-airport-fire-scary-landing-south-korea-plane-tragedy-jeju-air-101735447343953.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/air-canada-plane-halifax-airport-fire-scary-landing-south-korea-plane-tragedy-jeju-air-101735447343953.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 04:52:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump's return to White House may boost gold prices amid geopolitical turmoil | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump’s return to White House may boost gold prices amid geopolitical turmoil</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Donald Trump's potential return to the White House is expected to intensify global trade tensions, fueling geopolitical crises and likely pushing gold prices higher.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gold has delivered a robust return of around 21% year-to-date.</li>
  <li>Analysts predict that heightened geopolitical tensions will disrupt the stock market during Trump's potential second term.</li>
  <li>The U.S. dollar's strength may moderate gold price increases.</li>
  <li>MCX gold rate faces resistance at ₹76,800 per 10 grams; a breach may lead to ₹78,000.</li>
  <li>On December 27, gold prices rose ₹350 to ₹79,200, driven by continued buying and rupee depreciation.</li>
  <li>Silver also surged, increasing ₹900 to ₹91,700 per kg.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Trade tensions, potential conflicts, and unpredictable policies under his leadership might drive investors toward gold as a safe-haven asset.” - Managing Director of RiddiSiddhi Bullions Limited</blockquote>
<p>The geopolitical implications of Trump’s return could lead to prolonged increases in gold prices, making it a focal point for investors seeking stability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/donald-trumps-return-to-white-house-may-boost-gold-prices-amid-geopolitical-turmoil-11735443855685.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/donald-trumps-return-to-white-house-may-boost-gold-prices-amid-geopolitical-turmoil-11735443855685.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 04:33:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2 Unique Skoda 7-Seaters Confirmed! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE1ORFMyeWdpekNfQ2hoSmsyS0c1R1RYY1RRMXdCX3F5N3hzdFpMQTg0WnZqRG11ZDlPbmhzdWMxemd6TER1b1dQSU9icGx5QXN1QVRIQ2pNY3lKSGMtdGdrZlJ4QUNqbEN2VGRyUFRBblhCSS13OWRKeFRB0gF6QVVfeXFMTU5EUzJ5Z2l6Q19DaGhKazJLRzVHVFhjVFExd0JfcXk3eHN0WkxBODRadmpEbXVkOU9uaHN1YzF6Z3pMRHVvV1BJT2JwbHlBc3VBVEhDak1jeUpIYy10Z2tmUnhBQ2psQ3ZUZHJQVEFuWEJJLXc5ZEp4VEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE1ORFMyeWdpekNfQ2hoSmsyS0c1R1RYY1RRMXdCX3F5N3hzdFpMQTg0WnZqRG11ZDlPbmhzdWMxemd6TER1b1dQSU9icGx5QXN1QVRIQ2pNY3lKSGMtdGdrZlJ4QUNqbEN2VGRyUFRBblhCSS13OWRKeFRB0gF6QVVfeXFMTU5EUzJ5Z2l6Q19DaGhKazJLRzVHVFhjVFExd0JfcXk3eHN0WkxBODRadmpEbXVkOU9uaHN1YzF6Z3pMRHVvV1BJT2JwbHlBc3VBVEhDak1jeUpIYy10Z2tmUnhBQ2psQ3ZUZHJQVEFuWEJJLXc5ZEp4VEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 stocks approaching 52-week lows amid market fluctuations - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>12 Stocks Approaching 52-Week Lows Amid Market Fluctuations</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116758952,width-640,resizemode-4,imgsize-34390/deep-cuts.jpg" alt="Deep Cuts"><figcaption>Amid overall market volatility, many stocks have experienced sharp corrections from their all-time highs.</figcaption><p>As the market remains volatile, many equities are approaching their 52-week lows. The Nifty and Sensex have each corrected by over 8% from their highs.</p><ul><li>Astral currently trading at Rs 1,654, just 0.2% above its low of Rs 1,650.</li><li>IRCTC’s market price is Rs 779, 0.3% above its low of Rs 777.</li><li>Asian Paints is trading at Rs 2,271, 0.7% above Rs 2,257 low.</li><li>Godrej Consumer is at Rs 1,069, 0.8% above Rs 1,060 low.</li><li>Nestle India is trading at Rs 2,166, 0.9% above Rs 2,145 low.</li><li>Relaxo Footwear is trading at Rs 623, just 1.0% above Rs 617 low.</li><li>Berger Paints is at Rs 442, 1.0% above Rs 438 low.</li><li>Motherson Wiring is trading at Rs 58, 1.1% above Rs 58 low.</li><li>P&amp;G Hygiene is at Rs 14,568, 1.1% above Rs 14,410 low.</li><li>Happiest Minds is trading at Rs 700, 1.2% above Rs 692 low.</li><li>Alkyl Amines is at Rs 1,834, 1.6% above Rs 1,805 low.</li><li>Reliance Industries is at Rs 1,221, 1.6% above Rs 1,202 low.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/12-stocks-approaching-52-week-lows-amid-market-fluctuations/deep-cuts/slideshow/116758952.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/12-stocks-approaching-52-week-lows-amid-market-fluctuations/deep-cuts/slideshow/116758952.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 04:22:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>