<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:20:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:20:13 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Picks: PSU shares that currently offer the highest potential upside - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Picks: PSU shares that currently offer the highest potential upside</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="PSU Stocks" title="PSU Stocks" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption></figcaption><p>This article discusses the top public sector unit (PSU) stocks that present the most significant upside potential following substantial corrections from their peak values. Stocks such as Oil India, Coal India, and ONGC are highlighted for their projected recoveries.</p><ul><li>PSU stocks experienced strong performance in the first half of the year but faced declines during the second half, with the Nifty PSE index still up 22% year-to-date.</li><li>Stocks have corrected between 30% to 50% from their highs, yet are projected to rebound in the next year.</li><li>Oil India is the top gainer with a 70% return, but down 45% from its peak, with a projected upside of 47%.</li><li>Coal India predicted to rise 41% after a 30% decline from peak levels.</li><li>PFC and ONGC also show strong recovery potential, with estimated upsides of 35.4% and 35%, respectively.</li><li>REC and NTPC have notable projections of 34% and 33.5% upside, respectively.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite the corrections, analysts remain bullish on several PSU stocks, suggesting significant recovery potential in the coming months.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, various PSU stocks are well-positioned for recovery, making them enticing options for investors looking to capitalize on their projected upside.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/top-psu-stock-picks-ongc-oil-india-rec-pfc-coal-india-ntpc-share-price-upside-potential-19531436.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/top-psu-stock-picks-ongc-oil-india-rec-pfc-coal-india-ntpc-share-price-upside-potential-19531436.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:48:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold price appreciates as traders anticipate Fed policy outlook next year - FXStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Price Recovers Recent Losses</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 31, 2022
<strong>Source:</strong> FXStreet</p>
<img src="https://editorial.fxsstatic.com/miscelaneous/image-638711237254973322.png" alt="Gold Price Chart" width="500" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"><figcaption>Gold Price Chart</figcaption>
<p>The Gold price (XAU/USD) has recovered its recent losses, currently trading near $2,620.00, as markets anticipate signals regarding the United States (US) economy and the Federal Reserve’s (Fed) interest rate outlook under the incoming Trump administration.</p>
<ul>
<li>Gold gains support due to increased risk aversion and potential trade conflicts.</li>
<li>The outlook for fewer Fed rate cuts in 2025 might cap the upside for Gold.</li>
<li>Geopolitical risks, including Israeli attacks on Gaza hospitals, also support Gold prices.</li>
<li>Gold is set to finish the year with a 27% gain, its strongest annual performance since 2010.</li>
</ul>
<p>Gold prices are influenced by the US Dollar Index (DXY), US Treasury bond yields, and geopolitical tensions. The Fed's recent hawkish pivot and the anticipated economic strategies of the incoming Trump administration are also key factors affecting Gold prices.</p>
<p>The daily chart indicates a consolidation phase for Gold, with the 14-day Relative Strength Index (RSI) hovering just below the 50 mark. Key resistances and supports are identified for potential future price movements.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-receives-support-from-safe-haven-demand-ahead-of-trump-administration-202412300247</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-receives-support-from-safe-haven-demand-ahead-of-trump-administration-202412300247</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to BUY for 2025: Up to 80% upside! Adani Enterprises, IndusInd Bank, SBI Life and more - LIST - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to BUY for 2025: Up to 80% upside!</h1><p><strong>Updated Dec 30, 2024</strong> by ET NOW Digital</p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-116766001,updatedat-1735467174007,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/116766001.jpg" alt="shares to buy"><figcaption>ET NOW Swadesh provides insights from a Bloomberg survey, identifying stocks anticipated to do well over the coming year.</figcaption><p>As we approach 2025, investors are eager to find stocks with the potential for significant profits. Bloomberg researchers conducted a poll focusing on the Nifty Mid Cap 100 and Nifty Small Cap 100 indexes.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li><strong>Large Cap Stocks:</strong> Adani Enterprises is forecasted to have an 80% increase in price. IndusInd Bank and SBI Life are expected to reach 40-50% growth.</li><li><strong>Mid Cap Stocks:</strong> Oil India anticipated to offer returns over 40%. NLC India and AB Capital both expected to give returns above 39%.</li><li><strong>Small Cap Stocks:</strong> Sterling and Wilson Solar could see over 80% returns; Great Eastern Shipping and JK Bank likely above 55%.</li></ul><h2>Market Outlook 2025:</h2><p>Prateek Agrawal from Motilal Oswal AMC emphasizes the bright future for the electronics and nuclear sectors, as well as optimism for India's growth trajectory.</p><blockquote>“The growth opportunity that our nation provides entices many individuals. We are in the world's largest economy; this is our moment, and we are developing strongly.”</blockquote><p>(Disclaimer: The above article is meant for informational purposes only, and should not be considered as any investment advice. ET NOW DIGITAL suggests consulting financial advisors before making any money-related decisions.)</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/stocks-to-buy-adani-enterprises-indusind-bank-sbi-life-hudco-shares-to-look-out-for-2025-bloomberg-report-article-116765311</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/stocks-to-buy-adani-enterprises-indusind-bank-sbi-life-hudco-shares-to-look-out-for-2025-bloomberg-report-article-116765311</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:33:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The mother of all Indian IPOs: Is it coming in the year 2025? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The mother of all Indian IPOs: Will 2025 be the year India witnesses its largest-ever listing?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>The article discusses the robust trend of IPOs in India, highlighting significant fundraising in 2024 and the anticipation of continued growth leading into 2025.</p><ul><li>India witnessed a surge in IPOs in 2024 with companies like Hyundai Motors raising significant funds.</li><li>Equity fundraising has surpassed Rs 3 lakh crore, showcasing a 64% increase from the previous record in 2021.</li><li>Major companies, including LG India and Flipkart, are preparing to list in 2025.</li><li>The potential for a record-breaking IPO in 2025 is emphasized, particularly for Reliance Jio.</li></ul><blockquote>“India Inc’s significant fundraising in 2024 can be attributed to a favorable macroeconomic environment, a robust equity market, and increased investor confidence...” - Pinak Bhattacharya</blockquote><p>In conclusion, 2025 could see historic IPO activity in India, indicating a bullish outlook for the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/ipos/fpos/the-mother-of-all-indian-ipos-is-it-coming-in-the-year-2025/articleshow/116786586.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/ipos/fpos/the-mother-of-all-indian-ipos-is-it-coming-in-the-year-2025/articleshow/116786586.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:06:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Government To Impose This New Tax If You Own A Car! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Government Plans New Congestion Tax for Vehicle Owners</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Recent<br><strong>Source: </strong>MotorOctane</p><img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1729766964-8261.avif" alt="New Tax -- Congestion tax"><figcaption>New Tax -- Congestion tax</figcaption><p>The Delhi government has proposed a new congestion tax on vehicles entering the city during peak hours to combat rising pollution and traffic congestion.</p><ul><li>The GST on used cars has increased from 12% to 18%.</li><li>The congestion tax will apply during peak hours from 8 AM to 10 AM and 5:30 PM to 8 PM.</li><li>Exemptions will apply for two-wheelers and non-polluting vehicles like EVs.</li><li>The tax will be collected automatically via FASTag and number plate recognition technology.</li><li>Revenue generated will be used to improve public transportation and road infrastructure.</li></ul><blockquote>“Currently, Delhi is witnessing increasing pollution thanks to stubble burning and vehicular emission.”</blockquote><p>This new tax is still in planning stages and will require necessary legal adjustments to the Motor Vehicles Act.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/281508-government-to-impose-this-new-tax-if-you-own-a-car</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/281508-government-to-impose-this-new-tax-if-you-own-a-car</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senores Pharmaceuticals Listing: Shares debut strong with 53% premium over IPO price - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Senores Pharmaceuticals IPO Debuts with 53% Premium, Raising ₹582 Crore</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: [Insert Date], Source: [Insert Source]</strong></p><img src="[Insert Image URL]"><figcaption>[Insert Image Caption]</figcaption><p>The Ahmedabad-based Senores Pharmaceuticals made a strong debut on the stock market, with its shares listed at ₹600, a 53.45% premium on its issue price on the NSE. On the BSE, the stock debuted at ₹593.70, a 52% premium.</p><ol><li>The company raised about ₹582 crore from the primary market.</li><li>The listing was below grey market premium (GMP) estimates, with GMP holding its ground despite market volatility.</li><li>The IPO was subscribed 93.41 times, with strong demand from all categories.</li><li>Proceeds will be used for setting up a manufacturing facility, funding working capital, supporting inorganic growth, and paying debt, among other purposes.</li><li>The company specializes in developing and manufacturing specialty pharmaceutical products and reported strong earnings growth.</li></ol><blockquote>The IPO was subscribed 93.41 times, indicating strong investor interest.</blockquote><p>The successful IPO indicates robust demand for pharmaceutical stocks and the company's potential for growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/senores-pharmaceuticals-share-price-ipo-listing-date-today-premium-gmp-latest-what-should-investors-do-19531088.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/senores-pharmaceuticals-share-price-ipo-listing-date-today-premium-gmp-latest-what-should-investors-do-19531088.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 04:28:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid H-1B debate, US Attorney accuses Indian CEO of ruining culture: Hired only Indians, forced salary cu - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Attorney Accuses Indian CEO of Ruining Company Culture Amid H-1B Debate</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116785305,imgsize-39980,width-400,resizemode-4/116785305.jpg" alt="Amid H-1B debate, US Attorney accuses Indian CEO of ruining culture" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Representative image</figcaption><p>The ongoing H-1B visa debate in the US intensifies as a US attorney’s post criticizes an Indian CEO for allegedly destroying company culture, instituting salary cuts, and laying off 15% of the workforce.</p><ul><li>The attorney claims the CEO hired only Indian executives and outsourced work to India.</li><li>Employees faced a 10% salary cut and frozen promotions during the pandemic.</li><li>Many employees reported increased workload and diminished job security.</li><li>Client satisfaction reportedly decreased due to changes in management and lack of support.</li><li>The post has sparked discussions on social media about H-1B visas and the trend of Indian executives in American companies.</li></ul><blockquote>“Work product also suffered across the company. Client satisfaction drastically decreased as a result.”</blockquote><p>This event highlights concerns among American workers regarding the shift in company culture due to leadership changes and raises questions about immigration policies affecting the tech industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/relationships/work/amid-h-1b-debate-us-attorney-accuses-indian-ceo-of-ruining-culture-hired-only-indians-forced-salary-cuts-froze-promotions-and-fired15workforce/articleshow/116785320.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/relationships/work/amid-h-1b-debate-us-attorney-accuses-indian-ceo-of-ruining-culture-hired-only-indians-forced-salary-cuts-froze-promotions-and-fired15workforce/articleshow/116785320.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 04:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Week ahead: NIFTY50 struggles below 200 DMA, Auto sales and Q3 updates in focus amid low volatility - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxPV3FHOTR4SktzTm5GaVV4UUp2dGJKRktnS2hzNGtUaU1PVHhiaExscU5xclpJd2FpSTZlTTlfVnJQb05rRWFZcjlEaEVsYjFldW1UYmZNUURVOEYyeWNESU9neFJqUnlNbFI4bmRzU3RtMXY4YmZ4MWZSY3FtNERIUnJXT1BZa3BhbW10UWVZdVdqZTRkcmpGQ2M4TUFDM1hjbGh3TkRObmk0QjdZMVN6S1pIYmJIblV0WTl3ZmZzeVJqTUZOUXMzcVVkbXJwRzJVRGZ3OFdmMmpzeFVYZUVJWGRqbkhCNmdraEFoZzY0aw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxPV3FHOTR4SktzTm5GaVV4UUp2dGJKRktnS2hzNGtUaU1PVHhiaExscU5xclpJd2FpSTZlTTlfVnJQb05rRWFZcjlEaEVsYjFldW1UYmZNUURVOEYyeWNESU9neFJqUnlNbFI4bmRzU3RtMXY4YmZ4MWZSY3FtNERIUnJXT1BZa3BhbW10UWVZdVdqZTRkcmpGQ2M4TUFDM1hjbGh3TkRObmk0QjdZMVN6S1pIYmJIblV0WTl3ZmZzeVJqTUZOUXMzcVVkbXJwRzJVRGZ3OFdmMmpzeFVYZUVJWGRqbkhCNmdraEFoZzY0aw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 04:14:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market today: BSE Sensex opens in red; Nifty50 above 23,750 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock market today: BSE Sensex opens in red; Nifty50 above 23,750</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 17, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>Today's stock market opened with the BSE Sensex in negative territory, while the Nifty50 remains above the 23,750 mark. Investors are closely watching market performance.</p>
<ul>
  <li>BSE Sensex showing declines at the opening.</li>
  <li>Nifty50 maintains a valuation above 23,750.</li>
  <li>Market trends indicating cautious investor sentiment.</li>
  <li>Focus on global economic factors influencing local markets.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Investors are keeping a close eye on global cues”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the stock market's current trend is indicative of broader economic sentiments, with investors advised to remain vigilant.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/stock-market-today-bse-sensex-nifty50-december-30-2024-dalal-street-indian-equities-global-markets/articleshow/116783902.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/stock-market-today-bse-sensex-nifty50-december-30-2024-dalal-street-indian-equities-global-markets/articleshow/116783902.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold price today: Rates rise on geopolitical concerns; experts unveil strategy for MCX Gold | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxPM0R4Mkg3a2tmUHFpYm1VVHpYaGNOcHlMMDhucmtBNU0tRDB0YTlSd0VsQVdycjUwNHRfUmY5cTZlQ1ZMUnZWUzU3Y1VjbW1WWXVYY3BIcHp4d0dKXy1USU5qWHhpOHA5dWprR1NQQ1VWa085blRpZDVBN0otYWFNQmVkeVN5STZRck5TVXQwSGN0ZWhWVVVONGFRLU84Y1pfcXdOdXFTMzk0Zi1vaFJOcmF3X1l4T2ZJOXpsWm9uNXBNS0gxRTZlNzBRRFc0LU04UUVoUEQ3bTFiaDExR0s1a0x2RmtsNmMw0gHuAUFVX3lxTFBneVhWN0NPeDFiU1BlUHNnejYxQ0RRR0NzcTlaY1hLa0RDdTJwS0RfclVTMjdZWlNzU0tvNDRTWUEyM0QzRjF3cWZrRnVVNEtRSmxJc1d3NnU4QUl5TnkyS0w4LXlXTzVRTzM4NGdYbThVR3R0cTlpUUQ1dW94cmlvZGs3QURkYkFIMFF5aUlHY0xzZUdSaUpJQXpwQldBREtfRjgwc3AxUjROdkE4ZHBqdU0xSFZGdjdMX2t2QS1TZVJTdHVnZjNlUTIxNUZfVVE4eVdfRG83WFh2ZHJFLWU5WEpoZjU1WUw1NWZaOFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxPM0R4Mkg3a2tmUHFpYm1VVHpYaGNOcHlMMDhucmtBNU0tRDB0YTlSd0VsQVdycjUwNHRfUmY5cTZlQ1ZMUnZWUzU3Y1VjbW1WWXVYY3BIcHp4d0dKXy1USU5qWHhpOHA5dWprR1NQQ1VWa085blRpZDVBN0otYWFNQmVkeVN5STZRck5TVXQwSGN0ZWhWVVVONGFRLU84Y1pfcXdOdXFTMzk0Zi1vaFJOcmF3X1l4T2ZJOXpsWm9uNXBNS0gxRTZlNzBRRFc0LU04UUVoUEQ3bTFiaDExR0s1a0x2RmtsNmMw0gHuAUFVX3lxTFBneVhWN0NPeDFiU1BlUHNnejYxQ0RRR0NzcTlaY1hLa0RDdTJwS0RfclVTMjdZWlNzU0tvNDRTWUEyM0QzRjF3cWZrRnVVNEtRSmxJc1d3NnU4QUl5TnkyS0w4LXlXTzVRTzM4NGdYbThVR3R0cTlpUUQ1dW94cmlvZGs3QURkYkFIMFF5aUlHY0xzZUdSaUpJQXpwQldBREtfRjgwc3AxUjROdkE4ZHBqdU0xSFZGdjdMX2t2QS1TZVJTdHVnZjNlUTIxNUZfVVE4eVdfRG83WFh2ZHJFLWU5WEpoZjU1WUw1NWZaOFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:41:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JSW Energy shares jump over 7.5% as arm acquires 4.7 GW renewable energy platform O2 Power; check the enterprise value - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JSW Energy Shares Jump Over 7.5% as Arm Acquires 4.7 GW Renewable Energy Platform O2 Power</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><p>JSW Energy's shares rose by 7.67% following the announcement that its subsidiary, JSW Neo Energy Ltd., will acquire a 4,696 MW renewable energy platform from O2 Power for ₹12,468 crore. The acquisition is contingent upon regulatory approvals.</p><ul><li>JSW Neo Energy will acquire O2 Power Midco Holdings and O2 Energy SG.</li><li>The enterprise value for the transaction is ₹12,468 crore after net current asset adjustments.</li><li>O2 Power boasts a renewable energy platform with a capacity of 4,696 MW.</li><li>2,259 MW will be operational by June 2025, with more in the pipeline.</li><li>The acquisition increases JSW Energy's generation capacity by 23%.</li></ul><blockquote>"The enterprise value indicates the potential cost to acquire a business based on the company's capital structure."</blockquote><p>JSW Energy has seen its shares rally over 50% in the past year, reflecting strong market performance and investor confidence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/jsw-energy-shares-in-focus-as-arm-acquires-4-7-gw-renewable-energy-platform-o2-power-check-the-enterprise-value/article-137488/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/jsw-energy-shares-in-focus-as-arm-acquires-4-7-gw-renewable-energy-platform-o2-power-check-the-enterprise-value/article-137488/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:10:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee set to extend recovery on RBI-motivated dollar-long liquidation | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee Set to Extend Recovery on RBI-Motivated Dollar-Long Liquidation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><p>The Indian rupee is expected to rise, continuing momentum from the previous session due to the Reserve Bank of India's interventions that prompted exiting speculative dollar-long positions.</p><ul><li>The rupee is set to open between 85.40 and 85.42 against the U.S. dollar.</li><li>It recently hit a lifetime low of 85.8075, leading to heavy dollar sales by the RBI.</li><li>Traders noted that the RBI's intervention was significant, as it helped flush out excessive speculative positions.</li><li>High U.S. Treasury yields and concerns over U.S. trade policies have recently affected the rupee.</li><li>Key indicators include a one-month non-deliverable rupee forward at 85.70 and a dollar index at 108.</li></ul><blockquote>"Unless the trajectory of U.S. yields turns, the rupee will have it difficult," a currency dealer commented.</blockquote><p>The RBI's ongoing interventions aim to mitigate the decline of the rupee, although its actions have driven forex reserves to a seven-month low.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/rupee-set-to-extend-recovery-on-rbi-motivated-dollar-long-liquidation-11735527381982.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/rupee-set-to-extend-recovery-on-rbi-motivated-dollar-long-liquidation-11735527381982.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:56:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold price receives support from safe-haven demand ahead of Trump administration - FXStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Price Rises as Traders Anticipate Fed Policy Outlook for 2025</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>December 30, 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>FXStreet</p><img src="https://editorial.fxsstatic.com/miscelaneous/image-638711237254973322.png"><figcaption>Gold price trend analysis chart.</figcaption><p>Gold prices have advanced due to increased risk aversion ahead of the incoming Trump administration, but outlook for fewer Fed rate cuts in 2025 may challenge further gains.</p><ul><li>Gold price appreciates amid rising geopolitical tensions, particularly from the ongoing Russia-Ukraine conflict.</li><li>Market reacts cautiously as the US Fed hints at a more restrained monetary policy for 2025.</li><li>Attacks by Israeli forces in Gaza escalate geopolitical risks, influencing safe-haven demand for gold.</li></ul><blockquote>“Gold prices are set to finish the year with an impressive 27% gain, marking the strongest annual performance since 2010.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the anticipation of policy changes from the Federal Reserve and geopolitical developments are shaping traders’ sentiment towards gold prices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-receives-support-from-safe-haven-demand-ahead-of-trump-administration-202412300247</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-receives-support-from-safe-haven-demand-ahead-of-trump-administration-202412300247</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:47:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ola Electric shares slide 5% after CTO and CMO resign amid leadership exodus - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPZkNNb2xNblpKOTZmYWlxWkhnRkpKSE9Iemp1bDBnX19SMkt6c0ZuLUJpdDdnQmljSWpKWnphWExQbDZSMUx5XzFEb0doZTI1QW1nOWM4b0ZvOGRGc3N4dmsxN0U3dFhtdk9DZmdpMFFGMGlkS19PTnhkVW9WT0ZEYUNZQS1CT1djRF9sNlpGOXhDRFRkNncxY1BfOFhyZnNLcWZ2N0h6WDgxT0RfcE94S1JpRC1jT0w4cWRGQUpraHRkZGRHeldIMWNMSk9NcWJZN29peUY0RTFUdE1teFpITTdsWW7SAeoBQVVfeXFMTmstVldxbklIbTZ4bTlFSnM4M1JFSG52ZHF4dkt6Rno0elZZOGl3WTFHR2xrY3R0TnBGTkhkXzhPZGhSaUJ6d1lQek9oYnJvT0U5aWstcW9sLThwaUlPMWZka3NVbUxacTYyOFNHRXNSeHBsUXdmdC1HNXhscEZPWDdnekRndDdScHV1b1g1Zk05b3NSTDd3cTlxZGRVOTAyODdLQVZDWUhaOG5jODJsVHdRTVBOVk5hT21mb01SdnRPeWd4enBWaGhqZGZ3TWo1dTFSUkNEUU1SMXd5SDNBT1JhSGY0TzBWYWh3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPZkNNb2xNblpKOTZmYWlxWkhnRkpKSE9Iemp1bDBnX19SMkt6c0ZuLUJpdDdnQmljSWpKWnphWExQbDZSMUx5XzFEb0doZTI1QW1nOWM4b0ZvOGRGc3N4dmsxN0U3dFhtdk9DZmdpMFFGMGlkS19PTnhkVW9WT0ZEYUNZQS1CT1djRF9sNlpGOXhDRFRkNncxY1BfOFhyZnNLcWZ2N0h6WDgxT0RfcE94S1JpRC1jT0w4cWRGQUpraHRkZGRHeldIMWNMSk9NcWJZN29peUY0RTFUdE1teFpITTdsWW7SAeoBQVVfeXFMTmstVldxbklIbTZ4bTlFSnM4M1JFSG52ZHF4dkt6Rno0elZZOGl3WTFHR2xrY3R0TnBGTkhkXzhPZGhSaUJ6d1lQek9oYnJvT0U5aWstcW9sLThwaUlPMWZka3NVbUxacTYyOFNHRXNSeHBsUXdmdC1HNXhscEZPWDdnekRndDdScHV1b1g1Zk05b3NSTDd3cTlxZGRVOTAyODdLQVZDWUhaOG5jODJsVHdRTVBOVk5hT21mb01SdnRPeWd4enBWaGhqZGZ3TWo1dTFSUkNEUU1SMXd5SDNBT1JhSGY0TzBWYWh3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:42:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ola Electric shares in focus after CTO and CMO resign amid leadership exodus - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPZkNNb2xNblpKOTZmYWlxWkhnRkpKSE9Iemp1bDBnX19SMkt6c0ZuLUJpdDdnQmljSWpKWnphWExQbDZSMUx5XzFEb0doZTI1QW1nOWM4b0ZvOGRGc3N4dmsxN0U3dFhtdk9DZmdpMFFGMGlkS19PTnhkVW9WT0ZEYUNZQS1CT1djRF9sNlpGOXhDRFRkNncxY1BfOFhyZnNLcWZ2N0h6WDgxT0RfcE94S1JpRC1jT0w4cWRGQUpraHRkZGRHeldIMWNMSk9NcWJZN29peUY0RTFUdE1teFpITTdsWW7SAeoBQVVfeXFMTmstVldxbklIbTZ4bTlFSnM4M1JFSG52ZHF4dkt6Rno0elZZOGl3WTFHR2xrY3R0TnBGTkhkXzhPZGhSaUJ6d1lQek9oYnJvT0U5aWstcW9sLThwaUlPMWZka3NVbUxacTYyOFNHRXNSeHBsUXdmdC1HNXhscEZPWDdnekRndDdScHV1b1g1Zk05b3NSTDd3cTlxZGRVOTAyODdLQVZDWUhaOG5jODJsVHdRTVBOVk5hT21mb01SdnRPeWd4enBWaGhqZGZ3TWo1dTFSUkNEUU1SMXd5SDNBT1JhSGY0TzBWYWh3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPZkNNb2xNblpKOTZmYWlxWkhnRkpKSE9Iemp1bDBnX19SMkt6c0ZuLUJpdDdnQmljSWpKWnphWExQbDZSMUx5XzFEb0doZTI1QW1nOWM4b0ZvOGRGc3N4dmsxN0U3dFhtdk9DZmdpMFFGMGlkS19PTnhkVW9WT0ZEYUNZQS1CT1djRF9sNlpGOXhDRFRkNncxY1BfOFhyZnNLcWZ2N0h6WDgxT0RfcE94S1JpRC1jT0w4cWRGQUpraHRkZGRHeldIMWNMSk9NcWJZN29peUY0RTFUdE1teFpITTdsWW7SAeoBQVVfeXFMTmstVldxbklIbTZ4bTlFSnM4M1JFSG52ZHF4dkt6Rno0elZZOGl3WTFHR2xrY3R0TnBGTkhkXzhPZGhSaUJ6d1lQek9oYnJvT0U5aWstcW9sLThwaUlPMWZka3NVbUxacTYyOFNHRXNSeHBsUXdmdC1HNXhscEZPWDdnekRndDdScHV1b1g1Zk05b3NSTDd3cTlxZGRVOTAyODdLQVZDWUhaOG5jODJsVHdRTVBOVk5hT21mb01SdnRPeWd4enBWaGhqZGZ3TWo1dTFSUkNEUU1SMXd5SDNBT1JhSGY0TzBWYWh3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:42:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ventive Hospitality IPO Share Price LIVE: Stock lists at 11.35% premium over issue price on NSE - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ventive Hospitality IPO Shares List at 11.35% Premium on NSE</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 30, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Ventive Hospitality shares debuted on the stock exchanges with a significant premium, indicating strong investor interest following its IPO.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Traded Volume:</strong> 100.53 lakh shares</li>
  <li><strong>Traded Value:</strong> ₹726.94 crore</li>
  <li><strong>Current Share Price:</strong> ₹725.10 (+1.27%)</li>
  <li><strong>Market Capitalisation:</strong> ₹16,965.63 crore</li>
  <li><strong>Opening Price:</strong> ₹716</li>
  <li><strong>Listing Price:</strong> ₹718.15 on BSE, ₹716 on NSE</li>
  <li><strong>IPO Subscription:</strong> 9.82 times overall</li>
  <li><strong>Financial Highlights:</strong> FY23 revenue of ₹430.81 crore with a net profit of ₹131.27 crore</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The proceeds from the IPO will be used to clear the debt of the company and its subsidiaries.”</blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The successful IPO listing of Ventive Hospitality reflects robust demand from investors and bodes well for the company's future in the hospitality sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/ventive-hospitality-ipo-listing-date-share-price-live-shares-list-premium-nse-bse-stock-news-review-key-details/article-137483/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/ventive-hospitality-ipo-listing-date-share-price-live-shares-list-premium-nse-bse-stock-news-review-key-details/article-137483/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:42:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ventive Hospitality IPO Listing, Share Price: Shares to debut on NSE and BSE, all you need to know - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-wFBVV95cUxPZHRqTEhhTWNSZ080RXUxY2xxMGlwb1lSLUFob3NkdVdNOGdsMVdyaEZpR29lMjUteXBVdS11UEwzUVZxTlJZdHZpSXZZcFJWdWF3WjBZU19mVUVweEEwekYycWM4TXJMSE8tNW1jVkUwZFQwcmdBWTgzMWRBcllwcUQxNlcxZVRsenlRZ0NJYmR1M21Ca1ZyaUEwa3ZQbGNJYzg2TEs1OHFFZ0c4MENtZG82bV9RNzZvaEcxTTRGRDNlQUN6b3FWdEM4ZWZTYmxGc0ZKMFJreVMzbDdLSkZxcFEzLWhLZmdkSEZiaVdyUnpRWXJoZ1UtWXVKSQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-wFBVV95cUxPZHRqTEhhTWNSZ080RXUxY2xxMGlwb1lSLUFob3NkdVdNOGdsMVdyaEZpR29lMjUteXBVdS11UEwzUVZxTlJZdHZpSXZZcFJWdWF3WjBZU19mVUVweEEwekYycWM4TXJMSE8tNW1jVkUwZFQwcmdBWTgzMWRBcllwcUQxNlcxZVRsenlRZ0NJYmR1M21Ca1ZyaUEwa3ZQbGNJYzg2TEs1OHFFZ0c4MENtZG82bV9RNzZvaEcxTTRGRDNlQUN6b3FWdEM4ZWZTYmxGc0ZKMFJreVMzbDdLSkZxcFEzLWhLZmdkSEZiaVdyUnpRWXJoZ1UtWXVKSQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:42:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to watch, December 30: IT stocks, Gujarat Fluorochemicals, Coforge, JSW Energy, Hero MotoCorp, Senores Pharmaceuticals, and more - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgJBVV95cUxOS3RVVmxTTGR2Z19jMWVXaEJNNHFCODdDMVAwYlhYNDBXMFI4X2tnQWhCMHBsZDFzbXBENzJVajQxNTNzRnc0M0FnWVczUldVak1kUHJCN1k0cTVDb2ZWTXI5XzRCTDRmd0V3QVhSYTg5MzdJTThaMFFRYmdmNUNxRVdzS3RwSUFzWElMcl9nN3pCRk9vRmJHcW9uT3hFa0pjQlN6NWYtOG5lZnRXbmVyT2xiS0Z1OFlOcEZlZkxLbkRLeGlYVmZncEJ5b19uNERNVnEyendLMTl5R1pnRFNZa3N6ZVU0WU1sWllDbjh2NGF3Y01hWTdZd3hPY0JhSERoQWl6LUNjc3FyWVM0b2VzdlM3Umdwdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgJBVV95cUxOS3RVVmxTTGR2Z19jMWVXaEJNNHFCODdDMVAwYlhYNDBXMFI4X2tnQWhCMHBsZDFzbXBENzJVajQxNTNzRnc0M0FnWVczUldVak1kUHJCN1k0cTVDb2ZWTXI5XzRCTDRmd0V3QVhSYTg5MzdJTThaMFFRYmdmNUNxRVdzS3RwSUFzWElMcl9nN3pCRk9vRmJHcW9uT3hFa0pjQlN6NWYtOG5lZnRXbmVyT2xiS0Z1OFlOcEZlZkxLbkRLeGlYVmZncEJ5b19uNERNVnEyendLMTl5R1pnRFNZa3N6ZVU0WU1sWllDbjh2NGF3Y01hWTdZd3hPY0JhSERoQWl6LUNjc3FyWVM0b2VzdlM3Umdwdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:39:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senores Pharmaceuticals Share Price LIVE: Stock lists at 53.45% premium over issue price on NSE - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Senores Pharmaceuticals Share Price LIVE: Stock lists at 53.45% premium over issue price on NSE</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Upstox</p>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Senores Pharmaceuticals successfully listed its shares on the National Stock Exchange (NSE) at a premium over its issue price, marking a notable debut in the stock market.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Traded volume reached 107.79 lakh shares, with a traded value of ₹633.66 crore.</li>
  <li>The stock opened at ₹600, reflecting a premium of 53.45% over the issue price of ₹391.</li>
  <li>Current trading price as of the time of reporting was ₹568, down 5.33% from the previous value.</li>
  <li>The market cap of the company is approximately ₹2,565.18 crore.</li>
  <li>The share IPO was heavily subscribed, with a total subscription ratio of 93.69 times.</li>
<!-- Add figures and important tables if needed -->
</ul>
<blockquote>“Senores Pharmaceuticals develops and manufactures pharmaceutical products for the regulated markets of the UK, the US, and Canada.”</blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The strong market performance and substantial investor interest indicate a positive outlook for Senores Pharmaceuticals in the coming periods.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/senores-pharmaceuticals-ipo-listing-date-share-price-live-shares-list-premium-nse-bse-stock-news-review-all-you-need-to-know/article-137479/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/senores-pharmaceuticals-ipo-listing-date-share-price-live-shares-list-premium-nse-bse-stock-news-review-all-you-need-to-know/article-137479/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:21:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senores Pharmaceuticals IPO Listing, Share Price LIVE: Shares to list on NSE, BSE today, key things to know - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Senores Pharmaceuticals Shares Debut with Strong Premium on NSE</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Upstox</p>
<img src="image_url_here" alt="Senores Pharmaceuticals Logo">
<figcaption>Senores Pharmaceuticals Stock Listing</figcaption>
<p>Senores Pharmaceuticals made a strong debut on the stock market, listing at a significant premium over its issue price, showcasing investor confidence amidst robust subscription levels.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Stock debuted at ₹600 on NSE, a 53.45% premium over the issue price of ₹391.</li>
  <li>Market capitalisation reached ₹2,652.69 crore after initial trading.</li>
  <li>Shares saw fluctuations, with a decline to ₹576, representing a 4% drop shortly after listing.</li>
  <li>The IPO was heavily subscribed, with an overall subscription of 93.69 times.</li>
  <li>Lead book-running managers included Equirus Capital and Ambit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>“The issue was highly anticipated, and the strong listing reflects the market’s belief in Senores Pharmaceuticals’ growth potential.”</p></blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Senores Pharmaceuticals’ initial public offering highlights its promising start in the stock market, supported by significant investor interest and strategic financial objectives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/senores-pharmaceuticals-ipo-listing-date-share-price-live-shares-list-premium-nse-bse-stock-news-review-all-you-need-to-know/article-137479/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/senores-pharmaceuticals-ipo-listing-date-share-price-live-shares-list-premium-nse-bse-stock-news-review-all-you-need-to-know/article-137479/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:21:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upcoming IPOs: Indo Farm Equipment along with 2 other IPOs to open for subscription; 6 new listings - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxONnFBWWRRZXZSc2xNbkRudm9yaXlxTTRYN29XaGpOc216UUlxMEJzSlpkR25GcGRnSmZVOUEzWFh5WEt0MDRnWHA1bEF0OXlueXd1OVQ0M1duNC11NlFra25WOExFR3d1eGpKSTNwRnNEcFVqVVA2U1Btd3hxSXkxNjY1aXRPZWdPeUlsYWNfakFaSjhuRmF6bC1XdmRnd0E5VGdTS0t5Q01PTldfaDZuYlEtbzhMeEt6aEdadE0yX2JpdXhibW1tcGZWT3k1ZHlhNnRiM29ERGJQTVZUS1hhMHhxYThYZHp1dVFhVy0wZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxONnFBWWRRZXZSc2xNbkRudm9yaXlxTTRYN29XaGpOc216UUlxMEJzSlpkR25GcGRnSmZVOUEzWFh5WEt0MDRnWHA1bEF0OXlueXd1OVQ0M1duNC11NlFra25WOExFR3d1eGpKSTNwRnNEcFVqVVA2U1Btd3hxSXkxNjY1aXRPZWdPeUlsYWNfakFaSjhuRmF6bC1XdmRnd0E5VGdTS0t5Q01PTldfaDZuYlEtbzhMeEt6aEdadE0yX2JpdXhibW1tcGZWT3k1ZHlhNnRiM29ERGJQTVZUS1hhMHhxYThYZHp1dVFhVy0wZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:21:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HDFC Bank shares are back in Chris Wood's Asia ex-Japan portfolio at the expense of these stocks - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HDFC Bank shares are back in Chris Wood's Asia ex-Japan portfolio at the expense of these stocks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="HDFC Bank shares are back in Chris Wood's Asia ex-Japan portfolio at the expense of these stocks" /><figcaption>HDFC Bank shares reviewed by Chris Wood</figcaption><p>Chris Wood of Jefferies has reintroduced HDFC Bank shares in his Asia ex-Japan portfolio, increasing its weightage while reducing investments in other stocks.</p><ul><li>HDFC Bank has a 4% weightage in the Asia ex-Japan portfolio.</li><li>Investments in Macrotech Developers, L&amp;T, ICICI Bank, and Axis Bank trimmed by 1% each to accommodate HDFC Bank.</li><li>HDFC Bank's weightage in India's portfolio also increased by 1% at the expense of Axis Bank.</li><li>Siemens India is introduced in both portfolios with a 4% weightage.</li><li>Chris Wood's portfolio includes stocks like Bharti Airtel, Zomato, and Coal India.</li></ul><blockquote>“Shares of HDFC Bank have now seen positive annual returns for the last decade but three out of the last four years have seen single-digit returns for the lender.”</blockquote><p>The reallocation reflects confidence in HDFC Bank's performance while addressing shifts in investments towards Siemens India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/hdfc-bank-share-price-siemens-india-chris-wood-greed-and-fear-india-asia-portfolio-lodha-lt-icici-weight-19531322.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/hdfc-bank-share-price-siemens-india-chris-wood-greed-and-fear-india-asia-portfolio-lodha-lt-icici-weight-19531322.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:13:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intraday stocks for today under ₹100: Experts recommend three shares to buy today — 30 December 2024 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Intraday Stocks Under ₹100: Experts Recommend Three Shares to Buy Today</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 30 December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The Indian stock market remains sideways with the Nifty 50 index struggling to break above key resistance levels. Despite mixed movements in various indices, experts have identified three stocks under ₹100 worth buying today.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Nifty 50 closed at 23,832, with resistance around 24,000 to 24,200.</li><li>Bank Nifty closed slightly higher, trading within a range of 50,550 to 51,650.</li><li>Experts suggest buying Grauer And Weil, Niraj Cement, and Paramount Communications for intraday trading.</li></ul><h2>Stock Recommendations:</h2><ol><li><strong>Grauer And Weil:</strong> Buy at ₹98-99, targets ₹103, ₹105, ₹110, ₹115, stop loss ₹95.</li><li><strong>Niraj Cement:</strong> Buy at ₹69.5, target ₹75, stop loss ₹67.50 (Closing Basis).</li><li><strong>Paramount Communications:</strong> Buy at ₹81, target ₹89, stop loss ₹78 (Closing Basis).</li></ol><blockquote>“The short-term trend of the Nifty 50 index is slightly positive with range-bound action.” - Nagaraj Shetti</blockquote><p>With limited immediate triggers, the stock market is likely to remain range-bound but may experience movements based on upcoming quarterly business updates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/intraday-trading-for-today-under-rs-100-experts-recommend-three-shares-to-buy-today-30-december-2024-11735523553105.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/intraday-trading-for-today-under-rs-100-experts-recommend-three-shares-to-buy-today-30-december-2024-11735523553105.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:05:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian stock market: 7 key things that changed for market over weekend - Gift Nifty, Asian markets to US treasury yields | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian stock market: 7 key things that changed for market over weekend - Gift Nifty, Asian markets to US treasury yields</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> LiveMint</p><p>The Indian stock market is set to open on a tepid note following sluggish trends in global markets, with Asian shares lower and potential influences from US treasury yields and macroeconomic data.</p><ul><li>Sensex closed at 78,699.07, up 226.59 points (0.29%).</li><li>Nifty 50 settled at 23,813.40, up 63.20 points (0.27%).</li><li>Gift Nifty indicating a tepid start for the markets.</li><li>Global markets saw a decline, with Wall Street affected by losses in tech stocks.</li><li>US Treasury yields are at eight-month highs.</li><li>Gold prices increased due to heightened safe-haven demand amid Middle East conflicts.</li><li>Crude oil prices are falling in holiday trade.</li></ul><blockquote>“With no significant triggers in the near term, markets are likely to remain range-bound.” - Siddhartha Khemka, Head - Research, Wealth Management, Motilal Oswal Financial Services Ltd.</blockquote><p>The markets are poised to react to upcoming economic data and the performance of key sectors, with potential implications for investors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/indian-stock-market-7-key-things-that-changed-for-market-over-weekend-gift-nifty-asian-markets-to-us-treasury-yields-11735476598230.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/indian-stock-market-7-key-things-that-changed-for-market-over-weekend-gift-nifty-asian-markets-to-us-treasury-yields-11735476598230.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:49:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oil inches higher in thin trade, investors focus on China, US data By Reuters - Investing.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxNelFJUVdINWdJd2EyYnlMa2hEM0xEWWdPMVRUZENlMjhkbjNCRlR4d3pqXzVqdjJoN3hraG9LTHVKTURTajc2enJfa3Q5eDkwUm1ZUHBPRklqX2twVTFkWUZoRGJtUUc0OHpLcFVwb2d5eDhhWjN0OHRLXzNOalBNMzFmd09KcVg1UzIxaHpOQjdoUlZjN0FTRk1pMUFpTi1nNUc0T1BYT0xTZHBXQ1ZwMlJmOGo?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxNelFJUVdINWdJd2EyYnlMa2hEM0xEWWdPMVRUZENlMjhkbjNCRlR4d3pqXzVqdjJoN3hraG9LTHVKTURTajc2enJfa3Q5eDkwUm1ZUHBPRklqX2twVTFkWUZoRGJtUUc0OHpLcFVwb2d5eDhhWjN0OHRLXzNOalBNMzFmd09KcVg1UzIxaHpOQjdoUlZjN0FTRk1pMUFpTi1nNUc0T1BYT0xTZHBXQ1ZwMlJmOGo?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:45:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breakout stocks to buy or sell: Sumeet Bagadia recommends five shares to buy today — 30 December 2024 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Breakout stocks to buy or sell: Sumeet Bagadia recommends five shares to buy today</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 30 December 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> LiveMint</p>
<p>The Indian stock market continues to trade sideways as the Nifty 50 index struggles with resistance at 23,850. Despite slight gains, market sentiment remains cautious.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Nifty 50 closed at 23,832, up by 82 points.</li>
  <li>BSE Sensex increased by 259 points to 78,732.</li>
  <li>Mid-cap and Small-cap indices show subdued movement; Nifty Mid-cap 100 Index declined while Small-cap Index gained slightly.</li>
  <li>Bagadia recommends five stocks: DCX Systems, Manaksia Coated Metals, Camlin Fine Sciences, Sikko Industries, and IXIGO.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>"Overall, India's stock market bias is sideways to positive... a bullish or bearish trend can be assumed on the breakage of either side of the range." - Sumeet Bagadia</blockquote>
<p>This analysis highlights the cautious approach investors are advised to take, with a focus on technical chart strength for stock selection.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/breakout-stocks-to-buy-or-sell-sumeet-bagadia-recommends-five-shares-to-buy-today-30-december-2024-11735521741165.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/breakout-stocks-to-buy-or-sell-sumeet-bagadia-recommends-five-shares-to-buy-today-30-december-2024-11735521741165.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:32:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Looking at 2025, Tech: Rising above the AI line - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Looking at 2025, Tech: Rising above the AI line</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: December 29, 2023</strong> | <strong>Source: The Indian Express</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/ai-2025-explainer.jpg?w=640" alt="Artificial Intelligence" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>New Technology Trends for 2025: This image was generated by OpenAI’s chatbot ChatGPT-4o, which was given the text written alongside and then prompted to “create an image for this story.”</figcaption>
<p>2024 was a pivotal year for AI, marking its role as a leading technology. The upcoming year, 2025, is predicted to reflect a recalibration of AI’s applications within various sectors.</p>
<ul>
  <li>AI is becoming ubiquitous, yet the returns on heavy investments may require reassessment.</li>
  <li>Large corporations are expected to limit AI deployment to areas with visible impact.</li>
  <li>Humans will increasingly serve as copilot, leveraging AI for processing and decision-making.</li>
  <li>Focus on specialized, high-level tasks will differentiate humans from AI capabilities.</li>
  <li>Expect significant advancements in responsible AI, greener technology, and enhanced privacy.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Everyone is adopting AI, but finding returns on these heavy investments has not been easy.”</blockquote>
<p>This article presents a forward-looking view on how AI technology will evolve in 2025, emphasizing the need for a balanced approach in leveraging AI for an effective, responsible future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-sci-tech/looking-at-2025-tech-rising-above-the-ai-line-9750694/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-sci-tech/looking-at-2025-tech-rising-above-the-ai-line-9750694/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pre-market action: Here's the trade setup for today's session - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxPS3NYaEhKRE9TTlF4dVU5ZzBNaFRzUHcwa0tzWThReWdDRW44OVJ5RzZpVXljRVJWNXd6UjRzRXBpRWtRemw3S2JOU2NpMTVacGNkWFJ5elZRM1F0Nkg1SDljX2JuaklGLWhHRjg3ZzFVVVF5aldBMzZZQmkzZ0ZYcWRkYnNGRDZzTXZfd2E1LWotOHQzbVZVdlZzM1A0cG9ISXlMMjZkZmQ0WFlRYzZMRGk2NFZoUHpEZmpDcXptdnRfbzB4YUJFYS1QRG_SAdIBQVVfeXFMUF9DZjhDcThvUHppRVFFN2VnYzZPMlYwNERnRktHN3JHWWJEY18yclZZeFltOWY3TFVfSTlXbWxhLXhzQll4blpERFJaaFB2R1J4VnhVQnVNTGswREtTd21ZZmR5d2tYbjkwS2Z6eWJLWmFSQTNURDhFZlRyZDQxVjVQdXA1T043VW1FNlRnd0pxeVR4bXVrdjBCcWJMR1FyU25xNDJ2dnNMVXNzTzVxNDNBejA0bEZwZ3RWWFh1WVJrZkprajJ1OEVPcWN2SnBXSXRR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxPS3NYaEhKRE9TTlF4dVU5ZzBNaFRzUHcwa0tzWThReWdDRW44OVJ5RzZpVXljRVJWNXd6UjRzRXBpRWtRemw3S2JOU2NpMTVacGNkWFJ5elZRM1F0Nkg1SDljX2JuaklGLWhHRjg3ZzFVVVF5aldBMzZZQmkzZ0ZYcWRkYnNGRDZzTXZfd2E1LWotOHQzbVZVdlZzM1A0cG9ISXlMMjZkZmQ0WFlRYzZMRGk2NFZoUHpEZmpDcXptdnRfbzB4YUJFYS1QRG_SAdIBQVVfeXFMUF9DZjhDcThvUHppRVFFN2VnYzZPMlYwNERnRktHN3JHWWJEY18yclZZeFltOWY3TFVfSTlXbWxhLXhzQll4blpERFJaaFB2R1J4VnhVQnVNTGswREtTd21ZZmR5d2tYbjkwS2Z6eWJLWmFSQTNURDhFZlRyZDQxVjVQdXA1T043VW1FNlRnd0pxeVR4bXVrdjBCcWJMR1FyU25xNDJ2dnNMVXNzTzVxNDNBejA0bEZwZ3RWWFh1WVJrZkprajJ1OEVPcWN2SnBXSXRR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:06:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks on brokerages’ radar for December 30 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywJBVV95cUxNdWJIV0o0cVhmeTRmMTVHUzQycnV2TjNaMXBhYW9yblBzcHdrYS1lck1qUDBXWnFxNXVNdlNQNXA2Qy1lcnREa05CLVpYYndVY3RoQ1JSajNKR0FiSU45Nkg3ZzBRc0UtZ09aZmhNZlJLV2p3WWJSYXZOUVlqU1lrQzZaeGk0ZUZtQUhhSjcxb2NxRlJVQlpOYk45YjNDWlRIaldoMGFzRVhpQ19QdHllQUNmT0txcDVTbGZ1eTZ0MzBkVmY4U3h0SDZVZjBnZmJndVFHVGpPcXRXbTBlM3RqdzlqV1g4c3VObnlJS1A4LUtkMmFKcm9EUGJ2WkcyZzNnUWNDclJqT0J3b2FIM3FNZXJzRlR5U2JaMDlqa2Jwc2NUeDN2VXJZTXJuYlk1YXBjbVpsamtManJDNkxwOUJ2OWNWVXBEQWdleXZz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywJBVV95cUxNdWJIV0o0cVhmeTRmMTVHUzQycnV2TjNaMXBhYW9yblBzcHdrYS1lck1qUDBXWnFxNXVNdlNQNXA2Qy1lcnREa05CLVpYYndVY3RoQ1JSajNKR0FiSU45Nkg3ZzBRc0UtZ09aZmhNZlJLV2p3WWJSYXZOUVlqU1lrQzZaeGk0ZUZtQUhhSjcxb2NxRlJVQlpOYk45YjNDWlRIaldoMGFzRVhpQ19QdHllQUNmT0txcDVTbGZ1eTZ0MzBkVmY4U3h0SDZVZjBnZmJndVFHVGpPcXRXbTBlM3RqdzlqV1g4c3VObnlJS1A4LUtkMmFKcm9EUGJ2WkcyZzNnUWNDclJqT0J3b2FIM3FNZXJzRlR5U2JaMDlqa2Jwc2NUeDN2VXJZTXJuYlk1YXBjbVpsamtManJDNkxwOUJ2OWNWVXBEQWdleXZz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks in news: IOL Chemicals, Alkyl Amines, Ola Electric, JSW Energy, Hero MotoCorp - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks in Focus: Highlights from IOL Chemicals, Alkyl Amines, Ola Electric, JSW Energy, and Hero MotoCorp</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent Market Update</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>Last week, trading sentiment in the markets remained subdued, influenced by persistent selling from FIIs and muted global cues as the year-end festive season approaches. Key stocks like IOL Chemicals, Alkyl Amines, Ola Electric, JSW Energy, and Hero MotoCorp are highlighted for their recent developments.</p><ul><li><strong>AstraZeneca India:</strong> Laid off over 125 employees from its biopharmaceutical business.</li><li><strong>Alkyl Amines:</strong> Reported a rupture in a residue tank at its Maharashtra plant.</li><li><strong>IL&amp;FS Engineering:</strong> Secured a project worth Rs 302.82 crore for Bhubaneswar Metro Phase-I.</li><li><strong>SJVN:</strong> Appointed Sanjay Kumar as CFO from January 1, 2025.</li><li><strong>Ola Electric:</strong> Two high-profile resignations occurred in its management team.</li><li><strong>CAMS:</strong> Chief Technology Officer resigned on December 27.</li><li><strong>IOL Chemicals:</strong> Board approved a share split of 1 into 5.</li><li><strong>JSW Energy:</strong> Signed a $1.47 billion acquisition agreement.</li><li><strong>Utkarsh SFB:</strong> Approved a sale of stressed microfinance loans worth Rs 355 crore.</li><li><strong>Hero MotoCorp:</strong> Extended partnership with Harley-Davidson to develop new motorcycle variants.</li></ul><blockquote>“Hero MotoCorp extended its partnership with Harley-Davidson to expand the X440 into new variants.”</blockquote><p>This update highlights important financial moves and management changes affecting key players in the Indian market. The ongoing market trends reflect cautious investor sentiment as companies navigate year-end challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/stocks-in-news-iol-chemicals-alkyl-amines-ola-electric-jsw-energy-hero-motocorp/articleshow/116781135.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/stocks-in-news-iol-chemicals-alkyl-amines-ola-electric-jsw-energy-hero-motocorp/articleshow/116781135.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:01:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>