<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:19:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:19:59 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NTPC Green Energy Share Price: 1000MW solar project from UPPCL! Time to BUY shares? Check target - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NTPC Green Energy Secures 1000MW Solar Project: Is It Time to Buy Shares?</h1><p><strong>Updated: January 5, 2025, Source: ET NOW News</strong></p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="ntpc green 2"><figcaption>NTPC REL secured a capacity of 1000 MW at an impressive tariff of Rs 2.56/kWh. (Image: Freepik/ET NOW News)</figcaption><p>NTPC REL successfully bid for a 1000 MW solar project with UPPCL, prompting discussions on share investment opportunities.</p><ul><li>NTPC REL has secured a capacity of 1000 MW at a tariff of Rs 2.56/kWh, pending the letter of award (LOA) from UPPCL.</li><li>On the stock market, NTPC Green Energy shares rose to Rs 128.35, with a notable increase from the previous close.</li><li>The company began commercial energy delivery from its solar plant in Gujarat.</li></ul><p><strong>Share Price Target:</strong> Current target for NTPC Green Energy shares is around Rs 128; potential short-term target at Rs 134 with a stop-loss at Rs 120.</p><blockquote>“The second part capacity of 30 MW out of 150 MW Gujarat Solar PV Project… is declared on commercial operation,” stated the company's regulatory filing.</blockquote><p>The ongoing projects and investment agreements signal growth for NTPC Green Energy, indicating a proactive position in the renewable energy sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/ntpc-green-energy-share-price-1000mw-solar-project-from-uppcl-time-to-buy-shares-check-target-article-116939481</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/ntpc-green-energy-share-price-1000mw-solar-project-from-uppcl-time-to-buy-shares-check-target-article-116939481</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 04:27:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Union Bank of India shares fall 7% after weakest business update so far amongst all lenders - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Union Bank of India Shares Plummet 7% Following Weakest Business Update</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 4, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Union Bank of India shares fall 7% after weakest business update so far amongst all lenders"><figcaption>Union Bank of India reports weakest business update among lenders.</figcaption><p>Union Bank of India's latest business update reveals a decline, causing shares to fall significantly.</p><ul><li>Shares dropped 7% after the release of the quarterly business update.</li><li>Deposits increased by 3.8% year-on-year, but fell 2% from the previous quarter.</li><li>Advances growth was 5.9% year-on-year, totaling ₹9.49 lakh crore.</li><li>Total business slightly declined by 0.24% quarter-on-quarter but rose 4.7% year-on-year to ₹21.65 lakh crore.</li><li>Currently trading at ₹115.67, down 6.7%.</li></ul><blockquote>“Union Bank's performance has shown weaknesses in key growth areas, leading to a significant market response.”</blockquote><p>The quarterly update raises concerns about Union Bank's performance relative to other lenders, pointing towards potential ongoing challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/union-bank-share-price-q3-update-global-business-down-sequentially-19534593.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/union-bank-share-price-q3-update-global-business-down-sequentially-19534593.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 04:09:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Easy Trip Planners shares surge up to 17% after Nishant Pitti confirms 'no further stake sale' - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Easy Trip Planners shares surge up to 17% after Nishant Pitti confirms 'no further stake sale'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC-TV18</p><img alt="Easy Trip Planners shares surge up to 17% after Nishant Pitti confirms 'no further stake sale'" title="Easy Trip Planners shares surge up to 17% after Nishant Pitti confirms 'no further stake sale'" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Easy Trip Planners shares surge after announcement</figcaption><p>Shares of Easy Trip Planners Ltd., the parent company of online travel aggregator EasyMyTrip, surged by 17% following confirmation that there would be no further stake sales from its promoters.</p><ul><li>Nishant Pitti confirmed via social media that he will not sell any further stake in the company.</li><li>He explained that the small percentage of stake sold last week was due to personal requirements.</li><li>Despite the stake sale, Pitti assured that he retains a 14.2% stake in the company.</li><li>Nishant Pitti stepped down as CEO but remains as Chairman, while Rikant Pittie was appointed the new CEO.</li></ul><blockquote>“Exciting times ahead for @EaseMyTrip! As Chairman, I’ll focus on shaping our future and driving international expansions, while Rikant steps in as CEO to lead day-to-day operations and driving our vision forward.” — Nishant Pitti</blockquote><p>With cash reserves of ₹400 crore, the company appears poised for investment in the travel sector, further solidifying its market position.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/easy-trip-planners-share-price-ease-my-trip-promoter-nishant-pitti-no-further-stake-sale-quits-ceo-outlook-19534866.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/easy-trip-planners-share-price-ease-my-trip-promoter-nishant-pitti-no-further-stake-sale-quits-ceo-outlook-19534866.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 03:52:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BSE, NSE to hold special session for ITC-ITC Hotels demerger: What we know - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BSE and NSE Prepare for ITC-ITC Hotels Demerger on January 6, 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><p>Monday, January 6, 2025, is the record date for ITC shareholders to determine eligibility for shares of ITC Hotels following its demerger that took effect on January 1, 2025.</p><ul><li>The ITC stock undergoes a pre-open session for price discovery.</li><li>Eligible shareholders will receive ITC Hotels shares based on their existing holdings.</li><li>The ITC stock will remain part of the indices for three trading days.</li><li>ITC retains a 40% stake in the new entity, distributing the remaining 60% to shareholders.</li><li>ITC Hotels shares are expected to list by mid-February 2025.</li><li>Early expiration for all ITC Futures and Options contracts related to the demerger.</li></ul><blockquote>“This move allows ITC Hotels to focus on growth in the luxury hospitality sector while maximising shareholder returns.”</blockquote><p>This demerger represents a strategic shift for ITC, aiming to enhance shareholder value and business focus.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/bse-nse-to-hold-special-session-for-itc-itc-hotel-demerger-what-we-know-125010600085_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/bse-nse-to-hold-special-session-for-itc-itc-hotel-demerger-what-we-know-125010600085_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 02:45:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indo Farm Equipment IPO Listing Date: Key things to know before debut on NSE and BSE - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indo Farm Equipment IPO Listing Date: Key Things to Know Before Debut on NSE and BSE</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, Source: Upstox</p><p>Indo Farm Equipment Ltd is set to debut on the NSE and BSE on January 7, following a strong investor response during its IPO bidding period.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The IPO received a final subscription of 229.68 times, with bids for 194.53 crore shares against 84.70 lakh shares reserved.</li><li>Non-institutional investors subscribed at 503.83 times, while qualified institutional buyers (QIBs) subscribed at 242.40 times.</li><li>The retail investors' quota was 104.92 times subscribed.</li><li>The IPO proceeds will fund business expansion, debt repayment, and general corporate purposes.</li><li>Trading will commence at 10 am on January 7.</li></ul><h2>Financial Performance:</h2><table><thead><tr><th>Particulars</th><th>FY22</th><th>FY23</th><th>FY24</th><th>Q1FY25</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Revenue</strong></td><td>₹352.08 cr</td><td>₹370.75 cr</td><td>₹375.23 cr</td><td>₹74.95 cr</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Net Profit</strong></td><td>₹13.72 cr</td><td>₹15.37 cr</td><td>₹15.59 cr</td><td>₹2.45 cr</td></tr></tbody></table><p><strong>For more information on IPO listings and upcoming IPOs, visit our page.</strong></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-listing-date-and-time-key-things-to-know-before-debut-on-nse-and-bse/article-138943/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-listing-date-and-time-key-things-to-know-before-debut-on-nse-and-bse/article-138943/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 02:44:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to watch, January 6: Bajaj Finance, ITC, HDFC Bank, Marico, Dabur, Vedanta, HUL, L&T Finance, and more - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to Watch, January 6</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Market Insights</p>
<p>The domestic equity market is anticipated to open positively on January 6, with significant updates from various major companies across sectors.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dabur:</strong> Anticipates low single-digit growth due to inflation; strategic price increases planned.</li>
<li><strong>HUL:</strong> Close to acquiring Minimalist; potential deal valued at ₹3,000 crore.</li>
<li><strong>Marico:</strong> Reports a sequential uptick in domestic volume growth but modest operating profit growth due to input cost inflation.</li>
<li><strong>Kotak Mahindra Bank:</strong> COO Milind Nagnur resigns effective February 15, 2025.</li>
<li><strong>ICICI Bank:</strong> Faces over ₹153 crore in tax penalties from Maharashtra GST Department.</li>
<li><strong>HDFC Bank:</strong> Loan growth marginally up by 3% to ₹25.42 lakh crore.</li>
<li><strong>ITC:</strong> Shares in focus due to hotel business demerger on record date.</li>
<li><strong>Bajaj Finance:</strong> Reports a 28% YoY rise in assets under management (AUM) to ₹3.98 lakh crore.</li>
<li><strong>Adani Wilmar:</strong> Reports 6% growth in sales volumes and 33% revenue increase in December quarter.</li>
<li><strong>Vedanta:</strong> Aluminium production rose 3% YoY; zinc production reached record levels.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If the deal goes through, Minimalist would have seen its valuation increase from around Rs 630 crore to ₹3,000 crore in a span of about three years.”</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing activity in the domestic stock market showcases the mixed economic prospects and company performances as investors position themselves ahead of critical economic announcements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/stocks-to-watch-january-6-bajaj-finance-itc-hdfc-bank-marico-dabur-vedanta-hul-l-and-t-finance-and-more/article-138944/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/stocks-to-watch-january-6-bajaj-finance-itc-hdfc-bank-marico-dabur-vedanta-hul-l-and-t-finance-and-more/article-138944/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 02:41:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bonus, Stock Split Alert: ITC demerger, Shriram Finance share division key events - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Key Corporate Actions: ITC Demerger and Shriram Finance Stock Split</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="bonus issue" title="bonus issue" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360"><figcaption></figcaption><p>As the earnings season approaches, significant corporate actions occur next week, including the ITC demerger and Shriram Finance stock split.</p><ul><li><strong>ITC Demerger:</strong> Record date fixed for January 6; shareholders receive one hotel share for every 10 ITC shares.</li><li><strong>Algoquant Fintech:</strong> A bonus issue of 1:2; record date is January 8.</li><li><strong>Camlin Fine Sciences:</strong> Rights issue to raise ₹225 crore; record date is January 8.</li><li><strong>Jagsonpal Pharma:</strong> Share split from ₹5 to ₹2 each; record date is January 8, 2025.</li><li><strong>Shriram Finance:</strong> Stock split from ₹10 to ₹2 each; record date is January 10.</li></ul><blockquote>“The record date for ITC's demerger has been fixed as January 6. Shareholders will be eligible for hotel business shares.”</blockquote><p>This week marks critical corporate restructuring events that may influence stock prices and trading patterns significantly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/bonus-stock-split-alert-itc-demerger-shriram-finance-jagsonpal-camlin-fine-share-price-19534823.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/bonus-stock-split-alert-itc-demerger-shriram-finance-jagsonpal-camlin-fine-share-price-19534823.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 01:31:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks To Watch Today: ITC, HDFC Bank, Dabur, Kotak Mahindra Bank, Marico, Bajaj Housing Finance And More - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks To Watch Today: ITC, HDFC Bank, Dabur, Kotak Mahindra Bank, Marico, Bajaj Housing Finance And More</h1><p><strong>Date &amp; Source:</strong> January 5, 2025, BloombergQuint</p><figure><img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2025-01-05%2Fuoksrs89%2Fjason-briscoe-amLfrL8LGls-unsplash.jpg?rect=0%2C0%2C6000%2C3375&amp;w=1200" alt="Stocks to watch"/><figcaption>Your guide to the most important stocks that will be on radar in Monday's trading session. (Photo source: Jason Briscoe on Unsplash)</figcaption></figure><p>Your guide to the most important stocks that will be on radar in Monday's trading session.</p><ul><li><strong>ITC:</strong> The stock will go ex-trade for demerger. ITC Hotels will be demerged from the parent company.</li><li><strong>HDFC Bank:</strong> Strong performance with total advances growing by 3% and deposits increasing by 15.8% YoY.</li><li><strong>Dabur India:</strong> Anticipated low single-digit growth in the third-quarter revenue.</li><li><strong>Bank of Baroda:</strong> Deposits rose 9.23% year-on-year to Rs 11.66 lakh crore.</li><li><strong>Kotak Mahindra Bank:</strong> COO and CTO Milind Nagnur resigned.</li><li><strong>Brigade Enterprises:</strong> Signed agreement for a major residential project in Bengaluru.</li><li><strong>Marico:</strong> Revenue delivered mid-teen growth with modest profit expectations.</li><li><strong>Bank of India:</strong> Reports 13.3% growth in domestic deposits.</li><li><strong>DCX Systems:</strong> Received an export order worth Rs 483 crores.</li><li><strong>Bajaj Housing Finance:</strong> Assets under management grew by 26% YoY.</li><li><strong>L&amp;T Finance:</strong> Retail loan book rose by 23% YoY.</li><li><strong>NTPC Green Energy:</strong> Secured a project in UPPCL’s solar auction.</li></ul><p>This trading session will be influenced by the performance of these key stocks and their latest updates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/stocks-to-watch-today-itc-hdfc-bank-dabur-kotak-mahindra-bank-marico-bajaj-housing-finance-and-more</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/stocks-to-watch-today-itc-hdfc-bank-dabur-kotak-mahindra-bank-marico-bajaj-housing-finance-and-more</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ITC demerger: Stock exchanges to hold special session today to set ITC Hotels share price - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxNUUFGN2xZYWE5VUNOVEl1UmpuV2lOX1Rxc21mdW9EbXZuSVlvNDVtelhXeFFUV1NCemdBTU45NHRtN1EzV3Y4Q0Y2UGhkWkJLZUtCdmhtTkR6ZHUyMWxsNF9wRk9GekhvNFlLZkd2UDdzMWNUemMzS2F4ZjBPWnF5Y3M1RVk4dFJYVlpvcDdXWFZiZUxVSTE5eG4zSUw2YnI3SlNrWkVYZkdqV3FIYkxiTUNoazRkMC0tcTRkVEo0WXdma0NCaFhCb2dJdG5Vb2xqR3RVU2Z0cFVwWHVVcHVpa1hxZDExZmlWYXB5aHh5cmw3blN40gH6AUFVX3lxTE0ydXhUSkl1bFg5TnA5NVlRdU4xeHE4QXVXTGV1Y0pUYkNHVU9yQy1Eclp0WUE2MVl3bmN4Tk51VTFWdndDYVlUUlkwa3p0c0VERTZuXzV1N2JCZWVuMlY1UXFOc2pMTmU5NTFTaFdzUmxuOFItVjNMN0xvbVNPb1RpX29WYTlBNXB2c0FZNkxhaXEydEpUZDBWOV9aeHpSN3l1MUNlNVp3UG1vdFgyWDJwQy1XcGtOc1NVQUQ5Tklla21DT0pBRk1ILU9WN3phSDBvZ2xLMWRhcjdJRG1mb3hoa1dBZ2Rkc0ZoZFF5VzBCZWxyRVptcU82OEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxNUUFGN2xZYWE5VUNOVEl1UmpuV2lOX1Rxc21mdW9EbXZuSVlvNDVtelhXeFFUV1NCemdBTU45NHRtN1EzV3Y4Q0Y2UGhkWkJLZUtCdmhtTkR6ZHUyMWxsNF9wRk9GekhvNFlLZkd2UDdzMWNUemMzS2F4ZjBPWnF5Y3M1RVk4dFJYVlpvcDdXWFZiZUxVSTE5eG4zSUw2YnI3SlNrWkVYZkdqV3FIYkxiTUNoazRkMC0tcTRkVEo0WXdma0NCaFhCb2dJdG5Vb2xqR3RVU2Z0cFVwWHVVcHVpa1hxZDExZmlWYXB5aHh5cmw3blN40gH6AUFVX3lxTE0ydXhUSkl1bFg5TnA5NVlRdU4xeHE4QXVXTGV1Y0pUYkNHVU9yQy1Eclp0WUE2MVl3bmN4Tk51VTFWdndDYVlUUlkwa3p0c0VERTZuXzV1N2JCZWVuMlY1UXFOc2pMTmU5NTFTaFdzUmxuOFItVjNMN0xvbVNPb1RpX29WYTlBNXB2c0FZNkxhaXEydEpUZDBWOV9aeHpSN3l1MUNlNVp3UG1vdFgyWDJwQy1XcGtOc1NVQUQ5Tklla21DT0pBRk1ILU9WN3phSDBvZ2xLMWRhcjdJRG1mb3hoa1dBZ2Rkc0ZoZFF5VzBCZWxyRVptcU82OEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 01:16:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market today: Trade setup for Nifty 50 to US dollar; 5 stocks to buy or sell on Monday — 6 January, 2025 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock market today: Trade setup for Nifty 50 to US dollar; 5 stocks to buy or sell on Monday — 6 January, 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The domestic stock market indices closed lower on January 3, with profit booking amid weak global cues. The Nifty 50 dropped to 24,004.75 points, and the BSE Sensex fell to 79,223.11 points. Experts provided insights on the outlook for the Nifty 50 and recommended five stocks to consider for trading.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Nifty 50 index closed down 0.76% and BSE Sensex down 0.90%.</li><li>Market sentiment remains cautiously positive with anticipation of further rises.</li><li>Parekh highlighted crucial resistance and support levels for Nifty and Bank Nifty.</li><li>US Dollar Index was trading lower, affecting commodity prices.</li><li>Experts recommended stocks including Titan Company, Authum Investment, GAIL India, Shriram Finance, and Aditya Birla Capital.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes:</h2><blockquote>“The index would have the important support near the 200 period MA at 23,900 levels which needs to be sustained.” - Market Expert</blockquote><blockquote>“TITAN presents a promising buying opportunity with a target of ₹3,693.” - Stock Analyst</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the stock market indicates cautious trading with potential for upward movements in selected stocks amid ongoing monitoring of global factors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stock-market-today-trade-setup-for-nifty-50-to-us-dollar-5-stocks-to-buy-or-sell-on-monday-6-january-2025-11736085371477.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stock-market-today-trade-setup-for-nifty-50-to-us-dollar-5-stocks-to-buy-or-sell-on-monday-6-january-2025-11736085371477.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 01:11:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Debt mutual funds may get tax relief on capital gains - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Debt Mutual Funds Seek Tax Relief on Capital Gains</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p><p>The mutual fund industry is advocating for the reintroduction of indexation benefits for capital gains on debt-oriented funds, potentially to be announced in the upcoming Budget FY26. This comes as current returns have diminished due to inflation.</p><ul><li>The government may favorably consider the reintroduction of indexation benefits, previously withdrawn in Finance Bill 2023.</li><li>The mutual fund industry requests a long-term capital gains tax rate of 12.5%, similar to that for listed bonds.</li><li>Investments made in debt funds prior to April 1, 2023, lost the indexation advantage due to recent budget changes.</li><li>Industry executives stress that indexation is a necessary tool to counterbalance inflation's impact on returns.</li></ul><blockquote>“While the ministry’s intention was tax simplicity, withdrawing indexation benefit for debt MF inadvertently introduced tax uncertainty. Reinstating it would not only restore investor confidence but also promote tax equality among various financial instruments.” – Neeraj Agarwala, partner, Nangia & Co.</blockquote><p>The mutual fund sector is focused on lobbying the government to align tax policies favorably towards long-term investments to enhance investor confidence and participation in capital markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/money/debt-mutual-funds-may-get-tax-relief-on-capital-gains-3707781/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/money/debt-mutual-funds-may-get-tax-relief-on-capital-gains-3707781/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[KEC, Tata Motors: Osho Krishan of Angel One picks 2 stocks to buy today - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>KEC, Tata Motors: Osho Krishan of Angel One picks 2 stocks to buy today</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 6, 2023</p><p>An expert analysis recommends two stocks to buy today, KEC and Tata Motors, highlighting their bullish trends and potential for gains.</p><ul><li><strong>KEC:</strong> Last Close – Rs 1,223.80. Recommended to buy around Rs 1,210 with a Stop Loss (SL) at Rs 1,145 and a Target (TGT) of Rs 1,320-1,340.</li><li><strong>Tata Motors:</strong> Last Close – Rs 790.40. Recommended to buy around Rs 780 with a SL at Rs 735 and a TGT of Rs 850-870.</li></ul><blockquote>“Technically, the counter has surged above the 20-DEMA after a long haul, which implies initial positive development.”</blockquote><p><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> Osho Krishan is a senior analyst at Angel One Ltd. Views expressed are his own.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/kec-tata-motors-osho-krishan-of-angel-one-picks-2-stocks-to-buy-today-125010600045_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/kec-tata-motors-osho-krishan-of-angel-one-picks-2-stocks-to-buy-today-125010600045_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:57:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks in news: ITC, HDFC Bank, Adani Wilmar, Kotak Bank, HUL - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks in news: ITC, HDFC Bank, Adani Wilmar, Kotak Bank, HUL</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 6, 2024, ETtech</p><figure><img height="158" width="210" alt="Stocks in news" src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116970982,width-210,height-158,imgsize-95072,resizemode-75/stocks-in-news.jpg"><figcaption>Dabur expected third quarter revenue to grow in low single digits, and expects sequential demand improvement.</figcaption></figure><p>Indian markets faced selling pressure, with various shares in focus due to recent news developments. Notable companies include ITC, HDFC Bank, Adani Wilmar, and Hindustan Unilever.</p><ul><li><strong>ITC:</strong> The demerger of ITC Hotels took effect as of January 1, with January 6 as the record date.</li><li><strong>Union Bank:</strong> Reported a 2% YoY increase in domestic deposits, totaling Rs 11.82 lakh.</li><li><strong>Adani Wilmar:</strong> Revenue grew by 33% YoY for the December quarter.</li><li><strong>HDFC Bank:</strong> Gross advances increased by 3% YoY to Rs 25.42 lakh crore.</li><li><strong>HUL:</strong> Advanced discussions to acquire skincare startup Minimalist for Rs 3,000 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bandhan Bank's loans and advances rose 15% YoY to Rs 1.33 lakh crore.”</blockquote><p>This period demonstrates fluctuations in market performance and strategic movements by major companies affecting their stock responses.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/stocks-in-news-itc-hdfc-bank-adani-wilmar-kotak-bank-hul/articleshow/116970960.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/stocks-in-news-itc-hdfc-bank-adani-wilmar-kotak-bank-hul/articleshow/116970960.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold Price Forecast: XAU/USD holds below $2,650 as traders await fresh catalysts - FXStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Price Forecast: XAU/USD holds below $2,650 as traders await fresh catalysts</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> FXStreet</p><p>The Gold price (XAU/USD) remains steady around $2,640 amid stronger US manufacturing data and ongoing geopolitical tensions. Analysts are looking towards upcoming US labor market data for further direction.</p><ul><li>Gold price holds steady around $2,640 in Monday’s early Asian session.</li><li>US Manufacturing PMI improved to 49.3 in December vs. 48.4 prior, stronger than expected.</li><li>Sustained geopolitical risks and a wave of purchases by central banks could lift the Gold price.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Central banks are forecast to continue to be net buyers of around 8 million oz. in 2025.”</p></blockquote><p>Overall, the stability in Gold prices reflects a combination of market dynamics, including central bank purchasing patterns and geopolitical uncertainties, making it a pivotal asset for investors during turbulent times.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-forecast-xau-usd-holds-below-2-650-as-traders-await-fresh-catalysts-202501060037</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-forecast-xau-usd-holds-below-2-650-as-traders-await-fresh-catalysts-202501060037</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:37:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tata Sons ends debt support for new businesses, focus on independent financing - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxNcS02R0lVU3VfcnpWSUhXMUlJUkExRkRYQnA4R3lRWm9OdTRXMzdkMk5FVy1MUTl3aEhXTmhOY0hQSWdBWlhYN05JeVhZNTEwUE5NN09PT0ZoUlN4c1lvc3ctb1MxeDMtWXFUcmU0Y3JPRHpQWGphM19VeWZuaVZOLXdlUUJiZmNIMUN1YW1rQ1BkckJLRU9haG9CUE1MM0QyWjZGeDc0cFc4bjM1M2dkOXIzckJYOUJvWVE5Z0VMbTFndy1rWFh6LXVqUHFaREdBZXdKVVdOSzFkWFB4empZZHRjbTYwNmdpZU9UencxT1ZTRVXSAfgBQVVfeXFMTndRMTZpYlc4RkI1a1hFMnBfOF9CN2RTc1N5VXZUeTBaWFN0cDFROTJBUUVac19OWEs4aDU0TDc3clF1aWtUZ2ZfWEhfMnROZkxwNVkwS05ob3RfcnNOb2laTXRYNFJ0YTBOYkJMd0FWWDNQdFdaWlRkd24xakk5Q3ZMamxZQ0x2cGs5WGxEZm1nZnpGNUY0VkVJNDNiTzJocDJJc2lRcGNPZER1NktqTGZWbU1lWVRXNU5TbEM4WGdtVFR0MGdTWFNJNDR6OFhTQ1gybXluSXFELUc0UC1tNV85M2Z4OGU4STVQbUdSd0ZMWHhmSTdycUk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxNcS02R0lVU3VfcnpWSUhXMUlJUkExRkRYQnA4R3lRWm9OdTRXMzdkMk5FVy1MUTl3aEhXTmhOY0hQSWdBWlhYN05JeVhZNTEwUE5NN09PT0ZoUlN4c1lvc3ctb1MxeDMtWXFUcmU0Y3JPRHpQWGphM19VeWZuaVZOLXdlUUJiZmNIMUN1YW1rQ1BkckJLRU9haG9CUE1MM0QyWjZGeDc0cFc4bjM1M2dkOXIzckJYOUJvWVE5Z0VMbTFndy1rWFh6LXVqUHFaREdBZXdKVVdOSzFkWFB4empZZHRjbTYwNmdpZU9UencxT1ZTRVXSAfgBQVVfeXFMTndRMTZpYlc4RkI1a1hFMnBfOF9CN2RTc1N5VXZUeTBaWFN0cDFROTJBUUVac19OWEs4aDU0TDc3clF1aWtUZ2ZfWEhfMnROZkxwNVkwS05ob3RfcnNOb2laTXRYNFJ0YTBOYkJMd0FWWDNQdFdaWlRkd24xakk5Q3ZMamxZQ0x2cGs5WGxEZm1nZnpGNUY0VkVJNDNiTzJocDJJc2lRcGNPZER1NktqTGZWbU1lWVRXNU5TbEM4WGdtVFR0MGdTWFNJNDR6OFhTQ1gybXluSXFELUc0UC1tNV85M2Z4OGU4STVQbUdSd0ZMWHhmSTdycUk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bajaj Housing Finance Q3 Results FY 2024-25 Date and Time ANNOUNCED: Check quarterly earnings schedule of Bajaj Group's stock - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgJBVV95cUxQejVSVWJaX3Ffa0dUc09qajlYcjZMSmQ5a0Qyd3FNODBFZUg0RlVuUnE3enloZ2t6bk1MRml4Sl8yWmw2QlhNR0NURmJmNk0zamRKS1hHS1N6S28xYkJJcnRSWUtVOE11OFFnTkFPUldzb1hzTEVLdGNfREZZRnBNaTVtdF9uSk5WdUdiZkJXRkpwMnVWTkQwcXFVUWVnT3NjaVRaM012cmdKZUdLM2tpY2lYbnU5eHlVaGpZajN6Y0ZWVm4xR1p1X1RqcHdCZDJTaS16dm5QWkdybU02b0d1dnJacENaNFRwVURTQlJ0dHVDRmZWY3REQmE2MmxqckRKbUFJYjJn0gGLAkFVX3lxTFBsR0JVNDNTcHE3R2Q0Z2hubE5SdnBuVkluYzZxWGRNOHRMNmk1SlF6NTI2d1JOQkFUcU0tcGFQNjRzRFhaeFVPZVI0TDU0c0hjMVgwZ1QwdVhFclNZbW15Rld1dkJsRWg3eGVqekw4cnY2LU43S0RBaC1xcGxzcDZBcHJOSFVGazBKUjRKRGo5dkpRM2JmTzFxNXpjeHBVcVA1ZVA0R0lHbUhyUi1mWDA2dzR4Z0Q4RU5WQWJtQVBkdUhjYkd0WHdDZWtSU2phcHZTSTdJQ1RjODhwZFBwYTRFa2NZeWFiR3ZfOFZBT1JYSXllZENiNXJ3Y2poV0Rtd3pHMFM2YlhOcVRJWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgJBVV95cUxQejVSVWJaX3Ffa0dUc09qajlYcjZMSmQ5a0Qyd3FNODBFZUg0RlVuUnE3enloZ2t6bk1MRml4Sl8yWmw2QlhNR0NURmJmNk0zamRKS1hHS1N6S28xYkJJcnRSWUtVOE11OFFnTkFPUldzb1hzTEVLdGNfREZZRnBNaTVtdF9uSk5WdUdiZkJXRkpwMnVWTkQwcXFVUWVnT3NjaVRaM012cmdKZUdLM2tpY2lYbnU5eHlVaGpZajN6Y0ZWVm4xR1p1X1RqcHdCZDJTaS16dm5QWkdybU02b0d1dnJacENaNFRwVURTQlJ0dHVDRmZWY3REQmE2MmxqckRKbUFJYjJn0gGLAkFVX3lxTFBsR0JVNDNTcHE3R2Q0Z2hubE5SdnBuVkluYzZxWGRNOHRMNmk1SlF6NTI2d1JOQkFUcU0tcGFQNjRzRFhaeFVPZVI0TDU0c0hjMVgwZ1QwdVhFclNZbW15Rld1dkJsRWg3eGVqekw4cnY2LU43S0RBaC1xcGxzcDZBcHJOSFVGazBKUjRKRGo5dkpRM2JmTzFxNXpjeHBVcVA1ZVA0R0lHbUhyUi1mWDA2dzR4Z0Q4RU5WQWJtQVBkdUhjYkd0WHdDZWtSU2phcHZTSTdJQ1RjODhwZFBwYTRFa2NZeWFiR3ZfOFZBT1JYSXllZENiNXJ3Y2poV0Rtd3pHMFM2YlhOcVRJWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 20:00:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NPS systematic withdrawal plan suits retirees with large corpus - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NPS Systematic Withdrawal Plan Benefits Retirees</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recently | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Main Image"><figcaption>An image associated with the article.</figcaption><p>The National Pension System (NPS) offers a systematic withdrawal plan particularly beneficial for retirees with a substantial corpus.</p><ul><li>The systematic withdrawal plan allows retirees to withdraw funds periodically instead of a lump sum.</li><li>This mechanism aids in financial planning by ensuring a steady income stream post-retirement.</li><li>Retirees can customize their withdrawal frequency and amount based on their needs.</li><li>This option is particularly advantageous for those with larger retirement savings, enabling better cash flow management.</li></ul><blockquote>“The systematic withdrawal plan is tailored to meet the diverse financial needs of retirees, providing flexibility and security.”</blockquote><p>The NPS's systematic withdrawal plan not only secures financial stability for retirees but also encourages a more strategic approach to managing retirement funds.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/nps-systematic-withdrawal-plan-suits-retirees-with-large-corpus/articleshow/116971948.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/nps-systematic-withdrawal-plan-suits-retirees-with-large-corpus/articleshow/116971948.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 18:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Standard Glass Lining IPO GMP today percentage gain of share price band, listing date - DETAILS - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Standard Glass Lining IPO Launch Details and Expected Gains</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW</p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Standard Glass Lining IPO GMP today" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Standard Glass Lining IPO GMP today</figcaption><p>Standard Glass Lining Technology is set to launch its IPO on January 6, 2025, with a closing date of January 8, 2025. The IPO aims to raise Rs 410 crore and is expected to generate notable gains based on current grey market prices.</p><ul><li>The IPO includes a fresh issue of shares worth up to Rs 210 crore and an offer for sale of 1,42,89,367 equity shares.</li><li>The price band for the shares is set between Rs 133 and Rs 140.</li><li>Currently, shares are trading at a grey market premium (GMP) of Rs 97, indicating a 69.29% gain potential over the issue price.</li><li>The allotment date for shares is scheduled for January 9, 2025, with the listing expected on January 13, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>"The company aims to use the proceeds for capital expenditure, debt repayment, and strategic investments."</blockquote><p>This IPO is generating significant interest among investors, highlighting the company's strong market position and financial stability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/standard-glass-lining-ipo-gmp-today-percentage-gain-of-share-price-band-listing-date-details-article-116968831</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/standard-glass-lining-ipo-gmp-today-percentage-gain-of-share-price-band-listing-date-details-article-116968831</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:51:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dai-ichi Life Takes ¥140 Billion Loss Selling Off Long Bonds | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dai-ichi Life Takes ¥140 Billion Loss Selling Off Long Bonds</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p><p>Dai-ichi Life Insurance Co. incurred a loss of approximately ¥140 billion ($890 million) by selling long-term bonds in anticipation of rising interest rates. The company sold ¥500 billion in Japanese government bonds, primarily of longer maturities, in the first half of the fiscal year.</p><ul><li>The sales were concentrated in the first half of the fiscal year, with plans for more restrained activity in the second half.</li><li>President Toshiaki Sumino assured that the loss would not impact the company's financial soundness.</li><li>Dai-ichi Life holds ¥18.9 trillion in yen-denominated bonds.</li><li>Sumino predicts a rate hike by the Bank of Japan due to the economy showing signs of recovery.</li><li>The company is focused on replacing sold assets while being mindful of profit impacts.</li><li>Annualized premiums from new contracts rose significantly in the first half of fiscal 2024, marking a recovery from previous scandals.</li></ul><blockquote>“I don’t think the loss will have any impact on our financial soundness,” said Sumino.</blockquote><p>Overall, Dai-ichi Life is navigating the challenges posed by the changing interest rate environment while also working to rebound from past setbacks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/daiichi-life-takes-140-billion-loss-selling-off-long-bonds-11736090905509.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/daiichi-life-takes-140-billion-loss-selling-off-long-bonds-11736090905509.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:28:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chinese hack of US telecoms compromised more firms than previously known, WSJ says - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxPeGlWSmFHNm9jb1psUVdTMzRVZFctalZ3Z05ibVNXbjVMNDF3OExDemdfWERKWTFWQl9Sd2trcEY5My0tdTdyTHlfVHVmZk9adFVwUFVoeFdVaHBXZ0R3bDJFelFOVTVnanFCYUxqWVluODQxUUZnbDFJSFU3VWw1dkxDazYxekFPYkVKQTNoZXB4YlVkUk92MVNTc0Z5X1hnVXNCa2xDVXlhcnVGRE5LQzZJZmlaSEFBdXFpVmJVTk9Vc1NUTjFJT3Z4TlVlNUlVT2s0aU52Z2pPOXgySElGYVFQVlNQUDF4M19tS0NKVjBicWxRNGfSAfsBQVVfeXFMT2p0N2ppbm1uMlRycExLbHBESl8wNW16ZUVEQk1iRU54VEdFWjJGMVFLTWFBMEROSGZILU9GMlFIT0VCcUJTRlBmMG1xMHlmUDl6QnkwX281RjN1dlNyNUhVeTMwREY3Z3R2NWhiUUthcjJyVGZFWEl5TGllbE9sR2l5cXllajJCcDJkOFozMVk2aXJ2dS11bnJJUV80VWZFNU1HU0VkQWpYbVF2OWJhNnZFWktrY2lvbms4V3I3YlpfYjNNeVRDZmNlSWVuVHlZZlE5NTFMVHZ4TkhKTkF6THlzSDJPXzUtQnAyWERzRzJybTZVd2p5QmxFYXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxPeGlWSmFHNm9jb1psUVdTMzRVZFctalZ3Z05ibVNXbjVMNDF3OExDemdfWERKWTFWQl9Sd2trcEY5My0tdTdyTHlfVHVmZk9adFVwUFVoeFdVaHBXZ0R3bDJFelFOVTVnanFCYUxqWVluODQxUUZnbDFJSFU3VWw1dkxDazYxekFPYkVKQTNoZXB4YlVkUk92MVNTc0Z5X1hnVXNCa2xDVXlhcnVGRE5LQzZJZmlaSEFBdXFpVmJVTk9Vc1NUTjFJT3Z4TlVlNUlVT2s0aU52Z2pPOXgySElGYVFQVlNQUDF4M19tS0NKVjBicWxRNGfSAfsBQVVfeXFMT2p0N2ppbm1uMlRycExLbHBESl8wNW16ZUVEQk1iRU54VEdFWjJGMVFLTWFBMEROSGZILU9GMlFIT0VCcUJTRlBmMG1xMHlmUDl6QnkwX281RjN1dlNyNUhVeTMwREY3Z3R2NWhiUUthcjJyVGZFWEl5TGllbE9sR2l5cXllajJCcDJkOFozMVk2aXJ2dS11bnJJUV80VWZFNU1HU0VkQWpYbVF2OWJhNnZFWktrY2lvbms4V3I3YlpfYjNNeVRDZmNlSWVuVHlZZlE5NTFMVHZ4TkhKTkF6THlzSDJPXzUtQnAyWERzRzJybTZVd2p5QmxFYXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:13:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian-origin founder clueless after selling $975 million firm: ‘No idea what to do’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian-origin founder clueless after selling $975 million firm: ‘No idea what to do’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/Untitled_1736089428898_1736089435938.png" alt="Indian-origin entrepreneur Vinay Hiremath sold his startup Loom to Atlassian for $975 million in 2023.(Instagram/vhmth)" title="Indian-origin entrepreneur Vinay Hiremath sold his startup Loom to Atlassian for $975 million in 2023.(Instagram/vhmth)"><figcaption>Indian-origin entrepreneur Vinay Hiremath sold his startup Loom to Atlassian for $975 million in 2023.(Instagram/vhmth)</figcaption><p>Vinay Hiremath, co-founder of Loom, expressed confusion after selling his startup for $975 million, revealing his struggles with newfound wealth and direction in life.</p><ul><li>Hiremath sold Loom to Atlassian for $975 million in 2023.</li><li>He shared his thoughts in a blog post, detailing feelings of aimlessness despite financial freedom.</li><li>He apologized to his ex-girlfriend, reflecting on personal insecurities affecting his relationships.</li><li>He considered starting a robotics company but felt uninspired by the idea.</li><li>Hiremath attempted to work for Elon Musk, describing it as a valuable experience.</li><li>After an ill-fated expedition in the Himalayas, he is currently in Hawaii learning physics to build a foundation for future ventures.</li></ul><blockquote>“After selling my company, I find myself in the totally un-relatable position of never having to work again.”</blockquote><p>Hiremath’s journey highlights the emotional challenges that can accompany sudden wealth and the search for purpose beyond financial success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/indianorigin-founder-clueless-after-selling-975-million-firm-no-idea-what-to-do-101736089080662.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/indianorigin-founder-clueless-after-selling-975-million-firm-no-idea-what-to-do-101736089080662.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:11:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Expert take | 'Private banks, IT and pharma sectors seen attractive for 2025,' says Geojit Fin Services' Vinod Nair | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Private Banks, IT, and Pharma Sectors Expected to Thrive in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The article discusses the outlook for the stock market in 2025, emphasizing the attractiveness of private banks, IT, and pharma sectors despite potential challenges such as elevated valuations and reduced liquidity.</p><ul><li>Domestic stock markets may face challenges but investment opportunities remain due to economic performance.</li><li>Capital preservation and high-quality stocks will be key investment themes.</li><li>Private banks are expected to benefit from GDP growth and low valuations.</li><li>IT and pharma sectors are favored due to stable business outlooks and dollar strength.</li><li>Consumer sectors face headwinds, but FMCG could benefit from favorable conditions.</li><li>Infrastructure and textiles sectors show strong growth potential.</li></ul><blockquote>The author, Vinod Nair, states, "Value stocks and high dividend payers will be a big theme of 2025."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while challenges exist, strategic investments in key sectors could yield positive outcomes in 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/time-to-sell-equities-as-sentiment-turns-cautious-heres-what-expert-advices-11736081888579.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/time-to-sell-equities-as-sentiment-turns-cautious-heres-what-expert-advices-11736081888579.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:47:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weakening rupee may not be shot in the arm for India's pharma exporters - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weakening rupee may not be shot in the arm for India's pharma exporters</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" title="medicine" alt="medicine" width="826" height="465"><figcaption>Premium</figcaption><p>The recent depreciation of the Indian rupee against the US dollar raises concerns for India's pharmaceutical exporters, as experts debate its immediate impact on the industry.</p><ul><li>India’s pharmaceutical exports to the US constituted 31% of total drug exports, amounting to $8.7 billion in 2023-24.</li><li>Experts suggest that currency fluctuations may have little immediate impact due to hedged contracts.</li><li>Concerns arise over smaller exporters potentially lowering prices, leading to price renegotiations.</li><li>Higher import costs for active pharmaceutical ingredients (APIs) could offset benefits from export gains.</li></ul><blockquote>“The devaluing rupee may not boost exports as expected.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while a weaker rupee has the potential to help exporters, the overall impact is complicated by various factors that may limit its effectiveness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/economy/news/weakening-rupee-may-not-be-shot-in-the-arm-for-india-s-pharma-exporters-125010500409_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/economy/news/weakening-rupee-may-not-be-shot-in-the-arm-for-india-s-pharma-exporters-125010500409_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:40:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Growth in agri credit may top 13% in FY25: Nabard chairman Shaji KV - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Growth in Agri Credit May Exceed 13% in FY25, Says Nabard Chairman Shaji KV</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> (Date Not Provided) <strong>Source:</strong> (Source Not Provided)</p><p>During a media interaction in New Delhi, Shaji KV, chairman of the National Bank for Agriculture and Rural Development (Nabard), announced that agricultural credit growth is expected to surpass 13% in FY25, reaching Rs 27-28 trillion.</p><ul><li>In FY24, agricultural credit reached Rs 25.1 trillion, exceeding the target of Rs 20 trillion by 25%.</li><li>There is a notable decline in reliance on informal credit sources, indicating a trend toward the formalisation of rural credit.</li><li>The government aims to digitise land records through the agri stack initiative to aid credit growth.</li><li>Nabard plans to computerise 67,000 of the 100,000 primary cooperative societies this financial year.</li><li>As of June 30, 2023, the Kisan Credit Card (KCC) scheme has over 74 million active accounts, totaling outstanding credit of Rs 8.9 trillion.</li></ul><blockquote>“Agriculture encompasses more than just crop production, and these sectors need access to subsidised credit to improve their per capita income.” - Shaji KV</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the growth in agricultural credit reflects both an increasing financial inclusion for farmers and a need for supportive infrastructures like digitised records and better credit accessibility.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/industry/agriculture/agriculture-credit-growth-may-surpass-13-in-fy25-nabard-chairman-125010500422_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/industry/agriculture/agriculture-credit-growth-may-surpass-13-in-fy25-nabard-chairman-125010500422_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:33:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is the salary of Apple's new Indian-origin CFO Kevan Parekh? Details here - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple's New CFO Kevan Parekh: Salary and Background Details</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/GV9SzR-aoAEH0_e_1736053309136_1736053317262.jpg" alt="Indian-origin Kevan Parekh, who has been appointed as the new chief financial officer of Apple Inc." title="Indian-origin Kevan Parekh, who has been appointed as the new chief financial officer of Apple Inc."><figcaption>Indian-origin Kevan Parekh, who has been appointed as the new chief financial officer of Apple Inc.</figcaption><p>This article discusses the appointment of Kevan Parekh as the new Chief Financial Officer (CFO) of Apple Inc., effective January 1, 2025, along with details of his salary and professional background.</p><ul><li>Kevan Parekh's annual salary is set at $1 million (₹8.57 crore).</li><li>Parekh joined Apple in June 2013 and held previous roles in financial planning and analysis.</li><li>He succeeds Luca Maestri as part of a planned transition.</li><li>Parekh has extensive experience with Thomson Reuters and General Motors.</li><li>Apple's CEO Tim Cook praised Parekh's intellect and judgment in his appointment announcement.</li></ul><blockquote>“For more than a decade, Kevan has been an indispensable member of Apple's finance leadership team...” - Tim Cook</blockquote><p>Parekh's leadership is expected to steer Apple's financial strategies effectively as he steps into this significant role.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/what-is-indian-origin-kevan-parekh-s-salary-as-apple-s-new-cfo-101736050627448.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/what-is-indian-origin-kevan-parekh-s-salary-as-apple-s-new-cfo-101736050627448.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:27:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Etihad Airways flight aborts takeoff at Melbourne airport after tyre burst, passengers evacuated safely - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Etihad Airways Flight Abort Soaring at Melbourne Airport Due to Tyre Burst</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>An Etihad Airways flight had to abort its takeoff at Melbourne Airport after experiencing a tyre burst, leading to the safe evacuation of passengers.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred during takeoff.</li><li>All passengers were evacuated safely without injury.</li><li>The flight's safety protocols were effectively executed.</li></ul><blockquote>“Safety is our top priority and our team acted quickly to ensure all passengers were unharmed.”</blockquote><p>The swift action taken ensured the safety of all onboard, highlighting the importance of aircraft safety measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/etihad-airways-flight-aborts-takeoff-at-melbourne-airport-after-tyre-burst-passengers-evacuated-safely/articleshow/116968238.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/etihad-airways-flight-aborts-takeoff-at-melbourne-airport-after-tyre-burst-passengers-evacuated-safely/articleshow/116968238.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks To Watch on January 6: HDFC Bank, ITC, Kotak Mahindra Bank, Vedanta and more - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks To Watch on January 6: HDFC Bank, ITC, Kotak Mahindra Bank, Vedanta and More</h1><p><strong>Date: January 6, 2024</strong></p><p><strong>Source: CNBC TV18</strong></p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Stocks to Watch" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption><p>This article highlights key stocks to monitor in the trade on January 6, including significant updates and announcements from various companies.</p><ul><li><strong>HDFC Bank:</strong> Reported a year-on-year growth in gross advances by 3% and deposits by 15.8%; however, CASA deposits decreased by 4.4%.</li><li><strong>ITC:</strong> Record date for ITC Hotels demerger where shareholders will receive one ITC Hotels share for every 10 ITC shares.</li><li><strong>Kotak Mahindra Bank:</strong> CTO and COO Milind Nagnur has resigned, effective February 15, 2025.</li><li><strong>ICICI Bank:</strong> Received a GST demand and penalty order of ₹100.76 crore from Maharashtra's GST Department.</li><li><strong>Bajaj Finance:</strong> Announced a business update with AUM growing by 28% year-on-year.</li><li><strong>Vedanta:</strong> Production increased by 3% in Q3 FY25 with record-high mined metal production.</li><li><strong>Premier Explosives:</strong> A fire in Telangana factory resulted in one fatality and severe injuries.</li><li><strong>NTPC Green:</strong> Secured 1000 MW capacity in a bid at ₹2.56 per kWh from UPPCL.</li><li><strong>Andhra Paper:</strong> Production disrupted due to a workers' strike at its Rajahmundry plant.</li><li><strong>UCO Bank:</strong> Reported a 16.2% increase in total advances in Q3 FY25.</li><li><strong>Quess Corp:</strong> Announced an income tax refund of ₹124.80 crore for FY24.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/hdfc-bank-itc-kotak-mahindra-bank-vedanta-stocks-to-watch-on-january-6-share-price-19534781.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/hdfc-bank-itc-kotak-mahindra-bank-vedanta-stocks-to-watch-on-january-6-share-price-19534781.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:01:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BRICS: India Likely Dumping the U.S. Dollar - Watcher Guru]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidkFVX3lxTE0tQmgxUmRzSVZ4QmZrN0JTOTAzWVdkTEYwR2FkdUFIRGFpX3BSTEVZMUpSUVdSQUhHNHloRkgyT1oydzRUb3pBU0pxRXpJOHdXbWFyTkRuNjk3ZkhlMjk5RW9IMy1IYWtnR2xLS204TzlSazJ3M1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidkFVX3lxTE0tQmgxUmRzSVZ4QmZrN0JTOTAzWVdkTEYwR2FkdUFIRGFpX3BSTEVZMUpSUVdSQUhHNHloRkgyT1oydzRUb3pBU0pxRXpJOHdXbWFyTkRuNjk3ZkhlMjk5RW9IMy1IYWtnR2xLS204TzlSazJ3M1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:01:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani Wilmar to expand FMCG portfolio, emulates ITC post-Adani group exit - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Adani Wilmar to Expand FMCG Portfolio, Emulating ITC Post-Adani Group Exit</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p>
<p>Adani Wilmar Ltd (AWL), India's largest edible oil company, is adopting a strategy akin to ITC's to bolster its FMCG portfolio following the exit of the Adani group. By leveraging its dominant edible oil business and extensive distribution network, AWL aims to achieve growth in high-margin FMCG products.</p>
<ul>
<li>AWL's FMCG segment achieved a 24% year-on-year growth in volume in the December quarter.</li>
<li>The overall share of food and FMCG in volumes increased to 20%, and in revenues to 9%.</li>
<li>Key packaged products in the food category saw robust double-digit growth.</li>
<li>AWL's significant distribution network reaches 2.1 million outlets.</li>
<li>Due to higher oil prices, revenue from the edible oil segment increased by 39% year-on-year.</li>
<li>AWL's total revenues grew by 33%, surpassing analysts' expectations.</li>
<li>Gautam Adani's group sold its entire stake in AWL for over USD 2 billion.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our integrated distribution model is helping us capitalise on the strength of our oil distribution network to expand the reach of our food products, particularly in urban markets.”</blockquote>
<p>With these strategic moves, AWL plans to introduce global FMCG brands into the Indian market, following the exit of the Adani Group.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/adani-wilmar-to-expand-fmcg-portfolio-emulates-itc-post-adani-group-exit-125010500473_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/adani-wilmar-to-expand-fmcg-portfolio-emulates-itc-post-adani-group-exit-125010500473_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 13:59:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Petrol Pump booked for delivering deficit fuel to consumers in Anantnag - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Petrol Pump in Anantnag Penalized for Deficient Fuel Delivery</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Greater Kashmir</p>
<p>A petrol pump on National Highway Anantnag has been booked for delivering less fuel to consumers following a surprise inspection by the Enforcement unit of Legal Metrology Anantnag.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The inspection revealed that every 5 litres delivered was short by 30 ml.</li>
  <li>The display boards at the petrol pump were found to be inaccurate.</li>
  <li>The nozzle was seized, and prosecution under the Legal Metrology Act has begun against the pump owner.</li>
  <li>Consumers are encouraged to check fuel delivery using a verified 5 litre measure, which should be visible at all petrol pumps.</li>
  <li>Consumer rights awareness was promoted in the local community, with a toll-free number provided for complaints.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Accuracy in the quantity of goods or fuel is the basic right of consumers.”</blockquote>
<p>Consumers in the area appreciated the enforcement action and have been informed about their rights to ensure fair delivery of fuel.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/kashmir/petrol-pump-booked-for-delivering-deficit-fuel-to-consumers-in-anantnag/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/kashmir/petrol-pump-booked-for-delivering-deficit-fuel-to-consumers-in-anantnag/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 13:53:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>