<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 03:22:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 03:22:49 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kia Syros Bookings Open, Launch On February 1, 2025 - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kia Syros Bookings Open, Launch On February 1, 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> CarDekho.com</p><img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/67768a7a08ec3.jpg" alt="New Kia Syros Bookings Now Open Ahead Of Launch In February"><figcaption>New Kia Syros Bookings Now Open Ahead Of Launch In February</figcaption><p>Kia has opened bookings for the new Syros SUV with a token amount of Rs 25,000 ahead of its launch on February 1, 2025.</p><ul><li>Bookings for the Kia Syros are open.</li><li>It slots between the Sonet and Seltos in Kia's line-up.</li><li>Available in six variants: HTK, HTK (O), HTK Plus, HTX, HTX Plus, HTX Plus (O).</li><li>Engine options include a 1L turbo petrol and a 1.5L diesel.</li><li>Features include ventilated seats, dual 12.3-inch screens, and ADAS.</li><li>Expected pricing starts at Rs 9.7 lakhs (ex-showroom).</li></ul><p>The Kia Syros will be showcased at the Bharat Mobility Global Expo 2025, with deliveries expected soon after the launch.</p><blockquote>“Kia is offering the Syros with various segment-first features, ensuring a competitive edge in the market.”</blockquote><p>Overall, the Kia Syros is positioned as an exciting new entry in the SUV segment, blending modern features with competitive pricing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/new-kia-syros-bookings-now-open-ahead-of-launch-in-february-33764.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/new-kia-syros-bookings-now-open-ahead-of-launch-in-february-33764.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 02:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breakout stocks to buy or sell: Sumeet Bagadia recommends five shares to buy today — 3 January 2025 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Breakout stocks to buy or sell: Sumeet Bagadia recommends five shares to buy today — 3 January 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 3 January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Despite a downturn in the Asian stock market, the Indian stock market showed resilience with significant gains. Sumeet Bagadia of Choice Broking offers his insights into current market trends and recommends five stocks for investors.</p><h2>Sumeet Bagadia's breakout stock recommendations</h2><ul><li>The Nifty 50 index rose by 425 points, closing at 24,168.</li><li>The BSE Sensex increased by 1,385 points, ending at 79,893.</li><li>Bagadia recommends a bullish outlook with a focus on breakout stocks for intraday trading.</li><li>Five shares recommended for buying include Apollo Micro Systems, Reliance Infrastructure, DCX Systems, FSL, and Transformers and Rectifiers (India).</li></ul><blockquote>“Nifty today can be assumed in a broader range of 23,850 to 24,250.” - Sumeet Bagadia</blockquote><p>The recommended stocks and their details are as follows:</p><ul><li><strong>Apollo Micro Systems:</strong> Buy at ₹123.96, target ₹133, stop loss ₹119.</li><li><strong>Reliance Infrastructure:</strong> Buy at ₹322.65, target ₹345, stop loss ₹311.</li><li><strong>DCX Systems:</strong> Buy at ₹393, stop loss ₹355.</li><li><strong>FSL:</strong> Buy at ₹394.50, target ₹422, stop loss ₹380.</li><li><strong>Transformers and Rectifiers (India):</strong> Buy at ₹1230, target ₹1300, stop loss ₹1186.</li></ul><p><i><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> The views and recommendations made above are those of individual analysts or broking companies and not of Mint. We advise investors to check with certified experts before taking any investment decisions.</i></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/breakout-stocks-to-buy-or-sell-sumeet-bagadia-recommends-five-shares-to-buy-today-3-january-2025-11735868482299.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/breakout-stocks-to-buy-or-sell-sumeet-bagadia-recommends-five-shares-to-buy-today-3-january-2025-11735868482299.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 01:52:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Market Today: All You Need To Know Going Into Trade On Jan. 3 - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Today: All You Need To Know Going Into Trade On Jan. 3</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 03 Jan 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Profit</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2025-01-03%2Fri02tp2q%2FWhatsApp-Image-2025-01-03-at-06.17.36.jpeg?w=1200" alt="Stock Market Today: All You Need To Know Going Into Trade On Jan. 3">
  <figcaption>Stock Market Overview</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The stock market showed positive momentum as Indian benchmarks closed higher for the second consecutive day. The NSE Nifty 50 and BSE Sensex recorded significant gains while foreign portfolio investments resumed after a selling streak.</p>
<ul>
  <li>NSE Nifty 50 closed up 445.75 points (1.88%) at 24,188.65</li>
  <li>BSE Sensex rose by 1,436.30 points (1.83%) to 79,943.71</li>
  <li>Asian markets also saw positive trade with South Korea's Kospi leading gains.</li>
  <li>The Indian Rupee weakened slightly against the US Dollar, closing at 85.75.</li>
  <li>Foreign investors purchased stocks worth approximately Rs 1,506.75 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The NSE Nifty 50 closed 445.75 points or 1.88% up at 24,188.65 and the BSE Sensex ended 1,436.30 points or 1.83% higher at 79,943.71."</blockquote>
<p>This positive trend suggests a bullish outlook for the markets going into the trading session on January 3, 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/stock-market-today-all-you-need-to-know-going-into-trade-on-jan-3-3</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/stock-market-today-all-you-need-to-know-going-into-trade-on-jan-3-3</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jeff Bezos' $500M Yacht hit with surprise raid as Lauren Sánchez's sunbathing gets interrupted by customs officers - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Surprise Customs Check Interrupts Bezos' Yacht Day</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 03, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/ezgif-1-9f21160730_1690609393097_1735862456009.jpg" alt="Jeff Bezos, Lauren Sánchez cuddle and kiss on Italian yacht(laurensanchez/ Instagram)"><figcaption>Jeff Bezos, Lauren Sánchez cuddle and kiss on Italian yacht(laurensanchez/ Instagram)</figcaption><p>While Lauren Sánchez was sunbathing aboard Jeff Bezos' $500 million yacht, customs officers conducted a surprise inspection, causing a brief interruption on New Year's Eve.</p><ul><li>Customs officials boarded the yacht for a routine inspection that lasted approximately three hours.</li><li>Lauren Sánchez appeared unbothered, engaging with friends during the check.</li><li>Jeff Bezos was not present during the customs inspection.</li><li>Speculation about a lavish New Year’s Eve wedding was denied by Bezos.</li></ul><blockquote>“This whole thing is completely false — none of this is happening,” Bezos stated regarding the wedding rumors.</blockquote><p>The unexpected customs check added an unusual twist to what was planned as a luxurious day on the high seas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/jeff-bezos-500m-yacht-hit-with-surprise-raid-as-lauren-s-nchezs-sunbathing-gets-interrupted-by-customs-officers-101735861931474.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/jeff-bezos-500m-yacht-hit-with-surprise-raid-as-lauren-s-nchezs-sunbathing-gets-interrupted-by-customs-officers-101735861931474.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:03:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scamster Ketan Parekh back in Sebi net, banned from market - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ketan Parekh Banned from Market by Sebi</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Ketan Parekh" width="600">
<figcaption>Ketan Parekh, the infamous scamster, has been banned from the market.</figcaption>
<p>Ketan Parekh, a notorious figure in Indian stock market history, has found himself once again in the regulatory spotlight as he faces a ban from the market imposed by the Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi). This development highlights ongoing concerns about market manipulation and investor protection.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Parekh is a key figure in a major stock market scam that erupted in 2001.</li>
  <li>The ban comes amidst efforts by Sebi to clean up the financial markets and safeguard investor interests.</li>
  <li>Parekh is accused of stock price manipulation and fraudulent trading activities.</li>
  <li>This renewed scrutiny raises questions about the integrity of the Indian financial system.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We are committed to ensuring a fair and transparent trading environment in the stock market,” said a Sebi spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>This action against Parekh signals a stricter regulatory approach to market misconduct, aiming to enhance overall market integrity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/scamster-ketan-parekh-back-in-sebi-net-banned-from-market/articleshow/116896158.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/scamster-ketan-parekh-back-in-sebi-net-banned-from-market/articleshow/116896158.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 22:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold climbs to over two-week high on safe-haven demand; Trump's policies in focus - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/gold-nudges-higher-market-awaits-us-data-economic-cues-2025-01-02/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/gold-nudges-higher-market-awaits-us-data-economic-cues-2025-01-02/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:19:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why the US dollar is so strong to start the year - ForexLive]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why the US dollar is so strong to start the year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Forexlive</p><img src="https://images.financemagnates.com/user-profiles/c97fe488-0a4b-4549-9382-1fe0b770a597_size50.jpeg" alt="Adam Button"><figcaption>Adam Button</figcaption><p>The US dollar is the top performer as it surges at the start of 2025, outperforming major currencies like the euro and pound. This performance is driven by strong capital flows toward US assets, with US equity markets vastly outperforming others.</p><ul><li>The US dollar is up more than 1% against the euro and pound.</li><li>The recent economic news included initial jobless claims and soft data on construction spending and manufacturing sentiment.</li><li>Capital flows are the main driver of the dollar's strength, with significant investment occurring in US markets.</li><li>There are risks such as tariffs and fiscal policies that could affect the markets.</li><li>Investors see a big opportunity when markets shift, similar to Argentina's market performance after political changes.</li></ul><blockquote>“The short answer is that right now the US and US companies are not just winning, but they're running up the score.”</blockquote><p>The US dollar's strong performance is a result of sustained capital flows and market dynamics, with potential risks ahead that could impact the trend.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forexlive.com/news/why-the-us-dollar-is-so-strong-to-start-the-year-20250102/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forexlive.com/news/why-the-us-dollar-is-so-strong-to-start-the-year-20250102/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee to marginally depreciate against USD in CY25, outperform many of its peers: Report - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee to marginally depreciate against USD in CY25, outperform many of its peers: Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>The article analyzes the forecast for the Indian Rupee, indicating a slight depreciation against the US Dollar in the calendar year 2025, while also projecting better performance compared to other currencies.</p><ul><li>Forecasted depreciation of Rupee against USD.</li><li>Expected to outperform many peer currencies.</li><li>Factors influencing the currency movements are discussed.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/rupee-to-marginally-depreciate-against-usd-in-cy25-outperform-many-of-its-peers-report/articleshow/116891990.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/rupee-to-marginally-depreciate-against-usd-in-cy25-outperform-many-of-its-peers-report/articleshow/116891990.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to Watch on January 3: Varun Beverages, NHPC, Hindustan Zinc, Wockhardt and more - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to Watch on January 3: Varun Beverages, NHPC, Hindustan Zinc, Wockhardt and More</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="Stock market overview" title="Stocks to Watch" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Overview of key stocks to monitor today</figcaption><p>This article discusses stocks to watch today, including Varun Beverages and NHPC, alongside their recent developments and financial performance.</p><ul><li><strong>Varun Beverages:</strong> Announced a ₹413 crore investment in South African subsidiary Bevco, acquiring an additional 2.42% shareholding.</li><li><strong>NHPC:</strong> Received a ₹250 crore payment under its Mega Insurance Policy following business interruption losses due to a flash flood.</li><li><strong>Hindustan Zinc:</strong> Reported a 2% decrease in mined metal production year-on-year but a 3% increase compared to the previous quarter.</li><li><strong>Wockhardt:</strong> Received CDSCO approval for Miqnaf, a new treatment for Community-Acquired Bacterial Pneumonia.</li><li><strong>Biocon:</strong> Secured approval from the NMPA in China for Tacrolimus capsules used in organ transplant patients.</li><li><strong>Avenue Supermarts:</strong> Reported a 17.5% year-on-year increase in standalone revenue to ₹15,565.23 crore.</li><li><strong>RITES:</strong> Awarded a ₹69.78 crore contract by SAIL for repairs of locomotives.</li><li><strong>Bank of Maharashtra:</strong> Announced a 16.9% year-on-year increase in total business to ₹5.08 lakh crore.</li><li><strong>Pricol:</strong> Approved divestment of its wiping business to Auto Ignition Ltd for ₹20 crore.</li><li><strong>Honasa Consumer:</strong> Chief Business Officer Master Zairus resigned effective February 28, 2025.</li><li><strong>Capital Small Finance Bank:</strong> Reported a 12% increase in total deposits to ₹8,384 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“We aim to strengthen our balance sheet and support future growth,” said Varun Beverages regarding their recent investment.</blockquote><p>This article highlights significant stock movements and news that investors should monitor for informed decision-making in the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/stocks/stocks-to-watch-on-january-3-varun-beverages-nhpc-hindustan-zinc-wockhardt-and-more-19533721.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/stocks/stocks-to-watch-on-january-3-varun-beverages-nhpc-hindustan-zinc-wockhardt-and-more-19533721.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:15:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple to pay $95 million to settle Siri privacy lawsuit - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/legal/apple-pay-95-million-settle-siri-privacy-lawsuit-2025-01-02/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/legal/apple-pay-95-million-settle-siri-privacy-lawsuit-2025-01-02/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:12:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tata Motors share price target 2025: Stock to cheer investors ahead of 1:1 split, demerger? - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxQNTVvSDRxTGVFS1JSZ01VY3FGd2VaLWdXb0hXVWZ6QjJHSEZLR3RuZHIzOUFvaTlnNUhINVpZOWtHTzBTZ2NUNFpxZkRDb3h2dHhMLVdNb3pJTmwwcjU3Y2ZDYkFsbGxNRzRwRW1lNTdWV3dvOHI3VDdSbm9Rd0hUR2YwVFNVdWFRbjdJZEZqSlZpNDI1OUtJZjU0VDdfTTFGT1hfN1lXOFpwTnZwQXc4R2FuTHY2enRvN1F4Z1EzbGJWanhYdENZbXIxQmt0WEZfZGRsMXZ30gHbAUFVX3lxTFBvdkRneGxfd0dYcXZtSVoybGR6blU4aUhFWi1YVmpQY3pJZ0JvSGJPSHkxMnZCRUdkVTBKRmx3b1lUS2tJT2d5WWNNYVRaenhRa2h5S2h6RlFVVk1Qd1lEVzlFOHBPWTZEb3NJSEp4OXdVbVp1ZEplOEpKcDRRVGdVeU1BcDFZNkx2akFFT1N0dGs0Z1hRUFdOZmZfN3ZmQ1lTb3ZIYUIzVWgwNzkxZWFsZml1MnJ5U25JZ2pmR1Rsb1BNTk8ybldfdWpsUWIyYW1tVmQzQ1V0QnZHcw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxQNTVvSDRxTGVFS1JSZ01VY3FGd2VaLWdXb0hXVWZ6QjJHSEZLR3RuZHIzOUFvaTlnNUhINVpZOWtHTzBTZ2NUNFpxZkRDb3h2dHhMLVdNb3pJTmwwcjU3Y2ZDYkFsbGxNRzRwRW1lNTdWV3dvOHI3VDdSbm9Rd0hUR2YwVFNVdWFRbjdJZEZqSlZpNDI1OUtJZjU0VDdfTTFGT1hfN1lXOFpwTnZwQXc4R2FuTHY2enRvN1F4Z1EzbGJWanhYdENZbXIxQmt0WEZfZGRsMXZ30gHbAUFVX3lxTFBvdkRneGxfd0dYcXZtSVoybGR6blU4aUhFWi1YVmpQY3pJZ0JvSGJPSHkxMnZCRUdkVTBKRmx3b1lUS2tJT2d5WWNNYVRaenhRa2h5S2h6RlFVVk1Qd1lEVzlFOHBPWTZEb3NJSEp4OXdVbVp1ZEplOEpKcDRRVGdVeU1BcDFZNkx2akFFT1N0dGs0Z1hRUFdOZmZfN3ZmQ1lTb3ZIYUIzVWgwNzkxZWFsZml1MnJ5U25JZ2pmR1Rsb1BNTk8ybldfdWpsUWIyYW1tVmQzQ1V0QnZHcw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:09:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trade setup for January 3: Top 15 things to know before the opening bell - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trade setup for January 3: Top 15 things to know before the opening bell</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 / 21:52 IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250102155937_Image102012025.jpg" alt="Nifty Trade Setup" title="Nifty Trade Setup" width="770" height="431"></p><figcaption>Nifty Trade Setup</figcaption><p>Bulls staged a strong performance on January 2, helping the Nifty 50 surpass the psychological 24,000 mark with a 446-point gain, marking the biggest single-day gain in the last six weeks.</p><ul><li>Short-term moving averages (10-day and 20-day EMAs) are climbing.</li><li>The Nifty may face resistance at the 24,200-24,250 zone.</li><li>Immediate support levels are at 24,900 and 24,700.</li><li>Overall momentum has strengthened, but some consolidation may occur before further gains.</li></ul><blockquote>“The momentum has definitely strengthened.”</blockquote><p>The article highlights key levels to watch for potential profitable trades in the Nifty 50.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/trade-setup-for-january-3-top-15-things-to-know-before-the-opening-bell-12902426.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/trade-setup-for-january-3-top-15-things-to-know-before-the-opening-bell-12902426.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:06:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hindenburg Research claims used-car dealer Carvana's involvement in $800 million loan sales undisclosed transactions | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hindenburg Research Accuses Carvana of $800 Million Loan Misconduct</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 2, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>US-based short seller Hindenburg Research has alleged that Carvana Co., an online car dealer, engaged in $800 million of loan sales involving undisclosed related party transactions. Following the report's release, Carvana's stock dropped nearly 5%.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Hindenburg's report claims $800 million in undisclosed loan sales by Carvana.</li><li>The report suggests accounting manipulation and lax underwriting practices.</li><li>Despite bankruptcy risks in previous years, Carvana's stock surged 284% in 2024.</li><li>Used vehicle prices have dropped 20.3% over the past three years, creating significant headwinds for Carvana.</li><li>The company's solvency is questioned due to insider stock unloading.</li></ul><blockquote>“For every $1 in net income it reported, the company has added $139 in market cap – a $34 billion market cap increase,” Hindenburg alleged.</blockquote><p>Hindenburg Research has established a short position in Carvana shares, projecting serious concerns regarding the company's financial practices and future viability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/hindenburg-research-alleges-800-million-loan-sales-by-carvana-to-undisclosed-related-party-11735832465065.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/hindenburg-research-alleges-800-million-loan-sales-by-carvana-to-undisclosed-related-party-11735832465065.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:48:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sebi bans Ketan Parekh, 2 others from markets in front-running scam, impounds Rs 65 crore - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sebi Bans Ketan Parekh and Associates in Front-Running Scam, Seizes ₹65 Crore</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Thursday | <strong>Source:</strong> The Economic Times</p><figure><img height="158" width="210" alt="Sebi bans Ketan Parekh, 2 others from markets in front-running scam, impounds Rs 65 crore" src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116891308,width-210,height-158,imgsize-27670,resizemode-75/sebi-bans-ketan-parekh-2-others-from-markets-in-front-running-scam-impounds-rs-65-crore.jpg"><figcaption>ET Bureau &amp; Agencies</figcaption></figure><p>The Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi) has barred Ketan Parekh and Rohit Salgaocar from the Indian capital markets due to their involvement in a front-running scam, resulting in the impounding of ₹65.77 crore.</p><ul><li>Ketan Parekh, known for his role in the 2001 stock scam, faces renewed restrictions.</li><li>Sebi's investigation revealed unlawful gains earned through front-running activities.</li><li>The accused exploited non-public information related to a foreign portfolio investment.</li></ul><blockquote>"Noticees no. 1 and 2 i.e. Rohit Salgaocar and Ketan Parekh devised the entire scheme to unjustly enrich from the NPI pertaining to the Big Client by orchestrating front running activities." - Sebi's Order</blockquote><p>The ruling emphasizes the importance of regulatory oversight in preventing similar fraudulent activities in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/sebi-bans-ketan-parekh-2-others-from-markets-in-front-running-scam-impounds-rs-65-crore/articleshow/116891317.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/sebi-bans-ketan-parekh-2-others-from-markets-in-front-running-scam-impounds-rs-65-crore/articleshow/116891317.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:47:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Market Trading Guide: Welspun Corp, BLS International are stock recommendations for Friday - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxNZGRodzdSTjBRandlVENleGROZ19QRnNsbnBMbjY4NXlsMUpwalF6TGFpT2VHNWZ1NHhBUEowQUlaZWFmdWx2ZXBPbGJONFNkRVZHaGoxS3hKVjhYM3lseFpJYmNySXktZlB2YmRsQzRvc3pjdmNXYmItWkI0Z0ZuUzhLN3JBajNqRktCZlBFNF9wem8zQVRDX0syemkwUGdQOWVZWlBMTURIZXRSUzdrME4zMU9jcWZadUpjbEZLQW1MQURwQl9CU3gzbG0zeXhhbzJoUzFYUW5ZdEIzdXhkM2RQby1CUmM1aXdGRzJRVE50dklrM05HQU9QTHI5Uy1jT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxNZGRodzdSTjBRandlVENleGROZ19QRnNsbnBMbjY4NXlsMUpwalF6TGFpT2VHNWZ1NHhBUEowQUlaZWFmdWx2ZXBPbGJONFNkRVZHaGoxS3hKVjhYM3lseFpJYmNySXktZlB2YmRsQzRvc3pjdmNXYmItWkI0Z0ZuUzhLN3JBajNqRktCZlBFNF9wem8zQVRDX0syemkwUGdQOWVZWlBMTURIZXRSUzdrME4zMU9jcWZadUpjbEZLQW1MQURwQl9CU3gzbG0zeXhhbzJoUzFYUW5ZdEIzdXhkM2RQby1CUmM1aXdGRzJRVE50dklrM05HQU9QTHI5Uy1jT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:46:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Solana and XRP Surge as Dogecoin and Bitcoin Hit Weekly Highs - Decrypt]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Solana and XRP Surge as Dogecoin and Bitcoin Hit Weekly Highs</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Decrypt</p><p>Major cryptocurrencies including Solana and XRP are experiencing significant gains as Bitcoin and Dogecoin reach weekly highs.</p><img src="https://example.com/path/to/image.jpg" alt="Cryptocurrency Surge" /><figcaption>Major cryptocurrencies on the rise.</figcaption><p>In the past day, Solana has increased by 10%, reaching $209, while XRP has climbed 11% to $2.41. Bitcoin has surged above $97,000, boosting the market.</p><ul><li>Solana (SOL) is up 10% to $209, marking its highest price since December 19.</li><li>XRP is up 11% to $2.41, touching a peak of $2.44 earlier.</li><li>Dogecoin rises to $0.34, up more than 7% on the day.</li><li>Bitcoin climbs above the $97,000 mark, up 3.5% in 24 hours.</li><li>Fartcoin sees a massive spike of 47% to $1.40.</li></ul><blockquote>“Many have liquidated both traditional and crypto assets to offset tax gains,” said Isaac Joshua, CEO of Gems.</blockquote><p>The recent spikes in these cryptocurrencies reflect a positive momentum in the market, likely driven by Bitcoin's recovery.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://decrypt.co/299328/solana-xrp-surge-dogecoin-bitcoin-weekly-highs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://decrypt.co/299328/solana-xrp-surge-dogecoin-bitcoin-weekly-highs</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:30:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NHPC gets ₹250 crore payment under Mega Insurance Policy for Teesta-V power station loss - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/stocks/nhpc-share-price-gets-rs-250-crore-payment-under-mega-insurance-policy-for-teesta-v-power-station-loss-19533680.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/stocks/nhpc-share-price-gets-rs-250-crore-payment-under-mega-insurance-policy-for-teesta-v-power-station-loss-19533680.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:10:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video | Asia Shares Fall | Maruti, Mahindra Boost December Car Sales In India| The World Report - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxOeEtBWEJVUU43Ty0wR1Y4bEZ6VloteEFMRXpidl9meGVKRzdHN1h0RjVlRDdFTnllTFJDWE5RVUlwaF9MRVQ0WG9PTW0wSEozbXEwVGVVUDJjUURhOE1UZ0pmT003M21ldFdDMnFOT2FGbncwRDByWkVoV3JIUXRiTnZkenh2eGpIZ2g0ZjRRSldoWEVwVmpwT0s1NkI4Zlp5RDE2QkdEQUR6eUxQRVl6WnVqUWJFRjhM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxOeEtBWEJVUU43Ty0wR1Y4bEZ6VloteEFMRXpidl9meGVKRzdHN1h0RjVlRDdFTnllTFJDWE5RVUlwaF9MRVQ0WG9PTW0wSEozbXEwVGVVUDJjUURhOE1UZ0pmT003M21ldFdDMnFOT2FGbncwRDByWkVoV3JIUXRiTnZkenh2eGpIZ2g0ZjRRSldoWEVwVmpwT0s1NkI4Zlp5RDE2QkdEQUR6eUxQRVl6WnVqUWJFRjhM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tesla deliveries miss expectations, stock drops - Investing.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tesla Stock Falls 7% Following Lower-Than-Expected Q4 Deliveries</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Investing.com</p>
<p>Tesla reported record vehicle deliveries but fell short of market expectations, leading to a significant drop in stock prices.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Tesla delivered 495,570 vehicles in Q4, below the expected 512,277.</li>
  <li>Shares fell over 7% at market open after the announcement.</li>
  <li>In 2023, Tesla delivered a total of 1.79 million vehicles, marking a decline in annual EV sales for the first time in over a decade.</li>
  <li>Energy storage deployments reached a total of 31.4 GWh for the year.</li>
  <li>Tesla plans to release its Q4 2024 financial results on January 29, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Overall, we would characterize this is a respectable delivery number although the Street and bulls wanted to see a 500k+ number and the stock will be a bit weak on the knee-jerk reaction." - Wedbush</blockquote>
<p>The report highlights challenges Tesla faces in meeting investor expectations despite strong overall performance and ambitious growth plans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/tesla-deliveries-miss-expectations-stock-drops-3794114</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/tesla-deliveries-miss-expectations-stock-drops-3794114</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:38:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sebi clubs fund diversion, disclosure violation probes against ZEE, Punit Goenka and Subhash Chandra | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sebi Combines Probes Against ZEE, Punit Goenka, and Subhash Chandra</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi) has consolidated ongoing investigations into Zee Entertainment Enterprises Ltd (ZEEL) and its executives over allegations of fund diversion and disclosure violations.</p><ul><li>Sebi has clubbed investigations against ZEEL, CEO Punit Goenka, and former chairman Subhash Chandra.</li><li>Allegations include failure to comply with listing regulations and corporate governance violations.</li><li>A show-cause notice was issued in July 2022, questioning the actions of the involved parties.</li><li>Settlement applications filed by Zee and Goenka were rejected in April 2023, leading to further investigations.</li><li>An interim order barred Chandra and Goenka from holding key positions in listed companies amid the allegations.</li><li>Sebi's investigations into LODR violations will now be included in the funds diversion probe.</li><li>The proceeding against the company and executives were dropped to avoid multiplicity of cases.</li></ul><blockquote>“The allegations in the show-cause notice of 6 July 2022 issued by the adjudicating officer are to be subsumed with the findings of the further investigation carried out by SEBI in the instant (funds diversion) matter.”</blockquote><p>This development is significant as it centralizes the investigation process and streamlines legal proceedings within the corporate governance framework.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/sebi-zee-punit-goenka-subhash-chandra-fund-diversion-disclosure-violation-investigations-11735824784831.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/sebi-zee-punit-goenka-subhash-chandra-fund-diversion-disclosure-violation-investigations-11735824784831.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:22:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Indian CEO Is The Highest-Paid Employee In The World; This Is His Salary... - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jagdeep Singh: The Highest-Paid CEO in the World</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2025/01/untitled-design-40-2025-01-413fbbd5fa3cff053e46553e9c804c93.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Jagdeep Singh founded Quantumscape, a leading electric car battery developer." />
<figcaption>Jagdeep Singh founded Quantumscape, a leading electric car battery developer.</figcaption>
<p>Jagdeep Singh holds the title for the highest annual salary in the world at Rs 17,500 crore, with earnings that reflect his significant impact on the evolving landscape of wealth and technology.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Singh earns an astonishing Rs 48 crore per day, surpassing the annual revenue of many corporations.</li>
  <li>He is the founder of Quantumscape, a leader in electric car battery technology.</li>
  <li>Singh's monthly income stands at Rs 1,459 crore, setting a new benchmark for salary globally.</li>
  <li>His academic background includes a B.Tech from Stanford University and an MBA from the University of California.</li>
  <li>Quantumscape is driving innovations in electric vehicle technology, contributing to sustainable transportation.</li>
  <li>Singh's journey from an employee to a CEO exemplifies the potential of entrepreneurship and innovation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Singh is King,” reflecting the pride in his achievement as the highest-paid employee worldwide.</blockquote>
<p>Jagdeep Singh’s story serves as an inspiration for aspiring entrepreneurs, highlighting the intersection of technology, opportunity, and financial success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/this-indian-ceo-is-the-highest-paid-employee-in-the-world-this-is-his-salary-ws-ab-9175104.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/this-indian-ceo-is-the-highest-paid-employee-in-the-world-this-is-his-salary-ws-ab-9175104.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:09:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indo Farm Equipment IPO Day 3 Live Updates: Issue subscribed 229.68 times on third day; check latest GMP | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indo Farm Equipment IPO Day 3 Live Updates: Issue Subscribed 229.68 Times</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 02 Jan, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> LiveMint</p><figure><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2025/01/02/600x338/pexels-photo-8064065_1735288947424_1735783688453.jpeg" alt="Indo Farm Equipment IPO Day 3 Live Updates" title="Indo Farm Equipment IPO enters the third and last day of the bidding process today."><figcaption>Indo Farm Equipment IPO enters the third and last day of the bidding process today.</figcaption></figure><p>The Indo Farm Equipment IPO saw exceptional demand, closing with an oversubscription of over 229 times on the final day of bidding. This article provides the details and implications of the IPO, which aims to raise significant capital for business expansion and debt reduction.</p><ul><li>IPO subscription was strong, with bids for 1.94 billion shares against 847,000 shares on offer.</li><li>The price band for the IPO is set between ₹204 and ₹215 per share, targeting to raise ₹260.15 crore.</li><li>The QIB segment attracted a subscription of 242.40 times, while NII was subscribed 503.83 times.</li><li>Indo Farm Equipment's strategic plans include expanding production capacity and reducing debt.</li></ul><blockquote>“At the upper end of the price band, the company aims to raise ₹260.15 crore from the book-built issue.”</blockquote><p>This IPO is seen as a strong investment opportunity, backed by the company’s growth strategy and market position.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-day-3-live-updates-indo-farm-equipment-ipo-gmp-subscription-status-price-band-apply-or-not-11735783633123.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-day-3-live-updates-indo-farm-equipment-ipo-gmp-subscription-status-price-band-apply-or-not-11735783633123.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:53:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TVS Motors report 7% gain for December FY25, EV boasts 79% - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/tvs-motors-report-7-gain-for-december-fy25-ev-boasts-79/articleshow/116888631.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/tvs-motors-report-7-gain-for-december-fy25-ev-boasts-79/articleshow/116888631.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blinkit launches 10-minute ambulance service in Gurugram, to expand across major cities in 2 years - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Blinkit Launches 10-Minute Ambulance Service in Gurugram</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Thursday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Blinkit</p>
<p>Blinkit has introduced a 10-minute ambulance service in select areas of Gurugram, marking its entry into the healthcare space.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Five ambulances equipped with Basic Life Support (BLS) systems deployed.</li>
  <li>Users can book ambulances via the Blinkit app.</li>
  <li>The service is designed to be affordable and not profit-driven.</li>
  <li>Company aims to expand to all major cities in the next two years.</li>
  <li>Ambulances are equipped with essential life-saving equipment and staffed for emergency care.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Profit is not a goal here. We will operate this service at an affordable cost for customers.” - Albinder Dhindsa</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Blinkit's new ambulance service aims to address a critical urban challenge while ensuring quick and reliable emergency healthcare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/business-news/latest-updates/zomato-s-blinkit-launches-10-minute-ambulance-service-in-gurugram/article-138496/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/business-news/latest-updates/zomato-s-blinkit-launches-10-minute-ambulance-service-in-gurugram/article-138496/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:22:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indo Farm Equipment IPO subscribed 229.31x on Day 3; Check latest GMP, subscription status, other details | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indo Farm Equipment IPO Subscribed 229.31x on Final Day</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>The initial public offering (IPO) of Indo Farm Equipment witnessed an extraordinary response, being oversubscribed by 229.31 times on its final bidding day.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The IPO opened on December 31 and closed on January 2, 2023.</li>
  <li>Investors bid for 194,221,841 shares against 8,470,000 shares available.</li>
  <li>Non-Institutional Investors led the subscriptions at 503.39 times, followed by Qualified Institutional Buyers at 242.40 times, and Retail Investors at 104.36 times.</li>
  <li>The IPO raised ₹78 crore from anchor investors prior to the public issue.</li>
  <li>The grey market premium (GMP) is currently ₹96 per share.</li>
  <li>Proceeds will be used for loan repayment, expansion of manufacturing capacity, and investment in their NBFC subsidiary.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Indo Farm Equipment IPO Latest GMP</h2>
<p>The grey market premium (GMP) reflects investor sentiment, indicating a listing price around ₹311, representing a premium of 44.65% over the upper price band of ₹215.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“As of January 2, the grey market premium (GMP) of Indo Farm Equipment stands at ₹96 per share.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This IPO is expected to list on the stock market on January 7, 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> The views and recommendations given in this article are those of individual analysts and do not represent the views of Mint. Consult certified experts before making investment decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-subscribed-229-31-times-check-latest-gmp-subscription-status-other-details-11735822685562.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-subscribed-229-31-times-check-latest-gmp-subscription-status-other-details-11735822685562.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:19:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ketan Parekh strikes again! SEBI unearths unusual front-running scam, impounds Rs 65.77 crore - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ketan Parekh strikes again! SEBI unearths unusual front-running scam, impounds Rs 65.77 crore</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2022/11/gavel-3575414_960_720-770x424.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431' alt='SEBI Investigation' width='770' height='431'><figcaption>In an order issued on January 2, the Securities and Exchange Board of India detailed the investigation that spanned over 20 locations</figcaption><p>The market regulator has uncovered a significant front-running scam involving Ketan Parekh, leading to the impounding of Rs 65.77 crore.</p><ul><li>SEBI issued an interim order detailing the investigation conducted across over 20 locations.</li><li>The order was passed against 22 involved entities.</li><li>Ketan Parekh, previously imprisoned for a similar scam, is involved along with trader Rohit Salgaocar.</li><li>The investigation revealed tactics to unjustly enrich from trading activities.</li><li>Individuals involved have been previously prohibited from trading in securities.</li></ul><blockquote>“Noticees no. 1 and 2 ... devised the entire scheme to unjustly enrich from the NPI pertaining to the Big Client by orchestrating front running activities.” - SEBI's Whole-time Member Kamlesh Varshney</blockquote><p>This investigation marks another chapter in Ketan Parekh's controversial history in the Indian securities market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/ketan-parekh-strikes-again-sebi-unearths-unusual-front-running-scam-impounds-rs-65-77-crore-12902368.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/ketan-parekh-strikes-again-sebi-unearths-unusual-front-running-scam-impounds-rs-65-77-crore-12902368.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:14:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breakout Stocks: How to trade Eicher Motors, PB Fintech & Ipca Laboratories on Friday - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxPNWZoRHBiR0I4dmtDSXZESmRYLVJkc09Qa1VxYkhZaXRwVGhrV0ttRFJPbWFlZlVsU1FfTXlnMGExc0c4dTh3dEdUR2c2R3kyUE1teXFZeThkOWpFdjRNWGNDZG4yMHJ5bTZ4V2JGVEJKUlc1bjYwYXNVOFpVd1I3MkxaRVB5WGRZOWVuYjdFQm0xLUhtTU9iZ0xLT1NDRUtVYmEtbVBiWTVRR0dPUXR0RG1ua3RuRDUwNUx4bWZvQ3R2eVhTaGNoVjlIS2lQRXFFU0hHUU1NbmhXV1JlRktLbTVCdjZKVEM5d3NRQlJBbnU4ajRfcFE1Yl9ETVZJQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxPNWZoRHBiR0I4dmtDSXZESmRYLVJkc09Qa1VxYkhZaXRwVGhrV0ttRFJPbWFlZlVsU1FfTXlnMGExc0c4dTh3dEdUR2c2R3kyUE1teXFZeThkOWpFdjRNWGNDZG4yMHJ5bTZ4V2JGVEJKUlc1bjYwYXNVOFpVd1I3MkxaRVB5WGRZOWVuYjdFQm0xLUhtTU9iZ0xLT1NDRUtVYmEtbVBiWTVRR0dPUXR0RG1ua3RuRDUwNUx4bWZvQ3R2eVhTaGNoVjlIS2lQRXFFU0hHUU1NbmhXV1JlRktLbTVCdjZKVEM5d3NRQlJBbnU4ajRfcFE1Yl9ETVZJQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:11:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyundai Creta Electric With 473KM Claimed Range, Active Air Flaps Unveiled in India: Features, Launch Dat... - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQcU1WeTU4LXJmLUtLQUlsaWFaUG9HRjViRjZCZzQwajFZV3NIWWhMZ0V5X052T0p2dVRmQWFDMk84SmNCaW5ocWo0Y2RVSnBXTWd5MG1kNHNrMEdQdjJUazMzcVM0dnoxLUdHdk54eThURVlha25Bbm4zWWdlMUdEWEIxTDlWSG5TN1pqcE0wS1JnN3BmQTZ1LU54N3RBVE1nQlQ4RlZ3MNIBrAFBVV95cUxNY0VZQTl4NFlwUXVFTnljRmE2MWpvNm1ydElBZ1B4T0RSTnZ4dEV2N1MxMWZQNS1Vb04tSzZ3eDJSbF9SSG85MHhuazYtcjlaZEliX1BGUlVNaHJaLWxhc2JGT1ByOUtueU93MFIwYUpnS1E5cVE2UGpsem9fYlE4Y25DaG8yaWZTWVNlWWNEcmtKSGZqNUVURHk4MUNVMEp5VXBzX1hTOVRWa3Nf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQcU1WeTU4LXJmLUtLQUlsaWFaUG9HRjViRjZCZzQwajFZV3NIWWhMZ0V5X052T0p2dVRmQWFDMk84SmNCaW5ocWo0Y2RVSnBXTWd5MG1kNHNrMEdQdjJUazMzcVM0dnoxLUdHdk54eThURVlha25Bbm4zWWdlMUdEWEIxTDlWSG5TN1pqcE0wS1JnN3BmQTZ1LU54N3RBVE1nQlQ4RlZ3MNIBrAFBVV95cUxNY0VZQTl4NFlwUXVFTnljRmE2MWpvNm1ydElBZ1B4T0RSTnZ4dEV2N1MxMWZQNS1Vb04tSzZ3eDJSbF9SSG85MHhuazYtcjlaZEliX1BGUlVNaHJaLWxhc2JGT1ByOUtueU93MFIwYUpnS1E5cVE2UGpsem9fYlE4Y25DaG8yaWZTWVNlWWNEcmtKSGZqNUVURHk4MUNVMEp5VXBzX1hTOVRWa3Nf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:53:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mutual Funds: Why passive funds can be a great choice for retail investors to invest in 2025? | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why Passive Mutual Funds Are Ideal for Retail Investors in 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>If you're considering investing in mutual funds this year, you'll face a choice between active and passive funds. With the volatility in the benchmark index, passive funds present a promising option for growth.</p>
<img src='https://www.example.com/image.jpg' alt='Investment Growth' />
<figcaption>Investment Strategies in 2025</figcaption>
<ul>
  <li>The Sebi has introduced a mutual fund lite framework to enhance passive fund options.</li>
  <li>Passive schemes follow benchmarks, offering predictable returns compared to active funds.</li>
  <li>Data shows that a significant percentage of active funds have underperformed in recent years.</li>
  <li>Investors are increasingly leaning towards cost-effective passive options.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Sebi's Lite framework provides a good opportunity for investors to invest in passive funds,” says Sridharan S., investment advisor.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, as more investors recognize the challenges of active funds, passive mutual funds are becoming an attractive and straightforward choice for retail investors in 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/mutual-funds-why-passive-funds-can-be-a-great-choice-for-retail-investors-to-invest-in-2025-11735818079399.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/mutual-funds-why-passive-funds-can-be-a-great-choice-for-retail-investors-to-invest-in-2025-11735818079399.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:47:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avenue Supermarts reports 17.5% growth in Q3 revenue - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Avenue Supermarts Reports 17.5% Revenue Growth in Q3 FY25</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Avenue Supermarts reports 17.5% growth in Q3 revenue" title="Avenue Supermarts reports 17.5% growth in Q3 revenue" width="640" height="360" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Avenue Supermarts reports 17.5% growth in Q3 revenue</figcaption><p>Avenue Supermarts Ltd, which operates the D-Mart retail chain, has reported significant growth in its third-quarter revenues, highlighting strong operational performance.</p><ul><li>Standalone revenue for Q3 FY25 reached ₹15,565.23 crore, a 17.5% increase year-on-year.</li><li>The company had 387 stores operational as of December 31, 2024.</li><li>Net profit in Q2 FY25 was ₹710 crore, representing a 7.9% increase over last year.</li><li>EBITDA for Q2 FY25 was ₹1,105 crore with a margin of 7.9%.</li><li>Basic earnings per share for Q2 FY25 were ₹10.92, compared to ₹10.12 in Q2 FY24.</li></ul><blockquote>“The firm's total revenue for the first six months of FY25 has risen to ₹27,762 crore, up from ₹23,892 crore last year.”</blockquote><p>The financial results demonstrate Avenue Supermarts' resilience and growth, positioning it strongly in the competitive retail sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/stocks/d-mart-avenue-supermarts-share-price-reports-17-5-growth-in-q3-revenue-19533561.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/stocks/d-mart-avenue-supermarts-share-price-reports-17-5-growth-in-q3-revenue-19533561.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:43:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>