<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:17:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:17:35 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold sets forth winning streak with Trump considering emergency tariffs and Fed Minutes ahead - FXStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Prices Rise Amid Economic Uncertainty from Trump and Fed Minutes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> FXStreet</p><img alt="XAU/USD: Daily Chart" src="https://editorial.fxsstatic.com/miscelaneous/_XAU_USD_2025-01-08_11-43-55-638719355282965417.png"><figcaption>XAU/USD: Daily Chart</figcaption><p>Gold prices continue their upward momentum, supported by rising yields and geopolitical dynamics, as President-elect Donald Trump considers enacting emergency tariffs.</p><ul><li>Gold prices have increased for the second consecutive day driven by economic news.</li><li>Trump is contemplating a national economic emergency to implement universal tariffs.</li><li>The ISM Services Prices Paid index has surged, influencing gold market behavior.</li><li>Key economic indicators are expected from the Federal Open Market Committee.</li></ul><blockquote>“I believe inflation will continue to cool toward the central bank’s 2% target.” – Christopher J. Waller, Federal Reserve Board Member.</blockquote><p>The current trends in gold pricing reflect not just market behaviors but also the anticipated actions of the incoming president, indicating a volatile economic landscape ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-tests-resistance-while-us-yields-sprint-higher-202501081219</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-tests-resistance-while-us-yields-sprint-higher-202501081219</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:25:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trade Setup for January 9: Nifty bulls see a ray of hope after defending 23,500 ahead of TCS results - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nifty Index Shows Resilience at 23,500 Mark Ahead of TCS Earnings</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 9, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/uploads/2025/01/fiis-diis-2025-01-b1a71719b97a687b86f6049efc0db566.jpeg?im=Resize,width=360,aspect=fit,type=normal" alt="Nifty Cues" width="962" height="541"><figcaption>Nifty Index Trading Insights</figcaption><p>The Nifty 50 index bounced back from lows after a sluggish start, managing to hold 23,500. The market sentiment remains cautious amidst global pressures.</p><ul><li>The index fell initially but recovered to close down by only 19 points at 23,689.</li><li>Global cues and disappointing US job reports led to selling in broader markets.</li><li>Reliance Industries and IT stocks supported the index, with IT sector recovering significantly.</li><li>Important earnings season kicks off with TCS results expected soon, despite ongoing challenges.</li><li>Foreign institutional investors (FIIs) were net sellers, offloading significant equity shares.</li><li>Technical analysts suggest the Nifty's short-term trend is weak, but a closure above key resistance levels could signal a potential recovery.</li></ul><blockquote>"Despite adverse global cues, managing to defend the 23,500 level provides comfort to bulls," – Market Analyst</blockquote><p>Overall, while immediate challenges remain, there's cautious optimism with opportunities for recovery if key levels hold.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/trade-setup-for-january-9-nifty-bulls-see-a-ray-of-hope-after-defending-23500-ahead-of-tcs-results-19536798.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/trade-setup-for-january-9-nifty-bulls-see-a-ray-of-hope-after-defending-23500-ahead-of-tcs-results-19536798.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:00:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingfisher beer maker UB suspends supply to Telangana; association alleges state pays 90% less than other states - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kingfisher beer maker UB suspends supply to Telangana; association alleges state pays 90% less than other states</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>BSE-listed United Breweries Ltd (UBL) has suspended beer supplies to Telangana due to ongoing operating losses. The company states that there has been no price revision for its products since FY20, leading to unsustainable operations.</p><ul><li>UBL attributes the supply suspension to the Telangana government not adjusting beer prices to offset production costs which have risen by 35-40% since 2019.</li><li>The prices per case in Telangana are reported to be 90% lower than in other states, ranging from ₹290-315 compared to ₹550-600 in Karnataka.</li><li>The Brewers Association of India (BAI) has made multiple appeals to the Telangana government for price hikes to alleviate the situation without success.</li><li>UB has a 70% market share in Telangana and contributes significantly to the state revenue.</li></ul><blockquote>“Businesses will find it harder to continue, and state governments need to understand what manufacturers are going through.” - Prem Dewan, Chairman, Devans Modern Breweries</blockquote><p>The decision is expected to lead to a short-term loss in market share but could have long-term positive ramifications if price negotiations advance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/kingfisher-beer-maker-ub-suspends-supply-to-telangana-association-alleges-state-pays-90-less-than-other-states-11736337125044.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/kingfisher-beer-maker-ub-suspends-supply-to-telangana-association-alleges-state-pays-90-less-than-other-states-11736337125044.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Casagrand Premier Builder receives Sebi nod to launch ₹1,100 crore IPO | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Casagrand Premier Builder receives SEBI approval for ₹1,100 crore IPO</h1><p><strong>Date: December 31, 2024; Source: Live Mint</strong></p><p>Chennai-based residential real estate developer Casagrand Premier Builder has received approval from the Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) to launch an initial public offering (IPO).</p><ol><li>The IPO consists of a fresh share sale of up to ₹1,000 crore and an offer for sale (OFS) of up to ₹100 crore.</li><li>The proceeds will be used to repay outstanding borrowings and for general corporate purposes.</li><li>Casagrand Premier Builder had a market share of approximately 24% in launches and 20% in demand for the period from January 1, 2017, to March 31, 2024.</li><li>Its revenue grew from ₹1,876.82 crore in FY 2022 to ₹2,613.99 crore in FY 2024, reflecting a CAGR of 18.02%.</li></ol><blockquote>“The profit after tax surged from ₹146.08 crore to ₹256.95 crore, reflecting a CAGR of 32.63%.”</blockquote><p>This IPO will support the company's growth and expansion in the residential real estate market of Chennai.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/casagrand-premier-builder-receives-sebi-nod-to-launch-rs-1-100-crore-ipo-11736338597700.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/casagrand-premier-builder-receives-sebi-nod-to-launch-rs-1-100-crore-ipo-11736338597700.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:23:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold supported while US yields hit fresh nine-month high - FXStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold Heads Higher with Tariff Uncertainty Shaking Up Markets Again Ahead of Fed Minutes</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> FXStreet</p>
<img src="https://editorial.fxsstatic.com/miscelaneous/_XAU_USD_2025-01-08_11-43-55-638719355282965417.png" alt="XAU/USD: Daily Chart">
<figcaption>XAU/USD: Daily Chart</figcaption>
<p>Gold prices continue to rise as tariff uncertainties loom with President-elect Donald Trump considering an economic state of emergency. The market is also awaiting insights from the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) Minutes.</p>
<ul>
<li>Gold price gaining for the second consecutive day, around the technical level of $2,655.</li>
<li>Trump's potential global tariffs contributing to market tremors.</li>
<li>ISM Services Prices Paid index increased to a significant 64.4.</li>
<li>Upcoming FOMC Minutes to provide insights into interest rate changes.</li>
<li>Technical analysis shows Gold testing critical resistance levels.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Inflation will continue to cool toward the central bank’s 2% target, prompting support for additional interest-rate cuts this year." - Christopher J. Waller, Federal Reserve Board Member</blockquote>
<p>The market remains sensitive to geopolitical and economic factors, with Gold's safe-haven appeal likely to increase amid uncertainty.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-tests-resistance-while-us-yields-sprint-higher-202501081219</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-tests-resistance-while-us-yields-sprint-higher-202501081219</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:19:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyundai Venue 1.2 MT engine variants get updates for 2025 - CarWale]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxOeU5aazBBMEhjTVVQNEd6TVF5d0poV3c1cDhWb1pleWtWWllVMXNKY3E2NVIxaHR4b3ItT194a1dPWllXMWZGOExLLVZ1UUxlWDBKS2dHeks0UWtBVVNZc0RXMmZxOU1JWXo3RWJCM1AzUTJmRHlnM2ktTllnQ0JUQzlkcFk0b2pGakVXbmhNWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxOeU5aazBBMEhjTVVQNEd6TVF5d0poV3c1cDhWb1pleWtWWllVMXNKY3E2NVIxaHR4b3ItT194a1dPWllXMWZGOExLLVZ1UUxlWDBKS2dHeks0UWtBVVNZc0RXMmZxOU1JWXo3RWJCM1AzUTJmRHlnM2ktTllnQ0JUQzlkcFk0b2pGakVXbmhNWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:17:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingfisher and Heineken beer will no longer be available in Telangana as UB suspends beer supplies with immediate effect - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kingfisher and Heineken Beer Supplies Halted in Telangana by United Breweries</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/pskpoa/article69076603.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/183341783" alt="United Breweries Limited (UBL) announced on Wednesday (January 8, 2024) that it has decided to halt beer supplies to the Telangana Beverages Corporation Limited (TGBCL) with immediate effect." title="United Breweries Limited (UBL) announced on Wednesday (January 8, 2024) that it has decided to halt beer supplies to the Telangana Beverages Corporation Limited (TGBCL) with immediate effect."><figcaption>Photo Credit: Getty Images</figcaption></img><p>United Breweries Limited (UBL) has announced that it will cease beer supplies to the Telangana Beverages Corporation Limited (TGBCL), citing financial losses and operational challenges within the state's brewing industry.</p><ul><li>Kingfisher and Heineken will no longer be available in Telangana.</li><li>The halt in supply is attributed to severe operating losses and stagnant base prices over two years.</li><li>UBL highlighted that rising costs and overdue payments from TGBCL contributed to its decision.</li><li>The Brewers Association of India has called on the government to address industry concerns.</li><li>UBL is committed to supporting its employees during this transition.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite our continuous efforts, there has been no increase in base prices, resulting in escalating losses. With each beer sold at a loss, continuing our operations in the State has become unsustainable.” - United Breweries Limited</blockquote><p>UBL has urged the Telangana government to take immediate steps to resolve the issues affecting the brewing industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/kingfisher-and-heineken-beer-will-no-longer-be-available-in-telangana-as-ub-suspends-beer-supplies-with-immediate-effect/article69076132.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/kingfisher-and-heineken-beer-will-no-longer-be-available-in-telangana-as-ub-suspends-beer-supplies-with-immediate-effect/article69076132.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyundai Grand i10 Nios, Venue, And Verna Receive New Variants And Features As Part Of MY25 Updates - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hyundai Grand i10 Nios, Hyundai Verna, And Hyundai Venue Get New Variants And Features, Prices Revised By Up To Rs 36,000</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> CarDekho.com</p><img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/677e6c1f75479.jpg" alt="Hyundai Grand i10 Nios, Venue, And Verna Receive New Variants And Features As Part Of MY25 Updates"><figcaption>Hyundai Grand i10 Nios, Venue, And Verna Receive New Variants And Features As Part Of MY25 Updates</figcaption><p>The year 2025 has begun with Hyundai introducing model-year updates for the Grand i10 Nios, Venue, and Verna. These updates bring new variants with added features and adjustments in pricing, particularly for the turbo-petrol DCT variant of the Verna.</p><ul><li>The Grand i10 Nios receives a new mid-spec Sportz (O) variant with enhanced features and increased pricing.</li><li>The Venue now includes a new SX Executive variant and updated features across existing trims, leading to minor price hikes.</li><li>The Verna introduces new automatic variants at reduced prices, enhancing accessibility for consumers.</li></ul><blockquote>“The newly introduced S(O) turbo DCT variant of the Verna is Rs 91,000 more affordable than the previously available SX turbo DCT variant.”</blockquote><p>These updates aim to enhance competitiveness in the market while providing consumers with more options and features in the Hyundai lineup.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/hyundai-grand-i10-nios-venue-and-verna-receive-new-variants-and-features-as-part-of-my25-updates-33796.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/hyundai-grand-i10-nios-venue-and-verna-receive-new-variants-and-features-as-part-of-my25-updates-33796.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US President-elect Trump considering economic emergency declaration to allow for new tariff program – CNN - FXStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Considers Economic Emergency Declaration for New Tariff Program</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p><p>US President-elect Donald Trump is contemplating a national economic emergency declaration to enable a new tariff program, as reported by CNN citing multiple sources.</p><h2>Market Reaction</h2><p>The USD is gaining strength against other currencies following this news, with the USD Index rising by 0.62% to 109.35.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Trump is considering using the International Economic Emergency Powers Act (IEEPA) for the tariff program.</li><li>This act allows the president to manage imports during a national emergency.</li><li>The declaration and its implications have caused a positive reaction in the US Dollar market.</li></ul><blockquote>“The declaration would allow Trump to construct a new tariff program by using the International Economic Emergency Powers Act.”</blockquote><p>This potential declaration could significantly impact trade policies under Trump's administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fxstreet.com/news/us-president-elect-trump-considering-economic-emergency-declaration-to-allow-for-new-tariff-program-cnn-202501081142</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fxstreet.com/news/us-president-elect-trump-considering-economic-emergency-declaration-to-allow-for-new-tariff-program-cnn-202501081142</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:45:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sebi imposes Rs 9 lakh penalty on stock broker whose 1,103 clients were 'dependent children' aged between - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAJBVV95cUxPRnZTWGpsZzJvdTVJTTRFbnJOa3I2VTFEMUtfVGVaOTNScExuM3hEdjRQODZfUXozdjBGVUg5cklvaG90NmxZTVVPd1JLb01jTE03NXpBQlVNQVRwUS1wN0l3SmtsVG02d01kS0tfUjNQaUFvMXUyTkw4WUtuc2d3OFFORWtuUC1Jc0FlU0JOZHY1ZWYzNTBuUEJfNG1XTHo4bHh4cUhwU19nT3loWnVDNzUyazFoVEJZTVBGOEVhQUxWRVEtS2tyNmY4UWVjalF0a0NmcFByc1JTQS04T0pYeUJRQTFqZjRjcXBEU3hNUVg5eFJYcDg0cFRQZFZRdkRlalVkN2habmxaemJZdERQZDNOc2d4RnVk0gGeAkFVX3lxTE5HMnQwczhMZGgxZnVvYzQyTi0zTmhJTFhhdUpIVkYzLW9oZVVUM0lSc2N0V2FmU0lveGs2OG54b0VOS2RCbWtDUFhUazVwSmg5d0U1ZmpLZGtuVWhVaTV5Y0lIYkhETnlBeDFGM09RSV9kaHVEaGh0blFuMGVOVDVWN0lSMFdkV2FWY3NDSVp4VjNEbzJrQ3hHaXIyaHFpQXhyWV9oRVdLbThHLTRhQnVKdDJBR1F1Mk9XUzRJaExhVHZ3U0pIZzNZMG5yQ2xXdjB3eVRDZjBXVURLbm0tRWNmTDFSOFZScF9hZERjR2otb3VnQlRDbmVDRC1RX0hGYzUxMzdaUDJDN0cwSzdNaURkbmtwN2RHRlVhUnJtLVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAJBVV95cUxPRnZTWGpsZzJvdTVJTTRFbnJOa3I2VTFEMUtfVGVaOTNScExuM3hEdjRQODZfUXozdjBGVUg5cklvaG90NmxZTVVPd1JLb01jTE03NXpBQlVNQVRwUS1wN0l3SmtsVG02d01kS0tfUjNQaUFvMXUyTkw4WUtuc2d3OFFORWtuUC1Jc0FlU0JOZHY1ZWYzNTBuUEJfNG1XTHo4bHh4cUhwU19nT3loWnVDNzUyazFoVEJZTVBGOEVhQUxWRVEtS2tyNmY4UWVjalF0a0NmcFByc1JTQS04T0pYeUJRQTFqZjRjcXBEU3hNUVg5eFJYcDg0cFRQZFZRdkRlalVkN2habmxaemJZdERQZDNOc2d4RnVk0gGeAkFVX3lxTE5HMnQwczhMZGgxZnVvYzQyTi0zTmhJTFhhdUpIVkYzLW9oZVVUM0lSc2N0V2FmU0lveGs2OG54b0VOS2RCbWtDUFhUazVwSmg5d0U1ZmpLZGtuVWhVaTV5Y0lIYkhETnlBeDFGM09RSV9kaHVEaGh0blFuMGVOVDVWN0lSMFdkV2FWY3NDSVp4VjNEbzJrQ3hHaXIyaHFpQXhyWV9oRVdLbThHLTRhQnVKdDJBR1F1Mk9XUzRJaExhVHZ3U0pIZzNZMG5yQ2xXdjB3eVRDZjBXVURLbm0tRWNmTDFSOFZScF9hZERjR2otb3VnQlRDbmVDRC1RX0hGYzUxMzdaUDJDN0cwSzdNaURkbmtwN2RHRlVhUnJtLVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:41:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SEBI-Sahara Case: Supreme Court Calls For Review Of Versova Property Development Plans - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SEBI-Sahara Case: Supreme Court Calls For Review Of Versova Property Development Plans</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 08 Jan 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Profit</p><figure><img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2016-08%2F64d38d6a-6347-446f-8313-3c7926dad6eb%2Fsupreme%20court.jpg?rect=0%2C0%2C662%2C372&amp;w=1200" alt="Supreme Court" /><figcaption>In September 2024, Sahara was granted 30 days to negotiate a joint venture or land development agreement for its Versova property. (Photo source: Supreme Court of India website)</figcaption></figure><p>The Supreme Court has directed the Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) to evaluate land development proposals for the Sahara Group's Versova property, submitted by two developers, Oberoi Realty and Valor Estate.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court will reconvene in three weeks to assess which developer will proceed with the land development.</li><li>Both developers must deposit Rs 1,000 crore, which will remain uncashed until a final decision is made.</li><li>This case is part of ongoing efforts to address a Rs 10,000 crore shortfall in the SEBI-Sahara Fund.</li><li>In past rulings, the court has mandated Sahara to refund over Rs 24,000 crore to over 2 crore small investors.</li></ul><blockquote>“The matters concerning the conduct of an entity will continue regardless of individual presence.” – SEBI Chief Madhabi Puri Buch</blockquote><p>This ruling marks another significant step in a complex legal saga involving the Sahara Group, which has been dealing with regulatory scrutiny for several years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/law-and-policy/sebi-sahara-case-supreme-court-calls-for-review-of-versova-property-development-plans</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/law-and-policy/sebi-sahara-case-supreme-court-calls-for-review-of-versova-property-development-plans</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:17:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[November's 'unusual' gold import that pushed up trade deficit revised lower by 34% to $9.84 billion - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>November's 'unusual' gold import that pushed up trade deficit revised lower by 34% to $9.84 billion</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/06/20240603210804_Gold-Bar.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Gold Bar" title="The revised figures for inbound shipments of gold in value terms are nearly 34 percent lower than what was previously reported on December 16, 2024."><figcaption>The revised figures for inbound shipments of gold in value terms are nearly 34 percent lower than what was previously reported on December 16, 2024.</figcaption><p>The surge in gold imports in November had widened India’s trade deficit to a record level and pushed the Rupee to an all-time low, which was later attributed to an error in calculation.</p><ul><li>The gold import figures for November were revised downwards by 34%.</li><li>The initial report had indicated a much larger trade deficit stemming from gold imports.</li><li>This revision has implications for India's economic stability and currency value.</li></ul><blockquote>"The revised figures for inbound shipments of gold in value terms are nearly 34 percent lower than what was previously reported."</blockquote><p>This revision of gold import data highlights the importance of accurate reporting and its significant implications for economic indicators such as trade deficits and currency value.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/europe/?url=https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/november-gold-import-data-revised-12905942.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/europe/?url=https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/november-gold-import-data-revised-12905942.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:13:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Gainers and Losers today on 8 January, 2025: Oil & Natural Gas Corporation, Reliance Industries, Apollo Hospitals Enterprise, Trent among most active stocks; Check full list here | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Gainers and Losers Today on January 8, 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025<br> <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The equity markets saw mixed performance on January 8, 2025, with the Nifty index closing slightly lower, while specific stocks showed notable gains and losses.</p><h2>Nifty Index Performance</h2><p>The Nifty index closed at 23,707.9, down by 0.08%. Meanwhile, the Sensex also concluded lower at 78,199.11, signaling a tight trading environment.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Nifty Midcap 50 closed down by 1.11%.</li><li>Nifty Small Cap 100 ended at 18,673.45, down by 1.65%.</li><li>Top gainers in the Nifty included Oil & Natural Gas Corporation (+2.98%) and Reliance Industries (+1.99%).</li><li>Top losers were Apollo Hospitals Enterprise (-3.95%) and Trent (-2.55%).</li><li>Bank Nifty closed at 50,202.15, affected by a decline over recent weeks.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics</h2><blockquote>“The performance of the Nifty 50 over various time frames shows a mixed outlook, with a yearly growth of 10.19% amidst recent declines.”</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>The trading session on January 8, 2025, highlighted ongoing volatility in the markets, with specific stocks demonstrating resilience while others faced declines.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/top-gainers-and-losers-today-on-8-january-2025-oil-natural-gas-corporation-reliance-industries-apollo-hospitals-enterprise-trent-among-most-active-stocks-check-full-list-here-11736332395894.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/top-gainers-and-losers-today-on-8-january-2025-oil-natural-gas-corporation-reliance-industries-apollo-hospitals-enterprise-trent-among-most-active-stocks-check-full-list-here-11736332395894.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:33:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia’s Jensen Huang hints at ‘plans’ for its own desktop CPU - The Verge]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nvidia’s Jensen Huang hints at ‘plans’ for its own desktop CPU</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Verge</p>
<img alt="An exploded image of Nvidia’s Project Digits AI supercomputer showing all of its components" loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://duet-cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0x0:1322x733/2400x1331/filters:focal(661x367:662x368):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25820687/chrome_NP3LJVKJfM.png">
<figcaption><em>Nvidia’s Project Digits AI computer, featuring a new 20-core Arm CPU.</em></figcaption>
<p>At CES, Nvidia unveiled Project Digits, a personal AI supercomputer powered by a new superchip, hinting at plans for its own consumer CPU expected in 2025.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nvidia is rumored to enter the consumer CPU market in 2025.</li>
  <li>The company unveiled Project Digits, a $3,000 personal AI supercomputer powered by the GB10 Grace Blackwell Superchip.</li>
  <li>CEO Jensen Huang indicated bigger plans for an Arm-based CPU within that chip during an investor presentation.</li>
  <li>MediaTek may also market the new CPU independently, according to Huang.</li>
  <li>Nvidia’s entry into the CPU market could challenge Qualcomm’s current dominance in Arm-based Windows PCs.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“You know, obviously we have plans,” Huang said during an investor presentation.</blockquote>
<p>With increased competition, 2025 could be pivotal in the battle between x86 and Arm architectures in the PC market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/8/24338939/nvidia-jensen-huang-hints-arm-desktop-cpu</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/8/24338939/nvidia-jensen-huang-hints-arm-desktop-cpu</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:33:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor India introduces new variants and updates for Venue, Verna, and Grand i10 Nios - Autocar Professional]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQWFhzem45NW1Bc2JVNU5aUjZCV1JMUTl3V25BWXFxU1FIdWdoZ3MwdWVDdm9ORktNS2VzTXY4Ul9WaVpmT3E3M3pUS05RWGpudnk0enRRX0lqTGRpU29EQUhvM09nV0E5WXR4SjJtUmktN3N2Yk9zRnJrbWExc2JCX2NpR0piN1dqaHZSYURYXy1SQVVldkxKaDRNNTFhQjFyZ1Y2OHVwWFh0ZDlidXlKSDV1Q2RZRnVxSXNuQ0dFcms2MDYxbWE4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQWFhzem45NW1Bc2JVNU5aUjZCV1JMUTl3V25BWXFxU1FIdWdoZ3MwdWVDdm9ORktNS2VzTXY4Ul9WaVpmT3E3M3pUS05RWGpudnk0enRRX0lqTGRpU29EQUhvM09nV0E5WXR4SjJtUmktN3N2Yk9zRnJrbWExc2JCX2NpR0piN1dqaHZSYURYXy1SQVVldkxKaDRNNTFhQjFyZ1Y2OHVwWFh0ZDlidXlKSDV1Q2RZRnVxSXNuQ0dFcms2MDYxbWE4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:25:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi man shares resignation letter with 'finest reasons': ‘With this salary it’s not possible’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Man's Humorous Resignation Letter Goes Viral</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/resignation_1736330691592_1736330696844.png" alt="The employee expressed disappointment, citing an unusual but relatable reason for leaving.(X/@Rishabhsingh)"><figcaption>The employee expressed disappointment, citing an unusual but relatable reason for leaving.(X/@Rishabhsingh)</figcaption><p>A resignation letter shared by Rishabh Singh, co-founder of EngineerHub, humorously encapsulates an employee's reason for leaving his job due to an inability to afford a smartphone, striking a chord among netizens.</p><ul><li>The resignation letter started straightforwardly but soon displayed wit and humor.</li><li>The employee expressed disappointment over stagnant salary preventing him from buying the iQOO 13 smartphone.</li><li>He humorously questioned how his career would progress without the fastest phone in India.</li><li>The last working day was mentioned as December 4, 2024, with a note of appreciation for the company.</li></ul><blockquote>“After two wonderful years of dedication and hard work, it seems my salary has remained as frozen as my hopes for an increment.”</blockquote><p>The resignation resonated widely online, generating laughter and empathy for its honesty, evidence of social media’s reaction with supportive comments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/delhi-man-shares-resignation-letter-with-finest-reasons-with-this-salary-it-s-not-possible-101736330122313.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/delhi-man-shares-resignation-letter-with-finest-reasons-with-this-salary-it-s-not-possible-101736330122313.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:09:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISB student orders from Blinkit, Swiggy and Zepto to see who delivers first. Guess who won - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxOTk81cTRtdzkxdlF1ZzhqUFdfUnJQeXpWYldHRXB6bzh0dExUVFdCZlcxcFdodUZzQnlKZGh3N29UQm5kVzFsVjFPTWpZUEwycXZWS3VuRHNYd3I1TTlSR0E3YXA3elNmQzh0V3ZpVUVnU3NNbGtuWkhsQm9vSzNRWGpsUTBjeWlvbmR1QjhSTFdZT2syRTFXY0swZ3lrYmpqcXVRMnhwOGF6aTIzNFFsbUR3c3VNck5kZVlHRXJOcDRIcEgxNW11N3F0VEVXY2VKY0c5R0ZSaW1rMjRqU1RqekwtUdIB6AFBVV95cUxNY0tnckRKR1llaW0xT0c4RnU0N2psTGlMSVlPVTRqSlpPaGpPVGt1aXNPdWk1WnBfX1dMNVBXZUFtTE5LdDI5S3J0WWFuMlRHWXd4Y2ZUZjFNc3UzNEVMMVdMcjJOVk9sQXpkMG5WOENERW52QnZfZGtoZ1htWFhCanhsUlE2U0xsSWI3MVgxVlAxd3dnQ3VPX1JJcEZGd0VybFljTkZuN1NzQjEwV19TUUd5cGlpYkhCd0NpbXJzRGZLX3hzTHNPQVpUVFBVV2Y2RXcwYm90UzVHNTYwTXdvTkdFeDBNNkpS?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxOTk81cTRtdzkxdlF1ZzhqUFdfUnJQeXpWYldHRXB6bzh0dExUVFdCZlcxcFdodUZzQnlKZGh3N29UQm5kVzFsVjFPTWpZUEwycXZWS3VuRHNYd3I1TTlSR0E3YXA3elNmQzh0V3ZpVUVnU3NNbGtuWkhsQm9vSzNRWGpsUTBjeWlvbmR1QjhSTFdZT2syRTFXY0swZ3lrYmpqcXVRMnhwOGF6aTIzNFFsbUR3c3VNck5kZVlHRXJOcDRIcEgxNW11N3F0VEVXY2VKY0c5R0ZSaW1rMjRqU1RqekwtUdIB6AFBVV95cUxNY0tnckRKR1llaW0xT0c4RnU0N2psTGlMSVlPVTRqSlpPaGpPVGt1aXNPdWk1WnBfX1dMNVBXZUFtTE5LdDI5S3J0WWFuMlRHWXd4Y2ZUZjFNc3UzNEVMMVdMcjJOVk9sQXpkMG5WOENERW52QnZfZGtoZ1htWFhCanhsUlE2U0xsSWI3MVgxVlAxd3dnQ3VPX1JJcEZGd0VybFljTkZuN1NzQjEwV19TUUd5cGlpYkhCd0NpbXJzRGZLX3hzTHNPQVpUVFBVV2Y2RXcwYm90UzVHNTYwTXdvTkdFeDBNNkpS?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zomato joins quick food delivery space with 15-minute delivery service - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPSUw2WU1pRGxKMk1UV3VEeG8zQjY5dW84R1F1XzZVekJ3WFFyVTFOWU9UWVgwWHFONnZKUG9weWdOcjkwUVJGWlR0M2pKX2lZY2F3WGhZdGN5X0xjNGhxOXBZOEcybVJJcHFyY2Nic081NkpEdEhBZll4MlZyS2R3ekh6N2xId3JUUUlfc05PTzViQmotUkN0NFNSUXlkT0lhNzlBNnMwMVc2NDhhT01sczhtTm0zZVJyLU9ZOFcxbkRCYkxyWUllNm12UXh2OFVS?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPSUw2WU1pRGxKMk1UV3VEeG8zQjY5dW84R1F1XzZVekJ3WFFyVTFOWU9UWVgwWHFONnZKUG9weWdOcjkwUVJGWlR0M2pKX2lZY2F3WGhZdGN5X0xjNGhxOXBZOEcybVJJcHFyY2Nic081NkpEdEhBZll4MlZyS2R3ekh6N2xId3JUUUlfc05PTzViQmotUkN0NFNSUXlkT0lhNzlBNnMwMVc2NDhhT01sczhtTm0zZVJyLU9ZOFcxbkRCYkxyWUllNm12UXh2OFVS?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 Dates Announced: These Smartphones to Get Discounts - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 Announced: Here's What to Know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/tQ8BVvkGKLE/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Promo for Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025</figcaption><p>The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 is set to start on January 13, featuring substantial discounts on a variety of products for Prime members and the general public.</p><ul><li>The sale begins at noon on January 13 for all customers, with early access for Prime members.</li><li>Discounts include up to 40% on smartphones and up to 65% on smart TVs and projectors.</li><li>Offers include a 10% instant discount with SBI credit cards.</li><li>Electronics, laptops, kitchenware, and fashion items will also see price cuts.</li><li>Major phone brands like Apple, Samsung, and Xiaomi will have discounts on mobile devices.</li><li>Pricing for travel bookings, fashion, and daily needs will start at discounted rates.</li></ul><blockquote>“Further details about the new big sale will be disclosed in the coming days.”</blockquote><p>The sale promises a vast array of discounts and is anticipated to attract significant consumer interest, highlighting Amazon's competitive position in the e-commerce market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/internet/news/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-2025-date-offers-discounts-deals-teasers-7426430</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/internet/news/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-2025-date-offers-discounts-deals-teasers-7426430</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:57:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Great Republic Day Sale begins on January 13, Prime members to get 12-hour early access - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amazon Great Republic Day Sale Begins on January 13, Prime Members to Get 12-Hour Early Access</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Amazon_Great_Republic_Day_Sale_1736323715522_1736323720287.png" alt="Get ready for amazing deals! The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale starts January 13, with exclusive early access for Prime members. Don’t miss it!" title="Get ready for amazing deals! The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale starts January 13, with exclusive early access for Prime members. Don’t miss it!">
<figcaption>Get ready for amazing deals! The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale starts January 13, with exclusive early access for Prime members. Don’t miss it!</figcaption>
<p>The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale is set to commence on January 13, providing Prime members with an exclusive 12-hour early access to amazing discounts across various categories.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Deals on washing machines, saving up to 65%.</li>
  <li>Smart TVs available at discounts up to 65%.</li>
  <li>Refrigerators discounted by up to 65%.</li>
  <li>Excellent promotions on laptops catering to various needs.</li>
  <li>Significant bank offers for additional savings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale ensures significant savings for every shopper.”</blockquote>
<p>This upcoming sale promises an extensive range of discounted items, making it a great opportunity to snag some incredible deals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-begins-on-january-13-prime-members-to-get-12-hour-early-access-101736323669229.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-begins-on-january-13-prime-members-to-get-12-hour-early-access-101736323669229.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:45:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quadrant Future Tek IPO Day 2: Issue booked over 40 times so far; check offer size, price band and more - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxOeHFwSDd0WFFzRXJXM01qTnJIel82cTJwdEZqQWVnMWxFeGRBWU1fYTBTcHZEbW9ENS1YM1lYSFZhQlRwdzRnTXJjVS1YdkozMUlIZWNoLXpVV3VHRmU4QzZPUVdNLTM4YkZTbWc3b0Y2SzZueHZEUW5SZk40cXZzT3dFemtXdmhNZDFnZ1M3Q1p3a3k3dVVZRVA1eDhfaHRobW1IeWEwa18yTHpjVEhsM2hNNXZPOGdVRnRoT2JJZUVhZVQxTnVqWjVDdjFUOEc3WFFaWjg4VEtwRkJ2bHdYU3RuSmk5OVlDVGZVWg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxOeHFwSDd0WFFzRXJXM01qTnJIel82cTJwdEZqQWVnMWxFeGRBWU1fYTBTcHZEbW9ENS1YM1lYSFZhQlRwdzRnTXJjVS1YdkozMUlIZWNoLXpVV3VHRmU4QzZPUVdNLTM4YkZTbWc3b0Y2SzZueHZEUW5SZk40cXZzT3dFemtXdmhNZDFnZ1M3Q1p3a3k3dVVZRVA1eDhfaHRobW1IeWEwa18yTHpjVEhsM2hNNXZPOGdVRnRoT2JJZUVhZVQxTnVqWjVDdjFUOEc3WFFaWjg4VEtwRkJ2bHdYU3RuSmk5OVlDVGZVWg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:35:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The new Enyaq with Modern Solid - ŠKODA Storyboard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxNS2hfcElpSnpxVmhSbmxSUm9tMWRYQjh3X1VVVUFQbnR5NHhtVkd4UlBMZFBDeUZwWmg1bUxOR2pDZE9VcDVWVGE0NVpvbFdGX1ZzRUJ4c3ZJUGRpeFREQ0ZnMEJhTHZKVjAyUUVnelMxaUxvdS1tWnpnRHZiYjNNbTZtb2RYcmRE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxNS2hfcElpSnpxVmhSbmxSUm9tMWRYQjh3X1VVVUFQbnR5NHhtVkd4UlBMZFBDeUZwWmg1bUxOR2pDZE9VcDVWVGE0NVpvbFdGX1ZzRUJ4c3ZJUGRpeFREQ0ZnMEJhTHZKVjAyUUVnelMxaUxvdS1tWnpnRHZiYjNNbTZtb2RYcmRE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk has a powerful new acolyte: Mark Zuckerberg - Business Insider]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mark Zuckerberg Unveils His Latest Persona: Elon Musk</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified. <strong>Source:</strong> Business Insider</p><p>In a strategic pivot, Mark Zuckerberg has adopted an approach similar to Elon Musk's, including policy changes at Meta to forge a better relationship with the Trump administration. This aligns with Musk's influence as one of the most powerful non-elected figures in U.S. politics today.</p><ul><li>Meta announced it would end third-party fact-checking, moving to a community-driven moderation system.</li><li>Zuckerberg's language echoes Musk’s rhetoric about prioritizing free speech.</li><li>The changes come as Zuckerberg aims to improve ties with Trump after years of tension.</li><li>Meta's shift represents a broader trend in Big Tech's relationship with government and political figures.</li><li>Community notes implementation shows Zuckerberg is aligning closely with Musk's methods in handling social media governance.</li></ul><blockquote>“The recent elections also feel like a cultural tipping point towards, once again, prioritizing speech.” - Mark Zuckerberg</blockquote><p>This marks another transformation in Zuckerberg's long career, as he continues to reshape his public persona in response to shifts in the political landscape. As Meta's direction evolves, it seems poised to realign closely with conservative ideologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/mark-zuckerberg-copying-elon-musk-content-moderation-trump-efficiency-2025-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.businessinsider.com/mark-zuckerberg-copying-elon-musk-content-moderation-trump-efficiency-2025-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paytm shares fall over 7% after NPCI data shows no UPI market share gains in December - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Paytm shares fall over 7% after NPCI data shows no UPI market share gains in December</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 / 14:11 IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/08/20240828121545_paytm.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="stock" title="stock" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>Paytm's market share has significantly dropped, despite prior approvals for customer additions.</figcaption>
<p>Paytm's shares have seen a notable decline of over 7% following new data from the NPCI, which indicated that the company did not gain any market share in the UPI segment during December. Analysts noted a substantial reduction in Paytm's market share from 10% at the start of 2024 to 5.5% by year-end.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Paytm's share price decreased by over 7% after NPCI data release.</li>
  <li>The company's UPI market share fell from 10% to 5.5% in 2024.</li>
  <li>This decline comes despite being approved to add more customers in October.</li>
  <li>Over the past three months, Paytm's shares had previously gained over 22%.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Despite receiving approval to add customers in October, Paytm's share of the UPI market has nearly halved," - Analysts at UBS.</blockquote>
<p>This recent data highlights significant challenges for Paytm in maintaining its competitive position within the UPI market, raising concerns among investors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/europe/?url=https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/paytm-shares-fall-over-7-after-npci-data-shows-no-upi-market-share-gains-in-december-12905780.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/europe/?url=https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/paytm-shares-fall-over-7-after-npci-data-shows-no-upi-market-share-gains-in-december-12905780.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:41:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[United Breweries shares fall 4% as firm suspends beer supply to Telangana Beverages Corp - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxNNk0tOE9TOG02UjB6OXloLUJkSThPUURTcElSRDVrWmIyR3RsZzdvdjFHd21ERld0eGFqaVZMcUprdHAwWFV4SEN0NTRZR2N5ZmpXR1Axay1RdjN0NTJaNGljd0F5Mm9jajRHMWwtT1lCbmtBS29qcmZsSlZ5M2hTaTltRVpYdzY4eUZuWTN4dXVWTldNcnVTR0dmS3V4eXIxQk9pQS1EMUlJWVdmZS1jQWI0ZFM5RzJEUWNIc3laeUxyTmV3aHpGbmk3SWFybjNfbEoyWV9ROXFTZWYxTHd6a3ZZVUpKTkV4QmV2MlpCMmvSAfYBQVVfeXFMUDFEQ2lzaHNaYUxBUVZZSzhHdjFTV1NucFBfSVNuWHBSYm5UWnd0b1prYnpDVUJnQ3ZGSC1EVl9mRTZscE1ienRHWXdkaF9ZOEJwbjF5bHJTc0s2R3pWWm1ZdXZwUXUyWWNaRkVzTjgtSTVGYjloSUlnbVdWek5VVVlMbWFrWWthMjVEWWJpZkNSQXk5eDRhc1paRkVJX25DejRjN0VBTlNublVMV0F6YW03eXJ2dnlDSWV4WjBIalV4R1gtdlc0VjVJTEJGSUlKRU44TFB0ZHhmZFFPN013VzVtbGU4WWM1OXc1LVJuTFVNQm5wUzdB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxNNk0tOE9TOG02UjB6OXloLUJkSThPUURTcElSRDVrWmIyR3RsZzdvdjFHd21ERld0eGFqaVZMcUprdHAwWFV4SEN0NTRZR2N5ZmpXR1Axay1RdjN0NTJaNGljd0F5Mm9jajRHMWwtT1lCbmtBS29qcmZsSlZ5M2hTaTltRVpYdzY4eUZuWTN4dXVWTldNcnVTR0dmS3V4eXIxQk9pQS1EMUlJWVdmZS1jQWI0ZFM5RzJEUWNIc3laeUxyTmV3aHpGbmk3SWFybjNfbEoyWV9ROXFTZWYxTHd6a3ZZVUpKTkV4QmV2MlpCMmvSAfYBQVVfeXFMUDFEQ2lzaHNaYUxBUVZZSzhHdjFTV1NucFBfSVNuWHBSYm5UWnd0b1prYnpDVUJnQ3ZGSC1EVl9mRTZscE1ienRHWXdkaF9ZOEJwbjF5bHJTc0s2R3pWWm1ZdXZwUXUyWWNaRkVzTjgtSTVGYjloSUlnbVdWek5VVVlMbWFrWWthMjVEWWJpZkNSQXk5eDRhc1paRkVJX25DejRjN0VBTlNublVMV0F6YW03eXJ2dnlDSWV4WjBIalV4R1gtdlc0VjVJTEJGSUlKRU44TFB0ZHhmZFFPN013VzVtbGU4WWM1OXc1LVJuTFVNQm5wUzdB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:38:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market crash: IRCTC along with 2 other stocks hit 52-week low; here’s why - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxOOENQYWpfN2QzSjFTYVdITWJvZ2JQaWVGLTdSUnBnTHJfZ2ZPcHFTallJRHZCUHZpc3ItVk5KS1VkbkRGZGpIaU1TSUFqLWZTbnNNemVBWTg2U29TWTRYdEIwWmhLeURjcHFQTGVIV2JiRVhiMkx4T2wyOWxWWFRQcHZGcU1XNGY3eTR5VktDSXo3SVVKakR3bXlaYnM4ZVR4NHA3NWZFQTJaMjVJUzRsMzhBY2pEWkxGU0xSNjV1czdEbmVKQ0Z0TnVSTWh5ekdIcEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxOOENQYWpfN2QzSjFTYVdITWJvZ2JQaWVGLTdSUnBnTHJfZ2ZPcHFTallJRHZCUHZpc3ItVk5KS1VkbkRGZGpIaU1TSUFqLWZTbnNNemVBWTg2U29TWTRYdEIwWmhLeURjcHFQTGVIV2JiRVhiMkx4T2wyOWxWWFRQcHZGcU1XNGY3eTR5VktDSXo3SVVKakR3bXlaYnM4ZVR4NHA3NWZFQTJaMjVJUzRsMzhBY2pEWkxGU0xSNjV1czdEbmVKQ0Z0TnVSTWh5ekdIcEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:31:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zomato’s losing steam and the Blinkit drag | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zomato’s losing steam and the Blinkit drag | Stock Market News</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Zomato, a notable success story in the startup domain, experienced a significant stock surge until recently, but it now appears to be losing momentum after a remarkable rally.</p><ul><li>After its IPO in 2021, Zomato's performance was lackluster until mid-2023.</li><li>For the first time, Zomato reported positive bottom-line results in June 2023.</li><li>The stock saw a remarkable 44% annual revenue growth, quadrupling investor wealth.</li><li>However, recent corrections have led to a 17% decline from its peak value.</li></ul><blockquote>“The stock quadrupled investor wealth in the year and a half until December.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while Zomato's initial successes positioned it as a frontrunner, the current market trend indicates a need for strategic reassessment as investor confidence wanes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/zomato-blinkit-food-delivery-quick-commerce-competition-amazon-tez-flipkart-minutes-jeffrey-s-downgrade-11736322742018.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/zomato-blinkit-food-delivery-quick-commerce-competition-amazon-tez-flipkart-minutes-jeffrey-s-downgrade-11736322742018.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:25:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft backs its $3B AI push in India with public and private sector deals - TechCrunch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Microsoft backs its $3B AI push in India with public and private sector deals</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, Publication Source: TechCrunch</p><p>Microsoft has announced a series of AI partnerships across key sectors in India, following its commitment to invest $3 billion over the next two years to enhance its competitive edge against Google and Amazon.</p><ul><li>Agreements established with five major sectors: railways, healthcare, financial services, manufacturing, and education.</li><li>Collaboration with the Indian Ministry of Electronics and IT for the IndiaAI Mission Datasets platform.</li><li>Training program set to equip 500,000 individuals with AI technologies by 2026.</li><li>RailTel partners with Microsoft for a five-year digital transformation initiative in Indian railways.</li><li>Apollo Hospitals aims to develop AI copilots for healthcare delivery.</li><li>Bajaj Finance anticipates annual savings of $18 million through AI implementation by 2026.</li><li>Other collaborations include working with edtech firm Upgrad to enhance AI applications in the workplace.</li></ul><blockquote>“The push comes as Google and Amazon are racing to broaden their AI offerings and court Indian businesses.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Microsoft's strategic investment in AI not only bolsters its position in the competitive landscape but also aims to spur innovation and skill development across various sectors in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/08/microsoft-backs-its-3b-ai-push-in-india-with-public-and-private-sector-deals/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/08/microsoft-backs-its-3b-ai-push-in-india-with-public-and-private-sector-deals/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:17:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sensex crashes over 600 points: What's behind the fall in Indian stock market & how to trade now? | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sensex Crashes Over 600 Points: What’s Behind the Fall in Indian Stock Market & How to Trade Now?</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>January 8, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source: </strong>Live Mint</p><p>The Indian stock market faced a significant downturn today, with the Sensex crashing over 700 points amid global weakness and increased selling pressure from foreign investors. The Nifty 50 also recorded a notable decline.</p><img src='link-to-image.jpg' alt='Sensex Downfall' /><figcaption>A visual representation of the market decline</figcaption><p>The following key factors have contributed to the market's drop:</p><ul><li>Weak global cues affecting domestic sentiment.</li><li>Waning hopes for a US Federal Reserve rate cut.</li><li>Caution ahead of expected Q3 earnings season.</li><li>Poor performance from major IT and banking stocks.</li><li>Sustained foreign capital outflows impacting market stability.</li></ul><blockquote>"The trend of strong US macros weakening emerging markets is continuing." - V K Vijayakumar, Chief Investment Strategist at Geojit Financial Services</blockquote><p>Investors are encouraged to consider a long-term perspective, targeting large-cap stocks in financials and pharmaceuticals as potential recovery plays.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/sensex-crashes-over-600-points-whats-behind-the-fall-in-indian-stock-market-how-to-trade-now-11736319472533.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/sensex-crashes-over-600-points-whats-behind-the-fall-in-indian-stock-market-how-to-trade-now-11736319472533.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:08:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zomato shares drop 10% in a week. Is the worst over? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQYkhub1lwQ1V2MEpvZy1PTVZTaEk0NnJ6Vi10ZW0ycGEtZkh5d2ZxdDJUaTMxQjN4c2xLMEhjYnJYcG5jYWEwOUwwc0V4NHJlR2FKbEEtUlZIRUFUS3pDMDA0Y3JSSDJFSy1rb29VWF9IOFhKNXhoa2wxU3dmblM2OU81Z01jVzlvN0dfRk16TXRhcXZQOUNFY19sZFItLVhxUTI5LV9uZjJRVWtVcmZCMWM3MEl0LTJhV0xGcmx4bVDSAcYBQVVfeXFMTVM2ZGcxNHRUclpKcmluODYtaU1LM1JhRzBOVnQ5ZmwxeHlrTFBOTFRFSUYwOHo1SGZvZmQzQlVnazUyb1U1bDdIbnpJaFVlTWVZMkwyTFg0YTUzSEE1ZXhEZXE5ZHRXcUNJR05YWXNzb2dONUQ4Zm91YWRNaml0azlKRFlSM1pGa2lKTjFHbzN6cFlGbGhwdGZabjNoVElVc1ZkN3lFTTU3azdXSnFKZEI1cm0xOEtJN1RUUDJhRWFUSXNHMDlR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQYkhub1lwQ1V2MEpvZy1PTVZTaEk0NnJ6Vi10ZW0ycGEtZkh5d2ZxdDJUaTMxQjN4c2xLMEhjYnJYcG5jYWEwOUwwc0V4NHJlR2FKbEEtUlZIRUFUS3pDMDA0Y3JSSDJFSy1rb29VWF9IOFhKNXhoa2wxU3dmblM2OU81Z01jVzlvN0dfRk16TXRhcXZQOUNFY19sZFItLVhxUTI5LV9uZjJRVWtVcmZCMWM3MEl0LTJhV0xGcmx4bVDSAcYBQVVfeXFMTVM2ZGcxNHRUclpKcmluODYtaU1LM1JhRzBOVnQ5ZmwxeHlrTFBOTFRFSUYwOHo1SGZvZmQzQlVnazUyb1U1bDdIbnpJaFVlTWVZMkwyTFg0YTUzSEE1ZXhEZXE5ZHRXcUNJR05YWXNzb2dONUQ4Zm91YWRNaml0azlKRFlSM1pGa2lKTjFHbzN6cFlGbGhwdGZabjNoVElVc1ZkN3lFTTU3azdXSnFKZEI1cm0xOEtJN1RUUDJhRWFUSXNHMDlR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:07:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>