<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 02:55:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 02:55:54 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Outlook 2025: Top fund managers remain bullish on Indian stock market, suggest these 4 sectors to invest in - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Outlook 2025: Fund Managers Optimistic About Indian Stock Market Investments</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Market veterans and fund managers believe the Indian stock market is positioned for growth despite global challenges. They anticipate a revival in consumption and investment as key drivers for the market next year.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Fund managers are optimistic about the market, viewing current economic slowdowns as temporary.</li>
  <li>They expect growth to recover with increased government and corporate spending in the second half of the year.</li>
  <li>Key sectors for investment include IT, banks, FMCG, and infrastructure.</li>
  <li>The shift in global supply chains presents opportunities for India to play a significant role.</li>
  <li>Emerging industries like battery storage and green hydrogen are highlighted as future growth drivers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"With a growing middle class and a favourable business environment, India can emerge as a key global economic player..." - Karan Doshi, Fund Manager.</blockquote>
<p>The consensus among experts is that 2025 will provide robust opportunities for investors in various sectors as structural growth factors continue to support the Indian economy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/outlook-2025-top-fund-managers-remain-bullish-on-indian-stock-market-suggest-these-4-sectors-to-invest-in-11734711972538.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/outlook-2025-top-fund-managers-remain-bullish-on-indian-stock-market-suggest-these-4-sectors-to-invest-in-11734711972538.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 01:57:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Singapore Post fires CEO, other senior leaders amid whistleblowing charges | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Singapore Post Dismisses CEO Amid Whistleblower Allegations</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p><p>Singapore Post Ltd. has terminated its CEO, Vincent Phang, and other senior executives due to allegations of misconduct following a whistleblower report.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>SingPost launched an investigation after receiving a whistleblower report regarding manual data alterations to avoid contract penalties.</li><li>Three managers were dismissed, and a police report was filed against them.</li><li>Phang and other executives were deemed “grossly negligent” and have contested their terminations.</li><li>SingPost plans to appoint a new CEO and will pay a settlement to the affected customer without impacting its financial results.</li></ul><blockquote>“The allegations are without merits, and procedurally unfair,” stated Phang and Yik.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights significant challenges in corporate governance at SingPost as it seeks to restore integrity and trust.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/singapore-post-fires-ceo-other-senior-leaders-amid-whistleblowing-charges-11734915709899.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/singapore-post-fires-ceo-other-senior-leaders-amid-whistleblowing-charges-11734915709899.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 01:33:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vedanta demerger plan revised - Anil Agarwal-led company says 'shareholders will…’ - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vedanta demerger plan revised - Anil Agarwal-led company says 'shareholders will…’</h1><p><strong>Updated:</strong> Dec 21, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ET Now</p><img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Vedanta Demerger Plan" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Vedanta Demerger Plan</figcaption><p>Billionaire Anil Agarwal-led mining major Vedanta Limited has revised its proposed demerger plan, now choosing to retain its Base Metals undertaking within the parent firm.</p><ul><li>Anil Agarwal-led Vedanta has announced a revision in its demerger plan</li><li>The demerger of the Vedanta Base Metals undertaking will be considered at a later stage</li><li>The change will not affect the overall value creation as envisioned</li></ul><blockquote>“The shareholders will continue to enjoy value unlocking of the Vedanta Base Metals business as part of legacy residual Vedanta...”</blockquote><p>The demerger process is expected to conclude in the first quarter of next year, with a favorable dividend policy anticipated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/companies/vedanta-demerger-plan-revised-anil-agarwal-led-company-says-shareholders-will-article-116532106</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/companies/vedanta-demerger-plan-revised-anil-agarwal-led-company-says-shareholders-will-article-116532106</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 01:10:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pre-market action: Here's the trade setup for today's session - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GIFT Nifty Up 150 Points; Here's the Trading Setup for Today's Session</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today's Date & Source: Economic Times</p><p>Indian markets are experiencing a downturn, but GIFT Nifty indicates a positive start for the upcoming session.</p><ul><li>GIFT Nifty traded higher by 147.5 points, signaling Dalal Street is poised for a positive start.</li><li>Nifty remains in a downtrend with key support at 23,263 and resistance around 23,834.</li><li>U.S. stocks rallied due to a better-than-expected inflation report.</li><li>Asian markets also showed gains, driven by hopes of rate cuts.</li><li>Foreign portfolio investors sold a net Rs 3,598 crore, while domestic investors purchased Rs 1,374 crore.</li><li>The rupee appreciated to close at 85.04 against the US dollar.</li></ul><blockquote>“Nifty is in continuation of a downtrend and the only support that is visible on the chart is the swing low of 23,263.” - Nandish Shah, HDFC Securities</blockquote><p>Overall, the markets are reflecting mixed sentiments but are poised for potential recovery.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/pre-market-action-heres-the-trade-setup-for-todays-session/articleshow/116581036.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/pre-market-action-heres-the-trade-setup-for-todays-session/articleshow/116581036.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:52:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bonus, Dividend, Stock Split Alert: Vedanta payout, Mazagon Dock division, NMDC free shares this week - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Corporate Actions This Week: Vedanta Dividends, Mazagon Dock Stock Split, NMDC Bonus Shares</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="bonus shares" title="bonus shares"><figcaption></figcaption><p>This week marks a wave of corporate actions including Vedanta's dividend distribution, stock split announcements from various companies, and NMDC's grant of bonus shares.</p><ul><li><strong>Vedanta:</strong> Fourth interim dividend of ₹8.5 per share with a record date of December 24, 2024.</li><li><strong>Bharat Global Developers:</strong> Announced an 8:10 bonus issue and a stock split (face value from ₹10 to ₹1) with a record date of December 26.</li><li><strong>Dhanlaxmi Bank:</strong> Rights issue offering 14 rights equity shares for every 25 shares held, record date December 27, with a price of ₹21 per share.</li><li><strong>Mazagon Dock Shipbuilders:</strong> $10 share to split into two ₹5 shares, record date December 27.</li><li><strong>NMDC:</strong> Bonus issue of two shares for every one held, record date December 27.</li></ul><blockquote>"Shareholders will receive two free shares of the company for every one share they own."</blockquote><p>This series of actions illustrates a proactive approach by these companies to engage their shareholders and manage corporate structuring effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/bonus-dividend-stock-split-vedanta-nmdc-mazagon-dock-dhanlaxmi-bank-share-price-record-date-19528170.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/bonus-dividend-stock-split-vedanta-nmdc-mazagon-dock-dhanlaxmi-bank-share-price-record-date-19528170.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:49:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Liquor sale hits new high on Air India Express's first Surat-Bangkok flight - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Record Sales of Liquor on Air India Express's Inaugural Surat-Bangkok Flight</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>The first flight of Air India Express from Surat to Bangkok has reported unprecedented liquor sales, marking a significant milestone for the airline.</p><ul><li>The inaugural flight took off on a significant date, highlighting the airline's expansion.</li><li>Passengers expressed delight at the variety of liquor options available during the flight.</li><li>This event emphasizes the growing demand for international travel from Surat.</li></ul><blockquote>"The response from passengers was overwhelming, with many enjoying the new offerings."</blockquote><p>This successful flight sets a positive precedent for future international routes from Surat, enhancing the region's connectivity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/liquor-sale-hits-new-high-on-air-india-expresss-first-surat-bangkok-flight/articleshow/116576170.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/liquor-sale-hits-new-high-on-air-india-expresss-first-surat-bangkok-flight/articleshow/116576170.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 20:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Completely false': Jeff Bezos denies wedding claims; here's what Elon Musk replied - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Completely false’: Jeff Bezos denies wedding claims; here's what Elon Musk replied</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 25, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Jeff Bezos and Elon Musk" width="600"><figcaption>Jeff Bezos with Elon Musk.</figcaption><p>In a recent exchange, Jeff Bezos publicly denied rumors about his alleged wedding. Elon Musk, involved in the conversation, responded humorously.</p><ul><li>Jeff Bezos labeled the wedding rumors as "completely false."</li><li>The interaction between Bezos and Musk attracted significant media attention.</li><li>Social media users engaged widely with the content, leading to mixed reactions.</li></ul><blockquote>Elon Musk commented, "What’s a wedding without a little drama?"</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the ongoing public interest in the lives of high-profile individuals like Bezos and Musk.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/completely-false-jeff-bezos-denies-wedding-claims-heres-what-elon-musk-replied/articleshow/116574764.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/completely-false-jeff-bezos-denies-wedding-claims-heres-what-elon-musk-replied/articleshow/116574764.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epigamia co-founder Rohan Mirchandani dies at 42 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Epigamia co-founder Rohan Mirchandani dies at 42</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><p>Rohan Mirchandani, the co-founder of Epigamia, has passed away at the age of 42, leaving behind a legacy in the food industry.</p><ul><li>Mirchandani was instrumental in popularizing Greek yogurt in India through his brand Epigamia.</li><li>He was also known for his entrepreneurial spirit and commitment to healthier food options.</li><li>The sudden demise has shocked the startup community.</li></ul><blockquote>"Rohan's vision and drive have created a lasting impact on the food landscape in India."</blockquote><p>His contributions to the industry will be remembered as a testament to innovation and resilience in entrepreneurship.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/epigamia-co-founder-rohan-mirchandani-dies-at-42/articleshow/116575279.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/epigamia-co-founder-rohan-mirchandani-dies-at-42/articleshow/116575279.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two Air India passengers fight over armrest before landing in Delhi: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Two Air India Passengers Fight Over Armrest Before Landing in Delhi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/air_india_1734887529396_1734887529625.png" alt="It was impossible to determine how many people were on board the Boeing 787-8 piloting AI 158 (Copenhagen-Delhi)." title="It was impossible to determine how many people were on board the Boeing 787-8 piloting AI 158 (Copenhagen-Delhi)."><figcaption>It was impossible to determine how many people were on board the Boeing 787-8 piloting AI 158 (Copenhagen-Delhi).</figcaption><p>Two passengers on an Air India flight from Copenhagen to Delhi engaged in a physical altercation over armrest space just before landing. The argument escalated after the cabin crew intervened during meal service.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred on a flight that landed at Indira Gandhi International Airport.</li><li>The argument began during meal service when cabin crew strived to manage the situation.</li><li>Even after being separated by the cabin crew, the passengers clashed again while retrieving baggage after landing.</li><li>Air India officials reported that the dispute was eventually resolved with both passengers shaking hands before departing the airport.</li><li>The flight was reportedly nearly full, but the exact passenger count remains unclear.</li></ul><blockquote>“There was an argument between the two passengers over some issue but it was resolved amicably. They even shook hands before leaving the airport.” - Air India Official</blockquote><p>This incident underscores ongoing tensions that can arise during flights, particularly regarding personal space and comfort.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/two-air-india-passengers-fight-over-armrest-before-landing-in-delhi-report-101734882695751.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/two-air-india-passengers-fight-over-armrest-before-landing-in-delhi-report-101734882695751.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:14:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Holiday Week Ahead: Global Trends And FIIs' Moves To Drive Stock Market Sentiment - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQQjNUNU1xSlpoR3BHbTd2VkhrdXBETE1vSDc4ZktBamUzeTBWcnB1ZVBJSzhqdUdKZzlfTHJkbDdJUHBNOFNVdXNVcGVjUG9YOHRYYXJRN0tsajV6NmRMY3pKVkF0TlNWQ3l2SEpnM2JpVk5jYlpQcDlWNGFhN3BkUGJMZFBNdTAtazJtV2RHbm9zZHN1SWJxQTkxcmtLZ252ck50QkNiRdIBrAFBVV95cUxQUFdiV3VmZlQtT21tMTBNcXNPSi1fYnMxbVBvaEdISUQ2YV9BZVBDUFA2WE92TEpfQ19IYTl3cVJROFp4d2pDYllDTERhNjc2aWJhY19EREVIMnE1VGRRWnlKMFEyN052Nk0zei1BUEZQMEpUQmxvaXdKTF9lajVZSGw1UVkySDdoQlk5RzhrakhlX2w5OEFpRXR0VFI3b3NZV3RRYi1vYk11bXhK?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQQjNUNU1xSlpoR3BHbTd2VkhrdXBETE1vSDc4ZktBamUzeTBWcnB1ZVBJSzhqdUdKZzlfTHJkbDdJUHBNOFNVdXNVcGVjUG9YOHRYYXJRN0tsajV6NmRMY3pKVkF0TlNWQ3l2SEpnM2JpVk5jYlpQcDlWNGFhN3BkUGJMZFBNdTAtazJtV2RHbm9zZHN1SWJxQTkxcmtLZ252ck50QkNiRdIBrAFBVV95cUxQUFdiV3VmZlQtT21tMTBNcXNPSi1fYnMxbVBvaEdISUQ2YV9BZVBDUFA2WE92TEpfQ19IYTl3cVJROFp4d2pDYllDTERhNjc2aWJhY19EREVIMnE1VGRRWnlKMFEyN052Nk0zei1BUEZQMEpUQmxvaXdKTF9lajVZSGw1UVkySDdoQlk5RzhrakhlX2w5OEFpRXR0VFI3b3NZV3RRYi1vYk11bXhK?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:06:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Passengers on board Delhi-bound Air India flight come to blows over armrest space - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Passengers Fight Over Armrest Space on Air India Flight to Delhi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Sunday, 7.35 am<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p><p>Two passengers on a Delhi-bound Air India flight from Copenhagen got into a physical altercation over armrest space as the aircraft was landing at Indira Gandhi International Airport.</p><ul><li>The argument escalated during the flight while cabin crew was serving food and beverages.</li><li>One passenger was moved to another seat by the cabin crew to diffuse the situation.</li><li>As the flight approached landing, the conflict reignited when retrieving belongings, leading to a physical fight.</li><li>An Air India official stated that the matter was initially resolved amicably, and both passengers left on good terms.</li></ul><blockquote>“There was an argument between the two passengers over some issue but it was resolved amicably. They even shook hands before leaving the airport.” - Air India Official</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/india/passengers-on-board-delhi-bound-air-india-flight-come-to-blows-over-armrest-space/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/india/passengers-on-board-delhi-bound-air-india-flight-come-to-blows-over-armrest-space/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 16:34:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rajasthan Couple Caught Smuggling Luxury Watches Worth Rs 13 Crore In Gujarat - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rajasthan Couple Caught Smuggling Luxury Watches Worth Rs 13 Crore In Gujarat</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Rajasthan Couple Caught Smuggling Luxury Watches Worth Rs 13 Crore In Gujarat" alt="Rajasthan Couple Caught Smuggling Luxury Watches Worth Rs 13 Crore In Gujarat" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/3tqrdf5g_gujarat-watch-smuggling_625x300_22_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>A couple was caught attempting to smuggle luxury watches.</figcaption><p>A couple from Rajasthan has been detained by customs at Ahmedabad airport while allegedly trying to smuggle luxury watches valued around ₹ 13 crore from Dubai.</p><ul><li>The couple was intercepted separately upon their arrival from Dubai.</li><li>High-end watches include Audemars Piguet Royal Oak and Richard Mille, typically worn by celebrities.</li><li>The woman claimed the watch was a gift from her husband but could not produce a receipt.</li><li>The man initially undervalued the watch, claiming it cost around ₹ 1,000.</li><li>Both individuals admitted to smuggling and are from Pratapgarh, Rajasthan.</li><li>A detailed investigation is currently ongoing.</li></ul><blockquote>“They said they were made to travel to Dubai to bring the watches to Ahmedabad.”</blockquote><p>The couple's detention highlights ongoing issues with smuggling luxury goods, prompting authorities to take stricter actions at the airport.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rajasthan-couple-caught-smuggling-luxury-watches-worth-rs-13-crore-in-gujarat-7309414</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rajasthan-couple-caught-smuggling-luxury-watches-worth-rs-13-crore-in-gujarat-7309414</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 16:31:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jeff Bezos and Lauren Sanchez to tie knot in $600 million dreamy winter wonderland wedding - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jeff Bezos and Lauren Sanchez to Tie the Knot in $600 Million Dreamy Winter Wonderland Wedding</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> TBD | <strong>Source:</strong> TBD</p>
<p>Jeff Bezos and Lauren Sanchez are set to have a lavish winter wonderland wedding estimated at $600 million, marking a milestone in their high-profile relationship.</p>
<ul>
<li>The wedding is anticipated to feature extravagant decorations and stunning winter themes.</li>
<li>It will be one of the most talked-about social events in recent history.</li>
<li>The couple's relationship has garnered considerable public interest and media coverage.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We’re excited to celebrate our love in such a spectacular setting.”</blockquote>
<p>This wedding is not just a celebration of their love, but also an indication of their significant status in society and the media.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/jeff-bezos-and-lauren-sanchez-to-tie-knot-in-600-million-dreamy-winter-wonderland-wedding/articleshow/116571810.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/jeff-bezos-and-lauren-sanchez-to-tie-knot-in-600-million-dreamy-winter-wonderland-wedding/articleshow/116571810.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 16:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jeff Bezos, Lauren Sanchez slam report of $600 million lavish Aspen wedding: ‘None of this is happening’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jeff Bezos denies reports of a $600 million wedding to Lauren Sanchez, calling them completely false.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 22, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Jeff_bezos_Lauren_Sanchez_2_1734858585104_1734882395411.jpg" alt="Jeff Bezos and Lauren Sanchez got engaged in 2023 in Italy.(Instagram/LaurenWSanchez)"><figcaption>Jeff Bezos and Lauren Sanchez got engaged in 2023 in Italy.(Instagram/LaurenWSanchez)</figcaption><p>Billionaire Jeff Bezos has rubbished reports of his wedding to fiancée, Lauren Sanchez, costing a whopping $600 million as some media reports claimed. The Amazon boss took to X to clear the air about his wedding plans and said that the "whole thing was completely false".</p><ul><li>Bezos called the $600 million wedding rumors completely false.</li><li>Investor Bill Ackman commented on the reports, questioning their credibility.</li><li>Sanchez supported Bezos' statement by sharing it on her Instagram stories.</li><li>The original reports suggested a lavish wedding in Aspen, Colorado, with a multi-day celebration and high-profile guests.</li></ul><blockquote>"Furthermore, this whole thing is completely false — none of this is happening." - Jeff Bezos</blockquote><p>The couple has addressed the rumors to prevent misinformation about their wedding plans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/jeff-bezos-lauren-sanchez-slam-report-of-600-million-lavish-aspen-wedding-none-of-this-is-happening-101734882341458.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/jeff-bezos-lauren-sanchez-slam-report-of-600-million-lavish-aspen-wedding-none-of-this-is-happening-101734882341458.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:50:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet two men who are changing Anil Ambani's fortunes, clearing debts, they work as... - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meet two men who are changing Anil Ambani's fortunes, clearing debts, they work as...</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 22, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> DNA India</p>
<img src="https://cdn.dnaindia.com/sites/default/files/styles/full/public/2024/12/22/2668223-image-2024-12-22t210919.192.jpg" alt="Anil Ambani's debts are decreasing">
<figcaption>Anil Ambani’s debts are decreasing</figcaption>
<p>In the past year, Anil Ambani's fortunes have improved significantly, with a notable decrease in his debts. His companies are now securing new orders and enhancing their public image. This turnaround is largely attributed to his sons, Jai Anmol and Jai Anshul Ambani, who are taking charge of the family business.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Anil Ambani's debts are decreasing.</li>
  <li>His sons are actively involved in managing the companies.</li>
  <li>The image of the companies is improving, attracting more public trust.</li>
  <li>Jai Anmol Ambani is playing a crucial role in the revival of Reliance Capital Limited.</li>
  <li>New ventures like Reliance Life Insurance and Reliance Capital Asset Management have been launched.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Jai Anmol Ambani played a crucial role in increasing the stake of the Japanese firm Nippon in Reliance Nippon Life Asset Management, significantly boosting the company's value.”</blockquote>
<p>The involvement of Anil Ambani's sons signifies a new chapter for his business empire, promising to enhance its performance and stability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/business/photo-gallery-meet-two-men-who-are-changing-anil-ambani-s-fortunes-clearing-debts-jai-anmol-ambani-reliance-capital-limited-3123730</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/business/photo-gallery-meet-two-men-who-are-changing-anil-ambani-s-fortunes-clearing-debts-jai-anmol-ambani-reliance-capital-limited-3123730</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to Watch on December 23: Vedanta, NHPC, Reliance Industries, and more - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to Watch on December 23: Key Updates from Vedanta, NHPC, Reliance Industries, and More</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Stocks to Watch" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Stock updates for Vedanta, NHPC, Reliance Industries and more.</figcaption><p>This article highlights key stocks to monitor based on recent updates and decisions affecting various companies, including Vedanta, NHPC, and Reliance Industries, among others.</p><ul><li><strong>Vedanta:</strong> Revised its demerger plan to retain its base metals business, reflecting new business priorities.</li><li><strong>NHPC Ltd:</strong> Signed a ₹5,500-crore MoU with Bihar for solar and green hydrogen projects.</li><li><strong>Reliance Industries Ltd:</strong> Acquired a 45% stake in US-based Health Alliance Group for $10 million.</li><li><strong>UltraTech Cement:</strong> Acquired 32.72% stake in India Cements for ₹3,954 crores.</li><li><strong>Hindustan Construction Company:</strong> Divested stake in Steiner AG and raised ₹600 crore through QIP.</li><li><strong>AGI Greenpac Ltd:</strong> Plans to raise ₹1,500 crore through equity securities.</li><li><strong>Piramal Enterprises:</strong> Approved a public issuance of NCDs worth up to ₹2,000 crore.</li><li><strong>Insurance and Auto Stocks:</strong> Expected reactions to GST decisions impacting premiums and used cars.</li><li><strong>TeamLease Services Ltd:</strong> Acquired TSR Darashaw HR Services to enhance its portfolio.</li><li><strong>Aurobindo Pharma Ltd:</strong> Received UK MHRA approval for its biosimilar product.</li></ul><blockquote>“The stock market is reacting to significant updates affecting major industries.”</blockquote><p>Investors are encouraged to follow these developments closely as they may influence stock performance in the near term.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/stocks-to-watch-vedanta-nhpc-reliance-ultratech-shares-and-more-on-dec-23-19528140.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/stocks-to-watch-vedanta-nhpc-reliance-ultratech-shares-and-more-on-dec-23-19528140.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:01:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to Buy: 5 Stocks to buy now for an upside of up to 80%; Are you holding any? - Trade Brains]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxOQ2N4WTRVekRhSDd2MG1pZlVQZGllVVNJb1plSnVJMkZ4QUFnRXlZTWVWd0hQeUoySUZmck5zOWE0NVhhWllTUlVHVzI0VC1wMjU1LUV2SGNhancxWllvU0lHVXRMU3k5cGFkdmhtc1U4TUhPV2ZObGVvTG1pODdsajJ5Sm1mdkxoSkVvV25RV1lnTmt0Y3NEUTF6OHlWWTdtaU5qdTRBejNRdjZabTk4SzVn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxOQ2N4WTRVekRhSDd2MG1pZlVQZGllVVNJb1plSnVJMkZ4QUFnRXlZTWVWd0hQeUoySUZmck5zOWE0NVhhWllTUlVHVzI0VC1wMjU1LUV2SGNhancxWllvU0lHVXRMU3k5cGFkdmhtc1U4TUhPV2ZObGVvTG1pODdsajJ5Sm1mdkxoSkVvV25RV1lnTmt0Y3NEUTF6OHlWWTdtaU5qdTRBejNRdjZabTk4SzVn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Number of UPI apps grows in 2024, yet top two command maximum market share - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/finance/news/number-of-upi-apps-grows-in-2024-yet-top-two-command-maximum-market-share-124122200429_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/finance/news/number-of-upi-apps-grows-in-2024-yet-top-two-command-maximum-market-share-124122200429_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:25:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Outlook 2025: Top fund managers remain bullish on Indian stock market, suggest these 4 sectors to invest in | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Outlook 2025: Fund Managers Optimistic About Indian Stock Market Investments</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Market veterans and fund managers believe the Indian stock market is positioned for growth despite global challenges. They anticipate a revival in consumption and investment as key drivers for the market next year.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Fund managers are optimistic about the market, viewing current economic slowdowns as temporary.</li>
  <li>They expect growth to recover with increased government and corporate spending in the second half of the year.</li>
  <li>Key sectors for investment include IT, banks, FMCG, and infrastructure.</li>
  <li>The shift in global supply chains presents opportunities for India to play a significant role.</li>
  <li>Emerging industries like battery storage and green hydrogen are highlighted as future growth drivers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"With a growing middle class and a favourable business environment, India can emerge as a key global economic player..." - Karan Doshi, Fund Manager.</blockquote>
<p>The consensus among experts is that 2025 will provide robust opportunities for investors in various sectors as structural growth factors continue to support the Indian economy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/outlook-2025-top-fund-managers-remain-bullish-on-indian-stock-market-suggest-these-4-sectors-to-invest-in-11734711972538.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/outlook-2025-top-fund-managers-remain-bullish-on-indian-stock-market-suggest-these-4-sectors-to-invest-in-11734711972538.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epigamia CEO Rohan Mirchandani passes away at 42 due to cardiac arrest - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohan Mirchandani, Co-Founder of Epigamia, Passes Away at 42</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/feat-image-20.jpg?w=640" alt="Rohan Mirchandani, Epigamia" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>The sudden demise of Rohan Mirchandani has sent shockwaves through the startup community. (Photo: @RoMirchandani/ X)</figcaption><p>Rohan Mirchandani, the co-founder of Epigamia, tragically passed away at the age of 42 due to a cardiac arrest, leaving a void in the startup community.</p><ul><li>Rohan's death was confirmed by the senior leadership of Drums Food International, the parent company of Epigamia.</li><li>His colleagues expressed their heartbreak and commitment to carry on his vision and legacy.</li><li>Mirchandani had previously been a mentor and leader to many, inspiring them with his passion and dedication.</li><li>His passing raises concerns about health issues affecting individuals in their 40s and 50s.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is heartbreaking to see so many people I know losing their lives in their 40s and 50s to heart attacks and stress-related ailments.” – Radhika Gupta</blockquote><p>The startup community continues to mourn the loss of a visionary leader whose impact will be felt for years to come.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/business/epigamia-ceo-rohan-mirchandani-cardiac-arrest-9739191/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/business/epigamia-ceo-rohan-mirchandani-cardiac-arrest-9739191/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:48:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Transrail Lighting IPO: GMP, subscription status, should you apply as issue ends tomorrow | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Transrail Lighting IPO: GMP, subscription status, should you apply as issue ends tomorrow</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The Transrail Lighting Limited IPO is closing for subscriptions tomorrow, December 23. With a subscription rate of 5.31 times, investors are showing significant interest in the offer.</p><img src="<image-url-if-available>" alt="Transrail Lighting IPO" /><figcaption>Transrail Lighting IPO Overview</figcaption><ul><li>The IPO is open for bidding until December 23, 5 p.m.</li><li>It has been subscribed 5.31 times with 7,38,94,750 shares bid against 1,39,16,742 shares offered.</li><li>Grey market premium is at ₹175, suggesting a potential listing price of ₹607 per share.</li><li>Non-Institutional Investors have subscribed 7.23 times, while retail investors at 6.90 times.</li><li>Analysts recommend a 'Subscribe - Long Term' approach due to the growing demand for power infrastructure.</li></ul><blockquote>"The growing demand for power, coupled with government initiatives, has driven the need for transmission and distribution lines." - Anand Rathi</blockquote><p>The IPO is set for strong market placement, guided by optimism in governmental support and business capability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/transrail-lighting-ipo-gmp-subscription-status-should-you-apply-as-issue-ends-tomorrow-11734871416604.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/transrail-lighting-ipo-gmp-subscription-status-should-you-apply-as-issue-ends-tomorrow-11734871416604.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:41:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IPOs to Watch: Senores Pharma, Ventive Hospitality, Carraro India – which is worth subscribing to? - Trade Brains]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOdEdiT3lpMU5oSjdjNlVMMUhTcDZiaDAyOE43RzdpREE5Z1BUOU5MWXM1dTFkOUctOWQwemFxS0hCZEFwQVhEM2xIS2lXWXBGY3htVnJqcmFjUm9uMFdtcmFmRkJtUFZHak9nY01Ra25LNmNhbk5LQlUxOG1FRXdLb184WmlSdGFvcUVrOVhkakVwdUJQVnZhMG1OV05sN0pJenpLdUR5RzR4YTY3eDFnLXlFUGdEbVk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOdEdiT3lpMU5oSjdjNlVMMUhTcDZiaDAyOE43RzdpREE5Z1BUOU5MWXM1dTFkOUctOWQwemFxS0hCZEFwQVhEM2xIS2lXWXBGY3htVnJqcmFjUm9uMFdtcmFmRkJtUFZHak9nY01Ra25LNmNhbk5LQlUxOG1FRXdLb184WmlSdGFvcUVrOVhkakVwdUJQVnZhMG1OV05sN0pJenpLdUR5RzR4YTY3eDFnLXlFUGdEbVk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:33:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Name Of Document Isn’t Decisive Factor; Guarantee Not Part Of Document Just Because Title Contains Word... - Verdictum]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Ruling on Document Titles and Financial Creditor Status</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Verdictum</p>
<p>The Supreme Court held that the name of a document is not decisive in determining its nature. The ruling clarified that simply having the word hypothecation in a document's title does not imply that a guarantee is included.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The case involved appeals by the China Development Bank against the NCLAT's judgment.</li>
  <li>Justice Abhay S. Oka and Justice Pankaj Mithal emphasized that the title alone does not define the document or its implications.</li>
  <li>Financial Creditors can claim status under the IBC even if there is no default in payments.</li>
  <li>The Court affirmed that contract provisions are severable; invalid provisions do not affect the validity of the remaining ones.</li>
  <li>The judgment quashed the NCLAT's order, allowing the appellants' appeals.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Only the title of a document cannot be a decisive factor in deciding the nature of the document or the transactions affected by the document.”</blockquote>
<!-- No image provided in the article -->
<p>The Supreme Court's decision underscores the importance of interpreting contracts based on their content rather than their titles, impacting how financial creditor statuses are classified under the IBC.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.verdictum.in/court-updates/supreme-court/china-development-bank-v-doha-bank-qpsc-2024-insc-1029-document-name-title-1561907</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.verdictum.in/court-updates/supreme-court/china-development-bank-v-doha-bank-qpsc-2024-insc-1029-document-name-title-1561907</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:30:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bajaj Chetak 3502 - Top five highlights - BikeWale]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bajaj Chetak 3502 - Top Five Highlights</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> BikeWale</p><img src="https://imgd.aeplcdn.com/642x361/n/cw/ec/194539/chetak-right-front-three-quarter-4.jpeg?isig=0&amp;q=75" alt="Bajaj Chetak Right Front Three Quarter"><figcaption>Bajaj Chetak Right Front Three Quarter</figcaption><p>Bajaj Auto has expanded its electric scooter portfolio with the launch of the Chetak 35 series, including the mid-spec model, the Chetak 3502. Here are its top five highlights.</p><ul><li><strong>Design:</strong> The Chetak 3502 maintains a retro look with some tweaks, including a longer seat and improved underseat storage of 35 litres.</li><li><strong>Features:</strong> It includes a TFT display with smartphone connectivity, navigation, and two ride modes - Eco and Sports.</li><li><strong>Motor and Battery:</strong> Equipped with a 3.5kWh battery and a 4kW motor, offering a range of 153km and a top speed of 73kmph.</li><li><strong>Hardware:</strong> Features a monoshock setup and a combination of front disc and rear drum brakes.</li><li><strong>Price:</strong> Priced at Rs. 1,20,000 (ex-showroom, Bengaluru), making it Rs. 7,000 cheaper than the 3501 variant.</li></ul><blockquote>“The 3502’s battery charges up to 80 percent in three hours and 25 minutes.”</blockquote><p>The Bajaj Chetak 3502 stands out with its blend of classic design and modern features, making it a competitive choice in the electric scooter market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bikewale.com/news/bajaj-chetak-3502-top-five-highlights/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bikewale.com/news/bajaj-chetak-3502-top-five-highlights/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:16:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohan Mirchandani death: Radhika Gupta advices professionals to 'live the moments' as Epigamia CEO dies af - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingJBVV95cUxPeXg3RHBtY2J2M1BpVVpBSDZXMkNwU1dLSFJENEREYURYY3VxMnBiWWFVSTR3dnczLW90czFNeEswMERsWGY1bVVXWGZsTHh0TGczUEJCNXozaE0zM2l4dXUzWjItM3FjSjRfalk3YzZpMi03SW1EX0p3dDBlRHpzT0VJUmU3SmdyeDVKUl9ZT21RcUVVNFQyTG9Nb0dxMHg3U3Jmb1E2R2JXaEMyemdNNHVSTjlWR0sxaFdzT2NiWUNtTGhQSXlHUXU0eDJhR1J2Tm5GbTdPMHU4LWlGUHNlZXpEOTJVUkpqNDhjZUxGaXotb2VMQ1pKbG9fRmxsMWl3ZmlHV0x5UkRCcXV5Z29GUTh0U0FlUnRYaTZUOFlB0gGjAkFVX3lxTE5tNHdGMmtabUk3VjFOZk92ZmJCcERyOTAxWXdMNENYTTloRHUyeDc0Z0N2YlNwVWN5NlJqY3BqSm9icU9RemZMOVVkZWVmSnlvMzFISWJ5WVVwYUxYWTVLR1hTV1MtR09NVTBTQU1NRGFHWlNObVg3WkdaYzkzZlk3X0tmeDhpbHdHVnU1TW5qbkstTldnOEpOdlRFekxsbU0wNXl2LXlMMlJMNzhVZTBtdWNxeV9MdERfRXJYSGhYMFgxOTZLN0lCU1JLS0dXXzIyOW1XUnplZHM2dXYwLVZYVVVHMXJSQm5nVDNoZDRfcjdUTW16R1AwbHdlSzZvV1pjbjI0ai1zQ1dKNFI1M1gxRlM0d0NOdkpXTTBSM1MzSVBfTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingJBVV95cUxPeXg3RHBtY2J2M1BpVVpBSDZXMkNwU1dLSFJENEREYURYY3VxMnBiWWFVSTR3dnczLW90czFNeEswMERsWGY1bVVXWGZsTHh0TGczUEJCNXozaE0zM2l4dXUzWjItM3FjSjRfalk3YzZpMi03SW1EX0p3dDBlRHpzT0VJUmU3SmdyeDVKUl9ZT21RcUVVNFQyTG9Nb0dxMHg3U3Jmb1E2R2JXaEMyemdNNHVSTjlWR0sxaFdzT2NiWUNtTGhQSXlHUXU0eDJhR1J2Tm5GbTdPMHU4LWlGUHNlZXpEOTJVUkpqNDhjZUxGaXotb2VMQ1pKbG9fRmxsMWl3ZmlHV0x5UkRCcXV5Z29GUTh0U0FlUnRYaTZUOFlB0gGjAkFVX3lxTE5tNHdGMmtabUk3VjFOZk92ZmJCcERyOTAxWXdMNENYTTloRHUyeDc0Z0N2YlNwVWN5NlJqY3BqSm9icU9RemZMOVVkZWVmSnlvMzFISWJ5WVVwYUxYWTVLR1hTV1MtR09NVTBTQU1NRGFHWlNObVg3WkdaYzkzZlk3X0tmeDhpbHdHVnU1TW5qbkstTldnOEpOdlRFekxsbU0wNXl2LXlMMlJMNzhVZTBtdWNxeV9MdERfRXJYSGhYMFgxOTZLN0lCU1JLS0dXXzIyOW1XUnplZHM2dXYwLVZYVVVHMXJSQm5nVDNoZDRfcjdUTW16R1AwbHdlSzZvV1pjbjI0ai1zQ1dKNFI1M1gxRlM0d0NOdkpXTTBSM1MzSVBfTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:11:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Accenture’s hiring spree means for Indian IT industry | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What Accenture’s hiring spree means for Indian IT industry</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Accenture Plc’s renewed hiring—it added 49,000 people globally in the last six months—suggests technology services companies expect much better growth in the coming months. This hiring spree paints a positive outlook for homegrown IT services companies that are expected to record better growth in the coming quarters, according to analysts.</p>
<ul>
<li>Accenture added 49,000 employees globally in six months.</li>
<li>Analysts suggest better growth prospects for technology services companies.</li>
<li>The hiring trend indicates a sanguine outlook for the Indian IT sector.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Analysts indicated that the move reflects expectations of better growth in the tech sector.”</blockquote>
<p>The hiring activity from Accenture signifies optimism in the tech industry, particularly benefitting Indian IT services firms, leading to an anticipated acceleration in growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/what-accenture-s-hiring-spree-means-for-indian-it-11734862274497.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/what-accenture-s-hiring-spree-means-for-indian-it-11734862274497.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:07:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Nothing Short Of Nightmare": Woman Misses Life Event, Slams Air India - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/nothing-short-of-nightmare-journalist-shivani-bazaz-misses-life-event-slams-air-india-7308292</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/nothing-short-of-nightmare-journalist-shivani-bazaz-misses-life-event-slams-air-india-7308292</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:07:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Nightmare...": Air India Passenger Misses Life Event, Slams Airline - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxOc3lpRTJKRDB3ZDNSU0pWQWRKZHVvZkdYYlZQYmFyc21WeC1mOTgyVFFoMEwzUV9qZFdZcUJFTDNDbW10cExySU5oWnAyMUUxQlhpZjBfTm83OGlEMERheHZndkZLYll3cTNiZlJFN3BONUc4NE8zNWVqOC0zUVlCNmdFWkNINmpJby1rNm9hcUhnQllHUzVLR2xCZV9sSERNOVV5azZzck16dDYteUNndk81UFN6VjhxOWlhLXQzTG5zSEnSAcsBQVVfeXFMTVpaV19zby10VkVOZlNlZWg2d1JfOWlxUmF3TkhueU0zekRaeFpUM25pNmhPZl8wU2RZUnEtUGRHTWVKUWhfbmpHQVZwMkVxUlZDNllEd1JmZGFJek9EZGxTdkJNYW9xS0RHLUxhNlQ3Smo5UG1VMnVrWTlJOHZuRHoxcV9BWXQ5TnJMYUtYWXZHWWRXNlhPMDkyMHAtUno0VFI4TzVtNkZUd2dQc0tzVTBqaGctOGZacHlOelEtRDVPbmhNZ2Q5TThabmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxOc3lpRTJKRDB3ZDNSU0pWQWRKZHVvZkdYYlZQYmFyc21WeC1mOTgyVFFoMEwzUV9qZFdZcUJFTDNDbW10cExySU5oWnAyMUUxQlhpZjBfTm83OGlEMERheHZndkZLYll3cTNiZlJFN3BONUc4NE8zNWVqOC0zUVlCNmdFWkNINmpJby1rNm9hcUhnQllHUzVLR2xCZV9sSERNOVV5azZzck16dDYteUNndk81UFN6VjhxOWlhLXQzTG5zSEnSAcsBQVVfeXFMTVpaV19zby10VkVOZlNlZWg2d1JfOWlxUmF3TkhueU0zekRaeFpUM25pNmhPZl8wU2RZUnEtUGRHTWVKUWhfbmpHQVZwMkVxUlZDNllEd1JmZGFJek9EZGxTdkJNYW9xS0RHLUxhNlQ3Smo5UG1VMnVrWTlJOHZuRHoxcV9BWXQ5TnJMYUtYWXZHWWRXNlhPMDkyMHAtUno0VFI4TzVtNkZUd2dQc0tzVTBqaGctOGZacHlOelEtRDVPbmhNZ2Q5TThabmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:07:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senores Pharma IPO: GMP, subscription status, review, other details. Apply or not? | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Senores Pharma IPO: GMP, Subscription Status, and Analysis</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The IPO for Senores Pharmaceuticals Limited opened on December 20 and is expected to close on December 24. The IPO has garnered significant interest from investors.</p><img src='image_url_if_available' alt='Senores Pharma IPO' /><figcaption>Senores Pharma IPO Overview</figcaption><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>The IPO was subscribed 1.78 times, with 1,51,86,662 shares applied against 85,34,681 shares offered.</li><li>The price band is set between ₹372 and ₹381 per share, with a lot size of 38 shares.</li><li>The grey market premium is currently ₹200 per share, suggesting a listing price of ₹591.</li><li>Retail investors showed strong demand, bidding at 7.20x the retail portion of the offer.</li><li>Analysts recommend a “Subscribe” rating based on a fair valuation of the company.</li></ul><blockquote>“At the upper price band, the company is valued at P/E of 55x.” - Anand Rathi</blockquote><p>The funds raised will be used for subsidiary investments and repayment of borrowings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/senores-pharma-ipo-gmp-subscription-status-review-other-details-apply-or-not-11734864687364.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/senores-pharma-ipo-gmp-subscription-status-review-other-details-apply-or-not-11734864687364.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 12:41:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sterling And Wilson Wins Rs 1,200 Crore Order In Gujarat - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/business/sterling-and-wilson-wins-rs-1200-crore-order-in-gujarat</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/business/sterling-and-wilson-wins-rs-1200-crore-order-in-gujarat</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 12:37:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>