<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Business Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:50:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:50:37 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BYD Sealion 7 to debut at Bharat Mobility Global Expo, launch in March 2025 - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BYD Sealion 7 to debut at Bharat Mobility Global Expo, launch in March 2025</h1><p><strong>Published on Jan 08 2025 | Source: Business Standard</strong></p><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" alt="BYD Sealion" title="BYD Sealion" width="826" height="465"><figcaption>BYD Sealion</figcaption><p>The BYD Sealion 7 is all set to make its debut at the upcoming Bharat Mobility Global Expo in March 2025. This affordable coupe SUV, inspired by the BY Seal, features advanced technology and impressive design.</p><ul><li>Unveiled last year in China, it serves as an alternative to the Tesla Model Y.</li><li>It includes a 360-degree camera system for enhanced safety.</li><li>The SUV offers two battery options with a maximum range of up to 502 km.</li><li>Expected to compete with EVs like Kia EV6 and Hyundai Ioniq 5 in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Sealion 7 is built on BYD’s e-Platform 3.0 Evo and features the brand’s Blade battery technology.”</blockquote><p>This new model is anticipated to attract significant attention at the expo and in the Indian market upon its official launch.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/auto-expo/news/byd-sealion-7-to-debut-at-bharat-mobility-global-expo-launch-in-march-2025-125010800118_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/auto-expo/news/byd-sealion-7-to-debut-at-bharat-mobility-global-expo-launch-in-march-2025-125010800118_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:16:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Getty Images, Shutterstock gear up for AI challenge with $3.7 billion merger - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Getty Images and Shutterstock Merge in $3.7 Billion Deal to Face AI Challenges</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 7, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/BT6WOT3B5ROI7BLLIKB22MFFHY.jpg?auth=ce3da8331f74b2d89485809f5c854e431431d620d5a18f9d5d32207dcd82c073&amp;width=4646&amp;quality=80" alt="Craig Peters, CEO of Getty Images, speaks during an interview on the floor of the NYSE in New York" /><figcaption>Craig Peters, CEO of Getty Images, speaks during an interview on the floor of the NYSE in New York City, U.S., August 15, 2022.</figcaption><p>The merger between Getty Images and Shutterstock aims to create a powerhouse in the stock-image industry, valued at $3.7 billion, to adapt to challenges posed by artificial intelligence technology.</p><ul><li>Getty Images is merging with rival Shutterstock to combat challenges from growing AI tools.</li><li>The deal is notable for its potential antitrust scrutiny from regulators.</li><li>Shutterstock shareholders will have several options in the merger, including cash or stock from Getty.</li><li>The combined company will lead with nearly $2 billion in annual revenues.</li><li>Getty’s CEO Craig Peters expresses confidence in securing antitrust approval.</li><li>The merger may yield up to $200 million in cost savings within three years.</li></ul><blockquote>"We don't control the timing of (the approval), but we have a high confidence. This has been a situation where customers have not had choice. They've always had choice," said Craig Peters.</blockquote><p>This merger reflects an adaptive strategy in response to new technological threats in the visual content industry and highlights the evolving landscape with AI integration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/shutterstock-merge-with-getty-images-deal-valued-37-billion-2025-01-07/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/shutterstock-merge-with-getty-images-deal-valued-37-billion-2025-01-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 20:38:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Getty Images, Shutterstock gear up for AI challenge with $3.7 billion merger - Reuters.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/shutterstock-merge-with-getty-images-deal-valued-37-billion-2025-01-07/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/shutterstock-merge-with-getty-images-deal-valued-37-billion-2025-01-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 20:38:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple sacks desi employees for 'misusing' donation plan - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Fires Employees Over Misuse of Donation Program</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Apple logo"/><figcaption>Apple logo</figcaption><p>Apple has recently terminated employment for a number of its employees, citing misuse of a donation initiative intended to aid charitable causes. The move has provoked discussions regarding corporate ethics and employee behavior.</p><ul><li>The termination was due to alleged misuse of a company donation program.</li><li>Apple emphasizes its commitment to charitable contributions and ethical behavior.</li><li>The incident is under scrutiny and raises questions about employee oversight and corporate responsibility.</li></ul><blockquote>"Our donation program is designed to support those in need, and misuse cannot be tolerated," a company spokesperson remarked.</blockquote><p>This incident brings to light the importance of maintaining ethical standards in corporate contributions and the potential consequences for violations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/apple-sacks-desi-employees-for-misusing-donation-plan/articleshow/117034813.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/apple-sacks-desi-employees-for-misusing-donation-plan/articleshow/117034813.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 20:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here is TRUTH behind 'QuantumScape CEO Jagdeep Singh's Rs 48 cr daily earnings, highest salary in the world' viral claim | ET NOW VERIFIED - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowJBVV95cUxPX2FubkZCZ0EtdFVtYTBmQTN5eTJzVTJnRDBMS1BlaXBLQ3R6cHlnQmR2NHlIQkpuekJ3amF1dXBwd05nMFA1SmE3RGVnMGRTVXRab2RmRFAxTUZHUXpzNUhVd3J5RHY0SndPbHMyVnVwVEJhZGJUMXp0U3FGZ0lFd0xxN2Y0ODVzMDJrUkE5MTdtUnFtaWdzZzFQQ2o2bFJaM2F5d3FfcTB6TWpTdHhEZUdpSHQ2SVJSQ1c4amtFNnV6NVJlZDREM3ZSMnB2LUdXUXhidzZ5N0Nac0QtSWl5ckdiX1N3QS1aaGFla2ZhVnBHMmRRckxfYk1ReXJEMHRkMXNjSG1Od09Kd1J1c0Vqd3VWdXdmWEJuY1NGaTBNemgtV0XSAagCQVVfeXFMTjUtNjdfRHRSeDh3bUlXSU00a0twYm56SjZPTTMwSGREYlEwNzB1T1o1b1lDOWt4M2xnSGNkalRWT3gzbExicGo5QXNCUk9sSjhJYkV2QlpTRlhnVUx5YjB4dU4teEFXSW9tMW1RbmdKb3ZiQWF6bU9hVEJIS2dWU2RqcE9fbUFDbUxxWnM2Rk0wUkVuamFEOVlSV3FnQjhlNGpHUmJjRkFQTlpoNDFZNHdyM3docmVDQTVNRGNNdGw1WWQ1RzFzV2pLNFZXOFVKYUhLNmpxMGIzZkNHWmhnN0xkWWlDbVY3eXdOQkx5SlFESjdMbmM3MU13c3ZCN2ZNS3Z3SGpiNU90MmhKMzNOQVRDalRpLUhLWkJsQTBBeWF5b0t2TkZscVI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowJBVV95cUxPX2FubkZCZ0EtdFVtYTBmQTN5eTJzVTJnRDBMS1BlaXBLQ3R6cHlnQmR2NHlIQkpuekJ3amF1dXBwd05nMFA1SmE3RGVnMGRTVXRab2RmRFAxTUZHUXpzNUhVd3J5RHY0SndPbHMyVnVwVEJhZGJUMXp0U3FGZ0lFd0xxN2Y0ODVzMDJrUkE5MTdtUnFtaWdzZzFQQ2o2bFJaM2F5d3FfcTB6TWpTdHhEZUdpSHQ2SVJSQ1c4amtFNnV6NVJlZDREM3ZSMnB2LUdXUXhidzZ5N0Nac0QtSWl5ckdiX1N3QS1aaGFla2ZhVnBHMmRRckxfYk1ReXJEMHRkMXNjSG1Od09Kd1J1c0Vqd3VWdXdmWEJuY1NGaTBNemgtV0XSAagCQVVfeXFMTjUtNjdfRHRSeDh3bUlXSU00a0twYm56SjZPTTMwSGREYlEwNzB1T1o1b1lDOWt4M2xnSGNkalRWT3gzbExicGo5QXNCUk9sSjhJYkV2QlpTRlhnVUx5YjB4dU4teEFXSW9tMW1RbmdKb3ZiQWF6bU9hVEJIS2dWU2RqcE9fbUFDbUxxWnM2Rk0wUkVuamFEOVlSV3FnQjhlNGpHUmJjRkFQTlpoNDFZNHdyM3docmVDQTVNRGNNdGw1WWQ1RzFzV2pLNFZXOFVKYUhLNmpxMGIzZkNHWmhnN0xkWWlDbVY3eXdOQkx5SlFESjdMbmM3MU13c3ZCN2ZNS3Z3SGpiNU90MmhKMzNOQVRDalRpLUhLWkJsQTBBeWF5b0t2TkZscVI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:57:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Tech Trends of 2025: AI-powered everything - Capgemini]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Tech Trends for 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Capgemini</p>
<img src="https://www.capgemini.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Top-tech-trends-2025-Generative-AI.jpg" alt="Generative AI" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Generative AI: From copilots to reasoning AI agents</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the critical technology trends expected to shape businesses in 2025, with a focus on AI and its applications across various industries.</p>
<ul>
<li>The major impact of AI and Gen AI on business priorities and technology domains.</li>
<li>AI in cybersecurity ranks as the top most impactful trend for 2025.</li>
<li>AI-driven robotics will enhance productivity and safety in workplaces.</li>
<li>Nuclear energy is poised for a resurgence in response to the energy demands of AI technologies.</li>
<li>New-generation supply chains will leverage AI and other technologies to improve efficiency and sustainability.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In 2025, we see AI and Gen AI having a major impact on companies’ priorities and also on many adjacent technology domains, such as robotics, supply chains, or tomorrow’s energy mix.”</blockquote>
<p>Organizations are advised to leverage these trends to drive innovation and competitive advantage in the fast-evolving digital landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.capgemini.com/insights/research-library/top-tech-trends-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.capgemini.com/insights/research-library/top-tech-trends-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:35:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's one-word take on alarming population decline in India and China - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk's One-Word Reaction to Population Decline in India and China</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>An alarming decrease in population growth in India and China has drawn a succinct yet impactful response from Elon Musk.</p><ul><li>Musk refers to the population decline as 'Alarming'.</li><li>Both countries are facing significant demographic challenges.</li><li>The impact could have far-reaching implications on the global economy and labor markets.</li></ul><blockquote>'This trend signals potential challenges for future economic growth.' - Elon Musk</blockquote><p>As major players in the global economy, India and China's demographic shifts could reshape international markets and geopolitical dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musks-one-word-take-on-alarming-population-decline-in-india-and-china/articleshow/117032603.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musks-one-word-take-on-alarming-population-decline-in-india-and-china/articleshow/117032603.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to Watch on January 8: Tata Steel, RVNL, NTPC, Jindal Worldwide and more - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stocks to Watch on January 8: Tata Steel, RVNL, NTPC, Jindal Worldwide and more</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Tata Steel, top stocks, stocks to watch, today stock to watch"><figcaption></figcaption><p>This article highlights key stocks to monitor for market trends today, featuring insights into Tata Steel, RVNL, NTPC, Jindal Worldwide, and others.</p><ul><li><strong>Tata Steel:</strong> Reported a 6.17% YoY increase in crude steel production in Q3FY25, reaching 5.68 million tonnes.</li><li><strong>RVNL:</strong> Signed a MoU with GBHIC for civil infrastructure projects in the GCC region.</li><li><strong>NTPC:</strong> Established a subsidiary, NPUNL, to lead nuclear energy initiatives.</li><li><strong>Jindal Worldwide:</strong> Announced a 4:1 bonus share issuance, pending shareholder approval.</li><li><strong>Tata Technologies:</strong> Partnered with Telechips to advance software solutions for SDVs.</li><li><strong>Birlasoft:</strong> CEO Roopinder Singh resigns for personal reasons.</li><li><strong>WPIL:</strong> Acquired 100% of MISA S.R.L, enhancing its presence in pump technology.</li></ul><blockquote>“The partnership aims to leverage the strengths of both entities to pursue business opportunities in the growing infrastructure sector.”</blockquote><p>The stocks mentioned are essential for investors to keep an eye on today due to their significant developments, which may impact market performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/stocks/stocks-to-watch-on-january-8-tata-steel-rvnl-ntpc-jindal-worldwide-and-more-19536149.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/stocks/stocks-to-watch-on-january-8-tata-steel-rvnl-ntpc-jindal-worldwide-and-more-19536149.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 16:28:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ExplainSpeaking: What the latest GDP estimates tell about the state of India’s economy - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ExplainSpeaking: What the latest GDP estimates tell about the state of India’s economy</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/TABLE-1.jpg?resize=600,266" alt="GDP Trends">
<figcaption>Table 1: GDP Trends Analysis</figcaption>
<p>The Ministry of Statistics and Programme Implementation (MoSPI) has released the First Advance Estimates (FAEs) of India’s GDP growth for the financial year 2024-25. These estimates suggest that India's nominal GDP is projected to reach Rs 324 lakh crores, growing 9.7% over the previous financial year.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The estimated nominal GDP for FY25 is $3.8 trillion at the exchange rate of 85 rupees to a dollar.</li>
  <li>Real GDP is expected to be Rs 184.9 lakh crores, accounting for 57% of nominal GDP, indicating a growth deceleration.</li>
  <li>Private consumption demand (PFCE) plays a crucial role, contributing almost 60% to GDP.</li>
  <li>Government spending growth has been slow, averaging just 4.2% for the current year.</li>
  <li>Investments have stalled since 2014, leading to reduced productive capacity growth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"When one considers a slightly longer period, it becomes clear that India’s real economy is growing at less than 5% per annum."
</blockquote>
<p>The latest GDP figures serve as a reality check, revealing that while India's growth appears strong, much of this is boosted by a low base effect from the pandemic's economic contraction.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/gdp-estimates-india-economy-9765608/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/gdp-estimates-india-economy-9765608/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 16:07:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold rallies as concerns swell over US debt and upcoming bond auctions for this week - FXStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold pops as concerns on rates and inflation in the US grow again after red hot ISM Services report</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 7, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> FXStreet</p>
<img alt="XAU/USD: Daily Chart" src="https://editorial.fxsstatic.com/miscelaneous/_XAU_USD_2025-01-07_15-43-48-638718578471894441.png">
<figcaption>XAU/USD: Daily Chart</figcaption>
<p>Gold price sees upward momentum as markets react to increasing concerns over US debt issuances and inflation following a strong ISM Services report.</p>
<ul>
  <li>US markets are preparing for substantial debt issuances, raising concerns about potential increases in interest rates.</li>
  <li>The ISM Services sector report indicated inflationary pressures, which negatively affected expectations for interest rate cuts by the Federal Reserve.</li>
  <li>Gold prices are stabilizing within a tactical formation, with upward and downward trends noted.</li>
  <li>The US 10-year yield has reached an eight-month high due to inflation concerns.</li>
  <li>Market speculations suggest that significant reactions to the new administration's tariff plans could influence gold prices.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"A stronger position for gold can be expected if patterns become clearer amid the ongoing economic tensions."</blockquote>
<p>The article emphasizes the uncertainty in financial markets and the pivotal role of gold as a hedge against inflation in turbulent economic times.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-consolidates-amid-expectations-about-us-tariff-plans-202501071235</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fxstreet.com/news/gold-price-consolidates-amid-expectations-about-us-tariff-plans-202501071235</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:39:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahindra XEV 9e, BE 6 top variant prices announced; Check battery range, features, booking dates here - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahindra XEV 9e, BE 6 top variant prices announced; Check battery range, features, booking dates here</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Tuesday<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>Mahindra and Mahindra has unveiled the prices for its electric SUVs, the Mahindra XEV 9e and BE 6, with various options and features designed for consumers eager for electric vehicle options.</p>
<h2>Key Points</h2>
<ul>
<li>The Mahindra XEV 9e is priced at Rs 30.90 lakh for the top variant with a 79 kWh battery.</li>
<li>The BE 6 top-spec variant will retail at Rs 26.9 lakh.</li>
<li>Bookings for both SUVs will commence on February 14, with test drives starting January 14.</li>
<li>Deliveries of the XEV 9e will begin in March 2025, while the BE 6 deliveries are expected in early March.</li>
<li>The XEV 9e features two battery options (59kWh and 79kWh) and claims a range of 656km on the MIDC cycle.</li>
<li>Both models come equipped with advanced technology like a three-screen setup, augmented reality head-up displays, and a comprehensive ADAS suite.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>“The 79kWh battery can be charged from 20 to 80 percent in 20 minutes using a 175kW DC fast charger.”</p>
</blockquote>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Mahindra’s new electric SUVs promise exciting features and competitive pricing, catering to the growing market for electric vehicles in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/renewables/mahindra-xev-9e-be-6-top-variant-prices-announced-check-battery-range-features-booking-dates-here/articleshow/117029707.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/renewables/mahindra-xev-9e-be-6-top-variant-prices-announced-check-battery-range-features-booking-dates-here/articleshow/117029707.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:09:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unlocking value: These 6 mutual funds offered over 15% annual returns in last 10 years; should you invest? | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unlocking Value: These 6 Mutual Funds Offered Over 15% Annual Returns in Last 10 Years; Should You Invest?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Prior to investing in a mutual fund, investors should evaluate the performance of various schemes to understand historical trends and set realistic expectations for future performance.</p><h2>What are Value Funds?</h2><p>Value mutual funds follow a strategy focused on identifying undervalued stocks, investing at least 65% in stocks.</p><h2>These Funds Gave Record Performance in 10 Years</h2><figure><table><thead><tr><th>Value Funds</th><th>10-Year Returns (%)</th><th>AUM (₹ crore)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Bandhan Sterling Value Fund</td><td>15.12</td><td>9,843.17</td></tr><tr><td>HSBC Value Fund</td><td>16.80</td><td>13,391.19</td></tr><tr><td>ICICI Prudential Value Discovery Fund</td><td>15.17</td><td>48,439.21</td></tr><tr><td>JM Value Fund</td><td>17.40</td><td>1,095.15</td></tr><tr><td>Nippon India Value Fund</td><td>15.92</td><td>8,496.36</td></tr><tr><td>Tata Equity PE Fund</td><td>15.00</td><td>8,444.31</td></tr></tbody></table></figure><p><i>Source: AMFI; Returns as of January 6, 2025</i></p><p>The JM Value Fund had the highest return at 17.40%, while the ICICI Prudential Value Discovery Fund is the largest in terms of assets managed.</p><blockquote><i>This story is for informational purposes only. Please speak to a SEBI-registered investment advisor before making any investment-related decision.</i></blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/unlocking-value-6-funds-that-outperformed-with-over-15-per-cent-annualised-returns-over-a-decade-11736255880467.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/unlocking-value-6-funds-that-outperformed-with-over-15-per-cent-annualised-returns-over-a-decade-11736255880467.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:51:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Market Trading Guide: JK Cement, Pfizer among stock recommendations for Wednesday - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Market Trading Guide: JK Cement, Pfizer among 4 stock recommendations for Wednesday</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-117029107,width-640,resizemode-4,imgsize-57988/stock-ideas.jpg" alt="Stock Ideas">
<figcaption>Indian frontline indices broke their two-sessions losing streak on Tuesday after assurances poured-in from various quarters including the government that the Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) was not lethal and unlike the Covid-19 virus. Banks and energy stocks helped the markets sail through.</figcaption>
<p>On January 7, the S&amp;P BSE Sensex settled at 78,199.11, up by 234.12 points or 0.30%. The broader Nifty closed at 23,707.90, higher by 91.85 points or 0.39%. Jatin Gedia, a Technical Research Analyst at Mirae Asset Sharekhan, provided insights into market trends and recommended investors to monitor key support and resistance levels.</p>
<p>Here are 4 stock recommendations for Wednesday:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Buy J K Cement at Rs 4,823.55:</strong> Target Price: Rs 5,050, Stop Loss: Rs 4,700</li>
<li><strong>Buy Datamatics Global Services at Rs 696.9:</strong> Target Price: Rs 760, Stop Loss: Rs 670</li>
<li><strong>Buy Pfizer at Rs 5,350:</strong> Target Price: Rs 5,780, Stop Loss: Rs 5,025</li>
<li><strong>Buy Minda Corp at Rs 534:</strong> Target Price: Rs 585, Stop Loss: Rs 495</li>
</ul>
<p>(Disclaimer: Recommendations, suggestions, views, and opinions given by the experts are their own. These do not represent the views of Economic Times)</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/market-trading-guide-jk-cement-pfizer-among-stock-recommendations-for-wednesday/stock-ideas/slideshow/117029107.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/market-trading-guide-jk-cement-pfizer-among-stock-recommendations-for-wednesday/stock-ideas/slideshow/117029107.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:38:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quadrant Future Tek IPO: Issue subscribed 15.86 times on day 1; check details here | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Quadrant Future Tek IPO: Issue subscribed 15.86 times on day 1; check details here</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025; <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The initial public offering (IPO) of Quadrant Future Tek opened for subscription today, January 7, and saw exceptional interest, being subscribed over 15.86 times on the first day.</p><ul><li>The IPO received bids for 9,18,47,850 shares against the offered 57,99,999 equity shares.</li><li>The price band for the shares is set between ₹275-290.</li><li>Retail and Non-Institutional portions were significantly oversubscribed at 54.84 times and 21.51 times, respectively.</li><li>Qualified Institutional Buyer portion received only 0.05 times subscription.</li><li>The company aims to raise ₹290 crore from this fresh issue.</li><li>Notable anchor investors included Citigroup, Capri Global, and various mutual funds.</li></ul><p>Link Intime India Private Limited is the official registrar, while Sundae Capital Advisors acts as the lead manager for the public issue.</p><blockquote>“Quadrant is a research-oriented company engaged in developing new generation Train Control and Signalling Systems for Indian Railways.”</blockquote><p>This IPO marks a significant step for Quadrant Future Tek as it seeks to enhance operational capabilities and expand its market presence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/quadrant-future-tek-ipo-issue-subscribed-15-86-times-on-day-1-check-details-here-11736259793319.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/quadrant-future-tek-ipo-issue-subscribed-15-86-times-on-day-1-check-details-here-11736259793319.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:37:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Temasek nears deal to buy 10% stake in Haldiram at $10 billion valuation - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Temasek Approaches Deal for 10% Stake in Haldiram Valued at $10 Billion</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>After prolonged negotiations, Singapore government-owned investment firm Temasek is nearing a deal to acquire a 10 per cent stake in Haldiram Snacks Foods, with a valuation of $10 billion.</p><ul><li>Temasek and the Agrawal family have signed a term sheet for the sale.</li><li>Other PE firms, including Bain Capital and Blackstone, also made offers.</li><li>Temasek plans to conduct due diligence and make a binding offer within a month.</li><li>Potential listing of Haldiram within a year to take advantage of the IPO boom.</li><li>Temasek's focus includes significant investments in healthcare and consumer products in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“Haldiram Snacks reported revenue of Rs 6,375 crore in FY23, up from Rs 5,195 crore in FY22.”</blockquote><p>This transaction could reshape the investment landscape of India's consumer products sector, with Temasek looking to increase its footprint in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/temasek-nears-deal-to-buy-10-stake-in-haldiram-at-10-billion-valuation-125010701157_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/temasek-nears-deal-to-buy-10-stake-in-haldiram-at-10-billion-valuation-125010701157_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:36:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Temasek nears deal to buy 10% stake in Haldiram's at $10 billion valuation - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Temasek nears deal to buy 10% stake in Haldiram's at $10 billion valuation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img alt="Haldiram Chart" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>Projected Haldiram's Valuation Chart</figcaption><p>Temasek is close to finalizing a deal to acquire a 10% stake in Haldiram Snacks Foods, valued at $10 billion, from the Agrawal family. The deal, if completed, could be one of the largest in India.</p><ul><li>Temasek has signed a term sheet with the promoters of Haldiram Snacks Foods.</li><li>This opportunity comes after competing offers from private equity firms, including Blackstone and Bain Capital.</li><li>The firm is proceeding with due diligence and anticipates making a binding offer soon.</li><li>Haldiram Snacks reported an impressive revenue growth in FY23, achieving revenues of Rs 6,375 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“Temasek plans to invest $10 billion in India by 2027.”</blockquote><p>The potential acquisition is a strategic move by Temasek aimed at tapping into the growing consumer products sector in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/temasek-nears-deal-to-buy-10-stake-in-haldiram-at-10-billion-valuation-125010701157_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/companies/news/temasek-nears-deal-to-buy-10-stake-in-haldiram-at-10-billion-valuation-125010701157_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:36:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OYO Results: Hotels chain operator reports ₹114.64 crore net profit in FY2024, revenue drop 15% | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OYO Results: Hotels chain operator reports ₹114.64 crore net profit in FY2024, revenue drop 15%</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> March 2024, <a href="https://www.livemint.com/">Live Mint</a></p>
<p>OYO Hotels and Homes Pvt. Ltd. has reported a net profit for FY2024, despite a significant drop in operational revenue compared to the previous year.</p>
<ul>
<li>The company reported a net profit of ₹114.64 crore for FY2024, an improvement from the previous year's loss.</li>
<li>Operational revenue decreased by 15%, totaling ₹1,112.83 crore.</li>
<li>OYO achieved its first positive EBITDA since 2020, reported at ₹153 crore.</li>
<li>Total revenue for March 2024 was ₹1,179 crore, compared to ₹1,400 crore in the previous year.</li>
<li>OYO's first-ever post-tax profit was ₹229 crore, exceeding earlier profit projections.</li>
<li>Earnings per share improved to approximately ₹0.36 from a loss of ₹1.93 per share in FY23.</li>
<li>The company expanded its hotel portfolio significantly, growing inventory from 12,938 to 18,103 hotels.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The company's reported profits for FY24 significantly exceeded CEO Ritesh Agarwal's earlier projection of ₹100 crore.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, OYO's financial recovery in FY2024 is notable, highlighting a turnaround amidst declining revenue but with an expansion in its hotel operations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/company-results/oyo-results-hotels-chain-operator-earned-rs-114-64-crore-net-profit-in-fy2024-revenues-drop-15-11736253001817.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/company-results/oyo-results-hotels-chain-operator-earned-rs-114-64-crore-net-profit-in-fy2024-revenues-drop-15-11736253001817.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:27:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NSE to add 6 more stocks in F&O contracts from January 31 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NSE to Add 6 More Stocks in F&O Contracts from January 31</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The National Stock Exchange of India (NSE) will introduce futures and options contracts for six new securities beginning January 31, 2025, following regulatory approval.</p><img src='URL_TO_IMAGE' alt='NSE Announcement' /><figcaption>NSE's new F&O contracts announcement</figcaption><p>This decision aligns with SEBI's stock selection guidelines and introduces the following securities to the F&O segment:</p><ul><li>Castrol India Ltd</li><li>Gland Pharma Ltd</li><li>NBCC (India) Ltd</li><li>The Phoenix Mills Ltd</li><li>Solar Industries India Ltd</li><li>Torrent Power Ltd</li></ul><p>Furthermore, the NSE recently removed F&O contracts for 16 other securities, effective February 28, 2025.</p><blockquote>“This decision reinforces our commitment to enhance trading opportunities in line with regulatory guidelines.” - NSE representative</blockquote><p>This change is part of an ongoing effort to adjust the market offerings and improve trading conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/nse-to-add-6-more-stocks-in-f-o-contracts-from-january-31-11736258544521.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/nse-to-add-6-more-stocks-in-f-o-contracts-from-january-31-11736258544521.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:21:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCLAT approves merger between Equinox India and Embassy Group - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NCLAT Approves Merger of Equinox India and Embassy Group</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-07T14:08:12.720Z" title="2025-01-07 14:08">07 Jan 2025, 2:08 pm</time></p>
<p>The National Company Law Appellate Tribunal (NCLAT) has approved the merger between Equinox India Developments and Embassy Group, overturning a previous NCLT ruling that halted the merger.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The NCLAT ruled against objections raised by a minor shareholder regarding the merger.</li>
  <li>The process received overwhelming support from 99.9987% of equity shareholders.</li>
  <li>The merger was assessed and approved by the Competition Commission of India.</li>
  <li>Valuation discrepancies raised by the Income Tax Department were addressed satisfactorily.</li>
  <li>The NCLAT emphasized the judicial wisdom of shareholders and creditors in approving the scheme.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“After going through the facts and circumstances... we hold that Ld. NCLT, Chandigarh has erred in interfering in the Scheme ignoring the commercial wisdom of shareholders...”</blockquote>
<p>The ruling allows the merger to proceed while stating that the Income Tax Department can still take action to protect revenue interests.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/nclat-approves-merger-equinox-india-and-embassy-group</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/nclat-approves-merger-equinox-india-and-embassy-group</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:08:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg's Meta to replace third-party fact-checkers with community notes like ‘X’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meta's Shift: Community Notes Replace Third-Party Fact-Checkers</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Mark_Zuckerberg_Meme_Viral_Video_Favourite_1728012954234_1736257846286.jpg" alt="Mark Zuckerberg remarked that fact checkers have just been too politically biased. (Bloomberg)"><figcaption>Mark Zuckerberg remarked that fact checkers have just been too politically biased. (Bloomberg)</figcaption><p>Meta has announced plans to replace its third-party fact-checking program with a community notes system, similar to the model on X (formerly Twitter), starting in the United States. This decision is based on the belief that expert fact-checkers carry biases and contribute to a loss of trust.</p><ul><li>Meta will begin scrapping the third-party fact-checking program in the US.</li><li>Mark Zuckerberg highlighted that fact-checkers have been politically biased.</li><li>The new community notes approach aims to empower users in determining misleading posts.</li><li>Meta plans to allow more speech by lifting restrictions on certain topics.</li><li>Zuckerberg expressed that recent US elections signify a cultural shift towards prioritizing speech.</li><li>Meta intends to move its trust and safety teams from California to Texas to combat perceived bias.</li><li>The company will also reverse its 2021 policy that reduced political content visibility.</li></ul><blockquote>“We're going to get rid of fact-checkers and replace them with community notes similar to X (formerly Twitter), starting in the US.” - Mark Zuckerberg</blockquote><p>This shift reflects Meta's effort to restore trust and move towards a more community-driven approach in content moderation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/mark-zuckerbergs-meta-to-replace-fact-checking-with-community-notes-x-101736257587422.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/mark-zuckerbergs-meta-to-replace-fact-checking-with-community-notes-x-101736257587422.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:53:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aakash Institute tells NCLT it urgently needs funds to sustain operations - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aakash Institute Urgently Seeks Funds Amid Legal Battles</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 07 Jan 2025, 1:30 pm</p><p>Coaching giant Aakash Education Services has informed the National Company Law Tribunal (NCLT) that it urgently needs to raise funds to sustain its operations amid ongoing legal disputes.</p><ul><li>Aakash has pleaded with the NCLT to vacate a stay that is affecting its funding efforts.</li><li>The institute employs 5,000 staff and caters to 3.5 lakh students.</li><li>Manipal Systems is identified as the key entity that can provide the necessary funds.</li><li>The legal challenges arise from a proposed amendment to Aakash's Articles of Association that Singapore Topco opposes.</li><li>The Karnataka High Court and Supreme Court have been involved in the case, impacting the procedural timeline.</li></ul><blockquote>“These are physical classes. We have 5,000 teaching and non-teaching staff and 3.5 lakh students. We need to raise funds.” - Senior Advocate CK Nandakumar</blockquote><p>The case has been adjourned to January 21 for further proceedings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/aakash-institute-tells-nclt-it-urgently-needs-funds-sustain-operations</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/aakash-institute-tells-nclt-it-urgently-needs-funds-sustain-operations</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:30:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India’s Most Affordable SUV With Range Rover Features Launched! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxOVFdTdWdraFVJUU12ZzBXY1BaX2Q0T2FWckwwd0RGc1VpdjRoRU14VGYwMEwwVHVwdUItTmxPekdwZlIzT2VhUFd4SEg1MXdfSHNlUVpyQTVRYUxoLWpkbkFqWk9jOW1qNFR5Mzc0WmEtRXREb213dWN3Mk15eGxPZ3YwYkNtZWdlYmhhR096U1dSSU54Sm5WNnRtMjRKQdIBngFBVV95cUxOVFdTdWdraFVJUU12ZzBXY1BaX2Q0T2FWckwwd0RGc1VpdjRoRU14VGYwMEwwVHVwdUItTmxPekdwZlIzT2VhUFd4SEg1MXdfSHNlUVpyQTVRYUxoLWpkbkFqWk9jOW1qNFR5Mzc0WmEtRXREb213dWN3Mk15eGxPZ3YwYkNtZWdlYmhhR096U1dSSU54Sm5WNnRtMjRKQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxOVFdTdWdraFVJUU12ZzBXY1BaX2Q0T2FWckwwd0RGc1VpdjRoRU14VGYwMEwwVHVwdUItTmxPekdwZlIzT2VhUFd4SEg1MXdfSHNlUVpyQTVRYUxoLWpkbkFqWk9jOW1qNFR5Mzc0WmEtRXREb213dWN3Mk15eGxPZ3YwYkNtZWdlYmhhR096U1dSSU54Sm5WNnRtMjRKQdIBngFBVV95cUxOVFdTdWdraFVJUU12ZzBXY1BaX2Q0T2FWckwwd0RGc1VpdjRoRU14VGYwMEwwVHVwdUItTmxPekdwZlIzT2VhUFd4SEg1MXdfSHNlUVpyQTVRYUxoLWpkbkFqWk9jOW1qNFR5Mzc0WmEtRXREb213dWN3Mk15eGxPZ3YwYkNtZWdlYmhhR096U1dSSU54Sm5WNnRtMjRKQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple fires 185 employees over fraudulent donations scheme, including several Indians: Report | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple fires 185 employees over fraudulent donations scheme, including several Indians: Report</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>October 2023, <strong>Source: </strong>India Today</p><p>Tech giant Apple has fired 185 employees in Cupertino as part of an investigation into fraudulent activities within its charitable Matching Grants program.</p><ul><li>Employees collaborated with non-profits to falsify donations for personal gain.</li><li>Six individuals identified as part of the scheme allegedly defrauded Apple of approximately $152,000.</li><li>The fraudulent activities also involved tax evasion related to fictitious donations.</li><li>Many of the terminated employees reportedly have connections to the Indian community.</li></ul><blockquote>“These individuals defrauded Apple of approximately $152,000 over a three-year period,” stated the Santa Clara County district attorney’s office.</blockquote><p>The situation continues to unfold as investigations by the district attorney’s office persist, reflecting on an alarming misuse of corporate social responsibility programs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/apple-fires-185-employees-over-fraudulent-donations-scheme-including-several-indians-report-11736256090888.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/apple-fires-185-employees-over-fraudulent-donations-scheme-including-several-indians-report-11736256090888.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:28:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru Metro’s Yellow Line to Electronic City likely to start operations with two trains - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru Metro Plans to Open Yellow Line to Electronic City by 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/yellow-line.jpg?w=640" alt="Yellow line, bmrcl, metro, bangalore" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>BMRCL is looking at operationalising the Yellow Line connecting to Electronic City by March/April. (Express Image)</figcaption>
<p>Bengaluru Metro Rail Corporation Limited (BMRCL) is set to operationalize the Yellow Line to Electronic City by March/April 2025, starting with just two driverless trains.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The first driverless train from Titagarh Rail System Ltd has been dispatched and will arrive in Bengaluru by January 15.</li>
  <li>BMRCL plans to initiate operations with a prototype train from China and another from Titagarh.</li>
  <li>If initial operations are unviable, BMRCL will wait for a third train.</li>
  <li>The Yellow Line will enhance connectivity for the Electronics City, spanning an 18-km route.</li>
  <li>Driverless trains will operate in automated mode, ensuring efficient and safe passenger transit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We are contemplating starting operations on the Yellow Line with two trains... If it is not viable, we will wait for the third train and start the operations by April.” - Maheshwara Rao, BMRCL managing director</blockquote>
<p>The introduction of these driverless trains is expected to improve the efficiency of the metro services and the production of additional trainsets is expected to ramp up by September 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/bengaluru-metro-yellow-line-electronic-city-9765391/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/bengaluru-metro-yellow-line-electronic-city-9765391/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahindra BE 6 Pack Three With The Larger Battery Pack Costs Rs 26.9 Lakh - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahindra BE 6 Pack Three Price Revealed: Rs 26.9 Lakh</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> <em>October 2023</em> | <strong>Source:</strong> <em>CarDekho.com</em></p>
<img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/677d281a4596e.jpg" alt="Mahindra BE 6 Pack Three price revealed">
<figcaption>Mahindra BE 6 Pack Three price revealed</figcaption>
<p>The Mahindra BE 6 Pack Three, the latest electric SUV variant, has a starting price of Rs 26.9 lakh. This model is part of Mahindra's new 'BE' sub-brand aimed at electric vehicles.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The BE 6 is the first model under Mahindra’s fresh ‘BE’ sub-brand developed for new EVs.</li>
  <li>Highlighted features include C-shaped LED DRLs, flush-type door handles, and optional 20-inch alloy wheels.</li>
  <li>Designed with a fighter jet-like cabin featuring grey upholstery and dual digital displays.</li>
  <li>Onboard equipment includes multi-zone AC, wireless phone chargers, and ADAS technology.</li>
  <li>The SUV offers options for two battery packs with a claimed range of up to 682 km.</li>
  <li>Starting price is Rs 18.9 lakh (ex-showroom) for the base variant.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The BE 6 features all-LED lighting, including horizontally placed headlights and C-shaped LED DRLs." - Mahindra spokesperson</blockquote>
<p>This new variant emphasizes Mahindra's commitment to the electric vehicle market, providing impressive features, technology, and performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/mahindra-be-6-pack-three-with-the-larger-battery-pack-costs-rs-269-lakh-33790.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/mahindra-be-6-pack-three-with-the-larger-battery-pack-costs-rs-269-lakh-33790.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Getty Images and Shutterstock to merge to form $3.7B stock photo giant - TechCrunch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Getty Images and Shutterstock to merge to form $3.7B stock photo giant</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Tuesday, January 3, 2025 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> TechCrunch</p><p>Getty Images has announced a merger with rival Shutterstock in a deal valued at $3.7 billion, allowing Getty to own approximately 54.7% of the new company.</p><ul><li>The merger combines the strengths of both companies in the stock photo and video footage market.</li><li>Shutterstock shareholders can choose between cash or stock options as part of the deal.</li><li>The merger comes amid a changing landscape for the stock image industry due to the rise of artificial intelligence.</li><li>Concerns exist about potential antitrust scrutiny of the merger.</li></ul><blockquote>“Today’s announcement is exciting and transformational for our companies, unlocking multiple opportunities to strengthen our financial foundation and invest in the future,” said Getty Images CEO Craig Peters.</blockquote><p>This merger is positioned to reshape the stock image industry significantly, amidst both opportunities and threats posed by emerging technologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/07/getty-images-and-shutterstock-will-merge-to-form-37-billion-stock-photo-giant/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/07/getty-images-and-shutterstock-will-merge-to-form-37-billion-stock-photo-giant/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:08:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These 5 healthcare stocks hit 52-week highs, rallied up to 20% in a month - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Healthcare Stocks Reach New Heights: 52-Week Tops with Up to 20% Gains</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ETMarkets.com</p>
<img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-117027301,width-640,resizemode-4,imgsize-20970/healthcare-highs.jpg" alt="Healthcare Highs">
<figcaption>Rally in healthcare stocks as benchmark Sensex rises.</figcaption>
<p>On January 7, 2025, the benchmark Sensex rose by approximately 234 points, leading five stocks in the BSE Healthcare Index to achieve their 52-week highs, reflecting a strong market performance.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Five healthcare stocks reached their highest prices in the past year.</li>
  <li>Indicators suggest ongoing positive momentum in the healthcare sector.</li>
  <li>Notable stock performances include Blue Jet Healthcare (+22%), Indraprastha Medical Corporation (+12%), and others with varying gains.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"A 52-week high is a key indicator for traders and investors, reflecting a stock's peak value over the last 12 months."</blockquote>
<p>This rally in healthcare stocks showcases solid investor confidence and potential for continued growth in the sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/these-5-healthcare-stocks-hit-52-week-highs-rallied-up-to-20-in-a-month/healthcare-highs/slideshow/117027301.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/these-5-healthcare-stocks-hit-52-week-highs-rallied-up-to-20-in-a-month/healthcare-highs/slideshow/117027301.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upcoming Hyundai Creta Is Now Safer! - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Upcoming Hyundai Creta Is Now Safer!</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> MotorOctane</p><figure><img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/front-left-side-47-14.avif" alt="Upcoming Hyundai SUV"><figcaption>Upcoming Hyundai SUV</figcaption></figure><p>Hyundai is gearing up to launch its new Creta EV in India, enhancing its safety features to meet buyer demands.</p><ul><li>The new Creta EV will feature more than 75 advanced safety features, with 52 as standard across all variants.</li><li>The vehicle includes a level 2 ADAS suite and is built with advanced high-strength steel for better protection.</li><li>Safety features such as six airbags, Hill Start and Descent Control, and a 360-degree view camera will be part of the package.</li><li>Interiors feature advanced technologies including an in-car payment system and dual 10.25-inch screens.</li><li>The EV offers two battery options (51.4 kWh generating 169 bhp and 42 kWh generating 133 bhp) and ranges of 473 km and 390 km, respectively.</li><li>Hyundai aims to attract previous buyers who found the Creta lacking in safety.</li></ul><blockquote>“The new model gets more than 75 advanced safety features out of which 52 are standard across all variants.”</blockquote><p>This new iteration of the Hyundai Creta not only enhances safety but also modernizes the SUV, potentially capturing the attention of safety-conscious consumers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/281809-upcoming-hyundai-creta-is-now-safer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/281809-upcoming-hyundai-creta-is-now-safer</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 12:57:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahindra BE 6 Pack Three Prices Start At Rs 26.9 Lakh - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahindra BE 6 Pack Three Price Revealed: Rs 26.9 Lakh</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> <em>October 2023</em> | <strong>Source:</strong> <em>CarDekho.com</em></p>
<img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/677d281a4596e.jpg" alt="Mahindra BE 6 Pack Three price revealed">
<figcaption>Mahindra BE 6 Pack Three price revealed</figcaption>
<p>The Mahindra BE 6 has launched its top-spec Pack Three variant featuring a larger 79 kWh battery pack at Rs 26.9 lakh. The electric SUV comes in three variants, offering advanced features and impressive range.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The BE 6 is the first model under Mahindra’s new ‘BE’ sub-brand for EVs.</li>
  <li>Exterior highlights include C-shaped LED DRLs, flush-type door handles, and 20-inch alloy wheels.</li>
  <li>Interior features include dual digital displays, a fighter jet-like cabin, and various luxury amenities.</li>
  <li>The vehicle offers two battery pack options with a claimed range of up to 682 km.</li>
  <li>Pricing starts from Rs 18.9 lakh for the base model.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The BE 6 gets a rear-wheel-drive setup and supports fast charging, allowing quick top-ups in just 20 minutes."</blockquote>
<p>This launch positions the Mahindra BE 6 as a strong competitor against other electric models like Tata Curvv EV and MG ZS EV.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/mahindra-be-6-pack-three-prices-start-at-rs-269-lakh-33790.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/mahindra-be-6-pack-three-prices-start-at-rs-269-lakh-33790.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 12:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech View: Nifty forms Inside Bar Candle, can correct below 23,600. How to trade on Wednesday - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nifty Forms Inside Bar Candle, Potential Correction Below 23,600: Trading Insights</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Tuesday<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Economic Times</p><p>The Nifty index has shown mixed signals, forming an Inside Bar candle near the 23,700 mark. A breach below 23,600 could signal further corrections, while resistance levels are identified at 23,800 and 24,000.</p><ul><li>Nifty closed near 23,700, with immediate support levels at 23,400 and 23,000.</li><li>Technical indicators show bearish momentum with an RSI of 43, while Stochastic RSI hints at a short-term recovery.</li><li>Highest open interest on the call side is at 24,000 and 23,800, with significant put-side interest at 23,500.</li></ul><blockquote>“The market lacks a definitive directional bias.” - Mandar Bhojane, Choice Broking</blockquote><p>Analysts suggest that traders should keep an eye on critical levels ranging from 23,550 to 24,100 as the index may consolidate. A breakout of these levels could further determine market direction.</p><p>For more insights, traders can watch for sector rotation and stock-specific actions during this phase. Immediate resistance is pegged at 23,950, with support at 23,500.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/tech-view-nifty-forms-inside-bar-candle-can-correct-below-23600-how-to-trade-on-wednesday/articleshow/117027063.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/tech-view-nifty-forms-inside-bar-candle-can-correct-below-23600-how-to-trade-on-wednesday/articleshow/117027063.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 12:51:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>