<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 17:16:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 17:16:10 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viduthalai Part - 2 Box Office Collection Day 5 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOci1SV19lTmZqMnYtNC1sVmpzcUIyd0F0bENlUVkyWWZYZkpnVFprWEJGV2JMckdnLU12QkV4LU1QcGgtT3pxRDFGYTdobkNrNkJRX2NZSDlJdUtOczFCdkJPbXZPdDhFdTREM1FkZlp2UXl3SXpHNW8zZFRKU0RLRXVYMlRZRjhjdHNqdjB3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOci1SV19lTmZqMnYtNC1sVmpzcUIyd0F0bENlUVkyWWZYZkpnVFprWEJGV2JMckdnLU12QkV4LU1QcGgtT3pxRDFGYTdobkNrNkJRX2NZSDlJdUtOczFCdkJPbXZPdDhFdTREM1FkZlp2UXl3SXpHNW8zZFRKU0RLRXVYMlRZRjhjdHNqdjB3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 15:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Malayalam’s most violent film Marco set to release in Telugu - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Malayalam’s Most Violent Film 'Marco' Set to Release in Telugu</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 at 7:56 pm IST</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Marco-1.jpg" alt="Marco Movie Poster" width="550" height="429"><figcaption>Marco Movie Poster</figcaption><p>'Marco', headlined by Unni Mukundhan, is promoted as the most violent Malayalam film ever. The film witnessed impressive box office collections from its release and is set for a Telugu release on January 1, 2025.</p><ul><li>'Marco' grossed almost Rs. 10 crores on its first day.</li><li>The film made over Rs. 30 crores globally in its first weekend.</li><li>It collected Rs. 4 crores on its first weekday in Kerala.</li><li>Unni Mukundhan announced the Telugu release on his X account.</li><li>The film has been described as a spine-chilling action entertainer with excessive violence.</li></ul><blockquote>'Marco is said to have more violence than Bollywood's Kill.'</blockquote><p>The film, directed by Haneef Adeni, features several notable actors including Jagadish and Siddique, and is produced by Shareef Muhammed with music composed by Ravi Basrur.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/malayalams-most-violent-film-marco-set-to-release-in-telugu.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/malayalams-most-violent-film-marco-set-to-release-in-telugu.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 14:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Param Sundari: Sidharth Malhotra, Janhvi Kapoor set to star in cross-cultural love story. See first look - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sidharth Malhotra and Janhvi Kapoor to Star in Cross-Cultural Love Story 'Param Sundari'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/Param_Sundari_1735044502996_1735044503412.jpg" alt="Sidharth Malhotra and Janhvi Kapoor in the first look from Param Sundari."><figcaption>Sidharth Malhotra and Janhvi Kapoor in the first look from Param Sundari.</figcaption><p>Actors Sidharth Malhotra and Janhvi Kapoor are set to team up for the first time in Dinesh Vijan's upcoming film 'Param Sundari', which is a cross-cultural love story set in the beautiful backwaters of Kerala. The film is directed by Tushar Jalota and is scheduled for release on July 25, 2025.</p><ul><li>Sidharth and Janhvi star in a romantic storyline that blends northern and southern cultures.</li><li>The first look features the actors in traditional South Indian attire, showcasing their chemistry.</li><li>The film is produced by Dinesh Vijan, known for other successful Bollywood projects.</li></ul><blockquote>“North ka swag, South ki grace - two worlds collide and sparks fly.”</blockquote><p>'Param Sundari' marks an exciting collaboration aimed at captivating audiences with its unique cultural narrative.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/param-sundari-sidharth-malhotra-janhvi-kapoor-set-to-star-in-cross-cultural-love-story-see-first-look-101735044042359.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/param-sundari-sidharth-malhotra-janhvi-kapoor-set-to-star-in-cross-cultural-love-story-see-first-look-101735044042359.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 13:03:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inside Justin Baldoni's messy legal battle with Blake Lively: Menendez Brothers, Johnny Depp connections explored - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Inside Justin Baldoni's messy legal battle with Blake Lively</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/NY-Premiere-of--It-Ends-with-Us--6_1725247663788_1735043322126.jpg" alt="Justin Baldoni penned a heartfelt note for domestic violence survivors. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)(Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)">
<figcaption>Justin Baldoni penned a heartfelt note for domestic violence survivors. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)(Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)</figcaption>
<p>Justin Baldoni is facing serious allegations from his co-star Blake Lively, who has filed a lawsuit claiming sexual harassment and manipulation. His legal representation, Bryan Freedman, is defending him while also representing the notorious Menendez Brothers in an ongoing legal matter.</p>
<ul>
<li>Blake Lively has filed a suit against Justin Baldoni, alleging sexual harassment.</li>
<li>Attorney Bryan Freedman is involved with both Baldoni's case and the Menendez Brothers' legal issues.</li>
<li>Baldoni's crisis management team has connections to Johnny Depp.</li>
<li>The case has drawn considerable media attention and public scrutiny.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These claims are completely false, outrageous, and intentionally salacious with an intent to publicly hurt...” - Bryan Freedman</blockquote>
<p>The allegations made by Lively, which include attempts to damage her reputation, are taken very seriously in Hollywood, especially given the high-profile nature of the parties involved. As both cases unfold, they have been drawing contrasting public opinions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/inside-justin-baldonis-messy-legal-battle-with-blake-lively-menendez-brothers-johnny-depp-connections-explored-101735000851131.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/inside-justin-baldonis-messy-legal-battle-with-blake-lively-menendez-brothers-johnny-depp-connections-explored-101735000851131.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 12:38:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Actor On Touching Alia In Inappropriate Place - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Actor Varun Dhawan Responds to Inappropriate Touching Allegations</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/varuna1735043524.jpg" alt="Actor On Touching Alia In Inappropriate Place"><figcaption>Varun Dhawan addressing recent allegations.</figcaption><p>Actor Varun Dhawan addresses allegations of inappropriate behavior with co-stars Alia Bhatt and Kiara Advani following controversial incidents during events and photoshoots.</p><ul><li>Varun clarified that a kiss on Kiara's cheek was pre-planned for a digital cover.</li><li>The belly-touching incident with Alia was unplanned but meant to be friendly.</li><li>He stated his playful interactions are consistent across both male and female co-stars.</li><li>Varun's upcoming film, Baby John, is set to release on Christmas.</li></ul><blockquote>“I have a close bond with Alia and the moment was lighthearted.”</blockquote><p>Varun Dhawan emphasizes his intentions were playful and highlights his camaraderie with his co-stars amidst the growing scrutiny.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/actor-on-touching-alia-in-inappropriate-place-142966</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/actor-on-touching-alia-in-inappropriate-place-142966</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 12:32:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Varun Dhawan’s Baby John just be Vijay’s Theri on steroids, or is there more to it? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Will Varun Dhawan’s Baby John Just Be Vijay’s Theri on Steroids, or Is There More to It?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Joseph-Kuruvilla-and-Baby-John.jpg?resize=600,338" alt="Vijay as Joseph and Varun as John in the flashback">
<figcaption>Still from Theri and Baby John</figcaption>
<p>Varun Dhawan’s upcoming film, <strong>Baby John</strong>, is an official remake of the 2016 Tamil blockbuster <strong>Theri</strong>, featuring Vijay. Directed by Atlee, <strong>Baby John</strong> marks Dhawan's first portrayal of a cop and raises expectations for a captivating narrative as it explores themes of familial bonds.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Key Connections:</strong> The film draws from the emotional core of <strong>Theri</strong>, emphasizing the father-daughter relationship and the protagonist's dual life as a father and a police officer.</li>
<li><strong>Character Dynamics:</strong> The movie updates character relationships, including the love story between the cop and his wife, which has evolved since <strong>Theri</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Casting Choices:</strong> Rajpal Yadav's addition is noted as a change from the original, bringing a fresh dynamic to the supporting roles.</li>
<li><strong>A Deeper Narrative:</strong> While promising more action and drama, the film aims to retain its emotional depth with themes of revenge and justice.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Baby John, summa Therikka vidunga” (Baby John, let the sparks fly).</blockquote>
<p>This film not only aims to resonate with fans of the original but also seeks to establish Varun Dhawan in a new light as he takes on the iconic role of a police officer. Expectations are set high as the film gears up for a big release this Christmas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/will-varun-dhawans-baby-john-just-be-vijays-theri-on-steroids-or-is-there-more-to-it-9742288/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/will-varun-dhawans-baby-john-just-be-vijays-theri-on-steroids-or-is-there-more-to-it-9742288/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 11:47:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Par idhar acting kaun karega?’ Fans compare Sid-Janhvi's Param Sundari first look to Chennai Express, 2 States - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fans Compare Sid-Janhvi's 'Param Sundari' First Look to Iconic Bollywood Films</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/Sidharth_Malhotra_Janhvi_Kapoors_Param_Sundari_1735035747487_1735035747889.jpg" alt="Sidharth Malhotra, Janhvi Kapoor's Param Sundari first look draws comparisons with SRK, Deepika Padukone's Chennai Express and Alia Bhatt's 2 States(Photos: X)" title="Sidharth Malhotra, Janhvi Kapoor's Param Sundari first look draws comparisons with SRK, Deepika Padukone's Chennai Express and Alia Bhatt's 2 States(Photos: X)"><figcaption>Sidharth Malhotra, Janhvi Kapoor's Param Sundari first look draws comparisons with SRK, Deepika Padukone's Chennai Express and Alia Bhatt's 2 States(Photos: X)</figcaption><p>The first look of the upcoming Bollywood film <i>Param Sundari</i>, featuring Sidharth Malhotra and Janhvi Kapoor, has sparked nostalgia among fans while drawing comparisons to classic films like <i>Chennai Express</i> and <i>2 States</i>. However, reactions to the film's leads have been mixed due to concerns over their acting abilities.</p><ul><li>Fans feel a sense of nostalgia with the first look, reminiscent of early 2010s Bollywood romcoms.</li><li>The film is set against the backdrop of the current 'stylish action-core' trend in Bollywood.</li><li>Comparisons have been made to Shah Rukh Khan and Deepika Padukone’s <i>Chennai Express</i> and Alia Bhatt’s <i>2 States</i>.</li><li>Concerns raised about the stereotypical representation of South Indian characters.</li><li>Produced by Maddock Films and directed by Tushar Jalota, <i>Param Sundari</i> is scheduled for release on July 25, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“Par idhar acting kaun karega?”</blockquote><p>The public’s reaction has suggested skepticism regarding the leads' performances, with comments humorously targeting their acting skills.</p><p>In conclusion, while the nostalgic elements of <i>Param Sundari</i> excite some fans, there are considerable concerns about its stereotypical portrayal of characters and the acting abilities of its stars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/janhvi-kapoor-sidharth-malhotra-param-sundari-first-look-compared-to-srk-deepika-chennai-express-alia-bhatt-2-states-101735035607506.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/janhvi-kapoor-sidharth-malhotra-param-sundari-first-look-compared-to-srk-deepika-chennai-express-alia-bhatt-2-states-101735035607506.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 11:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viduthalai Part - 2 Box Office Collection Day 4 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQMHpSWEdYcFM0MEFSR3c2WGZxaV9MUWpNdk1MMzlsR2tGMDVJLUwzLWVnV0VIUGhYWE5LQmJhZzZ4N19ib1pIVWlhOTVqaW9tazg2WnJFcUVRTHBsNUNrZGJlcW9Gb3pnalB2SktldV9US05FZHJ3WDV2R2NNNFlzVmVnNEtES3pLTzl2Z2ln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQMHpSWEdYcFM0MEFSR3c2WGZxaV9MUWpNdk1MMzlsR2tGMDVJLUwzLWVnV0VIUGhYWE5LQmJhZzZ4N19ib1pIVWlhOTVqaW9tazg2WnJFcUVRTHBsNUNrZGJlcW9Gb3pnalB2SktldV9US05FZHJ3WDV2R2NNNFlzVmVnNEtES3pLTzl2Z2ln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 10:45:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max (Kannada) First Day Advance Booking Report - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxPR3N3a3VVbF9McXNhTFFvaldxeVlfWXpqTFV1dFIxNTFOLVp5RmRkUEFZZWRURUJzQ1EyWVBkei0yV1VWMlYxbHNZaHZtalBVcVZ1ZmJZcGpCTWl0TDJVaWRBOUVpQXhsVXhQc0tvR1BnSktUdkItWDNIZF84WXNVaDZxZ2RIRzlZMXpF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxPR3N3a3VVbF9McXNhTFFvaldxeVlfWXpqTFV1dFIxNTFOLVp5RmRkUEFZZWRURUJzQ1EyWVBkei0yV1VWMlYxbHNZaHZtalBVcVZ1ZmJZcGpCTWl0TDJVaWRBOUVpQXhsVXhQc0tvR1BnSktUdkItWDNIZF84WXNVaDZxZ2RIRzlZMXpF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 10:32:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saiee Manjrekar’s first look from The India House released - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saiee Manjrekar’s first look from The India House released</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 4:00 pm IST</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/The-India-House.jpg" alt="First look of Saiee Manjrekar in The India House"><figcaption>First look of Saiee Manjrekar in The India House</figcaption><p>Nikhil Siddhartha, a talented and passionate Tollywood actor, is gearing up for a strong comeback after the lukewarm response to his recent film, Appudo Ippudo Eppudo. With two exciting projects, Swayambhu and The India House, he is ready to reclaim his place in the spotlight.</p><ul><li>The India House has released its first-look poster featuring Saiee Manjrekar, who appears in a beautiful blue saree.</li><li>Saiee will portray the character of Sati, with more details on her role expected soon.</li><li>Directed by Ram Vamsi Krishna, the film is currently in production.</li><li>Acclaimed actor Anupam Kher has also been cast in a significant role.</li><li>The film is a collaboration between Ram Charan, V Mega Pictures, and Abhishek Agarwal Arts.</li><li>Additional updates, including the release date, will be shared in the near future.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/saiee-manjrekars-first-look-from-the-india-house-released.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/saiee-manjrekars-first-look-from-the-india-house-released.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shyam Benegal Last Rites: Legendary Filmmaker Cremated With Full State Honours; Naseeruddin Shah, Gulzar Among Others Bid Tearful Adieu - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shyam Benegal Last Rites: Legendary Filmmaker Cremated With Full State Honours</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Zee News</p>
<p>Mumbai: Veteran filmmaker Shyam Benegal, the pioneer of the parallel cinema movement in Indian cinema in the 1970s and 1980s, was cremated on Tuesday with full state honours and a three-gun salute here.</p>
<ul>
<li>Benegal, known for films such as "Ankur", "Mandi", "Nishant", and "Junoon", died on Monday at a hospital due to chronic kidney disease.</li>
<li>The last rites were held at Dadar's Shivaji Park crematorium, attended by many film industry friends and family.</li>
<li>Notable attendees included Naseeruddin Shah, Gulzar, and other celebrated actors and directors.</li>
<li>Gulzar remarked on Benegal's revolutionary impact on Indian cinema, stating, "He brought a revolution that will never come again." </li>
<li>Actor Shreyas Talpade shared his unforgettable experience of working under Benegal's direction, highlighting his influence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"He hasn't departed, we have departed from him and seen him off. He brought a revolution, he has gone with that revolution of change in cinema." - Gulzar</blockquote>
<p>This gathering of tributes reflects the legacy of Shyam Benegal in Indian cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/people/shyam-benegal-last-rites-legendary-filmmaker-cremated-with-full-state-honours-naseeruddin-shah-gulzar-among-others-bid-tearful-adieu-2835378.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/people/shyam-benegal-last-rites-legendary-filmmaker-cremated-with-full-state-honours-naseeruddin-shah-gulzar-among-others-bid-tearful-adieu-2835378.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 10:23:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Sooraj Barjatya finds his new Prem; Signs Ayushmann Khurrana for next directorial - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>EXCLUSIVE: Sooraj Barjatya finds his new Prem; Signs Ayushmann Khurrana for next directorial</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p><img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/632047314_sooraj-barjatya-and-ayushmann.jpg" alt="Sooraj Barjatya and Ayushmann Khurrana" title="EXCLUSIVE: Sooraj Barjatya finds his new Prem; Signs Ayushmann Khurrana for next directorial" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Sooraj Barjatya signs Ayushmann Khurrana for the leading role in his next film.</figcaption><p>Sooraj Barjatya has chosen Ayushmann Khurrana to play the title role in his next directorial, aiming to appeal to family audiences.</p><ul><li>The film is a romantic saga set to go into production in Summer 2025.</li><li>It will explore themes rooted in Indian culture, with a fresh perspective.</li><li>Ayushmann brings innocence and charm, aligning with Barjatya's vision for the character.</li></ul><blockquote>“Sooraj ji was looking to cast someone who has an image among family audiences, and who better than Ayushmann Khurrana to play the new age Prem.”</blockquote><p>The collaboration is expected to resonate with fans of Barjatya's previous works, as Ayushmann's approach to the iconic character promises to rejuvenate the beloved series of films.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-sooraj-barjatya-finds-his-new-prem-signs-ayushmann-khurrana-for-next-directorial-1364146</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-sooraj-barjatya-finds-his-new-prem-signs-ayushmann-khurrana-for-next-directorial-1364146</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 10:17:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shyam Benegal's Funeral: Gulzar, Naseeruddin Shah, and others gather to honor the filmmaker - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shyam Benegal's Funeral: Gulzar, Naseeruddin Shah, and others gather to honor the filmmaker</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not provided<strong> | Source: </strong>Not provided</p><p>The film community came together to pay their respects to the renowned filmmaker Shyam Benegal, showcasing their love and admiration for his contributions to cinema.</p><ul><li>Prominent figures like Gulzar and Naseeruddin Shah attended the funeral.</li><li>Benegal was known for his impactful films that shaped Indian cinema.</li><li>The gathering emphasized the legacy he left behind in the film industry.</li></ul><blockquote>“His films will continue to inspire generations,” remarked a fellow filmmaker.</blockquote><p>Shyam Benegal's passing marks a significant loss for Indian cinema, but his body of work will continue to resonate and influence future filmmakers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/shyam-benegals-funeral-gulzar-naseeruddin-shah-and-others-gather-to-honor-the-filmmaker/articleshow/116627743.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/shyam-benegals-funeral-gulzar-naseeruddin-shah-and-others-gather-to-honor-the-filmmaker/articleshow/116627743.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 10:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jhanak: Jhanak to meet Aniruddha with her daughter post leap; Has she remarried? - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jhanak: Jhanak to meet Aniruddha with her daughter post leap; Has she remarried?</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Tuesday, December 24, 2024 at 9:41 AM | <strong>Source:</strong> Star Plus</p><figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/9051-jhanak-jhanak-to-meet-aniruddha-with-her-daughter-has-she-remarried.jpg" alt="Jhanak: Jhanak to meet Aniruddha with her daughter; Has she remarried?"><figcaption>Jhanak to adopt a baby girl</figcaption></figure><p>Following a dramatic leap, Jhanak adjusts to life without Aniruddha, grappling with the betrayal that forces her to reconsider her future.</p><ul><li>Jhanak leaves Aniruddha after discovering his betrayal.</li><li>In the storyline, a significant twist introduces a 5-year leap that shifts character dynamics.</li><li>Arshi's revelation of her pregnancy with Aniruddha's child leads Jhanak to cancel her wedding.</li><li>Jhanak decides to adopt a baby girl to help heal her emotional wounds.</li><li>Aniruddha mistakenly believes Jhanak has remarried when he sees her with the adopted child.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite being engrossed in her work, she will find it hard to erase the memory of Aniruddha's betrayal, leaving her feeling lonely.”</blockquote><p>The series explores themes of betrayal, motherhood, and unexpected reunions, illustrating how relationships evolve over time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/jhanak-jhanak-to-meet-aniruddha-with-her-daughter-has-she-remarried_215862</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/jhanak-jhanak-to-meet-aniruddha-with-her-daughter-has-she-remarried_215862</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 09:45:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shyam Benegal funeral: Naseeruddin Shah bids emotional goodbye to filmmaker, Gulzar pays last respects - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shyam Benegal funeral: Naseeruddin Shah bids emotional goodbye to filmmaker, Gulzar pays last respects</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/naseer_1735032584105_1735032584606.jpg" alt="Naseeruddin Shah and Gulzar paid their last respects to Shyam Benegal." title="Naseeruddin Shah and Gulzar paid their last respects to Shyam Benegal.">
<figcaption>Naseeruddin Shah and Gulzar paid their last respects to Shyam Benegal.</figcaption>
<p>Shyam Benegal, a pioneer of Indian parallel cinema, passed away at the age of 90 on December 23, 2024. His death was confirmed by his daughter, Pia Benegal. The funeral is scheduled for December 24 at Shivaji Park Electric Crematorium in Mumbai.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shabana Azmi confirmed the funeral details via her Instagram.</li>
  <li>The funeral is set to begin at 2 PM, attended by many Bollywood celebrities.</li>
  <li>Naseeruddin Shah was seen emotionally bidding farewell at the funeral.</li>
  <li>Known for his significant contributions to Indian cinema, Benegal had a career marked by social commentary and realism.</li>
  <li>He celebrated his 90th birthday just days before his passing.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“His films were marked by a degree of realism and social commentary, and helped in Indian parallel cinema movement in the 1970s and 1980s.”</blockquote>
<p>Shyam Benegal's legacy will be remembered for his impactful storytelling in Indian cinema, and his passing marks a significant loss for the film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shyam-benegal-funeral-naseeruddin-shah-bids-emotional-goodbye-to-filmmaker-gulzar-pays-last-respects-shabana-azmi-101735029938507.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shyam-benegal-funeral-naseeruddin-shah-bids-emotional-goodbye-to-filmmaker-gulzar-pays-last-respects-shabana-azmi-101735029938507.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 09:20:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohanlal recalls his prediction about Fahadh Faasil after his debut movie fiasco: ‘It came true’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohanlal's Faith in Fahadh Faasil's Talent: A Success Story</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 24, 2024, <a href="https://indianexpress.com">The Indian Express</a></p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Mohanlal-Fahadh-Faasil-24122024.jpg?w=640" alt="Mohanlal with Fahadh Faasil." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Mohanlal with actor Fahadh Faasil. (Image: Mohanlal/X)</figcaption><p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Malayalam superstar Mohanlal shares his belief in Fahadh Faasil's talent, even when the actor faced initial criticism after his debut movie.</p><ol><li>Both Mohanlal and Fahadh Faasil were introduced to cinema by Fazil, Fahadh's father.</li><li>While Mohanlal's debut was successful, Fahadh faced criticism for his performance in his first film, leading to a hiatus.</li><li>Mohanlal expressed his confidence in Fahadh's talent before the latter's successful return.</li><li>They have since collaborated in several films, including an upcoming project directed by Mahesh Narayanan.</li></ol><blockquote><p>“Once, Fazil Sir asked me, ‘How would you rate Fahadh as an actor?’ I told him, ‘Let Fahadh return and act in films.’ When he did return, my prediction came true. He is a great actor and is doing very well.” - Mohanlal</p></blockquote><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> Mohanlal's faith in Fahadh Faasil's talent highlights the importance of persistence and belief in one's abilities, even in the face of initial setbacks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/malayalam/mohanlal-recalls-his-prediction-about-fahadh-faasil-after-his-debut-movie-fiasco-it-came-true-9741997/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/malayalam/mohanlal-recalls-his-prediction-about-fahadh-faasil-after-his-debut-movie-fiasco-it-came-true-9741997/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 08:47:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BTS J-Hope shines in Weverse Magazine's December 2024 Issue Pictorial - allkpop]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BTS J-Hope shines in Weverse Magazine's December 2024 Issue Pictorial</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> allkpop</p><img src="/upload/2024/12/content/240338/1735029522-bts-j-hope-weverse-magazine-december-2024-issue-pictorial-v0-9axebc51qp8e1.jpg" alt="BTS J-Hope Weverse Magazine" /><figcaption>BTS J-Hope featured in Weverse Magazine's December 2024 issue.</figcaption><p>BTS member J-Hope is the feature of Weverse Magazine’s December 2024 issue, reflecting his evolving charm and artistic identity.</p><ul><li>The pictorial captures J-Hope’s unique style through bold outfits and minimalist visuals.</li><li>J-Hope shares insights about his creative journey and inspirations in an exclusive interview.</li><li>This feature emphasizes J-Hope's role as a cultural icon and trendsetter.</li></ul><blockquote>“His passion and dedication fuel his work.”</blockquote><p>Fans can check out the exclusive pictorial and heartfelt interview on the Weverse Magazine platform.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.allkpop.com/article/2024/12/bts-j-hope-shines-in-weverse-magazines-december-2024-issue-pictorial</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.allkpop.com/article/2024/12/bts-j-hope-shines-in-weverse-magazines-december-2024-issue-pictorial</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 08:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amber Heard weighs in on Blake-Baldoni controversy as netizens slam Justin's faux ‘male feminist’ persona; read - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amber Heard Comments on Blake Lively-Justin Baldoni Controversy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/amber_1735025512576_1735025539912.jpeg" alt="Amber Heard weighs in on Blake-Baldoni drama" title="Amber Heard weighs in on Blake-Baldoni drama"><figcaption>Amber Heard weighs in on Blake-Baldoni drama</figcaption></figure><p>The ongoing controversy surrounding Justin Baldoni and Blake Lively stemming from the film <i>It Ends With Us</i> has attracted attention, with Heard speaking out on social media misinformation.</p><ul><li>Blake Lively accuses Justin Baldoni of orchestrating a smear campaign against her.</li><li>Lively filed a complaint alleging sexual harassment and a hostile work environment.</li><li>Heard criticized the devastating impact of social media misinformation.</li><li>Netizens are questioning Baldoni's male feminist persona amidst the drama.</li></ul><blockquote>“Social media is the absolute personification of the classic saying ‘A lie travels halfway around the world before truth can get its boots on.’” - Amber Heard</blockquote><p>The unfolding drama highlights issues of credibility and the facade of feminism in the entertainment industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/amber-heard-weighs-in-on-blake-lively-and-justin-baldonis-controversy-it-ends-with-us-controversy-smear-campaign-101735022968929.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/amber-heard-weighs-in-on-blake-lively-and-justin-baldonis-controversy-it-ends-with-us-controversy-smear-campaign-101735022968929.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 08:33:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Border 2: Filming Begins For Sunny Deol, Varun Dhawan, Diljit Dosanjh Starrer; First Pic From Sets Out - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Filming Begins for 'Border 2' Starring Sunny Deol and Varun Dhawan</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Border 2: Filming Begins" title="Border 2: Filming Begins"><figcaption>First Image from the sets of Border 2.</figcaption><p>Sunny Deol and a star-studded cast have officially begun shooting for 'Border 2', the highly-anticipated sequel of the iconic 1997 war film.</p><ul><li>'Border 2' is directed by Anurag Singh and backed by producers Bhushan Kumar, JP Dutta, and Nidhi Dutta.</li><li>The film promises action, drama, and patriotism, scheduled for release on January 23, 2026.</li><li>It features Sunny Deol reprising his role from the original film alongside Varun Dhawan, Diljit Dosanjh, and Ahan Shetty.</li><li>The original film depicted the heroic actions of Indian soldiers during the 1971 Longewala battle.</li></ul><blockquote>“The cameras are rolling for Border 2! This promises action, drama, and patriotism like never before.”</blockquote><p>The revival of 'Border' highlights the ongoing appreciation for patriotic stories in Indian cinema, making 'Border 2' one of the most awaited films of 2026.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/sunny-deol-starts-filming-border-2-fans-await-2026-release-9166554.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/sunny-deol-starts-filming-border-2-fans-await-2026-release-9166554.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 08:14:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Peeping Moon EXCLUSIVE: Sujoy Ghosh left Shah Rukh Khan's King because it seemed more like a Siddharth Anand film than his - PeepingMoon]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwJBVV95cUxNVkE0YWNDalZnZ1ZwVnlPTHJRaGpSc0xxcE9Qa04xOXduRTZOQjFrNDBIVk5yNXBOU3NDbGZVVXFBWnRNWHplNUdDSV9kS3Qxc2pkSHJDWllldnE1OEhqUC1sR2xHbjY1ZkNkS0ZXZlhhQ2gzVXNTVE1JWW5PM2xiWXFxZDJ2MlVLMVBFbnM5WmtGSkZGaWROTUk4bERyekh6S0UwdEZxYy1SdlpkVzZQWE84aHdyTkl3bDVQT2M4aEVUUHBPeGtPdW02R0VpYkhZYkl2MHliM1hqYkk0Y2E2ZU9oTFpzMllSODNQZXdZV3RjeWpfbnNWaHNnWk9vUUpzX2dnY0sxUU53UFU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwJBVV95cUxNVkE0YWNDalZnZ1ZwVnlPTHJRaGpSc0xxcE9Qa04xOXduRTZOQjFrNDBIVk5yNXBOU3NDbGZVVXFBWnRNWHplNUdDSV9kS3Qxc2pkSHJDWllldnE1OEhqUC1sR2xHbjY1ZkNkS0ZXZlhhQ2gzVXNTVE1JWW5PM2xiWXFxZDJ2MlVLMVBFbnM5WmtGSkZGaWROTUk4bERyekh6S0UwdEZxYy1SdlpkVzZQWE84aHdyTkl3bDVQT2M4aEVUUHBPeGtPdW02R0VpYkhZYkl2MHliM1hqYkk0Y2E2ZU9oTFpzMllSODNQZXdZV3RjeWpfbnNWaHNnWk9vUUpzX2dnY0sxUU53UFU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 08:10:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby John advance booking: Varun Dhawan, Keerthy Suresh film sells fewer than 50,000 tickets, earns subpar 1.46 crore - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baby John Advance Booking: Kalees' Action Thriller Earns Subpar ₹1.46 Crore</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/baby_john_1730704229880_1735022991207.png" alt="Baby John advance booking: Varun Dhawan's film earns ₹2 crore." title="Baby John advance booking: Varun Dhawan's film earns ₹2 crore."><figcaption>Baby John advance booking: Varun Dhawan's film earns ₹2 crore.</figcaption><p>Baby John, starring Varun Dhawan and Keerthy Suresh, is set to release on Christmas Day but has faced disappointing advance ticket sales.</p><ul><li>The film has sold 49,557 tickets across 6,489 shows in India.</li><li>It has earned a total of ₹1.46 crore, a figure considered disappointing given the film's ambitions.</li><li>Baby John must compete with Sukumar's blockbuster Pushpa 2, which has made over ₹1,000 crore recently.</li><li>Producer Atlee is coming off the success of Jawan, which earned ₹733.6 crore at the Indian box office.</li><li>Varun Dhawan's recent films have struggled at the box office, making this release critical for his career.</li></ul><blockquote>“Baby John is facing a tough act to follow after the success of Pushpa 2, impacting its advance ticket sales.”</blockquote><p>The performance of Baby John will be closely monitored as it reflects both the film's potential and Varun Dhawan's standing in the industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/baby-john-advance-booking-varun-dhawan-keerthy-suresh-film-sells-50-000-tickets-earns-1-46-crore-atlee-kalees-101735022439657.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/baby-john-advance-booking-varun-dhawan-keerthy-suresh-film-sells-50-000-tickets-earns-1-46-crore-atlee-kalees-101735022439657.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 07:42:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marco Box Office Collection Day 4 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTFB0SUhWdkNCY0NpWVBGLU55RXNEdnc4YU1Ja2wtaWpVZ2Q3dFN4dmtwUjNpVUEyeTVUeGg5a251OXZOcVdKUkl4OG1TaTN2Q2dfazJTdDRFak5OaXpsX2hreS1vRl94Y1phYWN0TEExdFBQX2lsSmh6QmZmQ28?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTFB0SUhWdkNCY0NpWVBGLU55RXNEdnc4YU1Ja2wtaWpVZ2Q3dFN4dmtwUjNpVUEyeTVUeGg5a251OXZOcVdKUkl4OG1TaTN2Q2dfazJTdDRFak5OaXpsX2hreS1vRl94Y1phYWN0TEExdFBQX2lsSmh6QmZmQ28?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 07:40:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Did You Know...": What Cops Asked Allu Arjun In 'Pushpa 2' Stampede Case - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Investigation into Allu Arjun's Role in 'Pushpa 2' Stampede</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>Hyderabad Police have questioned actor Allu Arjun following a tragic stampede at a theater during a premiere of 'Pushpa 2', resulting in the death of a 35-year-old woman and severe injuries to her child.</p><img src='image_link_here' alt='Allu Arjun at the theatre' /><figcaption>Allu Arjun at the theater screening.</figcaption><p>Key points include:</p><ul><li>Allu Arjun was questioned about police permission for his appearance at the event.</li><li>He was arrested and later released on interim bail.</li><li>His presence reportedly caused a stampede as fans surged to see him.</li><li>The police have faced criticism regarding their handling of the situation.</li></ul><blockquote>“Just because he is an actor... he cannot be held like this,” cited the Telangana High Court in support of Allu Arjun.</blockquote><p>The incident has sparked protests and divided public opinion, with mixed reactions regarding the actor's accountability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pushpa-2-the-rise-stampede-death-case-allu-arjun-questioned-by-hyderabad-police-7320567</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pushpa-2-the-rise-stampede-death-case-allu-arjun-questioned-by-hyderabad-police-7320567</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 07:26:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Pushpa 2 The Rule’ stampede: Producer of Allu Arjun mass entertainer donates ₹50 lakh to the victim’s fa - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Producer of 'Pushpa 2 The Rule' Donates ₹50 Lakh to Victim's Family After Stampede</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>After a tragic stampede during the release of 'Pushpa 2 The Rule', producer Allu Arjun has stepped forward to support the victim's family by donating ₹50 lakh.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Stampede occurred during the film's premiere.</li>
    <li>Allu Arjun pledged ₹50 lakh to the family of the deceased.</li>
    <li>The incident has raised concerns about crowd control at large events.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>'In times of tragedy, we must come together to support those in need.'</blockquote>
<p>This donation highlights the importance of responsibility among filmmakers and event organizers in ensuring the safety of their audiences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/pushpa-2-the-rule-stampede-producer-of-allu-arjun-mass-entertainer-donates-50-lakh-to-the-victims-family/articleshow/116622360.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/pushpa-2-the-rule-stampede-producer-of-allu-arjun-mass-entertainer-donates-50-lakh-to-the-victims-family/articleshow/116622360.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 07:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marco Worldwide Box Office Day 4: Unni Mukundan Starrer Continues A Solid Run Despite A Drop, Inches Close To 40 Crores - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Marco Worldwide Box Office Day 4: Unni Mukundan Starrer Continues A Solid Run Despite A Drop</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p>
<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/marco-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-4-001.jpg" alt="Marco Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 4" width="1200" height="630">
<figcaption>Marco Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 4(Photo Credit – YouTube)</figcaption>
<p>The Unni Mukundan starrer Marco is turning out another successful offering from the Malayalam film industry. The movie, however, witnessed a drop on its fourth day. Look at the film’s box office performance on its 4th day.</p>
<h4><strong>Marco Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 4</strong></h4>
<p>The <a href="https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/marco-worldwide-box-office-day-3-makes-an-impressive-debut-maintaining-an-average-of-10-56-crores-on-each-day/">Unni Mukundan</a> starrer saw a drop of almost 30%. The movie earned <strong>3.63 crores</strong>, whereas it had garnered <strong>5.2 crores</strong> on its third day. The film opened at <strong>4.3 crores</strong>, and it had gone on to earn <strong>4.65 crores</strong> on its second day. The movie’s total India net collection now comes to <strong>17.7 crores</strong>.</p>
<p>At the same time, the gross collection comes to 20.28 crores. The movie earned a decent <strong>15 crores</strong> when it comes to the overseas collection. The worldwide collection of the film now stands at <strong>35.28 crores</strong>. The movie is now inching close to <strong>40 crores</strong>. Given its positive word of mouth, it might cross the same soon.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Budget of the film: <strong>30 crores</strong></li>
  <li>Current India net collection: <strong>17.7 crores</strong></li>
  <li>Against its budget, it has crossed <strong>59%</strong></li>
  <li>Challenge ahead with Mohanlal’s <a href="https://www.koimoi.com/what-to-watch/what-to-watch-this-weekend-dec-24-29-baby-john-barroz-to-squid-game-season-2/">Barroz</a> releasing tomorrow.</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>About The Movie</strong></h4>
<p>Apart from Unni Mukundan, Marco also stars Siddique, Jagadish, and Kabir Duhan Singh in pivotal roles. It has been helmed by Haneef Adeni. At the same time, the music has been composed by Ravi Basrur.</p>
<p>Note: Box office numbers are based on estimates and various sources. Numbers have not been independently verified by Koimoi.</p>
<p>For more stories and updates, stay tuned to Koimoi.</p>
<p><strong>Must Read:</strong> <a href="https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/rifle-club-worldwide-box-office-day-4-vijayaraghavan-anurag-kashyap-starrer-performs-well-during-the-opening-weekend/">Rifle Club Worldwide Box Office Day 4: Vijayaraghavan &amp; Anurag Kashyap Starrer Performs Well During The Opening Weekend</a></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/marco-worldwide-box-office-day-4-unni-mukundan-starrer-continues-a-solid-run-despite-a-drop-inches-close-to-40-crores/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/marco-worldwide-box-office-day-4-unni-mukundan-starrer-continues-a-solid-run-despite-a-drop-inches-close-to-40-crores/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 07:03:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s how Blake Lively got the bombshell texts from Justin Baldoni’s PR team - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Blake Lively Accuses Justin Baldoni of Sexual Harassment and Legal Drama Unfolds</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/Blake-Lively-Justin-Baldoni_1735023121540_1735023121876.webp" alt="Justin Baldoni’s lawyer has reacted to the claims saying that the leaked texts used against him were taken “out of context”." title="Justin Baldoni’s lawyer has reacted to the claims saying that the leaked texts used against him were taken “out of context”."><figcaption>Justin Baldoni’s lawyer has reacted to the claims saying that the leaked texts used against him were taken “out of context”.</figcaption><p>Blake Lively has filed a legal complaint against her co-star Justin Baldoni, alleging sexual harassment and an attempted smear campaign involving leaked text messages. This situation has drawn much attention regarding the origins of these texts.</p><ul><li>Blake Lively's complaint includes accusations of assault by Baldoni, including coercing unwanted kissing scenes and observing her naked.</li><li>The legal documents suggest Lively obtained private communications through a civil subpoena, but it remains unclear how she accessed the messages.</li><li>Content involved conversations about how to undermine Lively's reputation within Baldoni's PR team.</li><li>Baldoni's lawyer claims the leaked texts were taken out of context and asserts that Lively's team knows the true facts.</li><li>The case points to a broader narrative around power dynamics in Hollywood and the treatment of women in the industry.</li></ul><blockquote>“If all of the text messages were produced in that ‘subpoena,’ then Lively’s team knows the true facts of what actually happened and did not happen.” - Bryan Freedman, Baldoni's lawyer</blockquote><p>This legal battle highlights the complexities of power, privacy, and accountability within the entertainment industry. The outcome may have broader implications for how similar cases are viewed in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/heres-how-blake-lively-got-the-bombshell-texts-from-justin-baldoni-s-pr-team-101735023029574.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/heres-how-blake-lively-got-the-bombshell-texts-from-justin-baldoni-s-pr-team-101735023029574.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 07:01:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunny Deol, Varun Dhawan, Diljit Dosanjh, Ahan Shetty starrer Border 2 goes on floor; see pic - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Filming Begins for 'Border 2'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p>
<img src="https://media5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Sunny-Deol-Varun-Dhawan-Diljit-Dosanjh-Ahan-Shetty-620.jpg" alt="Sunny Deol, Varun Dhawan, Diljit Dosanjh, Ahan Shetty starrer Border 2 goes on floor; see pic" width="620" height="450">
<figcaption>Sunny Deol, Varun Dhawan, Diljit Dosanjh, Ahan Shetty starrer Border 2 goes on floor; see pic</figcaption>
<p>The cameras are rolling for the much-anticipated sequel <em>Border 2</em>, featuring a star-studded lineup including Sunny Deol and Varun Dhawan. Fans are excited as production officially begins.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Filming has officially begun for the sequel <em>Border 2</em>.</li>
  <li>The movie stars Sunny Deol, Varun Dhawan, Diljit Dosanjh, and Ahan Shetty.</li>
  <li>Directed by Anurag Singh, the film promises action and emotional depth.</li>
  <li>It is set against a backdrop of patriotism and is based on true events from the Indo-Pakistan war.</li>
  <li>Scheduled for release on January 23, 2026.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Also featured a deep insight into the infamous Indo-Pakistan war of 1971 which was known as the Battle of Longewala.”</blockquote>
<p>This sequel aims to deliver a grand cinematic experience and further the legacy of the original film.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/sunny-deol-varun-dhawan-diljit-dosanjh-ahan-shetty-starrer-border-2-goes-floor-see-pic/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/sunny-deol-varun-dhawan-diljit-dosanjh-ahan-shetty-starrer-border-2-goes-floor-see-pic/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:41:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Box Office: Mufasa: The Lion King ROARS ahead; sells double the tickets of Pushpa 2 on Christmas - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Box Office: Mufasa: The Lion King ROARS ahead; sells double the tickets of Pushpa 2 on Christmas</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p>
<img src="https://stat5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Mufasa-The-Lion-King-ROARS-ahead-1.jpg" alt="Box Office: Mufasa: The Lion King ROARS ahead; sells double the tickets of Pushpa 2 on Christmas" width="620" height="450">
<figcaption>Mufasa: The Lion King leading box office sales over Pushpa 2.</figcaption>
<p>The last big Hollywood release of the year, <em>Mufasa: The Lion King</em>, has sold double the tickets of <em>Pushpa 2</em> during the Christmas period. The film shows promising box office performance since its release on December 20.</p>
<ul>
    <li><em>Mufasa: The Lion King</em> sold 44,000 tickets, while <em>Pushpa 2</em> sold 27,000 tickets as of December 24.</li>
    <li>The film benefits from family audiences during holiday seasons.</li>
    <li>Positive word of mouth contributed to the successful ticket sales.</li>
    <li>Future holiday releases may further boost ticket sales until January 9.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"It’s praiseworthy that <em>Mufasa: The Lion King</em> has gone past the Pan-India movie."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, <em>Mufasa: The Lion King</em> is positioned well for continued success at the box office due to positive audience reception and strategic holiday releases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/box-office-mufasa-lion-king-roars-ahead-sells-double-tickets-pushpa-2-christmas/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/box-office-mufasa-lion-king-roars-ahead-sells-double-tickets-pushpa-2-christmas/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:34:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Varun Dhawan denies allegations that he behaved inappropriately with Alia Bhatt, Kiara Advani: ‘It was all in good fun, not flirting’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Varun Dhawan denies allegations that he behaved inappropriately with Alia Bhatt, Kiara Advani: ‘It was all in good fun, not flirting’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/varun-dhawan-alia-bhatt-kiara-advani.jpg?w=640" alt="varun dhawan alia bhatt kiara advani flirting" width="640" height="356"><figcaption>Varun Dhawan denied crossing the line with his female co-stars.</figcaption><p>Varun Dhawan has publicly responded to allegations regarding inappropriate behavior towards his co-stars Alia Bhatt and Kiara Advani, insisting that his actions were intended as harmless fun.</p><ul><li>Videos of Varun seemingly kissing Kiara and touching Alia sparked a public outcry.</li><li>Varun stated the kiss on Kiara's cheek was pre-planned for a photoshoot.</li><li>He emphasized that playful interactions with co-stars are common for him and mentioned that he also shares similar banter with male colleagues.</li><li>Varun admitted that some interactions, like pushing Kiara into a pool, were spontaneous and not planned.</li><li>He expressed that touching Alia's belly was also in good fun and not flirting, asserting their friendship.</li><li>Varun is set to star in the upcoming film 'Baby John', releasing on Christmas Day.</li></ul><blockquote>“Chhedam-chhaadi, if it is done in a happy space, a good space...” - Varun Dhawan</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Varun maintains that his interactions with co-stars were within the bounds of camaraderie, not crossing any lines of propriety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/varun-dhawan-denies-allegations-that-he-behaved-inappropriately-with-alia-bhatt-kiara-advani-9741762/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/varun-dhawan-denies-allegations-that-he-behaved-inappropriately-with-alia-bhatt-kiara-advani-9741762/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:24:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun At Hyderabad Police Station For Questioning In 'Pushpa 2' Stampede Case - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxPYzBMdHFDMnY1aUhHOU5xdy10aUgxQ1ZMU29TQ1dqdWwxdWp2MjBlTlE5Nk9fV05jNnNocVlwRnJOdTdEMmk3RWo3U01QNGVZUWRGZTVzNjZUdXA2RjgwTDNfR0pZNEJ4Q3JGLWppenBWTVlKa2xSLTFLMEU2OGdtQm45YTBQbUlqcmdoNmlEaDFieG9ENXhlZlloY3dRWE5lUjFDcXduOXA3LXQ0SjZfbDNBVlp3MHhnNVl4YTZmczc4NG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxPYzBMdHFDMnY1aUhHOU5xdy10aUgxQ1ZMU29TQ1dqdWwxdWp2MjBlTlE5Nk9fV05jNnNocVlwRnJOdTdEMmk3RWo3U01QNGVZUWRGZTVzNjZUdXA2RjgwTDNfR0pZNEJ4Q3JGLWppenBWTVlKa2xSLTFLMEU2OGdtQm45YTBQbUlqcmdoNmlEaDFieG9ENXhlZlloY3dRWE5lUjFDcXduOXA3LXQ0SjZfbDNBVlp3MHhnNVl4YTZmczc4NG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:20:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>