<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 09:23:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 09:23:33 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tiku Talsania suffers massive heart attack, critical: reports - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/tiku-talsania-suffers-massive-heart-attack-critical-reports/articleshow/117141900.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/tiku-talsania-suffers-massive-heart-attack-critical-reports/articleshow/117141900.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 07:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tiku Talsania suffers massive heart attack, critical: reports - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/tiku-talsania-suffers-massive-heart-attack-critical-reports/articleshow/117141900.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/tiku-talsania-suffers-massive-heart-attack-critical-reports/articleshow/117141900.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 07:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aamir Khan quits smoking: When he said his cigarette smoke affected ex-wife Kiran Rao, but she wasn't ‘averse’ to pipe - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aamir Khan Quits Smoking Ahead of Son's Film Release</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/Aamir_Kiran_1734800687226_1736576719187.jpg" alt="Aamir Khan and Kiran Rao were married for 16 years." title="Aamir Khan and Kiran Rao were married for 16 years."><figcaption>Aamir Khan and Kiran Rao were married for 16 years.</figcaption><p>Aamir Khan announced on January 11, 2025, that he has quit smoking in preparation for his son Junaid Khan's film, Loveyapa. He explained that he has previously struggled with smoking but is committed to supporting his son during his career launch.</p><ul><li>Aamir Khan recently quit smoking for his son's film release.</li><li>He had switched from cigarettes to pipe smoking a few years ago.</li><li>Kiran Rao, Aamir's ex-wife, was affected by his cigarette smoking but was not averse to pipe smoking.</li><li>Aamir has had a long history with smoking and has tried cigars but did not enjoy them.</li><li>He feels a personal sacrifice is needed as a father to support his son.</li></ul><blockquote>“I quit smoking for two-three years when I was training for Dhoom 3. But then, I went back to it again.” - Aamir Khan</blockquote><p>Aamir Khan's decision to quit smoking reflects his desire to enhance his role as a father as his son begins his film career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aamir-khan-quits-smoking-when-he-said-his-cigarette-smoke-affected-ex-wife-kiran-rao-but-she-was-not-averse-to-pipe-101736576486316.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aamir-khan-quits-smoking-when-he-said-his-cigarette-smoke-affected-ex-wife-kiran-rao-but-she-was-not-averse-to-pipe-101736576486316.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 07:10:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer Box Office Collections: Ram Charan and Shankar film underwhelms on first day in India - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Box Office Collections: Ram Charan and Shankar film underwhelms on first day in India</h1>
<p><strong>Updated on Jan 11, 2025 | Source: Pinkvilla</strong></p>
<img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/618885663_gc1.jpg" alt="Ram Charan," title="Ram Charan in Game Changer (image courtesy of AA Films)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Ram Charan in Game Changer (image courtesy of AA Films)</figcaption>
<p>Game Changer had a disappointing start at the Indian box office, collecting an approximate of Rs. 60 crore on its first day, which is considered underwhelming given the expectations set by its massive budget.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film grossed Rs. 59.50 crore on its opening day.</li>
  <li>Collections in Telugu states were below expectations, significantly lower than the targeted Rs. 60-65 crore.</li>
  <li>The Hindi version performed the best with Rs. 7 crore NETT.</li>
  <li>Low occupancy rates were observed with less than 50% in regular shows.</li>
  <li>The performance was notably poor in Tamil Nadu and Kerala, traditionally strong markets for director Shankar.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A little salt blends well with flour,” but here the salt is probably more than flour.</blockquote>
<p>This lackluster performance raises questions about the film's future at the box office, given the high expectations set by its marketing and budget.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/game-changer-box-office-collections-ram-charan-and-shankar-film-underhelms-on-first-day-in-india-1366849</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/game-changer-box-office-collections-ram-charan-and-shankar-film-underhelms-on-first-day-in-india-1366849</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 06:37:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Prabhas’ The Raja Saab gets postponed - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prabhas’ The Raja Saab gets postponed</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Jan 11, 2025</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/The-Raja-Saab1.jpg" alt="The Raja Saab poster" width="333" height="468">
<figcaption>The Raja Saab - Official Poster</figcaption>
<p>The upcoming film featuring Prabhas, The Raja Saab, has reportedly been postponed from its initial release date of April 10, 2025. The horror comedy, directed by Maruthi, is currently in its final production stages.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Raja Saab is a horror comedy romantic entertainer.</li>
    <li>Initial release was set for April 10, 2025, but may not be met.</li>
    <li>The reason for the delay has not been disclosed.</li>
    <li>A special poster is expected to be unveiled for Sankranthi.</li>
    <li>Co-stars include Malavika Mohanan and Niddhi Agerwal.</li>
    <li>Produced by People Media Factory with music by Thaman.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“An official confirmation from the team will make things clear.”</blockquote>
<p>This postponement has led to increased speculation, especially following the announcement of another film set to release on the same date.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/report-prabhas-the-raja-saab-gets-postponed.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/report-prabhas-the-raja-saab-gets-postponed.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer worldwide box office collection day 1: Ram Charan film opens big, yet over ₹100 cr behind Pushpa 2 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer worldwide box office collection day 1: After earning over ₹50 crore domestically, the action entertainer earns more than thrice globally.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/nana-hyraana_1736502313195_1736573571039.jpg" alt="Game Changer worldwide box office collection day 1: Kiara Advani and Ram Charan's film earns ₹186 crore." title="Game Changer worldwide box office collection day 1: Kiara Advani and Ram Charan's film earns ₹186 crore."><figcaption>Game Changer worldwide box office collection day 1: Kiara Advani and Ram Charan's film earns ₹186 crore.</figcaption><p>The film "Game Changer," directed by S Shankar and starring Ram Charan and Kiara Advani, has made a spectacular opening at the box office with a worldwide collection of ₹186 crore on its first day. Despite this impressive debut, it trails significantly behind the blockbuster "Pushpa 2."
</p><ul><li>Game Changer earned ₹51.25 crore domestically on its opening day.</li><li>The film is set in the political landscape, following an IAS officer's struggle against corruption.</li><li>Pushpa 2 had an opening day collection of ₹294 crore, outpacing Game Changer by over ₹100 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“The king's arrival is setting the box office ablaze. #GameChanger takes a blockbuster opening at the BOX OFFICE. GROSSES 186 CRORES WORLDWIDE on Day 1.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while "Game Changer" shows strong numbers on its opening day, it has a long way to go to match the success of other major Telugu films such as "Pushpa 2."</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/game-changer-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-film-opens-big-over-rs-100-cr-behind-allu-arjun-pushpa-2-101736573417061.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/game-changer-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-film-opens-big-over-rs-100-cr-behind-allu-arjun-pushpa-2-101736573417061.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 06:16:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aamir Khan quits smoking: When he asked Shah Rukh Khan if he could smoke in front of Amitabh Bachchan - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aamir Khan Quits Smoking Ahead of His Son's Film Launch</h1><p><strong>Jan 11, 2025</strong> by <strong>HT Entertainment Desk</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/MixCollage-11-Jan-2025-10-19-AM-7791_1736570996878_1736571018133.jpg" alt="Aamir Khan once asked Shah Rukh Khan if he could smoke in front of Amitabh Bachchan." title="Aamir Khan once asked Shah Rukh Khan if he could smoke in front of Amitabh Bachchan."><figcaption>Aamir Khan once asked Shah Rukh Khan if he could smoke in front of Amitabh Bachchan.</figcaption><p>Aamir Khan has announced that he has quit smoking, as he prepares for his son Junaid's film. He mentioned that he has enjoyed smoking but felt it was the right time to stop.</p><ul><li>Aamir made his announcement at the trailer launch of 'Loveyapa'.</li><li>He recalled a humorous incident about asking Shah Rukh Khan if he could smoke around Amitabh Bachchan.</li><li>Aamir expressed his desire to set a good example for his son, whose career is just beginning.</li></ul><blockquote>“I made a resolve in my heart. I'm quitting, whether it (Junaid's next film) works or not, I'm doing this independent of that.”</blockquote><p>This decision reflects Aamir's commitment to being a positive influence on his son's career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aamir-khan-quits-smoking-when-he-asked-shah-rukh-khan-if-he-could-smoke-in-front-of-amitabh-bachchan-thugs-of-hindostan-101736570721619.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aamir-khan-quits-smoking-when-he-asked-shah-rukh-khan-if-he-could-smoke-in-front-of-amitabh-bachchan-thugs-of-hindostan-101736570721619.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:34:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Kalki 2898 AD, Jai Hanuman lands in trouble - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jai Hanuman Faces Legal Trouble Over Controversial Teaser</h1><p><strong>Published on Jan 11, 2025</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Jai-HanuMan-Kalki.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333"><figcaption>Image related to Jai Hanuman controversies.</figcaption><p>The upcoming film Jai Hanuman is facing backlash due to allegations of misrepresenting Lord Hanuman in its teaser. As legal troubles mount, the producers have yet to respond.</p><ul><li>A Hyderabad lawyer filed a petition against the makers of Jai Hanuman.</li><li>The teaser allegedly disrespects Lord Hanuman's image.</li><li>The production company, Mythri Movie Makers, has not issued a comment yet.</li><li>Jai Hanuman is a sequel to the successful film Hanu-Man.</li></ul><blockquote>“The teaser could mislead future generations about Lord Hanuman’s image,” claimed advocate Tirumala Rao.</blockquote><p>This controversy highlights the scrutiny faced by mythological films in India, especially regarding their portrayals of religious figures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/after-kalki-2898-ad-jai-hanuman-lands-in-trouble.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/after-kalki-2898-ad-jai-hanuman-lands-in-trouble.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karan Johar wears 'nepo baby' T-shirt during dinner with Gauri Khan, Malaika Arora; internet says: It's really on point - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karan Johar wore 'nepo baby' T-shirt during dinner with Gauri Khan, Malaika Arora; internet says: It's really on point</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 11, 2025</strong></p>
<p><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/Karan_Johar_1736571534980_1736571540285.jpg" alt="Karan Johar wore a unique T-shirt during his outing." title="Karan Johar wore a unique T-shirt during his outing."><figcaption>Karan Johar wore a unique T-shirt during his outing.</figcaption>
<p>Karan Johar garnered attention for wearing a T-shirt that read 'nepo baby' during a dinner outing with friends Gauri Khan and Malaika Arora.</p>
<ul>
<li>Karan wore a full-sleeved white T-shirt with black trousers and sneakers.</li>
<li>The dinner took place in Mumbai and was captured on social media.</li>
<li>Internet reactions highlighted the pride in Karan's choice of attire, with comments like 'Finally, wearing his Nepo Baby shirt proudly.'</li>
<li>In addition to his T-shirt, Karan has been active in the fashion scene, walking the ramp at events.</li>
<li>Karan is set to direct a new series for Netflix India and has several films in production.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>'Lol, Kjo's top is really on point haan (yes). He's proud to be a new baby.'</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Karan Johar's casual yet bold fashion choice sparked a lively discussion on social media, reflecting the ongoing cultural conversation around 'nepo babies' in the film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/karan-johar-wears-nepo-baby-t-shirt-during-dinner-with-gauri-khan-malaika-arora-internet-says-on-point-101736568103216.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/karan-johar-wears-nepo-baby-t-shirt-during-dinner-with-gauri-khan-malaika-arora-internet-says-on-point-101736568103216.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:02:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rekhachithram Box Office Collection Day 2 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxNLVFhaHZkRzl0Ym95NXlIaExwVHVNM2RWYnVudE9uU09IVnRmLUVvd0ZELWh6YmRidGRXSHl6dEYzOEtoeU9yY0g0cVJXVHhPV2ROenh1LV9nOFpXaEh2dFVTUnFJQmlwLWpfUkFhQXlPMHdQZmVUYnluU0ZQZ0hxRmFDSlUxZlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxNLVFhaHZkRzl0Ym95NXlIaExwVHVNM2RWYnVudE9uU09IVnRmLUVvd0ZELWh6YmRidGRXSHl6dEYzOEtoeU9yY0g0cVJXVHhPV2ROenh1LV9nOFpXaEh2dFVTUnFJQmlwLWpfUkFhQXlPMHdQZmVUYnluU0ZQZ0hxRmFDSlUxZlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:58:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE SmackDown Match Results, Highlights and Key Moments for January 10, 2025 - Ringside News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WWE SmackDown Match Results, Highlights, and Key Moments for January 10, 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Ringside News</p><p>This week’s WWE SmackDown delivered an exciting evening of wrestling action from the Moda Center in Portland, Oregon, featuring key title matches and surprise moments.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Shinsuke Nakamura defended his United States Championship against LA Knight.</li><li>Tiffany Stratton made an appearance to celebrate her victory as Women’s Champion.</li><li>Cody Rhodes confronted Paul Heyman regarding Roman Reigns' intentions.</li><li>LA Knight faced an unexpected attack from Jacob Fatu and Tama Tonga, leading to disqualification.</li><li>Jimmy Uso and Cody Rhodes helped fend off Tama and Fatu after the main event.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes:</h2><blockquote>“It’s Tiffy Time!” - Tiffany Stratton</blockquote><blockquote>“I’m ready to settle this tonight!” - Cody Rhodes</blockquote><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> This episode of SmackDown featured intense rivalries and set the stage for future matchups, culminating in unexpected entrances and confrontations that left fans anticipating the next events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ringsidenews.com/2025/01/10/wwe-smackdown-results-january-10-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ringsidenews.com/2025/01/10/wwe-smackdown-results-january-10-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:57:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madraskaaran Review | This Wannabe Tragedy Causes More Headaches Than Heartache - Lensmen Reviews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Madraskaaran Review | This Wannabe Tragedy Causes More Headaches Than Heartache</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Lensmen Reviews</p><p>Madraskaaran, starring Shane Nigam, attempts to evoke empathy as it portrays the trials of its protagonist, but it often falls short due to its bloated narrative and unconvincing emotional triggers.</p><img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/j2jZAiyXdk44ipNi8c/giphy.gif?cid=790b7611dxs48vetveqtsh5b3hwqghwokibl2nnbl8vams0e&amp;ep=v1_gifs_search&amp;rid=giphy.gif&amp;ct=g" alt="Reaction GIF"><figcaption>Reaction to the film</figcaption><p><strong>Key Points:</strong></p><ul><li>The film centers around Sathya, who faces an emotional crisis after an accident on the eve of his wedding.</li><li>Director Vaali Mohan Das fails to create genuine empathy for the protagonist, often leading to unintentional humor.</li><li>The supporting characters are depicted as impulsive, undermining the film's emotional impact.</li><li>Shane Nigam shows improvement in performance during the tragic sequences compared to the lighter ones.</li></ul><blockquote>“Madraskaaran is a bloated emotional drama that might touch the hearts of those who are addicted to daily soaps.”</blockquote><p>The film suffers from a lack of subtlety and predictability, leaving audiences weary rather than emotionally invested.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://lensmenreviews.com/madraskaaran-tamil-movie-review-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lensmenreviews.com/madraskaaran-tamil-movie-review-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:48:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 37: Allu Arjun’s Rs 1831 cr film slows down after Game Changer, hits lowest point since release - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 37</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Allu-Arjun-2.jpg?w=640" alt="Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 37: Allu Arjun starrer is starting to slow down in India." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 37: Allu Arjun starrer is starting to slow down in India.</figcaption><p>Pushpa 2: The Rule has achieved great success but is now slowing down after facing competition from Game Changer.</p><ul><li>The film has grossed over Rs 1831 crore worldwide.</li><li>It is the second-highest Indian grosser of all time, surpassing Baahubali 2.</li><li>Box office collections have declined with only Rs 1.15 crore on Day 37.</li><li>Its extended version release is planned for January 17.</li><li>Pushpa 2 has faced increased competition since the release of Game Changer.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pushpa 2 has started losing its steam at the box office now.”</blockquote><p>The film's performance is influenced by new releases, but it remains a significant achievement in Allu Arjun's career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-37-allu-arjun-film-hits-lowest-point-game-changer-release-rs-1831-cr-9772671/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-37-allu-arjun-film-hits-lowest-point-game-changer-release-rs-1831-cr-9772671/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:46:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suhana Khan impressed with Jahaan Kapoor's acting debut in '90 Feet from Home' - WATCH - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/suhana-khan-praises-jahaan-kapoors-acting-debut-in-90-feet-from-home/articleshow/117137232.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/suhana-khan-praises-jahaan-kapoors-acting-debut-in-90-feet-from-home/articleshow/117137232.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suhana Khan impressed with Jahaan Kapoor's acting debut in '90 Feet from Home' - WATCH - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/suhana-khan-praises-jahaan-kapoors-acting-debut-in-90-feet-from-home/articleshow/117137232.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/suhana-khan-praises-jahaan-kapoors-acting-debut-in-90-feet-from-home/articleshow/117137232.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 1: Ram Charan-starrer surpasses Vinaya Vidheya Rama but couldn’t overtake RRR, earns Rs 51.25 cr - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 1: Ram Charan-starrer earns Rs 186 crore worldwide, claim makers</h1><p><strong>Date: January 11, 2025 | Source: Indian Express</strong></p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Game-Changer-advance-booking.jpg?w=640" alt="Game Changer Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 1:" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Game Changer Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 1: Ram Charan-starrer has had a strong start at the box office.</figcaption><p>S Shankar’s highly anticipated film, Game Changer, starring Ram Charan and Kiara Advani, has taken a strong opening at the box office, with a reported collection of Rs 186 crore worldwide on its first day.</p><ul><li>Game Changer has grossed Rs 51.25 crore in India.</li><li>The film's collections include Rs 42 crore in Telugu, Rs 2.1 crore in Tamil, Rs 7 crore in Hindi, along with smaller amounts in Kannada and Malayalam.</li><li>The movie achieved a morning occupancy rate of 51.32% for the Telugu version and an 82% occupancy for its 4DX Hindi version afternoon shows.</li><li>This opening surpassed Ram Charan’s last solo film, Vinaya Vidheya Rama, which earned Rs 34 crore on its opening day.</li><li>Despite its success, it did not match the Day 1 collection of RRR, which opened at Rs 133 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>The king’s arrival is setting the box office ablaze 🤙🏼 #GameChanger takes a blockbuster opening at the BOX OFFICE 💥💥 GROSSES 186 CRORES WORLDWIDE on Day 1 ❤‍🔥</blockquote><p>Director S Shankar hopes to capitalize on this success as his previous film, Indian 2, opened at Rs 25.6 crore.</p><p>The film features Ram Charan in a dual role, with Kiara Advani as his love interest. Game Changer is expected to maintain its momentum through the weekend, especially after a dry spell in box office hits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-shankar-overtakes-vinaya-vidheya-rama-earns-rs-51-crore-9772659/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-shankar-overtakes-vinaya-vidheya-rama-earns-rs-51-crore-9772659/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fateh box office collection day 1: Sonu Sood's directorial debut opens at ₹2.45 cr - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fateh Box Office Collection Day 1: Sonu Sood's Directorial Debut Opens at ₹2.45 Cr</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/fateh_1736566731211_1736566738673.jpg" alt="Fateh box office collection day 1: Sonu Sood's directorial debut opens at ₹2.45 crore." title="Fateh box office collection day 1: Sonu Sood's directorial debut opens at ₹2.45 crore."><figcaption>Fateh box office collection day 1: Sonu Sood's directorial debut opens at ₹2.45 crore.</figcaption><p>Soon to be a notable directorial debut for actor Sonu Sood, the film Fateh managed to collect ₹2.45 crore on its opening day, facing competition from the Telugu blockbuster Game Changer.</p><ul><li>Fateh opened well with a collection of ₹2.45 crore on its first day.</li><li>The film competes with Game Changer, which earned ₹7 crore on its opening day.</li><li>Tickets were priced at ₹99 for the first day as part of an initiative to reach the common man.</li><li>All profits from the film will be donated to charity by Sonu Sood.</li><li>Fateh is based on real-life instances of cybercrime experienced during the COVID-19 pandemic.</li></ul><blockquote>“Fateh is a film made for the common man, and I wanted it to reach everyone in the most accessible way across India.” - Sonu Sood</blockquote><p>The opening day collection shows promise, and the film's strategy of affordable tickets may boost attendance. With a gripping narrative around cybercrime, Fateh aims to resonate with audiences nationwide.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/fateh-box-office-collection-day-1-sonu-sood-directorial-debut-opens-at-rs-2-cr-jacqueline-fernandez-101736566431568.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/fateh-box-office-collection-day-1-sonu-sood-directorial-debut-opens-at-rs-2-cr-jacqueline-fernandez-101736566431568.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:09:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prabhas Getting Married? Trade Analyst Drops BIG Hint, Leaves Fans Excited - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prabhas Getting Married? Trade Analyst Drops BIG Hint, Leaves Fans Excited</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 11, 2025, 14:43 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Netizens are wondering if Prabhas is getting married soon. "><figcaption>Netizens are wondering if Prabhas is getting married soon.</figcaption><p>Looks like Telugu star Prabhas is getting married. Recently, trade analyst Manobala Vijayabalan posted a cryptic tweet hinting at a wedding, prompting speculation among fans.</p><ul><li>Fans are reacting excitedly to the trade analyst's post about Prabhas potentially getting married.</li><li>There is speculation regarding Prabhas's relationship with his Baahubali co-star Anushka Shetty.</li><li>Previous rumors of his marriage were dismissed by Prabhas during an event, where he stated he doesn't want to hurt his female fans.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am not getting married soon because I don’t want to hurt the feelings of my female fans,” - Prabhas</blockquote><p>The rumors surrounding Prabhas's marriage have sparked significant interest and discussion among fans, as they eagerly await any confirmation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/prabhas-getting-married-trade-analyst-drops-big-hint-leaves-fans-excited-9185025.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/prabhas-getting-married-trade-analyst-drops-big-hint-leaves-fans-excited-9185025.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:43:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Game Changer, Daaku Maharaaj faces this obstacle - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After Game Changer, Daaku Maharaaj Faces This Obstacle</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Jan 11, 2025 9:53 am IST</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Game-Changer-DaakuMaharaaj.jpg" alt="Daaku Maharaaj Image" width="500" height="333">
<figcaption>Game Changer and Daaku Maharaaj obstacle faced in premieres.</figcaption>
<p>With the release of Game Changer starring Ram Charan, delays have impacted both Game Changer and the upcoming film Daaku Maharaaj.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Game Changer had several USA premiere shows cancelled due to delays, resulting in a loss of nearly $100K.</li>
  <li>Daaku Maharaaj, starring Balakrishna, is facing similar delivery delays that are affecting premiere shows.</li>
  <li>The ambitious project aims for a 2 million dollar collection, but initial losses are anticipated due to these delays.</li>
  <li>If the film content is well received, it could recover in the long run.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Due to this, the premiere collections will be affected to an extent."</blockquote>
<p>This situation highlights the challenges faced by the Telugu film industry amid logistical issues but also underscores the potential for recovery based on audience reception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/after-game-changer-daaku-maharaaj-faces-this-obstacle.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/after-game-changer-daaku-maharaaj-faces-this-obstacle.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fateh Review: The No-Nonsense, Unabashed And Ultra-Violent Film Is Surprisingly Watchable - NDTV Movies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fateh Review: The No-Nonsense, Unabashed And Ultra-Violent Film Is Surprisingly Watchable</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p>
<p>An ex-special ops agent embarks on a violent rampage to take down cyber criminals behind a fraudulent loan operation. Actor Sonu Sood makes his writing and directing debut with a film that is unapologetically violent and dynamic.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film opens with an intense confrontation where the protagonist, Fateh Singh, takes control by resorting to extreme violence.</li>
  <li>Fateh utilizes a variety of weapons in his mission against a network of cyber criminals, showcasing high body counts reminiscent of other action-packed films.</li>
  <li>The narrative includes a social purpose, focusing on the impact of a scam targeting financially vulnerable individuals.</li>
  <li>Despite the relentless violence, the film offers minimal mystery as the antagonist's identity is revealed early on.</li>
  <li>Sonu Sood's performance resonates with the film's gritty tone, although other characters struggle to stand out in the chaos.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Fateh is marked by dizzying momentum if not sustained clarity.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while <em>Fateh</em> may be overwhelming with its sheer brutality, it remains a captivating watch for those who appreciate action-packed narratives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/fateh-review-the-no-nonsense-unabashed-and-ultra-violent-film-is-surprisingly-watchable-2-5-stars-7447887</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/fateh-review-the-no-nonsense-unabashed-and-ultra-violent-film-is-surprisingly-watchable-2-5-stars-7447887</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:36:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 box office collection Day 37: Allu Arjun starrer begins 6th weekend with Rs 1.15 crore earning - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Collection Day 37: Allu Arjun Starrer Begins 6th Weekend with Rs 1.15 Crore Earning</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [not specified] <strong>Source:</strong> [not specified]</p><p>Pushpa 2 continues to perform strongly at the box office, beginning its 6th weekend with earnings of Rs 1.15 crore.</p><ul><li>After 37 days in theaters, the film shows remarkable box office resilience.</li><li>It maintained a steady audience turnout over the weeks.</li><li>The total earnings have significantly boosted the film's financial success.</li></ul><blockquote>“The film’s success is a testament to Allu Arjun’s popularity and the movie's strong storyline.”</blockquote><p>The continued box office strength of Pushpa 2 demonstrates its lasting appeal and the effectiveness of its marketing strategy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-37-allu-arjun-starrer-begins-6th-weekend-with-rs-1-15-crore-earning/articleshow/117135620.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-37-allu-arjun-starrer-begins-6th-weekend-with-rs-1-15-crore-earning/articleshow/117135620.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karan Johar's leaner look shocks fans as he and Sidharth Malhotra walk the ramp in plunging-neck suits - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karan Johar's leaner look shocks fans as he and Sidharth Malhotra walk the ramp in plunging-neck suits</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/Karan_Johar_Sidharth_Malhotra_1736563066210_1736563076993.jpg" alt="Karan Johar and Sidharth Malhotra walk the ramp at a fashion event." title="Karan Johar and Sidharth Malhotra walk the ramp at a fashion event."><figcaption>Karan Johar and Sidharth Malhotra walk the ramp at a fashion event.</figcaption><p>At a recent fashion show in Mumbai, Karan Johar and Sidharth Malhotra showcased stunning outfits, with Karan's surprising transformation stealing the spotlight.</p><ul><li>Karan Johar walked the ramp in an all-white ensemble, featuring a silk shirt and a matching long coat.</li><li>Sidharth Malhotra was the showstopper in a fitted navy blue suit with a plunging V neckline.</li><li>Karan's leaner appearance drew mixed reactions from fans online.</li></ul><blockquote>“He looks so skinny.”</blockquote><p>Overall, the fashion show combined high-style moments with intriguing celebrity appearances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/fashion/karan-johar-lean-look-shocks-fans-as-he-and-sidharth-malhotra-walk-the-ramp-in-plunging-neck-suits-101736561475592.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/fashion/karan-johar-lean-look-shocks-fans-as-he-and-sidharth-malhotra-walk-the-ramp-in-plunging-neck-suits-101736561475592.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:46:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today LIVE Updates on January 11, 2025 : Numerology Horoscope Today: Predictions for January 11, 2025 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOZHlPSmNYcHpJajNodi1VRjNHUkxxSzEyS0wyY0F3S2FSWGZjd1ZuYmV5SGRGNlg3VDdGNk9qTG9kOExSUFhTdERDR1VqdVVaa3owZmZZd1RVVF9zbGdXXzE1LTZwZHhHZk45b3B5cko1UUMxR25GNXdPZjRKSkV4d2ZsRnhQRjZJak9FWDJyX2VidmM5MDJTVEwybVk0bk5yeVkxbGxrcE8wRWthdERsd3JlbHQycWfSAbwBQVVfeXFMUEhhN0dvTE1ic2ozdGx2NWlVY0VIclhJd0xKU09pRTdBekdQSHBjUGg5R0ZyWDZqMVUycHlNUVYxUGdzYXB0V2k5VDdzbm00WHgwUW1nNFJwQ0liOWk5R2ZVd2tzeFFKWnJwN21DMzdQazdtX250VWlIeV8zV0RIRDFYRUhTSEE1WDBMcUdOX19sWVdKdHA1eWs0RG16NVQ2MmtvWmRHTGVQNVlsbXJKallYWlRGNUItWjkxYnY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOZHlPSmNYcHpJajNodi1VRjNHUkxxSzEyS0wyY0F3S2FSWGZjd1ZuYmV5SGRGNlg3VDdGNk9qTG9kOExSUFhTdERDR1VqdVVaa3owZmZZd1RVVF9zbGdXXzE1LTZwZHhHZk45b3B5cko1UUMxR25GNXdPZjRKSkV4d2ZsRnhQRjZJak9FWDJyX2VidmM5MDJTVEwybVk0bk5yeVkxbGxrcE8wRWthdERsd3JlbHQycWfSAbwBQVVfeXFMUEhhN0dvTE1ic2ozdGx2NWlVY0VIclhJd0xKU09pRTdBekdQSHBjUGg5R0ZyWDZqMVUycHlNUVYxUGdzYXB0V2k5VDdzbm00WHgwUW1nNFJwQ0liOWk5R2ZVd2tzeFFKWnJwN21DMzdQazdtX250VWlIeV8zV0RIRDFYRUhTSEE1WDBMcUdOX19sWVdKdHA1eWs0RG16NVQ2MmtvWmRHTGVQNVlsbXJKallYWlRGNUItWjkxYnY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:30:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aamir Khan on why he quit smoking ahead of son Junaid Khan's film release: ‘Maine apne dil mein mannat maangi’. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aamir Khan Quits Smoking Ahead of Son Junaid Khan's Film Release</h1><p><strong>Jan 11, 2025</strong> from <strong>Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/aamir_khan_smoking_1736560836192_1736560965224.jpg" alt="Aamir Khan quits smoking ahead of son Junaid Khan's Loveyapa release." title="Aamir Khan quits smoking ahead of son Junaid Khan's Loveyapa release." /><figcaption>Aamir Khan quits smoking ahead of son Junaid Khan's Loveyapa release.</figcaption><p>Aamir Khan has announced that he has quit smoking after years of heavy consumption. This announcement was made during the trailer launch of his son Junaid Khan's film, Loveyapa, in Mumbai.</p><ul><li>Aamir Khan reveals he has quit smoking.</li><li>He expresses his love for smoking but acknowledges its health risks.</li><li>He encourages others to quit smoking as well.</li><li>He attributes his decision partly to his son’s debut film and his desire to set a good example.</li><li>Junaid Khan's film Loveyapa is set to release on February 7, following his previous debut in a Netflix film.</li></ul><blockquote>“I have given up smoking, smoking is something I love very much... it’s not good for health. No one should do it.”</blockquote><p>The actor’s decision comes as he wishes to support his son in his new career path while also prioritizing his health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aamir-khan-quit-smoking-ahead-of-son-junaid-khan-film-loveyapa-release-watch-101736560435019.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aamir-khan-quit-smoking-ahead-of-son-junaid-khan-film-loveyapa-release-watch-101736560435019.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:26:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shark Tank India 4 pitcher Gauri Kaushish Varma slams ‘dismissive’ Vineeta Singh, Anupam Mittal: ‘They were impatient, refused to listen’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/television/shark-tank-india-4-pitcher-gauri-kaushish-varma-slams-dismissive-vineeta-singh-anupam-mittal-9770009/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/television/shark-tank-india-4-pitcher-gauri-kaushish-varma-slams-dismissive-vineeta-singh-anupam-mittal-9770009/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:26:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shark Tank India 4 pitcher Gauri Kaushish Varma slams ‘dismissive’ Vineeta Singh, Anupam Mittal: ‘They were impatient, refused to listen’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/television/shark-tank-india-4-pitcher-gauri-kaushish-varma-slams-dismissive-vineeta-singh-anupam-mittal-9770009/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/television/shark-tank-india-4-pitcher-gauri-kaushish-varma-slams-dismissive-vineeta-singh-anupam-mittal-9770009/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:26:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer box office collection Day 1: Ram Charan and Kiara Advani starrer makes a splash with Rs 51 c - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Box Office Collection Day 1: Ram Charan and Kiara Advani Starrer Makes a Splash</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>Ram Charan and Kiara Advani's film 'Game Changer' had an impressive start, grossing Rs 51 crore on its opening day, and Rs 7 crore from Hindi audiences.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film received a positive response from audiences and critics alike.</li>
  <li>It marks a significant debut for the lead actors in their respective careers.</li>
  <li>The box office numbers indicate strong word-of-mouth promotion.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"A fantastic start, signaling a strong presence in the upcoming weeks!" - Film Analyst</blockquote>
<p>The film's early success hints at a promising run and potential for record-breaking collections in the following days.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/game-changer-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-and-kiara-advani-starrer-makes-a-splash-with-rs-51-crore-debut-earns-rs-7-crore-in-hindi/articleshow/117134871.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/game-changer-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-and-kiara-advani-starrer-makes-a-splash-with-rs-51-crore-debut-earns-rs-7-crore-in-hindi/articleshow/117134871.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE SmackDown Results – 1/10/25 (United States Championship Matches, Tiffany Stratton) - Wrestleview.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WWE SmackDown Results</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Wrestleview.com</p><figure><img decoding="async" width="207" height="84" src="https://www.wrestleview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/image-3.png" alt=""><figcaption>WWE SmackDown Highlights</figcaption></figure><p>On January 10, 2025, WWE SmackDown featured several high-stakes matches including United States Championship bouts and a significant storyline involving Cody Rhodes, Roman Reigns, and Kevin Owens.</p><ul><li>The night began with Tiffany Stratton, the new WWE Women’s Champion.</li><li>Paul Heyman introduced Roman Reigns, announcing his entry into the 2025 Men’s Royal Rumble.</li><li>Cody Rhodes and Kevin Owens had a tense confrontation, escalating to a physical altercation.</li><li>WWE Women’s United States Championship saw Chelsea Green successfully defend her title against Michin.</li><li>LA Knight faced Shinsuke Nakamura for the United States Championship, resulting in a disqualification victory for Knight, while Nakamura retained his title.</li><li>The Motor City Machine Guns secured a victory against A-Town Down Under.</li></ul><blockquote>A very good start to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SmackDown?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SmackDown</a>. Roman Reigns being in the Royal Rumble for the first time in years, Cody Rhodes and Kevin Owens, Jacob Fatu and Tama Tonga. It's an interesting start.— Wrestleview.com</blockquote><p>The show ended with drama and setup for future high-profile matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wrestleview.com/top-story/338622-wwe-smackdown-results-1-10-25-united-states-championship-matches-tiffany-stratton/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wrestleview.com/top-story/338622-wwe-smackdown-results-1-10-25-united-states-championship-matches-tiffany-stratton/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:39:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE SmackDown Spoiler Lineup for January 10, 2025: Full Match Card and Backstage Notes Revealed - Ringside News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxNREswTkVtbUVwQU11YnQ1amg0d3JRaVlTLVZXemxpZ1NoQUpFaDNObDdCREZWcUlCc0ZFcExMYy1EcVhZZmMzVnlLNlRUc1oxNHdRZURmLS1scHo4WU9HUkVIbXFTcy1ZNUx4bnMtMXlKSUVlTndUaXkwRWVmakJNMnZsdU9IaGJhbGxlS2NMa1Q4d0dPbk5KMlRfcGxJSk50bV9GNWZ1MzlVUVZMNmxXZy1GVy0xTGhyUjVYSjFkRnduV09pdEdsSTJWZmRzVUHSAc8BQVVfeXFMTURLME5FbW1FcEFNdWJ0NWpoNHdyUWlZUy1WV3psaWdTaEFKRWgzTmw3QkRGVnFJQnNGRXBMTGMtRHFYWWZjM1Z5SzZUVHNaMTR3UWVEZi0tbHB6OFlPR1JFSG1xU3MtWTVMeG5zLTF5SklFZU53VGl5MEVlZmpCTTJ2bHVPSGhiYWxsZUtjTGtUOHdHT25OSjJUX3BsSUpOdG1fRjVmdTM5VVFWTDZsV2ctRlctMUxoclI1WEoxZEZ3bldPaXRHbEkyVmZkc1VB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxNREswTkVtbUVwQU11YnQ1amg0d3JRaVlTLVZXemxpZ1NoQUpFaDNObDdCREZWcUlCc0ZFcExMYy1EcVhZZmMzVnlLNlRUc1oxNHdRZURmLS1scHo4WU9HUkVIbXFTcy1ZNUx4bnMtMXlKSUVlTndUaXkwRWVmakJNMnZsdU9IaGJhbGxlS2NMa1Q4d0dPbk5KMlRfcGxJSk50bV9GNWZ1MzlVUVZMNmxXZy1GVy0xTGhyUjVYSjFkRnduV09pdEdsSTJWZmRzVUHSAc8BQVVfeXFMTURLME5FbW1FcEFNdWJ0NWpoNHdyUWlZUy1WV3psaWdTaEFKRWgzTmw3QkRGVnFJQnNGRXBMTGMtRHFYWWZjM1Z5SzZUVHNaMTR3UWVEZi0tbHB6OFlPR1JFSG1xU3MtWTVMeG5zLTF5SklFZU53VGl5MEVlZmpCTTJ2bHVPSGhiYWxsZUtjTGtUOHdHT25OSjJUX3BsSUpOdG1fRjVmdTM5VVFWTDZsV2ctRlctMUxoclI1WEoxZEZ3bldPaXRHbEkyVmZkc1VB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:09:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fateh box office collection Day 1: Sonu Sood starrer off to a slow start with Rs 2.45 crore debut - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fateh Box Office Collection Day 1: Sonu Sood Starrer Off to a Slow Start with Rs 2.45 Crore Debut</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117134679,imgsize-160030,width-400,resizemode-4/117134679.jpg" alt="Fateh box office collection Day 1: Sonu Sood starrer off to a slow start with Rs 2.45 crore debut" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Fateh box office collection Day 1: Sonu Sood starrer off to a slow start with Rs 2.45 crore debut</figcaption><p>The much-anticipated action film Fateh, featuring Sonu Sood, opened to a subdued box office collection of Rs 2.45 crore on its first day.</p><ul><li>The film revolves around themes of cybercrime, justice, and resilience.</li><li>Initial predictions estimated the film's first-day collection to be between Rs 70 lakh and Rs 1 crore.</li><li>Sood's return as a lead actor was highly anticipated, especially after his philanthropic work during the pandemic.</li><li>Fateh faces tough competition from major releases such as Ram Charan's Game Changer and Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2.</li><li>Industry experts suggest that positive word-of-mouth may improve the film's performance over the weekend.</li><li>Salman Khan showed support for Fateh, connecting it with a song he previously contributed to.</li></ul><blockquote>“I also have a contribution in the film Fateh. The song 'Heer' was very dear to me, but now it is part of this film.” - Salman Khan</blockquote><p>As the weekend progresses, the success of 'Fateh' is dependent on audience response and critical reception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/fateh-box-office-collection-day-1-sonu-sood-starrer-off-to-a-slow-start-with-rs-2-45-crore-debut/articleshow/117134678.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/fateh-box-office-collection-day-1-sonu-sood-starrer-off-to-a-slow-start-with-rs-2-45-crore-debut/articleshow/117134678.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>