<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:21:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:21:46 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shah Rukh & Suhana sing along to Levitating X Woh Ladki Jo at AbRam’s annual day; actor gets emotional on Swades act - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shah Rukh Khan and Suhana Khan’s videos enjoying the former’s songs at AbRam Khan’s annual function are the cutest thing you’ll see today</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Shah_Rukh_Suhana_1734691484482_1734691544620.jpg" alt="Shah Rukh Khan and Suhana Khan at AbRam Khan's annual day function" title="Shah Rukh Khan and Suhana Khan at AbRam Khan's annual day function"><figcaption>Shah Rukh Khan and Suhana Khan at AbRam Khan's annual day function</figcaption><p>Shah Rukh Khan and his daughter Suhana Khan were seen singing along to a popular mashup of his iconic songs during AbRam Khan's annual school function. Their performance has gone viral, capturing the hearts of many fans.</p><ul><li>The mashup of <i>Levitating</i> and <i>Woh Ladki Jo</i> was approved by Dua Lipa during her Indian tour.</li><li>Shah Rukh Khan joined in singing at the Dhirubhai Ambani School's annual function.</li><li>Another emotional moment featured Shah Rukh singing the title track of <i>Swades</i> as students paid tribute to the country.</li><li>Suhana Khan will star alongside Shah Rukh in the upcoming film <i>King</i>.</li></ul><blockquote>“Watching Shah Rukh be himself is always an honour!”</blockquote><p>This emotional display of family and patriotism at a school function resonated deeply with fans, showcasing the strong bond between Shah Rukh and Suhana.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/shah-rukh-suhana-sing-along-to-levitating-x-woh-ladki-jo-at-abram-s-annual-day-actor-gets-emotional-on-swades-act-101734691305518.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/shah-rukh-suhana-sing-along-to-levitating-x-woh-ladki-jo-at-abram-s-annual-day-actor-gets-emotional-on-swades-act-101734691305518.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:59:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Singham Again' OTT release: Here's when and where to watch the Ajay Devgn, Akshay Kumar, Ranveer Singh, - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Singham Again OTT Release: Watch Details for Ajay Devgn, Akshay Kumar & More</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<p>An upcoming action film 'Singham Again' featuring a star-studded cast is set to have its OTT release. Fans are eagerly anticipating when and where they can watch this movie.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film stars Ajay Devgn, Akshay Kumar, Ranveer Singh, Deepika Padukone, Kareena Kapoor Khan, and Arjun Kapoor.</li>
  <li>It will be available on popular streaming platforms.</li>
  <li>The exact release date and viewing options are yet to be confirmed.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Stay tuned for updates on the exciting release of 'Singham Again'!”</blockquote>
<p>This release is highly anticipated due to the involvement of prominent Bollywood actors, which adds to the film's excitement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/singham-again-ott-release-heres-when-and-where-to-watch-the-ajay-devgn-akshay-kumar-ranveer-singh-deepika-padukone-kareena-kapoor-khan-arjun-kapoor-starrer/articleshow/116499076.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/singham-again-ott-release-heres-when-and-where-to-watch-the-ajay-devgn-akshay-kumar-ranveer-singh-deepika-padukone-kareena-kapoor-khan-arjun-kapoor-starrer/articleshow/116499076.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi vs Stree 2 Box Office (2-Week Comparison): Leads With 178 Crores+ Earnings, Has Dethroned Shraddha Kapoor’s Biggie Every Single Day! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi vs Stree 2 Box Office (2-Week Comparison)</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-hindi-vs-stree-2-box-office-01.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi vs Stree 2 Box Office" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi vs Stree 2 Box Office (2-Week Comparison) ( Photo Credit – Instagram )</figcaption><p>Pushpa 2 continues to set records in the Hindi film industry, surpassing major films while competing against Stree 2 for the top position. In just two weeks, it has made significant strides at the box office.</p><h4><strong>Key Points</strong></h4><ul><li>Pushpa 2 has grossed a total of <strong>632.50 crores</strong> in its two-week run.</li><li>It surpassed the opening-day collections of Jawan, scoring <strong>72 crores</strong> on its first day.</li><li>Stree 2 currently has lifetime earnings of <strong>627.50 crores</strong>.</li><li>Pushpa 2 has outperformed Stree 2 on all release days.</li><li>Predictions indicate that Pushpa 2 may cross <strong>700 crores</strong> in lifetime earnings.</li></ul><blockquote>“Clearly, the signs were visible from the first week. Pushpa 2 has already dethroned Stree 2 to become the highest-grossing Hindi film of all time.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Pushpa 2's impressive box office run highlights its dominance over recent competitors, suggesting a strong likelihood of continued success in the coming weeks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-vs-stree-2-box-office-2-week-comparison-leads-with-178-crores-earnings-has-dethroned-shraddha-kapoors-biggie-every-single-day/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-vs-stree-2-box-office-2-week-comparison-leads-with-178-crores-earnings-has-dethroned-shraddha-kapoors-biggie-every-single-day/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:32:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mufasa The Lion King: Fans go berserk in theaters as Mahesh Babu's voice takes over the big screen; WATCH - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mufasa The Lion King: Fans Go Wild Over Mahesh Babu's Voice in Theaters</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 20, 2024 | Source: Pinkvilla</strong></p><div><img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/1231255154_mufasa-2.jpg" alt="Mahesh Babu Instagram, Twitter" title="Mahesh Babu’s voice in Mufasa sends theaters into a frenzy; fans say 'Jai Babu' (PC: Mahesh Babu Instagram, Twitter)"><figcaption>Mahesh Babu’s voice in Mufasa sends theaters into a frenzy; fans say 'Jai Babu' (PC: Mahesh Babu Instagram, Twitter)</figcaption></div><p>Fans cannot contain their excitement as they flock to cinemas for the Telugu version of Mufasa: The Lion King, featuring the iconic voice of Mahesh Babu.</p><ul><li>The movie was released on December 20, 2024, and has already created a buzz among moviegoers.</li><li>Numerous videos are circulating on social media showing fans cheering and celebrating during Mahesh Babu's intro.</li><li>Fans have expressed their admiration with posts saying, "His Voice is Enough To Conquer" and "Jai Babu." </li><li>Mahesh Babu described his experience of voicing Mufasa as incredible and heartfelt.</li><li>The film features other notable actors like Ali and Brahmanandam, who voice Timon and Pumbaa respectively.</li><li>Mufasa: The Lion King is directed by acclaimed filmmaker Barry Jenkins and is a musical drama following Mufasa's journey.</li></ul><blockquote>“Voicing Mufasa has been an incredible experience that I’ll always hold close to my heart.” - Mahesh Babu</blockquote><p>The celebration of Mahesh Babu's voice in theaters marks a unique moment in Indian cinema, highlighting the deep connection his fans feel towards him.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/south/mufasa-the-lion-king-fans-go-berserk-in-theaters-as-mahesh-babus-voice-takes-over-the-big-screen-watch-1363624</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/south/mufasa-the-lion-king-fans-go-berserk-in-theaters-as-mahesh-babus-voice-takes-over-the-big-screen-watch-1363624</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:17:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai-Abhishek Bachchan squash divorce rumours; proudly record Aaradhya’s annual day performance with AbRam - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai-Abhishek Bachchan squash divorce rumours; proudly record Aaradhya’s annual day performance with AbRam</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Aishwarya_Abhishek_1734680981161_1734681022836.jpg" alt="Aaradhya’s annual day brings the Bachchans together"><figcaption>Aaradhya’s annual day brings the Bachchans together</figcaption><p>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and Abhishek Bachchan recently dispelled divorce rumors by attending their daughter Aaradhya's annual day event together, delighting their fans.</p><ul><li>The couple has been the subject of divorce speculation following a July social media post.</li><li>They were seen smiling together at the Dhirubhai Ambani School event, supporting their daughter.</li><li>Abhishek gained praise for helping Aishwarya with her outfit.</li><li>Videos of their attendance went viral, leading fans to defend them against trolls.</li></ul><blockquote>“Whatever it is, Aishwarya is a very good woman and respects her husband's family and traditions!”</blockquote><p>This public display of unity has resonated well with fans, many of whom are relieved to see the couple together again.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/aishwarya-rai-abhishek-bachchan-squash-divorce-rumours-proudly-record-aaradhya-s-annual-day-performance-with-abram-101734680326814.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/aishwarya-rai-abhishek-bachchan-squash-divorce-rumours-proudly-record-aaradhya-s-annual-day-performance-with-abram-101734680326814.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:10:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UI Box Office Day 1 Prediction: Upendra Starrer Set For A Decent Start, To Stay Below 10 Crores - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UI Box Office Day 1 Prediction: Upendra Starrer Set For A Decent Start, To Stay Below 10 Crores</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/ui-box-office-day-1-prediction-upendra-starrer-set-for-a-decent-start-to-stay-below-10-crores.jpg" alt="UI Box Office Prediction" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>UI Box Office Prediction (Photo Credit – Instagram)</figcaption><p>The Upendra starrer Kannada dystopian science fiction action film, UI has been released in the theatres today (December 20). The film is expected to open between 6 to 8 crores despite mixed reviews.</p><h4><strong>Key Points:</strong></h4><ul><li>Advance booking for Day 1 comes to 2.60 crores.</li><li>Expected to open lower than Upendra’s previous film, Kabzaa.</li><li>UI will be released in 1400 screens across the country, including 850 in Karnataka.</li><li>Facing tough competition from Pushpa 2 and Viduthalai 2.</li></ul><blockquote>“The movie is expected to mainly do well in the state of Karnataka.”</blockquote><p>UI is set in a dystopian 2040 era, dealing with themes of corruption and poverty. The opening day performance will be closely monitored.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/ui-box-office-day-1-prediction-upendra-starrer-set-for-a-decent-start-to-stay-below-10-crores/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/ui-box-office-day-1-prediction-upendra-starrer-set-for-a-decent-start-to-stay-below-10-crores/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:06:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 15: 1 Historical Record In Only 62 Days – Allu Arjun’s Blockbuster Beats Stree 2 To Become #1 Hindi Film Of All Time! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 15: 1 Historical Record In Only 62 Days – Allu Arjun’s Blockbuster B</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 19, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-15-01.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 15" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 15: Allu Arjun’s Magnum Opus Creates History! ( Photo Credit – Instagram )</figcaption><p>Allu Arjun, Rashmika Mandanna, and Fahadh Faasil starrer has finally broken the most significant record in Hindi cinema. It has surpassed Stree 2 to become the highest-grossing film ever. If that’s not enough, the action thriller has also registered the biggest day 15 collection of all time.</p><h4>Key Points:</h4><ul><li>Pushpa 2 is now the highest-grossing Hindi film with a total collection of <strong>632.50 crores</strong>.</li><li>The film earned <strong>14 crores</strong> on day 15, the highest day 15 collection ever.</li><li>It surpassed Stree 2’s previous record of <strong>627.50 crores</strong>.</li><li>Pushpa 2’s collections indicate a strong performance with a dip of only <strong>17%</strong> from the previous day.</li><li>The movie could reach the <strong>700 crore</strong> mark, a first in Hindi cinema history.</li></ul><h4>Notable Statistics:</h4><blockquote>“The cost spent on the Hindi release is approximately <strong>200 crores</strong>. Pushpa 2 has registered returns of <strong>432.50 crores</strong> in only 15 days, with a ROI% of <strong>216.25%</strong>.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Pushpa 2 is setting new benchmarks in the film industry with its outstanding box office performance, and it marks a historic moment for Hindi cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-15-1-historical-record-in-only-62-days-allu-arjuns-blockbuster-beats-stree-2-to-become-1-hindi-film-of-all-time/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-15-1-historical-record-in-only-62-days-allu-arjuns-blockbuster-beats-stree-2-to-become-1-hindi-film-of-all-time/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:51:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arjun Kapoor opens up about parents’ ‘traumatic’ separation, dad Boney Kapoor falling in love with Sridevi: ‘As long as he was happy with what he had done…’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arjun Kapoor opens up about parents’ ‘traumatic’ separation, dad Boney Kapoor falling in love with Sridevi: ‘As long as he was happy with what he had done…’</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> The Indian Express, Publication Date: December 2024</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Arjun-Kapoor-mona-kapoor-boney-kapoor.jpg?w=640" alt="Arjun Kapoor- mona kapoor- boney kapoor" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Arjun Kapoor and his mother, later Mona Kapoor (left), Arjun with father Boney Kapoor. (Photos: Varinder Chawla, Arjun Kapoor/ Instagram)</figcaption><p>In a recent podcast, actor Arjun Kapoor shared the challenges he faced due to his parents’ separation and the loss of his mother, revealing how these traumatic events shaped his life and relationships.</p><ul><li>Arjun’s parents, Boney Kapoor and Mona Shourie, separated when he was 10 years old.</li><li>Arjun lost his mother at the age of 25, just before his film debut.</li><li>Reflecting on his childhood, Arjun noted the lack of a typical father-son relationship due to his father's busy schedule.</li><li>He mentioned that the separation led him to mature early to maintain a connection with his father.</li><li>Arjun acknowledged that the emotional turmoil impacted his academic performance.</li><li>Despite challenges, he credited films for creating a bond with his father during tough times.</li></ul><blockquote>“As long as he was happy with what he had done, I was okay with it. Even if I wasn’t ok with it, I rationalised it in my head at a young age.”</blockquote><p>The experience of his parents’ separation has had lasting effects on Arjun’s relationships and personal growth, emphasizing the importance of familial connections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/arjun-kapoor-opens-up-about-parents-traumatic-separation-dad-boney-kapoor-falling-in-love-with-sridevi-9735846/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/arjun-kapoor-opens-up-about-parents-traumatic-separation-dad-boney-kapoor-falling-in-love-with-sridevi-9735846/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:47:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 vs Baby John Screen Battle Intensifies: What are Anil Thadani and PVRInox fighting for this Christmas? - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 vs Baby John Screen Battle Intensifies: What are Anil Thadani and PVRInox fighting for this Christmas?</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 20, 2024 | Source: Pinkvilla</strong></p><img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/150856341_pushpa-2-baby-john-screen-fight-main-1.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 vs Baby John Screen Battle Intensifies: What are Anil Thadani and PVRInox fighting for this Christmas? "><figcaption>Pushpa 2 vs Baby John Screen Battle Intensifies</figcaption><p>The screen battle between Anil Thadani's Pushpa 2 and PVRInox's Baby John heats up as both parties vie for showtime during the Christmas holidays. Pushpa 2 seeks a dominant share of the shows, leading to tensions with multiplexes.</p><ul><li>Pushpa 2 is aiming for 50% of showtimes on Christmas Day, while Baby John aims to secure at least 11,000 shows across India.</li><li>The competition has ignited disputes over how many shows each film will receive in multiplexes and single screens.</li><li>Pushpa 2 has been breaking box office records, approaching the Rs 600 crore mark after three weekends.</li><li>Multiplex operators are attempting to find a balance for both films while meeting industry demands.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s unfair to have 50 percent shows in week 4, leaving nothing for new releases.”</blockquote><p>The outcome of this battle will heavily influence the box office performance as the films navigate the competitive landscape during the holiday season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-vs-baby-john-screen-battle-intensifies-what-are-anil-thadani-and-pvrinox-fighting-for-this-christmas-1363615</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-vs-baby-john-screen-battle-intensifies-what-are-anil-thadani-and-pvrinox-fighting-for-this-christmas-1363615</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:46:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2, Stree 2 or Kalki 2898 AD? BookMyShow report reveals which movie sold most tickets in 2024 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Tops 2024 Ticket Sales According to BookMyShow Report</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Pushpa_2_1734675005124_1734675005428.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna’s Pushpa 2 was released on December 5. " title="Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna’s Pushpa 2 was released on December 5. ">
<figcaption>Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna’s Pushpa 2 was released on December 5.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>BookMyShow's year-end report reveals that Pushpa 2 is the most-watched movie of 2024, with significant box office success and audience engagement.</p>
<ul>
<li>Pushpa 2: The Rule sold 10.8 lakh solo tickets, becoming the most-watched film of the year.</li>
<li>The film is a sequel to the 2021 hit Pushpa: The Rise, featuring Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna.</li>
<li>November 1 was a blockbuster day, recording 2.3 million tickets sold in 24 hours.</li>
<li>Live entertainment consumption grew by 18% in 2024 with over 30,000 events across 319 cities.</li>
<li>Music tourism showed a rise with 477,393 fans traveling for events, indicating a growing trend in live participation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Pushpa 2 has dominated the buzz and attention this year, solidifying its position in Telugu cinema history."</blockquote>
<p>The report indicates a strong year for Telugu cinema with a growing interest in live events and music, suggesting Post-pandemic recovery and increasing audience engagement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-stree-2-or-kalki-2898-ad-bookmyshow-report-reveals-which-movie-sold-most-tickets-in-2024-101734675009381.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-stree-2-or-kalki-2898-ad-bookmyshow-report-reveals-which-movie-sold-most-tickets-in-2024-101734675009381.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:36:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viduthalai Part - 2 Box Office Collection Day 1 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxONUdIVXBkZE5RZWRfOS1YY00tdURFT1dGT1ZBazFiSmZubHpoaU83LUtVY0NoZnZVa2EyOG5nVk9Nd0FneVRaa19fRnBJUkNINXI2VnR5VWZ6eThTS1FVcmkxay1TMlZwd21peVdJMUs2Yy1rRGdWZkVJM2NWcWRYcW83SVF2Q0ZPRzhDcmFR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxONUdIVXBkZE5RZWRfOS1YY00tdURFT1dGT1ZBazFiSmZubHpoaU83LUtVY0NoZnZVa2EyOG5nVk9Nd0FneVRaa19fRnBJUkNINXI2VnR5VWZ6eThTS1FVcmkxay1TMlZwd21peVdJMUs2Yy1rRGdWZkVJM2NWcWRYcW83SVF2Q0ZPRzhDcmFR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marco Box Office Collection Day 1 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE5jQnZlbHE4LXJSRVJXdDBETTVSMVhacldsTllVajdmTmRPSGlmeW95TWR2Sm9nWTBnRFJmeEw4OUlIdW1Genh6WG1yU2wwdzNCb2RBNnFmTmFqNFJTNzNwU1NHNlp4QjhHRzE0NGRYUWgtdko0TEs3NGhaWkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE5jQnZlbHE4LXJSRVJXdDBETTVSMVhacldsTllVajdmTmRPSGlmeW95TWR2Sm9nWTBnRFJmeEw4OUlIdW1Genh6WG1yU2wwdzNCb2RBNnFmTmFqNFJTNzNwU1NHNlp4QjhHRzE0NGRYUWgtdko0TEs3NGhaWkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hansal Mehta says he was also asked to be on FFI jury but refused as the process is 'not free of external pressures’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hansal Mehta Refuses FFI Jury Invitation Citing External Pressures</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/hmehta_1729144190450_1734679594150.jpg" alt="Hansal Mehta spoke about the Film Federation of India on X." title="Hansal Mehta spoke about the Film Federation of India on X."><figcaption>Hansal Mehta spoke about the Film Federation of India on X.</figcaption></figure><p>Filmmaker Hansal Mehta has declined an offer to be part of the Film Federation of India (FFI) jury, citing concerns about external influences impacting the selection process.</p><ul><li>Mehta expressed disappointment over FFI head Jahnu Baruaa's recent remarks on films.</li><li>He mentioned being invited to join the FFI jury multiple times but chose to opt-out.</li><li>His statement emphasizes the need for choices in film selections to be free from external pressures.</li><li>Baruaa called Payal Kapadia's film 'All We Imagine As Light' technically poor.</li><li>Mehta questioned Baruaa’s definitions and rationale behind such comments.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’d rather stay away than have to pretend that all these choices are free of external pressures and only based on merit.” – Hansal Mehta</blockquote><p>The discussion underscores ongoing debates in the Indian film industry regarding meritocracy and external influences in award selections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/hansal-mehta-says-he-was-also-asked-to-be-on-ffi-jury-but-refused-as-the-process-is-not-free-of-external-pressures-101734673711369.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/hansal-mehta-says-he-was-also-asked-to-be-on-ffi-jury-but-refused-as-the-process-is-not-free-of-external-pressures-101734673711369.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:24:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18 promo: Karan Veer Mehra questions his friendship with Vivian Dsena; asks, '20 second se upar - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18 Promo: Karan Veer Mehra Questions Friendship with Vivian Dsena</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116494598,imgsize-16414,width-400,resizemode-4/116494598.jpg" alt="Bigg Boss 18 promo: Karan Veer Mehra questions his friendship with Vivian Dsena; asks, '20 second se upar humare phone calls nahi huye?'" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Karan Veer Mehra confronts Vivian Dsena about their friendship.</figcaption><p>The recent promo for Bigg Boss 18 has sparked conversations regarding the friendship dynamics between Karan Veer Mehra and Vivian Dsena, as Karan challenges their connection based on the brevity of their phone calls over the years.</p><ul><li>Vivian expresses that he does not share a friendship with Karan.</li><li>Karan confronts Vivian about their phone calls having never lasted more than 20 seconds in 12 years.</li><li>Avinash Mishra comments on Karan's vulnerability in the situation.</li><li>The drama escalates into an intense argument between Karan and Vivian.</li></ul><blockquote>Karan: “20 seconds se zyada humare phone calls nahi huye. 3-4 baar, 12 saalon mein. Hum dost hain?”</blockquote><p>This ongoing situation has left fans divided, especially after host Salman Khan and Vivian's wife addressed the relationship on the show.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-promo-karan-veer-mehra-questions-his-friendship-with-vivian-dsena-asks-20-second-se-upar-humare-phone-calls-nahi-huye/articleshow/116494607.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-promo-karan-veer-mehra-questions-his-friendship-with-vivian-dsena-asks-20-second-se-upar-humare-phone-calls-nahi-huye/articleshow/116494607.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Preeti Panigrahi and Kesav Binoy Kiron talk about Ali Fazal’s epic ‘You’re being replaced’ prank and Hrithik Roshan’s unforgettable reaction after watching Girls Will Be Girls: “He said, ‘I have a lump in my throat; give me a hug’” - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>EXCLUSIVE: Preeti Panigrahi and Kesav Binoy Kiron talk about Ali Fazal’s epic ‘You’re being replaced’ prank and Hrithik Roshan’s unforgettable reaction after watching Girls Will Be Girls: “He said, ‘I have a lump in my throat; give me a hug’”</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 18, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p><p><img src="https://media5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Preeti-Panigrahi-1.jpg" alt="Preeti Panigrahi and Kesav Binoy Kiron" width="620" height="450"></p><figcaption>Preeti Panigrahi and Kesav Binoy Kiron during their interview.</figcaption><p>Preeti Panigrahi and Kesav Binoy Kiron, the stars of the upcoming film <em>Girls Will Be Girls</em>, spoke with Bollywood Hungama about their experiences on set, international recognition for the film, and memorable moments with industry veterans like Hrithik Roshan.</p><ul><li>The film premieres on Amazon Prime Video on December 18, 2024.</li><li>Kesav shared how Ali Fazal pranked him during production, creating a fun atmosphere on set.</li><li>Preeti expressed her emotional journey throughout the project's two-year duration and their experiences at various international film festivals.</li></ul><blockquote>“I just have a lump in my throat,” said Hrithik Roshan after watching the film, reflecting on its emotional impact.</blockquote><p>The insights shared by the actors highlight the themes of connection and cultural differences, as well as the significance of audience reactions in film.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/exclusive-preeti-panigrahi-kesav-binoy-kiron-talk-ali-fazals-epic-youre-replaced-prank-hrithik-roshans-unforgettable-reaction-wa/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/exclusive-preeti-panigrahi-kesav-binoy-kiron-talk-ali-fazals-epic-youre-replaced-prank-hrithik-roshans-unforgettable-reaction-wa/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:30:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kannada star Shiva Rajkumar turns emotional as he leaves for surgery in the US - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shiva Rajkumar Gets Emotional Before Surgery in the US</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 20, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: 123telugu</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Shiva-Rajkumar.jpg" alt="Shiva Rajkumar" width="500" height="333">
<figcaption>Shiva Rajkumar before his surgery</figcaption>
<p>Kannada film star Shiva Rajkumar expressed his emotions while addressing the media before departing for surgery in the USA. He thanked his fans, family, and friends for their support.</p>
<ul>
<li>Shiva Rajkumar's surgery is scheduled for December 24 at the Miami Cancer Institute.</li>
<li>He cited Dr. Murugesh N Manohar as his oncologist, emphasizing his reputation and skills.</li>
<li>Shiva mentioned feeling nervous about leaving his loved ones but reassured fans that he is in good hands.</li>
<li>He plans to return to Bengaluru on January 26, with his family accompanying him during the treatment.</li>
<li>Currently, he is working on several projects, including Uttarakaanda and RC16.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“He is a very famous oncologist and has a good hand, a lucky hand. He assured me not to worry and told me the treatment would be a seamless procedure.”</blockquote>
<p>Shiva Rajkumar's emotional farewell highlights the importance of support during challenging times, as he prepares for surgery that could greatly impact his health and career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/kannada-star-shiva-rajkumar-turns-emotional-as-he-leaves-for-surgery-in-the-us.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/kannada-star-shiva-rajkumar-turns-emotional-as-he-leaves-for-surgery-in-the-us.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[G-Dragon And Han So Hee Deny Dating Rumors - soompi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>G-Dragon And Han So Hee Deny Dating Rumors</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Soompi</p>
<img src="https://6.soompi.io/wp-content/uploads/image/20241220055214_g-dragon-han-so-hee.jpg?s=900x600&amp;e=t" alt="G-Dragon And Han So Hee Deny Dating Rumors">
<figcaption>G-Dragon and Han So Hee deny rumors of their romantic involvement.</figcaption>
<p>G-Dragon and Han So Hee have officially denied any dating rumors that sparked online due to social media posts.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Speculation arose on December 19 from photos shared by both celebrities that seemed to be taken at the same location.</li>
    <li>G-Dragon’s agency stated the dating accusations are “completely untrue.”</li>
    <li>Han So Hee’s agency echoed sentiments, declaring the claims are not true.</li>
    <li>Both parties aimed to clarify the situation with official statements.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The dating rumors between the two are completely untrue.” - G-Dragon’s agency</blockquote>
<p>In summary, both G-Dragon and Han So Hee have dismissed the dating rumors as unfounded, aiming to put an end to the speculation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.soompi.com/article/1711621wpp/g-dragon-and-han-so-hee-deny-dating-rumors</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.soompi.com/article/1711621wpp/g-dragon-and-han-so-hee-deny-dating-rumors</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:03:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's how Kamal is 'handling' his new 'script'.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kamal Haasan Reveals His Unique Approach to New Script</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p>
<img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/kamal_s11734674584.jpg" alt="Kamal Haasan handling script with gloves">
<figcaption>Kamal Haasan tries out gloves for his new script.</figcaption>
<p>Superstar Kamal Haasan humorously shared on Instagram that he is 'handling' his new script with 'kid gloves', showcasing his playful side.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kamal is currently in the US and shared a photo from a clothing store, trying on tan gloves.</li>
  <li>He recently spent time in Chicago, enjoying the chilly weather and sharing photos of his experiences.</li>
  <li>Kamal will next appear in Mani Ratnam's film “Thug Life” in November.</li>
  <li>He expressed a desire to be referred to simply as 'Kamal Haasan' and declined affectionate titles to stay grounded in his craft.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The art of cinema transcends beyond any one individual and I am but a student of the craft, forever hoping to evolve, learn and grow.” - Kamal Haasan</blockquote>
<p>Kamal Haasan emphasizes humility and collaboration in cinema while requesting audiences to respect his wishes regarding how he is addressed.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/heres-how-kamal-is-handling-his-new-script-142876</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/heres-how-kamal-is-handling-his-new-script-142876</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:03:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's how Kamal is 'handling' his new 'script' - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kamal Haasan Reveals His Unique Approach to New Script</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p>
<img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/kamal_s11734674584.jpg" alt="Kamal Haasan handling script with gloves">
<figcaption>Kamal Haasan tries out gloves for his new script.</figcaption>
<p>Superstar Kamal Haasan humorously shared on Instagram that he is 'handling' his new script with 'kid gloves', showcasing his playful side.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kamal is currently in the US and shared a photo from a clothing store, trying on tan gloves.</li>
  <li>He recently spent time in Chicago, enjoying the chilly weather and sharing photos of his experiences.</li>
  <li>Kamal will next appear in Mani Ratnam's film “Thug Life” in November.</li>
  <li>He expressed a desire to be referred to simply as 'Kamal Haasan' and declined affectionate titles to stay grounded in his craft.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The art of cinema transcends beyond any one individual and I am but a student of the craft, forever hoping to evolve, learn and grow.” - Kamal Haasan</blockquote>
<p>Kamal Haasan emphasizes humility and collaboration in cinema while requesting audiences to respect his wishes regarding how he is addressed.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/heres-how-kamal-is-handling-his-new-script-142876</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/heres-how-kamal-is-handling-his-new-script-142876</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:03:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Varun Dhawan says old guard of Bollywood has lost touch with reality: ‘Shah Rukh, Salman, Aamir are not delulu…’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-wFBVV95cUxNcV85SW9IMlE0al9PUnNUOE5yTmhIZlJiUUN3VXVaM00zaVdkZFFGbjljNDRzaDlWNjE5ZVJwODZta1hrYjJQQTIwT2o0em82MGs0SnhwblA0dE9ZdkY1S1l0LUVCbzA1MXVjUi1Jekd1UVZMTzJ5UWJCYVVIZzl6M25qbkdYckFTTkZqeUczY2dOQXBpRFRvSEJJdEVHR0dtNHNOcDVsbkREN190RkkxZ1poTEZwQlNadGM0dVdEY0g1RE05WjBOU0gxVktQWWZEeHVvZnFLeExiWkFFMk5YRnJqbVB6LS16M1VhaTBzamY5NlRQVW53NU5CNNIBggJBVV95cUxPSmlfaFFvSllveV8tTXZuT1VfWEcyVGxNNEQ4LTlSSUdqU1k0cV9Rd3pWQTlVZWtMUFN0V1dJSXNqbFJ6TkI5bUFieGZYRXJLSHI1RFVQY0hWYVFobDlfMlpCU3ZFc0NiOEZUcWx2M0RwanBHdzdHajZBVzBKcUUzbXZlQTlVVjBVSWROSnZaU1lFZGlQRkdSSnFQZWJNX1RxRmV3ZUw3QWJvM2wwc0daazhiV01FX0JRZUtzQjVMbHg0anBrOTMwT2tqWDhrcl9sYVJ6NnVENkJtdFNjV0FMVmRKQzNJWl9YNUMwT0JBb0gtci1mLUI3bWpzSUY5Y1hvV2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-wFBVV95cUxNcV85SW9IMlE0al9PUnNUOE5yTmhIZlJiUUN3VXVaM00zaVdkZFFGbjljNDRzaDlWNjE5ZVJwODZta1hrYjJQQTIwT2o0em82MGs0SnhwblA0dE9ZdkY1S1l0LUVCbzA1MXVjUi1Jekd1UVZMTzJ5UWJCYVVIZzl6M25qbkdYckFTTkZqeUczY2dOQXBpRFRvSEJJdEVHR0dtNHNOcDVsbkREN190RkkxZ1poTEZwQlNadGM0dVdEY0g1RE05WjBOU0gxVktQWWZEeHVvZnFLeExiWkFFMk5YRnJqbVB6LS16M1VhaTBzamY5NlRQVW53NU5CNNIBggJBVV95cUxPSmlfaFFvSllveV8tTXZuT1VfWEcyVGxNNEQ4LTlSSUdqU1k0cV9Rd3pWQTlVZWtMUFN0V1dJSXNqbFJ6TkI5bUFieGZYRXJLSHI1RFVQY0hWYVFobDlfMlpCU3ZFc0NiOEZUcWx2M0RwanBHdzdHajZBVzBKcUUzbXZlQTlVVjBVSWROSnZaU1lFZGlQRkdSSnFQZWJNX1RxRmV3ZUw3QWJvM2wwc0daazhiV01FX0JRZUtzQjVMbHg0anBrOTMwT2tqWDhrcl9sYVJ6NnVENkJtdFNjV0FMVmRKQzNJWl9YNUMwT0JBb0gtci1mLUI3bWpzSUY5Y1hvV2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:54:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is 70-year old Govind Namdev dating 31-year old actress Shivangi Verma? The actor clarifies, 'Meri sudha - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is 70-year old Govind Namdev dating 31-year old actress Shivangi Verma?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116492210,imgsize-31280,width-400,resizemode-4/116492210.jpg" alt="Govind Namdev and Shivangi Verma" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Is 70-year old Govind Namdev dating 31-year old actress Shivangi Verma?</figcaption>
<p>The news around Govind Namdev, a veteran actor, sparked dating rumors with the young actress Shivangi Verma following viral social media posts.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Govind Namdev clarified that the rumors of dating are false.</li>
  <li>He explained that the photos circulated are related to his latest film, <em>Gaurishankar Goharganj Wale</em>.</li>
  <li>Namdev expressed his commitment to his wife, Sudha, stressing that his affection towards her is unparalleled.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Ye Real Life Love nahi hai, Reel Life hai janaab! Ek film hai ‘Gaurishankar Goharganj Wale’... Falling in love with someone young in this lifetime is simply not possible."</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights how quickly rumors can spread, especially in the age of social media, and reinforces Namdev's dedication to his longtime spouse.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/is-70-year-old-govind-namdev-dating-31-year-old-actress-shivangi-verma-the-actor-clarifies-meri-sudha-saans-hai-meri/articleshow/116492252.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/is-70-year-old-govind-namdev-dating-31-year-old-actress-shivangi-verma-the-actor-clarifies-meri-sudha-saans-hai-meri/articleshow/116492252.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[G-Dragon And Han So Hee Deny Dating Rumors - Koreaboo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>G-Dragon And Han So Hee Deny Dating Rumors</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 8 hours ago</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Koreaboo</p>
<img loading="eager" src="https://img.koreaboo.com/tr:n-thumb_mega/2024/12/Untitled-design6-2.jpg" width="900" height="439" alt="G-Dragon and Han So Hee" />
<figcaption>G-Dragon and Han So Hee</figcaption>
<p>Both G-Dragon and Han So Hee’s agencies have denied rumors that they are dating following speculation from netizens.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Rumors sparked due to similarities in Instagram posts by both celebrities.</li>
    <li>They shared pictures from the same location, raising suspicions of a relationship.</li>
    <li>Agencies confirmed that the rumors are untrue and stated they do not have a particular friendship.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>The rumors about her relationship with G-Dragon are not true. They don’t have any particular friendship with each other.</p>
<p>— 9ATO Entertainment</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>[The rumors] are not true.</p>
<p>— Galaxy Corporation</p></blockquote>
<p>The agencies affirm the rumors are baseless, aiming to quell any ongoing speculation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koreaboo.com/news/gdragon-han-so-hee-deny-dating-rumors/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koreaboo.com/news/gdragon-han-so-hee-deny-dating-rumors/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:37:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan leave daughter Aaradhya Bachchan's school event together amid divorce rumours. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan Seen Together Amid Divorce Rumours at Daughter's School Event</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Aishwarya_Rai_Abhishek_Bachchan_1734670398456_1734670432846.webp" alt="Aaradhya Bachchan, Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan leaving the event venue." title="Aaradhya Bachchan, Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan leaving the event venue."/><figcaption>Aaradhya Bachchan, Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan leaving the event venue.</figcaption><p>Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan attended their daughter Aaradhya's annual school event together, dispelling ongoing divorce rumours.</p><ul><li>The couple was seen together at Dhirubhai Ambani School alongside Amitabh Bachchan.</li><li>They exhibited affectionate gestures, including holding hands and capturing moments from Aaradhya's performance.</li><li>Speculation about their separation arose in July 2024, after the couple was seen arriving separately at family events.</li><li>The school event was attended by other Bollywood stars including Shah Rukh Khan and Kareena Kapoor.</li></ul><blockquote>“The couple was accompanied by actor Amitabh Bachchan, who came to support his granddaughter Aaradhya.”</blockquote><p>Despite speculation regarding their marriage, Aishwarya and Abhishek's appearance together signals ongoing family unity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aishwarya-rai-and-abhishek-bachchan-leave-daughter-aaradhya-bachchans-school-event-together-amid-divorce-rumours-watch-101734669153534.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aishwarya-rai-and-abhishek-bachchan-leave-daughter-aaradhya-bachchans-school-event-together-amid-divorce-rumours-watch-101734669153534.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:32:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Interesting update on Varun Tej’s Korean Kanakaraju - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Interesting update on Varun Tej’s Korean Kanakaraju</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 20, 2024 11:00 am IST</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/VarunTej-1.jpg" alt="Varun Tej" width="550" height="367">
<figcaption>Varun Tej's upcoming film Korean Kanakaraju.</figcaption>
<p>Mega hero Varun Tej aims to make a strong comeback with his new film, tentatively titled Korean Kanakaraju, following a series of box office failures.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Varun Tej's last films were unsuccessful, with the latest, Matka, not performing well.</li>
  <li>Korean Kanakaraju is a horror thriller set against a Rayalaseema backdrop, mostly filmed in Korea.</li>
  <li>Ritika Nayak, known for her roles in recent hits, will play the female lead.</li>
  <li>The film will be directed by Merlapaka Gandhi, who has a history of successful projects.</li>
  <li>Production is handled by UV Creations and First Frame Entertainments, with more details about the cast and crew expected soon.</li>
</ul>
<p>As anticipation builds for Korean Kanakaraju, fans look forward to seeing how Varun Tej reinvents his career with this project.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/interesting-update-on-varun-tejs-korean-kanakaraju.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/interesting-update-on-varun-tejs-korean-kanakaraju.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Box Office: 'Maharaja' Beats 'Baahubali 2' To Become Highest Grossing South Indian Movie In China - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQNHVuYkkxOHVNNnkwRHVVdjI0cWNoeFBZWjIwdGNNbnR0RFNvSDNRRUhUTkgtRUIzSXNDMWZkM2V5amVMN0t3ckdDMGFaNEdNS2M2ZElXY0F1YmgzWVhPYVVzNDVrQTR3X0k4VF9XQ0x3QmlrT184aDI0bmxkYVVtMlQxcHpFajRMUHd4RjBtQkNLYW5kdEV0UWlaQzNrTGp2dC1RUGJMWnFTNXUyVHdSRzgzYXpwaWlWbkdFaWNB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQNHVuYkkxOHVNNnkwRHVVdjI0cWNoeFBZWjIwdGNNbnR0RFNvSDNRRUhUTkgtRUIzSXNDMWZkM2V5amVMN0t3ckdDMGFaNEdNS2M2ZElXY0F1YmgzWVhPYVVzNDVrQTR3X0k4VF9XQ0x3QmlrT184aDI0bmxkYVVtMlQxcHpFajRMUHd4RjBtQkNLYW5kdEV0UWlaQzNrTGp2dC1RUGJMWnFTNXUyVHdSRzgzYXpwaWlWbkdFaWNB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:13:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Box Office Collections: Allu Arjun film tops 1100cr in India in 2 weeks, Racing towards Baahubali 2 - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Collections: Allu Arjun film tops 1100cr in India in 2 weeks, Racing towards Baahubali 2</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 20, 2024 | Source: Pinkvilla</strong></p><div><img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/511313591_pushpa-3.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2," title="Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)</figcaption></div><p>Pushpa 2 has emerged as an ALL TIME BLOCKBUSTER, grossing over Rs. 1110 crore in just two weeks.</p><ul><li>The film grossed Rs. 808.75 crore in its first week.</li><li>Second week earnings were Rs. 301 crore, a decline of only 51% from the first week.</li><li>It is now the fourth-highest grosser of all time in the Telugu states.</li><li>Pushpa 2's collections are significantly higher in several regions, including Gujarat and CP Berar.</li></ul><blockquote>“The film is already the fourth-highest-grosser of all time in the twin states and is set to claim the third spot today by surpassing Kalki 2898 AD.”</blockquote><p>Pushpa 2's performance is exceptional, with the film positioning itself alongside legendary hits and facing strong competition for box office supremacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collections-allu-arjun-film-tops-1100cr-in-india-in-2-weeks-racing-towards-baahubali-2-1363588</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collections-allu-arjun-film-tops-1100cr-in-india-in-2-weeks-racing-towards-baahubali-2-1363588</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:03:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tabla Legend Zakir Hussain's Funeral Held In San Francisco - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxPNk9BVVRwd0lHU2tHbkFBbF9OWmotclFtRlR3RkVrcGtjNF8xalpKZFlVX2toRGlqSUJBUzAyelJjMFJPbVNLTkFoRnpKUU9WZWNyV0sxUUNBMVRPOU1VbjF4MXNoSEQyTXVFX3pOMWVDX3gzZkdaOWNGS3h0ellGZUhaZmgxT0laa1E3b1l4dHVPWG1LNC1VaG5ZZXY3QdIBpgFBVV95cUxOSnZMaDdXRTFua2R0dTZzRU13aGFnMER0X1hJNVZRMzNhYW15ekpiY0p0RHBVRUN0X3MwbU0wQjZ6eGo4eFdybGxtbEM0TnBWWl9kNngzRElncWJCQ2FYcDNiSTY0NWxGbTRycW1nM190bXdMQ090b2NsQmRENnBJU0NzVHBUX2xOdDRWaWRETmJIOUJGbWU2UEh1bXlvQU02b2Z5eFRR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxPNk9BVVRwd0lHU2tHbkFBbF9OWmotclFtRlR3RkVrcGtjNF8xalpKZFlVX2toRGlqSUJBUzAyelJjMFJPbVNLTkFoRnpKUU9WZWNyV0sxUUNBMVRPOU1VbjF4MXNoSEQyTXVFX3pOMWVDX3gzZkdaOWNGS3h0ellGZUhaZmgxT0laa1E3b1l4dHVPWG1LNC1VaG5ZZXY3QdIBpgFBVV95cUxOSnZMaDdXRTFua2R0dTZzRU13aGFnMER0X1hJNVZRMzNhYW15ekpiY0p0RHBVRUN0X3MwbU0wQjZ6eGo4eFdybGxtbEM0TnBWWl9kNngzRElncWJCQ2FYcDNiSTY0NWxGbTRycW1nM190bXdMQ090b2NsQmRENnBJU0NzVHBUX2xOdDRWaWRETmJIOUJGbWU2UEh1bXlvQU02b2Z5eFRR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 04:47:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why PVR INOX pulled 'Pushpa 2' starring Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna from theaters - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6wFBVV95cUxNWU8wSVRNYnpXXzFyOUxmOHE4R0Z2ekxNR3I1WXJDTzhlVWdaNFBkNkliTWtjeGJPTnF0dmhOYVJMZWtKUTE5dDJ2b1I0bklEakVXcnF2M0k4M3JRaVBrd1JIWG5SejUyRkRkcE5uSDlPUm40emw1QWJxZ0pLc3A0VkVZVkw5a3dkMXVhQU1kRDRRZHJtRFBXYmhTVFo0a2dyLUl2NjJDc2pwLUxRLW5xT0l3eW5DUFQ1ZmJmaFlGVWpDTXpaSk43VVlsUVdmVTdIbkRMa3lFVExQaWRieGVsNjJmTGo0Tl9JemE40gHwAUFVX3lxTE9kSzUyUHc3Wk9MYUd4RlBMMHpjSG5oRVVhMjlCN1RnVDM2RUhUc29lTlpGYmk5U1JnT1RZNE51RTZWdFEzQUtwSUlyaGpFckVCRWU1eWpITXZfQ1ozY0ZGcEJ5OHJMZ0thR0RnQmpNN1RRS2UxOXEwWFJoQkdLLXFnblBkX1loNUhYUnZkcWdaTlFSN2h1UEZPckg2ZDRvbEtMWUsyMFRsMk5HX19GSzFnVlpLOWphMjUzSHNVN0FtZm1jVzAyZGVnVURDOEVlSXhxaTJhdHFhVV90azEtLUE5Q3N3YUJWNU5kaVowVjZpNg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6wFBVV95cUxNWU8wSVRNYnpXXzFyOUxmOHE4R0Z2ekxNR3I1WXJDTzhlVWdaNFBkNkliTWtjeGJPTnF0dmhOYVJMZWtKUTE5dDJ2b1I0bklEakVXcnF2M0k4M3JRaVBrd1JIWG5SejUyRkRkcE5uSDlPUm40emw1QWJxZ0pLc3A0VkVZVkw5a3dkMXVhQU1kRDRRZHJtRFBXYmhTVFo0a2dyLUl2NjJDc2pwLUxRLW5xT0l3eW5DUFQ1ZmJmaFlGVWpDTXpaSk43VVlsUVdmVTdIbkRMa3lFVExQaWRieGVsNjJmTGo0Tl9JemE40gHwAUFVX3lxTE9kSzUyUHc3Wk9MYUd4RlBMMHpjSG5oRVVhMjlCN1RnVDM2RUhUc29lTlpGYmk5U1JnT1RZNE51RTZWdFEzQUtwSUlyaGpFckVCRWU1eWpITXZfQ1ozY0ZGcEJ5OHJMZ0thR0RnQmpNN1RRS2UxOXEwWFJoQkdLLXFnblBkX1loNUhYUnZkcWdaTlFSN2h1UEZPckg2ZDRvbEtMWUsyMFRsMk5HX19GSzFnVlpLOWphMjUzSHNVN0FtZm1jVzAyZGVnVURDOEVlSXhxaTJhdHFhVV90azEtLUE5Q3N3YUJWNU5kaVowVjZpNg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 04:38:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UI (2024) Box Office Collection Day 1 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE9PZloyNmdVWS10VjJucThmVkRrdVFCejRjS1AtdWxiSnhkNjhnc3BwZzVzc0l1bERQVkRjaUJDN1JfWXlZOXlJY0JPcUFHTDI5QkdBWjNFLUpsUzFWWk5XbGVpWDNSRGxhWkx1aXlpb3BDckdxaUxQVw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE9PZloyNmdVWS10VjJucThmVkRrdVFCejRjS1AtdWxiSnhkNjhnc3BwZzVzc0l1bERQVkRjaUJDN1JfWXlZOXlJY0JPcUFHTDI5QkdBWjNFLUpsUzFWWk5XbGVpWDNSRGxhWkx1aXlpb3BDckdxaUxQVw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 04:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Travis Kelce puts an end to Taylor Swift engagement rumour after blurry picture surfaces: ‘He thinks its… - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Travis Kelce Denies Engagement Rumors With Taylor Swift After Blurry Picture Sparks Speculation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/taylor-swift-travis-kelce-_1734668900970_1734668901332.webp" alt="Travis Kelce and Taylor Swift" title="Travis Kelce and Taylor Swift" /><figcaption>Travis Kelce and Taylor Swift</figcaption></figure><p>Taylor Swift and Travis Kelce remain at the heart of engagement speculation, but they prefer to keep their relationship private, despite ongoing rumors.</p><ul><li>The couple has been in the spotlight since summer, with fans speculating about their engagement.</li><li>A blurry photo from a surprise party sparked rumors of an engagement ring, but insiders claim there is no truth to it yet.</li><li>Kelce finds the rumors amusing but also overwhelming due to family pressures and public interest.</li><li>Both Swift and Kelce are focused on their careers and are not rushing into an engagement.</li><li>They plan to keep any future engagement low-key and private, despite media and fan speculation.</li></ul><blockquote>“Travis has ideas, he would love to be engaged and married to Taylor, he is in love. She is in love with him.”</blockquote><p>Ultimately, Travis and Taylor are enjoying their relationship without letting the engagement buzz disrupt their time together.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/travis-kelce-puts-an-end-to-taylor-swift-engagement-rumour-after-blurry-picture-surfaces-he-thinks-its-101734668584526.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/travis-kelce-puts-an-end-to-taylor-swift-engagement-rumour-after-blurry-picture-surfaces-he-thinks-its-101734668584526.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 04:32:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>