<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:22:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:22:29 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan recalls being offered Heeramandi in first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali: ‘It was in works but…' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan recalls being offered Heeramandi fifteen years ago when she was not even an actor, shares details of her first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/mahira_1734445320900_1734445344435.jpg" alt="Mahira Khan recalls her first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali when he offered her Heeramandi." title="Mahira Khan recalls her first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali when he offered her Heeramandi."><figcaption>Mahira Khan recalls her first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali when he offered her Heeramandi.</figcaption><p>In a recent interview, Mahira Khan shared her experience of being offered a role in Heeramandi during her first meeting with filmmaker Sanjay Leela Bhansali, a significant moment in her early career.</p><ul><li>Mahira Khan was introduced to Bhansali through a friend while attending a wedding in Mumbai.</li><li>She remembered Bhansali looking for a Pakistani actress for a project, leading to her impromptu meeting.</li><li>During the meeting, she was praised by Bhansali, who was interested in casting her for Heeramandi.</li><li>Despite the excitement, political issues prevented her from accepting the role at the time.</li><li>Heeramandi has since been released on Netflix, depicting the lives of courtesans during the British Raj.</li></ul><blockquote>“What a man he is! So creative and a genius. He said, 'Can you wipe your lipstick off?' I said, 'I'm not wearing any lipstick'.”</blockquote><p>Ultimately, Mahira's candid approach and desire for honesty regarding her marital status played a crucial role in her career decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mahira-khan-recalls-being-offered-heeramandi-in-first-meeting-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-it-was-in-works-but-101734444994653.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mahira-khan-recalls-being-offered-heeramandi-in-first-meeting-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-it-was-in-works-but-101734444994653.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:57:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Khanna REACTS to Sonakshi Sinha's post slamming him for questioning her upbringing: 'I have a cord - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mukesh Khanna REACTS to Sonakshi Sinha's post slamming him for questioning her upbringing</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116406511,imgsize-43502,width-400,resizemode-4/116406511.jpg" alt="Mukesh Khanna REACTS to Sonakshi Sinha's post slamming him for questioning her upbringing: 'I have a cordial relationship with Shatrughan Sinha'">
<figcaption>Mukesh Khanna and Sonakshi Sinha in a recent public spat.</figcaption>
<p>Mukesh Khanna has responded to Sonakshi Sinha's backlash regarding his comments on her upbringing and knowledge of the Ramayana. He clarifies that his intention was not malicious and emphasizes a need for deeper knowledge in today's generation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sonakshi Sinha criticized Mukesh Khanna for linking her inability to answer a KBC question to her father's teaching.</li>
  <li>Mukesh Khanna expressed surprise at the delay in Sonakshi's response and affirmed his cordial relationship with Shatrughan Sinha.</li>
  <li>He intended to comment on modern reliance on technology for information, using Sonakshi's situation as an example.</li>
  <li>Sonakshi defended herself, noting that others also struggled with the same question on KBC.</li>
  <li>Sonakshi recently married Zaheer Iqbal, with the wedding attended by several Bollywood celebrities.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Dear Sir, Mukesh Khanna ji ...I recently read a statement you made saying that it's my father's fault I did not answer a question about the Ramayana correctly on a show I attended many, many years back.” - Sonakshi Sinha</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing dialogue highlights the sensitive nature of public commentary on personal backgrounds and the importance of understanding context in such discussions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mukesh-khanna-reacts-to-sonakshi-sinhas-post-slamming-him-for-questioning-her-upbringing-i-have-a-cordial-relationship-with-shatrughan-sinha/articleshow/116406511.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mukesh-khanna-reacts-to-sonakshi-sinhas-post-slamming-him-for-questioning-her-upbringing-i-have-a-cordial-relationship-with-shatrughan-sinha/articleshow/116406511.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yami Gautam holds son Vedavid in her arms, joins Sanjay Dutt, Aditya Dhar to offer prayers at Golden Temple. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yami Gautam Holds Son Vedavid in Her Arms, Joins Sanjay Dutt, Aditya Dhar to Offer Prayers at Golden Temple</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/yami_1734447607806_1734447613966.jpg" alt="Yami Gautam, Aditya Dhar, Sanjay Dutt at the Golden Temple." title="Yami Gautam, Aditya Dhar, Sanjay Dutt at the Golden Temple.">
<figcaption>Yami Gautam, Aditya Dhar, Sanjay Dutt at the Golden Temple.</figcaption>
<p>Bollywood star Sanjay Dutt is currently in Amritsar for the shoot of his upcoming films with director Aditya Dhar. Yami Gautam joined them for a sacred visit to the Gurudwara with her newborn son, Vedavid.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sanjay Dutt and Aditya Dhar offered prayers at the Golden Temple during their shooting schedule.</li>
  <li>Yami Gautam participated in the visit, bringing her son Vedavid along.</li>
  <li>Visuals of the visit showed the trio seeking blessings and interacting with fans.</li>
  <li>Yami held Vedavid in her arms, wrapped in a cloth.</li>
  <li>Sanjay Dutt met with Punjab minister Kuldeep Dhaliwal during the visit.</li>
  <li>The upcoming film, in collaboration with Jio Studios, is based on historical events related to Indian Intelligence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Jaako raakhe sayiyaan maar sake na koi..” - Ranveer Singh on his visit to the Golden Temple.</blockquote>
<p>This visit highlights the intersection of personal spirituality and professional commitments in the lives of these celebrities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/sanjay-dutt-yami-gautam-aditya-dhar-offer-prayers-at-golden-temple-101734447361116.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/sanjay-dutt-yami-gautam-aditya-dhar-offer-prayers-at-golden-temple-101734447361116.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:07:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Khanna reacts after Sonakshi Sinha slams him for questioning her upbringing: ‘Surprised she took so much time’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mukesh Khanna says he didn't have any malicious intention as he reacts to Sonakshi Sinha slamming him for questioning her upbringing.</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/Sonak_1734441857233_1734441875913.jpg" alt="Mukesh Khanna reacts to Sonakshi Sinha slamming him for questioning her upbringing." title="Mukesh Khanna reacts to Sonakshi Sinha slamming him for questioning her upbringing."><figcaption>Mukesh Khanna reacts to Sonakshi Sinha slamming him for questioning her upbringing.</figcaption><p>Mukesh Khanna has responded to Sonakshi Sinha's criticism regarding his comments on her upbringing, clarifying he had no malicious intent.</p><ul><li>Sonakshi criticized Mukesh for connecting her inability to answer a Ramayana question on KBC to her upbringing.</li><li>Mukesh expressed surprise at the time it took for Sonakshi to respond.</li><li>He aimed to highlight the limits of knowledge in the current generation compared to past generations.</li><li>Sonakshi defended herself, pointing out that another contestant also failed to answer the same question on the show.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am surprised she took so much time to react. I had no malicious intention to malign her or her father.” - Mukesh Khanna</blockquote><p>The exchange highlights ongoing discussions about celebrity accountability and generational knowledge differences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mukesh-khanna-reacts-after-sonakshi-sinha-slams-him-for-questioning-her-upbringing-surprised-she-took-so-much-time-101734441561232.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mukesh-khanna-reacts-after-sonakshi-sinha-slams-him-for-questioning-her-upbringing-surprised-she-took-so-much-time-101734441561232.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:15:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stampede after Allu Arjun visit: Police notice to theatre points to lapses – ‘illegal’ flex boards, lack of proper entry-exit signs - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stampede after Allu Arjun visit: Police notice to theatre points to lapses</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Allu-Arjun-3col.jpg?w=640' alt='Actor Allu Arjun leaves a Hyderabad hospital after medical check-up following his arrest Friday in a stampede case.' width='640' height='360'><figcaption>Actor Allu Arjun leaves a Hyderabad hospital after medical check-up following his arrest Friday in a stampede case.</figcaption><p>The Hyderabad City Police issued a show cause notice to Sandhya 70MM Theatre for lapses leading to a tragic stampede during the premiere of the movie Pushpa 2, which resulted in a fatality and serious injuries.</p><ul><li>The stampede occurred on December 4 during the premiere of Pushpa 2.</li><li>39-year-old M Revathi died, and her nine-year-old son was seriously injured.</li><li>The theatre management failed to inform police about the arrival of Allu Arjun.</li><li>Lapses noted include lack of entry-exit signs and illegal flex boards encouraging crowds.</li><li>Police are considering canceling the theatre’s license.</li></ul><blockquote>“The boy’s neurological functions are affected. He is in and out of coma.” - C V Anand, City Police Commissioner</blockquote><p>This incident highlights serious safety oversights at public events and raises questions about crowd management at high-profile appearances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/allu-arjun-stampede-police-notice-theatre-lapses-9730458/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/allu-arjun-stampede-police-notice-theatre-lapses-9730458/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:01:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sameer Wankhede avoids question on Shah Rukh Khan, Mahira Khan on viral smoking photos with Ranbir Kapoor - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sameer Wankhede avoids question on Shah Rukh Khan, Mahira Khan on viral smoking photos with Ranbir Kapoor: Top 5 news</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116402690,imgsize-53230,width-400,resizemode-4/116402690.jpg" alt="Sameer Wankhede avoids question on Shah Rukh Khan, Mahira Khan on viral smoking photos with Ranbir Kapoor" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Sameer Wankhede addressing Shah Rukh Khan controversy in an interview.</figcaption><p>The entertainment world is abuzz with headlines ranging from Sameer Wankhede's evasive comments on Shah Rukh Khan to Mahira Khan's candid reflections on her viral smoking photos with Ranbir Kapoor.</p><ul><li>Sameer Wankhede refrained from discussing Shah Rukh Khan's involvement in the ongoing controversy regarding his son.</li><li>Mahira Khan expressed feelings of despair over her viral smoking photos, stating it felt like her career was ending.</li><li>Ranveer Singh shared a heartwarming interaction with paparazzi while discussing his daughter, Dua.</li><li>Shatrughan Sinha defended his daughter Sonakshi against comments made by Mukesh Khanna.</li><li>Adnan Sami mourned the loss of renowned musician Zakir Hussain.</li></ul><blockquote>“I felt my career was over,” - Mahira Khan on her viral smoking photos.</blockquote><p>This article encapsulates the current drama in Bollywood, highlighting the personalities involved and their reflections on significant moments impacting their careers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sameer-wankhede-avoids-question-on-shah-rukh-khan-mahira-khan-on-viral-smoking-photos-with-ranbir-kapoor-to-shatrughan-sinha-slams-mukesh-khannatop-5-entertainment-news-of-the-day/articleshow/116402690.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sameer-wankhede-avoids-question-on-shah-rukh-khan-mahira-khan-on-viral-smoking-photos-with-ranbir-kapoor-to-shatrughan-sinha-slams-mukesh-khannatop-5-entertainment-news-of-the-day/articleshow/116402690.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Interview: Upendra – UI will make audiences decode its metaphors - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Interview: Upendra – UI will make audiences decode its metaphors</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 17, 2024</strong></p><p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Updher.jpg" alt="Upendra UI" width="321" height="500"><figcaption>Upendra in his upcoming film UI</figcaption></p><p>Kannada superstar Upendra discusses his upcoming film UI, set for release on December 20, 2024. He shares insights into the film's concept, character design, and his thoughts on storytelling in cinema.</p><ul><li>UI is described as an interactive film that invites audiences to decode its metaphors.</li><li>The film's concept challenges traditional education and encourages critical thinking.</li><li>Upendra emphasizes the teamwork involved in creating the film, crediting the producers for their support.</li><li>The film features unique visual artistry and music recorded in Hungary.</li><li>Upendra expresses excitement about working with Rajinikanth in the upcoming film Coolie.</li></ul><blockquote>“What I feel is what you feel. This is an interactive film where audiences will decode many things as they watch.” – Upendra</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Upendra aims to create a thought-provoking cinematic experience that resonates with audiences, encouraging them to engage deeply with the film's content.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/interview-upendra-ui-will-make-audiences-decode-its-metaphors.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/interview-upendra-ui-will-make-audiences-decode-its-metaphors.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ustad Zakir Hussain died of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. What is this lung condition? - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ustad Zakir Hussain died of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. What is this lung condition?</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 17, 2024 06:00 pm IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/utvl3x/article68995452.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_iStock-1432432550_2_1_50C9NJ7U.jpg" alt="Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a disease that causes scarring of the lungs." title="Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a disease that causes scarring of the lungs."><figcaption>Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a disease that causes scarring of the lungs. Photograph used for representational purposes only | Photo Credit: Getty Images</figcaption><p>Ustad Zakir Hussain, a legendary tabla maestro and four-time Grammy award winner, passed away at 73 in San Francisco on December 15, 2024, due to idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, leaving behind a significant legacy in classical music.</p><h4>Key Points:</h4><ul><li>IPF is a chronic lung disease characterized by scarring of the lungs, leading to progressively difficult breathing.</li><li>The cause of IPF is classified as 'idiopathic', meaning unknown, and it is the most common form of pulmonary fibrosis.</li><li>Risk factors for developing IPF include being a former or current smoker, age (rare under 50), and family history of pulmonary fibrosis.</li><li>Symptoms can include shortness of breath, persistent dry cough, fatigue, and changes in fingernails.</li><li>Diagnosis may involve medical history, CT scans, and respiratory tests, while treatment options are limited to slowing disease progression and supportive care.</li></ul><blockquote>“Think of the lung as a balloon. IPF hardens the lung tissue, making its elasticity go away.” - R. P. Ilangho, pulmonologist</blockquote><p>This news underlines the serious and often misunderstood condition of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, highlighting the importance of awareness and understanding around lung diseases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/ustad-zakir-hussain-died-of-idiopathic-pulmonary-fibrosis-what-is-this-lung-condition/article68994802.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/ustad-zakir-hussain-died-of-idiopathic-pulmonary-fibrosis-what-is-this-lung-condition/article68994802.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan BREAKS silence on not being able to do 'Heeramandi' with Sanjay Leela Bhansali, recalls her f - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan BREAKS silence on not being able to do 'Heeramandi' with Sanjay Leela Bhansali, recalls her first meeting with him: 'Don't tell him you're married'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> TOI</p>
<p>In a recent statement, Mahira Khan opened up about her inability to star in the much-anticipated project 'Heeramandi' with renowned director Sanjay Leela Bhansali. During the interview, she reminisced about her first encounter with him, revealing his memorable advice to her.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Mahira Khan's reflections on not being able to participate in 'Heeramandi'.</li>
  <li>Her first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali and his advice: 'Don't tell him you're married'.</li>
  <li>Insights into her career choices and future projects.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Don't tell him you're married." - Mahira Khan reflecting on Bhansali's advice during their first meeting.</blockquote>
<p>Overall, Mahira Khan's insights illustrate both the challenges and opportunities faced by actors in the Bollywood industry, especially concerning collaborations with iconic filmmakers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mahira-khan-breaks-silence-on-not-being-able-to-do-heeramandi-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-recalls-her-first-meeting-with-him-dont-tell-him-youre-married/articleshow/116402016.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mahira-khan-breaks-silence-on-not-being-able-to-do-heeramandi-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-recalls-her-first-meeting-with-him-dont-tell-him-youre-married/articleshow/116402016.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa-2 stampede: Hyderabad police find 11 lapses in Sandhya theatre - Deccan Chronicle]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hyderabad Police Identify 11 Lapses After Pushpa-2 Stampede at Sandhya Theatre</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 4, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Hyderabad Police</p><p>In a tragic incident during the premiere of 'Pushpa 2' at Sandhya 70 MM theatre, a stampede led to the death of a woman and raised serious questions about theatre management and safety protocols.</p><ul><li>Hyderabad police issued a show cause notice to Sandhya theatre management regarding lapses that contributed to the stampede.</li><li>The incident occurred on December 4, 2024, when a large crowd gathered for the film's premiere, anticipating the arrival of lead actors.</li><li>A woman died due to suffocation in the crowd, despite prompt medical attention.</li><li>Police found multiple lapses in crowd management and safety measures at the theatre.</li><li>The management did not inform police of actor Allu Arjun's arrival, leading to a chaotic situation.</li><li>There was inadequate crowd control, with no separate entry for celebrities and insufficient security personnel present.</li><li>The theatre has a combined capacity of 2520 persons, with poor signage and crowd management policies.</li><li>Unused security measures, like a single metal detector, were in place, failing to screen the crowd effectively.</li><li>The police have registered a case against the management under several acts related to public safety.</li><li>The theatre management must respond to the show cause notice within 10 days to avoid further legal repercussions.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was clearly visible that the management has failed to provide a safe and secure environment to the public who is coming to the theatre.” - Hyderabad Police</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the critical need for improved safety measures and crowd management at public events to prevent tragedies in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/pushpa-2-stampede-hyderabad-police-find-11-lapses-in-sandhya-theatre-1847584</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/pushpa-2-stampede-hyderabad-police-find-11-lapses-in-sandhya-theatre-1847584</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:08:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan makes rare comment on viral photos of her smoking with Ranbir Kapoor: ‘Is my career over?' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan Reflects on Controversy Over Smoking Photos with Ranbir Kapoor</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> HT Entertainment Desk</p><p>Mahira Khan addressed the backlash she faced after viral photos of her smoking with actor Ranbir Kapoor in New York emerged in 2017, revealing emotional and professional struggles during that period.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Mahira described her journey, including significant life events like her divorce and motherhood.</li><li>She expressed her initial fears about the impact of the controversial photos on her career.</li><li>The actor shared insights into how the media coverage affected her mental health.</li><li>She made a successful debut in Bollywood with the film Raees opposite Shah Rukh Khan.</li></ul><blockquote>“Is my career over?” - Mahira Khan reflecting on the backlash she faced from the photos.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Mahira Khan's candid reflections show how public scrutiny can deeply affect personal and professional lives, and how resilience plays a key role in overcoming challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mahira-khan-makes-rare-comment-on-viral-photos-of-her-smoking-with-ranbir-kapoor-101734432697039.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mahira-khan-makes-rare-comment-on-viral-photos-of-her-smoking-with-ranbir-kapoor-101734432697039.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:58:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kapil Sharma BREAKS Silence About 'Insulting' Atlee: ‘Watch And Decide By Yourself…’ - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kapil Sharma BREAKS Silence About 'Insulting' Atlee: ‘Watch And Decide By Yourself…’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Kapil Sharma strongly reacts to accusations of him insulting Atlee." title="Kapil Sharma strongly reacts to accusations of him insulting Atlee."><figcaption>Kapil Sharma strongly reacts to accusations of him insulting Atlee.</figcaption><p>Kapil Sharma has responded to accusations of insulting filmmaker Atlee during an episode of 'The Great Indian Kapil Show'. He urged viewers to watch the segment and form their own opinions.</p><ul><li>Kapil was criticized for a question related to Atlee's appearance during the show.</li><li>After backlash, Kapil denied the accusations and asked not to spread hate.</li><li>Atlee's response emphasized judging by character rather than appearance.</li><li>The controversy arose from a post on social media that misinterpreted Kapil's intentions.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Dear sir, can you pls explain me where n when I talked about looks in this video? pls don’t spread hate on social media thank you. (guys watch n decide by yourself, don’t follow anybody’s tweet like a sheep).” — Kapil Sharma</p></blockquote><p>This incident highlights the sensitivity around comments made in the entertainment industry and how they can be perceived on social media.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/kapil-sharma-breaks-silence-about-insulting-atlee-watch-and-decide-by-yourself-9159106.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/kapil-sharma-breaks-silence-about-insulting-atlee-watch-and-decide-by-yourself-9159106.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:55:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' box office collection Day 12: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna starrer races to Rs 1,500 crore - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-12-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-records-its-lowest-monday-with-rs-27-75-crore-collection/articleshow/116383147.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-12-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-records-its-lowest-monday-with-rs-27-75-crore-collection/articleshow/116383147.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shatrughan Slams Mukesh Khanna Over Sonakshi-Ramayan Row: 'Who Appointed Him Guardian Of Hindu?' | Viral - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shatrughan Sinha Criticizes Mukesh Khanna for Attacks on Daughter Sonakshi Regarding Ramayan</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Viral</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Mukesh Khanna had criticised Shatrughan Sinha's daughter Sonakshi Sinha." /><figcaption>Mukesh Khanna had criticised Shatrughan Sinha's daughter Sonakshi Sinha.</figcaption><p>In a recent conflict, Shatrughan Sinha vocally opposed Mukesh Khanna's repeated criticisms of his daughter Sonakshi over her memory lapse regarding the Ramayan during a game show.</p><ul><li>Sonakshi Sinha confronted Mukesh Khanna after he remarked on her forgetting a detail about Ramayan on Kaun Banega Crorepati.</li><li>Shatrughan Sinha questioned Mukesh Khanna's authority to judge and labeled him 'guardian of the Hindu religion'.</li><li>Shatrughan emphasized that forgetting a question about the Ramayan does not undermine Sonakshi's identity as a Hindu.</li></ul><blockquote>“Not answering a question on the Ramayan doesn’t disqualify Sonakshi from being a good Hindu.” - Shatrughan Sinha</blockquote><p>Shatrughan Sinha expressed pride in his children, affirming Sonakshi's accomplishments and dismissing the need for validation through religious trivia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/shatrughan-sinha-mukesh-khanna-sonakshi-sinha-ramayan-question-kbc-throwback-9158828.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/shatrughan-sinha-mukesh-khanna-sonakshi-sinha-ramayan-question-kbc-throwback-9158828.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:51:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 1000-crore club: ‘Baahubali’ to ‘Pushpa’, Telugu cinema’s box office juggernaut - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The 1000-crore club: ‘Baahubali’ to ‘Pushpa’, Telugu cinema’s box office juggernaut</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 17, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<div>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/td4sp2/article68995034.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/Baahubali%202.jpg" alt="Anushka Shetty and Prabhas in ‘Baahubali 2: The Conclusion’" width="100%" height="100%">
<figcaption>Anushka Shetty and Prabhas in ‘Baahubali 2: The Conclusion’ | Photo Credit: Special Arrangement</figcaption>
</div>
<p>The Telugu film industry is celebrating its latest achievement with <i>Pushpa 2: The Rule</i> crossing the ₹1,000-crore mark at the box office, becoming the fastest Indian film to do so within a week of release. This marks a significant milestone as it is the fourth Telugu film to reach this milestone.</p>
<ul>
<li><i>Pushpa 2: The Rule</i> breaks box office records, making ₹1,000 crores within days of its release.</li>
<li>It joins the ranks of other blockbusters like <i>Baahubali 2</i>, <i>RRR</i>, and <i>Kalki 2898 AD</i>.</li>
<li>The success highlights the potential of 'pan India cinema,' moving Telugu films into the mainstream.</li>
<li>Smart marketing strategies contributed significantly to the films' success, especially in creating interest among Hindi-speaking audiences.</li>
<li>The article explores historical successes of Telugu cinema, such as earlier hits and the evolution of audience tastes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The term ‘pan India cinema’ came into vogue, and a handful of Telugu, Kannada, Tamil and Malayalam movies eyed similar box office receptions.”</blockquote>
<p>The article concludes by discussing upcoming sequels and the trend of franchises in Telugu cinema, indicating a robust future for the industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/baahubali-to-pushpa-telugu-cinemas-box-office-juggernaut/article68976736.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/baahubali-to-pushpa-telugu-cinemas-box-office-juggernaut/article68976736.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan says she thought her career was over when her smoking photos with Ranbir Kapoor went viral: ' - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan Reflects on Viral Smoking Photos and Their Impact on Her Career</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a recent interview, actress Mahira Khan shared her thoughts on the backlash she faced after photos of her smoking with actor Ranbir Kapoor went viral, affecting both her professional and personal life.</p><ul><li>Mahira felt that her career was at risk due to the negative media coverage.</li><li>She discussed the emotional toll and public scrutiny that ensued following the incident.</li><li>The actress emphasized the importance of mental health in navigating such challenges.</li></ul><blockquote>“It affected my professional and personal life,” Mahira stated, underscoring the heavy burden of public opinion.</blockquote><p>The experience highlighted the intense scrutiny public figures face and the impact such incidents can have on their lives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mahira-khan-says-she-thought-her-career-was-over-when-her-smoking-photos-with-ranbir-kapoor-went-viral-it-affected-my-professional-and-personal-life/articleshow/116399247.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mahira-khan-says-she-thought-her-career-was-over-when-her-smoking-photos-with-ranbir-kapoor-went-viral-it-affected-my-professional-and-personal-life/articleshow/116399247.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonakshi Sinha criticises Mukesh Khanna for 'distasteful' comments against her family - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/sonakshi-sinha-criticises-mukesh-khanna-for-distasteful-comments-against-her-family-3320959</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/sonakshi-sinha-criticises-mukesh-khanna-for-distasteful-comments-against-her-family-3320959</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:41:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today LIVE Updates on December 17, 2024 : Tarot Card Readings: Tarot daily prediction for December 17, 2024 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Horoscope Today LIVE Updates on December 17, 2024: Tarot Card Readings</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/photo-1600430086946-2d9fc61bbefc_1727861205484_1734424960804.jpg" alt="Horoscope Today LIVE Updates: Tarot Card Readings" title="Horoscope Today LIVE Updates: Tarot Card Readings"><figcaption>Horoscope Today LIVE Updates: Tarot Card Readings: Tarot daily prediction for December 17, 2024</figcaption><p>Find out how the stars are aligning for you today! Get your daily horoscope for insights on relationships, career, and more. This is an AI-generated live blog and has not been edited by Hindustan Times staff.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Daily Love Horoscope advises being gentle regarding heart issues.</li><li>Pisces should overcome work challenges through discipline.</li><li>Aquarius is urged to resolve love-related issues and spend more time with partners.</li><li>Capricorn can expect new project launches and enhanced love experiences.</li><li>Sagittarius anticipates better prospects in love today.</li><li>Other signs also receive tailored daily horoscope predictions.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes</h2><blockquote>“A pleasant love life is what waits for you today.”</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>Each zodiac sign has unique astrological guidance today, encouraging positive interactions and personal growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-live-updates-december-17-2024-101734377404649.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-live-updates-december-17-2024-101734377404649.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:27:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kapil Sharma breaks silence on alleged racist comment backlash on Atlee, says, "don’t follow... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/kapil-sharma-breaks-silence-on-alleged-racist-comment-backlash-on-atlee-says-don-t-follow-anybody-s-tweet-like-a-sheep-article-12891919.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/kapil-sharma-breaks-silence-on-alleged-racist-comment-backlash-on-atlee-says-don-t-follow-anybody-s-tweet-like-a-sheep-article-12891919.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:18:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai: Armaan and Abhira head for divorce but here's the twist - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai: Armaan and Abhira Head for Divorce but Here's the Twist</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Tuesday, December 17, 2024 at 9:13 AM | <strong>Source:</strong> Star Plus</p><img src='https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/8326-yeh-rishta-kya-kehlata-hai.jpg' alt='Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai'><figcaption>Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai</figcaption><p>The upcoming episode takes a dramatic turn as Armaan and Abhira decide to file for divorce. However, the court delivers an unexpected twist, granting them six months to reconsider their decision before finalizing the divorce.</p><ul><li>Armaan and Abhira file for divorce amid intense family dynamics.</li><li>The court gives them a six-month period to think over their decision.</li><li>Manish urges Abhira to separate from Armaan, while Swarna advises against pressure.</li><li>Abhira joins K.J. Law College and finds herself in a complex situation with Armaan, who is her professor.</li><li>The couple's unresolved feelings become evident during their interactions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Will this six-month reprieve allow Armaan to mend his relationship with Abhira, or will their differences push them further apart?”</blockquote><p>The upcoming episodes promise an emotional rollercoaster as the characters navigate their complicated relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/yeh-rishta-kya-kehlata-hai-armaan-and-abhira-head-for-divorce-heres-the-twist_215535</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/yeh-rishta-kya-kehlata-hai-armaan-and-abhira-head-for-divorce-heres-the-twist_215535</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:14:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aamir Khan Should Leave it to SS Rajamouli - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aamir Khan Should Leave the Mahabharata Adaptation to SS Rajamouli</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> M9 News</p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/aamir-khan-rajamouli-mahabharat-768x576.jpg" alt="Aamir Khan and SS Rajamouli discussing Mahabharata" /><figcaption>Aamir Khan expresses concerns over adapting Mahabharata</figcaption><p>Aamir Khan has expressed a desire to adapt the culturally significant epic Mahabharata, but has concerns about the potential pitfalls of such a project. He suggests that SS Rajamouli, known for his successes with films like Baahubali, might be better suited for the task.</p><ul><li>Aamir Khan has long wanted to adapt the Mahabharata.</li><li>He fears failing to do justice to its cultural significance.</li><li>SS Rajamouli is considered the ideal director for such a project.</li><li>Khan acknowledges the current political climate adds complexity to the adaptation.</li><li>His existing commitments raise questions about his involvement in the project.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s a huge responsibility because, as Indians, it’s in our blood.” – Aamir Khan</blockquote><p>Aamir Khan should reconsider taking on the Mahabharata adaptation and allow SS Rajamouli to lead, as he is better equipped for the challenging task.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.m9.news/movienews/aamir-khan-should-leave-it-to-ss-rajamouli/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.m9.news/movienews/aamir-khan-should-leave-it-to-ss-rajamouli/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:01:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kapil Sharma reacts to backlash against his alleged ‘racist jibes’ at Atlee on The Great Indian Kapil Show - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kapil Sharma Reacts to Backlash Against His Alleged ‘Racist Jibes’ at Atlee on The Great Indian Kapil Show</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/Kapil_Sharma_1734425642527_1734425642830.jpg" alt="Kapil Sharma took to social media to react to the ongoing buzz around him making a racist comment on filmmaker Atlee." title="Kapil Sharma took to social media to react to the ongoing buzz around him making a racist comment on filmmaker Atlee."><figcaption>Kapil Sharma took to social media to react to the ongoing buzz around him making a racist comment on filmmaker Atlee.</figcaption></figure><p>The controversy began when filmmaker Atlee appeared on The Great Indian Kapil Show to promote his upcoming movie, Baby John. Kapil Sharma faced backlash for joking about Atlee's appearance, prompting him to request viewers to watch the entire episode before forming opinions.</p><ul><li>Atlee participated in the show alongside actors Varun Dhawan, Keerthy Suresh, and Wamiqa Gabbi.</li><li>Kapil asked Atlee a question regarding meeting a star for the first time, which led to criticism for being insensitive.</li><li>Atlee emphasized the importance of judging people by their talent rather than appearance, which many found inappropriate in context.</li><li>Kapil publicly addressed the criticism on social media, urging people not to misinterpret his remarks.</li><li>Responses on social media were mixed, with some fans defending Kapil while others condemned his comment as body shaming and insensitive.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dear sir, can you pls explain me where n when I talked about looks in this video? pls don’t spread hate on social media.” - Kapil Sharma</blockquote><p>The incident generated significant discussion online, raising concerns about humor's boundaries in relation to race and appearance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/web-series/kapil-sharma-reacts-to-backlash-against-his-alleged-racist-jibes-at-atlee-on-the-great-indian-kapil-show-101734425585279.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/web-series/kapil-sharma-reacts-to-backlash-against-his-alleged-racist-jibes-at-atlee-on-the-great-indian-kapil-show-101734425585279.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:01:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bollywood rapper Badshah in legal trouble while attending Karan Aujla's concert in Gurugram; here's what happened | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxQemhZNkNEeklpOXBMZjl5ZU1LamJjc2RqZXBFQmhIRkhZUlFVOWhWZmtRSkQ3bVFadTFQUW1EQkZaUnZHTHNCRzFqQWVBRjJWMnB4OEpMSTAyb2ptdUxsMEpNRFZaVE9VTXRQWmtuXzhvWk5lTGlWXzNtZEZ1X2FKM1QyTFFZSldkQk1lY0E3Q2UxTURvYzYzeXU4am9mcFYzaGZ1MzVYVWdRX1pMVGVhdDVnM0FvUklQNFdrc2xDYlJGSm5LUTdzR1lGN3Q3YzNvUGRwbVRlbFMtRFF4TjZMN21ZWVJXUi1GUUhlOEJKLVpGQdIB9wFBVV95cUxPQ3ROcm41anhzS3hnSXJ5NkFYTEN2UnJYd1pRTWNCLTYxMm1OTU9wdGxOdTVHRi1ETWlfaUVGU28xeGJiSUVGUU5TZzFoNWRjcUJ0bjk2TXBRSDVwa2NXenBHQ29LME15UTdJZUxOWDZLX1ZONjJaWnEtZmtOandZNUJ3RFJNV24yd0xVU1BYSFRqNlc4ZUxhYzVIYXRjNkFGdGpWanN3MlFKaWFhcmFUWmZLYzZhNHRhWmZXVktvdFhUa3NlQ2VKSXdwM3ZoSUlkSG5udzJJMnBlTU1iN2czSkdFVnl5M0V0bDJxTW9DUW1pSmhjUTdr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxQemhZNkNEeklpOXBMZjl5ZU1LamJjc2RqZXBFQmhIRkhZUlFVOWhWZmtRSkQ3bVFadTFQUW1EQkZaUnZHTHNCRzFqQWVBRjJWMnB4OEpMSTAyb2ptdUxsMEpNRFZaVE9VTXRQWmtuXzhvWk5lTGlWXzNtZEZ1X2FKM1QyTFFZSldkQk1lY0E3Q2UxTURvYzYzeXU4am9mcFYzaGZ1MzVYVWdRX1pMVGVhdDVnM0FvUklQNFdrc2xDYlJGSm5LUTdzR1lGN3Q3YzNvUGRwbVRlbFMtRFF4TjZMN21ZWVJXUi1GUUhlOEJKLVpGQdIB9wFBVV95cUxPQ3ROcm41anhzS3hnSXJ5NkFYTEN2UnJYd1pRTWNCLTYxMm1OTU9wdGxOdTVHRi1ETWlfaUVGU28xeGJiSUVGUU5TZzFoNWRjcUJ0bjk2TXBRSDVwa2NXenBHQ29LME15UTdJZUxOWDZLX1ZONjJaWnEtZmtOandZNUJ3RFJNV24yd0xVU1BYSFRqNlc4ZUxhYzVIYXRjNkFGdGpWanN3MlFKaWFhcmFUWmZLYzZhNHRhWmZXVktvdFhUa3NlQ2VKSXdwM3ZoSUlkSG5udzJJMnBlTU1iN2czSkdFVnl5M0V0bDJxTW9DUW1pSmhjUTdr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:17:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Netizens question makers for Digvijay Singh Rathee’s limited screen time in the show - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Netizens Express Concerns Over Limited Screen Time of Digvijay Singh Rathee in Bigg Boss 18</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023-10-17<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/67fbe00e919405d21e0f61297b13f530.png' alt='Bigg Boss 18' /><figcaption>Image related to Bigg Boss 18</figcaption><p>The ongoing season of Bigg Boss 18 has sparked discussions among viewers regarding the limited screen time of contestant Digvijay Singh Rathee. Fans are questioning the show's producers about this notable absence during critical episodes.</p><ul><li>Viewers express frustrations on social media about Rathee's minimal appearances.</li><li>The contestant's strategic gameplay and fan base have earned him significant attention.</li><li>Netizens call for more equitable screen time for all contestants to enhance viewer experience.</li></ul><blockquote>“We want to see more of Digvijay. Why is he not featured as much?”</blockquote><p>Fans are hopeful that producers will address their concerns and offer more balanced airtime in upcoming episodes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-netizens-question-makers-for-digvijay-singh-rathees-limited-screen-time-in-the-show/articleshow/116394033.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-netizens-question-makers-for-digvijay-singh-rathees-limited-screen-time-in-the-show/articleshow/116394033.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 box office report: Allu Arjun's action drama beats RRR, KGF 2 to become 3rd highest-grossing Indian film - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 box office report: Allu Arjun's action drama beats RRR, KGF 2 to become 3rd highest-grossing Indian film</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/PUSHPAAA_1734422234254_1734422242150.webp" alt="Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2 becomes the third highest-grossing Indian film." title="Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2 becomes the third highest-grossing Indian film." />
<figcaption>Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2 becomes the third highest-grossing Indian film.</figcaption>
<p>The action drama, Pushpa 2 The Rule, has achieved significant success at the box office, surpassing RRR and KGF 2 to secure its place as the third highest-grossing Indian film in just 12 days of release.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Pushpa 2 has grossed ₹930 crore at the Indian box office.</li>
    <li>The film is aiming to beat Baahubali 2's collection of ₹1790 crore.</li>
    <li>On its 13th day, it collected ₹3.66 crore, with projections of reaching ₹1000 crore soon.</li>
    <li>It surpassed ₹500 crores in its Hindi version, becoming the fastest film to hit this mark.</li>
    <li>Despite a recent incident involving Allu Arjun's arrest, the film's collections increased by 70% following the event.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Pushpa 2 is now eyeing to surpass Baahubali 2 and Dangal to potentially become the second highest-grossing Indian film ever."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Pushpa 2's unprecedented box office success reflects its widespread appeal and the strength of its star power, indicating a promising future as it aims for higher milestones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-box-office-report-allu-arjuns-action-drama-beats-rrr-kgf-2-to-become-3rd-highest-grossing-indian-film-101734419375411.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-box-office-report-allu-arjuns-action-drama-beats-rrr-kgf-2-to-become-3rd-highest-grossing-indian-film-101734419375411.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:04:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I paid to pee in my pants at Bryan Adams Mumbai concert: Diabetic man lambasts Zomato CEO - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxQNlloaHhmY2tvNFFPa0VUbTBzbHRqVjJRRE9vYmN3QUJRTkNsZElYTG1ZVV96UGVUMEVJaGFyejdxS0tqR2JSMG5wMFAyeXRBeV84VktlV1hsblZmLXBrTWVLdUZ1Ymg4bm5LMHdfbzlHTVdxelhMZkFOQmdVX2Z6cjR0WWFXbU5icGpDVDZSY3JXczdPOGVIQmFpYUZpbnZfWUNsZENQckNyT1RVSlZQcUlURzVxNGJyNHl2bGxOM3BvSUYyeDV5cGdLM1pKZ0hma0dB0gHXAUFVX3lxTFB0Z01VWG5ZMl9KOU1DSGo5OWNqdzhhREUtNUpFRGZjNHlxSEhpQlhyakNpSncyTFhOeElCNGhielQzSnQ3dzh1dlY5M3ZjWV8wWFBiaXBQdV9aS2NVUXNMSTBfZkdhZGNrYXh1S0RlVzA2RlgtdUZkRUd2M1lUSjQybG9YUWRGN0ptaXZ0cmR0YlcxMU5pMldOUmFWeFVMNHBvTE1TZk5EdnNYaXp5d1ctTnZ4ODQzTm5qTGdkZlM1QjdrZGxWWUNQMlVzZEJnRmpkNWgwTVdv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxQNlloaHhmY2tvNFFPa0VUbTBzbHRqVjJRRE9vYmN3QUJRTkNsZElYTG1ZVV96UGVUMEVJaGFyejdxS0tqR2JSMG5wMFAyeXRBeV84VktlV1hsblZmLXBrTWVLdUZ1Ymg4bm5LMHdfbzlHTVdxelhMZkFOQmdVX2Z6cjR0WWFXbU5icGpDVDZSY3JXczdPOGVIQmFpYUZpbnZfWUNsZENQckNyT1RVSlZQcUlURzVxNGJyNHl2bGxOM3BvSUYyeDV5cGdLM1pKZ0hma0dB0gHXAUFVX3lxTFB0Z01VWG5ZMl9KOU1DSGo5OWNqdzhhREUtNUpFRGZjNHlxSEhpQlhyakNpSncyTFhOeElCNGhielQzSnQ3dzh1dlY5M3ZjWV8wWFBiaXBQdV9aS2NVUXNMSTBfZkdhZGNrYXh1S0RlVzA2RlgtdUZkRUd2M1lUSjQybG9YUWRGN0ptaXZ0cmR0YlcxMU5pMldOUmFWeFVMNHBvTE1TZk5EdnNYaXp5d1ctTnZ4ODQzTm5qTGdkZlM1QjdrZGxWWUNQMlVzZEJnRmpkNWgwTVdv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:37:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kangana Ranaut talks about Kapoor family meeting PM Narendra Modi, says, "They will go and dance at... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/kangana-ranaut-talks-about-kapoor-family-meeting-pm-narendra-modi-says-they-will-go-and-dance-at-gangsters-parties-in-dubai-this-is-a-very-good-step-article-12891714.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/kangana-ranaut-talks-about-kapoor-family-meeting-pm-narendra-modi-says-they-will-go-and-dance-at-gangsters-parties-in-dubai-this-is-a-very-good-step-article-12891714.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:22:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Highest Grossing Indian Films Worldwide: Allu Arjun starrer Pushpa 2 overtakes RRR for Third - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Surpasses RRR as the Third Highest-Grossing Indian Film Worldwide</h1><p><strong>Updated on:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p><p><img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/1113899056_pushpa-5.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2" title="Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"></p><figcaption>Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)</figcaption></p><p>Pushpa 2 has claimed the title of the third highest-grossing Indian film worldwide, surpassing RRR with a total gross of approximately Rs. 1259 crore.</p><ul><li>Pushpa 2 generated Rs. 33 crore approximately on its 2nd Monday, bringing its worldwide box office total to Rs. 1259 crore.</li><li>The film's domestic gross is Rs. 1039.50 crore, while the overseas total is Rs. 219.50 crore.</li><li>Pushpa 2 is now the second highest-grossing film in India, yet remains outside the top fifteen in overseas grosses.</li><li>Despite its success, it is predicted that Pushpa 2 is unlikely to surpass the Rs. 1744 crore gross of Baahubali 2.</li><li>The current highest-grossing Indian films are: Dangal (1910.00 cr.), Baahubali: The Conclusion (1744.00 cr.), and Pushpa: The Rule (1259.00 cr.).</li></ul><blockquote>“Pushpa 2 is favourite to become the highest-grossing film in India, beating Baahubali 2.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Pushpa 2’s record-setting performance reflects the film's strong appeal and the competitive landscape of Indian cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/top-highest-grossing-indian-films-worldwide-allu-arjun-starrer-pushpa-2-overtakes-rrr-for-third-1363095</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/top-highest-grossing-indian-films-worldwide-allu-arjun-starrer-pushpa-2-overtakes-rrr-for-third-1363095</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:19:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why SC restrained TM Krishna from claiming award named after MS Subbulakshmi. 'Added fuel to fire' - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Prevents T.M. Krishna from Claiming M.S. Subbulakshmi Award</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date Not Specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Print</p><p>Well-known Carnatic musician T.M. Krishna has been restrained by the Supreme Court from claiming the Sangita Kalanidhi M.S. Subbulakshmi Award, awarded by the Madras Music Academy, following an appeal by Subbulakshmi’s grandson.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court issued a notice regarding the award conferred upon Krishna.</li><li>Subbulakshmi’s grandson, V. Shrinivasan, challenged the Madras High Court's decision that allowed the award to be given.</li><li>The Supreme Court indicated that Krishna's comments about Subbulakshmi were disrespectful and necessary to address.</li><li>Krishna faces accusations of making derogatory remarks about Subbulakshmi in his writings.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a sensitive and important issue.” - Supreme Court Bench</blockquote><p>The controversy highlights a broader conflict regarding the recognition and memory of M.S. Subbulakshmi in the field of Carnatic music.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/judiciary/why-sc-restrained-tm-krishna-from-claiming-award-named-after-ms-subbulakshmi-added-fuel-to-fire/2406112/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/judiciary/why-sc-restrained-tm-krishna-from-claiming-award-named-after-ms-subbulakshmi-added-fuel-to-fire/2406112/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:17:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan thought her ‘career is over’ after photos with Ranbir Kapoor went viral, she was banned: ‘I was crying daily’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan Reflects on Career Challenges After Viral Photos with Ranbir Kapoor</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/mahira.jpg?w=640" alt="Mahira Khan Ranbir Kapoor" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Mahira Khan spoke about viral photos with Ranbir Kapoor and how it affected her mental health.</figcaption><p>Mahira Khan has opened up about the emotional toll that viral photos of her with Bollywood actor Ranbir Kapoor took on her career and mental health, describing a time when she feared her career was over.</p><ul><li>Mahira discussed the complexities of being a single mother and her ban from performing in India.</li><li>She shared how the viral smoking photos affected her mental health, leaving her extremely distressed.</li><li>Despite the challenges, Mahira focused on making personal choices for her and her child.</li><li>In 2017, the leaked photos of them sparked widespread speculation.</li></ul><blockquote>“When the photos came out there was an article called ‘The Little White Dress’ that was published in BBC ... I was crying daily, it affected my professional and personal life.”</blockquote><p>Mahira's resilience shone through as she chose to prioritize her personal well-being during a critical time in her life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/mahira-khan-thought-career-is-over-after-viral-photos-ranbir-kapoor-ban-cried-daily-9729286/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/mahira-khan-thought-career-is-over-after-viral-photos-ranbir-kapoor-ban-cried-daily-9729286/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 06:50:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>