<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:27:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:27:40 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fateh movie review: Sonu Sood goes into ‘Animal’ mode in this high-octane actioner - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fateh movie review: Sonu Sood tries his best to bring international action to desi screens.</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Fateh-review_1736504255240_1736504255673.webp" alt="Fateh review: Sonu Sood channels John Wick in this thriller." title="Fateh review: Sonu Sood channels John Wick in this thriller.">
<figcaption>Fateh review: Sonu Sood channels John Wick in this thriller.</figcaption>
<p>Sonu Sood’s directorial debut offers a high-octane blend of action and a narrative focused on cyber crime. While it showcases impressive action sequences, the film struggles with its screenplay and depth of storytelling.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sonu Sood plays Fateh Singh, a former secret agent turned contract killer.</li>
<li>The plot centers around fake loan apps and a missing girl entangled in a global scam.</li>
<li>The film features excessive violence that overshadows the intended theme of cyber crime.</li>
<li>Jacqueliene Fernandez portrays an ethical hacker but has a limited role.</li>
<li>The action sequences aim for international standards but lack substantive storytelling.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The slick action stops evoking shock after a point, and the digital scam gets amateur treatment.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while Fateh attempts to bring a captivating visual experience, it ultimately falls short in delivering a meaningful narrative.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/fateh-movie-review-sonu-sood-goes-into-animal-mode-in-this-high-octane-actioner-101736502729215.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/fateh-movie-review-sonu-sood-goes-into-animal-mode-in-this-high-octane-actioner-101736502729215.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:39:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fateh Review: Sonu Sood's Bloody Attempt At Direction Is Explosive And Impressive - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fateh Review: Sonu Sood's Bloody Attempt At Direction Is Explosive And Impressive</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 10, 2025, 21:35 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='Fateh Review: Sonu Sood impresses in directorial debut.'/><figcaption>Fateh Review: Sonu Sood impresses in directorial debut.</figcaption><p>Fateh follows the story of a former agent turned dairy farm supervisor, who works to rescue a girl caught in an online loan scam, unearthing a cybercrime ring in the process.</p><ul><li>The film marks Sonu Sood's directorial debut.</li><li>It features prominent actors such as Jacqueline Fernandez and Naseeruddin Shah.</li><li>The action sequences are intense, highlighting Sood's performance skills.</li><li>Critics noted a lack of depth in character development and writing.</li><li>While the film is visually appealing, it suffers from narrative inconsistencies.</li></ul><blockquote>Despite its flaws, the film is a decent watch for action genre fans.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while Fateh has its explosive moments, it also calls for better writing and emotional engagement from its cast.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/fateh-review-sonu-sood-bloody-attempt-at-direction-is-explosive-and-impressive-9184247.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/fateh-review-sonu-sood-bloody-attempt-at-direction-is-explosive-and-impressive-9184247.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:24:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fateh movie review: Sonu Sood is on a mission to slash, kill and burn - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fateh Movie Review: Sonu Sood is on a mission to slash, kill and burn</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Fateh-Review.jpg?w=640" alt="Fateh Review" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Fateh Review: Fateh walks into a crowded room and goes on a killing spree, employing all manner of sleight-of-hand skills. (Photo: Zee Studios/YouTube)</figcaption><p>Sonu Sood's directorial debut, Fateh, tackles the theme of cybercrime as the actor plays the lead role of an ex-spy on a violent mission.</p><ul><li>The film runs for 127 minutes and opens with a heavily choreographed action sequence.</li><li>The plot features Sood's Fateh traveling between locations, engaging in violent confrontations.</li><li>Supporting cast includes Naseeruddin Shah, Jacqueline Fernandes, and Vijay Raaz.</li><li>The film contains numerous villains and elaborate action scenes but suffers from an increasingly convoluted plot.</li></ul><blockquote>“Your tipping point depends upon how much sickening, relentless violence you can handle.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while Sonu Sood brings his acting chops, the film's excessive violence may leave viewers fatigued rather than entertained.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/movie-review/fateh-movie-review-sonu-sood-is-on-a-mission-to-slash-kill-and-burn-9771491/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/movie-review/fateh-movie-review-sonu-sood-is-on-a-mission-to-slash-kill-and-burn-9771491/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:07:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Annapurna Studios embrace new technology – Deets inside - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Annapurna Studios embrace new technology – Deets inside</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Jan 10, 2025 3:00 pm IST</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/annapurna-studios.jpg" alt="Annapurna Studios" width="360" height="450">
<figcaption>Annapurna Studios celebrates 50 years with a new Dolby Vision facility.</figcaption>
<p>Annapurna Studios, a renowned Tollywood production house, is celebrating its 50 glorious years by unveiling India’s first Dolby Vision Grading & Mastering Facility for Dolby Cinema and Home, inaugurated by acclaimed filmmaker SS Rajamouli.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Annapurna Studios celebrates its 50th anniversary.</li>
  <li>India's first Dolby Vision facility was inaugurated.</li>
  <li>SS Rajamouli, a leading filmmaker, marked the event.</li>
  <li>This marks a new partnership with Dolby for cinematic technology.</li>
  <li>Annapurna continues to pioneer film infrastructure excellence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Known for pioneering world-class infrastructure for films, Annapurna Studios continues its legacy of excellence with this remarkable addition in its golden jubilee year.</blockquote>
<p>This new venture by Annapurna Studios illustrates its commitment to advancing cinematic technology and enhancing viewer experience in Indian cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/annapurna-studios-embrace-new-technology-deets-inside.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/annapurna-studios-embrace-new-technology-deets-inside.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Woman sings 'Aaj Ki Raat' while playing harmonium, son adorably dances in background | Watch - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Woman sings 'Aaj Ki Raat' while playing harmonium, son adorably dances in background | Watch</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/mother-and-son-1736499606.webp" alt="Woman sings 'Aaj Ki Raat' while playing harmonium" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>A woman sings 'Aaj Ki Raat' while playing the harmonium.</figcaption>
<p>A delightful new video is making rounds on social media, featuring a woman singing 'Aaj Ki Raat' while playing the harmonium, accompanied by her son dancing adorably in the background.</p>
<ul>
  <li>A woman performs a melodious rendition of 'Aaj Ki Raat'.</li>
  <li>Her young son is seen dancing to the song, adding to the cuteness factor.</li>
  <li>The video has garnered over 192,000 views on the X platform, originating from @Prof_Cheems.</li>
  <li>Several users commented on the video, expressing admiration for both the singing and dancing.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Very cute child.”</blockquote>
<blockquote>“Very good performance, friend, very calibrated voice.”</blockquote>
<p>This charming video exemplifies the joy shared between the mother and son, resonating with audiences and driving conversations online.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/trending/news/woman-sings-tamannaah-bhatia-s-chartbuster-aaj-ki-raat-while-playing-harmonium-son-dances-in-background-watch-2025-01-10-970599</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/trending/news/woman-sings-tamannaah-bhatia-s-chartbuster-aaj-ki-raat-while-playing-harmonium-son-dances-in-background-watch-2025-01-10-970599</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:06:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hrithik Roshan turns 51: Sussanne Khan says his best is yet to come, Ameesha Patel wishes him ‘Gadar of a year’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hrithik Roshan Turns 51: Sussanne Khan Says His Best Is Yet to Come, Ameesha Patel Wishes Him ‘Gadar of a Year’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/hrithik_4_1736495824691_1736495839186.jpg" alt="Hrithik Roshan turns 51 today." title="Hrithik Roshan turns 51 today."><figcaption>Hrithik Roshan turns 51 today.</figcaption></figure><p>As Hrithik Roshan celebrates his 51st birthday today, his debut film Kaho Naa Pyaar Hai has been re-released in cinemas to mark the occasion. Celebrities from across the industry took to social media to share their wishes.</p><ul><li>Sussanne Khan celebrated by sharing a group picture and expressed her belief that Hrithik's best is yet to come.</li><li>Ameesha Patel wished Hrithik a double celebration for his birthday and the 25th anniversary of their film Kaho Naa Pyaar Hai.</li><li>Rakesh Roshan, Hrithik's father, shared childhood pictures and expressed his love.</li><li>Anil Kapoor reminisced about Hrithik's journey from intern to star, celebrating 25 years of his stardom.</li><li>Hrithik will next be seen in a docuseries about his family's history and in War 2.</li></ul><blockquote>“Keep shining!” - Anil Kapoor</blockquote><p>As Hrithik reaches this milestone, fans and friends alike are excited for what lies ahead in his career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/hrithik-roshan-51st-birthday-sussanne-khan-says-his-best-is-yet-to-come-ameesha-patel-wishes-him-gadar-of-a-year-101736495505767.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/hrithik-roshan-51st-birthday-sussanne-khan-says-his-best-is-yet-to-come-ameesha-patel-wishes-him-gadar-of-a-year-101736495505767.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:04:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer movie review Live Updates: Reviews call Ram Charan film ‘a Pongal, Sakranti gift’; will it meet the box office expectations? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Movie Review: Ram Charan's Anticipated Release for Pongal</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/game-changer-release-1600.jpg?w=750" alt="Game Changer Movie Release Live Updates" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Game Changer Movie Release Live Updates: Game Changer is Ram Charan's first Sankranti release since Vinaya VIdheya Rama.</figcaption>
<p>Game Changer marks Ram Charan's return as a solo hero in a film directed by Shankar, promising a commercial potboiler for audiences. The film is anticipated to perform well at the box office during the Sankranti festival.</p>
<ul>
<li>Ram Charan stars alongside Kiara Advani in this high-stakes action film.</li>
<li>Shankar's first direct Telugu film is generating considerable buzz due to its engaging trailer.</li>
<li>The story follows the themes of power, corruption, and the classic good vs evil narrative.</li>
<li>The film aims to set a commercial benchmark for Telugu cinema in 2025.</li>
<li>Game Changer also features notable actors like SJ Suryah, Anjali, and Jayaram.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“He is hoping to make a lasting impression in a commercial potboiler, helmed by the OG of this genre, Shankar.”</blockquote>
<p>The film has the potential to kickstart the year with impressive box office numbers, drawing significant interest from Ram Charan's fanbase and the Telugu film audience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-movie-review-rating-release-box-office-collection-live-updates-ram-charan-kiara-advan-9770253/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-movie-review-rating-release-box-office-collection-live-updates-ram-charan-kiara-advan-9770253/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What A Disaster! Game Changer Gets Leaked - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Movie Leaked on Release Day</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today | <strong>Source:</strong> M9 News</p>
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/game-changer-gets-leaked-768x576.jpg" alt="Game Changer Movie Poster" width="768" height="576">
<figcaption>Game Changer movie poster</figcaption>
<p>Ram Charan's latest film, Game Changer, has experienced a significant setback on its release day as it has fallen victim to internet piracy.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Ram Charan returns to the big screen as a solo hero in Game Changer.</li>
  <li>The film released today but has already been leaked online.</li>
  <li>An HD print of the movie is being circulated on various social media platforms.</li>
  <li>The anti-piracy team is working to take down pirated links.</li>
  <li>This piracy incident poses a serious threat to the film's box office performance.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>This really is a disaster of epic proportion as the film has fallen prey to the piracy issue on the most important day.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, immediate action is required to combat piracy and protect the film's potential success at the box office.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.m9.news/movienews/what-a-disaster-game-changer-gets-leaked/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.m9.news/movienews/what-a-disaster-game-changer-gets-leaked/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:38:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rashmika Mandanna Injured, Sikandar & other shoots Halted? Read — - Movie Talkies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxOR1dfZGloY0pZLXF2NGRsNkp4NDhtbFppXzY2eERnWjE1YlpST3BtNHE4UWY4V1lSNkZlT0F0Y1pQMThzaXp4LXFyZ2QyT0g4dTB0MnRpb0tWU3pIODhubjY4QzVFVmFuS3lLYk1QNFRXc0VLeGVqS3M3NGpRSkllVU9XSjVOaTdZOG5aN0pYR0cxMHPSAZMBQVVfeXFMTkdXX2RpaGNKWS1xdjRkbDZKeDQ4bWxaaV82NnhEZ1oxNWJaUk9wbTRxOFFmOFdZUjZGZU9BdGNaUDE4c2l6eC1xcmdkMk9IOHUwdDJ0aW9LVlN6SDg4bm42OEM1RVZhbkt5S2JNUDRUV3NFS3hlaktzNzRqUUpJZVVPV0o1Tmk3WThuWjdKWEdHMTBz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxOR1dfZGloY0pZLXF2NGRsNkp4NDhtbFppXzY2eERnWjE1YlpST3BtNHE4UWY4V1lSNkZlT0F0Y1pQMThzaXp4LXFyZ2QyT0g4dTB0MnRpb0tWU3pIODhubjY4QzVFVmFuS3lLYk1QNFRXc0VLeGVqS3M3NGpRSkllVU9XSjVOaTdZOG5aN0pYR0cxMHPSAZMBQVVfeXFMTkdXX2RpaGNKWS1xdjRkbDZKeDQ4bWxaaV82NnhEZ1oxNWJaUk9wbTRxOFFmOFdZUjZGZU9BdGNaUDE4c2l6eC1xcmdkMk9IOHUwdDJ0aW9LVlN6SDg4bm42OEM1RVZhbkt5S2JNUDRUV3NFS3hlaktzNzRqUUpJZVVPV0o1Tmk3WThuWjdKWEdHMTBz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:35:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun to star along side Alia Bhatt, Ranbir Kapoor, Vicky Kaushal in Sanjay Leela Bhansali's Love and War? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun to Star Alongside Alia Bhatt, Ranbir Kapoor, Vicky Kaushal in Sanjay Leela Bhansali's Love and War?</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Allu_Arjun_to_hold_a_cameo_in_SLBs_Love_and_War_1736491866718_1736491867084.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun to make a cameo in Sanjay Leela Bhansali's Love and War? (Photos: Instagram/alluarjunonline, X)"> <figcaption>Allu Arjun to make a cameo in Sanjay Leela Bhansali's Love and War? (Photos: Instagram/alluarjunonline, X)</figcaption> <p>Allu Arjun's recent visit to Sanjay Leela Bhansali's office has sparked speculation about a potential collaboration amidst his ongoing controversy. </p> <ul> <li>Allu Arjun may have a role in Bhansali's upcoming film, <i>Love and War</i>, but details are unclear.</li> <li>The film is slated for a 2026 release and stars Alia Bhatt, Ranbir Kapoor, and Vicky Kaushal.</li> <li>There is speculation that Arjun could take on a cameo role, which he generally does not entertain.</li> <li>Fans are debating the nature of his meeting with Bhansali and what it might entail.</li> <li>The actor is dealing with a personal crisis due to a tragic incident at a theater.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“Love and war mein cameo kar wa raha hai kya. Though Allu cameo karta nahin generally.”</blockquote> <p>The situation remains uncertain, leaving fans eagerly awaiting news on further collaborations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/allu-arjun-alia-bhatt-ranbir-kapoor-vicky-kaushal-in-sanjay-leela-bhansalis-love-and-war-amid-pushpa-2-controversy-101736491214835.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/allu-arjun-alia-bhatt-ranbir-kapoor-vicky-kaushal-in-sanjay-leela-bhansalis-love-and-war-amid-pushpa-2-controversy-101736491214835.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:22:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['He is not a friendly...': Months after separation from wife Saira Banu, Sonu Nigam makes SHOCKING claims abo - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘He is not a friendly…’: Months after separation from wife Saira Banu, Sonu Nigam makes SHOCKING claims about AR Rahman</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><figure><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2025-01-10T124847.710.png?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="'He is not a friendly...': Months after separation from wife Saira Banu, Sonu Nigam makes SHOCKING claims about AR Rahman"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Months after the separation from his wife Saira Banu, Sonu Nigam discussed his experiences working with renowned composer AR Rahman, describing him as a strict professional who struggles to open up.</p><ul><li>Nigam emphasized that Rahman does not engage in relationships and is focused solely on work.</li><li>He mentioned that Rahman remains detached from social gossip.</li><li>Nigam remarked that Rahman seems to maintain a unique personality.</li></ul><blockquote>“He doesn’t have relationships. He is not the kind of person who has relationships. He doesn’t open up to anyone.” - Sonu Nigam</blockquote><p>The comments follow Rahman's public separation from Saira Banu after 29 years of marriage, which surprised many fans and observers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/entertainment/he-is-not-a-friendly-months-after-separation-from-wife-saira-banu-sonu-nigam-makes-shocking-claims-about-ar-rahman-7528265/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/entertainment/he-is-not-a-friendly-months-after-separation-from-wife-saira-banu-sonu-nigam-makes-shocking-claims-about-ar-rahman-7528265/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ram Charan's Game Changer: Why Naanaa Hyraanaa Song Isn't Included & When It Will Get Added To The Runtime - Filmibeat]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ram Charan's Game Changer: Why Naanaa Hyraanaa Song Isn't Included & When It Will Get Added To The Runtime</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Filmibeat</p>
<img src="https://images.filmibeat.com/img/2025/01/newproject-2025-01-10t122942-716-1736492768.jpg" alt="Game Changer When Will Naanaa Hyraanaa Song Get Included" width="600" height="338">
<figcaption>Game Changer: When Will Naanaa Hyraanaa Song Get Included</figcaption>
<p>Ram Charan, Kiara Advani, and Shankar's film Game Changer debuted worldwide on January 10. The film has received mixed reviews and has been released in three languages featuring Ram Charan in a dual role.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film released as the first major Tollywood release for the Sankranthi festival.</li>
  <li>Ram Charan plays Ram Nandan IAS, facing political challenges in Visakhapatnam.</li>
  <li>The bustling and technically advanced song Naanaa Hyraanaa is not included in the initial release due to processing issues.</li>
  <li>The song will be added to the runtime starting January 14.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The song was shot using about Rs 27 Crore and is the first Indian song filmed with an infrared camera.”</blockquote>
<p>Despite initial setbacks, Game Changer has set the stage for an exciting inclusion with its unique song Naanaa Hyraanaa, promising to enhance the cinematic experience moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.filmibeat.com/telugu/news/2025/ram-charans-game-changer-why-naanaa-hyraanaa-song-isnt-included-when-it-will-get-added-to-the-437547.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.filmibeat.com/telugu/news/2025/ram-charans-game-changer-why-naanaa-hyraanaa-song-isnt-included-when-it-will-get-added-to-the-437547.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:10:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rich kids who ‘own’ Europe and Bali denied entry in Mukesh Ambani’s house - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rich Kids Denied Entry at Mukesh Ambani's Residence in Mumbai</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117109535,imgsize-29568,width-400,resizemode-4/117109535.jpg" alt="Rich kids who ‘own’ Europe and Bali denied entry in Mukesh Ambani’s house"><figcaption>Rich kids who ‘own’ Europe and Bali denied entry in Mukesh Ambani’s house</figcaption><p>This article describes a humorous incident where two content creators attempted to gain entry into Mukesh Ambani's luxurious residence, Antilia, by claiming to be friends with him. Their interactions with the security guard gained extensive attention on social media.</p><ul><li>Influencers Ben Sumadiwiria and Aris Yeager tried to enter Antilia to play PlayStation.</li><li>They claimed to have been invited by the Ambanis after meeting them at a wedding.</li><li>The security guard humorously rebuffed their attempts, stating, "It’s a house, it’s not a restaurant." </li><li>The prank video received over 30 million views on Instagram.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ambani’s security guard roasts a rich kid of Europe.” - Instagram user comment</blockquote><p>The attempted prank illustrates not only the allure of wealth and exclusivity but also how access to such places remains highly restricted, regardless of social status.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/rich-kids-who-own-europe-and-bali-denied-entry-in-mukesh-ambanis-house/articleshow/117109423.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/rich-kids-who-own-europe-and-bali-denied-entry-in-mukesh-ambanis-house/articleshow/117109423.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kangana Ranaut Wants To Work With Karan Johar 'Sir', Offers Him A Movie: 'I Am Sorry...' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kangana Ranaut Wants To Work With Karan Johar 'Sir', Offers Him A Movie: 'I Am Sorry...'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Kangana Ranaut has often referred to Karan Johar as a 'Bollywood mafia'." title="Kangana Ranaut has often referred to Karan Johar as a 'Bollywood mafia'."><figcaption>Kangana Ranaut has often referred to Karan Johar as a 'Bollywood mafia'. (Photos: Instagram)</figcaption></figure><p>In a surprising turn of events, Kangana Ranaut, known for her harsh criticism of Karan Johar, has expressed her desire to work with him. During an appearance on 'Indian Idol', she referred to him as 'sir' and made an official offer.</p><ul><li>Kangana expressed regret for past tensions and invited Karan to collaborate on a meaningful film.</li><li>She emphasized the desire to offer him a substantial role, distancing from typical Bollywood tropes.</li><li>Historically, Kangana has been vocal against Karan, calling him a 'movie mafia' and criticizing his contribution to Indian cinema.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’m sorry to say, but Karan sir should do a movie with me. I’ll give him a very good role...”</blockquote><p>This unexpected olive branch from Kangana raises questions about future collaborations in Bollywood, reflecting the constantly evolving dynamics within the industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/kangana-ranaut-wants-to-work-with-karan-johar-sir-offers-him-a-movie-i-am-sorry-9183949.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/kangana-ranaut-wants-to-work-with-karan-johar-sir-offers-him-a-movie-i-am-sorry-9183949.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:47:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TMKOC Actor Gurucharan Singh Is Critical, Has Not Eaten Food For 19 Days Now - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQX2draDkwc0xKZWJ6YWJOd1NqWDkxalk2TDN6bmJoeHY3XzYwWElmS01nWWYtM3JueE84S21kYkY4TTJER1pKanZHSDM1ai0zSlNiWXpQdDB4X2k2OTFCT1NVeWg0SllDcDVXY19JaWc5dVlfVzVLOHoyYzctbElkYlBnNFlGWWZRZ2ZlLXRkeVZMdWNtWl85Sy1rY1VPX2R5c0VFOFh1dHJpWWRxdHRtMzFWaW5ZTlh0OEIwbG930gHDAUFVX3lxTE55VjRKSWJhS2pabG9rT3ZNX0EzQkZzQXE3NC1CdFJESmw0aXNvRGhhb3RVU3FQNEFHNGJLaXY5bmF4Qm11ZlNCQVFuV2lvWlRPSzlYQ3BkaThDV2EzcFp0NjNmdEVrZ0RONUE2ZS0xaURFWnM3clllWlFfVEVEQUMtcTZSdm1XMlcydlp2aElQNS1WU2diY1J4Z2lKNnVrcXhTN2xsVVA2MTlhWXNRZHA4azNLalV5MXFCZzFHSVFETHc0dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQX2draDkwc0xKZWJ6YWJOd1NqWDkxalk2TDN6bmJoeHY3XzYwWElmS01nWWYtM3JueE84S21kYkY4TTJER1pKanZHSDM1ai0zSlNiWXpQdDB4X2k2OTFCT1NVeWg0SllDcDVXY19JaWc5dVlfVzVLOHoyYzctbElkYlBnNFlGWWZRZ2ZlLXRkeVZMdWNtWl85Sy1rY1VPX2R5c0VFOFh1dHJpWWRxdHRtMzFWaW5ZTlh0OEIwbG930gHDAUFVX3lxTE55VjRKSWJhS2pabG9rT3ZNX0EzQkZzQXE3NC1CdFJESmw0aXNvRGhhb3RVU3FQNEFHNGJLaXY5bmF4Qm11ZlNCQVFuV2lvWlRPSzlYQ3BkaThDV2EzcFp0NjNmdEVrZ0RONUE2ZS0xaURFWnM3clllWlFfVEVEQUMtcTZSdm1XMlcydlp2aElQNS1WU2diY1J4Z2lKNnVrcXhTN2xsVVA2MTlhWXNRZHA4azNLalV5MXFCZzFHSVFETHc0dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:47:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Years of Christmas Blues: Has Bollywoods Christmas Blockbuster Era come to an end? - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/7-years-christmas-blues-bollywoods-christmas-blockbuster-era-come-end/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/7-years-christmas-blues-bollywoods-christmas-blockbuster-era-come-end/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:30:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Years of Christmas Blues: Has Bollywoods Christmas Blockbuster Era come to an end? - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/7-years-christmas-blues-bollywoods-christmas-blockbuster-era-come-end/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/7-years-christmas-blues-bollywoods-christmas-blockbuster-era-come-end/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:30:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Witches & Westerns On Your OTT Menu - Rediff.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxNMjVOcjMwWHljUDVFUk0zTk84ZnlnREJLcnUxdEZCT3RSYnFaYS1ET2dCUzBDZmRBbnFLN2ZvTVdHQ3FRaWx3cC1qRjlCZHZIZE1SNTNYOXVYVXdJODZKdUNLOGlobl9lWmttUWZ5dGhpU1VTVFRZTXd1NjdGQUNHczNaX3dCS0F2QWNwUEI1WmQ5aGo2VlEtMExBTdIBmwFBVV95cUxNMjVOcjMwWHljUDVFUk0zTk84ZnlnREJLcnUxdEZCT3RSYnFaYS1ET2dCUzBDZmRBbnFLN2ZvTVdHQ3FRaWx3cC1qRjlCZHZIZE1SNTNYOXVYVXdJODZKdUNLOGlobl9lWmttUWZ5dGhpU1VTVFRZTXd1NjdGQUNHczNaX3dCS0F2QWNwUEI1WmQ5aGo2VlEtMExBTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxNMjVOcjMwWHljUDVFUk0zTk84ZnlnREJLcnUxdEZCT3RSYnFaYS1ET2dCUzBDZmRBbnFLN2ZvTVdHQ3FRaWx3cC1qRjlCZHZIZE1SNTNYOXVYVXdJODZKdUNLOGlobl9lWmttUWZ5dGhpU1VTVFRZTXd1NjdGQUNHczNaX3dCS0F2QWNwUEI1WmQ5aGo2VlEtMExBTdIBmwFBVV95cUxNMjVOcjMwWHljUDVFUk0zTk84ZnlnREJLcnUxdEZCT3RSYnFaYS1ET2dCUzBDZmRBbnFLN2ZvTVdHQ3FRaWx3cC1qRjlCZHZIZE1SNTNYOXVYVXdJODZKdUNLOGlobl9lWmttUWZ5dGhpU1VTVFRZTXd1NjdGQUNHczNaX3dCS0F2QWNwUEI1WmQ5aGo2VlEtMExBTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:28:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fateh X review: Sonu Sood wins over the internet with directorial debut - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fateh X review: Sonu Sood wins over the internet with directorial debut</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 10, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/fateh-101217397-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=I6dLgjflvzVNcx8VhhXY4uB6Q7pzgLYM&amp;size=690:388" alt="Fateh" title="Sonu Sood in the poster of Fateh"><figcaption>Sonu Sood in the poster of Fateh</figcaption><p>Actor-producer Sonu Sood has made his directorial debut with Fateh, an action film that has received widespread acclaim on social media.</p><ul><li>Fateh released in cinemas on January 10, 2025.</li><li>The film is praised for its thrilling sequences and strong performances.</li><li>Sonu Sood both directs and stars in the film, which features an ensemble cast including Jacqueliene Fernandez, Vijay Raaz, and Naseeruddin Shah.</li><li>The movie is inspired by true events and is expected to perform well at the box office.</li></ul><blockquote>“Fateh is an action entertainer with a good storyline. Sonu Sood has impressed with his directorial debut.”</blockquote><blockquote>“Fateh is a full-throttle action ride! A must-watch for action lovers!”</blockquote><p>Overall, Fateh has made a significant impact on viewers and is a noteworthy addition to Sonu Sood's career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/movies/bollywood/story/fateh-x-review-sonu-sood-wins-internet-with-directorial-debut-jacqueline-fernandez-stmp-2662721-2025-01-10</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/movies/bollywood/story/fateh-x-review-sonu-sood-wins-internet-with-directorial-debut-jacqueline-fernandez-stmp-2662721-2025-01-10</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:25:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer leaked online: Ram Charan, Kiara Advani-starrer becomes the victim of piracy within hours of release - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Movie Leaked Online Within Hours of Release</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>The highly anticipated film 'Game Changer', featuring Ram Charan and Kiara Advani, was leaked online just hours after its release. The pirated version of the film has reportedly spread across various piracy sites, raising concerns for the filmmakers.</p><ul><li>The film was directed by S Shankar and released on January 10, 2025.</li><li>Unauthorized copies are available on piracy sites like Tamilrockers, Movierulz, and others.</li><li>Fans have mixed reactions, praising Ram Charan's performance but criticizing the film's predictability.</li><li>The film was produced with a budget of Rs 450 crore, making it one of the most expensive films in Tollywood.</li><li>Three songs were removed from the movie due to technical issues but will be reinstated soon.</li></ul><blockquote>“#GameChanger is a crisp, fast-paced, & heartfelt entertainer. It boldly delves into themes of power dynamics & their ties to systemic injustices.”</blockquote><p>Despite the piracy issue, the film has generated a lot of buzz, with audiences eagerly discussing its various elements and performances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-leaked-online-ram-charan-kiara-advani-starrer-becomes-the-victim-of-piracy-within-hours-of-release-9770972/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-leaked-online-ram-charan-kiara-advani-starrer-becomes-the-victim-of-piracy-within-hours-of-release-9770972/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:24:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Woman sings Aaj Ki Raat while playing harmonium, son dances to it. Viral video - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Viral Video of Woman Singing Aaj Ki Raat While Her Son Dances</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 10, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/woman-sings-aaj-ki-raat-while-playing-harmonium--son-dances-to-it-photos-ooyesundayinstagram-101002780-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=kZUMQMIwCSaDGi9id7XUYEIALYitY9Yi&amp;size=690:388" alt="Woman sings Aaj Ki Raat while playing harmonium son dances to it"><figcaption>Woman sings Aaj Ki Raat while playing harmonium, son dances to it (Photos: ooyesunday/Instagram)</figcaption><p>A viral video of a woman singing Aaj Ki Raat while playing the tune on her harmonium has delighted the internet, especially as her son dances beside her.</p><ul><li>The video features a woman singing Tamannaah Bhatia’s Aaj Ki Raat.</li><li>Her son attempts to recreate the dance steps of the song, eliciting laughter from her.</li><li>The video has gone viral, gathering millions of views across social media platforms.</li><li>Aaj Ki Raat is a song from the movie Stree 2, sung by Madhubanti Bagchi and Divya Kumar.</li></ul><blockquote>“The internet enjoyed the mother-son duo's video just as much, and that is clear from the comments.”</blockquote><p>The joy and connection showcased in this heartwarming video have captured the attention and affection of viewers online.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/trending-news/story/aaj-ki-raat-harmonium-woman-sings-son-dance-video-viral-adorable-2662719-2025-01-10</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/trending-news/story/aaj-ki-raat-harmonium-woman-sings-son-dance-video-viral-adorable-2662719-2025-01-10</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:19:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neena Gupta recalls how aunt kicked her out of the house in middle of the night: ‘I had nowhere to go, had a baby with me’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Neena Gupta Recalls Night She Was Kicked Out by Her Aunt</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/10/Neena-Gupta-opens-up-about-her-initial-struggle-in-Mumbai.jpg?w=640" alt="Neena Gupta recalls when she was kicked out of the house in the middle of the night" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Neena Gupta recalls when she was kicked out of the house in the middle of the night. (Photo: Neena Gupta/Instagram)</figcaption><p>In a recent interview, Neena Gupta shares her experience of being kicked out by her aunt in the middle of the night while navigating her struggles in Mumbai.</p><ul><li>Neena moved to Mumbai in the 1980s and began buying apartments over time.</li><li>She faced homelessness after her aunt unexpectedly kicked her out with her baby.</li><li>Her uncle eventually allowed her to stay temporarily in an unoccupied flat, but she had to leave again.</li><li>Ultimately, she managed to get a refund from a builder and bought a new house in Aram Nagar.</li></ul><blockquote>“But one day, she threw me out in the middle of the night, she kicked me out.” Neena Gupta</blockquote><p>Neena's story highlights the precariousness many face while trying to build a life in a new city.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/neena-gupta-aunt-kicked-her-out-of-the-house-in-middle-of-the-night-9770878/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/neena-gupta-aunt-kicked-her-out-of-the-house-in-middle-of-the-night-9770878/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:05:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rakul Preet Singh stuns in 'blush pink' outfit - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rakul Preet Singh stuns in 'blush pink' outfit</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117107973,imgsize-11006,width-400,resizemode-4/117107973.jpg' alt='Rakul Preet Singh stuns in blush pink outfit' decoding='async' fetchpriority='high'><figcaption>Picture Credit: X</figcaption><p>Bollywood actress Rakul Preet Singh treated her fans with a string of stunning pictures of herself dressed in "blush pink" during a recent photoshoot. In the images, she paired an oversized shirt with gold jewelry, and invited her fans to suggest captions for her post.</p><ul><li>Rakul shared her photos on Instagram, seeking creative captions from her followers.</li><li>Her look included a golden choker, matt makeup, and a messy bun.</li><li>Earlier, she posted about enjoying her recent holiday, reflecting on letting go of guilt related to food indulgence.</li><li>Rakul will star in the upcoming film 'Mere Husband Ki Biwi' alongside Arjun Kapoor and Bhumi Pednekar, set for release on February 21.</li></ul><blockquote>"How you feel is more important than how you look... no one's validation is more important than your acceptance of yourself."</blockquote><p>The article highlights Rakul's confidence in embracing her appearance and her upcoming romantic comedy film.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/rakul-preet-singh-stuns-in-blush-pink-outfit/articleshow/117107958.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/rakul-preet-singh-stuns-in-blush-pink-outfit/articleshow/117107958.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll : What is your review of Ram Charan’s Game Changer? - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Poll: What is your review of Ram Charan's Game Changer?</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Latest Telugu Movie Videos</p>
<p>This article features a poll asking readers to share their reviews of the movie 'Game Changer' starring Ram Charan.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Options for voting include: Super Hit, Decent, Average, and Disaster.</li>
  <li>The poll aims to gauge audience reactions to the film.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Your opinion matters! Vote now!”</blockquote>
<p>Readers are encouraged to participate and share their opinions on the film.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/videos/polls/poll-what-is-your-review-of-ram-charans-game-changer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/videos/polls/poll-what-is-your-review-of-ram-charans-game-changer.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:47:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer Box Office Day 1 Prediction: Ram Charan Ready To Deliver Biggest Sankranti Opener With A 50 Crore+ Score! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Box Office Day 1 Prediction: Ram Charan Ready To Deliver Biggest Sankranti Opener With A 50 Crore</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p>
<img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2025/01/game-changer-box-office-day-1-prediction-ram-charans-magnum-opus-to-be-the-biggest-sankranti-opener-01.jpg" alt="Game Changer Box Office Day 1 Prediction: Ram Charan's Magnum Opus To Be The Biggest Sankranti Opener" width="1200" height="630">
<figcaption>Game Changer Box Office Day 1 Prediction: Ram Charan’s Magnum Opus To Be The Biggest Sankranti Opener ( Photo Credit – YouTube )</figcaption>
<p>Ram Charan’s much-anticipated film <em>Game Changer</em> is finally releasing, and the buzz is promising a huge start at the box office, particularly with strong advance bookings.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Expected to register a staggering <strong>55-60 crore</strong> net on day 1.</li>
  <li>Advance bookings have already crossed <strong>24 crores</strong> gross.</li>
  <li>Charan is anticipated to benefit from the popularity gained from his previous film <em>RRR</em>.</li>
  <li>The film is set to dethrone <em>Sarileru Neekevvaru</em> for the biggest Sankranti opening.</li>
  <li>Over 17,000 shows are scheduled nationwide with significant showings in both Hindi and Telugu.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Numbers are based on estimates and various sources. They have not been independently verified by Koimoi.”</blockquote>
<p>With high expectations from fans and a strong marketing push, <em>Game Changer</em> aims to make a significant impact on its opening day.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/game-changer-box-office-day-1-prediction-ram-charan-ready-to-deliver-biggest-sankranti-opener-with-a-50-crore-score/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/game-changer-box-office-day-1-prediction-ram-charan-ready-to-deliver-biggest-sankranti-opener-with-a-50-crore-score/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:37:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shah Rukh Khan turns down Chamunda; sets eyes on a unique project with Maddock and Amar Kaushik - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shah Rukh Khan Turns Down Chamunda for Unique Project with Maddock</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p>
<img src="https://stat5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Shah-Rukh-Khan.jpg" alt="Shah Rukh Khan turns down Chamunda; sets eyes on a unique project with Maddock and Amar Kaushik" width="620" height="450">
<figcaption>Shah Rukh Khan has set his sights on new projects, turning down Chamunda.</figcaption>
<p>Following the success of <em>Stree 2</em>, Shah Rukh Khan met with Dinesh Vijan and director Amar Kaushik to discuss potential collaborations, yet he decided to pass on the lead role in <em>Chamunda</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li>Shah Rukh was approached to star in <em>Chamunda</em>, a horror-comedy planned for release in 2026.</li>
<li>SRK prefers to create a new universe rather than joining an existing one.</li>
<li>He has requested a fresh concept from Maddock and Amar Kaushik.</li>
<li>The collaboration discussions are still ongoing, with them exploring new ideas.</li>
<li>Chamunda was just one of several projects pitched to him by Vijan.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Shah Rukh Khan didn't want to enter an already established universe and rather start a new world with Maddock and Amar Kaushik." - Source</blockquote>
<p>This development marks a significant shift in Shah Rukh's project choices as he looks for innovative narratives to explore.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-turns-chamunda-sets-eyes-unique-project-maddock-amar-kaushik/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-turns-chamunda-sets-eyes-unique-project-maddock-amar-kaushik/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:30:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Shanaya Kapoor, Aryan Khan to Rasha Thadani: 7 star kids who are all set to make their Bollywood debut in 2025 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>From Shanaya Kapoor, Aryan Khan to Rasha Thadani: 7 Star Kids Making Their Bollywood Debut in 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/star_kids_1736317083948_1736317112887.jpg" alt="Shanaya Kapoor, Aryan Khan and Rasha Thadani amongst others will debut in Bollywood this year"><figcaption>Shanaya Kapoor, Aryan Khan and Rasha Thadani amongst others will debut in Bollywood this year</figcaption><p>2025 has arrived with a fresh wave of star kids eager to debut in the Hindi film industry. This article explores seven star kids ready to take the leap and examines their backgrounds, debuts, and the films they're associated with this year.</p><ul><li><strong>Shanaya Kapoor:</strong> Set to debut in <i>Aankhon Ki Gustaakhiyan</i>.</li><li><strong>Ibrahim Ali Khan:</strong> Making his debut in <i>Sarzameen</i>.</li><li><strong>Ahaan Panday:</strong> Starring in a young love story directed by Mohit Suri.</li><li><strong>Rasha Thadani:</strong> Debuting in <i>Azaad</i>, releasing on January 17.</li><li><strong>Aaman Devgan:</strong> Also debuting in <i>Azaad</i>.</li><li><strong>Simar Bhatia:</strong> Set to appear in <i>Ikkis</i>.</li><li><strong>Aryan Khan:</strong> Making his debut as a writer and director with the Netflix series <i>Stardom</i>.</li></ul><blockquote>“After surfing through the batch of 2025, who do you have the highest expectations from this year?”</blockquote><p>This year is poised for exciting new entries in Bollywood, as these star kids step into the limelight, each with their unique backgrounds and flair.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/from-shanaya-kapoor-aryan-khan-to-rasha-thadani-7-star-kids-who-are-all-set-to-make-their-bollywood-debut-in-2025-101736317025780.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/from-shanaya-kapoor-aryan-khan-to-rasha-thadani-7-star-kids-who-are-all-set-to-make-their-bollywood-debut-in-2025-101736317025780.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:17:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kangana Ranaut wants Karan Johar to act in her directorial, says ‘it will not be on saas-bahu ki chuglibaazi' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/kangana-ranaut-wants-karan-johar-to-act-in-her-directorial-i-will-give-him-very-good-role-watch-101736481622290.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/kangana-ranaut-wants-karan-johar-to-act-in-her-directorial-i-will-give-him-very-good-role-watch-101736481622290.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 04:31:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: These 3 Contestants Likely To Be Evicted Before The Finale, Makers All Set To Reveal The Top 5! - News24]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18: These 3 Contestants Likely To Be Evicted Before The Finale, Makers All Set To Reveal The Top 5!</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Jan 10, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: News24</strong></p>
<p>As the grand finale of Bigg Boss 18 approaches, tensions rise with impending evictions as fans await to see who makes the top 5.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shilpa Shirodkar's gameplay is waning with diminishing support.</li>
  <li>Eisha Singh's standing deteriorates as audience response falters.</li>
  <li>Chaahat Pandey, although strong, may face eviction due to competition.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"As the countdown begins for the top 5, who will bid farewell?"</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming evictions are expected to reshape the final moments of the reality show, keeping fans on the edge of their seats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news24online.com/entertainment/bigg-boss-18-these-3-contestants-likely-to-be-evicted-before-the-finale-makers-all-set-to-reveal-the-top-5/437287/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news24online.com/entertainment/bigg-boss-18-these-3-contestants-likely-to-be-evicted-before-the-finale-makers-all-set-to-reveal-the-top-5/437287/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 03:57:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neena Gupta leaves a controversial comment on Anupam Kher's tribute to Pritish Nandy; says, 'NO RIP for... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Neena Gupta Sparks Debate with Comment on Anupam Kher's Tribute to Pritish Nandy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250110031304_neenagupta-pritishnandy.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Neena Gupta and Pritish Nandy" /><figcaption>Neena Gupta's controversial remarks on Pritish Nandy's tribute.</figcaption><p>The passing of prominent journalist Pritish Nandy led to tributes from many, including Anupam Kher. However, Neena Gupta's critical comment about Nandy ignited a heated debate.</p><ul><li>Pritish Nandy passed away on January 8, 2025, in Mumbai.</li><li>Anupam Kher expressed his sorrow in a heartfelt social media post.</li><li>Neena Gupta commented on Kher's post, stating she would not honor Nandy with an 'RIP'.</li><li>Gupta accused Nandy of stealing her child's birth certificate and publishing it.</li></ul><blockquote>“Do you know what he did to me, and I called him a bastard openly. He stole my baby's birth certificate and published it. So no RIP, you understand, and I have proof of it.”</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the complexities of personal relationships in the public eye, especially in the context of grief and remembrance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/neena-gupta-leaves-a-controversial-comment-on-anupam-kher-s-tribute-to-pritish-nandy-says-no-rip-for-him-he-stole-article-12907108.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/neena-gupta-leaves-a-controversial-comment-on-anupam-kher-s-tribute-to-pritish-nandy-says-no-rip-for-him-he-stole-article-12907108.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 03:14:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>