<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:26:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:26:34 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan turn paparazzi into cheerleaders at Mumbai event; Katrina Kaif, Suhana Khan seen too. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan Turn Paparazzi into Cheerleaders at Mumbai Event</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 22, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Shah_Rukh_Khan_1734837096232_1734837108917.jpg" alt="Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan, Suhana Khan and Katrina Kaif attended a Mumbai event." title="Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan, Suhana Khan and Katrina Kaif attended a Mumbai event.">
<figcaption>Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan, Suhana Khan and Katrina Kaif attended a Mumbai event.</figcaption>
<p>Shah Rukh Khan and Gauri Khan were among the many celebrities who attended a festive gathering at Mumbai’s Nita Mukesh Ambani Cultural Centre, where they charmed the paparazzi.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shah Rukh and Gauri rocked matching black outfits.</li>
  <li>They received cheers from fans upon arriving at the event.</li>
  <li>Other attendees included Katrina Kaif, Madhuri Dixit, and Suhana Khan.</li>
  <li>Shah Rukh Khan is set to appear in the upcoming film King.</li>
  <li>Shahid Kapoor's upcoming film Deva is scheduled for release on February 14, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“After posing for the paparazzi, Shah Rukh Khan smiled, blew a kiss, and flashed the thumbs-up sign.”</blockquote>
<p>This event highlighted the glamorous side of Bollywood and showcased the camaraderie among its stars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-gauri-khan-turn-paparazzi-into-cheerleaders-at-mumbai-event-katrina-kaif-suhana-khan-seen-too-watch-101734833677574.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-gauri-khan-turn-paparazzi-into-cheerleaders-at-mumbai-event-katrina-kaif-suhana-khan-seen-too-watch-101734833677574.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:36:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer: Dhop song release time pushed back - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer: Dhop Song Release Time Pushed Back</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 22, 2024 8:28 am IST</p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Game-Chager.jpg" alt="Game Changer" width="550" height="378">
<figcaption>Promotional image for Game Changer</figcaption>
<p>Global star Ram Charan is set to appear in a dual role in his upcoming political drama Game Changer, directed by Shankar Shanmugam. Kiara Advani plays the female lead in this highly anticipated film, which is scheduled for release on January 10, 2025, in all major Indian languages.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film's promotional events are currently taking place in Dallas, where Ram Charan is engaging with fans.</li>
  <li>The Dhop song, composed by popular music director Thaman, was initially scheduled for release at 8:20 AM but has been delayed to 9:30 AM.</li>
  <li>Despite the delay, fans anticipate that the track will be a major hit.</li>
  <li>Game Changer features a prominent cast including SJ Suryah, Srikanth, Anjali, and others.</li>
  <li>Produced by Dil Raju under the Sri Venkateswara Creations banner, the film comes with high budget expectations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Dhop song will become a chartbuster despite the wait.”</blockquote>
<p>This delay in the song release adds to the excitement surrounding the film's premiere, reflecting the high anticipation among fans for Game Changer.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/game-changer-dhop-song-release-time-pushed-back.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/game-changer-dhop-song-release-time-pushed-back.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 02:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jennifer Lopez ‘struggles’ being a single mom following her split with Ben Affleck - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jennifer Lopez discusses the challenges of raising her twins after her split from Ben Affleck.</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 22, 2024 | <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/469891966_18502433512037720_8448220938803038850_n_1733926660735_1734834028221.jpg" alt="In a British Vogue interview, Jennifer Lopez reflects on parenting struggles and her role in the film Unstoppable.(Instagram/Jennifer Lopez)" title="In a British Vogue interview, Jennifer Lopez reflects on parenting struggles and her role in the film Unstoppable.(Instagram/Jennifer Lopez)">
<figcaption>In a British Vogue interview, Jennifer Lopez reflects on parenting struggles and her role in the film Unstoppable.(Instagram/Jennifer Lopez)</figcaption>
<p>In a recent interview with British Vogue, Jennifer Lopez opened up about her struggles as a single mother of her 16-year-old twins, Emme and Max, following her split from Ben Affleck. She emphasized her experience and feelings of vulnerability amidst public scrutiny.</p>
<ul>
<li>Lopez describes parenting as a “beautiful, challenging blessing.”</li>
<li>She acknowledges her aim to always put forward a strong front for her children despite personal struggles.</li>
<li>The actress addresses her own moments of self-doubt as a single parent.</li>
<li>Her role in the film 'Unstoppable' has provided her with a sense of healing and reflection.</li>
<li>Lopez emphasizes that “all you need is really one good parent to love you.”</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Being a parent [is] the hardest job that anyone could ever have.”</blockquote>
<p>Jennifer Lopez's insights reveal the complexities and emotional depths of single parenthood, showing that even amidst fame, the challenges of raising children remain relatable.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jennifer-lopez-struggles-being-a-single-mom-following-her-split-with-ben-affleck-101734831288146.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jennifer-lopez-struggles-being-a-single-mom-following-her-split-with-ben-affleck-101734831288146.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 02:35:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shah Rukh Khan doesn't have any memorable songs after our fall out, says Abhijeet Bhattacharya - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Abhijeet Bhattacharya Reflects on Feud with Shah Rukh Khan and Career Impact</h1><p><strong>Dec 22, 2024</strong> - <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/Shah_Rukh_Khan_1734780505048_1734780512771.jpg" alt="Shah Rukh Khan's films would often feature songs by Abhijeet Bhattacharya in the 90s and early 2000s." title="Shah Rukh Khan's films would often feature songs by Abhijeet Bhattacharya in the 90s and early 2000s."><figcaption>Shah Rukh Khan's films would often feature songs by Abhijeet Bhattacharya in the 90s and early 2000s.</figcaption></figure><p>In a recent podcast interview, singer Abhijeet Bhattacharya addressed his long-standing feud with Shah Rukh Khan, stating that the actor has not produced any memorable songs since they stopped working together.</p><ul><li>Abhijeet expressed that he has not sung for Shah Rukh in 17 years, despite their successful collaborations in the past.</li><li>He highlighted Shah Rukh could have reached out to mend their relationship.</li><li>Abhijeet feels hurt by the lack of recognition for his contributions to Shah Rukh's early music success.</li><li>He likened their connection to a marital relationship, indicating that they are 'made for each other' despite conflicts.</li><li>Abhijeet critiqued the current quality of Shah Rukh's song selections against their iconic past work.</li></ul><blockquote>“I wasn’t feeling anger; I was hurt.”</blockquote><p>Abhijeet's recent remarks highlight the complexities of professional relationships in the entertainment industry and reflect on the impacts of personal disputes on artistic collaboration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-doesnt-have-any-memorable-songs-after-our-fall-out-says-abhijeet-bhattacharya-101734778706933.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-doesnt-have-any-memorable-songs-after-our-fall-out-says-abhijeet-bhattacharya-101734778706933.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:55:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viduthalai Part - 2 Box Office Collection Day 2 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxORkNDa2NRNnk4WW13T1hHTVNLbmxPdDhXUEN1Q3JEdUxON3hJM1gwTUpfOURCY3JaXzdQbkdDWGVhUDVPWHFBTXZGZGJlNUE3RjBORHEySWZFV1ZJRnhucGRrUG1tazJXay1lYUlaMUd1LUpibm9hV21tSWVmeC1LYXJjVHozUExRdmREenBn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxORkNDa2NRNnk4WW13T1hHTVNLbmxPdDhXUEN1Q3JEdUxON3hJM1gwTUpfOURCY3JaXzdQbkdDWGVhUDVPWHFBTXZGZGJlNUE3RjBORHEySWZFV1ZJRnhucGRrUG1tazJXay1lYUlaMUd1LUpibm9hV21tSWVmeC1LYXJjVHozUExRdmREenBn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:37:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Pisces, December 22 to 28, 2024 predicts financial stability - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope for Pisces: December 22 to 28, 2024 – Financial Stability Ahead</h1><p><strong>Date: December 22, 2024</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/Pisces_1728478870554_1734805629311.jpg" alt="Pisces Weekly Horoscope: Financial predictions for the week ahead." title="Pisces Weekly Horoscope: Financial predictions for the week ahead."><figcaption>Pisces Weekly Horoscope Today, December 22 to 28, 2024: New tasks may keep the office life busy. Your health is in good shape.</figcaption></figure><p>This week, Pisces will find value in personal relationships and should focus on managing financial matters wisely.</p><ul><li>This week emphasizes nurturing personal relationships and staying alert to career opportunities.</li><li>Financial management is crucial; consider reassessing your budget and avoiding impulsive spending.</li><li>Health is highlighted; maintain a balanced lifestyle with exercise and good nutrition.</li><li>Career prospects may arise; assess them carefully before making decisions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Balance is key to maintaining well-being.”</blockquote><p>Overall, focusing on love, career, and financial management will lead to a productive week for Pisces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-pisces-december-22-to-28-2024-predicts-financial-stability-101734805243700.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-pisces-december-22-to-28-2024-predicts-financial-stability-101734805243700.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 22:41:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Karan Veer Mehra Apologises To Digvijay Rathee, Salman Khan Says ‘Ab Kya Fayda’ - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18: Karan Veer Mehra Apologises To Digvijay Rathee</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Digvijay was a wild-card contestant in Bigg Boss 18." title="Digvijay was a wild-card contestant in Bigg Boss 18." loading="eager"><figcaption>Digvijay was a wild-card contestant in Bigg Boss 18. (Photo Credits: Instagram)</figcaption><p>Bigg Boss 18, hosted by Salman Khan, is heating up as contestant Digvijay Rathee faced a shocking mid-week eviction. Many viewers criticized the show's makers for biases favoring other contestants.</p><ul><li>Digvijay's unexpected eviction surprised housemates and viewers.</li><li>Salman Khan expressed disbelief at Digvijay's early exit during a promo.</li><li>Digvijay reflected on his connections, suggesting that Karan and Chum may have contributed to his eviction.</li><li>Karan Veer Mehra apologized to Digvijay after hearing his remarks.</li><li>Viewers expressed frustration with the eviction process, calling it unfair.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kisi ne nahi socha tha ki aap itni jaldi bahar ho jaage.” - Salman Khan</blockquote><p>This episode has sparked discussions among fans about fairness in the show and the emotional portrayal of contestants.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/entertainment/television/bigg-boss-18-karan-veer-mehra-apologises-to-digvijay-rathee-salman-khan-says-ab-kya-fayda-aa-9163788.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/entertainment/television/bigg-boss-18-karan-veer-mehra-apologises-to-digvijay-rathee-salman-khan-says-ab-kya-fayda-aa-9163788.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 22:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope 22nd December to 28th December, 2024: Virgo, Sagittarius and other signs — check astrological prediction - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope 22nd December to 28th December, 2024: Virgo, Sagittarius and other signs — check astrological prediction</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Astrology News</p>
<p>This week presents a unique opportunity for individuals to pursue long-term goals, whether in career or personal life, with an emphasis on facing challenges positively. Various zodiac signs receive tailored advice to navigate their week ahead.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Gemini:</strong> Discover hidden business talents and be mindful of relationship costs.</li>
  <li><strong>Cancer:</strong> Navigate emotional dynamics with charm rather than confrontation.</li>
  <li><strong>Leo:</strong> Assert yourself and avoid being taken advantage of.</li>
  <li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Embrace creativity amidst routine commitments.</li>
  <li><strong>Libra:</strong> Make balanced choices regarding personal security.</li>
  <li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Take control of your decisions, especially during job interviews.</li>
  <li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> Be honest to avoid financial pitfalls.</li>
  <li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Prepare for significant personal transformations.</li>
  <li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Stay clear of drama and engage in philanthropy.</li>
  <li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Teamwork is essential for success, both personally and professionally.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“You’re certainly on a winning ticket, but that doesn’t mean that life will all be plain sailing.”</blockquote>
<p>This week encourages embracing positive changes and addressing challenges head-on for personal growth and fulfillment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-22nd-december-to-28th-december-2024-virgo-sagittarius-and-other-signs-check-astrological-prediction-9737624/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-22nd-december-to-28th-december-2024-virgo-sagittarius-and-other-signs-check-astrological-prediction-9737624/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 21:30:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonu Nigam releases Aadesh Shrivastava’s last song, Ave Maria, this Christmas; also features Budapest Film Orchestra - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sonu Nigam Releases Aadesh Shrivastava's Last Song 'Ave Maria' This Christmas</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/ave_maria_1734814320450_1734814337456.jpg" alt="Sonu Nigam in Ave Maria; (right) late Aadesh Shrivastava" title="Sonu Nigam in Ave Maria; (right) late Aadesh Shrivastava">
<figcaption>Sonu Nigam in Ave Maria; (right) late Aadesh Shrivastava</figcaption>
<p>In a special tribute this Christmas, Sonu Nigam revives the prayer song 'Ave Maria,' originally envisioned by the late composer Aadesh Shrivastava, which they had worked on together in 2011 but could not finish.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sonu Nigam's release honors Aadesh Shrivastava's vision after his passing.</li>
  <li>The song features orchestration by the Budapest Film Orchestra.</li>
  <li>Nigam had received training in western vocal techniques to prepare for this project.</li>
  <li>The song blends Indian classical elements with western orchestration, showcasing Christianity's cultural identity in India.</li>
  <li>Nigam reflects on his personal inspirations, including his mother and early education in a convent school.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“My mother always instilled the belief in us that God is one... all paths lead to one supreme power.” - Sonu Nigam</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this release not only pays homage to Aadesh Shrivastava but also emphasizes the cultural and spiritual connections Sonu Nigam has nurtured through his music.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/sonu-nigam-releases-aadesh-shrivastava-s-last-song-ave-maria-this-christmas-also-features-budapest-film-orchestra-101734814088286.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/sonu-nigam-releases-aadesh-shrivastava-s-last-song-ave-maria-this-christmas-also-features-budapest-film-orchestra-101734814088286.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 20:58:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today: Astrological prediction for December 22, 2024 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Horoscope Today: Astrological Prediction for December 22, 2024</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Dec 22, 2024 01:00 AM IST</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/horoscope_1672156308727_1734791292942.jpg' alt='Horoscope Today: Astrological prediction for December 28, 2022(Pixabay)'><figcaption>Horoscope Today: Astrological prediction for December 28, 2022(Pixabay)</figcaption><p>This article provides daily astrological predictions for all zodiac signs, discussing the influences of cosmic alignments for December 22, 2024.</p><ul><li><strong>Aries:</strong> Adopt healthy alternatives; a journey ahead; beware of offending others.</li><li><strong>Taurus:</strong> New friends and fitness improvements; financial worries increase.</li><li><strong>Gemini:</strong> Clear misunderstandings; patience tested.</li><li><strong>Cancer:</strong> Health improves; spiritual pursuits increase.</li><li><strong>Leo:</strong> Positive changes; express love.</li><li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Enjoy recoveries and joy from visitors.</li><li><strong>Libra:</strong> Take precautions for health; social events revive.</li><li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Finances improve; social spotlight.</li><li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> Project becomes financially rewarding.</li><li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Self-discipline aids health; social respect grows.</li><li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Balance diet; business opportunities arise.</li><li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Healthy eating helps wellness; reconnecting with friends.</li></ul><blockquote>"Love Focus: Plan something special with your partner, as they’ll make time for you."</blockquote><p>This astrology forecast assures various signs of favorable changes or challenges ahead, urging readers to remain cautious and proactive in their lives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-astrological-prediction-for-december-22-2024-101734791075081.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-astrological-prediction-for-december-22-2024-101734791075081.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 19:30:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marco Box Office Collection Day 2 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE1UbV81QVRmMGhJX0hjcmJfV1FyMUpPbVpQVkpjVm9OVzRxTU9xS2xsRXcycWluVGdXWkJreUVQWGd5YXZXZnNSZzdUOFotbExLWWdPVFNSYWp5QzJPR0pPQ3NiVURLcU9RRWYxaEwtdjFBaVlFZzRCckt2c2M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE1UbV81QVRmMGhJX0hjcmJfV1FyMUpPbVpQVkpjVm9OVzRxTU9xS2xsRXcycWluVGdXWkJreUVQWGd5YXZXZnNSZzdUOFotbExLWWdPVFNSYWp5QzJPR0pPQ3NiVURLcU9RRWYxaEwtdjFBaVlFZzRCckt2c2M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 19:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aamir Khan told Kiran Rao one line from Laapataa Ladies, convincing her: ‘Was struggling as a Laapataa Lady myself’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kiran Rao remembers how she was like a Laapataa Lady before Aamir Khan told her one line from Laapataa Ladies</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong> Dec 21, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/Aamir_Kiran_1734800687226_1734800739827.jpg" alt="Aamir Khan and Kiran Rao" title="Aamir Khan and Kiran Rao">
<figcaption>Aamir Khan and Kiran Rao</figcaption>
<p>Kiran Rao reflects on her journey as a filmmaker, recounting how Aamir Khan inspired her to take on her latest project, Laapataa Ladies, after a long struggle with finding the right story.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Laapataa Ladies is Kiran Rao’s second film after Dhobi Ghat, released 13 years prior.</li>
  <li>The film received critical acclaim and was India’s entry for the Best International Feature Film at the Oscars.</li>
  <li>Kiran shared that Aamir’s compelling description of the film inspired her to direct it.</li>
  <li>She expressed enthusiasm about her next project, stating it won’t take another 13 years to announce.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“That one line was just so compelling that I was like, I want to do this, really badly.” - Kiran Rao</blockquote>
<p>Kiran Rao's story showcases the influence of collaboration in filmmaking and her continued commitment to the industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/aamir-khan-told-kiran-rao-one-line-from-laapataa-ladies-convincing-her-was-struggling-as-a-laapataa-lady-myself-101734800088420.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/aamir-khan-told-kiran-rao-one-line-from-laapataa-ladies-convincing-her-was-struggling-as-a-laapataa-lady-myself-101734800088420.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 17:14:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Gunn's 'Superman' Trailer Scored A Record 250+ Million Views In The First 24 Hours - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOM2dtODU5bzdzNm5GckQ2dEdZVXhiRE5qc0ZSTU5NWk5uUmdIbWZtaDEtRElwVDh1OUJRMVZJYUt2Y1h3OGdMbkZQS2MzX2FzZUZDOVRTcE1kQnYtM3l0NzE3TFhILWQ5YlIxNkVtUl9NVVAySjhUM3JEMERMWGtMVGhYbDd2T25iLWo0dlN6VVZyLXN3dlF4OTY1YzZock9sdmM5RDJmT04zMjRRUW15ZE52bw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOM2dtODU5bzdzNm5GckQ2dEdZVXhiRE5qc0ZSTU5NWk5uUmdIbWZtaDEtRElwVDh1OUJRMVZJYUt2Y1h3OGdMbkZQS2MzX2FzZUZDOVRTcE1kQnYtM3l0NzE3TFhILWQ5YlIxNkVtUl9NVVAySjhUM3JEMERMWGtMVGhYbDd2T25iLWo0dlN6VVZyLXN3dlF4OTY1YzZock9sdmM5RDJmT04zMjRRUW15ZE52bw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:56:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE SmackDown Results: All-New Bloodline Triumphs In Six-Man Tag Team Match - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WWE SmackDown Results: All-New Bloodline Triumphs In Six-Man Tag Team Match</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="WWE SmackDown: All-New Bloodline Triumphs in Six-Man Tag Team Match (WWE Media)"><figcaption>WWE SmackDown: All-New Bloodline Triumphs in Six-Man Tag Team Match (WWE Media)</figcaption></figure><p>The latest instalment of WWE’s weekly episode of Friday Night SmackDown premiered live on December 20 at the XL Center in Hartford, Connecticut. The event featured intense matches, including the All-New Bloodline competing against other formidable opponents.</p><ul><li>The show kicked off with a six-man tag team match featuring the All-New Bloodline.</li><li>Carmelo Hayes rematched Braun Strowman after a previous encounter.</li><li>Naomi and Bianca Belair defended their women's tag team titles against Nia Jax and Candice LeRae.</li></ul><blockquote>“Solo Sikoa revealed how Roman Reigns wanted to face him in a Tribal Combat Match on January 6.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, WWE SmackDown delighted fans with thrilling matchups, showcasing the strength and skills of its top wrestlers while setting the stage for upcoming events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/sports/wwe-smackdown-results-all-new-bloodline-triumphs-in-six-man-tag-team-match-9163676.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/sports/wwe-smackdown-results-all-new-bloodline-triumphs-in-six-man-tag-team-match-9163676.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:50:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun's Press Meet: A Poor Show With Lies.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun's Press Meet: A Poor Show With Lies</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/alluarjun_91734799754.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun's Press Meet: A Poor Show With Lies"><figcaption>Allu Arjun during the press meet.</figcaption><p>In response to allegations made by Revanth Reddy in the Assembly, Allu Arjun held a press meet but failed to address the accusations convincingly.</p><ul><li>Allu Arjun claimed he did not visit the accident victim based on legal advice.</li><li>He stated he refrained from celebrating after learning of a woman's death and a boy's critical condition.</li><li>Contrary to his claims, he attended celebrations in Delhi and Hyderabad after the incident.</li><li>His demeanor and body language during the press meet raised doubts about his sincerity.</li><li>He relied on pre-written notes instead of speaking from the heart.</li><li>Statements made appeared factually incorrect regarding the timeline of events.</li></ul><blockquote>“True emotion does not require preparation.”</blockquote><p>His attempt to quell controversy through this press meet has not succeeded, as his actions failed to reflect genuine remorse.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/allu-arjuns-press-meet-a-poor-show-with-lies-142908</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/allu-arjuns-press-meet-a-poor-show-with-lies-142908</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:49:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winners Of The 2024 SBS Drama Awards - soompi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Winners Of The 2024 SBS Drama Awards</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Soompi</p><img src="https://0.soompi.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01181019/soompi-dec2024-brewing-love.png" alt="Winners Of The 2024 SBS Drama Awards" width="610" height="130"><figcaption>A visual summary of the award ceremony.</figcaption><p>SBS has celebrated the top dramas and actors of 2024! The 2024 SBS Drama Awards took place to honor notable dramas from the past year.</p><ul><li>Daesang (Grand Prize) went to Jang Nara for her role in “Good Partner.”</li><li>Director’s Award awarded to Park Shin Hye for “The Judge From Hell.”</li><li>SBS Drama of the Year was awarded to “Connection.”</li><li>Other notable recognitions included various Excellence Awards across multiple categories.</li></ul><blockquote>“Congratulations to all the winners!”</blockquote><p>The event highlights the achievements in the industry, showcasing the notable talents and productions of the year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.soompi.com/article/1711836wpp/winners-of-the-2024-sbs-drama-awards</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.soompi.com/article/1711836wpp/winners-of-the-2024-sbs-drama-awards</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:38:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 The Rule box office collection day 17: Allu Arjun fights fresh allegations even as film mints over ₹1030 crore - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 The Rule box office collection day 17: Allu Arjun fights fresh allegations even as film mints over ₹1030 crore</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 21, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/Pushpa_2_The_Rule_ending_1733488357601_1734797123247.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun plays a red sanders smuggler called Pushpa Raj in Pushpa 2: The Rule." title="Allu Arjun plays a red sanders smuggler called Pushpa Raj in Pushpa 2: The Rule."/><figcaption>Allu Arjun plays a red sanders smuggler called Pushpa Raj in Pushpa 2: The Rule.</figcaption><p>Pushpa 2: The Rule continues to perform exceptionally well at the box office, generating over ₹1030 crore despite fresh allegations against lead actor Allu Arjun regarding a tragic incident at a film screening.</p><ul><li>The film has grossed approximately ₹25.31 crore net on its third Saturday, totaling ₹1030.21 crore net in 17 days.</li><li>It earned ₹10.65 crore during its premiere and ₹164.25 crore on opening day.</li><li>Pushpa 2 broke records to become the highest-grossing film of 2024.</li><li>Fresh allegations against Allu Arjun stem from a stampede during a film event that resulted in tragic consequences.</li><li>Telangana CM and MLA have accused him of irresponsibility during the incident.</li></ul><blockquote>“According to the information I have received...the film star turned to them, smiled and said, now the film will be a hit.” - MLA Akbaruddin Owaisi</blockquote><p>Despite the controversy, Pushpa 2: The Rule's box office numbers indicate strong audience engagement and commercial success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-the-rule-box-office-collection-day-17-allu-arjun-fights-fresh-allegations-even-as-film-mints-over-1030-crore-101734796756881.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-the-rule-box-office-collection-day-17-allu-arjun-fights-fresh-allegations-even-as-film-mints-over-1030-crore-101734796756881.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:37:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diljit Dosanjh Drops Baby's Photo From Mumbai Show; Katrina Kaif Calls Vicky Kaushal 'Adjusting' Over Bathr - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diljit Dosanjh Drops Baby's Photo From Mumbai Show; Katrina Kaif Calls Vicky Kaushal 'Adjusting' Over Bathroom Space</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Diljit Dosanjh wowed Mumbai with his concert, sharing a heartfelt moment of a toddler in ‘Main hoon Punjab’ attire. Meanwhile, Katrina Kaif praised Vicky Kaushal’s supportive and understanding nature." title="Diljit Dosanjh wowed Mumbai with his concert, sharing a heartfelt moment of a toddler in ‘Main hoon Punjab’ attire. Meanwhile, Katrina Kaif praised Vicky Kaushal’s supportive and understanding nature."><figcaption>Diljit Dosanjh wowed Mumbai with his concert, sharing a heartfelt moment of a toddler in ‘Main hoon Punjab’ attire.</figcaption></figure><p>Diljit Dosanjh set the stage on fire with his performance in Mumbai, sharing personal moments and calling attention to criticisms received from authorities regarding children attending his concerts.</p><ul><li>Diljit lit up the stage during the Dil-Luminati Tour.</li><li>A government advisory limited performance aspects for children's safety.</li><li>Katrina Kaif praised husband Vicky Kaushal for his supportive nature.</li></ul><blockquote>Katrina mentioned, "the secret to her gorgeous hair is her mother-in-law's homemade hair oil!"</blockquote><p>This concert showcased not just musical talent but also addressed the complexities of parenting and celebrity life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/diljit-shares-babys-photo-from-mumbai-show-katrina-calls-vicky-adjusting-9164282.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/diljit-shares-babys-photo-from-mumbai-show-katrina-calls-vicky-adjusting-9164282.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abhijeet Bhattacharya says Shah Rukh Khan has a different class while dismissing Salman Khan: 'Road par k - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Abhijeet Bhattacharya says Shah Rukh Khan has a different class while dismissing Salman Khan: 'Road par kutte ki tarah so rahe ho, to ek daarubaaz aayega, ek tharki...'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Not Provided]</p><p>In a recent statement, singer Abhijeet Bhattacharya made headlines by comparing Bollywood stars Shah Rukh Khan and Salman Khan, emphasizing the distinct class of Khan while dismissing his colleague Salman.</p><ul><li>Abhijeet highlights the stark differences between Shah Rukh Khan and Salman Khan.</li><li>He metaphorically criticized Salman by using a provocative analogy.</li><li>The comments have created a stir in media and fan circles.</li></ul><blockquote>“Road par kutte ki tarah so rahe ho, to ek daarubaaz aayega, ek tharki...”</blockquote><p>Abhijeet’s remarks reflect his personal views and have sparked discussions about the dynamics in Bollywood.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/abhijeet-bhattacharya-says-shah-rukh-khan-has-a-different-class-while-dismissing-salman-khan-road-par-kutte-ki-tarah-so-rahe-ho-to-ek-daarubaaz-aayega-ek-tharki-/articleshow/116543408.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/abhijeet-bhattacharya-says-shah-rukh-khan-has-a-different-class-while-dismissing-salman-khan-road-par-kutte-ki-tarah-so-rahe-ho-to-ek-daarubaaz-aayega-ek-tharki-/articleshow/116543408.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kareena Kapoor fans call out Pakistani actor Khaqan Shahnawaz for ‘age shaming’ after he jokes he can ‘play her son’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kareena Kapoor Fans Call Out Khaqan Shahnawaz for Age Shaming Remarks</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 21, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/Kareena_Kapoor_Khaqan_Shahnawaz_1734791141910_1734791153521.jpg" alt="Khaqan Shahnawaz's comment on Kareena Kapoor riled up her fans." title="Khaqan Shahnawaz's comment on Kareena Kapoor riled up her fans.">
<figcaption>Khaqan Shahnawaz's comment on Kareena Kapoor riled up her fans.</figcaption>
<p>Kareena Kapoor's fans expressed their outrage after Pakistani actor Khaqan Shahnawaz jokingly remarked that he could play her son, leading to a backlash on social media.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Khaqan made the comment during a TV show on Geo Urdu, after a fan suggested a collaboration.</li>
  <li>He humorously stated, "I can play her son. Kareena ji bohot badi hain." which fans found disrespectful.</li>
  <li>Fans criticized his attitude, with remarks indicating he was perceived as arrogant.</li>
  <li>Kareena has recently received acclaim for her performances in films like Jaane Jaan and Crew.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If age shaming had a face.”</blockquote>
<p>The Twitter and Instagram response from fans highlights a growing sensitivity towards age-related comments in the entertainment industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/kareena-kapoor-fans-call-out-pakistani-actor-khaqan-shahnawaz-for-age-shaming-after-he-jokes-he-can-play-her-son-101734790917419.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/kareena-kapoor-fans-call-out-pakistani-actor-khaqan-shahnawaz-for-age-shaming-after-he-jokes-he-can-play-her-son-101734790917419.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:08:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shark Tank's Namita Thapar And Anupam Mittal Clash Over 70-Hour Workweek Debate - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNZnpQRV9kZ0xLMFRHNGg3RnljU2JEdC12Z0pORkM1cVBlMGF4V3dmS3llY29mLXFBeU0zbnAtbFlvWmRwUGYyZEdOQTA2MTNmYzFOUjA1UzIyTFU5aDNKNkpEb1FDUmFCVW85THIzSlg4eUdnN1RhSXFVMXhNQXJYeGs5c20yWGxOZFRvbHhfUkJSemVtNkdQMzBraEFLZmwwblp3Y28weGsydHRyQko3QXcwOV9Vd9IBvgFBVV95cUxOWmx6T3FSQjhIMm9vbFQtR0NTT1lpTnlfcUVwQUdCS0w5RU02U3lrV0kwU3BPNXJWbmxKMmp5dklfV2dEMmF0Nml5RHRQbFlXU3FaZmtQU0NCYzhnYnJhVnp0RTBZbGpoS0tFNzMwYTVqSGpnal9vMmNTV3llSkJZa0pKRWlxSjBYZGhfM0szckhPNEFtVUZKcGxyOTZaN24wRF9tTG9yU2NNMHY4bTlVOHphUjlSc3BydHZEaUFB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNZnpQRV9kZ0xLMFRHNGg3RnljU2JEdC12Z0pORkM1cVBlMGF4V3dmS3llY29mLXFBeU0zbnAtbFlvWmRwUGYyZEdOQTA2MTNmYzFOUjA1UzIyTFU5aDNKNkpEb1FDUmFCVW85THIzSlg4eUdnN1RhSXFVMXhNQXJYeGs5c20yWGxOZFRvbHhfUkJSemVtNkdQMzBraEFLZmwwblp3Y28weGsydHRyQko3QXcwOV9Vd9IBvgFBVV95cUxOWmx6T3FSQjhIMm9vbFQtR0NTT1lpTnlfcUVwQUdCS0w5RU02U3lrV0kwU3BPNXJWbmxKMmp5dklfV2dEMmF0Nml5RHRQbFlXU3FaZmtQU0NCYzhnYnJhVnp0RTBZbGpoS0tFNzMwYTVqSGpnal9vMmNTV3llSkJZa0pKRWlxSjBYZGhfM0szckhPNEFtVUZKcGxyOTZaN24wRF9tTG9yU2NNMHY4bTlVOHphUjlSc3BydHZEaUFB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:06:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Attempt at character assassination, says Allu Arjun after Telangana Assembly discusses Pushpa 2 stampede - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Hyderabad/attempt-at-character-assassination-says-allu-arjun-after-telangana-assembly-discusses-pushpa-2-stampede/article69013372.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Hyderabad/attempt-at-character-assassination-says-allu-arjun-after-telangana-assembly-discusses-pushpa-2-stampede/article69013372.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Digvijay Rathee's unexpected eviction in Bigg Boss 18 to Sambhavna Seth suffering miscarriage in first trimester; Top TV news of the week - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>From Digvijay Rathee's unexpected eviction in Bigg Boss 18 to Sambhavna Seth suffering miscarriage in first trimester; Top TV news of the week</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Delhi Times</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/imgsize-1227946,msid-116542556,width-600,height-335,resizemode-75/116542556.jpg" alt="Top TV news of the week image" />
<figcaption>Highlights from the week in television news.</figcaption>
<p>The past week has been extremely eventful, with both happy and sad news for fans. Notable highlights include Digvijay Rathee's eviction from Bigg Boss and Sambhavna Seth's miscarriage.</p>
<ul>
<li>Digvijay Rathee was evicted from Bigg Boss 18 after being nominated by fellow contestants.</li>
<li>Sambhavna Seth and husband Avinash Dwivedi revealed they suffered a miscarriage in their first trimester.</li>
<li>Laughter Chefs returned for its second season with new and old celebrities.</li>
<li>Alisha Parveen was replaced in Anupamaa, expressing shock and disappointment.</li>
<li>Pankit Thakker finalized his divorce after a long separation from his wife.</li>
<li>Controversy arose between Eijaz Khan and Pavitra Punia regarding their relationship.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“For a long time, we have been facing this, and it has happened again…” - Avinash Dwivedi on their miscarriage experience.</blockquote>
<p>This week's television news encapsulates the mixture of joy and sorrow that often characterizes the entertainment industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/from-digvijay-rathees-unexpected-eviction-in-bigg-boss-18-to-sambhavna-seth-suffering-miscarriage-in-first-trimester-top-tv-news-of-the-week/photostory/116542191.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/from-digvijay-rathees-unexpected-eviction-in-bigg-boss-18-to-sambhavna-seth-suffering-miscarriage-in-first-trimester-top-tv-news-of-the-week/photostory/116542191.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mufasa: The Lion King Box Office Collection Day 2 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxQaG9BV2lNYkM0QTNSQ0hkRGVuWGNjVmMybzJNQUsydzdnck9FTTlZSUJ1ck03NVBHdjhhbGNWbmh4T05HX1FIdW4yN1FvdlBNcDhILTY0UHNpX1hwdFRaanVnWGRXcllqSlpNNE1kQ3VwM2ZzcnRfVmx6eXI1bmduQWxXVnA4Ml9YNnZ3RGxNU2M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxQaG9BV2lNYkM0QTNSQ0hkRGVuWGNjVmMybzJNQUsydzdnck9FTTlZSUJ1ck03NVBHdjhhbGNWbmh4T05HX1FIdW4yN1FvdlBNcDhILTY0UHNpX1hwdFRaanVnWGRXcllqSlpNNE1kQ3VwM2ZzcnRfVmx6eXI1bmduQWxXVnA4Ml9YNnZ3RGxNU2M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blake Lively sues Justin Baldoni for sexual harassment, his team denies accusation: ‘Desperate attempt to fix her negative reputation’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Blake Lively Sues Justin Baldoni for Sexual Harassment, His Team Denies Accusation</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Saturday, [Date not specified] &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/blake-lively-justin-baldoni-1.png?w=640" alt="Blake Lively and Justin Baldoni" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Blake Lively and Justin Baldoni appeared together in It Ends With Us.</figcaption>
<p>Blake Lively has filed a lawsuit against Justin Baldoni, the director of It Ends With Us, for allegations of sexual harassment, claiming emotional distress caused to her family.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Lively alleges Baldoni attempted to mount a smear campaign against her.</li>
  <li>Reported demands included restrictions on discussions about nudity and personal topics.</li>
  <li>Baldoni's team has denied these allegations as false and a desperate attempt to rehabilitate Lively's image.</li>
  <li>The lawsuit includes accusations of social manipulation by Baldoni.</li>
  <li>Lively's husband, Ryan Reynolds, was allegedly involved in discussions regarding the claims during production.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It is shameful that Ms Lively and her representatives would make such serious and categorically false accusations against Mr. Baldoni...”</blockquote>
<p>In summary, the legal battle highlights tensions from the film's production and exposes allegations of misconduct and reputational damage within Hollywood.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/hollywood/blake-lively-sues-justin-baldoni-for-sexual-harassment-his-team-denies-accusation-9738029/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/hollywood/blake-lively-sues-justin-baldoni-for-sexual-harassment-his-team-denies-accusation-9738029/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 14:50:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 box office day 17 early report: Allu Arjun-starrer just Rs 10 cr away from crossing Baahubali 2’s domestic record, inches away from Rs 1030 cr - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Day 17 Early Report</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Pushpa-2-18.jpg?w=640" alt="Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2's day 16 box office early report" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Actor Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2 is all set to cross Rs 1000 crore mark.</figcaption>
<p>Pushpa 2’s magic continues as it nears the Rs 1000 crore mark, breaking box office records daily and becoming the most successful film of 2024.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film has crossed Rs 1020 crore domestically as of day 17.</li>
  <li>After a slight drop in the second week, box office figures are rebounding as the weekend approaches.</li>
  <li>Pushpa 2 is expected to surpass Rs 1050 crore by the end of its third weekend.</li>
  <li>The film is just Rs 10 crore shy of Baahubali 2’s record of Rs 1030.42 crore in India.</li>
  <li>Occupancy rates on Day 17 were 29.97% for Telugu and 23.6% for Hindi screenings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Pushpa 2 will likely cross the Baahubali 2 record soon, with major upcoming films releasing later this month."</blockquote>
<p>Pushpa 2 shows strong box office potential heading into the holiday season, facing new releases that could challenge its success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/pushpa-2-box-office-day-17-early-report-allu-arjun-starrer-rs-10-crore-away-from-baahubali-2-eyes-1030-crore-9736271/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/pushpa-2-box-office-day-17-early-report-allu-arjun-starrer-rs-10-crore-away-from-baahubali-2-eyes-1030-crore-9736271/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 14:15:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bhavika Sharma-Hitesh Bharadwaj's Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin headed for another generation leap: REPORTS - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin Set for Another Generation Leap</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Saturday, December 21, 2024 at 1:56 PM</p><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/8822-bhavika-sharma-hitesh-bharadwajs-ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-headed-for-another-generation-leap-rep.jpg" width="640" height="360" alt="Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin Image"><figcaption>Bhavika Sharma-Hitesh Bharadwaj's Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin is headed for another generation leap.</figcaption><p>The show Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin, starring Bhavika Sharma and Hitesh Bharadwaj, is reportedly going for another generation leap, leading to the departure of the entire cast.</p><ul><li>Recent reports indicate the show is seeing a drop in viewership ratings.</li><li>Fans are divided, with some believing the plot is reminiscent of other shows while others enjoy the current storyline.</li><li>Official confirmation of the changes is still pending.</li><li>The show has managed to stay within the top 5 rankings despite the fluctuations in ratings.</li></ul><blockquote>This decision by the makers of the show could have triggered after the show's falling numbers from the past few weeks.</blockquote><p>As the show prepares for another evolution, its history of changes has kept it evolving over time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/bhavika-sharma-hitesh-bharadwajs-ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-headed-for-another-generation-leap-rep_215740</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/bhavika-sharma-hitesh-bharadwajs-ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-headed-for-another-generation-leap-rep_215740</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 14:00:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Radhika Merchant Shines in a Chic Loro Piana Co-Ord Set At Dhirubhai Ambani School Annual Day - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Radhika Merchant Shines in a Chic Loro Piana Co-Ord Set At Dhirubhai Ambani School Annual Day</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Radhika donned a chambray blue co-ord set from the luxury Italian brand Loro Piana, combining understated charm with high-end fashion.">
<figcaption>Radhika donned a chambray blue co-ord set from the luxury Italian brand Loro Piana, combining understated charm with high-end fashion.</figcaption>
<p>Radhika Merchant made a stylish appearance at the Dhirubhai Ambani International School’s annual day celebration, showcasing a blend of luxury and casual elegance.</p>
<ul>
<li>She wore a chambray blue co-ord set from Loro Piana including a button-down shirt priced at ₹1,32,556 and matching trousers priced at ₹1,22,406.</li>
<li>Accessories included an Hermès belt, Bolide crossbody bag, and Himalaya Niloticus Crocodile Oran sandals, completing her chic look.</li>
<li>The event featured a star-studded guest list with notable personalities like Shah Rukh Khan, Aishwarya Rai Bachchan, and others.</li>
<li>Radhika's minimal yet radiant beauty choices complemented her outfit, showcasing her elegant style.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"With her effortlessly chic co-ord set, Radhika showcased how to perfectly blend casual elegance with luxury."</blockquote>
<p>This event not only highlighted Radhika Merchant's fashion sense but also celebrated a grand gathering of the Ambani family and Bollywood stars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/radhika-merchant-shines-in-a-chic-loro-piana-co-ord-set-at-dhirubhai-ambani-school-annual-day-9163909.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/radhika-merchant-shines-in-a-chic-loro-piana-co-ord-set-at-dhirubhai-ambani-school-annual-day-9163909.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 13:42:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Simha-Raaga wedding: SS Rajamouli thanks some key people - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Simha-Raaga wedding: SS Rajamouli thanks some key people</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 21, 2024 7:03 pm IST</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Rajamouli.jpg" alt="SS Rajamouli" width="550" height="367"><figcaption>SS Rajamouli at a wedding event.</figcaption><p>Oscar-winning composer MM Keeravani’s son, Simha Koduri, recently married Raaga Maganti in a lavish destination wedding in Ras Al Khaimah, UAE. SS Rajamouli, known for his impactful storytelling, shared his gratitude towards those involved in making the wedding memorable.</p><ul><li>Simha Koduri, son of composer MM Keeravani, tied the knot with Raaga Maganti.</li><li>The wedding took place in Ras Al Khaimah, UAE, attended by family and friends.</li><li>Rajamouli praised the hospitality teams and event management for their efforts.</li><li>He acknowledged contributions from venues and decor teams that enhanced the celebration.</li></ul><blockquote>“The last 10 days were filled with lots of lovely moments during the Simha Raaga wedding. I would like to acknowledge the people who truly made it memorable for all of us in the family,” wrote Rajamouli.</blockquote><p>This wedding not only celebrated love but also highlighted the collaboration and effort made by many in the film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/simha-raaga-wedding-ss-rajamouli-thanks-some-key-people.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/simha-raaga-wedding-ss-rajamouli-thanks-some-key-people.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 13:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rashmika Mandanna thought she was ‘dancing on Allu Arjun’ after she watched Peelings rehearsal video: ‘I thought what is going on?’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rashmika Mandanna Surprised by Dance Rehearsal for 'Peelings'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date & Source:</strong> December 2024, Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Rashmika-Mandanna-3.jpg?w=640" alt="Rashmika Mandanna" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Rashmika Mandanna talks about shooting for the song Peelings. (Photo: T-Series/YouTube)</figcaption><p>In her latest interview, Rashmika Mandanna reflects on her experiences during the shoot of the controversial song 'Peelings' from the blockbuster film Pushpa 2, sharing her surprise at the dance choreography.</p><ul><li>The song has faced criticism for its suggestive dance steps.</li><li>Rashmika expressed shock after watching the rehearsal video.</li><li>She discussed overcoming her fear of being lifted during dancing.</li><li>The film has crossed ₹1500 crore globally.</li></ul><blockquote>“The second we saw the rehearsal video, I was like, ‘What in the world is going on?’” - Rashmika Mandanna</blockquote><p>Rashmika emphasized the importance of challenging herself with diverse roles without succumbing to typecasting.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/rashmika-mandanna-was-dancing-on-allu-arjun-after-she-watched-peelings-rehearsal-video-9737929/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/rashmika-mandanna-was-dancing-on-allu-arjun-after-she-watched-peelings-rehearsal-video-9737929/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 13:27:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>