<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:17:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:17:32 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sky Force Trailer OUT: Akshay Kumar and Veer Pahariya aim for the sky: video inside - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sky Force Trailer OUT: Akshay Kumar and Veer Pahariya aim for the sky: video inside</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>The much-anticipated trailer for 'Sky Force' featuring Akshay Kumar and Veer Pahariya has been released, showcasing their ambition and determination.</p><ul><li>The trailer highlights thrilling aerial stunts and high-stakes action scenes.</li><li>Akshay Kumar expresses excitement about his role in an interview.</li><li>Veer Pahariya marks his debut in a significant role alongside an established star.</li></ul><blockquote>“We aimed to create an exhilarating experience for the audience,” said Akshay Kumar during the trailer launch.</blockquote><p>This trailer is expected to generate significant buzz and engagement ahead of the film's release, promising a blend of action and drama.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sky-force-trailer-out-akshay-kumar-and-veer-pahariya-aim-for-the-sky-video-inside/articleshow/116959652.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sky-force-trailer-out-akshay-kumar-and-veer-pahariya-aim-for-the-sky-video-inside/articleshow/116959652.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 05:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Massive Pre-Business for Sankranthiki Vastunnam - TrackTollywood]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Massive Pre-Business for Sankranthiki Vastunnam</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Track Tollywood</p>
<p>Sankranthiki Vastunnam has made significant pre-business strides ahead of its release. Directed by Anil Ravipudi and starring Victory Venkatesh, the film competes with other major releases this Sankranthi.</p>
<img src='link_to_image_if_available' alt='Sankranthiki Vastunnam poster'>
<figcaption>Sankranthiki Vastunnam promotional poster</figcaption>
<ul>
  <li>The film is directed by Anil Ravipudi, known for previous successes.</li>
  <li>It is up against major films: Game Changer and Daaku Maharaaj.</li>
  <li>The worldwide theatrical business is projected to reach 55Cr.</li>
  <li>Positive word of mouth is expected to boost its box office performance.</li>
  <li>The trailer is set to be released on January 6th.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This is a very good business for the film, and also it will be easily achievable if it gets positive word of mouth."</blockquote>
<p>The strong promotional efforts and the established brand value of the cast and crew suggest that Sankranthiki Vastunnam is poised for a successful box office run amidst stiff competition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tracktollywood.com/massive-pre-business-for-sankranthiki-vastunnam/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tracktollywood.com/massive-pre-business-for-sankranthiki-vastunnam/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:27:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daaku Maharaaj trailer: After Suriya in Kanguva, Bobby Deol locks horns with Nandamuri Balakrishna in Telugu debut - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daaku Maharaaj trailer: Nandamuri Balakrishna is the dacoit who is hailed as 'Daaku Maharaaj'. He is also seen having a close relationship with a child.</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/Daaku_Maharaaj_trailer_1736050396588_1736050405204.png' alt='Daaku Maharaaj trailer: Nandamuri Balakrishna plays a dacoit.' title='Daaku Maharaaj trailer: Nandamuri Balakrishna plays a dacoit.' /><figcaption>Daaku Maharaaj trailer: Nandamuri Balakrishna plays a dacoit.</figcaption><p>The trailer of <em>Daaku Maharaaj</em>, featuring Nandamuri Balakrishna, was released on Sunday, showcasing action and drama with Balakrishna in the lead role.</p><ul><li>Nandamuri Balakrishna plays the titular role of a dacoit known as 'Daaku Maharaaj'.</li><li>Bobby Deol portrays the antagonist, causing turmoil for the characters.</li><li>The film also stars Urvashi Rautela and features intense action scenes.</li><li>The trailer reveals a close bond between Balakrishna's character and a child.</li><li>The movie is set to release on January 12.</li></ul><blockquote>“KING of the Jungle Begins it HUNT!! #DaakuMaharaaj is set to unleash the MASS MADNESS at theatres this Sankranthi!” - Naga Vamsi, producer.</blockquote><p>Fans have reacted positively to the trailer, expressing excitement for its release and praising Balakrishna's portrayal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/daaku-maharaaj-trailer-bobby-deol-locks-horns-with-nandamuri-balakrishna-in-telugu-debut-watch-101736047736288.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/daaku-maharaaj-trailer-bobby-deol-locks-horns-with-nandamuri-balakrishna-in-telugu-debut-watch-101736047736288.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:21:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coldplay faces a legal notice ahead of their Ahmedabad concert: ‘Cannot use children in any form on the s - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Coldplay faces a legal notice ahead of their Ahmedabad concert: ‘Cannot use children in any form on the stage’</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [insert date] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>Coldplay has been issued a legal notice ahead of their concert in Ahmedabad, stipulating that the band cannot use children in any capacity on stage during their performance. This directive arises amid concerns regarding the safety and ethical implications of child participation in the event.</p>
<ul>
<li>The notice emphasizes the absolute prohibition of children on stage.</li>
<li>Concerns about the responsibilities of event organizers regarding child welfare.</li>
<li>Coldplay is known for its high-energy performances, raising questions about the potential risks for young participants.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The safety and well-being of children must be the foremost priority during live performances,” said [insert relevant authority].</blockquote>
<p>This legal action exemplifies the ongoing discussions surrounding child safety in entertainment venues and may influence future concert policies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/english/music/news/coldplay-faces-a-legal-notice-ahead-of-their-ahmedabad-concert-cannot-use-children-in-any-form-on-the-stage/articleshow/116939691.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/english/music/news/coldplay-faces-a-legal-notice-ahead-of-their-ahmedabad-concert-cannot-use-children-in-any-form-on-the-stage/articleshow/116939691.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daaku Maharaaj Trailer: Action and emotion in perfect harmony - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daaku Maharaaj Trailer: Action and Emotion in Perfect Harmony</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 5, 2025 8:54 am IST</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Daaku-maharaaj.jpg" alt="Daaku Maharaaj Trailer Image" width="550" height="309"><figcaption>Daaku Maharaaj Trailer</figcaption><p>Daaku Maharaaj, directed by Bobby Kolli and starring Nandamuri Balakrishna, is gearing up for a grand Sankranthi release. This action-packed emotional drama has already captured attention with its high-octane trailer, unveiled during a pre-release event held in Dallas, USA.</p><ul><li>The trailer builds suspense by keeping the storyline shrouded in mystery.</li><li>Balakrishna delivers a restrained yet commanding performance with minimal but impactful dialogues.</li><li>The film's emotional depth, particularly the child sentiment, is a standout element.</li><li>Thaman’s background score enhances the trailer’s impact amidst stunning visuals.</li><li>The film stars Shraddha Srinath and Pragya Jaiswal in substantial roles, alongside Balakrishna.</li><li>Bobby Deol plays a ruthless animal smuggler, adding an edge to the narrative.</li><li>Daaku Maharaaj is set to release on January 12, 2025.</li></ul><p>With its intriguing trailer and star-studded cast, the film has already raised expectations to new heights. Stay tuned for more updates on this exciting project.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/daaku-maharaaj-trailer-action-and-emotion-in-perfect-harmony.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/daaku-maharaaj-trailer-action-and-emotion-in-perfect-harmony.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 03:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Don't Use...": Coldplay Issued Notice Ahead Of Ahmedabad Concert - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Don't Use...: Coldplay Issued Notice Ahead Of Ahmedabad Concert</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>The District Child Protection Unit in Ahmedabad has issued a notice to Coldplay, instructing them not to involve children in their concert on January 25-26 at the Narendra Modi Stadium due to health concerns regarding high sound levels.</p><ul><li>The concert is set to take place at the Narendra Modi Stadium in Ahmedabad.</li><li>The notice prohibits children from being on stage and mandates ear protection for those attending.</li><li>Sound levels over 120 decibels are deemed hazardous to children's health.</li><li>A complaint by Pandit Rao Dharnevar initiated the notice, focusing on protecting children from harmful environments.</li><li>Dharnevar has previously raised concerns regarding other concerts, advocating for children's rights.</li></ul><blockquote>“Involving children in concerts featuring loud sounds can harm their physical health and mental development.” - Pandit Rao Dharnevar</blockquote><p>This notice reflects increasing awareness and action towards safeguarding children's rights in entertainment contexts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/coldplay-chris-martin-issued-notice-ahead-of-ahmedabad-concert-dont-use-7402564</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/coldplay-chris-martin-issued-notice-ahead-of-ahmedabad-concert-dont-use-7402564</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 03:21:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arjun Kapoor makes a rare mention of late stepmother Sridevi, calls her ‘ma’am’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arjun Kapoor Reflects on Late Stepmother Sridevi in Rare Mention</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/MixCollage-05-Jan-2025-08-19-AM-1592_1736045367747_1736045403965.jpg" alt="Arjun Kapoor makes a rare mention of stepmother Sridevi." title="Arjun Kapoor makes a rare mention of stepmother Sridevi.">
<figcaption>Arjun Kapoor makes a rare mention of stepmother Sridevi.</figcaption>
<p>In a recent interview, Bollywood actor Arjun Kapoor made a rare mention of his late stepmother, legendary actress Sridevi, discussing her in the context of a film set where they both shared a significant connection.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Arjun referenced Sridevi while discussing the film 'Roop Ki Rani Choron Ka Raja'.</li>
  <li>The film was produced by his father Boney Kapoor and featured Sridevi alongside Anil Kapoor.</li>
  <li>Sridevi was dating Boney Kapoor during the film's production while he was still married to Arjun's mother, Mona Kapoor.</li>
  <li>Arjun expressed a protective feeling towards his stepsisters after Sridevi's tragic passing in 2018.</li>
  <li>His upcoming film 'Mere Husband Ki Biwi' is set for release on February 21.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“My entire life with my father was being on Roop Ki Rani Choron Ka Raja set... Even by today’s standards, it is one of the biggest films we ever made.” - Arjun Kapoor</blockquote>
<p>This mention highlights Arjun's deep connection to his family and the impact of Sridevi's presence in his life, despite her early passing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/arjun-kapoor-rare-mention-of-late-stepmother-sridevi-calls-her-madam-boney-kapoor-101736045122900.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/arjun-kapoor-rare-mention-of-late-stepmother-sridevi-calls-her-madam-boney-kapoor-101736045122900.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 03:21:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who was Jeff Baena? Aubrey Plaza's husband found dead at LA home - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jeff Baena, Filmmaker and Husband of Aubrey Plaza, Found Dead at 47</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/Jeff_Baena_1736046368801_1736046369059.jpg" alt="Jeff Baena is survived by Audrey Plaza, his parents, stepparents and stepsiblings.(Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP)" title="Jeff Baena is survived by Audrey Plaza, his parents, stepparents and stepsiblings.(Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP)"><figcaption>Jeff Baena is survived by Audrey Plaza, his parents, stepparents and stepsiblings.(Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP)</figcaption><p>Filmmaker Jeff Baena, known for his works including Life After Beth and Joshy, was found dead in a Los Angeles residence at the age of 47. The cause of death is currently under investigation.</p><ul><li>Baena directed notable films such as Life After Beth, Joshy, and The Little Hours.</li><li>He was married to actress Aubrey Plaza, who starred in many of his films.</li><li>Baena expressed his passion for cinema was influenced by films like A Clockwork Orange and 8 1/2.</li><li>His family includes his wife Aubrey, mother Barbara, father Scott, and stepfamily.</li></ul><blockquote>“The opportunities to create together, to do something creative where we’re both fulfilled, it’s like how rare is that?” - Jeff Baena</blockquote><p>Baena's death has raised questions about mental health and the pressures faced by those in the entertainment industry. His contributions to cinema will be remembered.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/who-was-jeff-baena-aubrey-plaza-husband-found-dead-life-after-beth-joshy-director-101736044098753.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/who-was-jeff-baena-aubrey-plaza-husband-found-dead-life-after-beth-joshy-director-101736044098753.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 03:19:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nara Brahmani Rejected Mani Ratnam’s Movie Offer - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nara Brahmani Rejected Mani Ratnam’s Movie Offer</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> M9 News</p>
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/nara-brahmani-rejected-mani-ratnam-movie-offer-768x576.jpg" alt="Nara Brahmani" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Nara Brahmani has a secret fan following online.</figcaption>
<p>Nara Brahmani, daughter of Nandamuri Balakrishna, recently made headlines after it was revealed that she humorously rejected a movie offer from renowned director Mani Ratnam.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nara Brahmani and her sister Tejeswini prefer to stay out of the limelight.</li>
  <li>Balakrishna disclosed the rejection during his show, highlighting Brahmani's charm.</li>
  <li>Brahmani expressed her disinterest in acting by saying, “I’m not a heroine face.”</li>
  <li>Brahmani is characterized as straightforward, contrasting with her more diplomatic younger sister.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I’m not a heroine face.” - Nara Brahmani</blockquote>
<p>This revelation adds to the intrigue surrounding Nara Brahmani, who remains a distinctive figure in the public eye despite her low profile.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.m9.news/movienews/nara-brahmani-rejected-mani-ratnams-movie-offer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.m9.news/movienews/nara-brahmani-rejected-mani-ratnams-movie-offer/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 03:11:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When Aubrey Plaza said isolating with husband Jeff Baena in pandemic ‘could have gone either way’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aubrey Plaza Reflects on Time Spent with Late Husband Jeff Baena During Pandemic</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/jeff_aubrey_1736042604955_1736042620168.jpg" alt="Jeff Baena, husband of Aubrey Plaza, dies." title="Jeff Baena, husband of Aubrey Plaza, dies."><figcaption>Jeff Baena, husband of Aubrey Plaza, dies.</figcaption></figure><p>Aubrey Plaza and her husband Jeff Baena spent the pandemic together, reflecting on their relationship and creative endeavors.</p><ul><li>Jeff Baena, filmmaker known for his work with Aubrey Plaza, was found dead at 47 in Los Angeles.</li><li>Aubrey shared insights into isolating with Jeff during the pandemic, noting their collaborative work.</li><li>She described the experience as both enjoyable yet challenging, stating it 'could have gone either way.'</li><li>The couple worked on multiple projects together, including Plaza's directorial debut.</li></ul><blockquote>“Could have gone either way, I guess,” Aubrey Plaza on isolating with Jeff Baena during the pandemic.</blockquote><p>This personal reflection highlights the depth of their relationship, even amidst hardship and loss.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/when-aubrey-plaza-said-isolating-with-husband-jeff-baena-in-pandemic-could-have-gone-either-way-101736042279294.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/when-aubrey-plaza-said-isolating-with-husband-jeff-baena-in-pandemic-could-have-gone-either-way-101736042279294.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 02:30:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["When The Phone Rings" Ends On Highest Ratings Of Its Run As "When The Stars Gossip" Premieres - soompi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>When The Phone Rings Ends On Highest Ratings Of Its Run As When The Stars Gossip Premieres</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 4</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Soompi</p>
<img src="https://0.soompi.io/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/01171129/soompi-jan-namib.png" alt="" width="610" height="130">
<figcaption>Promotional image for the dramas featured.</figcaption>
<p>MBC’s “When the Phone Rings” concluded its series with significant ratings, achieving a personal record for viewership. Meanwhile, new dramas are also making headlines with their premieres and competition in the ratings.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The finale of “When the Phone Rings” scored an average nationwide rating of 8.6 percent.</li>
  <li>JTBC's “The Tale of Lady Ok” reached a new high with 10.3 percent ratings.</li>
  <li>tvN’s “When the Stars Gossip” premiered with a 3.3 percent rating, winning its time slot.</li>
  <li>SBS’s “Love Scout” increased its viewership to 6.5 percent in its second episode.</li>
  <li>KBS 2TV’s “Iron Family” continues to lead with 17.4 percent ratings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When the Phone Rings” wrapped up on a new personal record!</blockquote>
<p>In summary, the competitive landscape of Korean dramas continues to shift with significant viewership overlaps and new series captures audience attention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.soompi.com/article/1713859wpp/when-the-phone-rings-ends-on-highest-ratings-of-its-run-as-when-the-stars-gossip-premieres</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.soompi.com/article/1713859wpp/when-the-phone-rings-ends-on-highest-ratings-of-its-run-as-when-the-stars-gossip-premieres</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 02:11:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Rajat Dalal cries inconsolably in front of his mother as he talks about his jail term; says - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AJBVV95cUxQZHNhZnBjbDNycHI5RlpGZXN0cjhfT0J4VTFaZG41VXpYbmZZdGQya2hIVGs2SGRGRnhCNEhXZDdadzNCblJTSHR0dGFOWjF5QnRTSTBvVzhHY3FlUlRWQjJ1NzlQeFVpMTRjNVlYTS14UFlzaHg5eVMwQlRWQktmR0RJTG1HQW11Ty1VS2MzXzg0VFhkalA0UEtXWXlRY2lmemlmY2tuZms0dHhGUEtPMmd1Wi1tdE0xc2s4U2p0aS1iY0xvVG4tZVFvVVlSWDRjNlp3cTE2Yl90YmwweDlFMXJ3ZDhIZ1ZvNnRJdEpNdDNpVVJMbVZpR3Z4bThSc1JBZXljSUV1b3JnRXJMQzJra3hoUGZpa2ZDNVM0QjkwdW9NekdIUnpROWl3aTJ3VVV5U1lzSWRzdVhpUkc0WVFpWHRuQzd2aGVaY1MwLWlCU09DeGZ1ZlYyVWNRRy1PaTRm0gHmAkFVX3lxTE5WSDByYXZOc3lGdG44QjRYa0NxaDNzTzd2aFdXcWxkb29aMVYwV1QtdENsSlFHREo1aGdVS3NzQWNpQ3V3NlVhNzZPV0JlOXpUcm9ZNHVxMHNRWkMxNjVicUdXWi1Vbmo0OWVaUDFGc3c5VTVhbUZUS2RFRXlJX2NsbGloX01rUEUxMDVUVTU1dXg4N0FFUG5hNTM3WEVjNG1KQ25rMkxYTUdhby1xcHY2TjBTaWVTRlZ3MS1UdG5zTlJLQlY1ZEtGa0dzTWdybXFxdHYwbUhvNElMWUd1NFZHTHdZUjFZV2tzTFpRSG0zeF9UZFpZS0x2dk8zRlNoZEdyX3RjREdad1VvVDFvaTlGMkt1QTlaWXdjU0c3MHFCdGo1ZWpQb3QzUGZJVEZfNVRnX3hPdmQ4bnloSkdpNmlNTTlRRVNTeDhvdHp1UFp4NnhzNkM4M0tjaF9UQ1NGU3VCdkp3Umc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AJBVV95cUxQZHNhZnBjbDNycHI5RlpGZXN0cjhfT0J4VTFaZG41VXpYbmZZdGQya2hIVGs2SGRGRnhCNEhXZDdadzNCblJTSHR0dGFOWjF5QnRTSTBvVzhHY3FlUlRWQjJ1NzlQeFVpMTRjNVlYTS14UFlzaHg5eVMwQlRWQktmR0RJTG1HQW11Ty1VS2MzXzg0VFhkalA0UEtXWXlRY2lmemlmY2tuZms0dHhGUEtPMmd1Wi1tdE0xc2s4U2p0aS1iY0xvVG4tZVFvVVlSWDRjNlp3cTE2Yl90YmwweDlFMXJ3ZDhIZ1ZvNnRJdEpNdDNpVVJMbVZpR3Z4bThSc1JBZXljSUV1b3JnRXJMQzJra3hoUGZpa2ZDNVM0QjkwdW9NekdIUnpROWl3aTJ3VVV5U1lzSWRzdVhpUkc0WVFpWHRuQzd2aGVaY1MwLWlCU09DeGZ1ZlYyVWNRRy1PaTRm0gHmAkFVX3lxTE5WSDByYXZOc3lGdG44QjRYa0NxaDNzTzd2aFdXcWxkb29aMVYwV1QtdENsSlFHREo1aGdVS3NzQWNpQ3V3NlVhNzZPV0JlOXpUcm9ZNHVxMHNRWkMxNjVicUdXWi1Vbmo0OWVaUDFGc3c5VTVhbUZUS2RFRXlJX2NsbGloX01rUEUxMDVUVTU1dXg4N0FFUG5hNTM3WEVjNG1KQ25rMkxYTUdhby1xcHY2TjBTaWVTRlZ3MS1UdG5zTlJLQlY1ZEtGa0dzTWdybXFxdHYwbUhvNElMWUd1NFZHTHdZUjFZV2tzTFpRSG0zeF9UZFpZS0x2dk8zRlNoZEdyX3RjREdad1VvVDFvaTlGMkt1QTlaWXdjU0c3MHFCdGo1ZWpQb3QzUGZJVEZfNVRnX3hPdmQ4bnloSkdpNmlNTTlRRVNTeDhvdHp1UFp4NnhzNkM4M0tjaF9UQ1NGU3VCdkp3Umc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer team surprises fans with three new songs - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Team Surprises Fans with Three New Songs</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 5, 2025 7:00 am IST</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/gamechanger-1.jpg" alt="Game Changer" width="550" height="367"><figcaption>Promotional image for Game Changer.</figcaption><p>The pre-release event of Game Changer has generated significant excitement with three unexpected new songs released by the team. The film stars Ram Charan and is set for a theatrical release soon.</p><ul><li>The team released seven songs in total, including three surprise tracks.</li><li>Ram Charan and Anjali's song “Arugu Meeda” has generated particular fan interest.</li><li>The film will release on January 10, 2025.</li><li>Full promotional activities are planned before the release.</li></ul><blockquote>"The pre-release event was a sensational success, further amplifying expectations."</blockquote><p>This surprise release has heightened anticipation for the film, which is expected to make a strong impact during the Sankranthi season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/game-changer-team-surprises-fans-with-three-new-songs.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/game-changer-team-surprises-fans-with-three-new-songs.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly horoscope from January 5 to January 11: Your luck for this week; see which signs have lady luck smiling for them - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope from January 5 to January 11</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Ayush Bisht</p><p>Discover your luck for the week as we explore the astrological insights for each zodiac sign from Aries to Pisces.</p><ul><li><strong>Aries:</strong> Focus on resilience despite challenges; patience is advised in financial matters.</li><li><strong>Taurus:</strong> Embrace new ideas and strategies, but be cautious of irritability.</li><li><strong>Gemini:</strong> Balance your financial focus and nurture family ties.</li><li><strong>Cancer:</strong> Work on control of tasks and relationships; be cautious with spending.</li><li><strong>Leo:</strong> Overcome fears to make important decisions; embrace new experiences.</li><li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Let go of grudges and seek enriching experiences; health improves.</li><li><strong>Libra:</strong> Embrace change and work on emotional connections; control expenses.</li><li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Make decisive choices; manage financial security wisely.</li><li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> Celebrate achievements and consider volunteer work; health improves.</li><li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Practice compassion with difficult people; avoid major financial decisions.</li><li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Re-evaluate your plans and maintain balance in relationships; financial surprises may arise.</li><li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Celebrate hard-earned successes and manage spending thoughtfully.</li></ul><p>Published By: Ayush Bisht</p><p>Published On: January 5, 2025</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/horoscopes/story/weekly-horoscope-from-january-5-to-january-11-your-luck-for-this-week-which-signs-have-lady-luck-smiling-2659789-2025-01-05</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/horoscopes/story/weekly-horoscope-from-january-5-to-january-11-your-luck-for-this-week-which-signs-have-lady-luck-smiling-2659789-2025-01-05</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 01:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' box office collection day 31: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna starrer picks pace on its fifth - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Pushpa 2' Box Office Collection Day 31</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>The film 'Pushpa 2', starring Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna, continues to perform well at the box office, generating Rs. 5.5 crore on its fifth Saturday. In contrast, Varun Dhawan’s film 'Baby John' struggles to reach Rs. 1 crore.</p><ul><li>'Pushpa 2' shows an upward trend in box office revenue.</li><li>It collected Rs. 5.5 crore on its 31st day of release.</li><li>'Baby John' is facing challenges at the box office with earnings below Rs. 1 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“'Pushpa 2' is proving to be a blockbuster while 'Baby John' fails to attract audiences.”</blockquote><p>The success of 'Pushpa 2' indicates its strong appeal among audiences, showcasing its enduring popularity in cinemas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-31-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-picks-pace-on-its-fifth-saturday-with-rs-5-5-crore-business-while-varun-dhawans-baby-john-struggles-to-mint-even-rs-1-crore/articleshow/116955671.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-31-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-picks-pace-on-its-fifth-saturday-with-rs-5-5-crore-business-while-varun-dhawans-baby-john-struggles-to-mint-even-rs-1-crore/articleshow/116955671.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Love and Relationship Horoscope for January 5, 2025 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Love and Relationship Horoscope for January 5, 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/photo-1504122398460-c635d6377010_1731621144550_1735989227785.jpg" alt="Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope 2025: Find out love predictions for January 5.(Unsplash)" title="Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope 2025: Find out love predictions for January 5.(Unsplash)"><figcaption>Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope 2025: Find out love predictions for January 5.(Unsplash)</figcaption><p>Today's horoscope encourages individuals to approach love with a sense of lightheartedness and simplicity. It emphasizes the importance of family moments, comfort in relationships, and small acts of kindness as ways to deepen bonds.</p><ul><li><strong>Aries:</strong> Love emerges in everyday moments. Relax and enjoy time with family to leave a lasting impression.</li><li><strong>Taurus:</strong> Family coziness strengthens love; shared activities bring partners closer.</li><li><strong>Gemini:</strong> Embrace love through quality time and companionship.</li><li><strong>Cancer:</strong> Social interactions can lead to new connections, enhancing love.</li><li><strong>Leo:</strong> Attention and personal events highlight emotional attachments.</li><li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Sentimental moments strengthen relationships; recall past memories.</li><li><strong>Libra:</strong> Let love flow freely and appreciate loved ones without agenda.</li><li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Reflect on love's depth; vulnerability strengthens bonds.</li><li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> Make room for love by focusing on loved ones.</li><li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Emotional reflections prompt deeper intimacy in relationships.</li><li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Share visions and passions to enhance connections.</li><li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Distance can be bridged with thoughtful gestures.</li></ul><blockquote>“Love is not always about big gestures; it's about safety and appreciation of being in someone's presence.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, this day's horoscope highlights the understated magic of love through simple actions and shared moments, encouraging individuals to embrace openness in their relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/love-and-relationship-horoscope-for-january-5-2025-101735984913116.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/love-and-relationship-horoscope-for-january-5-2025-101735984913116.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:30:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive - Bigg Boss 18's Chum Darang's sister backs ChumVeer; comments on her relationship with Karan V - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Exclusive - Bigg Boss 18's Chum Darang's sister backs ChumVeer; comments on her relationship with Karan Veer Mehra, says 'they both are grown-up adults..'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<p>Chum Darang's sister has openly defended her relationship with Karan Veer Mehra, highlighting their maturity as adults.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Chum Darang is a contestant on Bigg Boss 18.</li>
  <li>Her sister expressed support for the relationship.</li>
  <li>She mentioned that both individuals are adults and capable of making their own choices.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“They both are grown-up adults.”</blockquote>
<p>This statement underscores a commitment to personal autonomy in relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/exclusive-bigg-boss-18s-chum-darangs-sister-backs-chumveer-comments-on-her-relationship-with-karan-veer-mehra-says-they-both-are-grown-up-adults-/articleshow/116955321.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/exclusive-bigg-boss-18s-chum-darangs-sister-backs-chumveer-comments-on-her-relationship-with-karan-veer-mehra-says-they-both-are-grown-up-adults-/articleshow/116955321.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Pisces, January 5-11, 2025 predicts unexpected career developments - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Pisces, January 5-11, 2025: Predicting Unexpected Career Developments</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 04:11 AM IST <br/><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/Pisces_1728478870554_1735997549238.jpg" alt="Pisces Weekly Horoscope Today, January 5-11, 2025: Stay open-minded and adaptable." title="Pisces Weekly Horoscope Today, January 5-11, 2025: Stay open-minded and adaptable."><figcaption>Pisces Weekly Horoscope Today, January 5-11, 2025: Stay open-minded and adaptable.</figcaption></figure><p>This week brings Pisces both exciting opportunities and manageable challenges in love, career, money, and health. Stay open-minded and adaptable.</p><ul><li>Pisces should stay alert for unexpected career opportunities.</li><li>Networking could significantly enhance professional development.</li><li>Financially, this is a promising week; prudent spending is advised.</li><li>Health should be prioritized with a focus on balance and self-care.</li><li>Love opportunities for deeper connections are highlighted.</li></ul><blockquote>“Stay open-minded and adaptable” - Dr. J.N. Pandey</blockquote><p>Overall, maintaining a flexible approach will help Pisces navigate through new opportunities and challenges this week.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-pisces-january-5-11-2025-predicts-unexpected-career-developments-101735997369254.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-pisces-january-5-11-2025-predicts-unexpected-career-developments-101735997369254.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 22:41:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Capricorn, January 5-11, 2025 predicts unpredictable financial circumstances - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Capricorn Weekly Horoscope Today, January 5-11, 2025</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Jan 05, 2025<br><strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/Capricorn_1728478974232_1735998422808.jpg" alt="Capricorn Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025" title="Capricorn Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025"><figcaption>Capricorn Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025: This week brings opportunities for Capricorns to enhance their personal and professional lives.</figcaption></figure><p>This week, Capricorn individuals can expect growth in both personal and professional realms while focusing on clear communication and emotional balance.</p><ul><li>This week emphasizes emotional growth and stability.</li><li>Capricorns should focus on strategic thinking in career opportunities.</li><li>Financial prudence is crucial; avoid unnecessary expenditures.</li><li>Proper communication will deepen personal relationships.</li><li>Prioritize health and well-being through balanced routines.</li></ul><blockquote>“By maintaining a disciplined approach, you can safeguard your financial stability.”</blockquote><p>Overall, this week encourages Capricorns to be cautious yet open to new opportunities, ensuring they remain grounded despite any unpredictability in financial matters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-capricorn-january-5-11-2025-predicts-unpredictable-financial-circumstances-101735998081773.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-capricorn-january-5-11-2025-predicts-unpredictable-financial-circumstances-101735998081773.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 22:39:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Sagittarius, January 5-11, 2025 predicts a refreshing change - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sagittarius Weekly Horoscope January 5-11, 2025</h1><p><strong>Date: January 5, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/Sagittarius_1728479012112_1735999742564.jpg" alt="Sagittarius Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025: This week promises an exciting blend of opportunities across various aspects of your life. " title="Sagittarius Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025: This week promises an exciting blend of opportunities across various aspects of your life. "><figcaption>Sagittarius Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025: This week promises an exciting blend of opportunities across various aspects of your life.</figcaption></figure><p>This week promises an exciting blend of opportunities across love, career, money, and health. Stay balanced and focused to make the most of these possibilities.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Adventurous paths await in various aspects of life.</li><li>Refreshingly positive changes in romantic connections.</li><li>Networking is key for professional growth.</li><li>Prioritize financial planning and avoid impulse spending.</li><li>Health requires attention with a focus on physical and mental well-being.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is a great time to nurture your emotional connection and share your dreams with your loved one."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, staying mindful of balancing all areas of life will allow Sagittarius to truly thrive this week.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-sagittarius-january-5-11-2025-predicts-a-refreshing-change-101735999534457.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-sagittarius-january-5-11-2025-predicts-a-refreshing-change-101735999534457.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 22:38:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Libra, January 5-11, 2025 predicts financial stability - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope for Libra: Financial Stability Predicted</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 5, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/Libra_1728479045617_1735998973186.jpg" alt="Libra Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025" title="Libra Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025">
<figcaption>Libra Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025: This week brings an emphasis on relationships for Libra.</figcaption>
<p>This week's horoscope outlines an emphasis on relationships and communication for Libras, with predictions of potential financial growth and health considerations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>This week focuses on communication in personal and professional interactions.</li>
  <li>Opportunities for financial gain may arise, requiring careful attention.</li>
  <li>Health requires mindfulness, emphasizing both physical and mental well-being.</li>
  <li>In love, open communication is crucial for deepening connections.</li>
  <li>Career-wise, collaboration and diplomacy will be key for advancement.</li>
  <li>Budget planning is recommended to enhance financial stability.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"By tending to both body and mind, you'll achieve a harmonious sense of well-being."</blockquote>
<p>This week highlights the importance of balance in every aspect of life for Libras, ensuring stability and growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-libra-january-5-11-2025-predicts-financial-stability-101735998715332.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-libra-january-5-11-2025-predicts-financial-stability-101735998715332.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 22:36:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Virgo, January 5-11, 2025 predicts steady progress - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope for Virgo, January 5-11, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/Virgo_1728479056525_1735997195496.jpg" alt="Virgo Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025." title="Virgo Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025.">
<figcaption>Virgo Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025.</figcaption>
<p>This week, Virgos will experience steady progress through thoughtful decisions, focusing on balance in love, career, money, and health.</p>
<ul>
  <li>This week promotes personal growth and fulfillment.</li>
  <li>In love, communication strengthens relationships; singles could meet interesting people.</li>
  <li>Career progress requires focus and organization; teamwork is encouraged.</li>
  <li>Financial stability is possible with mindful spending and better budgeting.</li>
  <li>Health should be prioritized with regular exercise and nutrition.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Small gestures can have a significant impact on your relationship, strengthening the bond between you and your loved one.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, maintaining balance will lead Virgos to personal development and satisfaction this week.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-virgo-january-5-11-2025-predicts-steady-progress-101735996855890.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-virgo-january-5-11-2025-predicts-steady-progress-101735996855890.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 22:35:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Leo, January 5-11, 2025 predicts dynamic shifts - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Leo Weekly Horoscope January 5-11, 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/Leo_1728478322188_1735996756476.jpg" alt="Leo Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025" title="Leo Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025"><figcaption>Leo Weekly Horoscope January 5 to 11, 2025: This week promises to be dynamic for Leo natives, as you experience growth across various aspects of life.</figcaption><p>This week offers Leos opportunities for personal growth, romantic possibilities, and career progress while fostering financial stability and well-being. Embrace positive change and self-reflection.</p><ul><li>Expect unexpected developments in relationships, leading to joy and passion.</li><li>Career opportunities may present themselves, facilitating significant advancement.</li><li>Financial stability is achievable through careful budgeting and planning.</li><li>Health should be prioritized with a focus on physical and mental well-being, including stress relief activities.</li></ul><blockquote>"Embrace the opportunity to explore your feelings and desires, fostering a more fulfilling love life."</blockquote><p>Developments this week are integral, encouraging proactive engagement to seize opportunities along various fronts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-leo-january-5-11-2025-predicts-dynamic-shifts-101735995989101.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-leo-january-5-11-2025-predicts-dynamic-shifts-101735995989101.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 22:34:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AP govt approves ticket rate hike for Balayya’s Daaku Maharaaj; Deets inside - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ticket Rate Hike Approved for Balayya's Daaku Maharaaj</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 5, 2025, 2:57 am IST</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Daaku-Maharaaj-3.jpg" alt="Daaku Maharaaj Promotion" width="500" height="373"><figcaption>Promotional image for Daaku Maharaaj</figcaption><p>The Andhra Pradesh government has approved a ticket rate hike for the highly anticipated film, Daaku Maharaaj, starring Nandamuri Balakrishna. This decision will allow for increased ticket prices during the Sankranthi festive season.</p><ul><li>The ticket rates for benefit shows are capped at Rs 500 (incl GST) starting from January 12.</li><li>Five shows per day will be available from January 12 to 25.</li><li>The price hike includes Rs 135 for multiplexes and Rs 110 for single screens.</li><li>Bollywood star Bobby Deol and others feature in pivotal roles alongside Balakrishna.</li><li>The film is produced by Sithara Entertainments and Fortune Four Cinemas.</li></ul><blockquote>"The ticket rates for Daaku Maharaaj’s benefit shows starting from 4 AM on January 12 have been capped at Rs 500 (incl GST)."</blockquote><p>This ticket rate increase is expected to benefit the film significantly during its release amidst the festive period.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/ap-govt-approves-ticket-rate-hike-for-balayyas-daaku-maharaaj-deets-inside.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/ap-govt-approves-ticket-rate-hike-for-balayyas-daaku-maharaaj-deets-inside.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 21:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max (Kannada) Box Office Collection Day 11 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQaEc4Zlc4NUlIdWtEbndsTXM3VmZKbC1OVlhIUVlIczFwaHRvbEUzc2JhSUI2RkZEdjYxeFhFS0xoN0tKcEdoNjgyN0pZVllRUVY4VEZBdzZubnJBdUxkdEtSWnVpbGtZc1VpY2U1MExOQXBlMmNBRUtqRU91UW03bTUyRUk3QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQaEc4Zlc4NUlIdWtEbndsTXM3VmZKbC1OVlhIUVlIczFwaHRvbEUzc2JhSUI2RkZEdjYxeFhFS0xoN0tKcEdoNjgyN0pZVllRUVY4VEZBdzZubnJBdUxkdEtSWnVpbGtZc1VpY2U1MExOQXBlMmNBRUtqRU91UW03bTUyRUk3QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 20:36:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kiara Advani Advised Rest Due to Exertion, Misses Game Changer Event with Ram Charan - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kiara Advani Takes a Break Due to Exhaustion, Misses Game Changer Event</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 04, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Kiara Advani will be seen in Game Changer." title="Kiara Advani will be seen in Game Changer."><figcaption>Kiara Advani will be seen in Game Changer.</figcaption></figure><p>Actress Kiara Advani, set to star alongside Ram Charan in the film Game Changer, is currently resting at home following advice to recover from exhaustion after a busy schedule.</p><ul><li>Ian a surprising turn, Kiara was initially reported to be hospitalized, but her spokesperson clarified she is at home resting.</li><li>Her absence was noted at a promotional event for Game Changer, generating concern among fans.</li><li>The film, directed by Shankar, is set to release on January 10, 2025.</li><li>Game Changer has completed its censorship formalities and received a U/A certificate from the CBFC.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kiara Advani has not been hospitalised, she’s been advised to rest due to exertion as she’s been working non-stop,” said the actress’ spokesperson.</blockquote><p>The upcoming film Game Changer has created significant buzz and features an impressive cast, including Ram Charan, making it one of the most anticipated releases of the month.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/kiara-advani-hospitalised-in-mumbai-skips-game-changer-event-with-ram-charan-9176931.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/kiara-advani-hospitalised-in-mumbai-skips-game-changer-event-with-ram-charan-9176931.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 19:31:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope 5th January to 11th January, 2025: Virgo, Sagittarius and other signs — check astrological prediction - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope 5th January to 11th January, 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Astrology Weekly</p><p>The Sun's movement brings new perspectives on creativity and love, urging a deeper understanding of life. Each zodiac sign's weekly predictions forecast various themes, encouraging introspection, ambition, and relationship dynamics.</p><ul><li><strong>Gemini:</strong> Short distance travel may face delays.</li><li><strong>Cancer:</strong> Ambitious stars favor competitive success.</li><li><strong>Leo:</strong> Past experiences guide future ventures.</li><li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Solitude can be invigorating; plan social events ahead.</li><li><strong>Libra:</strong> Attention to routine matters is crucial.</li><li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Collaboration is necessary in partnerships.</li><li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> Travel plans may experience delays; be prepared.</li><li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Ethical considerations in adventures are advised.</li><li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Encourage others' autonomy regarding their choices.</li><li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Generosity towards deserving causes is encouraged.</li></ul><blockquote>“If you do your best for other people, they will undoubtedly do their best for you.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, this week’s horoscope emphasizes the importance of self-reflection and nurturing relationships, with each sign encountering unique challenges and opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-5th-january-to-11th-january-2025-virgo-sagittarius-and-other-signs-check-astrological-prediction-9749833/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-5th-january-to-11th-january-2025-virgo-sagittarius-and-other-signs-check-astrological-prediction-9749833/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 19:30:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pawan Kalyan garu is the real Game Changer in Indian politics – Ram Charan - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pawan Kalyan: The Real Game Changer in Indian Politics</h1><p><strong>Published on Jan 4, 2025 11:57 pm IST</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/RamCharan-Pawankalyan-1.jpg" alt="" width="550" height="350"><figcaption>Ram Charan and Pawan Kalyan at the pre-release event of Game Changer.</figcaption><p>Ram Charan praised his uncle, Pawan Kalyan, as the real game changer in Indian politics during a speech at the pre-release event of the film Game Changer.</p><ul><li>Ram Charan expressed gratitude to Pawan Kalyan for attending the event.</li><li>He recalled the massive crowds at Pawan Kalyan's first election rally.</li><li>Game Changer, directed by Shankar, is set to release on January 10, 2025.</li><li>The film features a star-studded cast including Kiara Advani and SJ Suryah.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pawan Kalyan garu is the real game changer in Indian politics.” - Ram Charan</blockquote><p>Game Changer is a high-budget political drama that is highly anticipated by audiences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/pawan-kalyan-garu-is-the-real-game-changer-in-indian-politics-ram-charan.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/pawan-kalyan-garu-is-the-real-game-changer-in-indian-politics-ram-charan.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 18:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diljit Dosanjh’s Song Hits The Right Note As PM Narendra Modi Taps Table In Perfect Sync | Watch - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/diljit-dosanjhs-song-hits-the-right-note-as-pm-narendra-modi-taps-table-in-perfect-sync-watch-9176812.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/diljit-dosanjhs-song-hits-the-right-note-as-pm-narendra-modi-taps-table-in-perfect-sync-watch-9176812.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 17:32:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aubrey Plaza’s husband, director Jeff Baena, 47, dies by suicide - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aubrey Plaza's Husband Jeff Baena Dies by Suicide at Age 47</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 04, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/88a6850dab0e4527a2f776c8980e6630-88a6850dab0e4527a_1736010035308_1736010035557.jpg" alt="Aubrey Plaza is grieving the death of her husband, director Jeff Baena, who died at 47.(Willy Sanjuan/Invision/AP)" title="Aubrey Plaza is grieving the death of her husband, director Jeff Baena, who died at 47.(Willy Sanjuan/Invision/AP)">
<figcaption>Aubrey Plaza is grieving the death of her husband, director Jeff Baena, who died at 47.(Willy Sanjuan/Invision/AP)</figcaption>
<p>Aubrey Plaza is mourning the loss of her husband, film director Jeff Baena, who was found dead in his Los Angeles home at the age of 47. Local authorities are currently investigating the circumstances surrounding his passing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jeff Baena was discovered dead by his assistant, prompting a police investigation.</li>
<li>Aubrey Plaza's representatives stated that the family is devastated and requests privacy.</li>
<li>The couple married in 2021 and had no children.</li>
<li>Baena's notable works include Joshy, Horse Girl, and co-writing I Heart Huckabees.</li>
<li>Plaza mentioned their spontaneous wedding during an appearance on The Ellen DeGeneres Show.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The family is devastated and asks for privacy at this difficult time.”</blockquote>
<p>This story is still developing as details emerge about Jeff Baena's death.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/aubrey-plaza-s-husband-director-jeff-baena-47-found-dead-in-suspected-suicide-101736009414071.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/aubrey-plaza-s-husband-director-jeff-baena-47-found-dead-in-suspected-suicide-101736009414071.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 17:01:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>