<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 21:17:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 21:17:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MT Vasudevan Nair: Celebrated Indian author dies at 91 - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MT Vasudevan Nair: Celebrated Indian Author Dies at 91</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Outlook India</p><p>MT Vasudevan Nair, a legendary writer from Kerala, has passed away at the age of 91 after being admitted to a hospital for breathing difficulties. Nair was not only a celebrated author but also an acclaimed film director and screenwriter.</p><ul><li>Nair was born in 1933 in Palakkad, Kerala, and began writing from a young age despite minimal encouragement in his family.</li><li>He achieved significant acclaim for his novel <em>Naalukettu</em>, which won one of Kerala's highest literary honours in 1959.</li><li>His retelling of the Mahabharata in <em>Randamoozham</em> is regarded as a classic of Indian literature.</li><li>Nair was awarded India's highest literary honour, the Jnanpith, among other accolades during his career.</li><li>He also had a prolific career in Malayalam cinema, noted for his screenplay in <em>Oru Vadakkan Veeragatha</em>.</li><li>Tributes have poured in highlighting his impact on Malayalam literature and cinema.</li></ul><blockquote>"You can change the dialogues of any other films, but not MT's, since those dialogues are essential to understand the essence of what is being conveyed." - Mohanlal</blockquote><p>Nair's legacy lives on through his extensive body of work, influencing generations of writers and filmmakers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czr3kdn7pv3o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czr3kdn7pv3o</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s The Exact Time ‘Squid Game’ Season 2 Lands On Netflix - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/erikkain/2024/12/25/heres-the-exact-time-squid-game-season-2-lands-on-netflix/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/erikkain/2024/12/25/heres-the-exact-time-squid-game-season-2-lands-on-netflix/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 18:32:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[M.T. Vasudevan Nair, doyen of Malayalam literature and cinema, passes away - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>M.T. Vasudevan Nair, Doyen of Malayalam Literature and Cinema, Passes Away</h1>
<p><strong>Published on December 25, 2024, by The Hindu</strong></p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ooqa92/article69027006.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/MT%20Vasudevan%20Nair.jpg" alt="M.T. Vasudevan Nair"/>
<figcaption>M.T. Vasudevan Nair, who was born at a village called Kudallur, near Ponnani, made a mark as a writer of remarkable skills from an early age.</figcaption>
<p>Renowned writer and filmmaker M.T. Vasudevan Nair passed away in Kozhikode at the age of 91. He was a significant figure in Malayalam literature and cinema, known for his revolutionary contributions to screenplay writing and his timeless novels.</p>
<ul>
<li>M.T. Vasudevan Nair died on December 25, 2024, in Kozhikode.</li>
<li>He was celebrated for his novels such as <i>Randamoozham</i> and <i>Asuravithu</i>.</li>
<li>His film debut as a director, <i>Nirmalyam</i>, won the National Award for Best Film in 1974.</li>
<li>Many of his works have become part of Malayali cultural life and continue to be published.</li>
<li>He was awarded the Jnanpith Award in 1995 and was a prolific screenwriter.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“M.T. championed modernism in his works.” - Kerala Governor Arif Mohammed Khan</blockquote>
<p>M.T. Vasudevan Nair's passing marks the end of an era in Malayalam literature and cinema, leaving behind a legacy that will continue to inspire future generations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/books/writer-mt-vasudevan-nair-passes-away/article69027005.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/books/writer-mt-vasudevan-nair-passes-away/article69027005.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby John box office collection day 1: Varun Dhawan film fails to beat Vijay's Theri, remake opens at ₹12 crore - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baby John Box Office Collection Day 1: The Varun Dhawan-Starrer Opens to Mixed Reviews</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 25, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/baby_john_theri_1735145627824_1735145629027.jpg" alt="Baby John, starring Varun Dhawan, is a remake of Theri." title="Baby John, starring Varun Dhawan, is a remake of Theri."><figcaption>Baby John, starring Varun Dhawan, is a remake of Theri.</figcaption><p>The Varun Dhawan-starrer 'Baby John' opened on December 25 but failed to beat the box office collection of its predecessor 'Theri'.</p><ul><li>As per early estimates, 'Baby John' collected ₹12.5 crore on its opening day.</li><li>The film had 24.53% Hindi occupancy on the release day.</li><li>'Theri' had an opening day collection of ₹13.1 crore despite only being released in Tamil Nadu.</li><li>'Pushpa 2' continues to outperform 'Baby John' with ₹20.7 crore collection.</li><li>Directed by Kalees and produced by Atlee, the film stars also Jackie Shroff and Rajpal Yadav, with a cameo by Salman Khan.</li></ul><blockquote>The film starts off on a very choppy note, and there’s no soul for about 40 minutes.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, 'Baby John' showcased a decent performance, but it struggled to surpass its competitors and faced criticism for its direction and storyline.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/baby-john-box-office-collection-day-1-varun-dhawan-film-fails-to-beat-vijays-theri-remake-opens-at-12-crore-101735143343211.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/baby-john-box-office-collection-day-1-varun-dhawan-film-fails-to-beat-vijays-theri-remake-opens-at-12-crore-101735143343211.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:56:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Baldoni Sued By Former Publicist Amid Blake Lively's Sexual Misconduct Charge - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Baldoni Sued By Former Publicist Amid Blake Lively's Sexual Misconduct Charge</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> New York Post</p>
<p>Justin Baldoni's former publicist, Stephanie Jones, has filed a lawsuit against him and his current publicity team, alleging breach of contract and involvement in a smear campaign against Blake Lively.</p>
<ul>
<li>The lawsuit claims Baldoni failed to pay $25,000 per month as per their contract.</li>
<li>Jones alleges she had no involvement in a smear campaign against Lively and that Abel and Nathan are deflecting blame to her.</li>
<li>Jones discovered evidence of a retaliation campaign against Lively upon reviewing company correspondence.</li>
<li>Blake Lively has also filed a lawsuit against Baldoni for sexual harassment and misconduct, claiming a hostile work environment.</li>
<li>Allegations against Baldoni include inappropriate behavior and ignoring boundaries during filming of 'It Ends With Us.'</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"To this day, Abel and Nathan continue to point the finger falsely at Jones now that their own misconduct is coming to light, and to defame and attack Jones in the industry."</blockquote>
<p>The allegations raise serious questions regarding workplace conduct and the treatment of actors in Hollywood, highlighting ongoing issues of power dynamics and harassment in the film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/feature/justin-baldoni-sued-by-former-publicist-amid-blake-livelys-sexual-misconduct-charge-7331119</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/feature/justin-baldoni-sued-by-former-publicist-amid-blake-livelys-sexual-misconduct-charge-7331119</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:50:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Barroz Box Office Collection Day 1 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE5weXEtbFVJbnNvTnBETy0xTElodzZ4WmotLWlxT1BsX3RrVFN1ZXJVTW9QcmdkeTdvUTlPVFEzMGRBZG1LcE9rdHNBVEFCVjJiaWMzYzBEOXBMT2I5QTdPY2xNb1dXZ3ZYN0tuZWF4SXlDTUZpU21CbG9lTUh0QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE5weXEtbFVJbnNvTnBETy0xTElodzZ4WmotLWlxT1BsX3RrVFN1ZXJVTW9QcmdkeTdvUTlPVFEzMGRBZG1LcE9rdHNBVEFCVjJiaWMzYzBEOXBMT2I5QTdPY2xNb1dXZ3ZYN0tuZWF4SXlDTUZpU21CbG9lTUh0QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:37:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trisha's 'Son' Zorro Passes Away On Christmas, Shares Heartbreaking Note: 'I Am Broken, In Shock' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trisha's 'Son' Zorro Passes Away On Christmas, Shares Heartbreaking Note: 'I Am Broken, In Shock'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2024/12/trisha-1-2024-12-210bcd5799dedc94c0f9a6bc6bfa5252.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Trisha's pet dog, Zorro passed away." title="Trisha's pet dog, Zorro passed away." loading="eager"><figcaption>Trisha's pet dog, Zorro passed away.</figcaption><p>Tamil actress Trisha shared heartbreaking news on Christmas that her pet dog Zorro has passed away. She expressed her shock and sorrow, stating that she needs time off to grieve.</p><ul><li>Trisha's pet dog Zorro passed away early on Christmas morning.</li><li>She shared an emotional note highlighting her loss and need for time away from work.</li><li>Fans flooded the comments section with condolences and support for the actress.</li><li>Zorro was a part of Trisha's life for over a decade and frequently appeared on her social media.</li><li>Trisha has several upcoming film projects lined up for future releases.</li></ul><blockquote>“My son Zorro passed away early this Christmas morning. For those who know me well know that my life has zero meaning henceforth. My family and I are broken and in a state of shock. Will be taking some time off work and will be off the radar.” - Trisha</blockquote><p>The loss of Zorro marks a significant emotional moment for Trisha, who has shared a deep bond with her pet over the years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/trishas-son-zorro-passes-away-on-christmas-shares-heartbreaking-note-i-am-broken-in-shock-9167849.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/trishas-son-zorro-passes-away-on-christmas-shares-heartbreaking-note-i-am-broken-in-shock-9167849.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:14:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alia Bhatt, Ranbir Kapoor spend cosy Christmas evening with Soni Razdan, Shaheen Bhatt. See pics - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor Celebrate Christmas with Family</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/Alia_Bhatt_Ranbir_Kapoor_Christmas_1735136722529_1735136722945.jpg" alt="Alia Bhatt spent Christmas evening with her mom Soni Razdan and sister Shaheen Bhatt." title="Alia Bhatt spent Christmas evening with her mom Soni Razdan and sister Shaheen Bhatt."><figcaption>Alia Bhatt spent Christmas evening with her mom Soni Razdan and sister Shaheen Bhatt.</figcaption><p>This year, Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor enjoyed a cozy Christmas evening after celebrating with the Kapoor family, spending quality time with Alia's family in Mumbai.</p><ul><li>The couple participated in the annual Kapoor lunch before celebrating with Alia's mom and sister.</li><li>Alia shared moments of love and joy on social media, highlighting their festive atmosphere.</li><li>Ranbir and Alia posed in festive attire, with Alia wearing a red dress for lunch and a white dress with Christmas-themed antlers for the evening.</li><li>Alia and Ranbir have exciting films coming up, including their collaboration in 'Love and War'.</li></ul><blockquote>“Under the twinkling lights, surrounded by love.. this is what Christmas feels like.” - Alia Bhatt</blockquote><p>Overall, Alia and Ranbir’s Christmas celebration was filled with warmth, family, and anticipation for their upcoming projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/alia-bhatt-ranbir-kapoor-spend-cosy-christmas-evening-with-soni-razdan-shaheen-bhatt-see-pics-101735136728401.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/alia-bhatt-ranbir-kapoor-spend-cosy-christmas-evening-with-soni-razdan-shaheen-bhatt-see-pics-101735136728401.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:13:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' stampede: Producer Dil Raju says 'entire film industry' will meet Telangana CM on Thursday - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2' stampede: Producer Dil Raju says 'entire film industry' will meet Telangana CM on Thursday</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='Pushpa 2 Stampede' />
<figcaption>Image from the incident.</figcaption>
<p>The unfortunate stampede incident at a screening of 'Pushpa 2' has sparked widespread concern, prompting the film industry to take action.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Producer Dil Raju expressed that the entire film industry will be meeting with the Chief Minister of Telangana.</li>
  <li>The meeting aims to discuss the repercussions of the stampede and ensure the safety of attendees at future screenings.</li>
  <li>Emergency protocols and safety measures are expected to be reviewed during this meeting.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The safety of our viewers is our foremost priority,” said Dil Raju.</blockquote>
<p>This tragic event has highlighted the need for improved crowd management at film events, as the industry takes steps to safeguard its audience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pushpa-2-stampede-producer-dil-raju-says-entire-film-industry-will-meet-telangana-cm-on-thursday/articleshow/116658749.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pushpa-2-stampede-producer-dil-raju-says-entire-film-industry-will-meet-telangana-cm-on-thursday/articleshow/116658749.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Varun Dhawan Regretted Rejecting Shraddha Kapoor After Seeing Her In College: 'When She Became A Teenager.. - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Varun Dhawan Regretted Rejecting Shraddha Kapoor After Seeing Her In College</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Varun Dhawan shares a fun anecdote about Shraddha Kapoor." title="Varun Dhawan shares a fun anecdote about Shraddha Kapoor." loading="eager">
<figcaption>Varun Dhawan shares a fun anecdote about Shraddha Kapoor.</figcaption>
<p>Varun Dhawan reminisces about his childhood friendship with Shraddha Kapoor, including her childhood crush on him and his eventual regret for rejecting her.</p>
<ul>
<li>Varun rejected Shraddha's crush at age eight, leading to a playful confrontation.</li>
<li>Years later, Varun saw Shraddha at a school event and was struck by her beauty.</li>
<li>The two have starred together in films like ABCD 2 and Street Dancer 3D.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When Shraddha became a teenager, she had become extremely beautiful.” - Varun Dhawan</blockquote>
<p>This nostalgic recollection highlights the playful nature of childhood relationships and their evolution over time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/childhood-crush-drama-varun-dhawan-and-shraddha-kapoors-filmy-tale-9167521.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/childhood-crush-drama-varun-dhawan-and-shraddha-kapoors-filmy-tale-9167521.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:44:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Box Office Collection Day 21: Allu Arjun movie refuses to slow down, mints ₹16.82 crore on Christmas | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Collection Day 21: Allu Arjun movie refuses to slow down, mints ₹16.82 crore on Christmas</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna's action thriller 'Pushpa 2' continues to dominate the box office on its 21st day, collecting ₹16.82 crore on Christmas.</p><h2>Worldwide collection</h2><p>The film has grossed ₹1547.40 crore worldwide, becoming the third Indian movie to cross the ₹1500 crore mark.</p><ul><li>The total domestic box office collection stands at ₹1106.92 crore.</li><li>Pushpa 2 has also collected ₹248 crore internationally.</li><li>The film achieved the ₹1500 crore mark in 18 days.</li><li>It is currently the second biggest grosser in India after 'Baahubali 2.'</li></ul><blockquote>“The #Christmas to #NewYear period traditionally witnesses an upswing at the #Boxoffice, and #Pushpa2 is expected to add substantial revenue to its already historic total... The ₹800 cr milestone now appears to be well within reach.” — Taran Adarsh</blockquote><p>This film is expected to continue its impressive performance during the holiday season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-21-allu-arjun-movie-refuses-to-slow-down-mints-rs-16-82-crore-on-christmas-11735131600732.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-21-allu-arjun-movie-refuses-to-slow-down-mints-rs-16-82-crore-on-christmas-11735131600732.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:38:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun's Horoscope Not Good, Claims Venuswamy.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun’s Horoscope Not Good, Claims Venuswamy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/venuswammy1735135926.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun's Horoscope Not Good, Claims Venuswamy"><figcaption>Venuswamy claims Allu Arjun will face challenges according to his horoscope.</figcaption><p>Venuswamy, a self-proclaimed astrologer, has made recent headlines by claiming that Allu Arjun's horoscope indicates upcoming challenges. His controversial statements come amid growing criticism and dwindling connections within the film industry.</p><ul><li>Venuswamy is under fire for sharing the horoscopes of other celebrities.</li><li>He is facing legal troubles that have affected his professional relationships.</li><li>Despite the backlash, he attempts to remain relevant by commenting on astrological forecasts.</li><li>He claims Allu Arjun will experience difficulties until March, with improvements expected after March 29.</li><li>Venuswamy visited a hospital to provide support to a boy injured in a theater stampede and donated Rs 2 lakh to the family.</li></ul><blockquote>“According to Allu Arjun's horoscope, Saturn is in the sixth house, which indicates challenges. No one is immune to such phases.” - Venuswamy</blockquote><p>Even in the midst of controversy, Venuswamy seems to be trying to regain his reputation by providing astrological insights into prominent figures like Allu Arjun.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/allu-arjuns-horoscope-not-good-claims-venuswamy-142990</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/allu-arjuns-horoscope-not-good-claims-venuswamy-142990</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:14:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ranbir Kapoor And Alia Bhatt Join Kapoor Family's Christmas Lunch, Raha Wishes Paps 'Merry Christmas' | Wat - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/ranbir-kapoor-and-alia-bhatt-join-kapoor-familys-christmas-lunch-raha-wishes-paps-merry-christmas-watch-9167931.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/ranbir-kapoor-and-alia-bhatt-join-kapoor-familys-christmas-lunch-raha-wishes-paps-merry-christmas-watch-9167931.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:42:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max (Kannada) Box Office Collection Day 1 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNNEVRekYtbUNuaUh3Szh4d1p6VW9CN1doSFd5d25vb1cyX2dqU25yUk9MSHZsTDQ3T2ZkNVBKNUVxN0tqQWtvdGRlMXFOUlg5N0VIejVCWWRJSnk3YTJObU1pa0ZrUVhyeGNyMUtEaE5uVFBlNkgyZmRZbkw4NHNUMkdUYTI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNNEVRekYtbUNuaUh3Szh4d1p6VW9CN1doSFd5d25vb1cyX2dqU25yUk9MSHZsTDQ3T2ZkNVBKNUVxN0tqQWtvdGRlMXFOUlg5N0VIejVCWWRJSnk3YTJObU1pa0ZrUVhyeGNyMUtEaE5uVFBlNkgyZmRZbkw4NHNUMkdUYTI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:36:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Farah Khan Wishes Anil Kapoor ‘Happy Birthday’ With Throwback Pics Featuring Salman Khan, Ranveer Singh - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/farah-khan-wishes-anil-kapoor-happy-birthday-with-throwback-pics-featuring-salman-khan-ranveer-singh-9167889.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/farah-khan-wishes-anil-kapoor-happy-birthday-with-throwback-pics-featuring-salman-khan-ranveer-singh-9167889.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:27:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alia Bhatt, Raha Kapoor, Neetu Kapoor, Navya Naveli, Agastya Nanda steal the spotlight in the Kapoor fami - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Alia Bhatt, Raha Kapoor, Neetu Kapoor, Navya Naveli, Agastya Nanda steal the spotlight in the Kapoor family Christmas celebrations</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 25<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</strong></p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116657299,imgsize-88288,width-400,resizemode-4/116657299.jpg" alt="Alia Bhatt, Raha Kapoor, Neetu Kapoor, Navya Naveli, Agastya Nanda steal the spotlight in the Kapoor family Christmas celebrations"><figcaption>Alia Bhatt with her daughter Raha during the Kapoor family's Christmas celebration.</figcaption><p>The Kapoor family came together for their annual Christmas lunch, showcasing their traditional festive spirit and heartwarming reunions.</p><ul><li>The family posed in red-and-white Christmas-themed outfits.</li><li>Alia Bhatt was seen holding her daughter Raha, with other family members, including Ranbir Kapoor and Neetu Kapoor.</li><li>Fans expressed their affection in the comments section of Neetu's social media post.</li><li>Raha Kapoor charmed attendees with her cuteness during the gathering.</li></ul><blockquote>“Merry Christmas to all of you. Stay blessed and stay happy always. Love you all.”</blockquote><p>The festive gathering highlights the Kapoor family's love and unity during Christmas celebrations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/alia-bhatt-raha-kapoor-neetu-kapoor-navya-naveli-agastya-nanda-steal-the-spotlight-in-the-kapoor-family-christmas-celebrations/articleshow/116657273.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/alia-bhatt-raha-kapoor-neetu-kapoor-navya-naveli-agastya-nanda-steal-the-spotlight-in-the-kapoor-family-christmas-celebrations/articleshow/116657273.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Raha changes into red for a family photo with Alia-Ranbir; fans miss Kareena, Suhana at Kapoors’ annual Christmas - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Raha Kapoor Steals the Show at the Kapoors' Annual Christmas Gathering</h1><p><strong>Published on: Dec 25, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/Kapoors_Christmas_brunch_1735132413025_1735132445833.jpg" alt="A family photo from the Kapoors' annual Christmas brunch" title="A family photo from the Kapoors' annual Christmas brunch"><figcaption>A family photo from the Kapoors' annual Christmas brunch</figcaption></figure><p>Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor's daughter Raha Kapoor delighted fans this Christmas as she interacted with paparazzi during the Kapoors’ annual family brunch, resulting in viral moments on social media.</p><ul><li>Raha Kapoor, the daughter of Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor, was introduced to the public last Christmas.</li><li>This year, she made headlines by waving and blowing kisses to paparazzi.</li><li>Alia wore a stunning red satin dress, while Ranbir was stylish in a blue and white striped shirt.</li><li>Raha charmed everyone in a festive red checkered outfit.</li><li>Notable absentees from the family photo included Kareena Kapoor Khan and Suhana Khan, which fans expressed disappointment over.</li></ul><blockquote>“According to Kareena’s insta posts she’s in the UK with Saifu & the kids, so I guess she won’t be there for Christmas this year either,” commented a fan.</blockquote><p>The Kapoor family continues to captivate fans with their charming gatherings, despite the absence of some familiar faces this year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/raha-changes-into-red-for-a-family-photo-with-alia-ranbir-fans-miss-kareena-suhana-at-kapoors-annual-christmas-101735131757290.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/raha-changes-into-red-for-a-family-photo-with-alia-ranbir-fans-miss-kareena-suhana-at-kapoors-annual-christmas-101735131757290.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:21:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby John Opening Day Box Office Trends: Varun Dhawan starrer aims at a Rs 12 crore start - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baby John Opening Day Box Office Trends: Varun Dhawan starrer aims at a Rs 12 crore start</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 25, 2024 | Source: Pinkvilla</strong></p><p><img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/156831764_baby-john-bo-1.jpg" alt="Varun Dhawan" title="Baby John looks to take a Rs 12 crore opening in India (Credit: Jio Studios)"></p><figcaption>Baby John looks to take a Rs 12 crore opening in India (Credit: Jio Studios)</figcaption></p><p>The Varun Dhawan led action entertainer, Baby John, has taken a promising start at the Indian box office, with early trends indicating a first-day business of Rs 11 crore to Rs 12 crore.</p><ul><li>The film's performance benefited from the Christmas holiday but faced competition from other releases like Pushpa 2 and Mufasa.</li><li>It is suggested that without competition, Baby John could have opened in the range of Rs 13 crore to Rs 15 crore.</li><li>Despite the challenges, this is the best opening for Varun Dhawan among recent non-franchise films, barring 83 directed by Kabir Khan.</li><li>The holiday period ahead offers opportunities for Baby John to potentially achieve Rs 100 crore by the end of its run.</li><li>The first day's drop and subsequent hold in business on Day 2 and Day 3 will be crucial in determining its long-term trajectory.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s a decent start for Baby John, but the trend over the next few days is crucial.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while Baby John shows promise, its success will depend on audience turnout in the coming days amid ongoing competition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/baby-john-opening-day-box-office-trends-varun-dhawan-starrer-aims-at-a-rs-12-crore-start-1364308</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/baby-john-opening-day-box-office-trends-varun-dhawan-starrer-aims-at-a-rs-12-crore-start-1364308</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:08:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sridevi was upset for 6 months after Boney Kapoor.. , said 'How can you...' - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sridevi was upset for 6 months after Boney Kapoor.. , said ‘How can you…’</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SB.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Sridevi was upset for 6 months after Boney Kapoor..." />
<figcaption>Sridevi was upset for 6 months after Boney Kapoor.. , said 'How can you...'</figcaption>
<p>Boney Kapoor shared how Sridevi was emotionally disturbed for six months after he confessed his love for her amidst the complexities of his previous marriage.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Boney Kapoor's love story with Sridevi was characterized by affection but also challenges.</li>
  <li>Their relationship evolved over time as Boney separated from his first wife.</li>
  <li>Sridevi initially hesitated to accept Boney's proposal due to his previous marriage and the resulting complications.</li>
  <li>Boney emphasized the importance of honesty in relationships.</li>
  <li>He reflected on how true selves are revealed only after years in a relationship.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I loved her, I love her and I will love her till my death.” - Boney Kapoor</blockquote>
<p>This narrative highlights the emotional depths of their relationship and the significance of honesty and patience in love.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/entertainment/sridevi-was-upset-for-6-months-after-boney-kapoor-said-how-can-you-7492328/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/entertainment/sridevi-was-upset-for-6-months-after-boney-kapoor-said-how-can-you-7492328/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:55:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MEGA EXCLUSIVE: Kartik Aaryan and Karan Johar join hands for Rs. 150 crore action love story; Sameer Vidhwans to direct - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kartik Aaryan and Karan Johar Collaborate on Ambitious Rs. 150 Crore Action Love Story</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p>
<img src="https://stat4.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Kartik-Aaryan-and-Karan-Johar.jpg" alt="Kartik Aaryan and Karan Johar" width="620" height="450">
<figcaption>Kartik Aaryan and Karan Johar join forces for a new film project.</figcaption>
<p>Kartik Aaryan and Karan Johar are set to collaborate on their first film together, an action-packed love story directed by Sameer Vidhwans, known for <em>Satyaprem Ki Katha</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li>The project has been in discussion for a long time and is now officially in place.</li>
<li>The film has a budget of Rs. 150 crores and is described as one of the most ambitious love stories of modern times.</li>
<li>Kartik Aaryan is enthusiastic about returning to the big screen after his role in <em>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</em>.</li>
<li>The film will be co-produced by Dharma Productions and Namah Pictures, with an announcement expected within two days.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"It's an ambitious film to be made on a budget of Rs. 150 crores, and the entire team is very excited to bring the film to the audience in 2026."</blockquote>
<p>This collaboration could have significant implications for both Aaryan's and Johar's careers, merging their fanbases and setting high expectations for the film's success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/mega-exclusive-kartik-aaryan-karan-johar-join-hands-rs-150-crore-action-love-story-sameer-vidhwans-direct/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/mega-exclusive-kartik-aaryan-karan-johar-join-hands-rs-150-crore-action-love-story-sameer-vidhwans-direct/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:37:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2’s Dammunte Pattukora song taken down – Fans left confused - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2’s Dammunte Pattukora Song Taken Down – Fans Left Confused</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 25, 2024 5:58 pm IST</strong></p><p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/PushpA2-13.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Image" width="450" height="450"><figcaption>Icon Star Allu Arjun from Pushpa 2: The Rule.</figcaption></p><p>Icon Star Allu Arjun recently delivered a blockbuster with Pushpa 2: The Rule, which has grossed over Rs. 1500 crores in record time. T-Series Telugu released a new track titled Dammunte Pattukora, based on powerful dialogue from the film, but it was taken down shortly after release, leaving fans confused and questioning the abrupt removal.</p><ul><li>The song was based on a key dialogue from the film.</li><li>It was released by T-Series just yesterday.</li><li>Fans are left wondering why it was taken down so quickly.</li><li>The film features Rashmika Mandanna alongside Allu Arjun.</li></ul><blockquote>“Fans are now eagerly waiting to see when the track will return to the platform.”</blockquote><p>The confusion surrounds the quick removal, and only the Pushpa 2 team and T-Series may have the answers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/pushpa-2s-dammunte-pattukora-song-taken-down-fans-left-confused.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/pushpa-2s-dammunte-pattukora-song-taken-down-fans-left-confused.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Recap 2024: Top 10 K-Drama ACTRESSES Ranked! Kim Ji-Won To Park Shin-Hye, Chae Soo-Bin To Kim Hye-Yoon, Here A - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Recap 2024: Top 10 K-Drama Actresses Ranked!</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>2024<p>
<p><strong>Source: </strong>Times Now</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116656361,thumbsize-60446,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116656361.jpg" alt="Recap 2024: Top 10 K-Drama ACTRESSES Ranked! Kim Ji-Won To Park Shin-Hye, Chae Soo-Bin To Kim Hye-Yoon, Here Are The Winners" title="Recap 2024: Top 10 K-Drama ACTRESSES Ranked! Kim Ji-Won To Park Shin-Hye, Chae Soo-Bin To Kim Hye-Yoon, Here Are The Winners">
<figcaption>Recap 2024: Top 10 K-Drama ACTRESSES Ranked!</figcaption>
<p>2024 was one of the best years for performances, especially with women-centric themes. Here are the top 10 female performers who stole hearts with their career-defining roles.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>10. Han So-Hee - Gyeongseong Creature</strong>: An emotionally charged performance in a thrilling season.</li>
<li><strong>9. Seo Hyun-Jin - The Trunk</strong>: A versatile actress, delivering excellence in mystery and romance.</li>
<li><strong>8. Park Min-Young - Marry My Husband</strong>: Capturing heartbreak and angst in a riveting revenge story.</li>
<li><strong>7. Shin Min-Ah - No Gain No Love</strong>: A comedic talent that balances laughter and heartfelt moments.</li>
<li><strong>6. Jung So-Min - Love Next Door</strong>: A rom-com queen who embodies relatable bickering convincingly.</li>
<li><strong>5. Chae Soo-Bin - When The Phone Rings</strong>: An impressive portrayal of a selective mute through expressive acting.</li>
<li><strong>4. Jang Na-Ra - Good Partner</strong>: Transitioning from sweet roles to a cold-hearted lawyer brilliantly.</li>
<li><strong>3. Park Shin-Hye - The Judge From Hell</strong>: A character that's ruthless yet captivatingly complex.</li>
<li><strong>2. Kim Hye-Yoon - Lovely Runner</strong>: Exceptional performance across different life stages and her chemistry is noteworthy.</li>
<li><strong>1. Kim Ji-Won - Queen of Tears</strong>: Her maturity as an actress has propelled her to the top with standout performances.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Special Mention:</strong> <strong>Kim Go-Eun - Exhuma</strong>: A remarkable performance that outshines rankings with her blend of thrills and emotion.</p>
<p>Who is your favourite actress of 2024? Let us know at @TimesNow.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/korean/top-10-k-drama-actresses-of-2024-ranked-recap-kim-ji-won-park-shin-hye-chae-soo-bin-kim-hye-yoon-queen-of-tears-lovely-runner-when-the-phone-rings-article-116654247</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/korean/top-10-k-drama-actresses-of-2024-ranked-recap-kim-ji-won-park-shin-hye-chae-soo-bin-kim-hye-yoon-queen-of-tears-lovely-runner-when-the-phone-rings-article-116654247</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:27:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trailer Talk: Another Cult Crime Thriller? - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trailer Talk: Another Cult Crime Thriller?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not available <strong>Source: </strong>M9 News</p>
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/asif-alis-rekhachithram-trailer-768x576.jpg" alt="asif-alis-rekhachithram-trailer">
<figcaption>Teaser image for Rekhachithram</figcaption>
<p>Asif Ali returns with another crime thriller titled Rekhachithram, following the success of Kishkindha Kaandam. The recently released teaser has garnered positive audience responses.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Asif Ali's previous films have been successful, including blockbuster Kishkindha Kaandam.</li>
    <li>Director Jofin T. Chacko leads the project with Asif Ali and Anaswara Rajan in principal roles.</li>
    <li>High expectations surround Rekhachithram based on prior successes of Ali's films.</li>
    <li>There is concern that elevated expectations might lead to potential disappointment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Let us see if Rekhachithram lives up to the audience’s expectations and becomes another blockbuster success.”</blockquote>
<p>The audience eagerly anticipates the film's release, hoping it meets the high bar set by its predecessors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.m9.news/tamil-movie-news/asif-ali-murder-mystery-rekhachithram-after-kishkindha-kaandam/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.m9.news/tamil-movie-news/asif-ali-murder-mystery-rekhachithram-after-kishkindha-kaandam/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:51:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Barroz movie review: Mohanlal’s passion project ends up as a lost opportunity - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Barroz Movie Review: Mohanlal's Passion Project Ends Up as a Lost Opportunity</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/kerala/hxmji5/article69026034.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/barroz.jpg" alt="A still from ‘Barroz’"><figcaption>A still from ‘Barroz’ | Photo Credit: ‘</figcaption><p>Mohanlal’s dream project, Barroz, directed by him, has turned out to be a disappointing fantasy drama that fails to engage its audience deeply. Despite its ambitious premise, the film's unimaginative screenplay and overdramatic dialogues leave it feeling underdeveloped.</p><ul><li>The film is based on a children’s story about a ghost guarding a treasure linked to Portuguese rule in India.</li><li>Barroz’s screenplay was significantly altered early in production, leading to a lack of coherence.</li><li>Visual effects and 3D sequences, while decent, do not suffice to mask the film's deeper storytelling issues.</li><li>Critics note that the film lacks the charm and engagement expected from a children's film.</li></ul><blockquote>“Barroz ended up as a lost opportunity.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Barroz carries the weight of a well-known star and significant ambition, but ultimately fails to deliver a captivating or emotionally resonant experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/barroz-movie-review-mohanlals-passion-project-ends-up-as-a-lost-opportunity/article69026045.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/barroz-movie-review-mohanlals-passion-project-ends-up-as-a-lost-opportunity/article69026045.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kiara Advani deletes mention of POSCO-accused Jani Master from her Instagram post after facing backlash - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kiara Advani deletes mention of POSCO-accused Jani Master from her Instagram post after facing backlash</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p>
<img src="https://media5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Kiara_Advani_Shoutout_Jani_Master.jpg" alt="Kiara Advani deletes mention of POSCO-accused Jani Master from her Instagram post after facing backlash" width="620" height="450">
<figcaption>Kiara Advani deletes mention of POSCO-accused Jani Master from her Instagram post after facing backlash</figcaption>
<p>Actress Kiara Advani has sparked controversy by praising choreographer Jani Master in a recent Instagram post, leading to significant backlash due to his legal history.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kiara posted a video thanking Jani Master for his choreography related to her upcoming film, <em>Game Changer</em>.</li>
  <li>Social media users criticized her association with Jani Master, who has faced serious allegations under the POCSO Act.</li>
  <li>Jani Master was accused of sexual assault against a former employee when she was 16 years old.</li>
  <li>After backlash, Kiara edited her post to remove mention of Jani Master.</li>
  <li>Kiara's upcoming film <em>Game Changer</em> is set to release on January 10, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Tone-deaf, especially when even his national award was taken back after the uproar over granting him bail.”</blockquote>
<p>Kiara Advani's association with Jani Master has raised questions about accountability within the industry and the sensitivity of such public endorsements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/kiara-advani-deletes-mention-posco-accused-jani-master-instagram-post-facing-backlash/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/kiara-advani-deletes-mention-posco-accused-jani-master-instagram-post-facing-backlash/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:58:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun, Pushpa 2 makers announce ₹2 crore aid to Sandhya Theatre stampede victim's family - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun, Pushpa 2 makers announce ₹2 crore aid to Sandhya Theatre stampede victim's family</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/ANI-20241221328-0_1735123027720_1735123042951.jpg" alt="Actor Allu Arjun now facing charges in the case, was questioned by police on Tuesday regarding his involvement.(ANI)"><figcaption>Actor Allu Arjun now facing charges in the case, was questioned by police on Tuesday regarding his involvement.(ANI)</figcaption><p>This article discusses the financial support announced by Allu Aravind and others for the family of an eight-year-old boy injured in the tragic Sandhya Theatre stampede that occurred during a screening of Pushpa 2.</p><ul><li>Allu Aravind announced ₹2 crores to support the family of the injured boy.</li><li>The boy's mother was killed in the stampede, which happened on December 4.</li><li>Allu Arjun is currently facing investigation regarding his involvement in the incident.</li><li>The boy is recovering and has been taken off ventilator support, according to his father.</li></ul><blockquote>“The boy, Sri Teja, is recovering. Now he is not on a ventilator. To support the family, we should support him with ₹2 crore.” - Allu Aravind</blockquote><p>Despite the ongoing investigation, the support from the film industry highlights the community's response to a tragic incident, focusing on aiding the affected family during a difficult time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/allu-arjun-pushpa-2-makers-announce-2-crore-aid-for-sandhya-theatre-stampede-victims-family-101735120782208.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/allu-arjun-pushpa-2-makers-announce-2-crore-aid-for-sandhya-theatre-stampede-victims-family-101735120782208.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:43:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viduthalai Part - 2 Box Office Collection Day 6 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxNTXIyZjhadlJldm5CSUo3N2ZxWlk2Wl9CU2lyUm1ST05SWjRFSkhJX1U0dHRJUTVtSHRMQ2NjUHFGQ1dwSlJIY0lydHEwa1YwVjVGdTF4NjQxbjVjb3NVUmRMSUNqc0VxVGwwRHFRcURGMG0tLXFyTUpuSlVYNmhkVGQxNENrQnVpc3ptMGt3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxNTXIyZjhadlJldm5CSUo3N2ZxWlk2Wl9CU2lyUm1ST05SWjRFSkhJX1U0dHRJUTVtSHRMQ2NjUHFGQ1dwSlJIY0lydHEwa1YwVjVGdTF4NjQxbjVjb3NVUmRMSUNqc0VxVGwwRHFRcURGMG0tLXFyTUpuSlVYNmhkVGQxNENrQnVpc3ptMGt3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:36:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Day 20: Less Than 10 Crores Away From Becoming Third Indian Film In History To Achieve This Feat! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Day 20: Less Than 10 Crores Away From Becoming Third Indian Film In History To Achieve This Feat</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-day-20-less-than-10-crores-away-from-becoming-third-indian-film-in-history-to-achieve-this-feat.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Day 20" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Day 20 Update! (Photo Credit – Instagram)</figcaption><p>Pushpa 2, featuring Allu Arjun, Rashmika Mandanna, and Fahadh Faasil, continues to perform exceptionally well at the box office, rapidly approaching a significant milestone in Indian cinema.</p><h4><strong>Key Points:</strong></h4><ul><li>On its third Tuesday, the film earned <strong>15 crores</strong> net in the domestic market.</li><li>After 21 days, the domestic box office total stands at <strong>1109 crores</strong>.</li><li>The film is now the highest-grossing Indian film.</li><li>Worldwide gross earnings after 21 days total <strong>1590.27 crores</strong>, just <strong>less than 10 crores</strong> away from crossing <strong>1600 crores</strong>.</li><li>Previous records for Indian films at this level include <strong>Dangal</strong> and <strong>Baahubali 2</strong>.</li></ul><h4><strong>Notable Quotes or Statistics:</strong></h4><blockquote>Pushpa 2 is already the highest-grossing Indian film.</blockquote><p>Note: Box office numbers are based on estimates and have not been independently verified.</p><h4><strong>Conclusion:</strong></h4><p>As it stands, Pushpa 2 is on track to set new benchmarks in the Indian film industry, continuing to attract audiences even amidst strong competition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-day-20-less-than-10-crores-away-from-becoming-third-indian-film-in-history-to-achieve-this-feat/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-day-20-less-than-10-crores-away-from-becoming-third-indian-film-in-history-to-achieve-this-feat/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:33:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trisha Krishnan's 'son' Zorro passes away on Christmas, PS 2 actress says, 'I am broken and in a state of shock' - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxNVkxzRXRIT21yMjlvMFNsZWFnektLb3I0bUZUcW1XeUhmRmd6MWNmYTdRQW1zZFUtLXhmaHkxYmJNSlpPSl96VUthb2tsZHZPRldHYTdkRGd3WTUwNnlrRjI2TDJvSU5wc3ZkZkcxX2RUZzBPemNqM2syTWxhNEg5TGJ5MUYxZml3VUZ5UEVuTVNyamxRZHlTRHNPc3VJS3ZwRUx1UC04N042c001WTM5TWtkX08zT0JUd2Y0a0x5bzFWbjBmdWJRNWJPdktfT0tuTS1qWmpZNTd3NV9NNXVQOEFxdFVPVmJRN0hUM0Y4cjfSAfYBQVVfeXFMTWwxN1ppUC01Q2JqME4zZmRlWWFTU2NYUGU2bTdYcHB0dkVhWHpKV2xyZFNJNXg1YVlMQTljTzRhRVBKWXl1WDMtbm9VbWFHU2dUOWV4VWJmd2dtUjJSOS1fQy1PX1RmVkhfX0lwQklNeEtQelJ0V19QZEhyOWhTeVRKVkkwTzBkVTRZM1FQV3dOdkNqdHBFYzBpbXp0cjRGUzBQRzJyTUhFQXhELVBucGNCYnhrVUl1Zk1sMUxuQWZsa2FabjJTaks5cUdYR1lZQ19ZLThwbF91UEFKWnNCd1hjRWhHN1hBc0FxN0xWU25HNE1ha0dB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxNVkxzRXRIT21yMjlvMFNsZWFnektLb3I0bUZUcW1XeUhmRmd6MWNmYTdRQW1zZFUtLXhmaHkxYmJNSlpPSl96VUthb2tsZHZPRldHYTdkRGd3WTUwNnlrRjI2TDJvSU5wc3ZkZkcxX2RUZzBPemNqM2syTWxhNEg5TGJ5MUYxZml3VUZ5UEVuTVNyamxRZHlTRHNPc3VJS3ZwRUx1UC04N042c001WTM5TWtkX08zT0JUd2Y0a0x5bzFWbjBmdWJRNWJPdktfT0tuTS1qWmpZNTd3NV9NNXVQOEFxdFVPVmJRN0hUM0Y4cjfSAfYBQVVfeXFMTWwxN1ppUC01Q2JqME4zZmRlWWFTU2NYUGU2bTdYcHB0dkVhWHpKV2xyZFNJNXg1YVlMQTljTzRhRVBKWXl1WDMtbm9VbWFHU2dUOWV4VWJmd2dtUjJSOS1fQy1PX1RmVkhfX0lwQklNeEtQelJ0V19QZEhyOWhTeVRKVkkwTzBkVTRZM1FQV3dOdkNqdHBFYzBpbXp0cjRGUzBQRzJyTUhFQXhELVBucGNCYnhrVUl1Zk1sMUxuQWZsa2FabjJTaks5cUdYR1lZQ19ZLThwbF91UEFKWnNCd1hjRWhHN1hBc0FxN0xWU25HNE1ha0dB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:30:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Raha Kapoor gives flying kisses, says hello to the paps and melts the internet as she arrives with parent - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Raha Kapoor Melts Hearts Arriving for Christmas Lunch with Parents Ranbir Kapoor and Alia Bhatt</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 25, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116652246,imgsize-39516,width-400,resizemode-4/116652246.jpg" alt="Raha Kapoor arrives for Christmas lunch" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Raha Kapoor gives flying kisses as she arrives with her parents for the Christmas lunch.</figcaption><p>This Christmas, the Kapoor family gathered for their traditional lunch, where Raha Kapoor charmed everyone with her adorable greetings to the paparazzi.</p><ul><li>Raha was seen saying hello and waving at the paparazzi, which made Alia Bhatt laugh heartily.</li><li>Ranbir Kapoor playfully carried Raha and asked if she wanted to stand outside the car.</li><li>Alia requested the photographers to be gentle around Raha, noting that she gets scared.</li><li>Alia was dressed in a stunning red dress while Raha wore a lovely white frock.</li><li>Ranbir was pictured looking stylish with a moustache, embodying his 'Love And War' character.</li><li>Both Ranbir and Alia are working on upcoming films, with Ranbir also involved in the project 'Ramayana' set to start next year.</li></ul><blockquote>“Thoda dheere, usko darr lagta hai (Be soft, she gets scared),” Alia Bhatt told the paparazzi.</blockquote><p>The affectionate moment shared by the Kapoor family reflects their deep bond, charming fans during the festive season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/raha-kapoor-says-hello-to-the-paps-throws-flying-kisses-and-melts-the-internet-as-she-arrives-with-parents-ranbir-kapoor-and-alia-bhatt-for-the-christmas-lunch-watch-video/articleshow/116652259.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/raha-kapoor-says-hello-to-the-paps-throws-flying-kisses-and-melts-the-internet-as-she-arrives-with-parents-ranbir-kapoor-and-alia-bhatt-for-the-christmas-lunch-watch-video/articleshow/116652259.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>