<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:26:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:26:08 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ananya Panday calls long-distance relationship ‘healthy’ amidst dating rumours with Walker Blanco - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ananya Panday Discusses Long-Distance Relationships Amidst Dating Rumors</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/Ananya_Panday_1733379575904_1735549788535.jpg" alt="Ananya Panday talked about long-distance relationships." title="Ananya Panday talked about long-distance relationships."><figcaption>Ananya Panday talked about long-distance relationships.</figcaption><p>Ananya Panday is currently rumored to be dating Walker Blanco, and she recently shared her thoughts on long-distance relationships during an interview, stating they can be 'healthy.'</p><ul><li>Ananya attended Anant Ambani and Radhika Merchant’s wedding with Walker Blanco.</li><li>In a new interview, she highlighted the benefits of having space in a relationship.</li><li>She reflected on her growth and comfort in her identity within relationships.</li><li>Her upcoming projects include a second season of 'Call Me Bae' and a romantic drama 'Chaand Mera Dil.'</li></ul><blockquote>“I actually think it is quite healthy sometimes to have some space. Two months is okay. Actually, distance does make the heart grow fonder.” - Ananya Panday</blockquote><p>Ananya Panday's evolving perspective on relationships reflects her personal growth, suggesting that distance may indeed enhance connections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/ananya-panday-calls-long-distance-relationship-healthy-amidst-dating-rumours-with-walker-blanco-101735549530255.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/ananya-panday-calls-long-distance-relationship-healthy-amidst-dating-rumours-with-walker-blanco-101735549530255.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chinese Snake Horoscope 2025: A Year to Shine and Set Goals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chinese Snake Horoscope 2025: A Year to Shine and Set Goals</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Unknown] <strong>Source:</strong> [Unknown]</p>
<p>This article explores the astrological predictions for individuals born under the Snake sign in the year 2025, emphasizing new opportunities, personal goals, and overall growth.</p>
<ul>
<li>2025 is seen as a year of prosperity for those born under the Snake sign.</li>
<li>Encouragement to set and pursue personal goals.</li>
<li>Predictions align with trends in career advancement and personal relationships.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Snake will find guidance in the stars to attain their dreams this year."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, 2025 is portrayed as a promising year for Snakes, encouraging them to seize opportunities for improvement and success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/astrology/vastu-feng-shui/chinese-snake-horoscope-2025-a-year-to-shine-and-set-goals/articleshow/116618776.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/astrology/vastu-feng-shui/chinese-snake-horoscope-2025-a-year-to-shine-and-set-goals/articleshow/116618776.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shalini Passi says she married at 20, had a son at 21 but had one important condition for husband: ‘He should not…’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shalini Passi: Marrying Young and Having a Child at 21, with No Regrets</h1><p><strong>Date: 2024-12-01, Source: Indian Express</strong></p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Shalini-Passi-3.jpg?w=640" alt="Shalini Passi on marrying young" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Shalini Passi shares marrying at 20 was the greatest move. (Photo: Shalini Passi/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Shalini Passi, known for her appearances in 'Fabulous Lives vs Bollywood Wives,' has shared her perspective on getting married at 20 and becoming a mother at 21. In an interview with Mojo Story, she expressed no regrets about her decision, describing it as a 'great move by the universe.'</p><ol><li>Shalini had an arranged marriage with Sanjay Passi, the owner of the PASCO group, after his family spotted her at a wedding.</li><li>She had a condition for her arranged marriage: her husband should not drink, smoke, or gamble.</li><li>Despite initial challenges, Shalini mastered the art of hosting and adapted to her new lifestyle.</li><li>She is known for her love for art and philanthropic work.</li></ol><blockquote>“It was a very good move by the universe because I had so much energy and enthusiasm back then. What happens with women is later in their life, the energy and recovery gets extremely different. When young, you recover early. I became a mom at 21. Because I was young, I used to get more excited than my son when I took him to a toy store. Its like I am almost living my life in reverse.”</blockquote><p>Shalini Passi reflects on her young marriage and motherhood, emphasizing her enthusiasm and energy during that period.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/web-series/shalini-passi-says-she-married-at-20-had-a-son-at-21-but-had-one-important-condition-for-husband-9751353/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/web-series/shalini-passi-says-she-married-at-20-had-a-son-at-21-but-had-one-important-condition-for-husband-9751353/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:29:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shweta Tiwari Reacts To Palak Tiwari And Ibrahim Ali Khan Dating Rumours: 'They Will Forget...' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shweta Tiwari Unfazed by Palak Tiwari and Ibrahim Ali Khan's Dating Rumors</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Last Updated: December 30, 2024, 17:51 IST</p>
<figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&width=360&height=270" alt="Shweta Tiwari says Palak Tiwari's dating rumours do not bother her. (Photos: Instagram)" title="Shweta Tiwari says Palak Tiwari's dating rumours do not bother her. (Photos: Instagram)"><figcaption>Shweta Tiwari says Palak Tiwari's dating rumours do not bother her. (Photos: Instagram)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Actress Shweta Tiwari has reacted to the persistent dating rumors surrounding her daughter, Palak Tiwari, and actor Ibrahim Ali Khan. While the two have repeatedly dismissed the rumors, Shweta has now revealed that she no longer lets such speculations bother her.</p>
<p>In a recent interview, Shweta expressed her indifference towards the rumors, stating that people's memory spans are short and that negativity sells in the media. She also mentioned that she has dealt with similar situations in the past and has learned to not let them affect her.</p>
<p>Palak and Ibrahim's dating rumors first surfaced in 2022 when they were photographed together. However, they have maintained that they are just friends. Palak, in an interview with Siddharth Kannan, clarified that they were with a group of people when they were snapped together and that there was no romantic involvement between them.</p>
<p>On the work front, Palak was last seen in Salman Khan's <em>Kisi Ka Bhai Kisi Ki Jaan</em>.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/shweta-tiwari-reacts-to-palak-tiwari-and-ibrahim-ali-khan-dating-rumours-they-will-forget-9172347.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/shweta-tiwari-reacts-to-palak-tiwari-and-ibrahim-ali-khan-dating-rumours-they-will-forget-9172347.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:25:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sangeeta Bijlani confirms she almost married Salman Khan, says ex didn’t let her wear short dress: ‘I changed that part of my life’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sangeeta Bijlani confirms she almost married Salman Khan, says ex didn’t let her wear short dress: ‘I changed that part of my life’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Sangeeta-Bijlani-1.jpg?w=640" alt="Sangeeta Bijlani on her relationship" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Sangeeta Bijlani confirms she almost married Salman Khan. (Photo: Sangeeta Bijlani/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Sangeeta Bijlani reminisces about her long relationship with Salman Khan, revealing they were on the verge of marriage before he called it off at the last minute. She discusses the restrictions placed on her during their relationship and expresses how she has changed since then.</p><ul><li>Sangeeta Bijlani dated Salman Khan for nearly a decade.</li><li>The couple had finalized their wedding plans before Salman called it off.</li><li>Bijlani shared her past restrictions on clothing choices imposed by her ex.</li><li>She expressed a desire to change that restrictive period of her life.</li><li>Bijlani confirmed that wedding invitations were printed before their breakup.</li></ul><blockquote>“I was very constricted that ‘you can’t wear short dresses... I was a little shy then. Now, I am a total gundi.” - Sangeeta Bijlani</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Sangeeta Bijlani reflects on her past relationship with Salman Khan, acknowledging how she has transformed and embraced her individuality since those years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/sangeeta-bijlani-confirms-she-almost-married-salman-khan-says-ex-didnt-let-her-wear-short-dress-9751435/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/sangeeta-bijlani-confirms-she-almost-married-salman-khan-says-ex-didnt-let-her-wear-short-dress-9751435/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hidden Love actor Zhao Lusi's pic in wheelchair goes viral, team shares statement - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chinese Actress Zhao Lusi Hospitalized: Team Suspends Work for Recovery</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 30, 2024, by Zinia Bandyopadhyay</strong></p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/chinese-actor-zhao-lusis-team-shares-statement-after-her-hospitalisation-300822265-16x9_0.jpg" width="690" height="388" alt="Chinese actor Zhao Lusi's team shares statement" title="Chinese actor Zhao Lusi's team shares statement after her hospitalisation."><figcaption>Chinese actor Zhao Lusi's team shares statement after her hospitalisation.</figcaption>
<p>Chinese actress Zhao Lusi, known for her role in Hidden Love, was recently hospitalized, sparking concerns over her health. Her team shared a statement announcing a suspension of all work commitments to allow for a speedy recovery.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Zhao was seen in a wheelchair as she was rushed to the hospital on December 18, with footage of the incident going viral on social media.</li>
  <li>Speculations about her health have been circulating, with online rumors pointing to severe depression or a neurological condition, possibly due to work-related stress.</li>
  <li>Zhao's management confirmed she has suspended all work commitments due to a health crisis but withheld details about her condition.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"After Ms. Zhao Lusi confirmed to play the role of Ruan Yu in the project 'Lovers', she actively carried out preparatory work and fulfilled the purpose of the contract. [...] We will prioritise the health of Ms. Zhao Lusi and suspend all subsequent work. We also hope that everyone who cares about Lusi will give her space to rest physically and mentally."</blockquote>
<p>Zhao, 26, began her acting journey in 2017 and has starred in hit series like The Romance of Tiger and Rose, Dating in the Kitchen, Love Better Than Immortality, Love Like the Galaxy, and Hidden Love.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/television/international-shows/story/c-drama-hidden-love-actor-zhao-lusi-health-concern-hospitalised-wheelchair-pic-2657279-2024-12-30</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/television/international-shows/story/c-drama-hidden-love-actor-zhao-lusi-health-concern-hospitalised-wheelchair-pic-2657279-2024-12-30</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:09:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin: Savi finally expresses her love for Rajat at the airport; says 'I Love You' - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Savi Confesses Her Love for Rajat at the Airport in Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Monday, December 30, 2024 at 9:56 AM | <strong>Source:</strong> Star Plus</p><figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/9612-rajat.jpg" width="640" height="360" alt="Rajat"><figcaption>Savi finally confesses her feelings for Rajat</figcaption></figure><p>In a dramatic turn of events on the popular show Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin, Savi realizes her feelings for Rajat just as he is about to leave for Singapore. This confrontation leads to a heartfelt moment where both characters express their love for each other.</p><ul><li>Savi rushes to the airport with Rajat’s mom, Bhagyashree, as Rajat prepares to leave.</li><li>Rajat believes he is a burden to Savi and plans to move to Singapore permanently.</li><li>After a series of misunderstandings and manipulations by a character named Arsh, Rajat and Savi's relationship faces turmoil.</li><li>Ultimately, Savi confronts Rajat at the airport and they share an emotional embrace, leading Rajat to cancel his trip.</li></ul><blockquote>“I love you,” Savi expresses as she tries to stop Rajat from leaving.</blockquote><p>This pivotal moment showcases the deep emotional connection between Savi and Rajat, hinting at future developments in their relationship.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-savi-finally-expresses-her-love-for-rajat-at-the-airport-says-i-love-yo_216121</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-savi-finally-expresses-her-love-for-rajat-at-the-airport-says-i-love-yo_216121</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:00:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BTS postpones content releases, expresses condolences for Jeju Air tragedy - allkpop]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BTS Postpones Content Releases and Honors Victims of Jeju Air Tragedy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> allkpop</p><img src="/upload/2024/12/content/300457/1735552623-2024-12-30-6.png" alt="BTS Condolences"/><figcaption>BTS expresses condolences for the Jeju Air tragedy.</figcaption><p>BTS and their agency, BIGHIT MUSIC, have expressed their condolences for the victims of the Jeju Air tragedy that occurred on December 29th, resulting in significant loss of life.</p><ul><li>BIGHIT MUSIC announced the postponement of content releases, including Episode 16 of 'Run Jin'.</li><li>The Jeju Air tragedy led to 179 fatalities out of 181 passengers.</li><li>Nationwide mourning is taking place, impacting events in the entertainment industry.</li></ul><blockquote>“We extend our deepest condolences and sympathies to the victims of the aviation accident and their families.” - BIGHIT MUSIC</blockquote><p>This incident has profoundly affected the community, prompting many in the entertainment industry to show their respect by canceling or postponing events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.allkpop.com/article/2024/12/bts-postpones-content-releases-expresses-condolences-for-jeju-air-tragedy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.allkpop.com/article/2024/12/bts-postpones-content-releases-expresses-condolences-for-jeju-air-tragedy</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Only 1 Indian actor made it to The Independent's list of Best Actors of 21st century. It's not Shah Rukh Khan, Amitabh - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Independent listed 60 best actors of the 21st century. Not Shah Rukh Khan, Aamir Khan or Amitabh Bachchan, but this Indian actor made the cut.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Independent</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/irrfan_1_1735546025534_1735546039246.jpg" alt="Only Irrfan Khan made it to The Independent's list of best actors of the 21st century." title="Only Irrfan Khan made it to The Independent's list of best actors of the 21st century."><figcaption>Only Irrfan Khan made it to The Independent's list of best actors of the 21st century.</figcaption></figure><p>The Independent has curated a list of the 60 best actors of the 21st century. Notably, the list includes international talents while specifically excluding performances from films released after 2000.</p><ul><li>Irrfan Khan is the only Indian actor to be featured on the list, ranked at #41.</li><li>Other prominent Indian actors such as Shah Rukh Khan, Aamir Khan, and Amitabh Bachchan are absent from this list.</li><li>The late actor celebrated for his roles in films such as The Warrior, Haasil, and Life of Pi.</li><li>Philip Seymour Hoffman was recognized as the best actor, with female representation by Emma Stone, ranked at #2.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s Irrfan Khan’s eyes, hooded and deep brown, that will live eternally. They granted him the ability to weave magic, to recite poetry without moving his lips.”</blockquote><p>The recognition of Irrfan Khan amidst international talents highlights his impactful performances and legacy in cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/irrfan-khan-only-indian-actor-independent-list-best-actors-21st-century-not-shah-rukh-khan-aamir-khan-amitabh-bachchan-101735545615521.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/irrfan-khan-only-indian-actor-independent-list-best-actors-21st-century-not-shah-rukh-khan-aamir-khan-amitabh-bachchan-101735545615521.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max (Kannada) Box Office Collection Day 5 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxOVHJwUGlyajNNcUd0MF9lTFE0dU1RQlVLdnAxQjJteE1QYW1Na2phcVZDYlp3ZjFyQ3NJOUhZSXlLTS1OMFcycEFYN3EtX2tleE1CeTBnaDJnenlzSXV6UGpqTDA2bmtFUHBLZUV6N3ZBT2JfdUhXREZGUVJPVkZjaE1tdzk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxOVHJwUGlyajNNcUd0MF9lTFE0dU1RQlVLdnAxQjJteE1QYW1Na2phcVZDYlp3ZjFyQ3NJOUhZSXlLTS1OMFcycEFYN3EtX2tleE1CeTBnaDJnenlzSXV6UGpqTDA2bmtFUHBLZUV6N3ZBT2JfdUhXREZGUVJPVkZjaE1tdzk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:41:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Sanjay Leela Bhansali signs KD director Prem for Rowdy Rathore 2; Scripting in progress - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sanjay Leela Bhansali Signs Director Prem for Rowdy Rathore 2; Scripting in Progress</h1><p><strong>Date & Source: Dec 30, 2024 | 02:59 PM IST | Pinkvilla</strong></p><img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/422270536_ananya-4.jpg" width="855" height="855" alt="Will Akshay Kumar return to Rowdy Rathore 2" title="Picture Courtesy: Pinkvilla/X"><figcaption>Picture Courtesy: Pinkvilla/X</figcaption><p>Over the years, there has been constant chatter on the sequel to Akshay Kumar’s 2012 blockbuster, Rowdy Rathore, which was produced by Sanjay Leela Bhansali and directed by Prabhudeva. Several names have been floating around in the media to carry forward this cop-based action entertainer. Now, we have exclusively learned that Sanjay Leela Bhansali has signed Kannada film director Prem and has entrusted him with the responsibility of developing the script for Rowdy Rathore 2.</p><p>According to sources close to the development, Sanjay Leela Bhansali is very excited to bankroll the sequel to Rowdy Rathore and had locked the core plot of the film a while back. The basic idea of Rowdy Rathore 2 has been in place for the longest time, and SLB was looking to partner with the right forces to develop a banger of a sequel to this 2012 blockbuster. His thoughts have aligned with Prem, and the duo is working towards developing the script of Rowdy Rathore 2.</p><p>The source further added that the Rowdy Rathore sequel will move into the casting stage once the screenplay is locked. Prem will full-fledgedly move into the pre-production of Rowdy Rathore 2 after the release of KD – The Devil. The film is expected to take off sometime by the end of 2025, and the casting will begin from Summer next year. Right now, the energies are being invested to develop a script that does justice to the legacy of the first part.</p><p>Will Akshay Kumar return to Rowdy Rathore 2? "We shall know that at the right time. It could be Akshay Kumar, a new hero, or who knows, a two-hero film too," the source concluded.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-sanjay-leela-bhansali-signs-kd-director-prem-for-rowdy-rathore-2-scripting-in-progress-1364865</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-sanjay-leela-bhansali-signs-kd-director-prem-for-rowdy-rathore-2-scripting-in-progress-1364865</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:29:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kangana shares pic of herself with Preity, Yami, Ranta, says Himachal women ‘equal or better looking’ than any of us - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/himachal/kangana-shares-picture-of-preity-yami-pratibha-ranta-says-himachal-women-equal-or-better-looking-than-any-of-us/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/himachal/kangana-shares-picture-of-preity-yami-pratibha-ranta-says-himachal-women-equal-or-better-looking-than-any-of-us/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:24:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today LIVE Updates on December 30, 2024 : Monthly Horoscope for January 2025: A Time for Achievements and Growth - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Horoscope for December 30, 2024: Monthly Predictions for January 2025</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Live Updates, December 30, 2024, <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology">Hindustan Times</a></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/1_1730985929261_1735550315632.jpg" alt="Horoscope Today LIVE Updates" title="Horoscope Today LIVE Updates" width="550" height="309" loading="lazy" decoding="async"><figcaption>Horoscope Today LIVE Updates: Monthly Horoscope for January 2025: A Time for Achievements and Growth</figcaption><p>Your horoscope today reveals insights into love, career, and health, guiding you toward a fulfilling day. Find out how the stars align for you, offering gentle reminders and helpful advice to take on the day with confidence and positive energy. This is an AI-generated live blog and has not been edited by Hindustan Times staff.</p><ol><li>Monthly horoscope for January 2025 for all zodiac signs is available <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/monthly-horoscope-for-january-2025-a-time-for-achievements-and-growth-101735549483381.html">here</a>.</li><li>Horoscope for December 31, 2024 is available <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-tomorrow-december-31-2024-read-predictions-for-all-sun-signs-101735502128248.html">here</a>.</li><li>Numerology prediction for December 30, 2024 is available <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/numerology-horoscope-today-predictions-for-december-30-2024-101735495786597.html">here</a>.</li><li>Weekly love horoscope for December 30 – January 5, 2025 is available <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-love-horoscope-for-december-30-january-5-2025-101735499967666.html">here</a>.</li><li>Daily horoscopes for each zodiac sign are available <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope">here</a>.</li><li>Weekly career horoscope for December 30 – January 5, 2025 is available <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-career-horoscope-for-december-30-january-5-2025-101735498639928.html">here</a>.</li><li>Astrological prediction for December 30, 2024 is available <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-astrological-prediction-for-december-30-2024-101735475559883.html">here</a>.</li></ol>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-live-updates-december-30-2024-101735500619047.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-live-updates-december-30-2024-101735500619047.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:19:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office (25 Days): Allu Arjun's Magnum Opus Is Just 19.53 Crores Away From Achieving A Big Milestone - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxNZXFyZUpJRzhiOEthQng2MFZQQlhxcWxQVEhiRGVTamxSWE9qdDEwZmFLV29zSjg2UVZqa1pjRXN5V29Ya1F0ZUFxQUxQN2JHbTZRQlZFUExxenFhUWdFTzVRbEtSeUpqdTBmSl9Ua210LU1qYVdveE9GRVc2c1d2VGtVUTBfUGVZRVZRd0ZiT1lyNVhDN2UwYXdPSGJlMno4bExTMXZfbUxjajh1RnM2cHRZV0NxNmUwMlhlbDlDNndhbHRkUmxvVmg2MFJndmlOeW1pSlVCWF84Z1piOFcyZnFvcUlfWENJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxNZXFyZUpJRzhiOEthQng2MFZQQlhxcWxQVEhiRGVTamxSWE9qdDEwZmFLV29zSjg2UVZqa1pjRXN5V29Ya1F0ZUFxQUxQN2JHbTZRQlZFUExxenFhUWdFTzVRbEtSeUpqdTBmSl9Ua210LU1qYVdveE9GRVc2c1d2VGtVUTBfUGVZRVZRd0ZiT1lyNVhDN2UwYXdPSGJlMno4bExTMXZfbUxjajh1RnM2cHRZV0NxNmUwMlhlbDlDNndhbHRkUmxvVmg2MFJndmlOeW1pSlVCWF84Z1piOFcyZnFvcUlfWENJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:14:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shweta Tiwari REACTS to rumours of Ibrahim Ali Khan dating Palak Tiwari: 'As per rumours, my daughter is - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shweta Tiwari Reacts to Rumors of Ibrahim Ali Khan Dating Palak Tiwari</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source: 13th August, 2023, Times of India</strong></p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116795144,imgsize-52346,width-400,resizemode-4/116795144.jpg" alt="Shweta Tiwari REACTS to rumours of Ibrahim Ali Khan dating Palak Tiwari: 'As per rumours, my daughter is dating every third guy'"><figcaption>Shweta Tiwari</figcaption>
<p>Rumors have been circulating about Saif Ali Khan's son, Ibrahim Ali Khan, and Shweta Tiwari's daughter, Palak Tiwari, being in a relationship. They have been spotted together in the city and at social gatherings, and it was recently speculated that they were holidaying together in the Maldives. Shweta Tiwari has now reacted to these dating rumors.</p>
<blockquote>
  "Rumours don’t bother me anymore... As per rumours, my daughter is dating every third guy, and I am getting married every year. As per the internet, I am already married thrice. These things don’t affect me now."
  <footer>Shweta Tiwari</footer>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
  "We were just out, and we got papped. It ends there... We are nice friends. He is a very sweet guy. That’s all there is to it. We talk sometimes and that’s all."
  <footer>Palak Tiwari</footer>
</blockquote>
<p>Earlier, Saif Ali Khan had also reacted to Ibrahim's dating life, saying, "He discusses his work and girlfriend/s with me, while Sara talks to me about her work."</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/shweta-tiwari-reacts-to-rumours-of-ibrahim-ali-khan-dating-palak-tiwari-as-per-rumours-my-daughter-is-dating-every-third-guy/articleshow/116795133.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/shweta-tiwari-reacts-to-rumours-of-ibrahim-ali-khan-dating-palak-tiwari-as-per-rumours-my-daughter-is-dating-every-third-guy/articleshow/116795133.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Srikanth Odela about his film with Chiru – You won’t see vintage Megastar - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Srikanth Odela about his film with Chiru – You won’t see vintage Megastar</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 30, 2024 2:33 pm IST</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/chiru.jpg" alt="Chiranjeevi" width="550" height="413">
<figcaption>Chiranjeevi in his upcoming film directed by Srikanth Odela.</figcaption>
<p>Megastar Chiranjeevi's collaboration with Dasara director Srikanth Odela is finally happening, much to the delight of fans. This long-awaited project promises to set a fresh tone for the iconic star.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Chiranjeevi teams up with new-age filmmaker Srikanth Odela.</li>
  <li>The film will be set against a period backdrop.</li>
  <li>Odela expresses his disbelief at working with Chiranjeevi, citing a lifelong admiration.</li>
  <li>He emphasizes that viewers will not see the traditional vintage Megastar.</li>
  <li>The script was finalized in just 48 hours with Chiranjeevi's enthusiasm inspiring Odela.</li>
  <li>Odela's upcoming film follows 'The Paradise' with actor Nani.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“You won’t see the vintage Megastar. Instead, you will see him in an age-appropriate and fresh role.” - Srikanth Odela</blockquote>
<p>This project marks an exciting new chapter for both Srikanth Odela and Chiranjeevi, as it aims to present the Megastar in a modern light.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/srikanth-odela-about-his-film-with-chiru-you-wont-see-vintage-megastar.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/srikanth-odela-about-his-film-with-chiru-you-wont-see-vintage-megastar.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pawan finds no fault with both Allu Arjun, Revanth.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pawan Kalyan Addresses Sandhya Theatre Incident Without Blame</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 4, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/pawan_new31735548853.jpg" alt="Pawan finds no fault with both Allu Arjun, Revanth"><figcaption>Pawan Kalyan Addresses the Media</figcaption><p>Pawan Kalyan, the Jana Sena Party president and Andhra Pradesh's deputy chief minister, spoke on the tragic Sandhya Theatre stampede incident that resulted in the death of a woman and the hospitalization of her son, choosing not to assign blame to individuals involved.</p><ul><li>Pawan Kalyan expressed that excitement for film stars can lead to overwhelming situations and reiterated that Allu Arjun should not be criticized for his behavior during the incident.</li><li>He emphasized the importance of proper precautions during such events and noted that the situation could have been managed better.</li><li>Kalyan highlighted the need for artists to show empathy towards affected individuals, suggesting that Allu Arjun should have taken steps to support the victims shortly after the incident occurred.</li><li>He acknowledged the police's efforts in maintaining security during events and praised the leadership of Revanth Reddy.</li><li>The deputy chief minister mentioned that in the film industry, collaboration is key and stressed that attributing sole blame to Allu Arjun is unfair.</li></ul><blockquote>Pawan Kalyan stated, “In cinema, it's a team effort, and everyone should be a part of it. In this case, Allu Arjun has been made the sole culprit, which I believe is not right.”</blockquote><p>The discussion highlighted the need for better management of crowd situations at public events and the responsibilities of public figures in ensuring safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/gossip/pawan-finds-no-fault-with-both-allu-arjun-revanth-143090</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/gossip/pawan-finds-no-fault-with-both-allu-arjun-revanth-143090</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:56:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max (Kannada) Box Office Collection Day 6 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQYjUyOHVUdTBrNldoOWVFaHk0eTdqQ2g2R1lha1BUQkJpVHg2X3pybXdGdTBTVjM3V3BnTE00UWg4dVpnUEsyT3k0eGhsWEFINURjU3g1Yy1LQzYwUFNqNEZDbHpadEhJT2VSWnVNbk1NemVEWUYwbUotZUVSZ3h5UlpsTFQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQYjUyOHVUdTBrNldoOWVFaHk0eTdqQ2g2R1lha1BUQkJpVHg2X3pybXdGdTBTVjM3V3BnTE00UWg4dVpnUEsyT3k0eGhsWEFINURjU3g1Yy1LQzYwUFNqNEZDbHpadEhJT2VSWnVNbk1NemVEWUYwbUotZUVSZ3h5UlpsTFQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:33:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai: Abhir Regains consciousness; accuses Vidya for Hit-and-Run case - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai: Abhir Accuses Vidya After Regaining Consciousness</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Monday, December 30, 2024 at 8:28 AM</p><figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/9608-yeh-rishta-kya-kehlata-hai-abhir-regains-consciousness-accuses-vidya-for-hit-and-run-case.jpg" alt="Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai: Abhir Regains consciousness; accuses Vidya for Hit-and-Run case" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Abhir gains consciousness and family members inquire about the person who did accident</figcaption></figure><p>In the upcoming episode of the show, Abhir wakes up post-accident and identifies Vidya as the person involved, shocking both Armaan and Abhira.</p><ul><li>After an accident involving Abhir and Vidya, Vidya unintentionally hits Abhir with her car due to brake failure.</li><li>Vidya panics and leaves the scene, leading to Abhir being rushed to the hospital.</li><li>Upon regaining consciousness, Abhir accuses Vidya, causing immediate distress for his family.</li><li>Abhira stands up for Abhir, believing he will be vindicated.</li><li>The episode highlights relationship dynamics, with Armaan seeking reconciliation with Abhira while facing challenges from Kaveri.</li></ul><blockquote>“Abhira stands firm in defending Abhir's innocence.”</blockquote><p>This episode promises dramatic developments surrounding Abhir's accusation and its effect on relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/yeh-rishta-kya-kehlata-hai-abhir-regains-consciousness-accuses-vidya-for-hit-and-run-case_216117</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/yeh-rishta-kya-kehlata-hai-abhir-regains-consciousness-accuses-vidya-for-hit-and-run-case_216117</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:30:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Latest : Pawan Kalyan comments on Allu Arjun - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pawan Kalyan Comments on Allu Arjun Incident</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 30, 2024 | Source: 123telugu</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/allu-arjun-pawan-kaalyan.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun and Pawan Kalyan" width="600" height="400">
<figcaption>Pawan Kalyan and Allu Arjun</figcaption>
<p>Pushpa 2's premiere tragedy and Allu Arjun's arrest sparked debates. Pawan Kalyan, for the first time, shares his perspective.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Pawan Kalyan appreciates Telangana CM Revanth Reddy's support to the film industry.</li>
  <li>He expresses sadness over Revathi's death and criticizes the lack of empathy shown.</li>
  <li>Kalyan believes Allu Arjun shouldn't be solely blamed for the incident.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote><p>"A minor issue was unnecessarily turned into a major controversy... The law is equal for everyone." - Pawan Kalyan</p></blockquote>
<p>Pawan Kalyan suggests better communication and empathy to handle such situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/latest-pawan-kalyan-comments-on-allu-arjun.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/latest-pawan-kalyan-comments-on-allu-arjun.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope for Aquarius from Dec 30 to Jan 5, 2025: Recipients of the letter should consider positions in creative fields or those that afford creative freedom - OTV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope for Aquarius from Dec 30 to Jan 5, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Date not specified by source</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Odishatv Bureau</p>
<img src="https://images.odishatv.in/uploadimage/library/16_9/16_9_3/IMAGE_1621847072.jpeg" alt="Odishatv Bureau" title="Odishatv Bureau">
<figcaption>Astrology insights for Aquarius</figcaption>
<p>This week, Aquarians can expect a surge of energy fueling creative pursuits. It’s a favorable time to engage in projects that leverage their creativity at work, and enjoy a bit of fun in their love lives.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Motivation to pursue creative projects at work.</li>
  <li>Consider roles that allow for creative freedom.</li>
  <li>Singles may find confidence drawing in potential partners.</li>
  <li>Best time for fun dates or surprises for partners.</li>
  <li>Thursday is highlighted as a lucky day for love.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is the time to bring out your creativity in your career.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this week promises a mix of creativity and romantic opportunities for Aquarius individuals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://odishatv.in/astrospeak/aquarius/weekly-horoscope-30-dec-2024-to-05-jan-2025-recipients-of-the-letter-should-consider-positions-in-creative-fields-or-those-that-afford-creative-freedom-252189</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://odishatv.in/astrospeak/aquarius/weekly-horoscope-30-dec-2024-to-05-jan-2025-recipients-of-the-letter-should-consider-positions-in-creative-fields-or-those-that-afford-creative-freedom-252189</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:57:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Box Office Collections: Allu Arjun film nears 1300cr in India after fourth weekend - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Collections: Allu Arjun film nears 1300cr in India after fourth weekend</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 30, 2024 | Source: Pinkvilla</strong></p>
<img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/2072197158_pushpa-2.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2" title="Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)</figcaption>
<p>By the end of its fourth weekend, Pushpa 2 is expected to gross around Rs. 1330 crore, inching closer to the record.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pushpa 2 grossed Rs. 39.50 crore approx at the Indian box office in its fourth weekend.</li>
  <li>Total gross as of now stands at Rs. 1294 crore approx.</li>
  <li>The film's record-setting ETA is projected for the fifth weekend.</li>
  <li>The territorial breakdown shows significant earnings across various regions, with a total of Rs. 1293.50 crore in India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The fourth week has the one big holiday for New Year's Day, which could lead to increased collections.”</blockquote>
<p>The success of Pushpa 2 continues to build momentum, setting it up for a record-breaking performance soon.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collections-allu-arjun-film-nears-1300cr-in-india-after-fourth-weekend-1364847</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collections-allu-arjun-film-nears-1300cr-in-india-after-fourth-weekend-1364847</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:46:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rana Daggubati unveils ‘Bapu’ first look poster - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rana Daggubati unveils ‘Bapu’ first look poster</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 1:15 pm IST</p><img src='https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bappu.jpg' alt='Bapu First Look' width='353' height='500'><figcaption>First look poster for 'Bapu'</figcaption><p>Rana Daggubati has released the first look for the upcoming film 'Bapu', a dark comedy-drama that promises to blend humor with emotional depth.</p><ul><li>Produced by Comrade Film Factory, 'Bapu' is directed by Daya.</li><li>The film features Brahmaji and a stellar ensemble cast including Amani, Balagam Sudhakar Reddy, and Dhanya Balakrishna.</li><li>The plot centers on a farming family facing a profound emotional dilemma.</li><li>The film combines a dark premise with dark comedy.</li></ul><blockquote>“It tackles grave situations with humor to present an unconventional yet poignant narrative.”</blockquote><p>The film aims to offer a unique experience by intertwining family dynamics with humor and emotion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/rana-daggubati-unveils-bapu-first-look-poster.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/rana-daggubati-unveils-bapu-first-look-poster.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin: Savi slaps Rajat at the airport to stop him - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin: Savi slaps Rajat at the airport to stop him</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Monday, December 30, 2024 at 7:24 AM</p><figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/9601-rajat.jpg" width="640" height="360" alt="Rajat" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Savi slaps Rajat at the airport</figcaption></figure><p>In the upcoming episode, Rajat plans to permanently relocate to Singapore, causing Savi to confront him in a moment of emotional turmoil.</p><ul><li>Rajat, manipulated by Arsh, believes Savi is having an affair, leading to jealousy and accusations.</li><li>Rajat aims to distance himself from Savi to allow her to move forward in life.</li><li>During an emotional confrontation at the airport, Savi slaps Rajat to express her deep love and desire for him to stay.</li><li>Rajat, realizing Savi's feelings, ultimately decides not to go to Singapore.</li></ul><blockquote>“This action symbolizes her deep love for him. Savi desires Rajat to stay and transform for the better.”</blockquote><p>The emotional confrontation between Savi and Rajat highlights the complexities of their relationship and the impact of misunderstandings fueled by external manipulation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-savi-slaps-rajat-at-the-airport-to-stop-him_216112</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-savi-slaps-rajat-at-the-airport-to-stop-him_216112</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:26:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abhishek Bachchan, Amitabh Bachchan, Jaya Bachchan attend a wedding; fans miss Aishwarya Rai Bachchan as - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/abhishek-bachchan-amitabh-bachchan-jaya-bachchan-attend-a-wedding-fans-miss-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-as-pic-goes-viral/articleshow/116788073.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/abhishek-bachchan-amitabh-bachchan-jaya-bachchan-attend-a-wedding-fans-miss-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-as-pic-goes-viral/articleshow/116788073.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Squid Game Season 2 ENDING Explained: Gi-Hun's Failed Rebellion, Front Man's Real Plan And More Cliffhanger Qu - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Squid Game Season 2 ENDING Explained: Gi-Hun's Failed Rebellion, Front Man's Real Plan And More Cliffhanger Questions</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The News Network</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116789379,thumbsize-76558,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116789379.jpg" alt="Squid Game Season 2 ENDING Explained" title="Squid Game Season 2 ENDING Explained">
<figcaption>Squid Game Season 2 ENDING Explained</figcaption>
<p>Squid Game Season 2 has unleashed mayhem on Netflix with its gripping storyline. This season follows Seong Gi-hun, who returns to the deadly game amidst chaos and strategic conflicts.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gi-hun plans a rebellion against the game but ends up without backup.</li>
  <li>The stakes rise as players face dire consequences, with numerous casualties.</li>
  <li>Hwang In-ho reveals his true identity as the Front Man and backstabs Gi-hun.</li>
  <li>The season ends with unresolved cliffhangers, leaving viewers eager for the next installment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“While we need to wait to get answers in its final season in 2025, here are some burning questions that have left us wondering.”</blockquote>
<p>The unresolved nature of the ending and the revelations about the characters heighten the anticipation for future episodes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/web-series/squid-game-season-2-ending-explained-gi-huns-failed-rebellion-front-mans-real-plan-and-more-cliffhanger-questions-article-116786421</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/web-series/squid-game-season-2-ending-explained-gi-huns-failed-rebellion-front-mans-real-plan-and-more-cliffhanger-questions-article-116786421</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:31:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dil Raju meets Pawan Kalyan – Game Changer pre-release event venue finalised? - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dil Raju Meets Pawan Kalyan: Venue Finalized for Game Changer Pre-Release Event?</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 30, 2024 12:01 pm IST</strong></p><img src='https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pawan-kalayan.jpg' alt='Pawan Kalyan' width='450' height='500'><figcaption>Pawan Kalyan at the meeting.</figcaption><p>Today, on a bustling Monday morning, Tollywood producer Dil Raju met with Andhra Pradesh Deputy CM Pawan Kalyan at his Mangalagiri camp office. This meeting aims to finalize the details for the pre-release event of Dil Raju's much-anticipated film <em>Game Changer</em>.</p><ul><li>Pawan Kalyan will attend the pre-release event for <em>Game Changer</em>.</li><li>The event is tentatively scheduled for January 4 or 5, 2025, in Rajahmundry.</li><li>Fans are excited about the appearance of Pawan Kalyan and Ram Charan together.</li><li>The film features notable actors, including Kiara Advani and SJ Suryah, and is set for release on January 10, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“More details are expected soon.”</blockquote><p>This meeting has raised anticipation among fans, who look forward to updates regarding the event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/dil-raju-meets-pawan-kalyan-game-changer-pre-release-event-venue-finalised.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/dil-raju-meets-pawan-kalyan-game-changer-pre-release-event-venue-finalised.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hidden Love C-Drama Star Zhao Lusi Rushed To Hospital Amid Reports Of Depression, Viral Video Shows Her Slumped In Wheelchair - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/entertainment/hidden-love-c-drama-star-zhao-lusi-rushed-to-hospital-amid-reports-of-depression-viral-video-shows-her-slumped-in-wheelchair</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/entertainment/hidden-love-c-drama-star-zhao-lusi-rushed-to-hospital-amid-reports-of-depression-viral-video-shows-her-slumped-in-wheelchair</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:16:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abhishek Bachchan, Amitabh Bachchan, Jaya Bachchan attend a wedding in Mumbai, PIC goes viral - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bachchan Family Attends Viral Wedding in Mumbai</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116787977,imgsize-119652,width-400,resizemode-4/116787977.jpg" alt="Abhishek Bachchan, Amitabh Bachchan, Jaya Bachchan attend a wedding in Mumbai, PIC goes viral"><figcaption>Abhishek Bachchan and family at the wedding.</figcaption><p>Abhishek Bachchan, along with Amitabh Bachchan and Jaya Bachchan, made headlines as they attended a wedding in Mumbai, sparking viral interest on social media.</p><ul><li>The Bachchan family attended the wedding reception of Rikin Yadav and Surabhi.</li><li>Rikin Yadav is the son of a long-time associate of the Bachchan family.</li><li>Abhishek was seen wearing an ivory kurta pyjama while Amitabh donned a black kurta pyjama with a bandh gala.</li><li>Fans noticed the absence of Aishwarya Rai Bachchan at the event.</li></ul><blockquote>Amitabh Bachchan referred to the swirling rumors around his family as 'speculated untruths' in a cryptic blog post.</blockquote><p>The appearance of the Bachchan family at the wedding reinforces positive public perception amid recent speculation regarding their personal lives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/abhishek-bachchan-amitabh-bachchan-jaya-bachchan-attend-a-wedding-fans-miss-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-as-pic-goes-viral/articleshow/116788073.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/abhishek-bachchan-amitabh-bachchan-jaya-bachchan-attend-a-wedding-fans-miss-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-as-pic-goes-viral/articleshow/116788073.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sharvari wraps up last working day of 2024 on Alpha set: “Going to work has been my biggest blessing” - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sharvari Wraps Up Last Working Day of 2024 on Alpha Set: “Going to Work Has Been My Biggest Blessing”</h1><p><strong>12/12/2024</strong>, Source: <a href="https://www.bollywoodhungama.com">Bollywood Hungama</a></p><img src="https://media5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Sharvari_Last_working_Day_Of_2024.jpg" alt="Sharvari wraps up last working day of 2024 on Alpha set: “Going to work has been my biggest blessing”" width="620" height="450"><figcaption>Sharvari on the set of Alpha.</figcaption><p>Bollywood actress Sharvari wrapped up her final working day of 2024 on a high note, filming an action sequence for her upcoming movie Alpha. She shared a behind-the-scenes image on her Instagram Stories, expressing gratitude for each working day of the year.</p><p>Alpha, a groundbreaking film in the YRF spy-universe, is directed by Shiv Rawail and features Sharvari alongside Alia Bhatt and Anil Kapoor. The film promises to be a high-octane spy thriller and the first female-led film in the franchise.</p><p>Sharvari reflected on her intense journey in 2024, with her work on Alpha being a significant source of motivation and accomplishment as the year comes to a close.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/sharvari-wraps-last-working-day-2024-alpha-set-going-work-biggest-blessing/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/sharvari-wraps-last-working-day-2024-alpha-set-going-work-biggest-blessing/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:45:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>