<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 03:22:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 03:22:13 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan attack case: Mumbai Police arrests accused from Thane - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/saif-ali-khan-attack-case-mumbai-police-arrests-accused-from-thane/article69115241.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/saif-ali-khan-attack-case-mumbai-police-arrests-accused-from-thane/article69115241.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 01:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan stabbing: Main accused arrested; used to work at Mumbai pub | Details so far - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saif Ali Khan Stabbing: Main Accused Arrested</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 19, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/19/550x309/saif_ali_khan_case_accused_1737249426726_1737249465097.png" alt="Vijay Das arrested for Saif Ali Khan stabbing" title="Vijay Das was arrested from a labour camp behind the TCS Call Center in Hiranandani Estate, Thane west.(X/@ANI)"><figcaption>Vijay Das was arrested from a labour camp behind the TCS Call Center in Hiranandani Estate, Thane west.(X/@ANI)</figcaption><p>The Mumbai Police have arrested Vijay Das, the main accused in the stabbing of actor Saif Ali Khan during a robbery attempt at his home. The incident occurred in the early hours of Thursday, leaving Khan with six stab wounds.</p><ul><li>The accused previously worked at a pub in Mumbai and has multiple aliases.</li><li>The attack was captured on CCTV, showing the intruder entering Khan's apartment.</li><li>Khan's son rushed him to the hospital after the attack, where he underwent several surgeries.</li><li>The assailant was later seen on CCTV buying headphones hours after the attack.</li></ul><blockquote>“He is completely cheerful. In fact, we are planning a discharge in the next two to three days.” - Dr. Niraj Uttamani, Chief Operating Officer, Lilavati Hospital</blockquote><p>Saif Ali Khan is reported to be recovering well and is likely to be discharged soon.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-main-accused-vijay-das-arrested-used-to-work-at-mumbai-pub-101737248462445.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-main-accused-vijay-das-arrested-used-to-work-at-mumbai-pub-101737248462445.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 01:21:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Love and Relationship Horoscope for January 19, 2025 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Love and Relationship Horoscope for January 19, 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 19, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/g14e30f0828f98023f90af4569207fde9cd4d22f477ee1b306_1737123062561_1737202249944.jpg" alt="Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope Today 2025: Find out love predictions for January 19. (Pixabay)"><figcaption>Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope Today 2025: Find out love predictions for January 19. (Pixabay)</figcaption><p>Today's horoscope emphasizes the importance of intuition and understanding in love. Each zodiac sign is encouraged to embrace their feelings and to adopt new perspectives on relationships.</p><ul><li><strong>Aries:</strong> Trust your intuition, even if others may lie to spare your feelings.</li><li><strong>Taurus:</strong> The process of falling in love is renewed; invite love into your life.</li><li><strong>Gemini:</strong> Unfulfilled expectations can cause tension; be flexible and understanding.</li><li><strong>Cancer:</strong> Focus on patience and allow love to unfold naturally.</li><li><strong>Leo:</strong> Indulge in fantasies about love and envision the characteristics you desire in a partner.</li><li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Break the monotony of routine to surprise your partner with spontaneity.</li><li><strong>Libra:</strong> Embrace unexpected love; new connections can arise at any time.</li><li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Support your loved ones and strengthen bonds through trust.</li><li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> Focus on emotional relationships rather than materialistic aspects.</li><li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Accept flaws in yourself and others to foster genuine connections.</li><li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Embrace change and move on from past relationships.</li><li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Pay attention to subtle signs of affection from friends.</li></ul><blockquote>"Love blooms when you are open to what is happening at the present time and ready for change." - Neeraj Dhankher, Vedic Astrologer</blockquote><p>Overall, the day highlights personal growth in relationships and encourages openness to new experiences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/love-and-relationship-horoscope-for-january-19-2025-101737202207981.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/love-and-relationship-horoscope-for-january-19-2025-101737202207981.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:30:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Capricorn, January 19-25, 2025 predicts robust health - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Capricorn Weekly Horoscope Today, January 19-25, 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 19, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Capricorn_1728478974232_1737206410993.jpg" alt="Capricorn Weekly Horoscope January 19 to 25, 2025: Professional success is also complemented by good health." title="Capricorn Weekly Horoscope January 19 to 25, 2025: Professional success is also complemented by good health."><figcaption>Capricorn Weekly Horoscope January 19 to 25, 2025: Professional success is also complemented by good health.</figcaption></figure><p>Health will not cause major issues this week as Capricorn natives focus on improving their love life and career.</p><ul><li>Pressure should not influence your actions.</li><li>Resolve any love-related issues and share emotions with loved ones.</li><li>Control your expenses even if you are doing well financially.</li><li>This week will involve challenges for professionals in various fields, including IT and construction.</li><li>Health is stable, but minors should be cautious about oral health.</li></ul><blockquote>“No major health issue will trouble you.”</blockquote><p>Capricorns are advised to seek stability in both personal and professional domains while being mindful of their financial dealings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-capricorn-january-19-25-2025-predicts-robust-health-101737206224581.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-capricorn-january-19-25-2025-predicts-robust-health-101737206224581.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 22:39:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Virgo, January 19-25, 2025 predicts job switch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Virgo, January 19-25, 2025 predicts job switch</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 19, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Virgo_1728479056525_1737208801316.jpg" alt="Virgo Weekly Horoscope January 19 to 25, 2025: Entrepreneurs will be serious about business expansion and the week is good for it." title="Virgo Weekly Horoscope January 19 to 25, 2025: Entrepreneurs will be serious about business expansion and the week is good for it."><figcaption>Virgo Weekly Horoscope January 19 to 25, 2025: Entrepreneurs will be serious about business expansion and the week is good for it.</figcaption><p>This week's horoscope for Virgo emphasizes financial prosperity and professional opportunities, suggesting potential job changes.</p><ul><li>Financial prosperity exists but caution against overspending is advised.</li><li>Professional success is likely, particularly for those in IT, healthcare, and banking.</li><li>Virgos may encounter opportunities abroad and potential job switches.</li><li>Health awareness is emphasized, especially for those with high blood pressure or diabetes.</li><li>Positive interactions in love life are anticipated, with a possibility of meeting someone special.</li></ul><blockquote>“This week is good for buying a car. Traders will see good returns from businesses associated with fashion, manufacturing, banking, pharmaceuticals, and transport.”</blockquote><p>Overall, this week presents a blend of opportunities and challenges to navigate wisely.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-virgo-january-19-25-2025-predicts-job-switch-101737208631849.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-virgo-january-19-25-2025-predicts-job-switch-101737208631849.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 22:35:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan stabbing case: Mumbai Police arrests accused in Thane - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Police Arrests Suspect in Saif Ali Khan Stabbing Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Saif Ali Khan Stabbing Case" /><figcaption>Saif Ali Khan during a recent event.</figcaption><p>The Mumbai Police have arrested a suspect involved in the stabbing case of actor Saif Ali Khan. The incident has drawn significant public attention and raised questions about celebrity safety.</p><ul><li>The police apprehended the suspect in Thane.</li><li>The case has sparked discussions on security measures for public figures.</li><li>Saif Ali Khan was reportedly injured but is recovering.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are investigating the motives behind the attack,” said a police spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the urgent need for enhanced security protocols for celebrities in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-mumbai-police-arrests-accused-from-thane/articleshow/117362474.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-mumbai-police-arrests-accused-from-thane/articleshow/117362474.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 21:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abhishek Bachchan On Teaching Aaradhya Values From Amitabh And Jaya Bachchan: ‘I Want My Daughter To…’ - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Abhishek Bachchan On Teaching Aaradhya Values From Amitabh And Jaya Bachchan: ‘I Want My Daughter To…’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 18, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Abhishek Bachchan shares parenting insights inspired by Amitabh and Jaya Bachchan, emphasizing resilience, dignity, and learning from Aaradhya." /><figcaption>Abhishek Bachchan shares parenting insights inspired by Amitabh and Jaya Bachchan, emphasizing resilience, dignity, and learning from Aaradhya.</figcaption><p>In a recent interview, Abhishek Bachchan reflected on the values he hopes to instill in his teenage daughter, Aaradhya, drawing inspiration from his parents. He emphasizes the importance of resilience, dignity, and learning from the younger generation.</p><ul><li>Abhishek believes that values are crucial for a successful life, learned through example rather than instruction.</li><li>He recognizes the inquisitive nature of today’s youth, who question rather than simply obey.</li><li>Abhishek aims to lead by example, inspired by his father's relentless work ethic.</li><li>He acknowledges the influence of his niece and nephew in preparing him for fatherhood.</li></ul><blockquote>“You have to learn to be resilient, hold on to your dream and fight for it.” - Abhishek Bachchan</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Abhishek Bachchan aims to impart essential values to Aaradhya while also learning from her perspective, illustrating a modern and reflective approach to parenting.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/abhishek-bachchan-on-teaching-aaradhya-values-from-amitabh-and-jaya-bachchan-i-want-my-daughter-to-9193365.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/abhishek-bachchan-on-teaching-aaradhya-values-from-amitabh-and-jaya-bachchan-i-want-my-daughter-to-9193365.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 21:18:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azaad Box Office Day 2 (Early Trends): Aaman Devgn & Rasha Thadani’s Film Holds As Well As The Opening Day! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Azaad Box Office Day 2 (Early Trends): Aaman Devgn & Rasha Thadani’s Film Holds As Well As The Open</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 19, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2025/01/azaad-box-office-day-2-early-trends-01.jpg" alt="Azaad Box Office Day 2 (Early Trends)" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Azaad Box Office Day 2 (Early Trends): Aaman Devgn & Rasha Thadani Hold Well! (Photo Credit – Facebook)</figcaption><p>Aaman Devgan and Rasha Thadani’s film Azaad has shown impressive performance on its second day at the box office, drawing in an estimated total of 3 crore despite strong competition from other releases.</p><h4><strong>Key Points:</strong></h4><ul><li>The film earned between 1.5 to 1.8 crore on January 18, 2025, following an opening day of 1.50 crore.</li><li>Azaad is nearly surpassing the box office figures of previous debutants from last year.</li><li>Despite strong competition, Azaad could potentially cross the 5 crore mark by the end of the weekend.</li><li>It is projected to finish its lifetime collection between 10 to 12 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“With a total of 3 crore, Azaad is close to surpassing several last debutants at the box office.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the film has managed to maintain a solid box office presence amidst competitive releases, showcasing the potential for continued success in its opening weekend.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/azaad-box-office-day-2-early-trends-aaman-devgn-rasha-thadanis-film-holds-as-well-as-the-opening-day/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/azaad-box-office-day-2-early-trends-aaman-devgn-rasha-thadanis-film-holds-as-well-as-the-opening-day/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 19:17:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Shilpa Shinde Mocks Eisha Singh, Latter’s Brother Hits Back, ‘Teen Baithe Hain Karan Ke Saath - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18: Shilpa Shinde Mocks Eisha Singh, Latter’s Brother Hits Back</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Bigg Boss 18: Shilpa Shinde supports Karan Veer Mehra, Rudraksh backs his sister Eisha Singh." title="Bigg Boss 18: Shilpa Shinde supports Karan Veer Mehra, Rudraksh backs his sister Eisha Singh."><figcaption>Bigg Boss 18: Shilpa Shinde supports Karan Veer Mehra, Rudraksh backs his sister Eisha Singh.</figcaption><p>The Bigg Boss 18 finale is just a day away, with both supporters and critics engaged in a dramatic media showdown. In a promo, Shilpa Shinde supports Karan Veer Mehra while Eisha Singh’s brother defends her amidst media scrutiny.</p><ul><li>Shilpa Shinde supports Karan in the Bigg Boss 18 finale, entering the house.</li><li>Eisha’s brother, Rudraksh, passionately defends his sister against media challenges.</li><li>Shilpa mocks Eisha and suggests she should leave with her brother.</li><li>Rudraksh counters that he is enough to support Eisha against the three with Karan.</li></ul><blockquote>Rudraksh: “These people have come to bring Eisha down. What should the girl do?”</blockquote><p>The show is building suspense and dramatic moments leading to the finale, with strong emotions on both sides.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/bigg-boss-18-shilpa-shinde-mocks-eisha-singh-latters-brother-hits-back-teen-baithe-hain-karan-ke-saath-9193344.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/bigg-boss-18-shilpa-shinde-mocks-eisha-singh-latters-brother-hits-back-teen-baithe-hain-karan-ke-saath-9193344.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 19:05:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azaad box office collection day 2: Ajay Devgn, Aaman Devgan, Rasha Thadani's film trails Kangana's Emergency, - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Azaad box office collection day 2: Ajay Devgn, Aaman Devgan, Rasha Thadani's film trails Kangana's Emergency, earns...</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> DNA India</p><img src="https://cdn.dnaindia.com/sites/default/files/2025/01/18/2672147-azaad-2.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(1200,900)" alt="A poster of Azaad"><figcaption>Azaad box office collection day 2</figcaption><p>Ajay Devgn, Rasha Thadani, and Aaman Devgan's film Azaad has shown no growth on its second day at the box office, trailing behind Kangana Ranaut's Emergency.</p><ul><li>Azaad earned Rs 1.50 crore on both Friday and Saturday.</li><li>Two-day total for Azaad stands at Rs 3 crore.</li><li>Emergency has collected Rs 6.50 crores over two days, outperforming Azaad.</li><li>Expectations for Azaad were low given its lack of connection with the audience.</li></ul><blockquote>Rasha Thadani shared her parents' reaction to her debut, emphasizing the importance of humility and staying grounded.</blockquote><p>The lack of engagement from the audience towards Azaad indicates mixed reviews and slow performance at the box office.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/bollywood/report-azaad-box-office-collection-day-2-ajay-devgn-aaman-devgan-rasha-thadani-film-trails-kangana-ranaut-emergency-earns-rs-3-crores-3127737</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/bollywood/report-azaad-box-office-collection-day-2-ajay-devgn-aaman-devgan-rasha-thadani-film-trails-kangana-ranaut-emergency-earns-rs-3-crores-3127737</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 18:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Bahut khushi horahi hai': Chris Martin flaunts fluent Hindi during Coldplay concert in Mumbai; fans roar with surprise - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chris Martin Speaks Fluent Hindi at Coldplay Concert in Mumbai</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/chris_martin_coldplay_1737221138637_1737221138884.jpg" alt="Musician Chris Martin of the British rock band Coldplay performs onstage during a concert as part of their Music of the Spheres World Tour, at the D.Y. Patil stadium in Navi Mumbai on January 18, 2025.(AFP)" />
<figcaption>Musician Chris Martin of the British rock band Coldplay performs onstage during a concert as part of their Music of the Spheres World Tour, at the D.Y. Patil stadium in Navi Mumbai on January 18, 2025.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Chris Martin charmed Mumbai fans by speaking Hindi during Coldplay's concert, marking the first of three back-to-back shows in the city.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Chris Martin spoke fluent Hindi, greeting the audience with joy about being in Mumbai.</li>
  <li>The concert is part of Coldplay's Music of the Spheres World Tour, with performances scheduled over three days.</li>
  <li>Fans were excited and took to social media to express their delight.</li>
  <li>The band will perform in Ahmedabad later in January.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Aap sabka bohot swagat hai. Mumbai mein aakar humein bohot Khushi ho rahi hai” - Chris Martin</blockquote>
<p>Coldplay’s performance in Mumbai has generated substantial excitement and engagement among fans, highlighting the band’s international appeal and connection with diverse audiences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/chris-martin-flaunts-fluent-hindi-during-coldplay-concert-in-mumbai-bahut-khushi-horahi-hai-101737219653700.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/chris-martin-flaunts-fluent-hindi-during-coldplay-concert-in-mumbai-bahut-khushi-horahi-hai-101737219653700.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:36:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan stabbing news: How railway police zeroed in on suspect in train - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saif Ali Khan Stabbing: Suspect Detained by Railway Police</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Jan 18, 2025, Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/ANI-20250118239-0_1737219873669_1737219901739.jpg" alt="The suspect, Akash Kanojia." title="The suspect, Akash Kanojia."><figcaption>The suspect, Akash Kanojia.</figcaption>
<p>The Railway Protection Force (RPF) detained a suspect in the Saif Ali Khan stabbing case while he was travelling by the Jnaneswari Express train in Durg district, Chhattisgarh.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The suspect, Aakash Kanojia, was located using information from the Mumbai police.</li>
  <li>Kanojia was apprehended in the train's general coach based on a photo and tower location provided by the Mumbai police.</li>
  <li>Saif Ali Khan was attacked in his home, resulting in multiple stab wounds.</li>
  <li>He was treated at Lilavati Hospital and is reported to be out of danger.</li>
  <li>The Mumbai police have assembled over 20 teams to find the intruder who attacked Khan.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The suspect's identity was confirmed through a video call with Mumbai Police. He has been detained. Further interrogation will be done by Mumbai Police." - Sanjay Sinha, RPF in-charge at Durg</blockquote>
<p>The swift action by the RPF showcases the effective collaboration between state police forces in the wake of a serious incident involving a public figure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-news-how-railway-police-zeroed-in-on-suspect-in-train-101737219571970.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-news-how-railway-police-zeroed-in-on-suspect-in-train-101737219571970.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coldplay Concert: Chris Martin Speaks In Hindi, Leaves Fans Berserk As He Says ‘Mumbai Mein Aake…’ | VIDEO - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Coldplay Concert: Chris Martin Speaks In Hindi, Leaves Fans Berserk As He Says ‘Mumbai Mein Aake…’ | VIDEO</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 19, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Chris Martin speaks in Hindi at Coldplay Mumbai concert"><figcaption>Chris Martin speaks in Hindi at Coldplay Mumbai concert (Pic Credit: Instagram/coldplayindia._in)</figcaption><p>The highly-anticipated Coldplay concert has finally begun, and videos from the event are going viral. Fans were left awestruck as the band’s lead singer Chris Martin spoke in Hindi!</p><ul><li>Chris Martin warmly greeted thousands of fans at the DY Patil Stadium.</li><li>He expressed joy at performing in Mumbai, stating it was their first real show in India.</li><li>His Hindi greeting elicited a positive reaction from the audience.</li><li>The concert marks the beginning of their Music of the Spheres World Tour.</li></ul><blockquote>“Good evening everybody. Aap sabka bohot swagat hai. Mumbai mein aakar humein bohot Khushi ho rahi hai.”</blockquote><p>This concert is part of Coldplay's return to India after their last performance in 2016.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/coldplay-concert-chris-martin-speaks-in-hindi-leaves-fans-berserk-as-he-says-mumbai-mein-aake-video-9193826.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/coldplay-concert-chris-martin-speaks-in-hindi-leaves-fans-berserk-as-he-says-mumbai-mein-aake-video-9193826.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 16:49:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Emergency box office collection day 2: Kangana Ranaut’s film mints over ₹5 crore - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Emergency box office collection day 2: Kangana Ranaut's maiden solo directorial also stars late Satish Kaushik, Shreyas Talpade, and Anupam Kher.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Emergency_1737216523332_1737216523509.jpg" alt="Emergency box office collection day 2: The Kangana Ranaut film was released on January 17. (Twitter)" title="Emergency box office collection day 2: The Kangana Ranaut film was released on January 17. (Twitter)"><figcaption>Emergency box office collection day 2: The Kangana Ranaut film was released on January 17. (Twitter)</figcaption></figure><p>Kangana Ranaut's long-delayed solo directorial 'Emergency' hit theaters on January 17 and has seen an increase in box office collection, earning over ₹5 crore in its second day.</p><ul><li>The film began with a low opening, grossing ₹2.35 crore on its first day.</li><li>On the second day, it earned ₹3.04 crore, totaling ₹5.54 crore.</li><li>The film has an overall occupancy of 13.32% in Hindi screenings.</li><li>'Emergency' is a biographical thriller focusing on the life of former Prime Minister Indira Gandhi.</li><li>The cast includes notable actors such as Anupam Kher and Shreyas Talpade.</li></ul><blockquote>“The political thriller begins by tracking the events that led to the imposition of the Emergency in India in 1975.”</blockquote><p>This film marks a significant moment for Kangana Ranaut as it showcases her directorial debut and is garnering attention for its portrayal of historical events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/emergency-box-office-collection-day-2-kangana-ranaut-s-film-mints-over-rs-5-crore-101737216437186.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/emergency-box-office-collection-day-2-kangana-ranaut-s-film-mints-over-rs-5-crore-101737216437186.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 16:38:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pankaj Tripathi bows down to his wife Mridula while celebrating their wedding anniversary - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pankaj Tripathi bows down to his wife Mridula while celebrating their wedding anniversary</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In a heartfelt celebration of their wedding anniversary, actor Pankaj Tripathi paid tribute to his wife Mridula. The occasion highlighted their strong bond and love for each other.</p><ul><li>Pankaj Tripathi expresses his gratitude to Mridula for her constant support.</li><li>The couple shared intimate moments with their family during the celebration.</li><li>Fans of the couple showed immense love and appreciation on social media.</li></ul><blockquote>“Her support has been my anchor throughout my journey.” - Pankaj Tripathi</blockquote><p>This anniversary serves as a reminder of the importance of love and partnership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/pankaj-tripathi-bows-down-to-his-wife-mridula-while-celebrating-their-wedding-anniversary/articleshow/117359231.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/pankaj-tripathi-bows-down-to-his-wife-mridula-while-celebrating-their-wedding-anniversary/articleshow/117359231.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 16:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Darshan Raval gets married to his 'best friend' Dharal Surelia. See pics - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/darshan-raval-gets-married-to-his-best-friend-dharal-surelia-see-pics-101737215532449.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/darshan-raval-gets-married-to-his-best-friend-dharal-surelia-see-pics-101737215532449.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:56:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Emergency box office collection: Kangana Ranaut's film jumps on Saturday, earns Rs 6 crore in two days - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kangana Ranaut's 'Emergency' Earns Rs 6 Crore in Opening Weekend</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 19, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> DNA India</p>
<img src="https://cdn.dnaindia.com/sites/default/files/2025/01/18/2672132-emergency-1.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(1200,900)" alt="Kangana Ranaut as Former PM Indira Gandhi in Emergency" title="Kangana Ranaut as Former PM Indira Gandhi in Emergency">
<figcaption>Kangana Ranaut as Former PM Indira Gandhi in Emergency</figcaption>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Kangana Ranaut's political drama 'Emergency' has experienced a great start at the box office, collecting Rs 6 crores over its first two days, aided by positive word of mouth.</p>
<ul>
<li>The film earned Rs 3.50 crores on Saturday after an opening day collection of Rs 2.50 crores.</li>
<li>Despite being produced on a budget of Rs 60 crores, the film may struggle to recover its costs.</li>
<li>Another jump in earnings is projected for Sunday.</li>
<li>Sadhguru reviewed the film, recommending it for younger audiences to understand historical contexts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"A very complex subject but fantastically presented." - Sadhguru</blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> 'Emergency' reflects on significant historical events, with Kangana portraying Indira Gandhi, and despite concerns over its financial performance, it is receiving critical acclaim for its production and relevance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/bollywood/report-emergency-box-office-collection-day-2-kangana-ranaut-anupam-kher-shreyas-talpade-film-suffers-minor-drop-earns-rs-232-crore-3127722</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/bollywood/report-emergency-box-office-collection-day-2-kangana-ranaut-anupam-kher-shreyas-talpade-film-suffers-minor-drop-earns-rs-232-crore-3127722</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chris Martin and Dakota Johnson visit Mumbai's Siddhivinayak Temple with Sonali Bendre and Gayatri Joshi: - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chris Martin and Dakota Johnson visit Mumbai's Siddhivinayak Temple with Sonali Bendre and Gayatri Joshi: Watch video</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a highlighted visit, Chris Martin and Dakota Johnson were spotted at the Siddhivinayak Temple in Mumbai along with renowned Indian actresses Sonali Bendre and Gayatri Joshi. The event drew attention for the celebrity presence at one of Mumbai's most sacred places.</p><ul><li>Chris Martin and Dakota Johnson visited the Siddhivinayak Temple.</li><li>They were accompanied by Sonali Bendre and Gayatri Joshi.</li><li>The visit was recorded in a video that gained widespread attention.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/english/hollywood/news/chris-martin-and-dakota-johnson-visit-mumbais-siddhivinayak-temple-with-sonali-bendre-and-gayatri-joshi-watch-video/articleshow/117358690.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/english/hollywood/news/chris-martin-and-dakota-johnson-visit-mumbais-siddhivinayak-temple-with-sonali-bendre-and-gayatri-joshi-watch-video/articleshow/117358690.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dakota Johnson visits Siddhivinayak Temple with Sonali Bendre, Gayatri Joshi. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dakota Johnson Visits Siddhivinayak Temple with Sonali Bendre, Gayatri Joshi</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Dakota_1737213577433_1737213577715.jpeg" alt="Dakota Johnson came to India with her boyfriend Chris Martin recently." title="Dakota Johnson came to India with her boyfriend Chris Martin recently."><figcaption>Dakota Johnson came to India with her boyfriend Chris Martin recently.</figcaption></figure><p>Hollywood actor Dakota Johnson is enjoying her visit to India with boyfriend Chris Martin. The couple, alongside Bollywood stars Sonali Bendre and Gayatri Joshi, visited the Siddhivinayak Temple to seek blessings on Sunday.</p><ul><li>Dakota was dressed in a navy-blue outfit with an orange dupatta.</li><li>The group was spotted happily engaging in conversation during their temple visit.</li><li>The singer Chris Martin has been exploring various spots in India as well.</li><li>They were accompanied by security during their visit.</li><li>Coldplay will perform in Mumbai and Ahmedabad shortly.</li></ul><blockquote>"Dakota was seen wearing a navy-blue ethnic outfit, with an orange dupatta draped around her."</blockquote><p>This visit highlights the couple's ongoing engagement with Indian culture as they prepare for their upcoming performances in the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/dakota-johnson-visits-siddhivinayak-temple-with-sonali-bendre-gayatri-joshi-watch-101737212103097.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/dakota-johnson-visits-siddhivinayak-temple-with-sonali-bendre-gayatri-joshi-watch-101737212103097.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nakuul Mehta takes a jibe at Urvashi Rautela following her remarks about Saif Ali Khan's attack - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nakuul Mehta Takes a Jibe at Urvashi Rautela Following Her Remarks About Saif Ali Khan's Attack</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong> January 18, 2025 <strong>Source: </strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Urvashi_Rautela_1737210424077_1737210424519.jpg" alt="Nakuul Mehta asked his followers to share their views on the issue as well." title="Nakuul Mehta asked his followers to share their views on the issue as well.">
<figcaption>Nakuul Mehta asked his followers to share their views on the issue as well.</figcaption>
<p>Actor Nakuul Mehta has taken a jibe at Urvashi Rautela following her controversial remarks about Saif Ali Khan’s attack and the box office performance of the film Game Changer. His comments came amidst a backlash directed at Urvashi for her insensitive comments.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nakuul Mehta responded on social media to Urvashi Rautela’s remarks.</li>
<li>Urvashi Rautela faced backlash for her comments regarding the stabbing incident involving Saif Ali Khan.</li>
<li>She attempted to condemn the attack while showcasing her jewelry.</li>
<li>Mehta's tweet suggested Urvashi should be a national spokesperson.</li>
<li>Urvashi deleted an apology she previously posted regarding her remarks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In today’s popular opinion, Urvashi Rautela should be our national spokesperson.” - Nakuul Mehta</blockquote>
<p>The controversy highlights the scrutiny celebrities face on social media and the impact of their statements on public perception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/nakuul-mehta-takes-a-jibe-at-urvashi-rautela-following-her-remarks-about-saif-ali-khans-attack-101737210225674.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/nakuul-mehta-takes-a-jibe-at-urvashi-rautela-following-her-remarks-about-saif-ali-khans-attack-101737210225674.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Singer Darshan Raval Gets Married To 'Best Friend' Dharal Surelia. FIRST Wedding Pics Out - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/bollywood/singer-darshan-raval-gets-married-to-best-friend-dharal-surelia-first-wedding-pics-out-article-117358206</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/bollywood/singer-darshan-raval-gets-married-to-best-friend-dharal-surelia-first-wedding-pics-out-article-117358206</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:00:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan stabbed: How cops managed to nab suspect in Chhattisgarh - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saif Ali Khan stabbed: How cops managed to nab suspect in Chhattisgarh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [insert publication date here] | <strong>Source:</strong> [insert source here]</p><p>Saif Ali Khan was involved in a stabbing incident, prompting a swift response from law enforcement, which led to the quick apprehension of the suspect.</p><ul><li>Cops acted promptly after receiving reports of the stabbing.</li><li>The suspect was apprehended within a short time frame.</li><li>The incident has raised concerns about safety in the region.</li></ul><blockquote>“The rapid response of police has been commendable,” said a local official.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the importance of quick police action in public safety situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/saif-ali-khan-stabbed-how-cops-managed-to-nab-suspect-in-chhattisgarh/articleshow/117356394.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/saif-ali-khan-stabbed-how-cops-managed-to-nab-suspect-in-chhattisgarh/articleshow/117356394.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan Stabbing Case Suspect Detained In Chhattisgarh - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-case-suspect-detained-in-madhya-pradesh-7502940</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-case-suspect-detained-in-madhya-pradesh-7502940</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 12:05:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan Stabbing Case Suspect Detained In Chhattisgarh - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-case-suspect-detained-in-madhya-pradesh-7502940</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-case-suspect-detained-in-madhya-pradesh-7502940</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 12:05:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[False lead and new footage later, Saif Ali Khan stabbing accused remains elusive - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOdG5yd3pvQUtseGdvOHlLeUw0ejFGQTVPb0ZRZWk2a1kxWkVWMEliX2FKVTBvaGp5cVpZeVlBcWFicjZNMzJDUmZtMHItR1N1a01uekszOWlBcWlyZXN0VTFTMlpMNGdBbTkxZU8wbHpwaEVOSnJrNTVwcUZGSVBVOTl0aVdxUE9HbS1XZ0pHRU1RZ3MxTDZ6Z2pkVE5PZ294QWFWbnNra1oyWXU2Z1ZmONIBtwFBVV95cUxPeGl2MUtOdnAtSmpRd2NWeWY4aEw1NlI2TldabWt4SXZQVzdqdW5yM3ZjbEJfUWJJYmx2b1NUSTVqdUJUN0I5d1dJMjFuNm04dkxCT1dfOTNEc3ItUldId3N1ZGN4WURKNTB6V2w1cTJ2RC0xTGRadFNPUmhoU1dIV0gtbDVORzl6MkpaQ1RwcndreUducUFMOWZnVnpNaV9Pc0dmRVpCeDlPTHpIT0NTSjZkaV9NWGM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOdG5yd3pvQUtseGdvOHlLeUw0ejFGQTVPb0ZRZWk2a1kxWkVWMEliX2FKVTBvaGp5cVpZeVlBcWFicjZNMzJDUmZtMHItR1N1a01uekszOWlBcWlyZXN0VTFTMlpMNGdBbTkxZU8wbHpwaEVOSnJrNTVwcUZGSVBVOTl0aVdxUE9HbS1XZ0pHRU1RZ3MxTDZ6Z2pkVE5PZ294QWFWbnNra1oyWXU2Z1ZmONIBtwFBVV95cUxPeGl2MUtOdnAtSmpRd2NWeWY4aEw1NlI2TldabWt4SXZQVzdqdW5yM3ZjbEJfUWJJYmx2b1NUSTVqdUJUN0I5d1dJMjFuNm04dkxCT1dfOTNEc3ItUldId3N1ZGN4WURKNTB6V2w1cTJ2RC0xTGRadFNPUmhoU1dIV0gtbDVORzl6MkpaQ1RwcndreUducUFMOWZnVnpNaV9Pc0dmRVpCeDlPTHpIT0NTSjZkaV9NWGM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 12:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rasha Thadani grooves with ‘adopted mother’ Tamannaah Bhatia and Vijay Varma; fans say ‘Aaj Ki Raat meets Uyi Amma’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rasha Thadani enjoys an Uyi Amma moment with Tamannaah Bhatia and Vijay Varma, who the star kid calls her ‘adopted parents’</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 18, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Rasha_Tamannaah_1737198052427_1737198080481.jpg" alt="Tamannaah Bhatia and Vijay Varma do Uyi Amma with Rasha Thadani" title="Tamannaah Bhatia and Vijay Varma do Uyi Amma with Rasha Thadani">
<figcaption>Tamannaah Bhatia and Vijay Varma do Uyi Amma with Rasha Thadani</figcaption>
<p>Rasha Thadani, daughter of Raveena Tandon, recently debuted in the film industry with her movie <i>Azaad</i>. The screening saw support from her close friend, Tamannaah Bhatia, who praised Rasha's song <i>Uyi Amma</i>. The duo later showcased their chemistry as they danced together on the said track.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rasha Thadani began her film journey with <i>Azaad</i>, which premiered recently.</li>
  <li>Tamannaah Bhatia, a close friend, has emerged as Rasha's biggest supporter, referring to her as her 'adopted mother.'</li>
  <li>Vijay Varma joined Tamannaah and Rasha in an Instagram video, singing and dancing to <i>Uyi Amma</i>.</li>
  <li>Fans commented positively on their performance, drawing comparisons to popular songs.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When Aaj ki raat meets Uyi Amma ❤️❤️🙌”</blockquote>
<p>This delightful interaction between Rasha, Tamannaah, and Vijay highlights their strong friendship and the supportive nature of their bonds in the entertainment industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/rasha-thadani-grooves-with-adopted-mother-tamannaah-bhatia-and-vijay-varma-fans-say-aaj-ki-raat-meets-azaad-uyi-amma-101737197744940.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/rasha-thadani-grooves-with-adopted-mother-tamannaah-bhatia-and-vijay-varma-fans-say-aaj-ki-raat-meets-azaad-uyi-amma-101737197744940.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 11:32:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sankranthiki Vasthunnam’s massive 4-day gross; Inches towards Rs 150 Cr club - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sankranthiki Vasthunnam’s massive 4-day gross; Inches towards Rs 150 Cr club</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 18, 2025 5:00 pm IST</p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Sankranthiki-Vasthunnam-14.jpg" alt="Sankranthiki Vasthunnam" width="300" height="450">
<figcaption>Sankranthiki Vasthunnam promotional image</figcaption>
<p>Top Tollywood star Venkatesh’s Sankranthi blockbuster, Sankranthiki Vasthunnam, is making waves at the global box office, emerging as the highest grosser in Venkatesh’s career.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The film collected a remarkable Rs 131 crore gross in just 4 days.</li>
    <li>It is expected to surpass the Rs 150 crore milestone shortly.</li>
    <li>In North America, the film is rapidly approaching the $1.5 million mark.</li>
    <li>Sankranthiki Vasthunnam has exceeded its breakeven point in almost all centers.</li>
    <li>The producers, Dil Raju and Shirish, are set to earn huge profits from the film.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The film’s ticket sales for Saturday and Sunday are phenomenal.”</blockquote>
<p>This film not only showcases Venkatesh's illustrious career but also highlights the increasing popularity of Telugu cinema globally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/sankranthiki-vasthunnams-massive-4-day-gross-inches-towards-rs-150-cr-club.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/sankranthiki-vasthunnams-massive-4-day-gross-inches-towards-rs-150-cr-club.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Emergency, Azaad box office collection day 2 early estimates: The Kangana Ranaut starrer expected to see - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Emergency, Azaad Box Office Collection Day 2 Early Estimates</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<div>
  <p>The box office collection for the film 'Emergency' starring Kangana Ranaut is showing early estimates for day 2, indicating a potential increase in ticket sales, while the co-feature 'Azaad' might experience a drop.</p>
</div>
<ul>
  <li>Day 2 collection estimates for 'Emergency' suggest a positive trend.</li>
  <li>'Azaad', co-starring Rasha Thadani, is expected to see a decline in collections.</li>
  <li>Kangana Ranaut's performance is garnering significant attention, potentially driving sales.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Emergency is expected to gain momentum after a strong opening day."</blockquote>
<p>As audiences respond to Kangana Ranaut's portrayal, the box office dynamics shift, promising further developments in the coming days.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/emergency-azaad-box-office-collection-day-2-early-estimates-the-kangana-ranaut-starrer-expected-to-see-a-jump-on-saturday-the-rasha-thadani-starrer-may-see-a-drop/articleshow/117354990.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/emergency-azaad-box-office-collection-day-2-early-estimates-the-kangana-ranaut-starrer-expected-to-see-a-jump-on-saturday-the-rasha-thadani-starrer-may-see-a-drop/articleshow/117354990.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 11:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18 finale: Chum Darang to beat Vivian Dsena, Karan Veer Mehra, Rajat Dalal and emerge as the game c - Bollywood Life]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18 Finale: Chum Darang Poised for Victory</h1><p><strong>Date: January 18, 2025 | Source: BollywoodLife</strong></p><p>The Bigg Boss 18 winner will soon be revealed, with predictions placing Chum Darang among the top contenders alongside Karan Veer Mehra, Vivian Dsena, and Rajat Dalal.</p><ul><li>Chum Darang is gaining support, especially from her home state of Arunachal Pradesh.</li><li>The finale is expected to be highly competitive, with strong performances from all finalists.</li><li>Previous seasons have shown that surprises can be expected on the finale night.</li></ul><blockquote>“We extend our heartfelt gratitude to you for your unwavering support for Chum Darang.” — Chum Darang</blockquote><p>The outcome will be revealed on January 19, 2025, as fans eagerly await to see if Chum will emerge as the winner.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodlife.com/bigg-boss/bigg-boss-18-finale-chum-darang-to-beat-vivian-dsena-karan-veer-mehra-rajat-dalal-and-emerge-as-the-game-changer-3059949/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodlife.com/bigg-boss/bigg-boss-18-finale-chum-darang-to-beat-vivian-dsena-karan-veer-mehra-rajat-dalal-and-emerge-as-the-game-changer-3059949/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 10:57:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan Stabbing Case Suspect Detained In Madhya Pradesh - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-case-suspect-detained-in-madhya-pradesh-7502940</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-case-suspect-detained-in-madhya-pradesh-7502940</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 10:35:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>