<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 03:23:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 03:23:37 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jennifer Garner’s family 'wants' her back with ex Ben Affleck especially after… - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jennifer Garner's Family Hopes for Reunion with Ex-Husband Ben Affleck</h1><p><strong>Published on: Jan 02, 2025 06:57 AM IST</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/jennifer-garner-ben-affleck-c232a2398ae842d7a50801_1694922857283_1735781178768.jpg" alt="Ex-Couple Ben Affleck and Jennifer Garner(ASON MERRITT/GETTY)"><figcaption>Ex-Couple Ben Affleck and Jennifer Garner(ASON MERRITT/GETTY)</figcaption><p>Jennifer Garner's family is rooting for a reunion between the actress and her ex-husband Ben Affleck, as the former couple has been spending quality time together with their children, including during holidays. While Garner maintains a relationship with her current beau, John Miller, her family believes there's still chemistry between her and Affleck.</p><p>Garner and Affleck, who share three children, have been spotted together recently, fueling speculation about a possible reconciliation. The 'Gone Girl' star is currently going through a high-profile divorce from Jennifer Lopez.</p><ol><li>Garner's family is hoping for a reunion.</li<li>The former couple has been spending more time together.</li<li>Affleck's friends and family are supportive of a reunion.</li<li>Garner's current partner, John Miller, may feel like a 'third wheel.'</li></ol><blockquote>"Ben is laying it on thick, he’s giving Jen so much of himself and his attention and being so charming," a source told In Touch. "It’s very hard not to love him when he’s acting this way, and a lot of people are predicting that they could end up back together."</blockquote><p>While there's no confirmation of a reunion, Garner's family and friends are optimistic about the possibility of the former couple getting back together.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jennifer-garner-s-family-wants-her-back-with-ex-ben-affleck-especially-after-101735780882930.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jennifer-garner-s-family-wants-her-back-with-ex-ben-affleck-especially-after-101735780882930.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:27:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi matches beats with Diljit Dosanjh, beats table like dholak as Punjabi singer croons. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/pm-narendra-modi-matches-beats-with-diljit-dosanjh-beats-table-like-dholak-as-punjabi-singer-croons-watch-101735780059927.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/pm-narendra-modi-matches-beats-with-diljit-dosanjh-beats-table-like-dholak-as-punjabi-singer-croons-watch-101735780059927.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:24:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 India Box Office Day 28 (Early Trends): Almost 70% Jump & 1208 Crore – Allu Arjun Is Still Screaming Jhukega Nahi Saala! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<html><body>
<h1>Pushpa 2: Box Office Day 28 - Early Trends Show Almost 70% Jump, Estimated Earnings at 1208 Crore</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 1, 2024, Koimoi</p>
<figure><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-box-office-day-28-early-trends-01.jpg" width="1200" height="630" alt="Pushpa 2 India Box Office Day 28 (Early Trends)"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 India Box Office Day 28 (Early Trends): Allu Arjun Is Beasting! ( Photo Credit – YouTube )</figcaption></figure>
<p>It has been 28 days, and Pushpa 2 is still performing exceptionally well at the box office, with estimated earnings of 1208 - 1209 crore! Mounted on a budget of 500 crore, the film has registered a profit of 141.6% at the box office in India.</p>
<h4>Pushpa 2 India Box Office Day 28 Estimates</h4>
<p>On the 28th day, January 1, the fourth Wednesday, Pushpa 2 roared yet again on the New Year holiday with almost a 70% jump from the previous day and brought almost 13 - 13.5 crore collection at the box office, taking the total earnings to more than 1208 crore!</p>
<p>Will Pushpa 3 See The Light Of The Day?</p>
<p>Earlier this year, at the Berlin Film Festival, Allu Arjun has already discussed the idea of Pushpa 3 and turning the film into a franchise. It would be interesting to see if the idea sees the light of the day sooner than planned owing to the magnanimous box office collection delivered by the sequel.</p>
</body></html>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-india-box-office-day-28-early-trends-almost-70-jump-1208-crore-allu-arjun-is-still-screaming-jhukega-nahi-saala/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-india-box-office-day-28-early-trends-almost-70-jump-1208-crore-allu-arjun-is-still-screaming-jhukega-nahi-saala/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:19:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 box office collection Day 28: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna starrer shatters records; earns o - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 box office collection Day 28: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna starrer shatters records; earns over Rs 10 crore on New Year's day</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116867722,imgsize-30702,width-400,resizemode-4/116867722.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 box office collection Day 28" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Image from Pushpa 2's record-breaking performance.</figcaption>
<p>The unstoppable 'Pushpa 2: The Rule', starring Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna, continues to break records at the box office, achieving remarkable earnings even in its fourth week.</p>
<ul>
  <li>On Day 28, the film earned an estimated Rs 13.15 crore across all languages.</li>
  <li>The Hindi version contributed approximately Rs 9.5 crore, a rare figure for a film this late in its theatrical run.</li>
  <li>The Telugu version added Rs 3.15 crore to the day's total.</li>
  <li>Dubbing versions in Tamil, Kannada, and Malayalam accounted for about Rs 1 crore.</li>
  <li>The cumulative earnings of Pushpa 2 now stand at approximately Rs 1184.65 crore, cementing its status among the highest-grossing Indian films of all time.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The film's strong New Year’s Day performance saw a staggering 70.78% boost in overall collections.</blockquote>
<p>As Pushpa 2 shows no signs of slowing down, it is anticipated to climb further in box office rankings, astonishing fans and the industry alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-28-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-shatters-records-earns-over-rs-10-crore-on-new-years-day/articleshow/116867699.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-28-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-shatters-records-earns-over-rs-10-crore-on-new-years-day/articleshow/116867699.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Love and Relationship Horoscope for January 2, 2025 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Love and Relationship Horoscope for January 2, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/01/550x309/Keerthy_Suresh_wedding_1735736486076_1735761119399.jpg" alt="Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope 2025: Find out love predictions for January 2." title="Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope 2025: Find out love predictions for January 2.">
<figcaption>Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope 2025: Find out love predictions for January 2.</figcaption>
<p>This horoscope provides insights into the love and relationships for each zodiac sign for January 2, 2025, highlighting the emotional landscapes and social dynamics at play.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Aries:</strong> A day to reflect on connection and self needs amidst feelings of loneliness.</li>
<li><strong>Taurus:</strong> Navigating changes in friendships, allowing relationships to evolve.</li>
<li><strong>Gemini:</strong> A strong desire for social interaction and connection; small gestures matter.</li>
<li><strong>Cancer:</strong> A day filled with nostalgia and opportunities to deepen ties with loved ones.</li>
<li><strong>Leo:</strong> Focus on goals despite distractions; love will come when prioritized.</li>
<li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Productivity leads to quality time with loved ones; balance is key.</li>
<li><strong>Libra:</strong> Need for authenticity in relationships; avoid misunderstandings.</li>
<li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Ignoring gossip and focusing on genuine relationships is essential.</li>
<li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> Embrace vulnerability for deeper connections with partners.</li>
<li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Striving for balance between joy and responsibilities in communication.</li>
<li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Enjoy leisure time by prioritizing what matters most in your life.</li>
<li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Let go of guilt and enjoy social interactions with confidence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Love is most likely to blossom where you are relaxed and free." - Neeraj Dhankher</blockquote>
<p>Overall, January 2 invites individuals to navigate their emotional needs while fostering connections with their loved ones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/love-and-relationship-horoscope-for-january-2-2025-101735760850565.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/love-and-relationship-horoscope-for-january-2-2025-101735760850565.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:30:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi meets Diljit Dosanjh; calls singer 'multifaceted, blend of talent and tradition' - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Meets Diljit Dosanjh</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 2, 2025, Source: Times of India</strong></p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116866875,imgsize-45592,width-400,resizemode-4/116866875.jpg" alt="PM Modi meets Diljit Dosanjh" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi with singer-actor Diljit Dosanjh.</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi met singer-actor Diljit Dosanjh and praised him as 'a combination of talent and tradition'. The two discussed music, culture, and India's vibrancy, including yoga, during their 'memorable' meeting.</p>
<ol>
<li>Modi lauded Dosanjh's achievements and praised his global success.</li>
<li>Dosanjh admired PM Modi's personal journey and his connection with India.</li>
<li>The meeting concluded with both parties expressing gratitude.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>"A fantastic start to 2025. A very memorable meeting with PM @narendramodi Ji." - Diljit Dosanjh</blockquote>
<p>Earlier, Diljit's concert in Ludhiana faced controversy due to songs promoting alcohol, despite previous warnings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/pm-modi-meets-diljit-dosanjh-calls-singer-multifaceted-blend-of-talent-and-tradition/articleshow/116866843.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/pm-modi-meets-diljit-dosanjh-calls-singer-multifaceted-blend-of-talent-and-tradition/articleshow/116866843.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 23:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Angelina Jolie's kids wanted her to defend herself in 8-year divorce battle; Brad Pitt source counters with winery sale - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Brad Pitt, Angelina Jolie's Kids and the Ongoing Divorce Saga</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 1, 2025, <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/">Hindustan Times</a></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/01/550x309/FILES-US-ENTERTAINMENT-FILM-JOLIE-PITT-0_1735764055461_1735764067771.jpg" alt="Famed actors Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie signed off on a divorce settlement on December 30, 2024, according to People Magazine, marking a turning point in the eight-year legal saga. (Photo by CARL COURT / AFP)" /><figcaption>Famed actors Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie signed off on a divorce settlement on December 30, 2024, marking a turning point in the eight-year legal saga. (Photo by CARL COURT / AFP)</figcaption>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Despite finalizing their divorce, <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/topic/angelina-jolie">Angelina Jolie</a> and <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/topic/brad-pitt">Brad Pitt</a>'s legal battle continues, with their kids taking sides and a contentious winery sale at the center of their dispute.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Jolie and Pitt's kids have publicly supported their mother during the divorce process.</li>
  <li>Three of their six children have dropped 'Pitt' from their names.</li>
  <li>Jolie's sons Maddox and Pax worked with her on a movie set, showing their support.</li>
  <li>Pitt and Jolie's divorce settlement was finalized on December 30, 2024.</li>
  <li>Their fight over the French winery, Chateau Miraval, continues.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote><p>A source close to Jolie told PEOPLE that her kids 'wanted her to speak up for herself, to defend herself over these years but she reminds them to focus on changing laws over telling public stories.'</p>
<p>A Brad Pitt source accused Jolie of deliberately disregarding their agreement regarding the winery, stating that she sold her share to 'punish' Pitt.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> Despite the finalization of their divorce, Pitt and Jolie's legal battle continues, with their kids taking sides and the future of their co-owned winery at stake.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/angelina-jolies-kids-wanted-her-to-defend-herself-in-8-year-divorce-battle-brad-pitt-source-counters-with-winery-sale-101735761015302.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/angelina-jolies-kids-wanted-her-to-defend-herself-in-8-year-divorce-battle-brad-pitt-source-counters-with-winery-sale-101735761015302.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:42:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sajid Khan recalls tough time after MeToo allegations despite clean chit: 'I have thought of ending my li - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Title: Sajid Khan Recalls Tough Time After MeToo Allegations Despite Clean Chit: 'I Have Thought of Ending My Life Many Times in the Last Six Years'</h1>
<p><strong>Date: 2023-03-08, Source: Times of India</strong></p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116863474,imgsize-26506,width-400,resizemode-4/116863474.jpg" alt="Sajid Khan" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Sajid Khan in an interview.</figcaption>
<p>In 2018, during the #MeToo movement, Sajid Khan faced multiple sexual harassment allegations, which severely impacted his career. After six years of silence, the 54-year-old filmmaker opens up about the mental and physical toll this period has inflicted on him.</p>
<ol>
<li>Allegations led to a career collapse overnight.</li>
<li>Sajid faced financial hardships, including selling his house.</li>
<li>He contemplated ending his life multiple times.</li>
<li>Despite clearance from the Indian Film and Television Directors Association (IFTDA), he struggled to find work.</li>
<li>Sajid acknowledged his blunt personality and past offensive humor, expressing regret and a change in his communication style.</li>
<li>He has a film starting mid-year but acknowledges the challenges in the industry.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote><p>"I have thought of ending my life many times in the last six years." - Sajid Khan</p></blockquote>
<p>Sajid emphasizes his desire to entertain and move forward, despite the hardships he has faced.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sajid-khan-recalls-tough-time-after-metoo-allegations-despite-clean-chit-i-have-thought-of-ending-my-life-many-times-in-the-last-six-years/articleshow/116863474.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sajid-khan-recalls-tough-time-after-metoo-allegations-despite-clean-chit-i-have-thought-of-ending-my-life-many-times-in-the-last-six-years/articleshow/116863474.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[38-Year-Old Man Warns Of World War III In 2025, Past Predictions Proven True - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>38-Year-Old Man Warns Of World War III In 2025, Past Predictions Proven True</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Nicholas Aujula asserts that at the age of 17, a figure in a dream revealed future events to him. (News18 Hindi)"><figcaption>Nicholas Aujula asserts that at the age of 17, a figure in a dream revealed future events to him. (News18 Hindi)</figcaption></img><p>As the world welcomes a new year, many wonder what the future holds. Nicholas Aujula, a 38-year-old hypnotherapist who predicted the COVID-19 pandemic, forecasts significant global events for 2025.</p><ul><li>Aujula predicts a Third World War will occur in 2025, characterized by violence and political murders.</li><li>He foresees excessive rainfall leading to devastating floods, displacing millions.</li><li>The predictions include rising sea levels that may submerge cities.</li><li>Aujula indicates a political downfall for British PM Keir Starmer and soaring global inflation.</li><li>On a personal level, he predicts reconciliation between Prince William and Harry.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Third World War is certain to happen in 2025. This will be a year where there will be no compassion.” - Nicholas Aujula</blockquote><p>While Aujula's past predictions have proven true, the world waits to see if his latest forecasts will manifest.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/38-year-old-man-warns-of-world-war-iii-in-2025-past-predictions-proven-true-ws-ab-9174394.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/38-year-old-man-warns-of-world-war-iii-in-2025-past-predictions-proven-true-ws-ab-9174394.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:06:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Katrina Kaif welcomes 2025 in style in polka-dot look; fans praise Vicky Kaushal’s clicks - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Katrina Kaif Welcomes 2025 in Style</h1><p><strong>Published on January 1, 2025 | Source: Times of India</strong></p><img src='https://example.com/katrina-kaif-image.jpg' alt='Katrina Kaif in polka-dot outfit' /><figcaption>Katrina Kaif rings in 2025 in a stylish polka-dot outfit.</figcaption><p>Actress Katrina Kaif welcomed 2025 with a stylish look, donning a polka-dot outfit. Fans have been praising the photos clicked by her husband, actor Vicky Kaushal.</p><ol><li>Kaif's outfit choice has been widely appreciated by her fans.</li><li>Kaushal's photography skills are also being lauded on social media.</li></ol><blockquote>"Her style is always on point!" - A fan on Instagram</blockquote><p>Fans are excited to see more of Kaif and Kaushal's PDA in the new year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/katrina-kaif-welcomes-2025-in-style-in-polka-dot-look-fans-praise-vicky-kaushals-clicks/articleshow/116855590.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/katrina-kaif-welcomes-2025-in-style-in-polka-dot-look-fans-praise-vicky-kaushals-clicks/articleshow/116855590.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Siddharth corrects Boney Kapoor as he calls Jr NTR a 'new face': 'You are talking about one of the bigges - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Siddharth Corrects Boney Kapoor on Jr NTR's Star Status</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Available upon access</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Available upon access</p><p>In a recent exchange, actor Siddharth responded to Boney Kapoor, who referred to Jr NTR as a 'new face' in the industry, emphasizing Jr NTR's stature as one of the biggest superstars in cinema.</p><ul><li>Siddharth pointed out the established status of Jr NTR in the film industry.</li><li>Boney Kapoor's comments seem to downplay Jr NTR's long-standing career.</li><li>The discussion highlights the recognition and respect given to established actors in the industry.</li></ul><blockquote>“You are talking about one of the biggest superstars in the industry,” Siddharth emphasized.</blockquote><p>This exchange sheds light on the understanding and acknowledgment of veteran actors in the film sector, showcasing the importance of recognizing their contributions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/siddharth-corrects-boney-kapoor-as-he-calls-jr-ntr-a-new-face-you-are-talking-about-one-of-the-biggest-superstars-in-the-industry/articleshow/116840243.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/siddharth-corrects-boney-kapoor-as-he-calls-jr-ntr-a-new-face-you-are-talking-about-one-of-the-biggest-superstars-in-the-industry/articleshow/116840243.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sridevi was distraught after her break-up with Mithun Chakraborty, says Sujata Mehta: 'They were madly in - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sridevi was distraught after her break-up with Mithun Chakraborty, says Sujata Mehta: 'They were madly in love'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116821096,imgsize-55580,width-400,resizemode-4/116821096.jpg" alt="Sridevi and Mithun Chakraborty" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Sridevi was distraught after her break-up with Mithun Chakraborty</figcaption><p>In a recent interview, veteran actress Sujata Mehta spoke about her experiences working with Sridevi, shedding light on Sridevi's professional dedication and personal struggles after her break-up with Mithun Chakraborty.</p><ul><li>Sujata Mehta reflects on Sridevi's humility and professionalism despite her emotional turmoil.</li><li>The interview highlights rumors of a secret marriage between Sridevi and Mithun Chakraborty.</li><li>Sujata contrasts Sridevi's personality with the public's perception of her as arrogant.</li><li>She also discusses Sridevi's relationship dynamics with Madhuri Dixit on set.</li></ul><blockquote>“She used to be so distraught, but she was so professional. The moment the camera turned on, she belonged only to the camera.”</blockquote><p>The interview provides insights not only into Sridevi's character but also into her relationships with other stars, celebrating their contributions to the industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sridevi-was-distraught-after-her-break-up-with-mithun-chakraborty-says-sujata-mehta-they-were-madly-in-love/articleshow/116821069.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sridevi-was-distraught-after-her-break-up-with-mithun-chakraborty-says-sujata-mehta-they-were-madly-in-love/articleshow/116821069.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anurag Kashyap says he is leaving Mumbai next year: 'I'm so disappointed and disgusted with my own indust - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anurag Kashyap Leaving Mumbai Next Year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date &amp; Source:</strong> December 21, 2022, Times of India</p><p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/94450419.cms' alt='Anurag Kashyap' width='200' height='200'/></p><p>Anurag Kashyap has announced that he will be leaving Mumbai next year and has expressed his disappointment and disgust with the film industry. The filmmaker, known for his work in both Bollywood and South Indian cinema, has been a prominent figure in the industry for several years. His decision to leave Mumbai has sparked speculation and concern among fans and industry insiders alike.</p><ul><li>Key Points:</li><li>Anurag Kashyap announces his decision to leave Mumbai next year.</li><li>He expresses his disappointment and disgust with the film industry.</li><li>His decision has sparked speculation and concern among fans and industry insiders.</li></ul><blockquote><p>I'm so disappointed and disgusted with my own industry. I'm leaving Mumbai next year. I can't work in this place anymore. I need to move on.</p><p><strong>Anurag Kashyap</strong></blockquote><p>This is a developing story. Stay tuned to ETimes for more updates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/anurag-kashyap-says-he-is-leaving-mumbai-next-year-im-so-disappointed-and-disgusted-with-my-own-industry/articleshow/116828357.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/anurag-kashyap-says-he-is-leaving-mumbai-next-year-im-so-disappointed-and-disgusted-with-my-own-industry/articleshow/116828357.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today, January 2, 2025: Check astrological prediction for Capricorn, Aries and other signs - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Horoscope Today, January 2, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/horoscope-2canva-1-3.jpg?w=640" alt="Horoscope: Astrological predictions today for January 2, 2025." width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Horoscope: Astrological predictions today for January 2, 2025. (Source: Canva)</figcaption>
<p>This article provides astrological predictions for all zodiac signs for January 2, 2025, highlighting personal commitments and opportunities across various areas of life.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Aries:</strong> Improved prospects in the property market.</li>
<li><strong>Taurus:</strong> A blinding flash of genius related to overseas connections.</li>
<li><strong>Gemini:</strong> Pressure at home may require compromise.</li>
<li><strong>Cancer:</strong> Coming to terms with self-identity amidst struggles.</li>
<li><strong>Leo:</strong> Career moves in progress, but caution is advised.</li>
<li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Focus on practical details over imaginative schemes.</li>
<li><strong>Libra:</strong> Uncertainty in communication, verify facts independently.</li>
<li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Clarity about true desires amidst current pressures.</li>
<li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> New friends influencing social dynamics.</li>
<li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Personal commitments essential for moving forward.</li>
<li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Confrontational lessons about change.</li>
<li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Awareness of impending crises requiring careful navigation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The most important lessons in life are often the hardest to learn." - Horoscope for Aquarius</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the horoscopes encourage self-reflection and commitment to personal growth amidst changing circumstances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/horoscope/horoscope-today-january-2-2025-check-astrological-prediction-for-aries-9745717/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/horoscope/horoscope-today-january-2-2025-check-astrological-prediction-for-aries-9745717/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:30:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max (Kannada) Box Office Collection Day 8 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNWTlFUDAxeUU3U0JPNjUxVndVT1RmZ3Y5Q1BuNExhS21PZW9iSFY1QVpjbmFXT0RoNlJvSWt1NGNtUjFlVklSRjJ5ekhHdUVCTnA5RUl4VXJwY2laS1ZJdE9nOFFPUWgzUjBkM05wNDd5a1dmaU9qS18tTjFhMHkyWnIwUmE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNWTlFUDAxeUU3U0JPNjUxVndVT1RmZ3Y5Q1BuNExhS21PZW9iSFY1QVpjbmFXT0RoNlJvSWt1NGNtUjFlVklSRjJ5ekhHdUVCTnA5RUl4VXJwY2laS1ZJdE9nOFFPUWgzUjBkM05wNDd5a1dmaU9qS18tTjFhMHkyWnIwUmE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:22:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inside Alia Bhatt, Ranbir Kapoor, and Raha’s Glamorous New Year Celebration - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Inside Alia Bhatt, Ranbir Kapoor, and Raha’s Glamorous New Year Celebration</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor celebrated New Year with family" title="Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor celebrated New Year with family"><figcaption>Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor celebrated New Year with family</figcaption></figure><p>Alia Bhatt, Ranbir Kapoor, and their daughter Raha welcomed 2025 surrounded by family, including Neetu Kapoor and Soni Razdan, creating unforgettable memories filled with love and style.</p><ul><li>The celebration featured heartfelt moments with family.</li><li>Alia wore a chic black dress, while Ranbir opted for an all-black look.</li><li>Neetu Kapoor also donned a striking black gown, complementing the couple.</li><li>Family members shared glimpses of the festivities on Instagram.</li></ul><blockquote>“Happy 2025 💕🌸” - Neetu Kapoor</blockquote><p>The Kapoor-Bhatt family kicked off the year on a stylish note, blending fashion and family togetherness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/inside-alia-bhatt-ranbir-kapoor-and-rahas-glamorous-new-year-celebration-9174358.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/inside-alia-bhatt-ranbir-kapoor-and-rahas-glamorous-new-year-celebration-9174358.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:13:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ileana D'Cruz Expecting 2nd Child With Michael? Actress Showcases Pregnancy Test Kit In New Year Post - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ileana D'Cruz Expecting 2nd Child With Michael? Actress Showcases Pregnancy Test Kit In New Year Post</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025<br /><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Ileana D'Cruz hints at second pregnancy in her New Year post. (Photos: Instagram)" /><figcaption>Ileana D'Cruz hints at second pregnancy in her New Year post. (Photos: Instagram)</figcaption><p>Ileana D’Cruz has sparked pregnancy rumours as she shared a New Year post on Instagram, featuring an emotional clip that included a pregnancy test kit.</p><ul><li>Ileana D’Cruz is married to Michael Dolan.</li><li>The couple welcomed their first child, Koa, in August 2023.</li><li>The Instagram post compiled moments from 2024, highlighting a pregnancy test kit in October.</li><li>Fans are speculating about a second pregnancy based on her New Year post.</li><li>Ileana recently celebrated Koa’s first birthday with heartwarming family photos.</li></ul><blockquote>“Love. Peace. Kindness. Here’s hoping 2025 is all that and so much more ✨,” - Ileana D’Cruz.</blockquote><p>This New Year post has excited fans, leading to speculation about a potential sibling for Koa in 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/ileana-dcruz-expecting-2nd-child-with-michael-actress-showcases-pregnancy-test-kit-in-new-year-post-9174361.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/ileana-dcruz-expecting-2nd-child-with-michael-actress-showcases-pregnancy-test-kit-in-new-year-post-9174361.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Chahat Pandey’s mom claims her daughter never had a boyfriend; Avinash says, “Sabko pata th - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18: Chahat Pandey’s Mom Claims Her Daughter Never Had a Boyfriend; Avinash Says, “Sabko Pata Tha Humare Set Pe Ki Usska BF Hai”</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116863480,imgsize-45094,width-400,resizemode-4/116863480.jpg" alt="Bigg Boss 18 Episode Highlight" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Chahat Pandey’s emotional moment with her mother during Bigg Boss 18.</figcaption><p>The latest episode of Bigg Boss 18 featured a heated exchange between Chahat Pandey's mother and Avinash Mishra regarding allegations about Chahat’s personal life. The confrontation brought joy and tension among the housemates and viewers alike.</p><ul><li>Chahat Pandey's mother defended her daughter's character vehemently against Avinash's remarks.</li><li>She claimed that her daughter has never had a boyfriend and expressed her frustration over Avinash's statements.</li><li>Avinash countered her claims, stating that everyone on set knew about Chahat's supposed boyfriend.</li><li>The conflict escalated tensions among housemates, splitting opinions on who to believe.</li></ul><blockquote>“Aap jiss character ka meri beti ko batate ho, vesi vo hai nahi.” - Chahat Pandey's mother</blockquote><p>The ongoing drama continues to evolve in Bigg Boss 18, leaving viewers guessing about the truth behind the claims and how it might affect the contestants' dynamics moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-chahat-pandeys-mom-claims-her-daughter-never-had-a-boyfriend-avinash-says-sabko-pata-tha-humare-set-pe-ki-usska-bf-hai/articleshow/116863481.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-chahat-pandeys-mom-claims-her-daughter-never-had-a-boyfriend-avinash-says-sabko-pata-tha-humare-set-pe-ki-usska-bf-hai/articleshow/116863481.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Salman Khan Didn't 'Allow' Sangeeta Bijlani To Wear Short Clothes, Actress Says 'I'm Not Afraid Now' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sangeeta Bijlani Opens Up About Salman Khan's Influence on Her Fashion Choices</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time>January 01, 2025, 16:30 IST</time></p>
<figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&width=360&height=270" alt="Sangeeta Bijlani opens up about her relationship with Salman Khan." title="Sangeeta Bijlani opens up about her relationship with Salman Khan." /><figcaption>Sangeeta Bijlani opens up about her relationship with Salman Khan.</figcaption></figure>
<p>During her appearance on Indian Idol 15, Sangeeta Bijlani revealed that Salman Khan had restrictions on her clothing choices during their relationship. She mentioned that she couldn't wear short or revealing clothes due to his preferences.</p>
<ul><li>Sangeeta said, "I was very constricted... I could not wear this kind of dress. Initially, I did but then I was not allowed to."</li><li>She added that she is now more confident and open about her fashion choices.</li></ul>
<p>Sangeeta and Salman's relationship was one of Bollywood's most talked-about love stories. Despite their breakup, they have maintained a cordial bond over the years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/salman-khan-didnt-allow-sangeeta-bijlani-to-wear-short-clothes-actress-says-im-not-afraid-now-9174337.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/salman-khan-didnt-allow-sangeeta-bijlani-to-wear-short-clothes-actress-says-im-not-afraid-now-9174337.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kriti Sanon Ends 2024 in Style, Serving Drama, Sparkles And Satin Sass - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kriti Sanon Ends 2024 in Style, Serving Drama, Sparkles And Satin Sass</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Kriti Sanon" title="Kriti Sanon"><figcaption>Kriti Sanon</figcaption><p>Kriti Sanon wrapped up 2024 on a high note, delivering a stunning fashion moment that’s perfect for ringing in the New Year.</p><ul><li>Kriti wore a bold black satin co-ord set adorned with Swarovski crystals.</li><li>Her outfit included a ruched and ruffled high-low mini skirt and a barely-there bralette.</li><li>She accessorized with black rectangular sunglasses, oversized gold hoop earrings, and a gold choker.</li><li>Kriti's look was completed with minimal makeup featuring fluffy brows and a soft rose-pink lip tint.</li></ul><blockquote>Kriti Sanon proved once again that she knows how to strike the perfect balance between daring and delightful.</blockquote><p>The actress’s final fashion moment of 2024 showcased her impeccable style and ability to shine at any event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/kriti-sanon-ends-2024-in-style-serving-drama-sparkles-and-satin-sass-9174342.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/kriti-sanon-ends-2024-in-style-serving-drama-sparkles-and-satin-sass-9174342.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 18:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Katrina Kaif Is All Smiles As She Wishes Happy New Year To Fans, Shares Photos From Her Celebration - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/katrina-kaif-is-all-smiles-as-she-wishes-happy-new-year-to-fans-shares-photos-from-her-celebration-9174570.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/katrina-kaif-is-all-smiles-as-she-wishes-happy-new-year-to-fans-shares-photos-from-her-celebration-9174570.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 18:02:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Your family named you 'Diljit', so you keep winning': GOAT Dosanjh meets PM Modi - Video - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diljit Dosanjh Meets PM Modi: The Inspiring Journey of a GOAT</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Date & Source</p><p>An engaging encounter occurred between celebrated singer and actor Diljit Dosanjh and Prime Minister Narendra Modi, highlighting the inspiring story of perseverance and success.</p><ul><li>Diljit credited his family's support for his achievements.</li><li>The meeting symbolizes the bridging of culture and leadership.</li><li>Dosanjh expresses gratitude for his journey from humble beginnings to stardom.</li></ul><blockquote>Diljit stated, "Your family named you 'Diljit', so you keep winning."</blockquote><p>The meeting marks a significant moment, blending cultural identity with national recognition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/your-family-named-you-diljit-so-you-keep-winning-goat-dosanjh-meets-pm-modi-video/articleshow/116862012.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/your-family-named-you-diljit-so-you-keep-winning-goat-dosanjh-meets-pm-modi-video/articleshow/116862012.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Day 27: Only 100 Crores Away From Baahubali 2, Will Allu Arjun’s Film Rewrite History? - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Day 27: Only 100 Crores Away From Baahubali 2</h1><p><strong>Publication date:</strong> January 1, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2025/01/pushpa-2-box-office-001.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Day 27" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Day 27&nbsp;(Photo Credit – Facebook)</figcaption><p>The action thriller Pushpa 2 is experiencing an exceptional run at the box office, nearing the 1700 crore mark after 27 days. The film features Allu Arjun, Rashmika Mandanna, and Fahadh Faasil and is set to potentially rewrite history by competing with Baahubali 2.</p><h4><strong>Key Points:</strong></h4><ul><li>The film earned <strong>8.55 crores</strong> net on day 27, making the domestic total reach <strong>1195.20 crores</strong> net.</li><li>Pushpa 2's global total currently stands at <strong>1699.58 crores</strong>.</li><li>It is just <strong>100 crores</strong> away from surpassing Baahubali 2's lifetime earnings of <strong>1800 crores</strong>.</li><li>Pushpa 2 may become the first Indian film to cross the <strong>1200 crore</strong> net mark.</li></ul><blockquote>“Only time will tell if Pushpa 2 will beat Baahubali 2.”</blockquote><p>With an impressive box office performance, it appears that Pushpa 2 may join the ranks of the highest-grossing Indian films, with its final earnings to be influenced by the post-holiday momentum.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-day-27-only-100-crores-away-from-baahubali-2-will-allu-arjuns-film-rewrite-history/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-day-27-only-100-crores-away-from-baahubali-2-will-allu-arjuns-film-rewrite-history/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:52:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer: Shankar drops a kick-ass poster of Ram Charan as IPS officer - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxON0ZOMTFrYVlrajRqM3RpNkFicFpCVDcxOUY2NmppdzNUM2ZtMnN1YXVERmhpNzRPSXN6aFNZbUYwR05DVVdxNDdMQnpjN0o4WkkxNkRKQWFIMXNGU0ZDc1pIR2hVMWI5S2NsNnBSSjJxQ2hfNlYtTjlmNWVTdWNKYjVrQkZJb1dHNXhVMktNSEpjTWNFNlZZOFFzZm1RRmhfSng4ZnVoNm5NeTVub0hF0gG0AUFVX3lxTE9rVUVWdGtzd3N0NTl5NFZUb2xrOGQtRkpxSFNTMEtwVWxxQlA2cUs2bjBmWEhWMERjc00zajdzUzNkenZCZFFZSXlxVWZLa2paZUR6RzdYaklDX00xb3N4dlRYMmVpd3dPc1dVRUpSdDB1Wkh1bHZGSXBsWnhYeGdCWERDTGJXVGw3TkhjRjRwSnBQYjBGTVVXZ21odVU1NjB2eF9sLUpqVS1PQWwtX0hqZS0xQw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxON0ZOMTFrYVlrajRqM3RpNkFicFpCVDcxOUY2NmppdzNUM2ZtMnN1YXVERmhpNzRPSXN6aFNZbUYwR05DVVdxNDdMQnpjN0o4WkkxNkRKQWFIMXNGU0ZDc1pIR2hVMWI5S2NsNnBSSjJxQ2hfNlYtTjlmNWVTdWNKYjVrQkZJb1dHNXhVMktNSEpjTWNFNlZZOFFzZm1RRmhfSng4ZnVoNm5NeTVub0hF0gG0AUFVX3lxTE9rVUVWdGtzd3N0NTl5NFZUb2xrOGQtRkpxSFNTMEtwVWxxQlA2cUs2bjBmWEhWMERjc00zajdzUzNkenZCZFFZSXlxVWZLa2paZUR6RzdYaklDX00xb3N4dlRYMmVpd3dPc1dVRUpSdDB1Wkh1bHZGSXBsWnhYeGdCWERDTGJXVGw3TkhjRjRwSnBQYjBGTVVXZ21odVU1NjB2eF9sLUpqVS1PQWwtX0hqZS0xQw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diljit Dosanjh Meets PM Narendra Modi After Successful Dil-Luminati Tour In India: Fantastic Start To 2025 - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diljit Dosanjh Meets PM Narendra Modi After Successful Dil-Luminati Tour In India: Fantastic Start To 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116862022,thumbsize-45918,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116862022.jpg" alt="Diljit Dosanjh Meets PM Narendra Modi" title="Diljit Dosanjh Meets PM Narendra Modi"><figcaption>Diljit Dosanjh with PM Modi after a successful tour.</figcaption><p>Diljit Dosanjh had a memorable meeting with PM Narendra Modi following his successful Dil-Luminati tour across India. They discussed various topics, including music and culture.</p><ul><li>Diljit completed his two-month concert tour on New Year’s Eve in Ludhiana.</li><li>He presented the official poster of Dil-Luminati to PM Modi during their meeting.</li><li>The Ludhiana concert faced legal issues over the performance of songs promoting alcohol.</li><li>PM Modi praised Diljit as a blend of talent and tradition.</li></ul><blockquote>“A fantastic start to 2025 A very memorable meeting with PM @narendramodi Ji. We talked about a lot of things including music of course!” - Diljit Dosanjh</blockquote><blockquote>“A great interaction with Diljit Dosanjh! He’s truly multifaceted, blending talent and tradition.” - PM Narendra Modi</blockquote><p>This meeting signifies a blend of culture and politics, marking an exciting beginning to the year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/bollywood/diljit-dosanjh-meets-pm-narendra-modi-after-successful-dil-luminati-tour-in-india-fantastic-start-to-2025-article-116861967</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/bollywood/diljit-dosanjh-meets-pm-narendra-modi-after-successful-dil-luminati-tour-in-india-fantastic-start-to-2025-article-116861967</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:31:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Squid Game' Season 2 Records Biggest Streaming Debut For Netflix With 68 Million Views - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxOSjh1ckg3eXkxTnVFU0RNcXRKVHFONWxfeENqNmcwbEtvTG9zQWRRUFpoeE4yRW5IVWFCcHNHY1RZUS1qSTNEby13Z185Mk5ib0lJaUZiMFFXMGkyVllsdU5mbU1JYjdaay1LRmxiYXNwaDcyTlZUVGJkQmZGTjF4R0FOOHFTVldoRGFwVU5SM3ZRZmRIRG4yY29fcXhqQ1Z4T2xxczBIRHV3SGRnRHpaU0xPdDE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxOSjh1ckg3eXkxTnVFU0RNcXRKVHFONWxfeENqNmcwbEtvTG9zQWRRUFpoeE4yRW5IVWFCcHNHY1RZUS1qSTNEby13Z185Mk5ib0lJaUZiMFFXMGkyVllsdU5mbU1JYjdaay1LRmxiYXNwaDcyTlZUVGJkQmZGTjF4R0FOOHFTVldoRGFwVU5SM3ZRZmRIRG4yY29fcXhqQ1Z4T2xxczBIRHV3SGRnRHpaU0xPdDE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:03:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Photo Moment: NTR poses with Prashanth Neel and Ravi Basrur - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQY0tWUkhDdVZDX0xfRDQ5ODlUVjVOenh3S2M4TXB1S1NrMlhHNExaY29mSm9Da2hHcW1wWFNGV21PWldFaHFHNlNiblJzSko4SzVoVldiRi1yeFRPaVg4QkpxUEFvRFJxUXlYUTRvRmdFanR2VFhXLXJRVGl2NjB4SlF3MHRVNmtySkE0M1R6ZWdfQXBPbGZ4cU03a9IBoAFBVV95cUxNLXpqbFpTbnB0Wkh0b3pWUk02SEVzaTFEQ0E5MUJwQnpRd1Q5YUlKNGE4Y3lFV0lXXzdTa21QamJZNXVRU3RrcTdCOGJVcXN2U1NqRWN2YXJGUDFNUjVsZmtNX1VUWFpqVlJQNzF3dVVvNmlZWHhaQkR3QlZ1QTBqeHd3RXdWcHdqMW96Ynl2X3hEMkYxWlF5LXhqTWhaLVFo?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQY0tWUkhDdVZDX0xfRDQ5ODlUVjVOenh3S2M4TXB1S1NrMlhHNExaY29mSm9Da2hHcW1wWFNGV21PWldFaHFHNlNiblJzSko4SzVoVldiRi1yeFRPaVg4QkpxUEFvRFJxUXlYUTRvRmdFanR2VFhXLXJRVGl2NjB4SlF3MHRVNmtySkE0M1R6ZWdfQXBPbGZ4cU03a9IBoAFBVV95cUxNLXpqbFpTbnB0Wkh0b3pWUk02SEVzaTFEQ0E5MUJwQnpRd1Q5YUlKNGE4Y3lFV0lXXzdTa21QamJZNXVRU3RrcTdCOGJVcXN2U1NqRWN2YXJGUDFNUjVsZmtNX1VUWFpqVlJQNzF3dVVvNmlZWHhaQkR3QlZ1QTBqeHd3RXdWcHdqMW96Ynl2X3hEMkYxWlF5LXhqTWhaLVFo?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby John Box Office Day 8 (Early Trends): Shows 27% Growth On New Year But That’s Peanuts Compared To Pushpa 2 - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baby John Box Office Day 8: Shows 27% Growth on New Year</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2025/01/baby-john-box-office-001.jpg" alt="Baby John Box Office Early Trends" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Baby John Box Office Day 8 Early Estimates! (Photo Credit – Facebook)</figcaption><p>Varun Dhawan and Keerthy Suresh's film 'Baby John' is struggling at the box office, showing slight growth during the New Year but still facing significant challenges compared to competitors.</p><h4><strong>Key Points:</strong></h4><ul><li>Day 8 saw a <strong>27% growth</strong>, earning <strong>2.75 crores</strong> compared to the previous day.</li><li>Total first-week earnings are estimated at <strong>36.03 crores</strong>.</li><li>The film is trailing behind other major releases like 'Pushpa 2' and 'Mufasa: The Lion King'.</li><li>Future projections suggest an eventual box office total of around <strong>60 crores</strong>.</li></ul><blockquote>“Baby John has badly gotten sandwiched between Pushpa 2 and Mufasa: The Lion King.”</blockquote><p>Despite a slight increase in earnings during the holiday season, the overall performance of 'Baby John' has left both audiences and makers disappointed.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/baby-john-box-office-day-8-early-trends-shows-27-growth-on-new-year-but-thats-peanuts-compared-to-pushpa-2/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/baby-john-box-office-day-8-early-trends-shows-27-growth-on-new-year-but-thats-peanuts-compared-to-pushpa-2/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:46:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 box office collection day 28: Allu Arjun film kicks off new year in style, crosses ₹1180 crore - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 The Rule Box Office Collection Day 28: Allu Arjun Film Kicks Off New Year in Style, Crosses ₹1180 Crore</h1>
<p><strong>Jan 01, 2025 - Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/01/550x309/Pushpa_2_box_office_numbers_1729766488699_1735748701477.jpeg" alt="Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 The Rule" /><figcaption>Allu Arjun as Pushpa Raj in the film.</figcaption>
<p>The Allu Arjun-starrer 'Pushpa 2 The Rule' continues its box office dominance, crossing the ₹1180 crore mark on its 28th day despite being in its fourth week. The film showed growth on New Year's Day, with collections of ₹13.1 crore. Directed by Sukumar, the action drama has had a massive opening weekend and maintained strong collections in its subsequent weeks.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film has collected ₹1184.6 crore in total.</li>
  <li>It had a massive opening weekend with ₹725.8 crore.</li>
  <li>The film has a star-studded cast including Allu Arjun, Rashmika Mandanna, and Fahadh Faasil.</li>
  <li>A sequel, 'Pushpa 2: The Rampage', has been announced.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The incident has brought unwanted attention to the film and its lead actor, Allu Arjun, who was arrested and released on bail following a stampede at the film's premiere that left a woman dead and a child injured.</blockquote>
<p>The film's success has been a major talking point in the Telugu film industry, with its box office collections drawing comparisons to other successful films like 'Dangal'.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-28-allu-arjun-film-kicks-off-new-year-in-style-crosses-1180-crore-101735748404860.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-28-allu-arjun-film-kicks-off-new-year-in-style-crosses-1180-crore-101735748404860.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:43:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive| Sajid Khan: I have thought of ending my life many times in the last six years - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sajid Khan Reflects on Life After #MeToo Allegations: A Journey Through Darkness</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/01/550x309/yogen_shah_sajid_1735749458474_1735749481648.jpg" alt="Sajid Khan" title="Sajid Khan"><figcaption>Sajid Khan</figcaption></figure><p>Sajid Khan talks about the toll of the #MeToo allegations on his life and career, revealing his struggles and thoughts of suicide over the past six years.</p><ul><li>Harassment allegations in 2018 disrupted Khan's career and personal life.</li><li>He reflects on the mental health challenges and financial hardships following the allegations.</li><li>Khan mentions that he has learned from his past and seeks to return to the film industry.</li><li>Despite the pain, he professes no animosity towards others involved in the #MeToo movement.</li><li>Khan expresses a desire to entertain again and acknowledges the struggle of overcoming public scrutiny.</li></ul><blockquote>“I thought of ending my life many times in the last 6 years.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Sajid Khan's experience serves as a reminder of the deep impacts of public allegations and the journey towards healing and renewal in the face of adversity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/exclusive-sajid-khan-i-have-thought-of-ending-my-life-many-times-in-the-last-six-years-101735748026199.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/exclusive-sajid-khan-i-have-thought-of-ending-my-life-many-times-in-the-last-six-years-101735748026199.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:39:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>