<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:20:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:20:57 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Check out: Third song from ‘Daaku Maharaaj’, titled ‘Dabidi Dibidi’, is out now - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Check out: Third song from ‘Daaku Maharaaj’, titled ‘Dabidi Dibidi’, is out now</h1>
<p><strong>Published Date:</strong> 2 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Telangana Today</p>
<img src="https://media.telanganatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/nandamuri-balakrishna.jpg" alt="Check out: Third song from ‘Daaku Maharaaj’, titled ‘Dabidi Dibidi’, is out now">
<figcaption>Nandamuri Balakrishna</figcaption>
<p>The much-anticipated third song from ‘Daaku Maharaaj’, titled ‘Dabidi Dibidi’, has been unveiled and is creating a buzz on social media. A lavish mass dance number, it pays tribute to the legendary dialogues of Nandamuri Balakrishna.</p>
<ul>
<li>Vagdevi’s vibrant vocals enhance the track.</li>
<li>The lyrics blend Balakrishna’s iconic monologues with dynamic music by S Thaman.</li>
<li>The song features high-energy performances by Balakrishna and Urvashi Rautela.</li>
<li>Rich visuals and choreography create a larger-than-life experience.</li>
<li>The film is set to release on January 12, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Set to become the next ‘Jai Balayya’ for fans.”</blockquote>
<p>‘Daaku Maharaaj’ promises a grand cinematic experience, blending action and heartfelt emotions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://telanganatoday.com/check-out-third-song-from-daaku-maharaaj-titled-dabidi-dibidi-is-out-now</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://telanganatoday.com/check-out-third-song-from-daaku-maharaaj-titled-dabidi-dibidi-is-out-now</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:02:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ben Affleck reaches out to hypnotist quit smoking amid divorce from Jennifer Lopez: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ben Affleck Reaches Out to Hypnotist to Quit Smoking Amid Divorce from Jennifer Lopez</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/ben_affleck_1735824640732_1735824641075.jpg" alt="In 2005, Ben Affleck had quit smoking with the help of a hypnotist. (AFP)" title="In 2005, Ben Affleck had quit smoking with the help of a hypnotist. (AFP)"><figcaption>In 2005, Ben Affleck had quit smoking with the help of a hypnotist. (AFP)</figcaption><p>Actor Ben Affleck is reportedly seeking to quit smoking as he navigates the stress of his ongoing divorce from Jennifer Lopez. A source reveals that he has reached out to a hypnotherapist for assistance.</p><ul><li>Affleck has been chain-smoking amid the stress of his divorce from Lopez.</li><li>He successfully quit smoking in 2005 with the help of hypnosis.</li><li>Photographed chain-smoking after Lopez filed for divorce.</li><li>Affleck is determined to begin 2025 smoke-free and has booked a hypnotherapy session.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ben was so happy 20 years ago when he quit. He swore he'd never go back, but here he is just as addicted as ever and desperate to stop.”</blockquote><p>The story highlights Affleck's struggle with smoking due to stress from his divorce, emphasizing his commitment to quit again with professional help.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/ben-affleck-reaches-out-to-hypnotist-quit-smoking-amid-divorce-from-jennifer-lopez-report-101735824414356.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/ben-affleck-reaches-out-to-hypnotist-quit-smoking-amid-divorce-from-jennifer-lopez-report-101735824414356.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:39:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Maddock Films set for horror comedy universe with 8 films lined up from 2025 to 2028; Shakti Shalini & Chamunda are 2 new entrants - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maddock Films Announces Ambitious Horror Comedy Universe with 8 Films from 2025 to 2028</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p><img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/1525876540_horror-universe-1.jpg" alt="EXCLUSIVE: Maddock Films set for a groundbreaking horror-comedy universe with 8 films lined up from 2025 to 2028" title="EXCLUSIVE: Maddock Films set for a groundbreaking horror-comedy universe with 8 films lined up from 2025 to 2028"><figcaption>EXCLUSIVE: Maddock Films set for a groundbreaking horror-comedy universe with 8 films lined up from 2025 to 2028</figcaption><p>Maddock Films is setting the stage for an interconnected horror-comedy superhero universe over the next four years, introducing eight films from 2025 to 2028, including new titles Thama, Shakti Shalini, and Chamunda.</p><ul><li>2025 will see the release of Thama on Diwali and Shakti Shalini on December 31.</li><li>2026 will bring Bhediya 2 on August 14 and Chamunda on December 4.</li><li>2027 will feature Stree 3 on August 13 and Mahamunjya on December 24.</li><li>2028 will culminate in the releases of Pehla Mahayudh on August 11 and Doosra Mahayudh during the Diwali period on October 18.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our mission at Maddock has always been to innovate and entertain... a cinematic universe that brings unforgettable characters and their stories to life like never before.” - Dinesh Vijan</blockquote><p>Maddock Films aims to reshape the future of Hindi cinema by blending heritage with innovation through its ambitious horror-comedy universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-maddock-films-set-for-horror-comedy-universe-with-8-films-lined-up-from-2025-to-2028-shakti-shalini-chamunda-are-2-new-entrants-1365308</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-maddock-films-set-for-horror-comedy-universe-with-8-films-lined-up-from-2025-to-2028-shakti-shalini-chamunda-are-2-new-entrants-1365308</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:02:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer trailer: Ram Charan pulls off multiple looks in father-son saga for righteousness. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer trailer: Ram Charan pulls off multiple looks in father-son saga for righteousness.</h1><p><strong>Date: January 02, 2025</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/Game_Changer_trailer_1735820628568_1735820628969.png" alt="Game Changer trailer: Ram Charan plays dual roles in the film directed by Shankar." title="Game Changer trailer: Ram Charan plays dual roles in the film directed by Shankar."><figcaption>Game Changer trailer: Ram Charan plays dual roles in the film directed by Shankar.</figcaption><p>Director Shankar’s upcoming film Game Changer, starring Ram Charan and Kiara Advani, is set for theatrical release on January 10 for Sankranthi. The trailer showcases Ram in multiple roles, including an IAS officer, as a student, and a police officer.</p><ul><li>The trailer was released at an event in Hyderabad attended by SS Rajamouli.</li><li>Ram Charan’s character faces a corrupt Chief Minister played by SJ Suryah.</li><li>The film includes a significant music investment, with ₹75 crore spent on four songs.</li><li>Production for the film faced delays but concluded in 2024.</li><li>Game Changer is expected to clash with other movies during the Sankranthi festival.</li></ul><blockquote>“So, whether Game Changer will redeem the director remains to be seen.”</blockquote><p>The anticipation around Game Changer highlights its potential impact on the upcoming festival box office competition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/game-changer-trailer-ram-charan-pulls-off-multiple-looks-in-father-son-saga-for-righteousness-watch-101735814696353.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/game-changer-trailer-ram-charan-pulls-off-multiple-looks-in-father-son-saga-for-righteousness-watch-101735814696353.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:30:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upasana Singh was the first choice for 'Maine Pyar Kiya' opposite Salman Khan: 'Kareena, Abhishek, Hrithi - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Upasana Singh was the first choice for 'Maine Pyar Kiya' opposite Salman Khan</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Upasana Singh reveals that she was the first choice for the lead female role in the iconic movie 'Maine Pyar Kiya' opposite Bollywood superstar Salman Khan. This revelation has surprised many in the industry, including celebrities like Kareena Kapoor, Abhishek Bachchan, and Hrithik Roshan, when director Raj Kumar Barjatya announced her casting.</p><ul><li>Singh was initially selected for the role in 'Maine Pyar Kiya'.</li><li>The announcement was surprising for several prominent actors.</li><li>Raj Kumar Barjatya made the casting decision public.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kareena, Abhishek, Hrithik were shocked when Raj Kumar Barjatya announced my casting.” - Upasana Singh</blockquote><p>This behind-the-scenes information sheds light on the casting dynamics in Bollywood during that era and highlights Singh's place in the film's history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/upasana-singh-was-the-first-choice-for-maine-pyar-kiya-opposite-salman-khan-kareena-abhishek-hrithik-were-shocked-when-raj-kumar-barjatya-announced-/articleshow/116887293.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/upasana-singh-was-the-first-choice-for-maine-pyar-kiya-opposite-salman-khan-kareena-abhishek-hrithik-were-shocked-when-raj-kumar-barjatya-announced-/articleshow/116887293.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer trailer: Impactful with solid visuals and Ram Charan’s mass avatar - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer trailer: Impactful with solid visuals and Ram Charan’s mass avatar</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Jan 2, 2025</strong> by OTT</p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Game-Changer-3.jpg" alt="Game Changer Trailer" width="550" height="309">
<figcaption>Game Changer trailer featuring Ram Charan</figcaption>
<p>The day Ram Charan fans have been waiting for is finally here, as the Game Changer team launched the theatrical trailer. Directed by Shankar, this political action drama has been produced on a massive budget and is packed with solid commercial elements.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The trailer showcases Ram Charan in various avatars, confirming his mass appeal.</li>
    <li>Shankar aims to reclaim his reputation following criticisms of previous projects.</li>
    <li>The trailer hints at a strong storyline and features notable actors such as Anjali, SJ Suryah, and Srikanth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Ram Charan seems to have got a role with multiple shades just like that of RRR.</blockquote>
<p>The anticipation for Ram Charan’s performance is at an all-time high after this trailer launch.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/game-changer-trailer-impactful-with-solid-visuals-and-ram-charans-mass-avatar.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/game-changer-trailer-impactful-with-solid-visuals-and-ram-charans-mass-avatar.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: 'I will consciously strive to elevate the mass screen presence of Salman Khan in Sikandar,' says Santhosh Narayanan - Movie Talkies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Santhosh Narayanan Discusses His Work on the Sikandar Teaser</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Movie Talkies</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://img-cdn.thepublive.com/fit-in/1280x960/filters:format(webp)/movietalkies/media/media_files/2025/01/02/39nJV6R8sEsOpeu4e1pK.jpg" alt="Sikandar Santhosh Narayanan">
  <figcaption>Santhosh Narayanan and his work on Sikandar.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The teaser for <strong>Sikandar</strong> featuring Salman Khan was released last week, garnering an enthusiastic response for its background score composed by Santhosh Narayanan. This marks Narayanan's first Bollywood film and has been a joyous experience for him.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sikandar's teaser was released on Salman Khan's birthday.</li>
  <li>Santhosh Narayanan received immense appreciation for his background score.</li>
  <li>Narayanan aims to enhance the mass screen presence of Salman Khan's character.</li>
  <li>The film is directed by AR Murugadoss and is set for release on Eid 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I am filled with gratitude and incredibly thankful that the music is connecting with the audience. This is my first Bollywood film, and it feels like an absolute dream." - Santhosh Narayanan</blockquote>
<blockquote>"I will make a conscious effort to elevate the mass screen presence of the character played by Salman sir." - Santhosh Narayanan</blockquote>
<p>The collaboration with renowned director AR Murugadoss and actor Salman Khan has been described by Narayanan as a privilege, enhancing his creative process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.movietalkies.com/news/santhosh-narayanan-about-sikandar-8585725</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.movietalkies.com/news/santhosh-narayanan-about-sikandar-8585725</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:07:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max (Kannada) Box Office Collection Day 9 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNa3pLM2VEWEtMWTNDa1RRcUhwTkFHU1h6UmZmRGhWVU1EMXRpaG4zR2o4bFdzZ2g4dnNPWnZGTWJOcDdvamJiZnNuUG9ZMUV4UUJ1UjBfeEN6d2tVcUtqRHBHeDRCaThGZ204UnNEU05SVXJSSW9ad0xtU0pJZmtmd3laN3k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNa3pLM2VEWEtMWTNDa1RRcUhwTkFHU1h6UmZmRGhWVU1EMXRpaG4zR2o4bFdzZ2g4dnNPWnZGTWJOcDdvamJiZnNuUG9ZMUV4UUJ1UjBfeEN6d2tVcUtqRHBHeDRCaThGZ204UnNEU05SVXJSSW9ad0xtU0pJZmtmd3laN3k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Armaan Malik ties the knot with Aashna Shroff; wedding photos go viral! - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Armaan Malik Ties the Knot with Aashna Shroff; Wedding Photos Go Viral</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116879437,imgsize-42098,width-400,resizemode-4/116879437.jpg" alt="Armaan Malik ties the knot with Aashna Shroff; wedding photos go viral!"><figcaption>Armaan and Aashna at their wedding celebration.</figcaption><p>Singer Armaan Malik and social media influencer Aashna Shroff have officially begun their journey as a married couple. The couple recently shared their wedding photos on social media, radiating love and joy.</p><ul><li>Armaan and Aashna shared stunning pictures from their wedding on Instagram, which quickly went viral.</li><li>The images captured heartfelt moments, including the couple exchanging vows and participating in traditional rituals.</li><li>Aashna wore a bright orange lehenga while Armaan complemented her with a pastel peach embroidered sherwani.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tu hi mera ghar,” the couple captioned their wedding post, encapsulating their love.</blockquote><p>Armaan Malik is well known for his hit romantic ballads, showcasing his exceptional musical talent that resonates with many.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/armaan-malik-ties-the-knot-with-aashna-shroff-wedding-photos-go-viral/articleshow/116879437.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/armaan-malik-ties-the-knot-with-aashna-shroff-wedding-photos-go-viral/articleshow/116879437.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunday's Golden Globes to launch Hollywood's awards festivities - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunday's Golden Globes to Launch Hollywood's Awards Festivities</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Jan 02, 2025 | Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/09/30/550x309/Entertainment_3_1727681278683_1727681354486.jpg" alt="Sunday's Golden Globes to launch Hollywood's awards festivities" title="Sunday's Golden Globes to launch Hollywood's awards festivities">
<figcaption>Sunday's Golden Globes to launch Hollywood's awards festivities</figcaption>
<p>Hollywood will kick off its 2025 awards festivities on Sunday at the annual Golden Globes ceremony, featuring competitors such as "Wicked," "The Brutalist," and "Emilia Perez".</p>
<ul>
  <li>Timothee Chalamet, Selena Gomez, and others compete for acting honors.</li>
  <li>The ceremony will mark Nikki Glaser's debut as host.</li>
  <li>Winners are chosen by 334 journalists from 85 countries.</li>
  <li>Winning a Globe can boost a film's Oscar chances significantly.</li>
  <li>"The Brutalist" is favored for the best film drama prize.</li>
  <li>In TV categories, the most nominations go to "The Bear".</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Winning a Globe can help films in the run-up to the Academy Awards in March." – Scott Feinberg, The Hollywood Reporter</blockquote>
<p>This year's Golden Globes promise a diverse lineup of nominees and could significantly influence the Oscars in March.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/sundays-golden-globes-to-launch-hollywood-s-awards-festivities-101735815670810.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/sundays-golden-globes-to-launch-hollywood-s-awards-festivities-101735815670810.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:01:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hits, Misses, Super Hits, Disasters and All-Time Blockbusters: The Box Office classification and Report card of 2024 - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hits, Misses, Super Hits, Disasters and All-Time Blockbusters: The Box Office classification and Report card of 2024</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p><p>The year 2024 has seen a wide range of box office performances in Bollywood, with films classified from All Time Blockbusters to Disasters based on their earnings. Notably, <em>Munjiya</em> stands out as a Super Hit while <em>Bade Miyaan Chote Miyan</em> disappoints as a Disaster.</p><figure><img src="https://stat5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/All-Time-Blockbuster.jpg" alt="All Time Blockbuster" width="1080" height="1350"><figcaption>All Time Blockbuster: Pushpa 2 [Hindi dubbed]</figcaption></figure><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Pushpa 2 has earned approximately Rs. 769.75 cr., making it an All Time Blockbuster.</li><li>Stree 2 became one of the biggest hits with Rs. 627.02 cr.</li><li>Munjya emerged as a sleeper hit, crossing Rs. 100 cr.</li><li><em>Bade Miyaan Chote Miyan</em> was classified as a Disaster with earnings of only Rs. 59.17 cr.</li></ul><blockquote>Pushpa 2: The Rule has raked in more than any other film this year.</blockquote><p>Overall, the classification system aids in understanding the economic landscape and viewer preferences in Bollywood.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/box-office-special-features/hits-misses-super-hits-disasters-time-blockbusters-box-office-classification-report-card-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/box-office-special-features/hits-misses-super-hits-disasters-time-blockbusters-box-office-classification-report-card-2024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:00:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Baldoni accuses Ryan Reynolds of ‘berating’ him for ‘fat-shaming’ Blake Lively - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Baldoni accuses Ryan Reynolds of ‘berating’ him for ‘fat-shaming’ Blake Lively</h1><p><strong>Date: January 02, 2025</strong><br><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/reyn_1735814016945_1735814027313.png" alt="Justin Baldoni accuses Ryan Reynolds of 'berating' him for 'fat-shaming' Blake Lively"><figcaption>Justin Baldoni accuses Ryan Reynolds of 'berating' him for 'fat-shaming' Blake Lively</figcaption></figure><p>Justin Baldoni has filed a $250 million libel lawsuit against the New York Times, alleging that Ryan Reynolds berated him for fat-shaming Blake Lively.</p><ul><li>Baldoni claims the incident stemmed from a reasonable inquiry about Lively's weight for a lift scene due to his back issues.</li><li>The confrontation with Reynolds reportedly involved aggressive accusations and forced Baldoni to apologize.</li><li>Following the incident, Lively refused to perform the scene, causing further complications.</li></ul><blockquote>Baldoni said that the situation was so aggressive he felt compelled to offer repeated apologies despite his query being reasonable.</blockquote><p>The lawsuit highlights issues of misunderstanding and aggression in Hollywood along with the implications of body image discussions in film.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/justin-baldoni-accuses-ryan-reynolds-of-berating-him-for-fat-shaming-blake-lively-101735812283381.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/justin-baldoni-accuses-ryan-reynolds-of-berating-him-for-fat-shaming-blake-lively-101735812283381.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:35:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Box Office New Year Record: Aamir Khan Dominates Top 10 List, Allu Arjun’s Pushpa 2 Strikes Shah Rukh Khan & Prabhas! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Box Office New Year Record: Aamir Khan Dominates Top 10 List, Allu Arjun’s Pushpa 2 Strikes Shah Rukh Khan</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2025/01/1st-january-box-office-dangal-pk-pushpa-2-01.jpg" alt="Box Office New Year Record: Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2 Strikes Shah Rukh Khan &amp; Prabhas!" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Box Office New Year Record: Where Does Allu Arjun’s Pushpa 2 Stands? ( Photo Credit – YouTube )</figcaption><p>Allu Arjun started the new year strongly as Pushpa 2 earned 10 crore INR on its 28th day of release, making it one of the top 10 collections for a Hindi film on January 1.</p><ul><li>Pushpa 2 makes 10 crore INR on January 1, 2025, ranking 8th in the top 10 first-day January box office collections.</li><li>Allu Arjun's film surpassed Shah Rukh Khan’s Dunki and Prabhas's Salaar, both of which had a box-office clash on December 21, 2023.</li><li>Aamir Khan leads the top 10 list with four films, including Dangal, PK, 3 Idiots, and Dhoom 3.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pushpa 2 earned 63% more than its predecessor on the same day.”</blockquote><p>This new achievement contributes significantly to Allu Arjun's standing in the industry while Aamir Khan continues to dominate the box office rankings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/box-office-new-year-record-aamir-khan-dominates-top-10-list-allu-arjuns-pushpa-2-strikes-shah-rukh-khan-prabhas/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/box-office-new-year-record-aamir-khan-dominates-top-10-list-allu-arjuns-pushpa-2-strikes-shah-rukh-khan-prabhas/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:32:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jhanak’s return to India marks a new chapter with Vihaan and their baby - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jhanak’s return to India marks a new chapter with Vihaan and their baby</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Thursday, January 2, 2025 at 9:56 AM</p><figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/9828-jhanak.jpg" alt="Jhanak"><figcaption>Jhanak and Vivian from the show Jhanak. Image Courtesy: Star Plus</figcaption></figure><p>The upcoming episode of <a href="https://www.indiaforums.com/show/jhanak_7098" title="Jhanak">Jhanak</a> will introduce a significant leap, showcasing Jhanak as she begins a new chapter in her life with a different family after her return from America.</p><ul><li>Jhanak is kidnapped by Kulbhushan and his associates.</li><li>She escapes but is later found unconscious in a truck.</li><li>The Bose family faces legal pressure over ancestral property.</li><li>Jhanak is welcomed into a Gujarati household as the younger daughter-in-law.</li><li>Vihaan, her husband, plans a visit to Kolkata to meet his childhood friend Aniruddha.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s the comforting power of a mother's embrace.”</blockquote><p>Jhanak's story evolves as she copes with her past while starting anew with her husband and child.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/jhanaks-return-to-india-marks-a-new-chapter-with-vihaan-and-their-baby_216255</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/jhanaks-return-to-india-marks-a-new-chapter-with-vihaan-and-their-baby_216255</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:00:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Bollywood's biggest dud The Lady Killer, Arjun Kapoor and Bhumi Pednekar reunite for Mere Husband Ki Biwi - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arjun Kapoor and Bhumi Pednekar Reunite for Mere Husband Ki Biwi</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>by:</strong> Devansh Sharma</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/The_Lady_Killer_1725368983879_1735808197706.jpg" alt="Arjun Kapoor and Bhumi Pednekar in The Lady Killer." title="Arjun Kapoor and Bhumi Pednekar in The Lady Killer.">
<figcaption>Arjun Kapoor and Bhumi Pednekar in The Lady Killer.</figcaption>
<p>Actors Arjun Kapoor, Bhumi Pednekar, and Rakul Preet Singh will share the screen in a film titled "Mere Husband Ki Biwi" after their previous collaboration in the poorly received film "The Lady Killer".</p>
<ul>
  <li>The upcoming film is set to be released on February 21, 2025.</li>
  <li>A playful announcement on Instagram describes the film's love story as unique: "Yahaan pyaar ki geometry thodi twisted hai - kyunki ye love triangle nahi, pura circle hai!"</li>
  <li>The film will be directed by Mudassar Aziz, known for his work on films like "Khel Khel Mein" and "Pati Patni Aur Woh".</li>
  <li>The film's producers include Vashu Bhagnani, Jackky Bhagnani, and Deepshikha Deshmukh.</li>
  <li>Arjun and Bhumi's last film, "The Lady Killer," was a commercial failure, earning only ₹60,000 against a budget of ₹45 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It's lighthearted, relatable, and full of moments that will stay with you long after you leave the theater,” said director Mudassar Aziz.</blockquote>
<p>In summary, the reunion of Arjun Kapoor and Bhumi Pednekar aims to create a better reception from audiences, following their last film's disappointing performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/arjun-kapoor-bhumi-pednekar-reunite-mere-husband-ki-biwi-after-biggest-dud-the-lady-killer-rakul-preet-singh-101735807897411.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/arjun-kapoor-bhumi-pednekar-reunite-mere-husband-ki-biwi-after-biggest-dud-the-lady-killer-rakul-preet-singh-101735807897411.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:57:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Baldoni sues Blake Lively and Ryan Reynolds accusing them of sabotaging his career and excluding h - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Baldoni sues Blake Lively and Ryan Reynolds accusing them of sabotaging his career and excluding him from 'It Ends With Us' premiere</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided]<br><strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><p>Actor Justin Baldoni has filed a lawsuit against Blake Lively and Ryan Reynolds, alleging that their actions have undermined his career and prevented him from participating in the premiere of the film 'It Ends With Us'.</p><ul><li>Baldoni claims malicious intent behind their actions.</li><li>The lawsuit seeks damages for emotional distress and lost opportunities.</li><li>It highlights the challenges faced by actors in Hollywood.</li></ul><blockquote>“I can’t believe they would go this far to exclude me,” Baldoni stated.</blockquote><p>This case sheds light on the competitive nature of the film industry and the pressure actors face.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/english/hollywood/news/justin-baldoni-sues-blake-lively-and-ryan-reynolds-accusing-them-of-sabotaging-his-career-and-excluding-him-from-it-ends-with-us-premiere/articleshow/116882518.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/english/hollywood/news/justin-baldoni-sues-blake-lively-and-ryan-reynolds-accusing-them-of-sabotaging-his-career-and-excluding-him-from-it-ends-with-us-premiere/articleshow/116882518.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin: Anubhav stops Rajat from seeing Savi during her critical hospitalisation - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-anubhav-stops-rajat-from-seeing-savi-during-her-critical-hospitalisatio_216250</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-anubhav-stops-rajat-from-seeing-savi-during-her-critical-hospitalisatio_216250</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:25:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Identity Review | Tovino Thomas Starrer Is Expensive, Expansive and Excessively Complicated - Lensmen Reviews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Identity Review | Expensive, Expansive and Excessively Complicated</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Lensmen Reviews</p><img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/L422JoNlBBBD42zkQ9/giphy.gif?cid=ecf05e477uira1nw9khdmi33fslmm0bxanchkudfp2nb0edz&amp;ep=v1_gifs_related&amp;rid=giphy.gif&amp;ct=g" alt="Reaction GIF"><figcaption>Audience Reaction GIF</figcaption><p>The review discusses the latest film 'Identity', highlighting both its ambitious scope and intricate plot that tends to overcomplicate a seemingly simple story.</p><ul><li>The story revolves around Haran Shankar, a character with an abusive past and unique skills as a sketch artist.</li><li>As Haran interacts with his police officer neighbor and a witness with face blindness, the narrative unfolds in unexpected ways.</li><li>The film is noted for its detailed research but suffers from excessive exposition that diminishes the impact of plot twists.</li><li>Director’s choices in cinematography and pacing received praise, especially during action sequences.</li><li>The review suggests that the film's ambitions could have benefited from a more refined screenplay.</li></ul><blockquote>“A bit more refinement on a writing level would have made Identity a quality film by all means.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while 'Identity' showcases ambitious filmmaking and intriguing concepts, its overly complicated storyline ultimately detracts from the viewer's experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://lensmenreviews.com/identity-malayalam-movie-review-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lensmenreviews.com/identity-malayalam-movie-review-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:21:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arjun Kapoor, Rakul Preet Singh, Bhumi Pednekar starrer Mere Husband Ki Biwi gets its FIRST poster - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Poster Released for 'Mere Husband Ki Biwi'</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>October 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>Bollywood Hungama</p><img src="https://media5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Arjun-Kapoor-Rakul-Preet-Singh-Bhumi-Pednekar-starrer-620.jpg" alt="First Poster for Mere Husband Ki Biwi" width="620" height="450"><figcaption>Arjun Kapoor, Rakul Preet Singh, Bhumi Pednekar starrer Mere Husband Ki Biwi gets its FIRST poster</figcaption><p>The excitement builds for the romantic comedy 'Mere Husband Ki Biwi,' starring Arjun Kapoor, Rakul Preet Singh, and Bhumi Pednekar, as the film reveals its first poster.</p><ul><li>Arjun Kapoor returns to the romantic comedy genre after his role in 'Singham Again.'</li><li>The film is produced by Pooja Entertainment and directed by Mudassar Aziz.</li><li>The first poster has garnered attention with its unique representation of the characters' footwear.</li><li>The movie promises a ‘love circle’ involved with comedic relationship confusions.</li><li>Scheduled for release on February 21, 2025, the film aims to deliver humor and relatability.</li></ul><blockquote>Mudassar Aziz stated, "Mere Husband Ki Biwi is a film that celebrates the quirks and complexities of romantic relationships."</blockquote><p>The film is expected to provide a lighthearted take on modern relationships, promising a blend of humor and heartwarming moments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/arjun-kapoor-rakul-preet-singh-bhumi-pednekar-starrer-mere-husband-ki-biwi-gets-first-poster/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/arjun-kapoor-rakul-preet-singh-bhumi-pednekar-starrer-mere-husband-ki-biwi-gets-first-poster/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:12:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ranveer Singh as Sardar in LEAKED photos from the sets of Aditya Dhar’s film leaves netizens impressed - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxNRWoyQzQzblFjd0F3V1VDcFNKWGNoSHFsT3FEVkdmNXo2OUhWd240M2E1TG9ORzNoRVpHdDVZcEdQSmdqTTY5eXJZVlMzNXNyTmVhcnp3TGFuWU5JWVVWcGFOU2gtNVZKN2dqR3d1ektBUi1xZFhvYVV0ZngtNk1NNDFZaS1RVU0yV0sxdzhrcm9DRldVcG12RFR1ZTZDTjZxYmZnVFl1d3dEMXFoN1VJVUo5R2NGMFpJZ3lmMzZfalJOMERaVExnVDVBQ1nSAdIBQVVfeXFMUEgxYnlCTEpKaUEyRFl5R3FUWmFiUXdDOTM1b2lmRFNuNjBLV0VGZTBJSXlaQ2d1aWhMOEt4UXp1bzhmaFg2R01MTmg2WjdzLThFeDA5NTY1V093cTNZbHZIRHIyYlJfbkdEMkJha0w2Rmg1eERxTUpSUTlESWtEQW8yWDgxazRZUGtfbXRodVBFY2NROXc0WF95NmpKdVdBOHV6VXBkeDRLc0Vjbm9Ma1VrMDNkb1pMbG1EQkVWZTFjakh4ME1OazQ5NDdTT0xwS053?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxNRWoyQzQzblFjd0F3V1VDcFNKWGNoSHFsT3FEVkdmNXo2OUhWd240M2E1TG9ORzNoRVpHdDVZcEdQSmdqTTY5eXJZVlMzNXNyTmVhcnp3TGFuWU5JWVVWcGFOU2gtNVZKN2dqR3d1ektBUi1xZFhvYVV0ZngtNk1NNDFZaS1RVU0yV0sxdzhrcm9DRldVcG12RFR1ZTZDTjZxYmZnVFl1d3dEMXFoN1VJVUo5R2NGMFpJZ3lmMzZfalJOMERaVExnVDVBQ1nSAdIBQVVfeXFMUEgxYnlCTEpKaUEyRFl5R3FUWmFiUXdDOTM1b2lmRFNuNjBLV0VGZTBJSXlaQ2d1aWhMOEt4UXp1bzhmaFg2R01MTmg2WjdzLThFeDA5NTY1V093cTNZbHZIRHIyYlJfbkdEMkJha0w2Rmg1eERxTUpSUTlESWtEQW8yWDgxazRZUGtfbXRodVBFY2NROXc0WF95NmpKdVdBOHV6VXBkeDRLc0Vjbm9Ma1VrMDNkb1pMbG1EQkVWZTFjakh4ME1OazQ5NDdTT0xwS053?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:33:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Armaan Malik ties the knot with Aashna Shroff; wedding photos go viral! - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Armaan Malik Ties the Knot with Aashna Shroff; Wedding Photos Go Viral!</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Popular singer Armaan Malik has recently married influencer Aashna Shroff, with their wedding photos quickly circulating online.</p><ul><li>Armaan Malik, known for his extensive vocal work in Bollywood, has wed Aashna Shroff.</li><li>The couple's wedding ceremony was shared widely across social media platforms.</li><li>Fans and celebrities alike are congratulating the newlyweds.</li></ul><blockquote>“It feels surreal to marry my best friend,” said Armaan Malik.</blockquote><p>This wedding marks a significant moment in both celebrity lives, bringing together the worlds of music and social media influence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/armaan-malik-ties-the-knot-with-aashna-shroff-wedding-photos-go-viral/articleshow/116879437.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/armaan-malik-ties-the-knot-with-aashna-shroff-wedding-photos-go-viral/articleshow/116879437.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SSMB 29 launch: SS Rajamouli's film with Mahesh Babu kicks off with pooja amid confusion over Priyanka Chopra's casting - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SS Rajamouli's SSMB 29 Launch with Mahesh Babu Amid Casting Confusion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/SSMB_29_1735796966497_1735796981335.jpg" alt="Expectations are high on SS Rajamouli's next film with Mahesh Babu.(X/Instagram)" title="Expectations are high on SS Rajamouli's next film with Mahesh Babu.(X/Instagram)"><figcaption>Expectations are high on SS Rajamouli's next film with Mahesh Babu.(X/Instagram)</figcaption><p>The highly anticipated film directed by SS Rajamouli and starring Mahesh Babu was officially launched with a pooja ceremony in Hyderabad.</p><ul><li>SSMB 29 is Mahesh Babu’s 29th film, marking a significant collaboration.</li><li>The launch took place at the Aluminium Factory and was attended by key team members.</li><li>Confusion surrounds Priyanka Chopra’s potential casting in the film, with no official confirmation yet.</li><li>The film is expected to be an action-adventure drama, potentially shot in locations including Kenya.</li></ul><blockquote>Rajamouli during a screening of RRR: “His name is Mahesh Babu, he is a Telugu actor. Hopefully, we finish the film a little bit fast.”</blockquote><p>This launch marks an exciting phase for Mahesh Babu and fans are eager for more details about the project.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/ssmb-29-launch-ss-rajamoulis-film-with-mahesh-babu-kicks-off-with-pooja-amid-confusion-over-priyanka-chopras-casting-101735796656945.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/ssmb-29-launch-ss-rajamoulis-film-with-mahesh-babu-kicks-off-with-pooja-amid-confusion-over-priyanka-chopras-casting-101735796656945.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:56:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Made for ₹160 crore, earned just ₹47 crore, how Varun Dhawan's Baby John became 2024's final box office disaster - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Varun Dhawan's Baby John: 2024's Final Box Office Disaster</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/Baby_John_Varun_Dhawan_1735130730759_1735802696464.jpeg" alt="Varun Dhawan's Baby John is en route to being the final box office bomb of 2024." title="Varun Dhawan's Baby John is en route to being the final box office bomb of 2024."><figcaption>Varun Dhawan's Baby John is en route to being the final box office bomb of 2024.</figcaption></figure><p>The Varun Dhawan starrer, Baby John, has failed to impress at the box office, earning only ₹47 crore against its ₹160 crore budget. Despite high expectations due to its mass action genre, the film opened poorly and received negative reviews.</p><ul><li>Released with a budget of ₹160 crore, Baby John has grossed just ₹47 crore globally.</li><li>The film opened to a disappointing ₹12 crore on its first day.</li><li>Negative reviews and poor word of mouth contributed to its decline in viewership.</li><li>Trade insiders predict total losses could reach ₹100 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“Baby John fell the hardest. Its failure may cause Bollywood makers to realize that merely formula will not help a film soar if everything else is hollow.”</blockquote><p>This film represents a significant failure for Varun Dhawan and may signal a need for change in the Bollywood mass action genre.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/made-for-160-crore-earned-just-47-crore-how-varun-dhawans-baby-john-became-2024s-final-box-office-disaster-101735802436863.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/made-for-160-crore-earned-just-47-crore-how-varun-dhawans-baby-john-became-2024s-final-box-office-disaster-101735802436863.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:47:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Singer Armaan Malik gets married to social media influencer Aashna Shroff. See first photos - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Singer Armaan Malik Gets Married to Aashna Shroff: First Photos Shared</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Armaan-Malik-Aashna-Shroff-wedding.jpg?w=640" alt="Singer Armaan Malik and Aashna Shroff Wedding" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Singer Armaan Malik and Aashna Shroff get married (Photos: Armaan Malik / Instagram)</figcaption><p>Singer Armaan Malik, known for his hit songs, has tied the knot with social media influencer Aashna Shroff in a private ceremony attended by close friends and family. The couple wore matching peach outfits and shared heartfelt moments on social media.</p><ul><li>Armaan Malik shared his wedding photos on Instagram.</li><li>The couple has been together since 2017, and their engagement was announced in October 2023.</li><li>Armaan expressed his love by saying, "Tu hi mera Ghar (You are my home)," which is also the title of his new single.</li><li>Congratulations from fans and celebrities flooded social media.</li></ul><blockquote>“My heart is so full, I’m crying.” - A Fan</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Armaan Malik’s recent marriage marks a joyful milestone in his life, celebrated by loved ones and fans alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/music/singer-armaan-malik-gets-married-to-social-media-influencer-aashna-shroff-see-first-photos-9756035/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/music/singer-armaan-malik-gets-married-to-social-media-influencer-aashna-shroff-see-first-photos-9756035/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:31:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SSMB29: SS Rajamouli, Mahesh Babu kickstart their 'Globe Trotting' jungle adventure film with pooja ceremony; WATCH - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SSMB29: SS Rajamouli, Mahesh Babu kickstart their 'Globe Trotting' jungle adventure film with pooja ceremony; WATCH</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 2, 2025 &nbsp;|&nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p>
<p><img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/926743118_ssmb29-3.jpg" alt="Mahesh Babu/SS Rajamouli Instagram" title="SSMB29: SS Rajamouli, Mahesh Babu launch their movie with pooja ceremony; WATCH (PC: Mahesh Babu/SS Rajamouli Instagram)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"> </p>
<figcaption>SSMB29: SS Rajamouli, Mahesh Babu launch their movie with pooja ceremony; WATCH (PC: Mahesh Babu/SS Rajamouli Instagram)</figcaption></p>
<p>The much-anticipated film SSMB29, directed by SS Rajamouli and starring Mahesh Babu, has officially begun with a pooja ceremony in Hyderabad.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The pooja ceremony took place on January 2, 2025.</li>
  <li>Priyanka Chopra has been confirmed as the female lead in the film.</li>
  <li>The script is in its final stages, with filming expected to commence in April 2025.</li>
  <li>Prithviraj Sukumaran is set to play the antagonist alongside Mahesh Babu.</li>
  <li>SS Rajamouli plans for the film to be a two-part saga, with the first part targeted for release in 2027 and the second part in 2029.</li>
  <li>Rajamouli intends to blend elements of thrill into the film.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The film is in the final stages of writing, and is all set to go on floors in April 2025.”</blockquote>
<p>The commencement of SSMB29 marks a significant milestone for both Mahesh Babu and director SS Rajamouli, generating excitement among fans for what promises to be an epic cinematic experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/south/ssmb29-ss-rajamouli-mahesh-babu-kickstart-their-globe-trotting-jungle-adventure-film-with-pooja-ceremony-watch-1365242</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/south/ssmb29-ss-rajamouli-mahesh-babu-kickstart-their-globe-trotting-jungle-adventure-film-with-pooja-ceremony-watch-1365242</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:21:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hidden Love actress Zhao Lusi speaks about abuse and mental heath issues, says "I think it is wrong... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwJBVV95cUxPcEJvTURMenFDYnZRbWt5UndyQ0g0ODhnSW5XS3RJU1MtaUJpMnlfaGxBOHdsS2R0X25BNVV3Vi1waVk4OVJjZS1ZQVVNWTFXQTlhQUxDTjE4ZngwaEFiZjJOTTBHY0VlQnFvRVl4WlpveGphdE1QM3QzNnVyN3lPNVBHYzBiT1pYSlRwUHRzX3ZLR3RkQ012TzJ4WGNPNUJaU2IweW11dTlUaE1aMndFX20wbXZlVTg0dnhwZ1NQU0pRdFdseDFwd1B5X29uQlJIcjFWcWV2d0c1elFISV9WUXZUbDlhQ1FWZHFpRzJ6azJ0bjQ0LUVSaDFJQ2VNaXU2OFJn0gGIAkFVX3lxTE1tbFhLU25WUVYwbjM3NkVDTFh5ek51UXpyNVQ4dHVPYnQ3eUpSb29xZWZxRFlnV1NMSUJNQWt0ZU12d2hwc1ByOWM5SHpjNmUtdGxRX0dKSk5lMmlGMnZUNktXQ3RjYzFKQVlDaF9qeThmWTBYYVVZTE4tVklHVUhJbnY3cHRaeXRpNmZOU1RQaFZDX0tyS25LdlBudkpVWTRmN1RrVVZyaVNWRktnNGRiQmJicnZXUGNsSl90TnVCWWYwcnRIbnlvN0VGOHBjUFJ5bjdmZDQ1LWw1ZnZTSi1qY2pRcDA2eE9Nc0lrNXhtcnZXLTJwYm9pZTJjMTVaRzBhRjRwZk1FNw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwJBVV95cUxPcEJvTURMenFDYnZRbWt5UndyQ0g0ODhnSW5XS3RJU1MtaUJpMnlfaGxBOHdsS2R0X25BNVV3Vi1waVk4OVJjZS1ZQVVNWTFXQTlhQUxDTjE4ZngwaEFiZjJOTTBHY0VlQnFvRVl4WlpveGphdE1QM3QzNnVyN3lPNVBHYzBiT1pYSlRwUHRzX3ZLR3RkQ012TzJ4WGNPNUJaU2IweW11dTlUaE1aMndFX20wbXZlVTg0dnhwZ1NQU0pRdFdseDFwd1B5X29uQlJIcjFWcWV2d0c1elFISV9WUXZUbDlhQ1FWZHFpRzJ6azJ0bjQ0LUVSaDFJQ2VNaXU2OFJn0gGIAkFVX3lxTE1tbFhLU25WUVYwbjM3NkVDTFh5ek51UXpyNVQ4dHVPYnQ3eUpSb29xZWZxRFlnV1NMSUJNQWt0ZU12d2hwc1ByOWM5SHpjNmUtdGxRX0dKSk5lMmlGMnZUNktXQ3RjYzFKQVlDaF9qeThmWTBYYVVZTE4tVklHVUhJbnY3cHRaeXRpNmZOU1RQaFZDX0tyS25LdlBudkpVWTRmN1RrVVZyaVNWRktnNGRiQmJicnZXUGNsSl90TnVCWWYwcnRIbnlvN0VGOHBjUFJ5bjdmZDQ1LWw1ZnZTSi1qY2pRcDA2eE9Nc0lrNXhtcnZXLTJwYm9pZTJjMTVaRzBhRjRwZk1FNw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:13:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Vivian Dsena breaks down in tears as Nouran brings his daughter Layan in the house - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18: Vivian Dsena breaks down in tears as Nouran brings his daughter Layan in the house</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a poignant moment on Bigg Boss 18, actor Vivian Dsena was overwhelmed with emotion when his daughter Layan was brought into the house by Nouran, bringing tears to his eyes.</p><ul><li>Vivian Dsena displayed a heartfelt reaction as he embraced his daughter.</li><li>The moment highlighted the emotional ties between family and contestants.</li><li>The audience praised the show's attempt to humanize reality TV contestants.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is the strongest emotional moment I’ve ever seen on the show.”</blockquote><p>The moment serves as a reminder of the personal stories behind the contestants in the competitive environment of reality television.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-vivian-dsena-breaks-down-in-tears-as-nouran-brings-his-daughter-layan-in-the-house/articleshow/116876035.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-vivian-dsena-breaks-down-in-tears-as-nouran-brings-his-daughter-layan-in-the-house/articleshow/116876035.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fans call Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Diljit Dosanjh’s ‘memorable meeting’ the ‘first unexpected col - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fans call PM Modi and Diljit Dosanjh’s meeting the ‘first unexpected collaboration of 2025’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116876091,imgsize-57502,width-400,resizemode-4/116876091.jpg" alt="PM Modi and Diljit Dosanjh’s meeting"><figcaption>Prime Minister Modi and Diljit Dosanjh during their meeting.</figcaption><p>The New Year dawned with an unexpected yet memorable meeting between Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and global icon Diljit Dosanjh, sparking excitement on social media.</p><ul><li>Diljit Dosanjh celebrated the start of 2025 with a meeting with PM Modi.</li><li>The meeting was shared on social media, highlighting their warm interaction.</li><li>PM Modi praised Diljit, emphasizing the pride of seeing talent from small beginnings shine globally.</li><li>Diljit expressed his realization of India's greatness through his travels.</li><li>The joint post received an enthusiastic response, with fans dubbing it the 'first unexpected collaboration of 2025.'</li></ul><blockquote>“When a boy from a small village in 'Hindustan' shines on the global stage, it feels amazing.” - PM Modi</blockquote><blockquote>“A fantastic start to 2025. A very memorable meeting with PM @narendramodi Ji.” - Diljit Dosanjh</blockquote><p>This heartwarming interaction highlights the blend of music, culture, and the importance of recognizing the human connections behind public figures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/music/news/fans-call-prime-minister-narendra-modi-and-diljit-dosanjhs-memorable-meeting-the-first-unexpected-collaboration-of-2025/articleshow/116876001.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/music/news/fans-call-prime-minister-narendra-modi-and-diljit-dosanjhs-memorable-meeting-the-first-unexpected-collaboration-of-2025/articleshow/116876001.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These two CBFC objections for Game Changer raise questions - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>These two CBFC objections for Game Changer raise questions</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 2, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> 123telugu.com</p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Game-Changer-2.jpg" alt="Game Changer Movie Poster" width="500" height="333">
<figcaption>Game Changer Movie Poster</figcaption>
<p>The grand arrival of Game Changer, a highly anticipated political drama directed by Shankar Shanmugam, is just around the corner, set to release on January 10, 2025.</p>
<ul>
<li>The movie has been granted a U/A certificate by the CBFC with a runtime of 2 hours and 45 minutes.</li>
<li>CBFC objections include the requirement for the movie's title to be presented in Telugu and the exclusion of the honorific 'Padmasree' before Brahmanandam's name.</li>
<li>The concerns prompt questions about inconsistencies with previous films like Prabhas’ Kalki 2898 AD.</li>
<li>The objections may relate to past controversies surrounding the misuse of award titles by actors, including a directive from the Andhra Pradesh High Court.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It remains to be seen who will provide clarity on these matters.”</blockquote>
<p>As the film's release approaches, the clarity regarding these objections is eagerly awaited by audiences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/these-two-cbfc-objections-for-game-changer-raise-questions.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/these-two-cbfc-objections-for-game-changer-raise-questions.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer US Box Office Premiere Pre-Sales: 98% Higher Than Guntur Kaaram But Pushpa 2 & Others Are Out Of League (8 Days To Go) - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer US Box Office Premiere Pre-Sales: 98% Higher Than Guntur Kaaram But Pushpa 2 & Others Are Outperforming</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p>
<img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2025/01/game-changer-us-box-office-premiere-pre-sales-01.jpg" alt="Game Changer US Box Office Premiere Pre-Sales" width="1200" height="630">
<figcaption>Game Changer US Advance Booking (Premieres) (Photo Credit – Facebook)</figcaption>
<p>Ram Charan and Kiara Advani's upcoming film, Game Changer, is making waves in advance ticket sales ahead of its US premiere.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Game Changer has achieved pre-sales of <strong>$359K</strong> as of January 2, 2025, having sold over 12.8K tickets across 1124 shows.</li>
  <li>It is 98% higher than the pre-sales of Mahesh Babu's Guntur Kaaram.</li>
  <li>Despite the positive numbers, it still lags significantly behind other major films like Pushpa 2 and Kalki 2898 AD.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The total pre-sales in North America have crossed the <strong>$375K</strong> mark. The Game Changer trailer is expected to release at 5 PM IST today, which may help to revive interest.”</blockquote>
<p>As the premiere date approaches, it will be crucial for the marketing of Game Changer to align with audience expectations and restore buzz.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/game-changer-us-box-office-premiere-pre-sales-98-higher-than-guntur-kaaram-but-pushpa-2-others-are-out-of-league-8-days-to-go/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/game-changer-us-box-office-premiere-pre-sales-98-higher-than-guntur-kaaram-but-pushpa-2-others-are-out-of-league-8-days-to-go/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:12:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>