<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:22:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:22:10 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Travis Kelce puts an end to Taylor Swift engagement rumour after blurry picture surfaces: ‘He thinks its… - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Travis Kelce Denies Engagement Rumors With Taylor Swift After Blurry Picture Sparks Speculation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/taylor-swift-travis-kelce-_1734668900970_1734668901332.webp" alt="Travis Kelce and Taylor Swift" title="Travis Kelce and Taylor Swift" /><figcaption>Travis Kelce and Taylor Swift</figcaption></figure><p>Taylor Swift and Travis Kelce remain at the heart of engagement speculation, but they prefer to keep their relationship private, despite ongoing rumors.</p><ul><li>The couple has been in the spotlight since summer, with fans speculating about their engagement.</li><li>A blurry photo from a surprise party sparked rumors of an engagement ring, but insiders claim there is no truth to it yet.</li><li>Kelce finds the rumors amusing but also overwhelming due to family pressures and public interest.</li><li>Both Swift and Kelce are focused on their careers and are not rushing into an engagement.</li><li>They plan to keep any future engagement low-key and private, despite media and fan speculation.</li></ul><blockquote>“Travis has ideas, he would love to be engaged and married to Taylor, he is in love. She is in love with him.”</blockquote><p>Ultimately, Travis and Taylor are enjoying their relationship without letting the engagement buzz disrupt their time together.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/travis-kelce-puts-an-end-to-taylor-swift-engagement-rumour-after-blurry-picture-surfaces-he-thinks-its-101734668584526.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/travis-kelce-puts-an-end-to-taylor-swift-engagement-rumour-after-blurry-picture-surfaces-he-thinks-its-101734668584526.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 04:32:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ram Kapoor stuns fans with dramatic weight loss: “Was working on myself quite extensively” - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ram Kapoor stuns fans with dramatic weight loss: “Was working on myself quite extensively”</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p><img src="https://media5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ram_Kapoor_Weight_Loss.jpg" alt="Ram Kapoor stuns fans with dramatic weight loss: “Was working on myself quite extensively”" width="620" height="450"><figcaption>Ram Kapoor's remarkable weight loss journey.</figcaption><p>Television and film actor Ram Kapoor has surprised fans with his significant weight transformation, revealing a new fit physique after a hiatus from social media.</p><ul><li>Ram Kapoor, 51, shared transformation pictures on Instagram.</li><li>Fans reacted positively, praising his dedication and transformation.</li><li>Mixed reactions were noted, with some missing his previous looks from popular shows.</li><li>Fellow actors and fans expressed admiration through comments and emojis.</li></ul><blockquote>“Hi guys, sorry for the slightly long absence from Insta was working on myself quite extensively.” - Ram Kapoor</blockquote><p>This transformation has ignited conversations around physical health and dedication, showcasing Kapoor's commitment to fitness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/ram-kapoor-stuns-fans-dramatic-weight-loss-working-quite-extensively/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/ram-kapoor-stuns-fans-dramatic-weight-loss-working-quite-extensively/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 03:35:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ram Kapoor stuns with drastic weight loss, flaunts cool new look; fans can't ‘recognise’ him - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ram Kapoor's Dramatic Weight Loss Stuns Fans</h1><p><strong>Published on: </strong>Dec 20, 2024 08:14 AM IST | <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/f33cfafd-53a5-473c-afcb-ddb173b66eed_1734613716034_1734613719536.jpg" alt="Ram Kapoor's stunning transformation in new look wows fans."><figcaption>Ram Kapoor's stunning transformation in new look wows fans.</figcaption><p>In a remarkable transformation, Ram Kapoor left his fans amazed after sharing his new look on Instagram, reflecting significant weight loss and a stylish new wardrobe.</p><ul><li>Ram Kapoor, seen recently after a long absence, showcased his stylish new look.</li><li>His outfit included a white graphic print shirt, black fitted jeans, and trendy sneakers.</li><li>The transformation has sparked a viral reaction on social media with many fans expressing disbelief.</li><li>Fellow celebrities and fans are commenting with surprise and admiration.</li></ul><blockquote>“Wow, the change is phenomenal.” - Comment from a fan.</blockquote><p>This transformation journey has resonated widely, marking a significant moment for Ram Kapoor and his followers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/fashion/ram-kapoor-stuns-with-incredible-weight-transformation-flaunts-cool-new-look-fans-could-not-recognise-101734613181627.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/fashion/ram-kapoor-stuns-with-incredible-weight-transformation-flaunts-cool-new-look-fans-could-not-recognise-101734613181627.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Great Indian Kapil fiasco: After Atlee jibe, Kapil Sharma needs to rethink his jokes - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Great Indian Kapil Fiasco: After Atlee Jibe, Kapil Sharma Needs to Rethink His Jokes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>Kapil Sharma's recent remarks about director Atlee have ignited a heated discussion about the comedian's style of humor, leading many to question if he needs to reassess his approach.</p><ul><li>The controversy revolves around Kapil's comments on Atlee's appearance during a promotional event for the film Jawan.</li><li>Netizens criticized Kapil for what they deemed inappropriate and racist comments aimed at Atlee.</li><li>In a response, Atlee emphasized that talent should not be judged by appearance.</li><li>This incident has reignited discussions about the offensive nature of humor on Kapil's show, which often relies on mocking individuals for their looks and characteristics.</li><li>Previous comments made by Kapil have also been scrutinized for perpetuating sexism and body shaming.</li><li>The article highlights the ongoing issue of regressive humor that continues to thrive in Hindi entertainment.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is a thin line that separates laughter and pain, comedy and tragedy, humour and hurt.” - Erma Bombeck</blockquote><p>Kapil Sharma's recent controversy prompts reflection on the need for a shift in comedic approaches within mainstream Indian entertainment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/television/the-great-indian-kapil-fiasco-after-atlee-jibe-kapil-sharma-need-to-rethink-his-jokes-9731531/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/television/the-great-indian-kapil-fiasco-after-atlee-jibe-kapil-sharma-need-to-rethink-his-jokes-9731531/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:35:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shah Rukh Khan and Aishwarya Rai smile as they record their kids AbRam, Aaradhya Bachchan's performance at school event - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shah Rukh Khan and Aishwarya Rai attend kids' school event, record performances</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 07:33 AM IST - Hindustan Times</p><p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Shah Rukh Khan and Aishwarya Rai attended a school event where their kids, AbRam Khan and Aaradhya Bachchan, performed on stage. Both stars were seen recording their kids' performances.</p><ol><li>Aishwarya and Abhishek's daughter, Aaradhya Bachchan, performed on stage.</li><li>Shah Rukh and Gauri's son, AbRam Khan, also performed with Aaradhya.</li><li>Aishwarya and Abhishek were seen together at the event, putting rumors about their marriage to rest.</li><li>Shah Rukh was accompanied by his wife Gauri and daughter Suhana.</li><li>Other celebrities like Shahid Kapoor, Mira Rajput, Kareena Kapoor, and Saif Ali Khan also attended the event.</li></ol><blockquote>Shah Rukh was seen dancing with the school kids.</blockquote><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The event was a star-studded affair with many celebrities attending to support their kids. Shah Rukh and Aishwarya were both actively involved in recording their kids' performances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-aishwarya-rai-smile-record-kids-abram-khan-aaradhya-bachchan-performance-school-event-101734658044767.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-aishwarya-rai-smile-record-kids-abram-khan-aaradhya-bachchan-performance-school-event-101734658044767.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:03:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2: Allu Arjun Film REMOVED From PVR Inox In North India. Here's WHY - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxQeVZrQWkwZDNDWEZlaXhiMnhZMUlzaHQxeWtpRFQtM191UUxZWVJMSmFwQ1J2ejlCbG8wcExJSFFKVXlJanp1dGNKX0d5UWxqSEUwNmtDem5WVFdnU1ZpbkNKMFNmS3ZxdnFHR3NqQ3JaT0dWNFRXeWhBR3lDN3Jrc3NRSWFYUWNwOWdvdXZET2FPbXlWQjI0ZGZiWGI4RFVSN0E1ZUhrZXpicUxfaUNwTXc2S0ZhelhDelE0dU4zaFBkb3pPNDk4cEVXUlZ6UFlvZUhEY1JEZXNVVjBCYnFrUTFUMjhoWloyUndrUG9HLVppZ0VVTUhXMWpqY1BGbEFralR0Y1VoSlQ5ZURMWkHSAZMCQVVfeXFMTnp3MXFrbUZWUUlOemJuMFRJY2hxUTQ1Rk53SmVaNHJPWC1DdE84SXhJTk9GaGZILXNYNnNRa010cE9oVExIV195WnhYcFVja21DaXAtNi1LUVoxZlZ1MUZMaklQZ1h0aHZVTmJqQVdndDczMUJ0UzZaVlhJQXRZdTNCcmd3UTg4dHBQRENmYkZyQlpudHF2T3VJS015elhMek45Zy1xQlhLVTFVWmtIb2d2RG5Jemc0Q1pCZnM0QXlNamhUNUFWUEkwRjdxRjNYOWxfZjRBM0tIWlJHckZvcjlydFhMSElsLVdYMERSTjN1UXpiNDg4YXMtTjY5QkpCSTVWZHNtUlVqV2lMenQyenczdWs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxQeVZrQWkwZDNDWEZlaXhiMnhZMUlzaHQxeWtpRFQtM191UUxZWVJMSmFwQ1J2ejlCbG8wcExJSFFKVXlJanp1dGNKX0d5UWxqSEUwNmtDem5WVFdnU1ZpbkNKMFNmS3ZxdnFHR3NqQ3JaT0dWNFRXeWhBR3lDN3Jrc3NRSWFYUWNwOWdvdXZET2FPbXlWQjI0ZGZiWGI4RFVSN0E1ZUhrZXpicUxfaUNwTXc2S0ZhelhDelE0dU4zaFBkb3pPNDk4cEVXUlZ6UFlvZUhEY1JEZXNVVjBCYnFrUTFUMjhoWloyUndrUG9HLVppZ0VVTUhXMWpqY1BGbEFralR0Y1VoSlQ5ZURMWkHSAZMCQVVfeXFMTnp3MXFrbUZWUUlOemJuMFRJY2hxUTQ1Rk53SmVaNHJPWC1DdE84SXhJTk9GaGZILXNYNnNRa010cE9oVExIV195WnhYcFVja21DaXAtNi1LUVoxZlZ1MUZMaklQZ1h0aHZVTmJqQVdndDczMUJ0UzZaVlhJQXRZdTNCcmd3UTg4dHBQRENmYkZyQlpudHF2T3VJS015elhMek45Zy1xQlhLVTFVWmtIb2d2RG5Jemc0Q1pCZnM0QXlNamhUNUFWUEkwRjdxRjNYOWxfZjRBM0tIWlJHckZvcjlydFhMSElsLVdYMERSTjN1UXpiNDg4YXMtTjY5QkpCSTVWZHNtUlVqV2lMenQyenczdWs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 box office collection day 14: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna’s collects 975 cr by 2nd Thursday - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 box office collection day 14: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna’s collects 975 cr by 2nd Thursday morning; to join elusive 1000 crore club soon</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116464525,imgsize-70816,width-400,resizemode-4/116464525.jpg' alt='Pushpa 2 box office collection day 14'><figcaption>Pushpa 2 continues its successful run at the box office.</figcaption><p>The film Pushpa 2 directed by Sukumar is close to joining the 1000 crore club, having collected Rs 975 crore as of Thursday morning.</p><ul><li>The film collected Rs 973.2 crore by the end of 14 days, with an additional Rs 1.8 crore from morning shows.</li><li>It has become the highest-grossing Hindi film of all time, collecting Rs 607.35 crore from its Hindi version.</li><li>The Telugu version has grossed Rs 323.3 crore, and other versions contribute Rs 51.6 crore from Tamil and Rs 20.92 crore from Kannada and Malayalam combined.</li><li>The detailed day-wise box office collection shows a strong performance throughout its run.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pushpa 2 has beaten records set by Aamir Khan’s Dangal, establishing itself as a major hit.”</blockquote><p>The film's legacy continues with plans for a third installment, Pushpa 3 - The Rampage, expected in 2-3 years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-14-updated-live-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandannas-collects-975-cr-by-2nd-thursday-morning-to-join-elusive-1000-crore-club-soon/articleshow/116464545.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-14-updated-live-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandannas-collects-975-cr-by-2nd-thursday-morning-to-join-elusive-1000-crore-club-soon/articleshow/116464545.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 01:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kareena Kapoor Khan and Shahid Kapoor unknowingly recreate iconic 'Jab We Met' moment; fans go WILD - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kareena Kapoor Khan and Shahid Kapoor unknowingly recreate iconic 'Jab We Met' moment; fans go WILD</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>In a delightful turn of events, Bollywood stars Kareena Kapoor Khan and Shahid Kapoor have shared a moment reminiscent of their iconic film 'Jab We Met', sparking excitement among fans on social media.</p><ul><li>Kareena and Shahid were spotted together recently.</li><li>Fans took to social media to express their joy and nostalgia.</li><li>This moment rekindled memories of their film released in 2007.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's amazing how a simple glance can take you back in time!” - a fan tweeted.</blockquote><p>Despite the passage of time, the chemistry between the two stars remains a cherished memory for their fans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/kareena-kapoor-khan-and-shahid-kapoor-unknowingly-recreate-iconic-jab-we-met-moment-fans-go-wild/articleshow/116486030.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/kareena-kapoor-khan-and-shahid-kapoor-unknowingly-recreate-iconic-jab-we-met-moment-fans-go-wild/articleshow/116486030.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 01:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024: Check here Astrological prediction for all zodiac signs - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daily Horoscope: Find out Astrological prediction for December 20 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 20, 2024<br /><strong>Published By:</strong> Ayush Bisht</p>
<p>Explore the daily horoscope for all zodiac signs to uncover insights on love, health, money, and career.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Aries:</strong> Friendships enhance happiness, significant progress in work, and good news from loved ones.</li>
<li><strong>Taurus:</strong> Focus on family matters, avoid haste, and maintain professionalism in career.</li>
<li><strong>Gemini:</strong> Opportunities for courage increase, important travels possible, and focus on social connections.</li>
<li><strong>Cancer:</strong> Support from loved ones leads to happiness, relationships improve, emphasis on family traditions.</li>
<li><strong>Leo:</strong> Increased socializing, creativity gains strength, and a positive family atmosphere.</li>
<li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Emphasize caution in work, long-distance travel possible, keep health in focus.</li>
<li><strong>Libra:</strong> Suitable work opportunities, increased income from new sources, and maintain healthy competition.</li>
<li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Strengthen connections with seniors, financial negotiations succeed, and performance aligns with capabilities.</li>
<li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> Luck will enhance business activities, long-term plans will advance, and networking will grow.</li>
<li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Health awareness is crucial, and fulfill responsibilities diligently.</li>
<li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Positive family dynamics, cooperation from friends, and focus on goals.</li>
<li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Focus on hard work for positive outcomes, maintain a disciplined approach, and improve logical thinking.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/horoscopes/story/horoscope-today-december-20-2024-aries-taurus-gemini-cancer-leo-virgo-libra-scorpio-sagittarius-capricorn-aquarius-pisces-2652369-2024-12-20</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/horoscopes/story/horoscope-today-december-20-2024-aries-taurus-gemini-cancer-leo-virgo-libra-scorpio-sagittarius-capricorn-aquarius-pisces-2652369-2024-12-20</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bachchala Malli Movie Review |Allari Naresh Bachchala Malli Review - Gulte]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bachhala Malli Movie Review</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 20-12-2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gulte</p>
<p>Subbu Mangadevvi's second directorial film, Bachhala Malli, featuring Allari Naresh, aims to deliver a serious rustic action drama. The film explores themes of stubbornness, love, and personal transformation.</p>
<img src='path-to-image.jpg' alt='Bachhala Malli Movie Poster'>
<figcaption>Bachhala Malli Movie Poster</figcaption>
<ul>
  <li>Rating: 2.25/5</li>
  <li>Allari Naresh delivers a commendable performance, particularly in the film's climax.</li>
  <li>Amritha Aiyer plays Kaveri, but her character feels out of place.</li>
  <li>Positives include realistic action choreography and the song 'Mari Antha Kopam'.</li>
  <li>Negatives highlight a lack of depth in writing, predictable screenplay, and uninspiring character development.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Overall, Bachhala Malli is a genuine effort to make a hard-hitting &amp; realistic movie.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, despite strong performances, the film suffers from poor writing and predictable direction.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gulte.com/moviereviews/330987/bachchala-malli-movie-review</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gulte.com/moviereviews/330987/bachchala-malli-movie-review</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:55:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Without cinema, I'd be dead or in prison': Danny Trejo on how films saved him, working in American Warrior | Exclusive - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Danny Trejo Discusses Redemption and His New Film 'American Warrior'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/Danny_Trejo_1734620320547_1734620328856.webp" alt="Danny Trejo stars in American Warrior, a film on MMA." title="Danny Trejo stars in American Warrior, a film on MMA.">
<figcaption>Danny Trejo stars in American Warrior, a film on MMA.</figcaption>
<p>Danny Trejo speaks on the role cinema has played in his life and his latest film, American Warrior, which emphasizes themes of redemption and transformation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trejo reflects on his life story of redemption, stating, "My life has been a story of redemption." </li>
  <li>He relates to his character in American Warrior, which focuses on an MMA fighter overcoming a troubled past.</li>
  <li>Trejo's life experiences include drug abuse and incarceration, which he attributes to the transformative power of cinema.</li>
  <li>At 80, he continues to act in multiple films, driven by love for his work and the desire to leave a legacy.</li>
  <li>After a successful premiere, American Warrior aims for a wide release in India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I'd be probably dead or, you know, in prison (without cinema)," Trejo shares, emphasizing the importance of films in his recovery.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Danny Trejo's experiences highlight the power of cinema as a medium for personal transformation and redemption, inspiring others along the way.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/without-cinema-id-be-dead-or-in-prison-danny-trejo-on-how-films-saved-him-working-in-american-warrior-exclusive-101734620163691.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/without-cinema-id-be-dead-or-in-prison-danny-trejo-on-how-films-saved-him-working-in-american-warrior-exclusive-101734620163691.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:43:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today LIVE Updates on December 20, 2024 : Virgo Health Horoscope for 2025 predicts steady health - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxPdUZEckJWTVQ5NWNCaWlKRi1nMS1vdU5GQTExRm9uYlVfVFdxRERFeUl2R1piQ0NhWkxodEhmN0FZWVQ0MVoyQXprUjNqR2g0bnFJMURjMDlKMHRBZHRfNE1QVWY5YVVab3BaWE9tbmlFX0ZpOWVQVHhJcHk0NzFka2xtWlpYTXZfT0o0cDAzcTE2S05kYUNVc252MTVmZ0Y5RFBuUWpCRmxRMmNXN3plNUJiWF9YbEpQ0gG-AUFVX3lxTE0yM3B2d29abjdJVlplcWxHUWpjSG9jVnptakdpMWlOYXRmcUUtWHR3bUtyZnBndXphY1o3NmJDTXNGNHRvX3pmeFFPX1ZKaVlkODJRaGRHY2VQVHRRMnBuR3A3cVgyOHV5dDFpS0NrQWtVY2cwLUhkT2c4Vml2RnFldFZSbktfOGFEWm51aTBOeUgzUW9GMkxpUDdSR0JlVndvTVp4dmtuXzlJRU9pM0hLTnhSOThQeENmYkdHLUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxPdUZEckJWTVQ5NWNCaWlKRi1nMS1vdU5GQTExRm9uYlVfVFdxRERFeUl2R1piQ0NhWkxodEhmN0FZWVQ0MVoyQXprUjNqR2g0bnFJMURjMDlKMHRBZHRfNE1QVWY5YVVab3BaWE9tbmlFX0ZpOWVQVHhJcHk0NzFka2xtWlpYTXZfT0o0cDAzcTE2S05kYUNVc252MTVmZ0Y5RFBuUWpCRmxRMmNXN3plNUJiWF9YbEpQ0gG-AUFVX3lxTE0yM3B2d29abjdJVlplcWxHUWpjSG9jVnptakdpMWlOYXRmcUUtWHR3bUtyZnBndXphY1o3NmJDTXNGNHRvX3pmeFFPX1ZKaVlkODJRaGRHY2VQVHRRMnBuR3A3cVgyOHV5dDFpS0NrQWtVY2cwLUhkT2c4Vml2RnFldFZSbktfOGFEWm51aTBOeUgzUW9GMkxpUDdSR0JlVndvTVp4dmtuXzlJRU9pM0hLTnhSOThQeENmYkdHLUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2: The Rule' box office collection Day 15 (Updated Live): Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna starre - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2: The Rule</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116485780,imgsize-111262,width-400,resizemode-4/116485780.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2: The Rule box office collection Day 15" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>'Pushpa 2: The Rule' box office collection misses Rs 1,000 crore mark</figcaption>
<p>On its 15th day, Pushpa 2 experiences a notable decline in box office collections, failing to reach the Rs 1,000 crore milestone amid competition from new releases.</p>
<ul>
<li>The film earned Rs 17.75 crore on Day 15, a 13% drop from Day 14.</li>
<li>The Hindi version significantly contributed with Rs 14 crore, followed by the Telugu version earning Rs 2.75 crore.</li>
<li>Despite the dip, Pushpa 2 closed its second week with a cumulative collection of Rs 264.9 crore.</li>
<li>The total worldwide collection has exceeded Rs 1,500 crore, marking it the fastest Indian film to do so.</li>
<li>Upcoming releases may impact the film's momentum in theatres.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Pushpa 2 has grossed over Rs 1,500 crore in worldwide box office collection, making it the fastest Indian film to reach the mark.”</blockquote>
<p>This moment marks a pivotal point for the film amidst fresh competition in the box office landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-the-rule-box-office-collection-day-15-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-misses-rs-1000-crore-mark-as-collections-dip-below-rs-20-crore/articleshow/116485796.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-the-rule-box-office-collection-day-15-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-misses-rs-1000-crore-mark-as-collections-dip-below-rs-20-crore/articleshow/116485796.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024 advices planning for vacation - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024</h1><p><strong>Date: December 20, 2024</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/Aquarius_1728478944944_1734615085491.jpg" alt="Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024: You should prefer smart investment decisions for a safe future." title="Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024: You should prefer smart investment decisions for a safe future."><figcaption>Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024: You should prefer smart investment decisions for a safe future.</figcaption></figure><p>This daily horoscope emphasizes financial success and the importance of planning crucial decisions in life, including potential vacations with loved ones.</p><ul><li>Life is not a mystery unresolved; focus on resolving issues in love and work.</li><li>Financial success allows for smart investment decisions and planning vacations.</li><li>Health is good, but exercise is recommended.</li><li>Today's love life suggests passion and conflict resolution might restore happiness.</li><li>Career advice discusses avoiding ego in professional settings and includes travel opportunities for some professions.</li></ul><blockquote>"Talk with the lover to resolve every problem that exists."</blockquote><p>This horoscope guides Aquarians to engage with loved ones meaningfully while making smart financial choices that may lead to prosperity and happiness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/aquarius-daily-horoscope-today-december-20-2024-advices-planning-for-vacation-101734614917303.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/aquarius-daily-horoscope-today-december-20-2024-advices-planning-for-vacation-101734614917303.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:40:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024 predicts a hike in salary - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024 predicts a hike in salary</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/Capricorn_1728478974232_1734615783857.jpg" alt="Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024: Your professional life will be productive while monetary success will be there." title="Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024: Your professional life will be productive while monetary success will be there.">
<figcaption>Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024: Your professional life will be productive while monetary success will be there.</figcaption>
<p>Today's Capricorn horoscope suggests promising professional success and a potential salary increase, along with positive developments in personal relationships.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Time spent with loved ones is encouraged; ensure the love life remains intact.</li>
  <li>Productivity at work is a focus, with indications of a salary hike or promotion for some.</li>
  <li>Financial opportunities through investments in mutual funds and real estate are recommended.</li>
  <li>Health remains generally good; exercise and proper diet are advised.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Your professional life will be productive while monetary success will be there." - Dr. J.N. Pandey</blockquote>
<p>The day looks positive for Capricorn, with many areas of life showing prospects for growth, particularly in career and relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/capricorn-daily-horoscope-today-december-20-2024-predicts-a-hike-in-salary-101734615549513.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/capricorn-daily-horoscope-today-december-20-2024-predicts-a-hike-in-salary-101734615549513.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:39:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024 predicts fortune in stock market - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024 predicts fortune in stock market</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/Sagittarius_1728479012112_1734616411301.jpg" alt="Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024. No serious medical issue will impact the day." title="Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024. No serious medical issue will impact the day.">
<figcaption>Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024. No serious medical issue will impact the day.</figcaption>
<p>The Sagittarius daily horoscope for December 20, 2024, highlights financial stability and opportunities for investment, particularly in the stock market, despite facing challenges in personal relationships.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The love relationship may face challenges, but professional life is likely to be successful.</li>
  <li>Financially, this is a day for making investments with the assurance of stability.</li>
  <li>Health is expected to be good, with no serious issues reported.</li>
  <li>Professionals might find new job opportunities and business expansion may be possible.</li>
  <li>There will be minor health complaints among children and some women.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Despite challenges, your professional life will be productive today.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Sagittarius individuals are poised for a prosperous day, especially in terms of finances, while also navigating personal relationships with care.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/sagittarius-daily-horoscope-today-december-20-2024-predicts-fortune-in-stock-market-101734616241230.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/sagittarius-daily-horoscope-today-december-20-2024-predicts-fortune-in-stock-market-101734616241230.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:38:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024 predicts wealth from new sources - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 20, 2024</strong>, <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/scorpio_1728479075489_1734617291885.jpg" alt="Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024. You need to sit and talk with the lover and this will also strengthen the bonding." title="Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024. You need to sit and talk with the lover and this will also strengthen the bonding.">
<figcaption>Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024. You need to sit and talk with the lover and this will also strengthen the bonding.</figcaption>
<p>Today's horoscope for Scorpio highlights deep love and job success, with an emphasis on smart financial decisions and overall good health.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Focus on smart monetary investments and explore new income sources.</li>
  <li>Your relationship will deepen, and it's a good time for conflict resolution.</li>
  <li>Professional challenges may arise, but confidence is key, especially for job interviews.</li>
  <li>Financially stable; consider investments carefully, particularly in property and stocks.</li>
  <li>Minor health concerns may arise, so maintaining a healthy diet is advised.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Your efforts will never go in vain.”</blockquote>
<p>Today’s predictions suggest a blend of personal and professional growth, with ample opportunities for financial gain and relationship strengthening.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/scorpio-daily-horoscope-today-december-20-2024-predicts-wealth-from-new-sources-101734617132853.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/scorpio-daily-horoscope-today-december-20-2024-predicts-wealth-from-new-sources-101734617132853.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:37:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taurus Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024 predicts an auspicious time - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Taurus Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024 to know your astrological predictions. Utilize finance smartly today.</h1><p><strong>Date: December 20, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/Taurus_1728477354135_1734614495653.jpg" alt="Taurus Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024: Be positive in attitude that will work out in both personal and professional life." title="Taurus Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024: Be positive in attitude that will work out in both personal and professional life."><figcaption>Taurus Daily Horoscope Today, December 20, 2024: Be positive in attitude that will work out in both personal and professional life.</figcaption></figure><p>The daily horoscope predicts an auspicious day for Taurus individuals in both personal and professional aspects. Financial planning is encouraged, and health remains stable.</p><ul><li>Positive personal and professional life.</li><li>Encourage smart financial planning.</li><li>Potential improvements in romantic relationships.</li><li>Career responsibilities may provide opportunities for growth.</li><li>Health should be monitored, especially for those with past cardiac issues.</li></ul><blockquote>"Egos are not your playmates."</blockquote><p>Overall, a productive day lies ahead, with opportunities for personal growth and relationship improvements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/taurus-daily-horoscope-today-december-20-2024-predicts-an-auspicious-time-101734614303615.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/taurus-daily-horoscope-today-december-20-2024-predicts-an-auspicious-time-101734614303615.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:31:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roshan Kanakala’s second film ‘Mowgli 2025’ launched in a grand manner - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Roshan Kanakala’s second film ‘Mowgli 2025’ launched in a grand manner</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 20, 2024 2:58 am IST | Source: 123Telugu</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Mowgli.jpg" alt="Mowgli 2025" width="550" height="366"><figcaption>The first look poster of Mowgli 2025</figcaption><p>Famous anchor Suma Kanakala’s son, Roshan Kanakala, debuted in Tollywood with the romantic entertainer Bubblegum. He has now teamed up with director Sandeep Raj for his second film, Mowgli 2025, set against a forest backdrop.</p><ul><li>The film was launched today with a traditional pooja ceremony attended by special guests.</li><li>Producer Vishwa Prasad began the proceedings by handing over the script to director Sandeep Raj.</li><li>Filmmaker Sandeep Reddy Vanga clapped the soundboard for the muhurtham shot featuring lead actors Roshan Kanakala and Sakshi Sagar Mhadolkar.</li><li>Mega director Srikanth Odela switched on the camera to mark the film's auspicious start.</li><li>The first-look poster was unveiled, showing Roshan in a vibrant forest setting.</li><li>Kaala Bhairava is composing the music, and Rama Maruti M is handling the cinematography.</li><li>The film is set to begin shooting next month.</li></ul><blockquote>“Mowgli 2025” promises to be an engaging romantic entertainer set in a lush forest environment.</blockquote><p>The launch of Mowgli 2025 is an exciting step for Roshan Kanakala, as he builds on his initial success with his debut film.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/roshan-kanakalas-second-film-mowgli-2025-launched-in-a-grand-manner.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/roshan-kanakalas-second-film-mowgli-2025-launched-in-a-grand-manner.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 21:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bachchala Malli Review: USA Premiere Report - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bachchala Malli Review: USA Premiere Report</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bachhala-mallimovie-review-768x576.jpg" alt="Bachhala Malli Movie Review">
<figcaption>Bachchala Malli Movie Review</figcaption>
<p>Bachchala Malli depicts the life struggle of Malli from childhood to love life set in a rustic backdrop, aiming for emotional depth but falling short.</p>
<ul>
<li>Allari Naresh shines in an intense role as Malli.</li>
<li>First half presents a routine narrative with a need for deeper emotional impact.</li>
<li>Background music aligns well with the story's tone.</li>
<li>Potential for a stronger second half remains.</li>
<li>Cast includes Allari Naresh and Amritha Aiyer, directed by Subbu Mangadevvi.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The desired emotional impact doesn’t quite land, though the effort is evident.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, while the film showcases Malli's journey, it may need more depth to resonate fully with the audience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.m9.news/reviews/bachchala-malli-movie-review/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.m9.news/reviews/bachchala-malli-movie-review/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 19:32:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today: Astrological prediction for December 20, 2024 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Horoscope Today: Astrological Prediction for December 20, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/horoscope_1672156308727_1734605572769.jpg" alt="Astrological prediction for December 20. (Pixabay)" title="Astrological prediction for December 20. (Pixabay)">
<figcaption>Astrological prediction for December 20. (Pixabay)</figcaption>
<p>The article provides daily astrological predictions for all zodiac signs focusing on what individuals can expect on December 20, 2024. It offers insights into health, finances, and personal relationships for each sign.</p>
<ul>
<li>Predictions for Aries suggest neglecting health could delay their fitness goals and recommend financial conservatism.</li>
<li>Taurus foresee an influx of funds and emphasize the joy that comes from family successes.</li>
<li>Gemini might deal with minor health issues and higher expenses but can expect essential trips to help achieve their dreams.</li>
<li>Cancer individuals are expected to be motivated to improve their health despite feeling less energetic.</li>
<li>Leo are encouraged to be cautious with finances but can anticipate successes at work.</li>
<li>Virgo can expect stress from property concerns but favorable business deals might be on the horizon.</li>
<li>Libra may find physical activities challenging but could see valuable property opportunities arising.</li>
<li>Scorpio might experience a windfall and face potential ancestral property issues affecting family dynamics.</li>
<li>Sagittarius can anticipate stability in their financial outlook while avoiding risks.</li>
<li>Capricorn should prepare for unexpected expenses related to loved ones but will see appreciation in family obligations.</li>
<li>Aquarius will enjoy health improvements through activity, with potential for lucrative property investments.</li>
<li>Pisces may deal with criticism at work but will take steps to create harmony at home.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Love Focus: Romance unfolds slowly as you take things carefully." - Pisces</blockquote>
<p>This horoscope highlights the varying energies for each sign, indicating opportunities and challenges that may lie ahead, fostering a greater awareness and understanding of astrological influences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-astrological-prediction-for-december-20-2024-101734604068578.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-astrological-prediction-for-december-20-2024-101734604068578.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 19:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proud parents Abhishek Bachchan, Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and grandfather Amitabh Bachchan beam with pride - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Proud parents Abhishek Bachchan, Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and grandfather Amitabh Bachchan beam with pride as Aaradhya Bachchan shines in Christmas play: Watch videos</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 25, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>Abhishek Bachchan, Aishwarya Rai Bachchan, and Amitabh Bachchan express their pride as Aaradhya, their daughter, takes center stage in a Christmas play, showcasing her talent and charm.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Aaradhya performed beautifully in her school's Christmas play.</li>
  <li>Proud family members shared videos celebrating her performance.</li>
  <li>Fans are delighted to see the young Bachchan shining in a public event.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Seeing Aaradhya shine on stage fills us with immense joy and pride,” said Amitabh Bachchan.</blockquote>
<p>This heartwarming family moment has garnered significant attention on social media, highlighting Aaradhya's budding talent and the Bachchan family's close-knit bond.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/proud-parents-abhishek-bachchan-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-and-grandfather-amitabh-bachchan-beam-with-pride-as-aaradhya-bachchan-shines-in-christmas-play-watch-videos/articleshow/116481394.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/proud-parents-abhishek-bachchan-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-and-grandfather-amitabh-bachchan-beam-with-pride-as-aaradhya-bachchan-shines-in-christmas-play-watch-videos/articleshow/116481394.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 18:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai Holds Aaradhya's Hand, Leaves With Abhishek After School Annual Day Amid Divorce Rumours - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai Holds Aaradhya's Hand, Leaves With Abhishek After School Annual Day Amid Divorce Rumours</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Aishwarya, Abhishek and Aaradhya at Dhirubhai Ambani International School." title="Aishwarya, Abhishek and Aaradhya at Dhirubhai Ambani International School."><figcaption>Aishwarya, Abhishek and Aaradhya at Dhirubhai Ambani International School.</figcaption><p>Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan were spotted leaving Aaradhya’s school annual day together in Mumbai, despite ongoing divorce rumours. They appeared to put on a united front as they drove off together.</p><ul><li>The couple arrived separately but were seen together for most of the evening.</li><li>Their daughter Aaradhya was also present at the event.</li><li>Amitabh Bachchan, Abhishek’s father, attended the event, adding to the family's public appearance.</li><li>Rumours of divorce have circulated for months, though Amitabh Bachchan addressed these speculations indirectly in a blog post.</li><li>Aishwarya and Abhishek married in April 2007 and have a daughter born in November 2011.</li></ul><blockquote>“Speculations are speculations… they are speculated untruths, without verifications…” - Amitabh Bachchan</blockquote><p>The couple continues to manage public scrutiny surrounding their marriage while attending family events together.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/aishwarya-rai-holds-aaradhyas-hand-leaves-with-abhishek-after-school-annual-day-amid-divorce-rumours-9162287.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/aishwarya-rai-holds-aaradhyas-hand-leaves-with-abhishek-after-school-annual-day-amid-divorce-rumours-9162287.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 18:26:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shahid Kapoor Sits Behind Ex Kareena Kapoor At Ambani School Annual Day; Fans Say 'Our Geet, Aditya' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/shahid-kapoor-sits-behind-ex-kareena-kapoor-at-ambani-school-annual-day-fans-say-our-geet-aditya-9162264.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/shahid-kapoor-sits-behind-ex-kareena-kapoor-at-ambani-school-annual-day-fans-say-our-geet-aditya-9162264.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 18:05:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Makers Of Real Star Upendra's 'UI The Movie' Shares A Special Request For Theatre Audiences - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Makers of Real Star Upendra's 'UI The Movie' Shares A Special Request For Theatre Audiences</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now News</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116482555,thumbsize-127842,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116482555.jpg" alt="Real Star Upendra's 'UI The Movie' makers make a humble request" title="Real Star Upendra's 'UI The Movie' makers make a humble request"><figcaption>Real Star Upendra's 'UI The Movie' makers make a humble request</figcaption><p>The makers of the highly anticipated action, sci-fi thriller 'UI The Movie' are appealing to audiences to refrain from sharing spoilers as the film releases in theaters.</p><h2>The Humble Request</h2><p>The makers expressed on social media: “<em>UI</em> will be all yours in a few hours. It's the film that needs to be celebrated and experienced on big screens.” They urged viewers not to provide minute-to-minute updates or spoilers.</p><h2>Cult Following</h2><p>Film directors and actors have shown admiration for Upendra, calling him a master in the industry. Telugu Star Rana Daggubati acknowledged the eagerness of noted filmmakers to watch the film, including Rishab Shetty, Prashanth Neel, and Ram Gopal Varma.</p><blockquote>Ram Gopal Varma stated: “WELCOME to the MAD MAD world of the MADDEST actor and even more MADDER Film maker in INDIA @nimmaupendra #UITheMovie…”</blockquote><p>With a strong following and the return of Upendra as a director, 'UI The Movie' is anticipated to make a significant impact in cinemas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/kannada/makers-of-real-star-upendra-s-ui-the-movie-shares-a-special-request-for-theatre-audiences-article-116480638</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/kannada/makers-of-real-star-upendra-s-ui-the-movie-shares-a-special-request-for-theatre-audiences-article-116480638</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Billie Eilish 'needs help' as paranoia grows from past threats and harassment: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/billie-eilish-needs-help-as-paranoia-grows-from-past-threats-and-harassment-report-101734628433672.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/billie-eilish-needs-help-as-paranoia-grows-from-past-threats-and-harassment-report-101734628433672.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:30:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hrithik Roshan's Special Birthday Message For Ex-Wife Sussanne Khan's Boyfriend Arslan Goes Viral - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxPSGVlRkZtM0RnRHZGaUxjQ0tuSnNTTHhxVzVjWXVsZVloUDlIQ0Z6aWZ5dlNGSk5Kc3g4UURRVXMwNzI0MllaRHVvX1gzbVBEU3ZfbzZMZnNWa25BaFpoaTBWR1FpSkFSQ1g0WXUwWnJQNDdUajFhaUozWWp1UHZmOG5EMkNOQzFjUUVzeDJEb2Zoby1zMW1MZzlwa3F2M3FGVFpVWks1ZHJ0bjNWdGxpYlR3UXFjQ3U1VGQ0U0NOekc0U0RVU21qQW9pajlBd2YtWThmbg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxPSGVlRkZtM0RnRHZGaUxjQ0tuSnNTTHhxVzVjWXVsZVloUDlIQ0Z6aWZ5dlNGSk5Kc3g4UURRVXMwNzI0MllaRHVvX1gzbVBEU3ZfbzZMZnNWa25BaFpoaTBWR1FpSkFSQ1g0WXUwWnJQNDdUajFhaUozWWp1UHZmOG5EMkNOQzFjUUVzeDJEb2Zoby1zMW1MZzlwa3F2M3FGVFpVWks1ZHJ0bjNWdGxpYlR3UXFjQ3U1VGQ0U0NOekc0U0RVU21qQW9pajlBd2YtWThmbg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:27:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ram Gopal Varma urges all stars to protest against Allu Arjun's arrest: '3 people died in the crowd to se - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ram Gopal Varma urges all stars to protest against Allu Arjun's arrest: '3 people died in the crowd to see Sridevi, will police go to heaven to arrest her?'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>Filmmaker Ram Gopal Varma has called for a protest from film stars against the arrest of actor Allu Arjun, emphasizing the absurdity of the situation by referencing past tragedies involving fans.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Varma highlights the emotional connection fans have with stars.</li>
  <li>He questions the police's motives in arresting public figures.</li>
  <li>Varma refers to past incidents where fans have died due to overwhelming situations at events.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“3 people died in the crowd to see Sridevi, will police go to heaven to arrest her?”</blockquote>
<p>Ram Gopal Varma's statement has sparked debate on the treatment of celebrities and the actions of law enforcement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/telugu/movies/news/ram-gopal-varma-urges-all-stars-to-protest-against-allu-arjuns-arrest-3-people-died-in-the-crowd-to-see-sridevi-will-police-go-to-heaven-to-arrest-her/articleshow/116479894.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/telugu/movies/news/ram-gopal-varma-urges-all-stars-to-protest-against-allu-arjuns-arrest-3-people-died-in-the-crowd-to-see-sridevi-will-police-go-to-heaven-to-arrest-her/articleshow/116479894.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[pHOTo Gallery: Poonam Flaunts Her Thighs.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Poonam Bajwa Flaunts Her Thighs in Stunning Photos</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/pooja_t11734627662.jpeg" alt="pHOTo Gallery: Poonam Flaunts Her Thighs"><figcaption>Poonam Bajwa showcasing her elegance and charm.</figcaption><p>Formerly a celebrated actress, Poonam Bajwa captivates fans with her stunning social media photographs that highlight her beauty and confidence.</p><ul><li>Poonam shares a mix of professional and candid photos on her social media.</li><li>Her latest images showcase her in swimwear, emphasizing her toned thighs.</li><li>The actress embraces her fuller curves with poise and confidence.</li><li>Despite not being a prominent figure in films, her social media presence keeps her in the spotlight.</li></ul><blockquote>Poonam exudes an irresistible confidence and charm, often matching the appeal of today's top actresses.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Poonam Bajwa remains a beloved personality through her engaging online presence and stunning visuals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/photo-gallery-poonam-flaunts-her-thighs-142867</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/photo-gallery-poonam-flaunts-her-thighs-142867</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:01:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leaked Beast Games entry rules reveal $500K penalty for contestants who disclose info - Dexerto]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Leaked Rules for MrBeast's Beast Games Impose $500K Penalty for Contestants</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 19, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Dexerto</p>
<img src="https://www.dexerto.com/cdn-image/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/11/MrBeast-Beast-Games-budget-1024x576.jpg?width=1200&amp;quality=75&amp;format=auto" alt="MrBeast surrounded by money" loading="lazy" />
<figcaption>YouTube: MrBeast, Beast Games has a massive $100M budget.</figcaption>
<p>Leaked documents reveal that contestants of MrBeast’s new show, Beast Games, may face hefty fines of $500,000 for disclosing information about the competition, which premieres on Amazon Prime.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Contestants are prohibited from sharing information until the final episode airs on February 13, 2025.</li>
  <li>Violating this confidentiality can result in fines, payable to the producers and network.</li>
  <li>The fines are outlined in a contestant agreement which has been deemed extreme by legal experts.</li>
  <li>Over 2,000 participants are involved in preliminary rounds, contributing to the production of the show.</li>
  <li>MrBeast claims the show has an extravagant $100 million budget, including significant expenses for set construction.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The producers use every available tool to give them ultimate flexibility to make the show and protect themselves from liability,” - Daniel J. Ain, Entertainment Lawyer.</blockquote>
<p>The imposition of such hefty penalties raises questions about contestant treatment and the lengths producers will go to safeguard their projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dexerto.com/youtube/leaked-beast-games-entry-rules-reveal-500k-penalty-for-contestants-who-disclose-info-3012485/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dexerto.com/youtube/leaked-beast-games-entry-rules-reveal-500k-penalty-for-contestants-who-disclose-info-3012485/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:57:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>