<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 20:18:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 20:18:33 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Radhika Merchant Ditches The Gown And Opts For A Pink Nightsuit For Ambani's Jamnagar Christmas Celebration - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Radhika Merchant Ditches The Gown And Opts For A Pink Nightsuit For Ambani's Jamnagar Christmas Celebration</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Radhika Merchant's pink night suit was adorned with candy cane prints.">
<figcaption>Radhika Merchant's pink night suit was adorned with candy cane prints.</figcaption>
<p>Radhika Merchant was spotted in a cozy pink nightsuit during the Ambani family's Christmas celebration in Jamnagar, marking her first Christmas with the family.</p>
<ul>
<li>The celebration was a casual pajama party theme rather than a formal affair.</li>
<li>Guests included celebrities like Janhvi Kapoor, Orry, and Shanaya Kapoor.</li>
<li>Radhika's night suit featured a candy cane print and was made of soft satin fabric.</li>
<li>The outfit is from Pretty Little Thing and retails for approximately Rs 5,400.</li>
<li>She accessorized with quirky earrings and a luxe wristwatch to elevate her look.</li>
<li>Radhika married Anant Ambani earlier in July 2024.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Radhika elevated her comfy look with stylish accessories and natural makeup.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, Radhika showcased a blend of comfort and style in her casual yet chic outfit for the festive occasion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/radhika-merchant-ditches-the-gown-and-opts-for-a-pink-nightsuit-for-ambanis-jamnagar-christmas-celebrations-9170813.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/radhika-merchant-ditches-the-gown-and-opts-for-a-pink-nightsuit-for-ambanis-jamnagar-christmas-celebrations-9170813.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 19:10:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Home Cooked Meals And A Cheat Day: Here's What Shilpa Shetty's Diet Looks Like - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shilpa Shetty's Diet: Emphasizing Home Cooked Meals and Cheat Days</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The actor said that she does not eat steamed or boiled food."/><figcaption>The actor said that she does not eat steamed or boiled food.</figcaption><p>Shilpa Shetty, a well-known figure in Bollywood, shares her approach to diet, emphasizing home-cooked meals and an enjoyable, balanced approach to eating.</p><ul><li>She prefers simple, hearty meals and avoids restrictive diets.</li><li>Cheat days are included for indulging in favorites like desserts.</li><li>Breakfast includes aloe vera juice, porridge, and tea with brown sugar.</li><li>Lunch typically consists of brown rice or chapatti, dal, chicken curry, and vegetables.</li><li>Dinner includes a light meal of salad, soup, and chicken dish.</li><li>Maintains fitness through yoga and weight training.</li></ul><blockquote>“My day starts with aloe vera juice. It is great for your immune system; it’s great for your skin.” - Shilpa Shetty</blockquote><p>Shilpa Shetty emphasizes the importance of home-cooked meals while incorporating a healthy lifestyle with her enjoyable eating habits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-home-cooked-meals-and-a-cheat-day-heres-what-shilpa-shettys-diet-looks-like-9170928.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-home-cooked-meals-and-a-cheat-day-heres-what-shilpa-shettys-diet-looks-like-9170928.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:50:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby John box office collection day 4: Varun Dhawan film fails to gain momentum on Saturday, earns just Rs... - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baby John Box Office Collection Day 4: Varun Dhawan Film Fails to Gain Momentum</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 28, 2024 &nbsp;| &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> DNA India</p>
<img src="https://cdn.dnaindia.com/sites/default/files/2024/12/28/2669232-baby-john.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(1200,900)" alt="Baby John box office collection" width="640" height="480">
<figcaption>Baby John box office collection</figcaption>
<p>Baby John, headlined by Varun Dhawan, is struggling at the box office, particularly in its fourth day of release. Despite the film's strong opening, it has failed to maintain momentum amidst stiff competition.</p>
<ul>
<li>The film, released on December 25, garnered Rs 19.65 crore in its first three days in India.</li>
<li>On Saturday, it earned only Rs 3.57 crore, bringing its total to Rs 23.22 crore over four days.</li>
<li>Critics and audiences have delivered mixed to negative reviews for the film, citing predictability and a lack of originality.</li>
<li>Despite notable performances, the film is considered one of the biggest flops of the year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“While a few have hailed Varun's performance, majority of the viewers have criticized the film for its predictability.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, Baby John is facing significant challenges at the box office, competing against the successful releases of Pushpa 2 and Mufasa.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/bollywood/report-baby-john-box-office-collection-day-4-varun-dhawan-film-fails-to-gain-momentum-earns-less-than-pushpa-2-mufasa-max-3124732</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/bollywood/report-baby-john-box-office-collection-day-4-varun-dhawan-film-fails-to-gain-momentum-earns-less-than-pushpa-2-mufasa-max-3124732</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:26:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathi actress Urmila Kothare's car accidentally hits metro workers in Mumbai; one killed - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Marathi actress Urmila Kothare's car accidentally hits metro workers in Mumbai; one killed</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a tragic incident in Mumbai, a car driven by actress Urmila Kothare accidentally struck metro workers, resulting in the death of one individual. The event has raised concerns about road safety and the welfare of construction workers.</p><ul><li>The accident occurred while metro construction work was being conducted in the area.</li><li>One worker was pronounced dead at the scene, leading to an investigation into the circumstances.</li><li>Kothare expressed her condolences and shock regarding the incident.</li><li>The Mumbai police are looking into the accident to establish accountability.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am devastated by this incident and my heart goes out to the family of the deceased.” - Urmila Kothare</blockquote><p>This event has sparked discussions on the safety protocols for workers in construction zones and the obligations of drivers in such scenarios.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/marathi/movies/news/marathi-actress-urmila-kothares-car-accidentally-hits-metro-workers-in-mumbai-one-killed/articleshow/116747115.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/marathi/movies/news/marathi-actress-urmila-kothares-car-accidentally-hits-metro-workers-in-mumbai-one-killed/articleshow/116747115.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viduthalai Part - 2 Box Office Collection Day 9 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxNV2FkRnAwX0FNVWR0ajM0c3BfSU5NMmRCb0lmSWtvSDh0WEUzVjRpRUQ1QzZQd1d0SFVlVHFOSmUxeG9abUlQc29nbUtrMU05Vk5zS19LbWhsV09BUkE3aW1Rc2tqVnZwUjYxMDVjUGxzLTNQSDhQTU1yWE5PZ3JaYThvSjRQNjNqcW5EVFd3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxNV2FkRnAwX0FNVWR0ajM0c3BfSU5NMmRCb0lmSWtvSDh0WEUzVjRpRUQ1QzZQd1d0SFVlVHFOSmUxeG9abUlQc29nbUtrMU05Vk5zS19LbWhsV09BUkE3aW1Rc2tqVnZwUjYxMDVjUGxzLTNQSDhQTU1yWE5PZ3JaYThvSjRQNjNqcW5EVFd3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 23: Record-Breaking Spree Continues As It Beats Uri & Baahubali 2 To Achieve A New Milestone! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 23: Record-Breaking Spree Continues</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided]<strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-vs-uri-vs-baahubali-box-office-01.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 23"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 23 Update! ( Photo Credit – Facebook )</figcaption><p>Allu Arjun led Pushpa 2 continues its rock-solid hold at the Hindi box office. It has entered its fourth week, and the daily collections have gone below the 10 crore mark. The action thriller has achieved yet another milestone in India.</p><ul><li>Day 23 earnings: <strong>7.50 crores</strong></li><li>Overall box office collection now stands at <strong>747.75 crores</strong></li><li>Pushpa 2 is only <strong>2.25 crores</strong> away from the 750 crore mark, the first ever for a Hindi film.</li><li>Achieved the highest day 23 earnings in Hindi cinema history, surpassing Baahubali 2, Uri, and Jawan.</li><li>Return on investment reported at <strong>273.62%</strong></li></ul><blockquote>“The record-breaking spree seems never-ending for Pushpa 2: The Rule.”</blockquote><p>This successful run showcases the film's significant impact on the box office, making history with its earnings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-23-record-breaking-spree-continues-as-it-beats-uri-baahubali-2-to-achieve-a-new-milestone/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-23-record-breaking-spree-continues-as-it-beats-uri-baahubali-2-to-achieve-a-new-milestone/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:25:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Squid Games meets Bigg Boss': Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser drop has an SRK connect and fans can't keep calm - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Salman Khan's Sikandar Teaser Drops</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/Sikandar_teaser_first_reactions_1735397902191_1735397902535.jpg" alt="Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser carries a Squid Game x Bigg Boss vibe, internet concludes(Photos: X)"><figcaption>Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser carries a Squid Game x Bigg Boss vibe, internet concludes(Photos: X)</figcaption><p>The official teaser for Salman Khan's upcoming film <i>Sikandar</i> has finally been released, generating excitement among fans. The teaser showcases Khan in an action-packed montage, reminiscent of popular shows like 'Squid Game' and 'Bigg Boss'.</p><ul><li>Teaser release followed an unexpected delay due to the demise of former PM Manmohan Singh.</li><li>Fans celebrated the teaser as a comeback for Salman Khan after his recent underwhelming performances.</li><li>The teaser hints at stunning visuals, with VFX handled by Shah Rukh Khan's Red Chillies Entertainment.</li><li>Film directed by AR Murugadoss, produced by Sajid Nadiadwala, featuring Rashmika Mandanna and Kajal Aggarwal.</li><li><i>Sikandar</i> is set to release around Eid 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“This looks really good, finally something worth Salman's stardom.”</blockquote><p>With the buzz generated by the teaser, there is great anticipation for <i>Sikandar</i>, and fans are eager to see Salman Khan back in his element.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/salman-khans-sikandar-teaser-has-a-shah-rukh-khan-connect-internet-detects-squid-game-x-bigg-boss-vibe-101735397614019.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/salman-khans-sikandar-teaser-has-a-shah-rukh-khan-connect-internet-detects-squid-game-x-bigg-boss-vibe-101735397614019.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:10:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Salman Khan enjoys birthday in Vantara; Sohail Khan, Deanne Panday share glimpses of celebration - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Salman Khan enjoys birthday in Vantara; Sohail Khan, Deanne Panday share glimpses of celebration</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: December 28, 2024</strong></p>
<p><strong>Source: Bollywood Hungama</strong></p>
<img src="https://stat5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Salman-Khan-celebrates-birthday-in-Vantara-620.jpg" alt="Salman Khan celebrates birthday in Vantara; Warda Nadiadwala shares glimpses of fireworks at the bash" width="620" height="450">
<figcaption>Salman Khan celebrates birthday in Vantara; Warda Nadiadwala shares glimpses of fireworks at the bash</figcaption>
<p>Salman Khan celebrated his birthday with family and friends at Vantara, an Ambani property, with vibrant festivities shared on social media.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Salman Khan arrived at Jamnagar airport with family members including his father, mother, and siblings.</li>
  <li>Friends Sohail Khan and Deanne Panday shared glimpses of the celebration online.</li>
  <li>The venue featured a large LED setup that read '<3 You Bhaijaan'.</li>
  <li>Fireworks displayed at the venue alongside popular songs played.</li>
  <li>Salman posed with Anant Ambani, showcasing their close friendship.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Latest, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SalmanKhan?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SalmanKhan</a> w/ Anant Ambani ???? <a href="https://t.co/bN8NBWFdtr">pic.twitter.com/bN8NBWFdtr</a></blockquote>
<p>Additionally, they celebrated the birthday of Ayaat Sharma, daughter of Arpita and Aayush Sharma.</p>
<p>Salman is preparing for his upcoming film <em>Sikandar</em>, set to release during Eid next year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/salman-khan-enjoys-birthday-vantara-deanne-panday-sohail-khan-share-glimpses-celebration/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/salman-khan-enjoys-birthday-vantara-deanne-panday-sohail-khan-share-glimpses-celebration/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:49:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shark Tank’s Aman Gupta tells all about ‘extremely egotistic’ movie star who projects himself as ‘humble’ in the public: ‘Our brand ambassador’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aman Gupta Reveals the Truth Behind a 'Humble' Movie Star</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Aman-Gupta.jpg?w=640" alt="Aman Gupta Shark Tank" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Aman Gupta says an actor, mostly shown as humble, is extremely arrogant. (Photo: Aman Gupta/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Aman Gupta, co-founder of Boat and Shark Tank India judge, recently criticized a movie star known for his humble persona, calling him 'extremely egotistic'. Gupta made these remarks during a podcast interview while promoting the new season of Shark Tank India.</p><ul><li>Gupta shared his experience working with an actor portrayed positively in the media as sweet and kind.</li><li>He highlighted the disparity between the actor's public image and his actual behavior during their collaboration.</li><li>He expressed his belief that people will eventually recognize the difference between genuine and pretentious personalities.</li><li>The article also recalls former Shark Ashneer Grover's experiences with Salman Khan, emphasizing the challenges in obtaining celebrity endorsements.</li></ul><blockquote>“Indians are pretty smart. One day or the other, they will get to know the reality.” - Aman Gupta</blockquote><p>Gupta's comments shed light on the contrast between celebrity image and reality, suggesting that public perceptions can often be misleading.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/shark-tank-aman-gupta-tells-all-about-extremely-egoistic-movie-star-who-projects-himself-as-humble-9749003/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/shark-tank-aman-gupta-tells-all-about-extremely-egoistic-movie-star-who-projects-himself-as-humble-9749003/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:19:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathi actor Urmila Kothare’s car runs over 2 workers in Kandivali; 1 killed - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Marathi actor Urmila Kothare’s car runs over 2 workers in Kandivali; 1 killed</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Early Saturday morning</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/car_a23d26.jpg?w=640" alt="car" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>A case was registered against Kothare’s driver at the Samta Nagar police station.</figcaption><p>In a tragic incident, Marathi actor Urmila Kothare’s vehicle struck two labourers working at a Metro construction site, resulting in one fatality and one injury.</p><ul><li>The accident occurred around 12:45 AM near Poisar Metro station in Kandivali.</li><li>Kothare was reportedly heading home after dropping off a friend in Jogeshwari.</li><li>The driver has been booked for rash and negligent driving.</li><li>One labourer died at the scene, while the other was injured and is receiving treatment.</li><li>Both Kothare and her driver also sustained injuries.</li></ul><blockquote>“She had just wrapped up her shooting and was returning home when the incident took place,” a police officer said.</blockquote><p>This incident raises concerns about road safety and the responsibilities of drivers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/marathi-actor-urmila-kothares-car-runs-over-2-workers-kandivali-killed-9748997/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/marathi-actor-urmila-kothares-car-runs-over-2-workers-kandivali-killed-9748997/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winners Of The 2024 APAN Star Awards - Jazmine Media ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNemozUW1aQVlxZUp5V0R5TWFvaHE1aUNfbHBKaXNLa0FpdWZRRkc0MUF5QmVwZ0xzYWphZDUyY3hweWQtZDlCRXBDOE85clZQZnV5LThOaW1iZ3ZCUjVXbXJNdWxLSzl6TEpKNXcwNkJQLVYzbExDaFJkRTF4VHFwSDdFR0Q?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNemozUW1aQVlxZUp5V0R5TWFvaHE1aUNfbHBKaXNLa0FpdWZRRkc0MUF5QmVwZ0xzYWphZDUyY3hweWQtZDlCRXBDOE85clZQZnV5LThOaW1iZ3ZCUjVXbXJNdWxLSzl6TEpKNXcwNkJQLVYzbExDaFJkRTF4VHFwSDdFR0Q?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:57:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Career Horoscope 2025: Predictions and Forecast for All Zodiac Signs - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/astrology/horoscope/yearly/career-horoscope-2025-predictions-and-forecast-for-all-zodiac-signs/articleshow/116707356.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/astrology/horoscope/yearly/career-horoscope-2025-predictions-and-forecast-for-all-zodiac-signs/articleshow/116707356.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Keerthy Suresh Shocked As Paparazzi Call Her 'Dosa', Baby John Actress Says 'Aur Dosa Mujhe...' | Watch - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Keerthy Suresh Reacts to Paparazzi Calling Her 'Dosa'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Keerthy Suresh is a popular name in the Tamil and Telugu film industries. (Photo Credit: Instagram)"><figcaption>Keerthy Suresh is a popular name in the Tamil and Telugu film industries. (Photo Credit: Instagram)</figcaption><p>Keerthy Suresh, who recently made her Bollywood debut with 'Baby John', was caught off guard when paparazzi referred to her as 'Dosa', leading to an amusing interaction.</p><ul><li>Keerthy Suresh posed for paparazzi in Mumbai.</li><li>Paparazzi mistakenly called her 'Kriti', which she corrected to 'Keerthy'.</li><li>One photographer humorously called her 'Dosa', which annoyed her.</li><li>Keerthy responded, stating she's not 'Keerthy dosa' but 'Keerthy Suresh' and humorously added that she does like dosa.</li><li>Despite mixed reviews for 'Baby John', Keerthy's performance has been praised.</li><li>Keerthy Suresh married her long-time partner Antony on December 12, 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>“Keerthy Suresh’s Bollywood debut as Meera is another highlight of the film. Her nuanced dialogue delivery and expressive acting make her a scene-stealer.”</blockquote><p>In light of the amusing encounter, Keerthy's charm continues to resonate with her audience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/keerthy-suresh-shocked-as-paparazzi-call-her-dosa-baby-john-actress-says-aur-dosa-mujhe-watch-9170833.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/keerthy-suresh-shocked-as-paparazzi-call-her-dosa-baby-john-actress-says-aur-dosa-mujhe-watch-9170833.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:28:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby John vs Pushpa 2 vs Mufasa Box Office Occupancy: Surprise Entry At #1 With 84% Higher Admits & No, It’s Not Allu Arjun’s Film! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baby John vs Pushpa 2 vs Mufasa Box Office Occupancy: Surprise Entry At #1 With 84% Higher Admits & No, I</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p>
<img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/baby-john-vs-pushpa-2-vs-mufasa-box-office-01.jpg" alt="Baby John Vs Pushpa 2 Vs Mufasa Box Office Occupancy!" width="1200" height="630">
<figcaption>Baby John Vs Pushpa 2 Vs Mufasa Box Office Morning & Afternoon Occupancy! ( Photo Credit – Instagram )</figcaption>
<p>The holiday season witnesses a fierce competition at the Indian box office as Mufasa: The Lion King emerges as a strong contender against established blockbusters like Pushpa 2 and Baby John.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Pushpa 2:</strong> On its 24th day, it shows a morning occupancy of 10.24% and an afternoon occupancy of 26.24%.</li>
  <li><strong>Baby John:</strong> On its 4th day, it has a morning occupancy of 7.14% and an afternoon occupancy of 15.38%.</li>
  <li><strong>Mufasa: The Lion King:</strong> On its 9th day, it records a morning occupancy of 12.47% and an afternoon occupancy of 28.29%.</li>
  <li>Mufasa surpasses Pushpa 2 in the occupancy race, completing an impressive 84% lead over Baby John in afternoon shows.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Compared to Baby John, Mufasa has clocked 74% higher occupancy during the morning show, which even improved to 84% during the afternoon shows.”</blockquote>
<p>This battle highlights the shifting dynamics at the box office, where audience preferences can rapidly change during the holiday season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/baby-john-vs-pushpa-2-vs-mufasa-box-office-occupancy-surprise-entry-at-1-with-84-higher-admits-no-its-not-allu-arjuns-film/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/baby-john-vs-pushpa-2-vs-mufasa-box-office-occupancy-surprise-entry-at-1-with-84-higher-admits-no-its-not-allu-arjuns-film/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:11:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daaku Maharaaj : Fans want more content from the Balakrishna film - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daaku Maharaaj: Fans Want More Content from the Balakrishna Film</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 5:04 pm IST</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Daaku-maharaaj-2.jpg" alt="Daaku Maharaaj" width="450" height="338"><figcaption>Daaku Maharaaj Promotional Image</figcaption><p>Daaku Maharaaj is scheduled for release on January 12, 2025. While promotions are underway, fans are urging for more content and details.</p><ul><li>Balakrishna's film generates anticipation among fans.</li><li>Producers and directors are conducting press interviews.</li><li>Fans seek additional songs and cast details amidst competitive releases for Sankranthi.</li><li>High-budget action drama with music composed by Thaman.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/daaku-maharaaj-fans-want-more-content-from-the-balakrishna-film.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/daaku-maharaaj-fans-want-more-content-from-the-balakrishna-film.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathi Actress Urmila Kothare's Vehicle Runs Over Labourers In Mumbai, 1 Killed - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/mumbai-labourer-killed-marathi-actress-urmila-kothare-car-runs-over-workers-kandivali-latest-news-9171140.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/mumbai-labourer-killed-marathi-actress-urmila-kothare-car-runs-over-workers-kandivali-latest-news-9171140.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:33:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Urmila Kothare Accident: Marathi actress' car hits two metro workers in Mumbai - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Urmila Kothare Accident: Marathi actress' car hits two metro workers in Mumbai, one dead</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/urmila-kothare-1735383771.webp" alt="Urmila Kothare" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Urmila Kothare</figcaption><p>Marathi actress Urmila Kothare was involved in a car accident in Mumbai that resulted in the death of one metro worker and injury to another. The incident occurred while she was returning from a shoot.</p><ul><li>The accident took place in the Kandivali area of Mumbai last Friday.</li><li>Kothare was in the back seat of the car, with the driver at the wheel, who was confirmed not to be under the influence of alcohol.</li><li>The airbag deployed correctly, keeping both Kothare and the driver unharmed.</li><li>A case has been registered against the driver at Samta Nagar Police Station.</li></ul><blockquote>“The police team is investigating this entire matter.”</blockquote><p>Kothare is a well-known figure in Marathi cinema, recognized for her roles in various films and TV shows.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/entertainment/news/urmila-kothare-accident-marathi-actress-car-hits-two-metro-workers-in-mumbai-2024-12-28-968354</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/entertainment/news/urmila-kothare-accident-marathi-actress-car-hits-two-metro-workers-in-mumbai-2024-12-28-968354</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:04:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘It was horrible to work with Bipasha Basu and Karan Singh Grover, they demanded separate rooms’: Mika recalls producing web series - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mika Singh Reflects on Challenging Experience with Bipasha Basu and Karan Singh Grover During Production</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Mika-Singh.jpg?w=640" alt="Mika Singh on Bipasha Basu" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Mika Singh says working with Bipasha Basu and Karan Singh Grover was a mistake. (Photo: Mika Singh/Bipasha Basu/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Mika Singh recounts his dire experience while producing the web series 'Dangerous', revealing challenges he faced working with actors Bipasha Basu and Karan Singh Grover.</p><ul><li>Despite intentions to keep the project budget-friendly, Basu's insistence on joining Grover led to significant complications during shooting.</li><li>The project that was meant to take three months extended to six months, incurring heavy costs for Singh.</li><li>Issues included demands for separate accommodations and resistance to performing a previously agreed upon kissing scene.</li><li>Singh ultimately decided to cease producing films due to this problematic experience.</li><li>Both Salman Khan and Akshay Kumar advised Singh against pursuing production, predicting financial loss.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was the most horrible experience of my career.” - Mika Singh</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Mika Singh's foray into film production serves as a cautionary tale about the unpredictability and potential turmoil of collaborating with established actors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/horrible-to-work-with-bipasha-basu-karan-singh-grover-they-demanded-for-separate-rooms-despite-being-married-mika-singh-9748775/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/horrible-to-work-with-bipasha-basu-karan-singh-grover-they-demanded-for-separate-rooms-despite-being-married-mika-singh-9748775/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘It was horrible to work with Bipasha Basu and Karan Singh Grover, they demanded for separate rooms’: Mika recalls producing web series - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mika Singh Reflects on Challenging Experience with Bipasha Basu and Karan Singh Grover During Production</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Mika-Singh.jpg?w=640" alt="Mika Singh on Bipasha Basu" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Mika Singh says working with Bipasha Basu and Karan Singh Grover was a mistake. (Photo: Mika Singh/Bipasha Basu/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Mika Singh recounts his dire experience while producing the web series 'Dangerous', revealing challenges he faced working with actors Bipasha Basu and Karan Singh Grover.</p><ul><li>Despite intentions to keep the project budget-friendly, Basu's insistence on joining Grover led to significant complications during shooting.</li><li>The project that was meant to take three months extended to six months, incurring heavy costs for Singh.</li><li>Issues included demands for separate accommodations and resistance to performing a previously agreed upon kissing scene.</li><li>Singh ultimately decided to cease producing films due to this problematic experience.</li><li>Both Salman Khan and Akshay Kumar advised Singh against pursuing production, predicting financial loss.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was the most horrible experience of my career.” - Mika Singh</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Mika Singh's foray into film production serves as a cautionary tale about the unpredictability and potential turmoil of collaborating with established actors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/horrible-to-work-with-bipasha-basu-karan-singh-grover-they-demanded-for-separate-rooms-despite-being-married-mika-singh-9748775/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/horrible-to-work-with-bipasha-basu-karan-singh-grover-they-demanded-for-separate-rooms-despite-being-married-mika-singh-9748775/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sikandar teaser: Salman Khan annihilates army of samurais with shotguns, fans say 'mass ka baap is here'. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sikandar teaser: Salman Khan annihilates army of samurais with shotguns</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/Sikandar_teaser_1735382686525_1735382686898.png" alt="Sikandar teaser: Salman Khan plays the titular character in the film." title="Sikandar teaser: Salman Khan plays the titular character in the film."><figcaption>Sikandar teaser: Salman Khan plays the titular character in the film.</figcaption><p>The teaser for director AR Murugadoss’ film Sikandar featuring Salman Khan and Rashmika Mandanna has been released, showcasing intense action sequences and a thrilling glimpse of the movie.</p><ul><li>The teaser was released a day late due to the death of former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh.</li><li>The 1-minute-41-second video highlights Salman’s character entering a trap filled with armed samurais.</li><li>Fans expressed excitement, with many praising the massy avatar Salman is portraying.</li><li>Sikandar is set to release in theatres on Eid 2025.</li><li>The film is produced by Sajid Nadiadwala under Nadiadwala Grandson Entertainment.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ab intezaar hua khatam. Here’s presenting a glimpse of the world of Sikandar.” - Film’s producers</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the teaser has generated significant buzz among fans, marking a strong follow-up to Salman Khan’s previous works and setting high expectations for its release.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/sikandar-teaser-salman-khan-annihilates-army-of-samurais-with-shotguns-fans-say-mass-ka-baap-is-here-watch-101735377456678.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/sikandar-teaser-salman-khan-annihilates-army-of-samurais-with-shotguns-fans-say-mass-ka-baap-is-here-watch-101735377456678.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:45:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Actor Urmila Kothare's car runs over labourers in Mumbai, 1 killed - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Actor Urmila Kothare's Car Runs Over Labourers in Mumbai, 1 Killed</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong> Dec 28, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/Urmila_Kothare_Mumbai_car_accident_1735387489828_1735387490186.jpg" alt="Actor Urmila Kothare was also injured in the accident." title="Actor Urmila Kothare was also injured in the accident."><figcaption>Actor Urmila Kothare was also injured in the accident.</figcaption></figure><p>In a tragic incident in Kandivali, Mumbai, actress Urmila Kothare's car lost control and hit two Metro workers, resulting in one death and another serious injury.</p><ul><li>The accident occurred while Kothare was returning from work near Poisar Metro station.</li><li>One labourer died on the spot, while the other sustained severe injuries.</li><li>Both the actress and her driver suffered minor injuries due to airbags deploying.</li><li>The police have filed a case against the driver and initiated an investigation.</li></ul><blockquote>“Urmila Kothare's car hit two labourers who were engaged in Metro rail work under the Poisar Metro station…” - Police Official</blockquote><p>The incident has raised concerns about road safety, particularly following other recent accidents in Mumbai. An investigation is underway to determine the cause.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/labourer-killed-actor-urmila-kothare-injured-in-horrific-accident-in-mumbai-101735382152099.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/labourer-killed-actor-urmila-kothare-injured-in-horrific-accident-in-mumbai-101735382152099.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:44:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sikandar teaser OUT! Salman Khan battles samurais in this grand, massy entertainer co-starring Rashmika M - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sikandar teaser OUT! Salman Khan battles samurais in this grand, massy entertainer co-starring Rashmika Mandanna: video inside</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116705940,imgsize-35810,width-400,resizemode-4/116705940.jpg" alt="Sikandar teaser OUT!" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Sikandar teaser poster featuring Salman Khan.</figcaption><p>The teaser for the much-anticipated film 'Sikandar' has been released after a brief delay due to notable events. Salman Khan is seen in action, battling futuristic goons.</p><ul><li>The teaser was initially set to release on Salman Khan's birthday, December 27, but was postponed.</li><li>Salman Khan's character is showcased fighting samurais and futuristic enemies.</li><li>The film features Rashmika Mandanna alongside Salman Khan.</li><li>Fans have expressed great excitement and positive reactions towards the teaser.</li></ul><blockquote>A fan stated, "Sikandar will create a havoc at Box Office 🔥It's a very emotional moment for every Salman Khan Die Heart Fan to see him directed by talented South Directors..."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the release of the 'Sikandar' teaser has stirred enthusiasm among fans, setting high expectations ahead of its release.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sikandar-teaser-salman-khan-is-set-to-woo-fans-with-a-grand-massy-entertainer-co-starring-rashmika-mandanna/articleshow/116705881.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sikandar-teaser-salman-khan-is-set-to-woo-fans-with-a-grand-massy-entertainer-co-starring-rashmika-mandanna/articleshow/116705881.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sikandar teaser OUT! Salman Khan is set to woo fans with a grand, massy entertainer co-starring Rashmika - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sikandar teaser OUT! Salman Khan battles samurais in this grand, massy entertainer co-starring Rashmika Mandanna: video inside</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116705940,imgsize-35810,width-400,resizemode-4/116705940.jpg" alt="Sikandar teaser OUT!" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Sikandar teaser poster featuring Salman Khan.</figcaption><p>The teaser for the much-anticipated film 'Sikandar' has been released after a brief delay due to notable events. Salman Khan is seen in action, battling futuristic goons.</p><ul><li>The teaser was initially set to release on Salman Khan's birthday, December 27, but was postponed.</li><li>Salman Khan's character is showcased fighting samurais and futuristic enemies.</li><li>The film features Rashmika Mandanna alongside Salman Khan.</li><li>Fans have expressed great excitement and positive reactions towards the teaser.</li></ul><blockquote>A fan stated, "Sikandar will create a havoc at Box Office 🔥It's a very emotional moment for every Salman Khan Die Heart Fan to see him directed by talented South Directors..."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the release of the 'Sikandar' teaser has stirred enthusiasm among fans, setting high expectations ahead of its release.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sikandar-teaser-salman-khan-is-set-to-woo-fans-with-a-grand-massy-entertainer-co-starring-rashmika-mandanna/articleshow/116705881.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sikandar-teaser-salman-khan-is-set-to-woo-fans-with-a-grand-massy-entertainer-co-starring-rashmika-mandanna/articleshow/116705881.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naga Vamsi gives juicy updates on Allu Arjun-Trivikram film - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Naga Vamsi gives juicy updates on Allu Arjun-Trivikram film</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 28, 2024 4:00 pm IST</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/AlluArjun-Trivikram.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333"><figcaption>Image related to Allu Arjun and Trivikram's movie updates</figcaption><p>Producer Naga Vamsi has shared details about his upcoming project with Allu Arjun and director Trivikram Srinivas, revealing plans to build a dedicated studio for filming.</p><ul><li>The film will have a significant VFX component.</li><li>Shooting is expected to start after summer 2025.</li><li>This will be Trivikram's first pan-India project, with the script nearly complete.</li></ul><blockquote>Naga Vamsi mentioned, "We are heavily investing in VFX for this project."</blockquote><p>Overall, the collaboration between these prominent figures in the Telugu film industry generates excitement for this unique project.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/naga-vamsi-gives-juicy-updates-on-allu-arjun-trivikram-film.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/naga-vamsi-gives-juicy-updates-on-allu-arjun-trivikram-film.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Due to poor collections, shows of Baby John replaced with Hindi version of Marco; Industry SHOCKED as PVR Inox Pictures manages to release Varun Dhawan-starrer in just 4 out of 275 single screens in CP Berar - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baby John Faces Poor Box Office Performance; Shows Replaced by Hindi Version of Marco</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p><p><img src="https://media5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Baby-John-replaced-.jpg" alt="Due to poor collections, shows of Baby John replaced with Hindi version of Marco; Industry SHOCKED as PVR Inox Pictures manages to release Varun Dhawan-starrer in just 4 out of 275 single screens in CP Berar"><figcaption>Due to poor collections, shows of Baby John replaced with Hindi version of Marco; Industry SHOCKED as PVR Inox Pictures manages to release Varun Dhawan-starrer in just 4 out of 275 single screens in CP Berar</figcaption></p><p>The film <em>Baby John</em>, starring Varun Dhawan, has had a disappointing start at the box office with collections dropping dramatically. As a result, many theaters have begun replacing its shows with the Hindi version of <em>Marco</em>.</p><ul><li>Opening day collection: Rs. 11.25 crores.</li><li>Second day drop to Rs. 5.13 crores.</li><li>Predicted weekend collection could be under Rs. 30 crores.</li><li>The film's shows are being replaced by <em>Marco</em>, <em>Pushpa 2</em>, and <em>Mufasa: The Lion King</em>.</li><li>Only 4 out of 275 single-screen theaters in CP Berar are showing <em>Baby John</em>.</li></ul><blockquote>“On Thursday, the film suffered a huge drop which made it clear for the exhibitors that it won’t even grow on Friday.”</blockquote><p>This situation raises concerns about distribution strategies and the future of films in theatrical releases as audiences clearly show preference for other titles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/due-poor-collections-shows-baby-john-replaced-hindi-version-marco-industry-shocked-pvr-inox-pictures-manages-release-varun-dhawan-starrer-just-4-275-single-screens-c/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/due-poor-collections-shows-baby-john-replaced-hindi-version-marco-industry-shocked-pvr-inox-pictures-manages-release-varun-dhawan-starrer-just-4-275-single-screens-c/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:09:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mufasa: The Lion King Box Office Collection Day 8 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxONWtDa0c2TEZ2N0RfRXRFalhpX2d3SkR6V1ZDRGk5ZXY4ckVpRWxMbkdNRHh4ejRKQ1phYlhXZ1J3MTl6R1VIaXZFT0pGRDNCMHhHYmMzd0NrbEstdmVfSmhiRUhtU2JVenQwb215eUVXemVtUHJWdXppNFlaQVd3eEdFeWhqUy1FZHhmdlV3bDE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxONWtDa0c2TEZ2N0RfRXRFalhpX2d3SkR6V1ZDRGk5ZXY4ckVpRWxMbkdNRHh4ejRKQ1phYlhXZ1J3MTl6R1VIaXZFT0pGRDNCMHhHYmMzd0NrbEstdmVfSmhiRUhtU2JVenQwb215eUVXemVtUHJWdXppNFlaQVd3eEdFeWhqUy1FZHhmdlV3bDE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:02:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin: Rajat moves to Singapore to distance himself from Savi - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rajat Moves to Singapore to Distance Himself from Savi in Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Saturday, December 28, 2024 at 9:59 AM</p><figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/9516-ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-rajat-moves-to-singapore-to-distance-himself-from-savi.jpg" width="640" height="360" alt="Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin: Rajat moves to Singapore to distance himself from Savi" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Hitesh Bhardwaj as Rajat in Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin. Image Courtesy: Star Plus</figcaption></figure><p>In the latest episode of <a href="https://www.indiaforums.com/show/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin_6570" title="Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin">Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin</a>, Rajat intends to take up a business opportunity in Singapore as a way to distance himself from Savi amidst misunderstandings and turmoil in their relationship.</p><ul><li>Rajat accuses Savi of betrayal, believing she is having an affair.</li><li>Rajat plans to sever all personal ties, citing business as the reason for his move.</li><li>Savi senses Rajat's true motives and confronts him about his intentions.</li><li>Rajat transfers his assets to his friend Aman before leaving, implying a drastic decision.</li><li>As the story unfolds, the impact of Arsh's manipulation comes into focus.</li></ul><blockquote>“Will Rajat truly end his relationship with Savi, or will Arsh's manipulation and lies finally come to light?”</blockquote><p>The upcoming twists in the series will reveal whether Rajat's actions will indeed sever his ties with Savi or if the truth about the misunderstandings will emerge in time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-rajat-moves-to-singapore-to-distance-himself-from-savi_216063</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-rajat-moves-to-singapore-to-distance-himself-from-savi_216063</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:00:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bombay Velvet’s Failure Still Haunts Amit Trivedi: 'It Shouldn’t Have Been This Bad' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bombay Velvet’s Failure Still Haunts Amit Trivedi: 'It Shouldn’t Have Been This Bad'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Bombay Velvet was released in 2015." title="Bombay Velvet was released in 2015."><figcaption>Bombay Velvet was released in 2015. (Photo Credits: Instagram)</figcaption></figure><p>In a recent interview, composer Amit Trivedi expressed deep regret over the failure of the film Bombay Velvet, despite putting in four years of hard work on its music.</p><ul><li>The film, directed by Anurag Kashyap, starred Ranbir Kapoor and Anushka Sharma.</li><li>Trivedi shared that the film's massive failure was one of the lowest points of his career.</li><li>He struggled with feelings of hopelessness after the film's release and questioned his direction in life.</li><li>Despite the setback, Trivedi highlighted his efforts to integrate Jazz into Bollywood music through Bombay Velvet.</li></ul><blockquote>“Everything was a disaster. The film came and did not work. So horrible; it shouldn’t have been so bad.”</blockquote><p>Trivedi is celebrated for his work in multiple hit films and has received a National Film Award for Best Music Director.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/bombay-velvets-failure-still-haunts-amit-trivedi-it-shouldnt-have-been-this-bad-aa-9170692.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/bombay-velvets-failure-still-haunts-amit-trivedi-it-shouldnt-have-been-this-bad-aa-9170692.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:53:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UI Box Office Collection Day 8: Upendra’s Film Falls Below 1 Crore On 2nd Friday, To Miss The 50 Crore Milestone In Lifetime Run - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UI Box Office Collection Day 8: Upendra’s Film Falls Below 1 Crore On 2nd Friday, To Miss The 50 Crore Mark</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 8, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><figure><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/ui-box-office-collection-day-8-01.jpg" alt="UI Box Office Collection Day 8" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>UI Box Office Collection Day 8 ( Photo Credit – Instagram )</figcaption></figure><p>The Kannada film industry has struggled with box office successes recently, and Upendra’s film UI is no exception, showing signs of exhaustion after a promising start. Despite receiving praise for its concept, it has failed to engage a broad audience.</p><ul><li>UI had a strong opening day with earnings of <strong>7 crores</strong>.</li><li>It earned a total of <strong>26.50 crores</strong> in its opening week.</li><li>The film's earnings dropped to <strong>0.87 crore</strong> on its second Friday.</li><li>Total box office collection stands at <strong>27.37 crores</strong>.</li><li>UI was made on a budget of over <strong>60 crores</strong>.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“The film is yet to recover 54.38% of the total cost.”</p></blockquote><p>Given the current trajectory, UI is unlikely to reach the 50 crore milestone at the Indian box office.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/ui-box-office-collection-day-8-upendras-film-falls-below-1-crore-on-2nd-friday-to-miss-the-50-crore-milestone-in-lifetime-run/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/ui-box-office-collection-day-8-upendras-film-falls-below-1-crore-on-2nd-friday-to-miss-the-50-crore-milestone-in-lifetime-run/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:38:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alia Bhatt Is "Keeping Her Dips Low" With Her Weekend Gym Workout - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOcW9VVDlMMjB5TDNDZkYzaDl5OFJUbU15eEJiT21lM2FMaXdWcTh5Z3Y3b1NBWjItZGNnd0JMbVRpcUhUVU1rTlRCNGJReDBFeUhibzRtc1FpNXRncUYyZERycEtCSDVkOEota1piRXhib3RNeUZlRHVjS3RwcnBxNEhieldmN09URE1JOGdycEVPQWpJQVFHaUxjVWh2S2xqYUQ1YTJNRzRZQW9hYklyMjYyanRubE02cTYycnBkREtHV3RvWlR3dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOcW9VVDlMMjB5TDNDZkYzaDl5OFJUbU15eEJiT21lM2FMaXdWcTh5Z3Y3b1NBWjItZGNnd0JMbVRpcUhUVU1rTlRCNGJReDBFeUhibzRtc1FpNXRncUYyZERycEtCSDVkOEota1piRXhib3RNeUZlRHVjS3RwcnBxNEhieldmN09URE1JOGdycEVPQWpJQVFHaUxjVWh2S2xqYUQ1YTJNRzRZQW9hYklyMjYyanRubE02cTYycnBkREtHV3RvWlR3dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:35:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>