<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 06:27:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 06:27:23 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Kalki 2898 AD, Jai Hanuman lands in trouble - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/after-kalki-2898-ad-jai-hanuman-lands-in-trouble.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/after-kalki-2898-ad-jai-hanuman-lands-in-trouble.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Kalki 2898 AD, Jai Hanuman lands in trouble - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/after-kalki-2898-ad-jai-hanuman-lands-in-trouble.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/after-kalki-2898-ad-jai-hanuman-lands-in-trouble.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 1: Ram Charan-starrer surpasses Vinaya Vidheya Rama but couldn’t overtake RRR, earns Rs 51.25 cr - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-shankar-overtakes-vinaya-vidheya-rama-earns-rs-51-crore-9772659/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-shankar-overtakes-vinaya-vidheya-rama-earns-rs-51-crore-9772659/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 1: Ram Charan-starrer surpasses Vinaya Vidheya Rama but couldn’t overtake RRR, earns Rs 51.25 cr - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-shankar-overtakes-vinaya-vidheya-rama-earns-rs-51-crore-9772659/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-shankar-overtakes-vinaya-vidheya-rama-earns-rs-51-crore-9772659/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prabhas Getting Married? Trade Analyst Drops BIG Hint, Leaves Fans Excited - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prabhas Getting Married? Trade Analyst Drops BIG Hint, Leaves Fans Excited</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 11, 2025, 14:43 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Netizens are wondering if Prabhas is getting married soon. "><figcaption>Netizens are wondering if Prabhas is getting married soon.</figcaption><p>Looks like Telugu star Prabhas is getting married. Recently, trade analyst Manobala Vijayabalan posted a cryptic tweet hinting at a wedding, prompting speculation among fans.</p><ul><li>Fans are reacting excitedly to the trade analyst's post about Prabhas potentially getting married.</li><li>There is speculation regarding Prabhas's relationship with his Baahubali co-star Anushka Shetty.</li><li>Previous rumors of his marriage were dismissed by Prabhas during an event, where he stated he doesn't want to hurt his female fans.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am not getting married soon because I don’t want to hurt the feelings of my female fans,” - Prabhas</blockquote><p>The rumors surrounding Prabhas's marriage have sparked significant interest and discussion among fans, as they eagerly await any confirmation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/prabhas-getting-married-trade-analyst-drops-big-hint-leaves-fans-excited-9185025.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/prabhas-getting-married-trade-analyst-drops-big-hint-leaves-fans-excited-9185025.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:43:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Game Changer, Daaku Maharaaj faces this obstacle - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After Game Changer, Daaku Maharaaj Faces This Obstacle</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Jan 11, 2025 9:53 am IST</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Game-Changer-DaakuMaharaaj.jpg" alt="Daaku Maharaaj Image" width="500" height="333">
<figcaption>Game Changer and Daaku Maharaaj obstacle faced in premieres.</figcaption>
<p>With the release of Game Changer starring Ram Charan, delays have impacted both Game Changer and the upcoming film Daaku Maharaaj.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Game Changer had several USA premiere shows cancelled due to delays, resulting in a loss of nearly $100K.</li>
  <li>Daaku Maharaaj, starring Balakrishna, is facing similar delivery delays that are affecting premiere shows.</li>
  <li>The ambitious project aims for a 2 million dollar collection, but initial losses are anticipated due to these delays.</li>
  <li>If the film content is well received, it could recover in the long run.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Due to this, the premiere collections will be affected to an extent."</blockquote>
<p>This situation highlights the challenges faced by the Telugu film industry amid logistical issues but also underscores the potential for recovery based on audience reception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/after-game-changer-daaku-maharaaj-faces-this-obstacle.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/after-game-changer-daaku-maharaaj-faces-this-obstacle.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fateh Review: The No-Nonsense, Unabashed And Ultra-Violent Film Is Surprisingly Watchable - NDTV Movies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fateh Review: The No-Nonsense, Unabashed And Ultra-Violent Film Is Surprisingly Watchable</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p>
<p>An ex-special ops agent embarks on a violent rampage to take down cyber criminals behind a fraudulent loan operation. Actor Sonu Sood makes his writing and directing debut with a film that is unapologetically violent and dynamic.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film opens with an intense confrontation where the protagonist, Fateh Singh, takes control by resorting to extreme violence.</li>
  <li>Fateh utilizes a variety of weapons in his mission against a network of cyber criminals, showcasing high body counts reminiscent of other action-packed films.</li>
  <li>The narrative includes a social purpose, focusing on the impact of a scam targeting financially vulnerable individuals.</li>
  <li>Despite the relentless violence, the film offers minimal mystery as the antagonist's identity is revealed early on.</li>
  <li>Sonu Sood's performance resonates with the film's gritty tone, although other characters struggle to stand out in the chaos.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Fateh is marked by dizzying momentum if not sustained clarity.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while <em>Fateh</em> may be overwhelming with its sheer brutality, it remains a captivating watch for those who appreciate action-packed narratives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/fateh-review-the-no-nonsense-unabashed-and-ultra-violent-film-is-surprisingly-watchable-2-5-stars-7447887</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/fateh-review-the-no-nonsense-unabashed-and-ultra-violent-film-is-surprisingly-watchable-2-5-stars-7447887</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:36:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 box office collection Day 37: Allu Arjun starrer begins 6th weekend with Rs 1.15 crore earning - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Collection Day 37: Allu Arjun Starrer Begins 6th Weekend with Rs 1.15 Crore Earning</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [not specified] <strong>Source:</strong> [not specified]</p><p>Pushpa 2 continues to perform strongly at the box office, beginning its 6th weekend with earnings of Rs 1.15 crore.</p><ul><li>After 37 days in theaters, the film shows remarkable box office resilience.</li><li>It maintained a steady audience turnout over the weeks.</li><li>The total earnings have significantly boosted the film's financial success.</li></ul><blockquote>“The film’s success is a testament to Allu Arjun’s popularity and the movie's strong storyline.”</blockquote><p>The continued box office strength of Pushpa 2 demonstrates its lasting appeal and the effectiveness of its marketing strategy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-37-allu-arjun-starrer-begins-6th-weekend-with-rs-1-15-crore-earning/articleshow/117135620.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-37-allu-arjun-starrer-begins-6th-weekend-with-rs-1-15-crore-earning/articleshow/117135620.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karan Johar's leaner look shocks fans as he and Sidharth Malhotra walk the ramp in plunging-neck suits - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karan Johar's leaner look shocks fans as he and Sidharth Malhotra walk the ramp in plunging-neck suits</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/Karan_Johar_Sidharth_Malhotra_1736563066210_1736563076993.jpg" alt="Karan Johar and Sidharth Malhotra walk the ramp at a fashion event." title="Karan Johar and Sidharth Malhotra walk the ramp at a fashion event."><figcaption>Karan Johar and Sidharth Malhotra walk the ramp at a fashion event.</figcaption><p>At a recent fashion show in Mumbai, Karan Johar and Sidharth Malhotra showcased stunning outfits, with Karan's surprising transformation stealing the spotlight.</p><ul><li>Karan Johar walked the ramp in an all-white ensemble, featuring a silk shirt and a matching long coat.</li><li>Sidharth Malhotra was the showstopper in a fitted navy blue suit with a plunging V neckline.</li><li>Karan's leaner appearance drew mixed reactions from fans online.</li></ul><blockquote>“He looks so skinny.”</blockquote><p>Overall, the fashion show combined high-style moments with intriguing celebrity appearances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/fashion/karan-johar-lean-look-shocks-fans-as-he-and-sidharth-malhotra-walk-the-ramp-in-plunging-neck-suits-101736561475592.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/fashion/karan-johar-lean-look-shocks-fans-as-he-and-sidharth-malhotra-walk-the-ramp-in-plunging-neck-suits-101736561475592.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:46:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aamir Khan on why he quit smoking ahead of son Junaid Khan's film release: ‘Maine apne dil mein mannat maangi’. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aamir Khan Quits Smoking Ahead of Son Junaid Khan's Film Release</h1><p><strong>Jan 11, 2025</strong> from <strong>Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/aamir_khan_smoking_1736560836192_1736560965224.jpg" alt="Aamir Khan quits smoking ahead of son Junaid Khan's Loveyapa release." title="Aamir Khan quits smoking ahead of son Junaid Khan's Loveyapa release." /><figcaption>Aamir Khan quits smoking ahead of son Junaid Khan's Loveyapa release.</figcaption><p>Aamir Khan has announced that he has quit smoking after years of heavy consumption. This announcement was made during the trailer launch of his son Junaid Khan's film, Loveyapa, in Mumbai.</p><ul><li>Aamir Khan reveals he has quit smoking.</li><li>He expresses his love for smoking but acknowledges its health risks.</li><li>He encourages others to quit smoking as well.</li><li>He attributes his decision partly to his son’s debut film and his desire to set a good example.</li><li>Junaid Khan's film Loveyapa is set to release on February 7, following his previous debut in a Netflix film.</li></ul><blockquote>“I have given up smoking, smoking is something I love very much... it’s not good for health. No one should do it.”</blockquote><p>The actor’s decision comes as he wishes to support his son in his new career path while also prioritizing his health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aamir-khan-quit-smoking-ahead-of-son-junaid-khan-film-loveyapa-release-watch-101736560435019.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aamir-khan-quit-smoking-ahead-of-son-junaid-khan-film-loveyapa-release-watch-101736560435019.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:26:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer box office collection Day 1: Ram Charan and Kiara Advani starrer makes a splash with Rs 51 c - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Box Office Collection Day 1: Ram Charan and Kiara Advani Starrer Makes a Splash</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>Ram Charan and Kiara Advani's film 'Game Changer' had an impressive start, grossing Rs 51 crore on its opening day, and Rs 7 crore from Hindi audiences.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film received a positive response from audiences and critics alike.</li>
  <li>It marks a significant debut for the lead actors in their respective careers.</li>
  <li>The box office numbers indicate strong word-of-mouth promotion.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"A fantastic start, signaling a strong presence in the upcoming weeks!" - Film Analyst</blockquote>
<p>The film's early success hints at a promising run and potential for record-breaking collections in the following days.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/game-changer-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-and-kiara-advani-starrer-makes-a-splash-with-rs-51-crore-debut-earns-rs-7-crore-in-hindi/articleshow/117134871.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/game-changer-box-office-collection-day-1-ram-charan-and-kiara-advani-starrer-makes-a-splash-with-rs-51-crore-debut-earns-rs-7-crore-in-hindi/articleshow/117134871.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE SmackDown Results – 1/10/25 (United States Championship Matches, Tiffany Stratton) - Wrestleview.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WWE SmackDown Results</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Wrestleview.com</p><figure><img decoding="async" width="207" height="84" src="https://www.wrestleview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/image-3.png" alt=""><figcaption>WWE SmackDown Highlights</figcaption></figure><p>On January 10, 2025, WWE SmackDown featured several high-stakes matches including United States Championship bouts and a significant storyline involving Cody Rhodes, Roman Reigns, and Kevin Owens.</p><ul><li>The night began with Tiffany Stratton, the new WWE Women’s Champion.</li><li>Paul Heyman introduced Roman Reigns, announcing his entry into the 2025 Men’s Royal Rumble.</li><li>Cody Rhodes and Kevin Owens had a tense confrontation, escalating to a physical altercation.</li><li>WWE Women’s United States Championship saw Chelsea Green successfully defend her title against Michin.</li><li>LA Knight faced Shinsuke Nakamura for the United States Championship, resulting in a disqualification victory for Knight, while Nakamura retained his title.</li><li>The Motor City Machine Guns secured a victory against A-Town Down Under.</li></ul><blockquote>A very good start to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SmackDown?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SmackDown</a>. Roman Reigns being in the Royal Rumble for the first time in years, Cody Rhodes and Kevin Owens, Jacob Fatu and Tama Tonga. It's an interesting start.— Wrestleview.com</blockquote><p>The show ended with drama and setup for future high-profile matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wrestleview.com/top-story/338622-wwe-smackdown-results-1-10-25-united-states-championship-matches-tiffany-stratton/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wrestleview.com/top-story/338622-wwe-smackdown-results-1-10-25-united-states-championship-matches-tiffany-stratton/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:39:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fateh box office collection Day 1: Sonu Sood starrer off to a slow start with Rs 2.45 crore debut - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fateh Box Office Collection Day 1: Sonu Sood Starrer Off to a Slow Start with Rs 2.45 Crore Debut</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117134679,imgsize-160030,width-400,resizemode-4/117134679.jpg" alt="Fateh box office collection Day 1: Sonu Sood starrer off to a slow start with Rs 2.45 crore debut" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Fateh box office collection Day 1: Sonu Sood starrer off to a slow start with Rs 2.45 crore debut</figcaption><p>The much-anticipated action film Fateh, featuring Sonu Sood, opened to a subdued box office collection of Rs 2.45 crore on its first day.</p><ul><li>The film revolves around themes of cybercrime, justice, and resilience.</li><li>Initial predictions estimated the film's first-day collection to be between Rs 70 lakh and Rs 1 crore.</li><li>Sood's return as a lead actor was highly anticipated, especially after his philanthropic work during the pandemic.</li><li>Fateh faces tough competition from major releases such as Ram Charan's Game Changer and Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2.</li><li>Industry experts suggest that positive word-of-mouth may improve the film's performance over the weekend.</li><li>Salman Khan showed support for Fateh, connecting it with a song he previously contributed to.</li></ul><blockquote>“I also have a contribution in the film Fateh. The song 'Heer' was very dear to me, but now it is part of this film.” - Salman Khan</blockquote><p>As the weekend progresses, the success of 'Fateh' is dependent on audience response and critical reception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/fateh-box-office-collection-day-1-sonu-sood-starrer-off-to-a-slow-start-with-rs-2-45-crore-debut/articleshow/117134678.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/fateh-box-office-collection-day-1-sonu-sood-starrer-off-to-a-slow-start-with-rs-2-45-crore-debut/articleshow/117134678.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive - Asit Kumarr Modi on Gurucharan Singh quitting the show; says 'It was his personal decision, h - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/exclusive-asit-kumarr-modi-on-gurucharan-singh-quitting-the-show-says-it-was-his-personal-decision-he-is-a-good-person-and-im-emotionally-connected-to-him/articleshow/117134456.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/exclusive-asit-kumarr-modi-on-gurucharan-singh-quitting-the-show-says-it-was-his-personal-decision-he-is-a-good-person-and-im-emotionally-connected-to-him/articleshow/117134456.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive - Asit Kumarr Modi on Gurucharan Singh quitting the show; says 'It was his personal decision, h - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/exclusive-asit-kumarr-modi-on-gurucharan-singh-quitting-the-show-says-it-was-his-personal-decision-he-is-a-good-person-and-im-emotionally-connected-to-him/articleshow/117134456.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/exclusive-asit-kumarr-modi-on-gurucharan-singh-quitting-the-show-says-it-was-his-personal-decision-he-is-a-good-person-and-im-emotionally-connected-to-him/articleshow/117134456.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today LIVE Updates on January 11, 2025 : Pisces Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 predicts successful outcomes at work - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOZHlPSmNYcHpJajNodi1VRjNHUkxxSzEyS0wyY0F3S2FSWGZjd1ZuYmV5SGRGNlg3VDdGNk9qTG9kOExSUFhTdERDR1VqdVVaa3owZmZZd1RVVF9zbGdXXzE1LTZwZHhHZk45b3B5cko1UUMxR25GNXdPZjRKSkV4d2ZsRnhQRjZJak9FWDJyX2VidmM5MDJTVEwybVk0bk5yeVkxbGxrcE8wRWthdERsd3JlbHQycWfSAbwBQVVfeXFMUEhhN0dvTE1ic2ozdGx2NWlVY0VIclhJd0xKU09pRTdBekdQSHBjUGg5R0ZyWDZqMVUycHlNUVYxUGdzYXB0V2k5VDdzbm00WHgwUW1nNFJwQ0liOWk5R2ZVd2tzeFFKWnJwN21DMzdQazdtX250VWlIeV8zV0RIRDFYRUhTSEE1WDBMcUdOX19sWVdKdHA1eWs0RG16NVQ2MmtvWmRHTGVQNVlsbXJKallYWlRGNUItWjkxYnY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOZHlPSmNYcHpJajNodi1VRjNHUkxxSzEyS0wyY0F3S2FSWGZjd1ZuYmV5SGRGNlg3VDdGNk9qTG9kOExSUFhTdERDR1VqdVVaa3owZmZZd1RVVF9zbGdXXzE1LTZwZHhHZk45b3B5cko1UUMxR25GNXdPZjRKSkV4d2ZsRnhQRjZJak9FWDJyX2VidmM5MDJTVEwybVk0bk5yeVkxbGxrcE8wRWthdERsd3JlbHQycWfSAbwBQVVfeXFMUEhhN0dvTE1ic2ozdGx2NWlVY0VIclhJd0xKU09pRTdBekdQSHBjUGg5R0ZyWDZqMVUycHlNUVYxUGdzYXB0V2k5VDdzbm00WHgwUW1nNFJwQ0liOWk5R2ZVd2tzeFFKWnJwN21DMzdQazdtX250VWlIeV8zV0RIRDFYRUhTSEE1WDBMcUdOX19sWVdKdHA1eWs0RG16NVQ2MmtvWmRHTGVQNVlsbXJKallYWlRGNUItWjkxYnY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 22:41:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pisces Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 predicts successful outcomes at work - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pisces Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Pisces_1728478870554_1736529837579.jpg" alt="Pisces Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: Today offers new opportunities for Pisces to grow personally and professionally, fostering meaningful connections and inspiring creative ideas." title="Pisces Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: Today offers new opportunities for Pisces to grow personally and professionally, fostering meaningful connections and inspiring creative ideas."><figcaption>Pisces Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: Today offers new opportunities for Pisces to grow personally and professionally, fostering meaningful connections and inspiring creative ideas.</figcaption></figure><p>Today offers new opportunities for Pisces to grow personally and professionally, fostering meaningful connections and inspiring creative ideas.</p><ul><li>Opportunities for growth and self-discovery in personal and professional spheres.</li><li>Focus on nurturing relationships; great day for expressing feelings.</li><li>Creative inspiration is high, encouraging innovative ideas at work.</li><li>Financial stability with opportunities for wise investments.</li><li>Maintain a balanced lifestyle focusing on health and well-being.</li></ul><blockquote>“Your emotional health is just as important, so ensure you're taking time for activities that bring you joy and relaxation.”</blockquote><p>In summary, today promises a fruitful day for Pisces, emphasizing personal and professional growth alongside relationship enhancement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/pisces-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-predicts-successful-outcomes-at-work-101736529649280.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/pisces-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-predicts-successful-outcomes-at-work-101736529649280.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 22:41:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 predicts unexpected situations - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 to know your astrological predictions</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Aquarius_1728478944944_1736530020845.jpg" alt="Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025" title="Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025"><figcaption>Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: This day brings a refreshing wave of energy, urging Aquarians to harness their strengths and pursue new endeavors.</figcaption><p>Today promises personal growth and new opportunities. Embrace positive changes, maintain open communication, and focus on self-care to navigate any challenges.</p><ul><li>Opportunities for personal growth and embracing positive changes.</li><li>Open communication will benefit relationships.</li><li>Career advancements possible with determination and focus.</li><li>Financial review and budgeting are essential today.</li><li>Health focus on maintaining balance, nutrition, and mental peace.</li></ul><blockquote>“Stay open to changes in personal relationships, which could benefit from honest communication.”</blockquote><p>Emphasizing the importance of self-care and relaxation, today's horoscope encourages Aquarians to stay determined and focused to capitalize on their potential for growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/aquarius-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-predicts-unexpected-situations-101736529894908.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/aquarius-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-predicts-unexpected-situations-101736529894908.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 22:40:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, Jan 11, 2025 astro tips for future investments - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 to know your astrological predictions</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Capricorn_1728478974232_1736531805068.jpg" alt="Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: Today is a day filled with potential for personal development and success." title="Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: Today is a day filled with potential for personal development and success.">
<figcaption>Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: Today is a day filled with potential for personal development and success.</figcaption>
<p>Today presents growth opportunities in love and career, encouraging openness and focus for the best outcomes.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Personal growth is highlighted, especially in love and career.</li>
  <li>Communication is crucial for enhancing relationships, whether single or in a relationship.</li>
  <li>Career opportunities arise; collaboration is key to success.</li>
  <li>Financial caution is advised; it's a good day for budget assessment and long-term investments.</li>
  <li>Health recommendations include light physical activity and a nutritious diet.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Stay focused on your goals while being open to new experiences.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Capricorn natives are encouraged to embrace new experiences while remaining grounded in their goals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/capricorn-daily-horoscope-today-jan-11-2025-astro-tips-for-future-investments-101736531668242.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/capricorn-daily-horoscope-today-jan-11-2025-astro-tips-for-future-investments-101736531668242.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 22:39:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 predicts a bright future - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 predicts a bright future</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Sagittarius_1728479012112_1736532122572.jpg" alt="Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: You'll find yourself at a crossroads where personal growth meets new adventures." title="Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: You'll find yourself at a crossroads where personal growth meets new adventures."><figcaption>Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: You'll find yourself at a crossroads where personal growth meets new adventures.</figcaption><p>Today’s horoscope for Sagittarius encourages exploration and nurturing of relationships, leading to growth and joy.</p><ul><li>Connecting with others is key; be open to new experiences.</li><li>Love life may take an interesting turn; singles might encounter new romances.</li><li>At work, fresh challenges require problem-solving skills; proactive networking is encouraged.</li><li>Financially focus on strategic planning; seek trusted advice before making decisions.</li><li>Prioritize health with physical activities and mindfulness practices.</li></ul><blockquote>"Stay open to experiences, as they will bring joy and growth."</blockquote><p>This horoscope emphasizes embracing change and maintaining a positive outlook for personal and professional advancement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/sagittarius-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-predicts-a-bright-future-101736531975903.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/sagittarius-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-predicts-a-bright-future-101736531975903.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 22:38:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Libra Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 advices fiscal responsibility - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Libra Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 to know your astrological predictions</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Libra_1728479045617_1736532705819.jpg" alt="Libra Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: By focusing on these areas, you'll set the tone for a productive and satisfying day." title="Libra Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: By focusing on these areas, you'll set the tone for a productive and satisfying day."><figcaption>Libra Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: By focusing on these areas, you'll set the tone for a productive and satisfying day.</figcaption><p>Today, Libra, you'll find that balance and harmony are your guiding stars. In relationships, communicate openly to strengthen bonds. New career opportunities might present themselves, so be prepared to make the most of them. Financially, it's a good day to review your budget and ensure you're on track. Pay attention to your mental health, taking time to relax and reflect. By focusing on these areas, you'll set the tone for a productive and satisfying day.</p><ul><li>Balance and harmony guide your interactions.</li><li>New career opportunities are on the horizon.</li><li>Financial assessments and fiscal responsibility are essential today.</li><li>Mental health should be prioritized through relaxation.</li></ul><blockquote>“By focusing on these areas, you'll set the tone for a productive and satisfying day.”</blockquote><p>Take this day to communicate openly in relationships, manage finances wisely, and focus on a nurturing mental health routine.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/libra-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-advices-fiscal-responsibility-101736532488163.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/libra-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-advices-fiscal-responsibility-101736532488163.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 22:36:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 predicts new possibilities - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 to know your astrological predictions</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 11, 2025, Dr. J.N Pandey</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Virgo_1728479056525_1736531584244.jpg" alt="Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: Today brings an opportunity to seek balance in various aspects of life." />
    <figcaption>Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025: Today brings an opportunity to seek balance in various aspects of life.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Today, Virgos may find themselves focused on personal growth and clarity. Trust your instincts and be open to new possibilities.</p>
<ul>
    <li>For personal growth, maintain a positive outlook and remain open to change.</li>
    <li>In love, focus on open communication to strengthen relationships.</li>
    <li>At work, set realistic goals and utilize your analytical skills.</li>
    <li>Financially, create a budget and seek long-term planning.</li>
    <li>For health, integrate physical activities and prioritize mental well-being.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Trust your instincts and be open to new possibilities." - Dr. J.N. Pandey</blockquote>
<p>This horoscope suggests a day for Virgos to focus on balance and open communication, encouraging personal and professional growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/virgo-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-predicts-new-possibilities-101736531440091.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/virgo-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-predicts-new-possibilities-101736531440091.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 22:35:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leo Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 predicts cosmic blessings - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Leo Daily Horoscope Today, January 11, 2025 predicts cosmic blessings</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 11, 2025, Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Leo_1728478322188_1736531337755.jpg" alt="Leo Daily Horoscope Today, October 10, 2024: Ensure you devote more time to the relationship." title="Leo Daily Horoscope Today, October 10, 2024: Ensure you devote more time to the relationship."><figcaption>Leo Daily Horoscope Today, October 10, 2024: Ensure you devote more time to the relationship.</figcaption><p>Today brings opportunities for personal growth and reflection for Leos. Positive interactions enhance relationships, while career advancements require careful planning and determination.</p><ul><li>Today is a day of self-discovery and learning.</li><li>Opportunities for personal growth and reflection are highlighted.</li><li>Positive interactions with loved ones can provide new insights.</li><li>Career advancements require patience and strategic planning.</li><li>Financial evaluation is advised for stability.</li><li>Focus on mental and physical health for balance.</li></ul><blockquote>“Communication will play a crucial role in resolving misunderstandings.”</blockquote><p>Leos are encouraged to embrace leadership roles at work and maintain focus on their financial stability. Overall, a favorable day for personal and professional development.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/leo-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-predicts-cosmic-blessings-101736531139024.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/leo-daily-horoscope-today-january-11-2025-predicts-cosmic-blessings-101736531139024.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 22:34:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Pushpa 2’ box office collection day 36: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna’s action drama sees steady busi - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Pushpa 2' box office collection day 36: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna’s action drama sees steady business in 5th week; beats ‘Baby John’ and ‘Mufasa’ with a heavy margin</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117100766,imgsize-1096774,width-400,resizemode-4/117100766.jpg' alt='‘Pushpa 2’: Box Office Collection Day 36' title='Picture Credit: X' decoding='async' fetchpriority='high'><figcaption>‘Pushpa 2’ continues to dominate the box office.</figcaption><p>‘Pushpa 2’ has shown remarkable resilience at the box office during its fifth week, maintaining strong earnings against new releases.</p><ul><li>On its 5th Thursday, the film collected approximately Rs. 2 crore.</li><li>The total net collection in India has surpassed Rs. 1215 crore.</li><li>In its opening week, the film collected Rs. 725.8 crore.</li><li>The film faced competition from Varun Dhawan's ‘Baby John’ and Disney's ‘Mufasa: The Lion King’ but remained largely unaffected.</li></ul><blockquote>“The fire nahi, wildfire hai” – a dialogue that reflects the film's success.</blockquote><p>Despite controversies and competition, ‘Pushpa 2’ has set unprecedented records and showcases sustained box office appeal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-36-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandannas-action-drama-sees-steady-business-in-5th-week-beats-baby-john-and-mufasa-with-a-heavy-margin/articleshow/117100770.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-36-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandannas-action-drama-sees-steady-business-in-5th-week-beats-baby-john-and-mufasa-with-a-heavy-margin/articleshow/117100770.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Shrutika Arjun gets eliminated from the show; Chum Darang breaks down into tears - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18: Shrutika Arjun gets eliminated from the show; Chum Darang breaks down into tears</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117130645,imgsize-35238,width-400,resizemode-4/117130645.jpg" alt="Bigg Boss 18: Shrutika Arjun gets eliminated from the show; Chum Darang breaks down into tears" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Shrutika Arjun's elimination affected her fellow contestant Chum Darang deeply.</figcaption><p>The final phase of Bigg Boss 18 is underway, with emotions running high as contestants face elimination. In the latest episode, Shrutika Arjun was eliminated, and her exit upset her close friend, Chum Darang.</p><ul><li>Shrutika Arjun was part of a three-contestant elimination task involving audience votes.</li><li>Chahat Pandey and Rajat Dalal were the other nominated contestants.</li><li>Shrutika's elimination is part of the lead-up to the grand finale scheduled for January 19th.</li><li>The episode focused on the emotional ties among the contestants and their farewells.</li></ul><blockquote>“Shrutika and Chum shared a great bond on the show, and their fun moments were a treat for the audience.”</blockquote><p>The emotional aftermath of Shrutika's departure underscores the deep connections formed during the competition, reminding viewers of the impact of such reality shows.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-shrutika-arjun-gets-eliminated-from-the-show-chum-darang-breaks-down-into-tears/articleshow/117130550.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-shrutika-arjun-gets-eliminated-from-the-show-chum-darang-breaks-down-into-tears/articleshow/117130550.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 19:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aamir Khan admits to being an absent father, praises ex-wife Reena Dutta's upbringing: 'I am proud of how - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aamir Khan admits to being an absent father, praises ex-wife Reena Dutta's upbringing: 'I am proud of how Junaid has conducted himself'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023<strong> | Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117130578,imgsize-55186,width-400,resizemode-4/117130578.jpg" alt="Aamir Khan admits to being an absent father, praises ex-wife Reena Dutta's upbringing: 'I am proud of how Junaid has conducted himself'" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Aamir Khan at his son's trailer launch.</figcaption><p>Aamir Khan opens up about his journey as a father while celebrating his son Junaid Khan's Bollywood debut in the film 'Loveyapa'. He admits to being an absent father but expresses pride in his son's accomplishments.</p><ul><li>Aamir Khan reflects on his parenting and the values instilled in his children.</li><li>He admits to being an absent father, consumed by work.</li><li>Junaid Khan is stepping into Bollywood with his debut film 'Loveyapa'.</li><li>Aamir praises his ex-wife Reena Dutta for her role in their children's upbringing.</li><li>The film 'Loveyapa' promises a humorous take on Gen-Z relationships.</li></ul><blockquote>“I feel happy that Junaid has started his career on his own terms.” - Aamir Khan</blockquote><p>Aamir Khan expresses hope and pride as he witnesses Junaid's independent journey in the film industry, reflecting on the emotional weight of parenthood and the legacies we impart to our children.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aamir-khan-admits-to-being-an-absent-father-praises-ex-wife-reena-duttas-upbringing-i-am-proud-of-how-junaid-has-conducted-himself/articleshow/117130593.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aamir-khan-admits-to-being-an-absent-father-praises-ex-wife-reena-duttas-upbringing-i-am-proud-of-how-junaid-has-conducted-himself/articleshow/117130593.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 19:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taarak Mehta Ka Ooltah Chashmah's Gurucharan Singh 'Critical': 'Has Not Eaten Food For 19 Days' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gurucharan Singh from Taarak Mehta Ka Ooltah Chashmah in Critical Condition After 19 Days Without Food</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Gurcharan Singh played the role of Roshan Singh Sodhi in TMKOC." title="Gurcharan Singh played the role of Roshan Singh Sodhi in TMKOC."><figcaption>Gurcharan Singh played the role of Roshan Singh Sodhi in TMKOC.</figcaption></figure><p>Taarak Mehta Ka Ooltah Chashmah actor Gurucharan Singh is currently hospitalized and in critical condition after not eating for 19 days.</p><ul><li>His friend Bhakti Soni expressed concern over Singh's health, stating he has not taken any food or water.</li><li>During their last conversation, Singh indicated uncertainty about his survival.</li><li>He recently shared a video on Instagram, thanking everyone for their support and acknowledging his serious health condition.</li><li>Gurucharan Singh is well-known for his role as Roshan Singh Sodhi on the show.</li></ul><blockquote>“He hasn’t eaten food or drunk water for 19 days. Because of that, he fell unconscious and was quickly rushed to the hospital.” - Bhakti Soni</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Singh’s situation is dire, and he is under medical care while his friends and family express their utmost concern over his well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/taarak-mehta-ka-ooltah-chashmah-gurucharan-singh-critical-has-not-eaten-food-for-19-days-9183999.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/taarak-mehta-ka-ooltah-chashmah-gurucharan-singh-critical-has-not-eaten-food-for-19-days-9183999.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 19:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ajith Kumar reveals he will not sign any film until the race season is over: 'I plan to pursue motorsport - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ajith Kumar reveals he will not sign any film until the race season is over: 'I plan to pursue motorsports'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117130557,imgsize-49152,width-400,resizemode-4/117130557.jpg" alt="Ajith Kumar reveals he will not sign any film until the race season is over: 'I plan to pursue motorsports'" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Ajith Kumar during his practice for the 24H Dubai car race.</figcaption><p>Ajith Kumar, the popular actor, has announced that he will focus on his motorsport career and will not be signing new films until the racing season is complete. He recently suffered an injury during his practice but remains committed to the upcoming 24H Dubai car race.</p><ul><li>Ajith is teaming up with Mathieu Detry, Fabian Duffieux, and Cameron McLeod for the race.</li><li>The race is scheduled for January 11-12.</li><li>He plans to pursue motorsports not just as a driver but as a team owner.</li><li>Ajith intends to act in films between October and March, before the racing season starts.</li><li>He has two major films coming in 2025, including 'Good Bad Ugly' on April 10.</li></ul><blockquote>“I plan to pursue motorsports, not just as a driver but as a team owner as well. Until the racing season is on, I won’t be signing any films.”</blockquote><p>Ajith's commitment to both film and racing highlights his dedication to his dual passions, ensuring he can give his all to both pursuits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/tamil/movies/news/ajith-kumar-reveals-he-will-not-sign-any-film-until-the-race-season-is-over-i-plan-to-pursue-motorsports/articleshow/117130389.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/tamil/movies/news/ajith-kumar-reveals-he-will-not-sign-any-film-until-the-race-season-is-over-i-plan-to-pursue-motorsports/articleshow/117130389.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 19:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govinda's wife Sunita Ahuja recalls her daughter's untimely death: 'I am not the kind of mother who would - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunita Ahuja Reflects on the Heartbreaking Loss of Her Daughter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117127002,imgsize-22778,width-400,resizemode-4/117127002.jpg' alt='Govinda's wife Sunita Ahuja recalls her daughter's untimely death' decoding='async' fetchpriority='high'><figcaption>Sunita Ahuja recalls her daughter's untimely death.</figcaption><p>In an interview, Sunita Ahuja discussed her decision to focus on motherhood over a career in acting and reflected on the emotional loss of her daughter.</p><ul><li>Sunita prioritized raising her children over pursuing an acting career.</li><li>She considers her children the center of her world and expresses her dedication to hands-on parenting.</li><li>She addressed the loss of her daughter due to health issues, emphasizing her commitment to family.</li><li>Now that her children are grown, Sunita is exploring new opportunities, like a potential podcast.</li><li>She prides herself on raising well-mannered and grounded children.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am not the kind of mother who would…” - Sunita Ahuja reflecting on her parenting commitment.</blockquote><p>The article highlights Sunita Ahuja's deep devotion to her family and the significant impact of her daughter's loss on her life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/govindas-wife-sunita-ahuja-recalls-her-daughters-untimely-death-i-am-not-the-kind-of-mother-who-would-/articleshow/117127002.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/govindas-wife-sunita-ahuja-recalls-her-daughters-untimely-death-i-am-not-the-kind-of-mother-who-would-/articleshow/117127002.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Akshay Kumar's 'Welcome 3' Eyes A Major Box Office Clash - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxNTzZkdVY3aEJoQXpzeWRSR19qTGhKS0hKa3B1cjBfNGxyNGxFcjZjVXRXb240WmNfRjFCRFFuYjRVNTBEZmliZEJpSTk5UzV1ZXBvcjkwQzh3bnlycUJfQXlYMWFOUVpvLWxnVkNMQ0ZhN2RKX05hMmxEejlQVHhrbENyUjRtanR1M1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxNTzZkdVY3aEJoQXpzeWRSR19qTGhKS0hKa3B1cjBfNGxyNGxFcjZjVXRXb240WmNfRjFCRFFuYjRVNTBEZmliZEJpSTk5UzV1ZXBvcjkwQzh3bnlycUJfQXlYMWFOUVpvLWxnVkNMQ0ZhN2RKX05hMmxEejlQVHhrbENyUjRtanR1M1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 17:30:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>