<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:21:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:21:17 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oscars 2025 final shortlist: India's Oscar hopes ride on Guneet Monga's 'Anuja' after Kiran Rao's 'Laapat - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Oscars 2025 final shortlist: India's Oscar hopes ride on Guneet Monga's 'Anuja' after Kiran Rao's 'Laapataa Ladies' misses the cut</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<p>'Anuja' by Guneet Monga stands as India's hope for an Oscar nomination following Kiran Rao's 'Laapataa Ladies' not making it to the final shortlist.</p>
<ul>
  <li>'Anuja' is receiving significant attention in the lead-up to the Oscars.</li>
  <li>Kiran Rao's 'Laapataa Ladies' was expected to be a contender but did not make the shortlist.</li>
  <li>The shortlist reflects current trends and preferences in the Academy Awards selection process.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>'Anuja' showcases remarkable talent and storytelling that resonates with a global audience.</blockquote>
<p>This year's Oscar race highlights the challenges Indian films face in gaining recognition at international film awards, while 'Anuja' aims to change that narrative.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/oscars-2025-final-shortlist-indias-oscar-hopes-ride-on-guneet-mongas-anuja-after-kiran-raos-laapataa-ladies-misses-the-cut/articleshow/116412513.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/oscars-2025-final-shortlist-indias-oscar-hopes-ride-on-guneet-mongas-anuja-after-kiran-raos-laapataa-ladies-misses-the-cut/articleshow/116412513.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 20:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oscars 2025: India's Laapataa Ladies fails to feature in shortlist, out of Best International Feature category - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAJBVV95cUxPQlN4RG9ZdDdTZzJ1QnRpN1h0X0t1VGU1dWVHMGttR3VmdG8tRS13Vm1ZRmtXVUxXWDFMWEpYUVF6UDVGajlwZEx5RWdQWGpibjBlOWpCdlRqN2dFdVZ4cXB6bTB3ZEwtOXlmcVFZQWpWZTZUd2Zsc1QwaFJvNHpJTjlpZ3dEa2lrSnVUek1FSi1GQm54SzlVTGdxV1psbUotSk9HSmR2R25TWlZGcXRHTGRSOGZTWFB0UDROc3JkUjVvV2JKUWtWTEtpU2JJRG1xNGFJQnNBN2E5WHRvVy1rODZwMXNnU05lWUhTVE94MzN3OWthOG1WeWFiWXhHNmg5U2o5bU9kUWFjY2ttU3dnQdIBlgJBVV95cUxNWVhDNU95cDlQMV9Nb1ItcVpUWXdQbW1lMnhJQ3ZCbFNydXJuWFozQzJGamtZMW94LTFPNmpxckNlYldzdTJpb1NXVjdKRlJHZ2FCaHhnZnRjZERibzBQY3RuYWZvTXlTM3FJeTYxdlNjNDhPNkdVOElsU0lTLVlTbENHdC1tYlRIbUUzSzNOTWJLbXU1ZDhBRFVZMEJSSGluX0xxOGR0dUMwNGt2ak9qMmJkWjFTclVzU2xiUnBBd3F2NTlYT0wzYU5nYXY4cGJPZEZvaFIwNG9oX0J5Zld4eFdwMktHRWloNjAtMnBiRFpJQV9xMThLQ3ZLdzltbTgtUU1xSVNCY1p4TjdDSjY0dEFoN25YQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAJBVV95cUxPQlN4RG9ZdDdTZzJ1QnRpN1h0X0t1VGU1dWVHMGttR3VmdG8tRS13Vm1ZRmtXVUxXWDFMWEpYUVF6UDVGajlwZEx5RWdQWGpibjBlOWpCdlRqN2dFdVZ4cXB6bTB3ZEwtOXlmcVFZQWpWZTZUd2Zsc1QwaFJvNHpJTjlpZ3dEa2lrSnVUek1FSi1GQm54SzlVTGdxV1psbUotSk9HSmR2R25TWlZGcXRHTGRSOGZTWFB0UDROc3JkUjVvV2JKUWtWTEtpU2JJRG1xNGFJQnNBN2E5WHRvVy1rODZwMXNnU05lWUhTVE94MzN3OWthOG1WeWFiWXhHNmg5U2o5bU9kUWFjY2ttU3dnQdIBlgJBVV95cUxNWVhDNU95cDlQMV9Nb1ItcVpUWXdQbW1lMnhJQ3ZCbFNydXJuWFozQzJGamtZMW94LTFPNmpxckNlYldzdTJpb1NXVjdKRlJHZ2FCaHhnZnRjZERibzBQY3RuYWZvTXlTM3FJeTYxdlNjNDhPNkdVOElsU0lTLVlTbENHdC1tYlRIbUUzSzNOTWJLbXU1ZDhBRFVZMEJSSGluX0xxOGR0dUMwNGt2ak9qMmJkWjFTclVzU2xiUnBBd3F2NTlYT0wzYU5nYXY4cGJPZEZvaFIwNG9oX0J5Zld4eFdwMktHRWloNjAtMnBiRFpJQV9xMThLQ3ZLdzltbTgtUU1xSVNCY1p4TjdDSjY0dEFoN25YQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 19:17:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 13 (Early Trends): Stree 2 Out Of Top 5 As Allu Arjun Topples Every Indian Film On Second Tuesday, Enters 600 Crore Club! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 13 (Early Trends): Stree 2 Out Of Top 5 As Allu Arjun Topples Every Indian Film</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-13-early-trends-stree-2-out-of-top-5-as-allu-arjun-topples-every-indian-film-on-second-tuesday-enters-600-crore-club.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 13 (Early Trends)" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 13 Early Estimates! (Photo Credit – Instagram)</figcaption><p>Pushpa 2 continues to perform remarkably well in the Hindi box office, surpassing Baahubali 2 and entering the 600 crore club.</p><h4><strong>Highlights:</strong></h4><ul><li>Day 13 box office earnings estimated between <strong>18-19 crores</strong>.</li><li>Dip of only 12-7% from the previous day.</li><li>Best second Tuesday earnings of all time, beating Baahubali 2.</li><li>Pushpa 2 is now the second highest-grossing Hindi film with <strong>600-601 crores</strong>.</li><li>Top 5 highest earnings Hindi films on the second Tuesday.</li></ul><blockquote>“With around <strong>27 crores</strong> more in the kitty, Pushpa 2 will surpass every Bollywood film to become the highest-grossing film in Hindi cinema!”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Pushpa 2's phenomenal box office performance indicates its position as a significant player in Hindi cinema, likely to surpass even more records.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-13-early-trends-stree-2-out-of-top-5-as-allu-arjun-topples-every-indian-film-on-second-tuesday-enters-600-crore-club/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-13-early-trends-stree-2-out-of-top-5-as-allu-arjun-topples-every-indian-film-on-second-tuesday-enters-600-crore-club/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:15:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 The Rule box office collection day 13: Allu Arjun film shows no sign of slowing down, collects ₹950 crore - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 The Rule Box Office Collection Day 13: Allu Arjun's Pushpa Raj Continues Its Wildfire Effect</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/Pushpa_2_The_Rule_review_2_1733348849370_1734452088543.jpg" alt="Rashmika Mandanna and Allu Arjun play Srivalli and Pushpa Raj in Pushpa 2: The Rule." title="Rashmika Mandanna and Allu Arjun play Srivalli and Pushpa Raj in Pushpa 2: The Rule."><figcaption>Rashmika Mandanna and Allu Arjun play Srivalli and Pushpa Raj in Pushpa 2: The Rule.</figcaption><p>The box office collection of 'Pushpa 2: The Rule' has crossed ₹950 crore in just 13 days, continuing its strong performance with minimal competition.</p><ul><li>The film has maintained its momentum at the box office even in its second week, earning ₹21.33 crore on its second Tuesday.</li><li>Pushpa 2 had a total collection of ₹950.38 crore, with a significant portion generated from the Hindi-dubbed version.</li><li>The film features Allu Arjun, Rashmika Mandanna, and Fahadh Faasil and is directed by Sukumar.</li><li>Pushpa 2 has already crossed the ₹1000-crore mark worldwide, ranking it among the top 10 highest-grossing Indian films ever.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pushpa 2 had a 21.00 percent Telugu occupancy and 18.08 percent Hindi occupancy.”</blockquote><p>The film's success comes as Allu Arjun faced controversy due to an incident involving the death of a fan at the premiere, for which he was briefly arrested.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-the-rule-box-office-collection-day-13-allu-arjun-rashmika-mandanna-film-crosses-950-crore-101734451874591.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-the-rule-box-office-collection-day-13-allu-arjun-rashmika-mandanna-film-crosses-950-crore-101734451874591.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 16:38:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shatrughan Sinha claps back at Mukesh Khanna for questioning Sonakshi Singha’s upbringing: ‘Who has appointed him the guardian of the Hindu religion?’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shatrughan Sinha Responds to Mukesh Khanna's Criticism of Sonakshi Sinha</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Shatrughan-Mukesh.jpg?w=640" alt="Shatrughan Sinha reacts to Mukesh Khanna's comment about Sonakshi Sinha" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Shatrughan Sinha slams Mukesh Khanna for his remarks on Sonakshi Sinha.</figcaption><p>Shatrughan Sinha has come to the defense of his daughter, Sonakshi, after Mukesh Khanna criticized her for not knowing an answer related to the Ramayana during a game show.</p><ul><li>Shatrughan Sinha questioned Mukesh Khanna's qualifications to judge Sonakshi and challenged his authority in matters concerning Hindu beliefs.</li><li>He expressed pride in Sonakshi's achievements and stated that not knowing an answer does not define her as a Hindu.</li><li>Sonakshi criticized Khanna's focus on her during the incident, echoing Sinha's sentiments about parental values.</li><li>Mukesh Khanna later clarified that his intention was to address a generational shift in knowledge concerning Indian culture.</li></ul><blockquote>“Not answering a question on the Ramayan doesn’t disqualify Sonakshi from being a good Hindu. She doesn’t need a certificate of approval from anyone.” - Shatrughan Sinha</blockquote><p>The public exchange highlights the ongoing discussion about cultural knowledge in modern society, as well as the responsibilities of parents in imparting this knowledge to younger generations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/shatrughan-sinha-claps-back-at-mukesh-khanna-for-questioning-sonakshi-singhas-upbringing-9730562/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/shatrughan-sinha-claps-back-at-mukesh-khanna-for-questioning-sonakshi-singhas-upbringing-9730562/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 16:30:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan recalls being offered Heeramandi in first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali: ‘It was in works but…' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan recalls being offered Heeramandi fifteen years ago when she was not even an actor, shares details of her first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/mahira_1734445320900_1734445344435.jpg" alt="Mahira Khan recalls her first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali when he offered her Heeramandi." title="Mahira Khan recalls her first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali when he offered her Heeramandi."><figcaption>Mahira Khan recalls her first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali when he offered her Heeramandi.</figcaption><p>In a recent interview, Mahira Khan shared her experience of being offered a role in Heeramandi during her first meeting with filmmaker Sanjay Leela Bhansali, a significant moment in her early career.</p><ul><li>Mahira Khan was introduced to Bhansali through a friend while attending a wedding in Mumbai.</li><li>She remembered Bhansali looking for a Pakistani actress for a project, leading to her impromptu meeting.</li><li>During the meeting, she was praised by Bhansali, who was interested in casting her for Heeramandi.</li><li>Despite the excitement, political issues prevented her from accepting the role at the time.</li><li>Heeramandi has since been released on Netflix, depicting the lives of courtesans during the British Raj.</li></ul><blockquote>“What a man he is! So creative and a genius. He said, 'Can you wipe your lipstick off?' I said, 'I'm not wearing any lipstick'.”</blockquote><p>Ultimately, Mahira's candid approach and desire for honesty regarding her marital status played a crucial role in her career decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mahira-khan-recalls-being-offered-heeramandi-in-first-meeting-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-it-was-in-works-but-101734444994653.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mahira-khan-recalls-being-offered-heeramandi-in-first-meeting-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-it-was-in-works-but-101734444994653.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:57:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Atlee breaks silence on A6 with Salman Khan: “It’s going to be proudest film for our country” - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>EXCLUSIVE: Atlee breaks silence on A6 with Salman Khan: “It’s going to be proudest film for our country”</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p>
<img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/1295840663_salman-khan-atlee-main-1.jpg" alt="EXCLUSIVE: Atlee breaks silence on A6 with Salman Khan: “It’s going to be proudest film for our country”" width="855" height="855">
<figcaption>EXCLUSIVE: Atlee shares insights on his upcoming film A6 starring Salman Khan.</figcaption>
<p>Atlee, director of the blockbuster Jawan, is gearing up for his next film, tentatively titled A6, which he claims will be a proud film for the nation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Atlee confirms A6 will star Salman Khan.</li>
  <li>Aiming to cast either Rajinikanth or Kamal Haasan alongside Khan.</li>
  <li>The script is nearly finished, and preparations are underway for the film.</li>
  <li>A6 is being touted as a major announcement coming soon.</li>
  <li>Varun Dhawan, the lead in Atlee's other project Baby John, expresses excitement about A6.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It’s going to be the proudest film of our country. We want a lot of blessings, just pray for us.” - Atlee</blockquote>
<p>The anticipation builds as fans await more details on A6, which promises to be a landmark project in Indian cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-atlee-breaks-silence-on-a6-with-salman-khan-its-going-to-be-proudest-film-for-our-country-1363161</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-atlee-breaks-silence-on-a6-with-salman-khan-its-going-to-be-proudest-film-for-our-country-1363161</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:54:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sachin Tendulkar's viral video of tabla masterclass with late Zakir Hussain resurfaces - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sachin Tendulkar's Viral Tabla Masterclass with Zakir Hussain</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p> <p>This article discusses a viral video showcasing Sachin Tendulkar's tabla masterclass with the late legendary tabla player Zakir Hussain, highlighting its significance and audience reception.</p> <ul> <li>The video features a musical interaction that captivates audiences.</li> <li>Tendulkar, celebrated for his cricketing prowess, demonstrates his passion for music.</li> <li>The collaboration underscores the bond between different art forms.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“Music transcends boundaries, uniting people in unique ways.”</blockquote> <p>This video serves as a reminder of the impact of art and music in our lives, bridging cultures and generations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/off-the-field/sachin-tendulkars-viral-video-of-tabla-masterclass-with-late-zakir-hussain-resurfaces/articleshow/116406786.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/off-the-field/sachin-tendulkars-viral-video-of-tabla-masterclass-with-late-zakir-hussain-resurfaces/articleshow/116406786.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Khanna REACTS to Sonakshi Sinha's post slamming him for questioning her upbringing: 'I have a cord - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mukesh Khanna REACTS to Sonakshi Sinha's post slamming him for questioning her upbringing</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116406511,imgsize-43502,width-400,resizemode-4/116406511.jpg" alt="Mukesh Khanna REACTS to Sonakshi Sinha's post slamming him for questioning her upbringing: 'I have a cordial relationship with Shatrughan Sinha'">
<figcaption>Mukesh Khanna and Sonakshi Sinha in a recent public spat.</figcaption>
<p>Mukesh Khanna has responded to Sonakshi Sinha's backlash regarding his comments on her upbringing and knowledge of the Ramayana. He clarifies that his intention was not malicious and emphasizes a need for deeper knowledge in today's generation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sonakshi Sinha criticized Mukesh Khanna for linking her inability to answer a KBC question to her father's teaching.</li>
  <li>Mukesh Khanna expressed surprise at the delay in Sonakshi's response and affirmed his cordial relationship with Shatrughan Sinha.</li>
  <li>He intended to comment on modern reliance on technology for information, using Sonakshi's situation as an example.</li>
  <li>Sonakshi defended herself, noting that others also struggled with the same question on KBC.</li>
  <li>Sonakshi recently married Zaheer Iqbal, with the wedding attended by several Bollywood celebrities.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Dear Sir, Mukesh Khanna ji ...I recently read a statement you made saying that it's my father's fault I did not answer a question about the Ramayana correctly on a show I attended many, many years back.” - Sonakshi Sinha</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing dialogue highlights the sensitive nature of public commentary on personal backgrounds and the importance of understanding context in such discussions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mukesh-khanna-reacts-to-sonakshi-sinhas-post-slamming-him-for-questioning-her-upbringing-i-have-a-cordial-relationship-with-shatrughan-sinha/articleshow/116406511.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mukesh-khanna-reacts-to-sonakshi-sinhas-post-slamming-him-for-questioning-her-upbringing-i-have-a-cordial-relationship-with-shatrughan-sinha/articleshow/116406511.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yami Gautam holds son Vedavid in her arms, joins Sanjay Dutt, Aditya Dhar to offer prayers at Golden Temple. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yami Gautam Holds Son Vedavid in Her Arms, Joins Sanjay Dutt, Aditya Dhar to Offer Prayers at Golden Temple</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/yami_1734447607806_1734447613966.jpg" alt="Yami Gautam, Aditya Dhar, Sanjay Dutt at the Golden Temple." title="Yami Gautam, Aditya Dhar, Sanjay Dutt at the Golden Temple.">
<figcaption>Yami Gautam, Aditya Dhar, Sanjay Dutt at the Golden Temple.</figcaption>
<p>Bollywood star Sanjay Dutt is currently in Amritsar for the shoot of his upcoming films with director Aditya Dhar. Yami Gautam joined them for a sacred visit to the Gurudwara with her newborn son, Vedavid.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sanjay Dutt and Aditya Dhar offered prayers at the Golden Temple during their shooting schedule.</li>
  <li>Yami Gautam participated in the visit, bringing her son Vedavid along.</li>
  <li>Visuals of the visit showed the trio seeking blessings and interacting with fans.</li>
  <li>Yami held Vedavid in her arms, wrapped in a cloth.</li>
  <li>Sanjay Dutt met with Punjab minister Kuldeep Dhaliwal during the visit.</li>
  <li>The upcoming film, in collaboration with Jio Studios, is based on historical events related to Indian Intelligence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Jaako raakhe sayiyaan maar sake na koi..” - Ranveer Singh on his visit to the Golden Temple.</blockquote>
<p>This visit highlights the intersection of personal spirituality and professional commitments in the lives of these celebrities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/sanjay-dutt-yami-gautam-aditya-dhar-offer-prayers-at-golden-temple-101734447361116.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/sanjay-dutt-yami-gautam-aditya-dhar-offer-prayers-at-golden-temple-101734447361116.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:07:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Khanna reacts after Sonakshi Sinha slams him for questioning her upbringing: ‘Surprised she took so much time’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mukesh Khanna says he didn't have any malicious intention as he reacts to Sonakshi Sinha slamming him for questioning her upbringing.</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/Sonak_1734441857233_1734441875913.jpg" alt="Mukesh Khanna reacts to Sonakshi Sinha slamming him for questioning her upbringing." title="Mukesh Khanna reacts to Sonakshi Sinha slamming him for questioning her upbringing."><figcaption>Mukesh Khanna reacts to Sonakshi Sinha slamming him for questioning her upbringing.</figcaption><p>Mukesh Khanna has responded to Sonakshi Sinha's criticism regarding his comments on her upbringing, clarifying he had no malicious intent.</p><ul><li>Sonakshi criticized Mukesh for connecting her inability to answer a Ramayana question on KBC to her upbringing.</li><li>Mukesh expressed surprise at the time it took for Sonakshi to respond.</li><li>He aimed to highlight the limits of knowledge in the current generation compared to past generations.</li><li>Sonakshi defended herself, pointing out that another contestant also failed to answer the same question on the show.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am surprised she took so much time to react. I had no malicious intention to malign her or her father.” - Mukesh Khanna</blockquote><p>The exchange highlights ongoing discussions about celebrity accountability and generational knowledge differences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mukesh-khanna-reacts-after-sonakshi-sinha-slams-him-for-questioning-her-upbringing-surprised-she-took-so-much-time-101734441561232.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mukesh-khanna-reacts-after-sonakshi-sinha-slams-him-for-questioning-her-upbringing-surprised-she-took-so-much-time-101734441561232.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:15:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This is Where Things Backfired For Allu Arjun - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxPSnQ0blVHVVQtZUFNT041a09DcjE2cUxsdEN5VUlCZjdQQ0wtVldHMDRlY3J3a2QxQVFZRW5ZaG9sSUxaVW9YNkdaSFh6bU5yRVc2TTNTR2ppeXBkWWtBM25pUVRhaXpTdnJQc1dzOXZDNThGSkF6OGQwN2ZRa3BqNTNB0gGHAUFVX3lxTFA3ajBNN3E0QWRZdm1ScjA5aHFWakVyZHNzalVsTWMzUmRiczlsUmxodE1WcEh3NFJYemdKVmQwWlM3bTBHZWd1a2FsOWlIMDg3Vm5ibEM2WUQ4RjBIN19Gbzd6THM2WFlBbVpUMUlPWlpsQTd3V1ZYcTd0cDNuNHI0SnR1NVlFdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxPSnQ0blVHVVQtZUFNT041a09DcjE2cUxsdEN5VUlCZjdQQ0wtVldHMDRlY3J3a2QxQVFZRW5ZaG9sSUxaVW9YNkdaSFh6bU5yRVc2TTNTR2ppeXBkWWtBM25pUVRhaXpTdnJQc1dzOXZDNThGSkF6OGQwN2ZRa3BqNTNB0gGHAUFVX3lxTFA3ajBNN3E0QWRZdm1ScjA5aHFWakVyZHNzalVsTWMzUmRiczlsUmxodE1WcEh3NFJYemdKVmQwWlM3bTBHZWd1a2FsOWlIMDg3Vm5ibEM2WUQ4RjBIN19Gbzd6THM2WFlBbVpUMUlPWlpsQTd3V1ZYcTd0cDNuNHI0SnR1NVlFdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:10:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stampede after Allu Arjun visit: Police notice to theatre points to lapses – ‘illegal’ flex boards, lack of proper entry-exit signs - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stampede after Allu Arjun visit: Police notice to theatre points to lapses</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Allu-Arjun-3col.jpg?w=640' alt='Actor Allu Arjun leaves a Hyderabad hospital after medical check-up following his arrest Friday in a stampede case.' width='640' height='360'><figcaption>Actor Allu Arjun leaves a Hyderabad hospital after medical check-up following his arrest Friday in a stampede case.</figcaption><p>The Hyderabad City Police issued a show cause notice to Sandhya 70MM Theatre for lapses leading to a tragic stampede during the premiere of the movie Pushpa 2, which resulted in a fatality and serious injuries.</p><ul><li>The stampede occurred on December 4 during the premiere of Pushpa 2.</li><li>39-year-old M Revathi died, and her nine-year-old son was seriously injured.</li><li>The theatre management failed to inform police about the arrival of Allu Arjun.</li><li>Lapses noted include lack of entry-exit signs and illegal flex boards encouraging crowds.</li><li>Police are considering canceling the theatre’s license.</li></ul><blockquote>“The boy’s neurological functions are affected. He is in and out of coma.” - C V Anand, City Police Commissioner</blockquote><p>This incident highlights serious safety oversights at public events and raises questions about crowd management at high-profile appearances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/allu-arjun-stampede-police-notice-theatre-lapses-9730458/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/allu-arjun-stampede-police-notice-theatre-lapses-9730458/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:01:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sameer Wankhede avoids question on Shah Rukh Khan, Mahira Khan on viral smoking photos with Ranbir Kapoor - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sameer Wankhede avoids question on Shah Rukh Khan, Mahira Khan on viral smoking photos with Ranbir Kapoor: Top 5 news</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116402690,imgsize-53230,width-400,resizemode-4/116402690.jpg" alt="Sameer Wankhede avoids question on Shah Rukh Khan, Mahira Khan on viral smoking photos with Ranbir Kapoor" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Sameer Wankhede addressing Shah Rukh Khan controversy in an interview.</figcaption><p>The entertainment world is abuzz with headlines ranging from Sameer Wankhede's evasive comments on Shah Rukh Khan to Mahira Khan's candid reflections on her viral smoking photos with Ranbir Kapoor.</p><ul><li>Sameer Wankhede refrained from discussing Shah Rukh Khan's involvement in the ongoing controversy regarding his son.</li><li>Mahira Khan expressed feelings of despair over her viral smoking photos, stating it felt like her career was ending.</li><li>Ranveer Singh shared a heartwarming interaction with paparazzi while discussing his daughter, Dua.</li><li>Shatrughan Sinha defended his daughter Sonakshi against comments made by Mukesh Khanna.</li><li>Adnan Sami mourned the loss of renowned musician Zakir Hussain.</li></ul><blockquote>“I felt my career was over,” - Mahira Khan on her viral smoking photos.</blockquote><p>This article encapsulates the current drama in Bollywood, highlighting the personalities involved and their reflections on significant moments impacting their careers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sameer-wankhede-avoids-question-on-shah-rukh-khan-mahira-khan-on-viral-smoking-photos-with-ranbir-kapoor-to-shatrughan-sinha-slams-mukesh-khannatop-5-entertainment-news-of-the-day/articleshow/116402690.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/sameer-wankhede-avoids-question-on-shah-rukh-khan-mahira-khan-on-viral-smoking-photos-with-ranbir-kapoor-to-shatrughan-sinha-slams-mukesh-khannatop-5-entertainment-news-of-the-day/articleshow/116402690.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Vidaa Muyarchi’: Ajith Kumar looks dapper in new stills; Magizh Thirumeni’s film to clash with ‘Good Bad Ugly’ for Pongal? - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ajith Kumar's 'Vidaa Muyarchi' Set for Pongal Release, Clashing with 'Good Bad Ugly'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/entertainment/movies/cw1zf7/article68995916.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/ajith%20kumar%20vidaa%20muyarchi%20trisha.jpg" alt="Ajith Kumar, Trisha and Magizh Thirumeni on the sets of ‘Vidaa Muyarchi’" title="Ajith Kumar, Trisha and Magizh Thirumeni on the sets of ‘Vidaa Muyarchi’"><figcaption>Ajith Kumar, Trisha and Magizh Thirumeni on the sets of ‘Vidaa Muyarchi’ | Photo Credit: @LycaProductions/X</figcaption><p><i>Vidaa Muyarchi</i>, Tamil superstar Ajith Kumar’s upcoming film with director Magizh Thirumeni, is nearing completion with plans for a release during Pongal in January 2025.</p><ul><li>Ajith Kumar is seen in new stills looking dapper in a tuxedo, reminiscent of his <i>Billa</i> days.</li><li>The film also features superstar Trisha and is characterized as an action-packed crime drama.</li><li>Both <i>Vidaa Muyarchi</i> and another Ajith film, <i>Good Bad Ugly</i>, are vying for the Pongal release window.</li><li>Speculations arise that <i>Good Bad Ugly</i> might change its release date to avoid a clash.</li><li>Ajith is set to return to racing as a team owner for Ajith Kumar Racing in 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are planning on releasing the film during Pongal in January 2025,” stated the film's producers.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the upcoming clash on Pongal has created significant buzz around both films and has captured the attention of fans and media alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/vidaa-muyarchi-ajith-kumar-looks-dapper-in-new-stills-magizh-thirumenis-film-to-clash-with-good-bad-ugly-for-pongal/article68995837.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/vidaa-muyarchi-ajith-kumar-looks-dapper-in-new-stills-magizh-thirumenis-film-to-clash-with-good-bad-ugly-for-pongal/article68995837.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Interview: Upendra – UI will make audiences decode its metaphors - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Interview: Upendra – UI will make audiences decode its metaphors</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 17, 2024</strong></p><p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Updher.jpg" alt="Upendra UI" width="321" height="500"><figcaption>Upendra in his upcoming film UI</figcaption></p><p>Kannada superstar Upendra discusses his upcoming film UI, set for release on December 20, 2024. He shares insights into the film's concept, character design, and his thoughts on storytelling in cinema.</p><ul><li>UI is described as an interactive film that invites audiences to decode its metaphors.</li><li>The film's concept challenges traditional education and encourages critical thinking.</li><li>Upendra emphasizes the teamwork involved in creating the film, crediting the producers for their support.</li><li>The film features unique visual artistry and music recorded in Hungary.</li><li>Upendra expresses excitement about working with Rajinikanth in the upcoming film Coolie.</li></ul><blockquote>“What I feel is what you feel. This is an interactive film where audiences will decode many things as they watch.” – Upendra</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Upendra aims to create a thought-provoking cinematic experience that resonates with audiences, encouraging them to engage deeply with the film's content.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/interview-upendra-ui-will-make-audiences-decode-its-metaphors.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/interview-upendra-ui-will-make-audiences-decode-its-metaphors.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ustad Zakir Hussain died of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. What is this lung condition? - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ustad Zakir Hussain died of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. What is this lung condition?</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 17, 2024 06:00 pm IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/utvl3x/article68995452.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_iStock-1432432550_2_1_50C9NJ7U.jpg" alt="Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a disease that causes scarring of the lungs." title="Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a disease that causes scarring of the lungs."><figcaption>Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) is a disease that causes scarring of the lungs. Photograph used for representational purposes only | Photo Credit: Getty Images</figcaption><p>Ustad Zakir Hussain, a legendary tabla maestro and four-time Grammy award winner, passed away at 73 in San Francisco on December 15, 2024, due to idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, leaving behind a significant legacy in classical music.</p><h4>Key Points:</h4><ul><li>IPF is a chronic lung disease characterized by scarring of the lungs, leading to progressively difficult breathing.</li><li>The cause of IPF is classified as 'idiopathic', meaning unknown, and it is the most common form of pulmonary fibrosis.</li><li>Risk factors for developing IPF include being a former or current smoker, age (rare under 50), and family history of pulmonary fibrosis.</li><li>Symptoms can include shortness of breath, persistent dry cough, fatigue, and changes in fingernails.</li><li>Diagnosis may involve medical history, CT scans, and respiratory tests, while treatment options are limited to slowing disease progression and supportive care.</li></ul><blockquote>“Think of the lung as a balloon. IPF hardens the lung tissue, making its elasticity go away.” - R. P. Ilangho, pulmonologist</blockquote><p>This news underlines the serious and often misunderstood condition of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, highlighting the importance of awareness and understanding around lung diseases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/ustad-zakir-hussain-died-of-idiopathic-pulmonary-fibrosis-what-is-this-lung-condition/article68994802.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/ustad-zakir-hussain-died-of-idiopathic-pulmonary-fibrosis-what-is-this-lung-condition/article68994802.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan reveals Sanjay Leela Bhansali wanted to cast her in Heeramandi 15 years ago - Dawn]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan Reveals Sanjay Leela Bhansali Wanted to Cast Her in Heeramandi 15 Years Ago</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>In a recent interview, Pakistani actress Mahira Khan shared that renowned Indian director Sanjay Leela Bhansali had considered her for a role in his Netflix series <em>Heeramandi</em> fifteen years ago, but political tensions prevented the collaboration.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Mahira Khan was suggested for the role by a childhood friend during a trip to India.</li>
  <li>Khan and Bhansali had a meeting where he expressed excitement about her potential involvement in the project.</li>
  <li>Political strife between India and Pakistan ultimately blocked her casting.</li>
  <li>Khan made her Bollywood debut in <em>Raees</em> opposite Shah Rukh Khan.</li>
  <li>Reflecting on her career, she acknowledges the significant opportunities for actors today.</li>
  <li>Khan discussed her marriage to Salim Karim, emphasizing pride in their bond and her family.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“But, yes, I was in this unique position where somehow I was given this opportunity.” – Mahira Khan</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Khan's journey highlights the impact of personal and political factors in career opportunities in the film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://images.dawn.com/news/1193068</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://images.dawn.com/news/1193068</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:28:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan BREAKS silence on not being able to do 'Heeramandi' with Sanjay Leela Bhansali, recalls her f - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan BREAKS silence on not being able to do 'Heeramandi' with Sanjay Leela Bhansali, recalls her first meeting with him: 'Don't tell him you're married'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> TOI</p>
<p>In a recent statement, Mahira Khan opened up about her inability to star in the much-anticipated project 'Heeramandi' with renowned director Sanjay Leela Bhansali. During the interview, she reminisced about her first encounter with him, revealing his memorable advice to her.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Mahira Khan's reflections on not being able to participate in 'Heeramandi'.</li>
  <li>Her first meeting with Sanjay Leela Bhansali and his advice: 'Don't tell him you're married'.</li>
  <li>Insights into her career choices and future projects.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Don't tell him you're married." - Mahira Khan reflecting on Bhansali's advice during their first meeting.</blockquote>
<p>Overall, Mahira Khan's insights illustrate both the challenges and opportunities faced by actors in the Bollywood industry, especially concerning collaborations with iconic filmmakers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mahira-khan-breaks-silence-on-not-being-able-to-do-heeramandi-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-recalls-her-first-meeting-with-him-dont-tell-him-youre-married/articleshow/116402016.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mahira-khan-breaks-silence-on-not-being-able-to-do-heeramandi-with-sanjay-leela-bhansali-recalls-her-first-meeting-with-him-dont-tell-him-youre-married/articleshow/116402016.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa-2 stampede: Hyderabad police find 11 lapses in Sandhya theatre - Deccan Chronicle]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hyderabad Police Identify 11 Lapses After Pushpa-2 Stampede at Sandhya Theatre</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 4, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Hyderabad Police</p><p>In a tragic incident during the premiere of 'Pushpa 2' at Sandhya 70 MM theatre, a stampede led to the death of a woman and raised serious questions about theatre management and safety protocols.</p><ul><li>Hyderabad police issued a show cause notice to Sandhya theatre management regarding lapses that contributed to the stampede.</li><li>The incident occurred on December 4, 2024, when a large crowd gathered for the film's premiere, anticipating the arrival of lead actors.</li><li>A woman died due to suffocation in the crowd, despite prompt medical attention.</li><li>Police found multiple lapses in crowd management and safety measures at the theatre.</li><li>The management did not inform police of actor Allu Arjun's arrival, leading to a chaotic situation.</li><li>There was inadequate crowd control, with no separate entry for celebrities and insufficient security personnel present.</li><li>The theatre has a combined capacity of 2520 persons, with poor signage and crowd management policies.</li><li>Unused security measures, like a single metal detector, were in place, failing to screen the crowd effectively.</li><li>The police have registered a case against the management under several acts related to public safety.</li><li>The theatre management must respond to the show cause notice within 10 days to avoid further legal repercussions.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was clearly visible that the management has failed to provide a safe and secure environment to the public who is coming to the theatre.” - Hyderabad Police</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the critical need for improved safety measures and crowd management at public events to prevent tragedies in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/pushpa-2-stampede-hyderabad-police-find-11-lapses-in-sandhya-theatre-1847584</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/pushpa-2-stampede-hyderabad-police-find-11-lapses-in-sandhya-theatre-1847584</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:08:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bandish Bandits creator Anand Tiwari says Shankar-Ehsaan-Loy 'gave their blessings' for new composer in S2 | Exclusive - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anand Tiwari talks to HT about the new season of Bandish Bandits and how a non-musician directs a show seeped in music.</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Anand_Tiwari_1734255123380_1734255148870.jpg" alt="Bandish Bandits' Anand Tiwari speaks exclusively with HT" title="Bandish Bandits' Anand Tiwari speaks exclusively with HT"><figcaption>Bandish Bandits' Anand Tiwari speaks exclusively with HT</figcaption><p>The second season of the musical romantic drama <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/web-series/bandish-bandits-2-trailer-love-conflict-and-musical-legacy-take-center-stage-as-ritwik-bhowmik-shreya-chaudhry-return-101733123706212.html">Bandish Bandits</a> is out, nearly four years after the first season premiered. Director Anand Tiwari discusses the reasons behind the long wait and the shift in composers.</p><ul><li>The second season premiered on December 12, 2024.</li><li>Anand Tiwari reflects on the challenges of writing a music-centered show as a non-musician.</li><li>Shankar-Ehsaan-Loy, the original composers, are not involved in season 2, replaced with Akashdeep under their blessings.</li></ul><blockquote>“When we wrote season 1, we took 2.5 years to write, but in season 2, we only took 1.5 years. So we have actually done better.” - Anand Tiwari</blockquote><p>Bandish Bandits is currently available for streaming on <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/tamil-cinema/vettaiyan-ott-release-confirmed-on-amazon-prime-video-heres-when-you-can-watch-rajinikanth-amitabh-bachchan-movie-101730351328979.html">Amazon Prime Video</a>.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/web-series/bandish-bandits-creator-anand-tiwari-on-replacing-shankar-ehsaan-loy-in-season-2-ritwik-bhowmik-shreya-chaudhary-101734254864944.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/web-series/bandish-bandits-creator-anand-tiwari-on-replacing-shankar-ehsaan-loy-in-season-2-ritwik-bhowmik-shreya-chaudhary-101734254864944.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:05:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Shameless fellow’: Kapil Sharma finally reacts to accusations of being racist towards Atlee, leaves internet divided - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kapil Sharma Responds to Racism Accusations After Atlee Controversy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/Atlee_Kapil_Sharma_1734436194356_1734436210081.jpg' alt='Atlee graced Kapil Sharma's show last weekend'><figcaption>Atlee graced Kapil Sharma's show last weekend</figcaption><p>After facing backlash for allegedly insulting filmmaker Atlee on his show, Kapil Sharma has addressed the controversy, sparking mixed reactions online.</p><ul><li>Kapil welcomed the cast of <i>Baby John</i>, during which a segment led to accusations of racism against Atlee.</li><li>A clip surfaced where Kapil questioned Atlee about people not recognizing him due to his youth, which some interpreted as an insult.</li><li>Kapil responded to the backlash on Twitter, asking followers to not spread hate and to form their own opinions.</li><li>The internet has divided opinions, with some supporting Kapil while others criticize his comments.</li></ul><blockquote>“Don’t judge by appearance, judge by the heart.” - Atlee</blockquote><p>The controversy raises questions about the line between humor and offense in comedy, leaving audiences to debate whether Kapil's comments were misinterpreted.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/shameless-fellow-kapil-sharma-finally-reacts-to-accusations-of-being-racist-towards-atlee-leaves-internet-divided-101734435347833.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/shameless-fellow-kapil-sharma-finally-reacts-to-accusations-of-being-racist-towards-atlee-leaves-internet-divided-101734435347833.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:59:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan makes rare comment on viral photos of her smoking with Ranbir Kapoor: ‘Is my career over?' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan Reflects on Controversy Over Smoking Photos with Ranbir Kapoor</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> HT Entertainment Desk</p><p>Mahira Khan addressed the backlash she faced after viral photos of her smoking with actor Ranbir Kapoor in New York emerged in 2017, revealing emotional and professional struggles during that period.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Mahira described her journey, including significant life events like her divorce and motherhood.</li><li>She expressed her initial fears about the impact of the controversial photos on her career.</li><li>The actor shared insights into how the media coverage affected her mental health.</li><li>She made a successful debut in Bollywood with the film Raees opposite Shah Rukh Khan.</li></ul><blockquote>“Is my career over?” - Mahira Khan reflecting on the backlash she faced from the photos.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Mahira Khan's candid reflections show how public scrutiny can deeply affect personal and professional lives, and how resilience plays a key role in overcoming challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mahira-khan-makes-rare-comment-on-viral-photos-of-her-smoking-with-ranbir-kapoor-101734432697039.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mahira-khan-makes-rare-comment-on-viral-photos-of-her-smoking-with-ranbir-kapoor-101734432697039.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:58:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kapil Sharma BREAKS Silence About 'Insulting' Atlee: ‘Watch And Decide By Yourself…’ - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kapil Sharma BREAKS Silence About 'Insulting' Atlee: ‘Watch And Decide By Yourself…’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Kapil Sharma strongly reacts to accusations of him insulting Atlee." title="Kapil Sharma strongly reacts to accusations of him insulting Atlee."><figcaption>Kapil Sharma strongly reacts to accusations of him insulting Atlee.</figcaption><p>Kapil Sharma has responded to accusations of insulting filmmaker Atlee during an episode of 'The Great Indian Kapil Show'. He urged viewers to watch the segment and form their own opinions.</p><ul><li>Kapil was criticized for a question related to Atlee's appearance during the show.</li><li>After backlash, Kapil denied the accusations and asked not to spread hate.</li><li>Atlee's response emphasized judging by character rather than appearance.</li><li>The controversy arose from a post on social media that misinterpreted Kapil's intentions.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Dear sir, can you pls explain me where n when I talked about looks in this video? pls don’t spread hate on social media thank you. (guys watch n decide by yourself, don’t follow anybody’s tweet like a sheep).” — Kapil Sharma</p></blockquote><p>This incident highlights the sensitivity around comments made in the entertainment industry and how they can be perceived on social media.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/kapil-sharma-breaks-silence-about-insulting-atlee-watch-and-decide-by-yourself-9159106.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/kapil-sharma-breaks-silence-about-insulting-atlee-watch-and-decide-by-yourself-9159106.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:55:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Khanna Reacts As Sonakshi Sinha Bashes Him Brutally: 'I Had No Malicious Intention' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mukesh Khanna Responds to Sonakshi Sinha's Criticism: 'No Malicious Intention'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Mukesh Khanna says he had no intention to hurt Sonakshi Sinha. (Photos: Instagram)"><figcaption>Mukesh Khanna says he had no intention to hurt Sonakshi Sinha. (Photos: Instagram)</figcaption><p>Mukesh Khanna has reacted to criticism from Sonakshi Sinha regarding his remarks about her upbringing, stating he had no intention to offend either her or her father, Shatrughan Sinha.</p><ul><li>Sonakshi Sinha lashed out at Khanna on Instagram for his comments, which she found distasteful.</li><li>Khanna expressed surprise at the delay in her response, clarifying his comments were not meant to malign them.</li><li>He intended to use the incident as a teaching moment about cultural knowledge among the youth.</li></ul><blockquote>“I had no malicious intention to malign her or her father...” - Mukesh Khanna</blockquote><p>The controversy arose after Khanna referenced a KBC episode where Sonakshi was unable to answer a question related to Lord Hanuman, suggesting it reflected on her father's knowledge impartation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/mukesh-khanna-reacts-as-sonakshi-sinha-bashes-him-brutally-i-had-no-malicious-intention-9159371.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/mukesh-khanna-reacts-as-sonakshi-sinha-bashes-him-brutally-i-had-no-malicious-intention-9159371.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:37:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' box office collection Day 12: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna starrer races to Rs 1,500 crore - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-12-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-records-its-lowest-monday-with-rs-27-75-crore-collection/articleshow/116383147.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-12-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-records-its-lowest-monday-with-rs-27-75-crore-collection/articleshow/116383147.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shatrughan Slams Mukesh Khanna Over Sonakshi-Ramayan Row: 'Who Appointed Him Guardian Of Hindu?' | Viral - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shatrughan Sinha Criticizes Mukesh Khanna for Attacks on Daughter Sonakshi Regarding Ramayan</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Viral</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Mukesh Khanna had criticised Shatrughan Sinha's daughter Sonakshi Sinha." /><figcaption>Mukesh Khanna had criticised Shatrughan Sinha's daughter Sonakshi Sinha.</figcaption><p>In a recent conflict, Shatrughan Sinha vocally opposed Mukesh Khanna's repeated criticisms of his daughter Sonakshi over her memory lapse regarding the Ramayan during a game show.</p><ul><li>Sonakshi Sinha confronted Mukesh Khanna after he remarked on her forgetting a detail about Ramayan on Kaun Banega Crorepati.</li><li>Shatrughan Sinha questioned Mukesh Khanna's authority to judge and labeled him 'guardian of the Hindu religion'.</li><li>Shatrughan emphasized that forgetting a question about the Ramayan does not undermine Sonakshi's identity as a Hindu.</li></ul><blockquote>“Not answering a question on the Ramayan doesn’t disqualify Sonakshi from being a good Hindu.” - Shatrughan Sinha</blockquote><p>Shatrughan Sinha expressed pride in his children, affirming Sonakshi's accomplishments and dismissing the need for validation through religious trivia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/shatrughan-sinha-mukesh-khanna-sonakshi-sinha-ramayan-question-kbc-throwback-9158828.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/shatrughan-sinha-mukesh-khanna-sonakshi-sinha-ramayan-question-kbc-throwback-9158828.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:51:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 1000-crore club: ‘Baahubali’ to ‘Pushpa’, Telugu cinema’s box office juggernaut - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The 1000-crore club: ‘Baahubali’ to ‘Pushpa’, Telugu cinema’s box office juggernaut</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 17, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<div>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/td4sp2/article68995034.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/Baahubali%202.jpg" alt="Anushka Shetty and Prabhas in ‘Baahubali 2: The Conclusion’" width="100%" height="100%">
<figcaption>Anushka Shetty and Prabhas in ‘Baahubali 2: The Conclusion’ | Photo Credit: Special Arrangement</figcaption>
</div>
<p>The Telugu film industry is celebrating its latest achievement with <i>Pushpa 2: The Rule</i> crossing the ₹1,000-crore mark at the box office, becoming the fastest Indian film to do so within a week of release. This marks a significant milestone as it is the fourth Telugu film to reach this milestone.</p>
<ul>
<li><i>Pushpa 2: The Rule</i> breaks box office records, making ₹1,000 crores within days of its release.</li>
<li>It joins the ranks of other blockbusters like <i>Baahubali 2</i>, <i>RRR</i>, and <i>Kalki 2898 AD</i>.</li>
<li>The success highlights the potential of 'pan India cinema,' moving Telugu films into the mainstream.</li>
<li>Smart marketing strategies contributed significantly to the films' success, especially in creating interest among Hindi-speaking audiences.</li>
<li>The article explores historical successes of Telugu cinema, such as earlier hits and the evolution of audience tastes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The term ‘pan India cinema’ came into vogue, and a handful of Telugu, Kannada, Tamil and Malayalam movies eyed similar box office receptions.”</blockquote>
<p>The article concludes by discussing upcoming sequels and the trend of franchises in Telugu cinema, indicating a robust future for the industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/baahubali-to-pushpa-telugu-cinemas-box-office-juggernaut/article68976736.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/baahubali-to-pushpa-telugu-cinemas-box-office-juggernaut/article68976736.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan says she thought her career was over when her smoking photos with Ranbir Kapoor went viral: ' - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan Reflects on Viral Smoking Photos and Their Impact on Her Career</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a recent interview, actress Mahira Khan shared her thoughts on the backlash she faced after photos of her smoking with actor Ranbir Kapoor went viral, affecting both her professional and personal life.</p><ul><li>Mahira felt that her career was at risk due to the negative media coverage.</li><li>She discussed the emotional toll and public scrutiny that ensued following the incident.</li><li>The actress emphasized the importance of mental health in navigating such challenges.</li></ul><blockquote>“It affected my professional and personal life,” Mahira stated, underscoring the heavy burden of public opinion.</blockquote><p>The experience highlighted the intense scrutiny public figures face and the impact such incidents can have on their lives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mahira-khan-says-she-thought-her-career-was-over-when-her-smoking-photos-with-ranbir-kapoor-went-viral-it-affected-my-professional-and-personal-life/articleshow/116399247.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mahira-khan-says-she-thought-her-career-was-over-when-her-smoking-photos-with-ranbir-kapoor-went-viral-it-affected-my-professional-and-personal-life/articleshow/116399247.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[₹15,500 challan sent after Badshah’s carcade spotted on wrong side: Gurugram cop - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Badshah's Carcade Fined ₹15,500 for Traffic Violation in Gurugram</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/Rapper-and-singer-Badshah--AP-_1734429549975.jpg" alt="Rapper and singer Badshah (AP)" title="Rapper and singer Badshah (AP)">
<figcaption>Rapper and singer Badshah (AP)</figcaption>
<p>The Gurugram traffic police have issued a fine of ₹15,500 to one of the vehicles in rapper Badshah's carcade for driving on the wrong side to reach a concert.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The fine was imposed after a video of the violation surfaced on social media.</li>
  <li>One vehicle, a Thar, was ticketed, while attempts are being made to trace a Scorpio and a Mercedes to take similar action.</li>
  <li>Police reviewed CCTV footage to confirm the infringement.</li>
  <li>Deputy Commissioner of Police (Traffic), Virender Vij, stated the Thar is registered to a person from Panipat.</li>
  <li>Investigations are ongoing to determine the owners and drivers of the other two vehicles.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The overall online fine imposed against Hooda was ₹15,500 under three sections of the Motor Vehicle Act, including dangerous driving and wrong-side driving.” - Virender Vij</blockquote>
<p>The incident raises concerns about traffic regulations and the responsibilities of public figures in adhering to them.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/gurugram-news/15500-challan-sent-after-badshah-s-carcade-spotted-on-wrong-side-gurugram-cop-101734429553382.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/gurugram-news/15500-challan-sent-after-badshah-s-carcade-spotted-on-wrong-side-gurugram-cop-101734429553382.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:59:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>