<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 16:23:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 16:23:40 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madha Gaja Raja release date: Vishal film to hit screens on Pongal after a 12-year delay; internet finds it hilarious - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Madha Gaja Raja Release Date Announced After 12-Year Delay</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 03, 2025 | Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/Madha_Gaja_Raja_1735911167165_1735911173306.jpg" alt="Varalaxmi Sarathkumar, Vishal and Anjali in Madha Gaja Raja." title="Varalaxmi Sarathkumar, Vishal and Anjali in Madha Gaja Raja.">
<figcaption>Varalaxmi Sarathkumar, Vishal and Anjali in Madha Gaja Raja.</figcaption>
<p>After a long wait of 12 years, the film Madha Gaja Raja, directed by Sundar C and featuring Vishal, Varalaxmi Sarathkumar, and Anjali, is set to release on Pongal 2025.</p>
<ul>
<li>The film was initially supposed to release in 2013.</li>
<li>Delayed due to financial troubles faced by the producers.</li>
<li>It completed production in 2013 but remained unreleased for over a decade.</li>
<li>Director Sundar C expressed confidence in the film's entertainment value despite the long wait.</li>
<li>Madha Gaja Raja will compete with several other films at the box office.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In fact, Vishal and I also requested that we buy and release the film. Even though the film was made in 2013, I am sure it will be entertaining even if it gets released today.” - Sundar C</blockquote>
<p>The announcement has generated significant buzz and humor online, with many people sharing clips and memes relating to the film's long delay.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/tamil-cinema/madha-gaja-raja-release-date-vishal-film-to-release-on-pongal-after-a-12-year-delay-internet-finds-it-hilarious-101735910281567.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/tamil-cinema/madha-gaja-raja-release-date-vishal-film-to-release-on-pongal-after-a-12-year-delay-internet-finds-it-hilarious-101735910281567.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:31:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Actor-filmmaker Aparna Malladi passes away - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Actor-filmmaker Aparna Malladi passes away</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 3, 2025 7:37 pm IST</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Aparna-Malladi-1.jpg" alt="Aparna Malladi"><figcaption>Aparna Malladi</figcaption><p>Aparna Malladi, a renowned actor, filmmaker, and teacher, passed away in Los Angeles on January 2 after a long battle with cancer. She was 54 years old and had been undergoing treatment after relocating from India.</p><ul><li>Aparna was well-known for her YouTube series 'Posh Poris' and her feature films including 'The Anushree Experiments' and 'Pellikuturu Party.'</li><li>She battled cancer for four years, with a relapse occurring two years ago.</li><li>Aparna made significant contributions to Telugu independent cinema and mentored several young filmmakers.</li><li>Her last film, 'Pellikuturu Party,' was released in 2022.</li></ul><blockquote>“Aparna’s untimely passing has left her friends and students in grief.”</blockquote><p>This loss marks a significant moment in the Telugu cinema community, highlighting the impact of Aparna's work and dedication.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/actor-filmmaker-aparna-malladi-passes-away.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/actor-filmmaker-aparna-malladi-passes-away.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Kartik Aaryan set to start Anurag Basu’s next in January; Tu Meri Main Tera Main Tera Tu Meri begins in May - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kartik Aaryan's Upcoming Films: Anurag Basu's Next and Tu Meri Main Tera Tu Meri</h1><p><strong>Published on Jan 03, 2025 | Source: Pinkvilla</strong></p><img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/1065925802_kartik-aaryan-line-up-main-2026.jpg" alt="Kartik Aaryan's Upcoming Films" title="Kartik Aaryan's Upcoming Films"><figcaption>Kartik Aaryan set to start Anurag Basu’s next in January; Tu Meri Main Tera begins in May</figcaption><p>Kartik Aaryan is gearing up for two major film projects in 2025, directed by Anurag Basu and produced by Karan Johar. Both films are set to release in 2026.</p><ul><li>Kartik will start shooting for Anurag Basu's untitled romantic film in January 2025, with a three-month schedule planned.</li><li>The casting is underway, and a fresh face may be introduced in the film.</li><li>After completing Basu's film, Kartik will move on to Tu Meri Main Tera Main Tera Tu Meri, an adventure romantic comedy starting in May 2025.</li><li>Both films represent different aspects of romance, from intense love stories to light-hearted comedies.</li></ul><blockquote>“The film is a collaboration of Dharma Production and Namah Pictures and is ready to roll from May 2025.”</blockquote><p>This year marks an exciting chapter for Kartik Aaryan as he explores various themes in romance across these two upcoming projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-kartik-aaryan-set-to-start-anurag-basus-next-in-january-tu-meri-main-tera-main-tera-tu-meri-begins-in-may-1365476</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-kartik-aaryan-set-to-start-anurag-basus-next-in-january-tu-meri-main-tera-main-tera-tu-meri-begins-in-may-1365476</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 13:15:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Actor Allu Arjun granted conditional bail in Sandhya theatre’s Pushpa stampede case - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Actor Allu Arjun granted conditional bail in Sandhya theatre’s Pushpa stampede case</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 03, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/f9vytb/article69057661.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/image%206.jpeg" alt="Actor Allu Arjun was arrested on December 13 after a case of culpable homicide not amounting to murder was booked against him." title="Actor Allu Arjun was arrested on December 13 after a case of culpable homicide not amounting to murder was booked against him."/><figcaption>Photo Credit: NAGARA GOPAL</figcaption><p>Actor Allu Arjun was granted conditional bail by the Nampally court of Hyderabad in connection with the ongoing investigation into the Sandhya 70 MM theatre stampede case, which resulted in one death during a screening of Pushpa 2.</p><ul><li>Arjun was arrested on December 13, 2024, under charges of culpable homicide.</li><li>The court required the actor to submit two sureties of ₹50,000 each.</li><li>Conditions of the bail include visiting the local police station every Sunday for two months.</li><li>The proceedings regarding his judicial remand are adjourned until January 10.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Hyderabad/pushpa-2-stampede-actor-allu-arjun-granted-conditional-bail/article69057602.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Hyderabad/pushpa-2-stampede-actor-allu-arjun-granted-conditional-bail/article69057602.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 stampede case: Actor Allu Arjun gets regular bail - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Stampede Case: Actor Allu Arjun Granted Regular Bail</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Actor Allu Arjun has been granted regular bail in connection with the stampede case associated with his film Pushpa 2, shedding light on the recent tragic events during the film's promotional activities.</p><ul><li>Allu Arjun's involvement in the stampede case stemming from a promotional event for Pushpa 2.</li><li>The court's decision to grant him bail after considering the circumstances surrounding the case.</li><li>Details of the stampede, including the number of casualties and injuries caused.</li><li>The impact of the stampede on the film's promotional strategy and public perception.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are relieved that justice has been served, and we hope to learn from this incident to ensure safety at future events." - A spokesperson for Allu Arjun.</blockquote><p>This case highlights the importance of safety measures at large public events, especially in the entertainment industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pushpa-2-stampede-case-actor-allu-arjun-gets-regular-bail/articleshow/116917243.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pushpa-2-stampede-case-actor-allu-arjun-gets-regular-bail/articleshow/116917243.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Key Box Office Records in Hindi: Pushpa 2 tops all charts, followed by Shah Rukh Khan and Stree 2 - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Key Box Office Records in Hindi: Pushpa 2 tops all charts, followed by Shah Rukh Khan and Stree 2</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 03, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p>
<img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/333656734_pushpa-5.jpg" alt="Key Box Office Records in Hindi: Pushpa 2 sweeps the record books, followed by Shah Rukh Khan and Stree 2" title="Key Box Office Records in Hindi: Pushpa 2 sweeps the record books, followed by Shah Rukh Khan and Stree 2">
<figcaption>Key Box Office Records in Hindi</figcaption>
<p>Pushpa 2 has set new records at the box office, becoming the highest-grossing Hindi film in numerous categories, a first since Bahubali 2 in 2017.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pushpa 2 is projected to gross between Rs 750 to Rs 775 crore.</li>
  <li>It has achieved records for the biggest opening day, single day collection, and overall lifetime gross among others.</li>
  <li>The film surpasses other major releases from the last two years like Shah Rukh Khan's Pathaan and Jawan.</li>
  <li>Allu Arjun is emerging as a significant star in the Hindi market following Pushpa's success.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Pushpa 2 has done the unthinkable by having a clean sweep in terms of record."</blockquote>
<p>As the film continues its run, it sets a high benchmark for future Hindi films.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/key-box-office-records-in-hindi-pushpa-2-sweeps-the-record-books-followed-by-shah-rukh-khan-and-stree-2-1365461</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/key-box-office-records-in-hindi-pushpa-2-sweeps-the-record-books-followed-by-shah-rukh-khan-and-stree-2-1365461</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:07:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Key Box Office Records in Hindi: Pushpa 2 sweeps the record books, followed by Shah Rukh Khan and Stree 2 - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Key Box Office Records in Hindi: Pushpa 2 tops all charts, followed by Shah Rukh Khan and Stree 2</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 03, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p>
<img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/333656734_pushpa-5.jpg" alt="Key Box Office Records in Hindi: Pushpa 2 sweeps the record books, followed by Shah Rukh Khan and Stree 2" title="Key Box Office Records in Hindi: Pushpa 2 sweeps the record books, followed by Shah Rukh Khan and Stree 2">
<figcaption>Key Box Office Records in Hindi</figcaption>
<p>Pushpa 2 has set new records at the box office, becoming the highest-grossing Hindi film in numerous categories, a first since Bahubali 2 in 2017.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pushpa 2 is projected to gross between Rs 750 to Rs 775 crore.</li>
  <li>It has achieved records for the biggest opening day, single day collection, and overall lifetime gross among others.</li>
  <li>The film surpasses other major releases from the last two years like Shah Rukh Khan's Pathaan and Jawan.</li>
  <li>Allu Arjun is emerging as a significant star in the Hindi market following Pushpa's success.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Pushpa 2 has done the unthinkable by having a clean sweep in terms of record."</blockquote>
<p>As the film continues its run, it sets a high benchmark for future Hindi films.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/key-box-office-records-in-hindi-pushpa-2-sweeps-the-record-books-followed-by-shah-rukh-khan-and-stree-2-1365461</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/key-box-office-records-in-hindi-pushpa-2-sweeps-the-record-books-followed-by-shah-rukh-khan-and-stree-2-1365461</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:07:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' Actor Allu Arjun Gets Regular Bail In Theatre Stampede Case - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun Granted Regular Bail in Theatre Stampede Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Actor Allu Arjun was granted regular bail by a local court in connection with a tragic stampede incident during the premiere of 'Pushpa 2'.</p><ul><li>Allu Arjun was arrested following the December 4 stampede at the Sandhya 70MM theatre in Hyderabad.</li><li>The incident resulted in the death of a 35-year-old woman and the hospitalization of her 9-year-old son due to asphyxiation.</li><li>The stampede occurred as fans rushed to see Allu Arjun and music director Devi Sri Prasad.</li><li>Hyderabad Police filed charges against Allu Arjun and his security team under various sections of the law.</li></ul><blockquote>A 35-year-old woman died and her nine-year-old son was hospitalized due to asphyxiation after a huge crowd jostled.</blockquote><p>This incident has raised discussions on crowd management and safety protocols during high-profile events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pushpa-2-actor-allu-arjun-gets-regular-bail-in-theatre-stampede-case-7391840</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pushpa-2-actor-allu-arjun-gets-regular-bail-in-theatre-stampede-case-7391840</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 11:58:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anurag Kashyap has misunderstood my statement: Shankar on claims of reel-lifying Game Changer - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Shankar Responds to Anurag Kashyap's Misunderstanding About Game Changer</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 03, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/6qxsd0/article69045749.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/80687_1_8_2024_19_5_29_5_31.JPG" alt="Game Changer Film Image"><figcaption>Game Changer Film Image</figcaption><p>Filmmaker Shankar clarifies that Anurag Kashyap misunderstood his comments about the upcoming film, Game Changer, which is aimed at engaging the audience effectively.</p><ul><li>Anurag Kashyap criticized Shankar's filmmaking approach, claiming it caters to short attention spans fostered by social media.</li><li>Shankar emphasized that he did not mention Instagram reels but highlighted the need for films to be engaging.</li><li>The upcoming Telugu film stars Ram Charan and is set to release on January 10.</li></ul><blockquote>“I didn’t say anything about Instagram reels. We should convey things quickly and effectively.” - Shankar</blockquote><p>The discussion reflects a broader concern regarding audience engagement in cinema and the impact of social media on viewing habits.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/anurag-kashyap-has-misunderstood-my-statement-shankar-on-claims-of-reel-lifying-game-changer/article69057407.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/anurag-kashyap-has-misunderstood-my-statement-shankar-on-claims-of-reel-lifying-game-changer/article69057407.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 11:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anthropic reaches deal with music publishers over lyric dispute - The Verge]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/3/24334866/anthropic-claude-music-publishers-lyric-copyright-lawsuit-deal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/3/24334866/anthropic-claude-music-publishers-lyric-copyright-lawsuit-deal</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 11:22:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jennifer Garner's boyfriend, John Miller, concerned about Ben Affleck's ‘constant presence’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jennifer Garner's Boyfriend Concerned About Ben Affleck's Constant Presence</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 03, 2025<strong> | Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/jennifer-garner-ben-affleck-c232a2398ae842d7a50801_1694922857283_1735902111715.jpg" alt="Despite their divorce, Ben Affleck and Jennifer Garner remain supportive co-parents, which worries Garner's boyfriend, John Miller.(ASON MERRITT/GETTY)" title="Despite their divorce, Ben Affleck and Jennifer Garner remain supportive co-parents, which worries Garner's boyfriend, John Miller.(ASON MERRITT/GETTY)"><figcaption>Despite their divorce, Ben Affleck and Jennifer Garner remain supportive co-parents, which worries Garner's boyfriend, John Miller.(ASON MERRITT/GETTY)</figcaption><p>Garner's boyfriend, John Miller, is reportedly worried about the boundaries between Affleck and Garner as they maintain a close friendship post-divorce.</p><ul><li>Despite their divorce, Affleck and Garner continue to support each other, especially during Affleck's recent troubles with Lopez.</li><li>Miller has expressed concerns about Affleck's frequent presence, feeling like a third wheel in his relationship with Garner.</li><li>Sources indicate that while Garner prioritizes her children, Miller is starting to doubt the boundaries that can be maintained with Affleck.</li><li>While tensions exist, some believe that Affleck and Garner's bond has improved over time.</li><li>Miller is described as the opposite of Affleck, which contributes to differing dynamics in his relationship with Garner.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ben’s constant presence is very hard to take; John’s like the third wheel in his own relationship.”</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the complexities of balancing co-parenting and romantic relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jennifer-garners-boyfriend-john-miller-concerned-about-ben-afflecks-constant-presence-101735901532324.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jennifer-garners-boyfriend-john-miller-concerned-about-ben-afflecks-constant-presence-101735901532324.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 11:04:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Baldoni accuses Blake Lively and Ryan Reynolds of sabotaging his career and excluding him from 'It - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/english/hollywood/news/justin-baldoni-sues-blake-lively-and-ryan-reynolds-accusing-them-of-sabotaging-his-career-and-excluding-him-from-it-ends-with-us-premiere/articleshow/116882518.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/english/hollywood/news/justin-baldoni-sues-blake-lively-and-ryan-reynolds-accusing-them-of-sabotaging-his-career-and-excluding-him-from-it-ends-with-us-premiere/articleshow/116882518.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why are fans furious over Ajith’s ‘Vidaamuyarchi’? | Explained - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/why-are-fans-furious-over-ajiths-vidaamuyarchi-explained/article69057000.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/why-are-fans-furious-over-ajiths-vidaamuyarchi-explained/article69057000.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘A Parsi, a Muslim, a Sikh, a Hindu’: Amitabh Bachchan pays tribute to Indian icons in heaven with sweet post - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amitabh Bachchan Pays Tribute to Indian Icons</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 03, 2025 <br> <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/amitabh_bachchan_1735900505787_1735900506076.jpg" alt="Amitabh Bachchan took to Instagram to express his views." title="Amitabh Bachchan took to Instagram to express his views."><figcaption>Amitabh Bachchan took to Instagram to express his views.</figcaption></figure><p>Amitabh Bachchan honors the memory of significant Indian figures lost in 2024 through a heartfelt portrayal by cartoonist Satish Acharya.</p><ul><li>Bachchan shared a post on social media remembering icons like Ratan Tata, Zakir Hussain, Manmohan Singh, and Shyam Benegal.</li><li>The artwork depicts them enjoying their passions in the afterlife, emphasizing unity among different communities.</li><li>The caption read: “A Parsi, a Muslim, a Sikh, and a Hindu passed away in 2024 and the whole nation mourned and remembered them only as Indians.”</li></ul><blockquote>The picture says it all.</blockquote><p>This tribute underscores the importance of unity and remembrance of those who contributed greatly to society.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/a-parsi-a-muslim-a-sikh-a-hindu-amitabh-bachchan-pays-tribute-to-indian-icons-in-heaven-with-sweet-post-101735897322284.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/a-parsi-a-muslim-a-sikh-a-hindu-amitabh-bachchan-pays-tribute-to-indian-icons-in-heaven-with-sweet-post-101735897322284.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:35:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here is the list of OTT movies and series releasing this week - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxNbUd1a256NEoxRkU3NlRrR2djRUlUY2JWSklGZ0NKN1dhak1iZzR5WjhJa2tNNmFYSVk4dmlaTzJHRVlHb2JIZWNLRGhGVFpJckliYW9LWHZFMUtpcEZBbXhicHVsTWhjbUliSmFFNFlUb0lwVzA1a2FYaFB3Q3Y1V19lanBJcmJnWUFDZmFsZWVHQ2F6N1FFV0h6RXRleVdlOXo40gGoAUFVX3lxTFBnVzlFSVdFY2hyd1YyaUpOTERCZ2s5TkowUkpWUnQ5b2FWc2RWbU5pcTdLUVNYNmJJb1Vsak1NZjR1cVVCRlVlRUEySFZ1dGNkQ3NyRkJLd3llcktXQVR6bnNSbTlCYnV4QUthT19reFdOQjJ3QVUxRXI1SDZ3d0ZHdWU1bndLRXp0NWE1QjVGTTVDV0JEeW9Oc1F1NWZxWFNqcVdUVzJ6Zg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxNbUd1a256NEoxRkU3NlRrR2djRUlUY2JWSklGZ0NKN1dhak1iZzR5WjhJa2tNNmFYSVk4dmlaTzJHRVlHb2JIZWNLRGhGVFpJckliYW9LWHZFMUtpcEZBbXhicHVsTWhjbUliSmFFNFlUb0lwVzA1a2FYaFB3Q3Y1V19lanBJcmJnWUFDZmFsZWVHQ2F6N1FFV0h6RXRleVdlOXo40gGoAUFVX3lxTFBnVzlFSVdFY2hyd1YyaUpOTERCZ2s5TkowUkpWUnQ5b2FWc2RWbU5pcTdLUVNYNmJJb1Vsak1NZjR1cVVCRlVlRUEySFZ1dGNkQ3NyRkJLd3llcktXQVR6bnNSbTlCYnV4QUthT19reFdOQjJ3QVUxRXI1SDZ3d0ZHdWU1bndLRXp0NWE1QjVGTTVDV0JEeW9Oc1F1NWZxWFNqcVdUVzJ6Zg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sundar C-Vishal's Madha Gaja Raja finally gets a release date after 13-year delay - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxOc0ZoeTdSSkdwMVhEZ2ZrWEVqQXNMazNhVy1lc0VLS2RudnpXXzhITHZ5OHhBbVV5LVlBNl93b2RZenJzMURTR2dDelhJNVUxTmJhaHBOTmxmeG1RY0pGOWhMcGp3d2M5UlNubFhSNG1TNW9YeTY5UHdTQ082aU5uSVlsS2M5VFJVUDQwQ1RoV0hJYnpWeDcyOUZDc3VGZHBfcFlMZnZuNDZFUjQ3dlF4clNCYUpob0tUVlVLYzlCdU1YeU5aVHFxNkdleG1aS3YxRWdRT0RXS0dadU1BR2xzQTBWQ2NyeW_SAewBQVVfeXFMTXJ2N3RmN0JVay1nWFBlTE11bmc1aW1TeUVJeVJaYUNTLW9WTTFaLTdvTElSOEdGa0lhOE9Gd1lZZTNiTVVsZkpMNEFUM2tZb3NoRjdqNHZ5eHoxTmlzZ1lCNGdTbmExczN4WGZfODM5Q0xMb242b3N5NDU3OGI1cDlfczZTQWY4WW53M2RaSS02b0JYZW0zOS1wUjJBV1Z3WnlOREJDZlF5ZmhjMElzaF8zNjlUbnRJbW5IeTV1enNJb0gydlVwS09uaFhjcnJHRGdpMFYyX0tUZjQ1ZE5wM2RGbEs2bUVVYm9uTXM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxOc0ZoeTdSSkdwMVhEZ2ZrWEVqQXNMazNhVy1lc0VLS2RudnpXXzhITHZ5OHhBbVV5LVlBNl93b2RZenJzMURTR2dDelhJNVUxTmJhaHBOTmxmeG1RY0pGOWhMcGp3d2M5UlNubFhSNG1TNW9YeTY5UHdTQ082aU5uSVlsS2M5VFJVUDQwQ1RoV0hJYnpWeDcyOUZDc3VGZHBfcFlMZnZuNDZFUjQ3dlF4clNCYUpob0tUVlVLYzlCdU1YeU5aVHFxNkdleG1aS3YxRWdRT0RXS0dadU1BR2xzQTBWQ2NyeW_SAewBQVVfeXFMTXJ2N3RmN0JVay1nWFBlTE11bmc1aW1TeUVJeVJaYUNTLW9WTTFaLTdvTElSOEdGa0lhOE9Gd1lZZTNiTVVsZkpMNEFUM2tZb3NoRjdqNHZ5eHoxTmlzZ1lCNGdTbmExczN4WGZfODM5Q0xMb242b3N5NDU3OGI1cDlfczZTQWY4WW53M2RaSS02b0JYZW0zOS1wUjJBV1Z3WnlOREJDZlF5ZmhjMElzaF8zNjlUbnRJbW5IeTV1enNJb0gydlVwS09uaFhjcnJHRGdpMFYyX0tUZjQ1ZE5wM2RGbEs2bUVVYm9uTXM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:14:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max (Kannada) Box Office Collection Day 10 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxPUVg5cnVTellpYUdBamlodGxkb1hpV3BTT0tjQ3VmU1NwSmh3OUVPdmJXeEdXWU02ZEdJNE8xUE9aNzBTOHRVTlVYU2xPMEx3RExOYXZyUEtQYkY1TlFSenotMHRQWFF2TUFsbGY2TlBfOFFQYjd5T3l0RWRxTWpERERiWE9Cdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxPUVg5cnVTellpYUdBamlodGxkb1hpV3BTT0tjQ3VmU1NwSmh3OUVPdmJXeEdXWU02ZEdJNE8xUE9aNzBTOHRVTlVYU2xPMEx3RExOYXZyUEtQYkY1TlFSenotMHRQWFF2TUFsbGY2TlBfOFFQYjd5T3l0RWRxTWpERERiWE9Cdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 09:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vishwambhara : Did the makers replace a key team? - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vishwambhara: Did the makers replace a key team?</h1><p><strong>Published on Jan 3, 2025 3:00 pm IST</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Vishwambhara-2.jpg" alt="Vishwambhara Movie Poster" width="280" height="476"><figcaption>Vishwambhara Movie Poster</figcaption><p>Megastar Chiranjeevi’s upcoming film, "Vishwambhara," has been postponed ahead of its January 10, 2025 release date, causing a stir among fans.</p><ul><li>The film has replaced its original CG team following negative feedback from a prior teaser.</li><li>Fans are hopeful that this change will lead to a more successful outcome for the film.</li><li>The film is directed by Vassishta Mallidi and produced by UV Creations.</li><li>Music for the movie is composed by MM Keeravani.</li><li>The cast includes Trisha Krishnan, Ashika Ranganath, Kunal Kapoor, and others.</li></ul><blockquote>"If this turns out to be true, it will be welcomed news for Chiranjeevi’s fans, who are eager for the movie to become a massive hit."</blockquote><p>As awaiting further updates on the film's release and developments continues, fans remain excited about its potential.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/vishwambhara-did-the-makers-replace-a-key-team.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/vishwambhara-did-the-makers-replace-a-key-team.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 09:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vishwambhara : Did the makers replace a key team? | Latest Telugu cinema news | Movie reviews | OTT Updates, OTT - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vishwambhara: Did the Makers Replace a Key Team?</h1><p><strong>Published on Jan 3, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: 123telugu</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Vishwambhara-2.jpg" alt="Vishwambhara" width="280" height="476"><figcaption>Vishwambhara movie promotional image.</figcaption><p>The upcoming movie Vishwambhara, featuring Megastar Chiranjeevi, has seen its release date postponed to avoid clashing with Ram Charan's Game Changer. There are rumors that the original CG team has been replaced after a negative reception of the teaser.</p><ul><li>The film was initially set to release on January 10, 2025.</li><li>Director Vassishta Mallidi leads the high-budget project under UV Creations.</li><li>Academy Award-winning composer MM Keeravani is aboard for the film's music.</li><li>Prominent cast members include Trisha Krishnan and Kunal Kapoor.</li></ul><blockquote>“If this turns out to be true, it will be welcomed news for Chiranjeevi’s fans, eager for the movie to succeed.”</blockquote><p>Stay tuned for further updates on the release date and more details about Vishwambhara.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/vishwambhara-did-the-makers-replace-a-key-team.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/vishwambhara-did-the-makers-replace-a-key-team.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 09:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Did Siddhant Chaturvedi, Ishaan Khatter, and Vedang Raina just hint at a Zindagi Na Milegi Dobara sequel? Fans think yes - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Did Siddhant Chaturvedi, Ishaan Khatter and Vedang Raina hint about Zindagi Na Milegi Dobara 2?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 03, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/ddjdjd_1735895624235_1735895632686.jpeg" alt="Siddhant Chaturvedi, Ishaan Khatter and Vedang Raina"><figcaption>Siddhant Chaturvedi, Ishaan Khatter and Vedang Raina</figcaption><p>This New Year, Siddhant Chaturvedi, Ishaan Khatter, and Vedang Raina's Instagram posts from a Goa road trip have ignited speculation about a possible sequel to the iconic film Zindagi Na Milegi Dobara, stirring excitement among fans.</p><ul><li>Fans reacted strongly to the trio's social media posts, which featured vintage shots from their trip.</li><li>Comments quickly began linking their getaway to Zindagi Na Milegi Dobara and Dil Chahta Hai, suggesting possible sequels.</li><li>Fans eagerly awaited a confirmation and tagged director Zoya Akhtar in hopes of clarification.</li></ul><blockquote>“ZNMD 2???? 😭🙏🏻🛐,” said one user, expressing hope for a sequel.</blockquote><p>While the hints may not be official, the buzz they’ve created among their fans showcases their growing popularity and the enduring love for the original films.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/siddhant-chaturvedi-ishan-khatter-and-vedang-raina-just-hint-at-a-zindagi-na-milegi-dobara-sequel-or-dil-chahta-hai-2-101735894431286.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/siddhant-chaturvedi-ishan-khatter-and-vedang-raina-just-hint-at-a-zindagi-na-milegi-dobara-sequel-or-dil-chahta-hai-2-101735894431286.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 09:21:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Paatal Lok' 2 teaser OUT; Jaideep Ahlawat's returns as inspector Hathi Ram Chaudhary, ready to confront - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Paatal Lok' 2 Teaser OUT; Jaideep Ahlawat's Returns as Inspector Hathi Ram Chaudhary, Ready to Confront New Societal Evils</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116911366,imgsize-26546,width-400,resizemode-4/116911366.jpg" alt="'Paatal Lok' 2 teaser poster" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>'Paatal Lok' Season 2 teaser poster</figcaption>
<p>Paatal Lok is returning to Prime Video, and the first teaser has been released on social media, generating excitement among fans.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Inspector Hathi Ram Chaudhary, played by Jaideep Ahlawat, faces a new case.</li>
  <li>Season 2 will also see Ishwak Singh returning as Imran Ansari.</li>
  <li>New cast members include Tillotama Shome and Gul Panag.</li>
  <li>The series is produced by Clean Slate Filmz and Eunoia Films LLP.</li>
  <li>Directed by Avinash Arun Dhaware, the eight-episode series will be available on Prime Video starting January 17, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The overwhelming response to the first season inspired me to craft stories that are raw, relatable, and intensely gripping.” - Sudip Sharma</blockquote>
<p>With its acclaimed first season, 'Paatal Lok' sets the stage for more gripping storytelling centered around crime and societal issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/web-series/news/hindi/paatal-lok-2-teaser-out-jaideep-ahlawats-returns-as-inspector-hathi-ram-chaudhary-ready-to-confront-new-societal-evils/articleshow/116911366.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/web-series/news/hindi/paatal-lok-2-teaser-out-jaideep-ahlawats-returns-as-inspector-hathi-ram-chaudhary-ready-to-confront-new-societal-evils/articleshow/116911366.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 09:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abhijeet Bhattacharya mocks AR Rahman’s ‘unsystematic’ way of working: ‘Recording at 3:33 am in the name of creativity…’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Abhijeet Bhattacharya mocks AR Rahman’s ‘unsystematic’ way of working: ‘Recording at 3:33 am in the name of creativity…’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023<br /><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/ar-rahman-abhijeet-bhattacharya.jpg?w=640" alt="AR Rahman Abhijeet Bhattacharya" width="640" height="356"><figcaption>AR Rahman and Abhijeet Bhattacharya collaborated only once.</figcaption><p>Controversial singer Abhijeet Bhattacharya shared his negative experience working with Oscar-winning composer AR Rahman, criticizing his unconventional working hours and studio practices.</p><ul><li>The collaboration between Bhattacharya and Rahman occurred only once on the song “Ae Nazneen Suno Na.”</li><li>Abhijeet described delays and Rahman's absence during the recording sessions.</li><li>He highlighted Rahman’s preference for late-night recording sessions, which he believed was unprofessional.</li><li>Abhijeet emphasized his own systematic approach to work and expressed frustration at the irregular schedule.</li><li>Despite the challenges, he acknowledged the talent of Rahman, crediting him for the song.</li></ul><blockquote>“In the name of creativity, if you say that you will record at 3:33 am, I don’t get it.” - Abhijeet Bhattacharya</blockquote><p>Abhijeet's remarks shed light on the different working styles in the music industry, especially between established artists.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/abhijeet-bhattacharya-mocks-ar-rahman-unsystematic-way-of-working-9758138/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/abhijeet-bhattacharya-mocks-ar-rahman-unsystematic-way-of-working-9758138/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 08:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Loveyapa title track: Junaid Khan and Khushi Kapoor bring 2025's first bad song; internet cringes hard - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Loveyapa Title Track: Junaid Khan and Khushi Kapoor's First Bad Song Cringes the Internet</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 03, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/loveyapa_junaid_khan_khushi_kapoor_1735891635280_1735891642427.png" alt="Loveyapa title track: Junaid Khan and Khushi Kapoor are caught up in a bad romance." title="Loveyapa title track: Junaid Khan and Khushi Kapoor are caught up in a bad romance."><figcaption>Loveyapa title track: Junaid Khan and Khushi Kapoor are caught up in a bad romance.</figcaption></figure><p>The title track of Junaid Khan and Khushi Kapoor’s movie Loveyapa has been released, but it has not made the lasting impact that fans hoped for.</p><ul><li>The title track promises to be quirky and upbeat.</li><li>The song was posted on Instagram, aimed at resonating with Gen-Z audiences.</li><li>Negative reactions include users calling the song "cringe" and questioning its quality.</li><li>The film, directed by Advait Chandan, is set to release in cinemas on February 7, 2025.</li><li>The film is a romantic drama and is said to be a remake of the Tamil film Love Today.</li></ul><blockquote>“Omg is this a real song,” commented one user. “What is this cringe,” remarked another.</blockquote><p>The underwhelming reception of the song leaves fans questioning whether the film will fare better.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/loveyapa-title-track-junaid-khan-and-khushi-kapoor-bring-2025s-first-bad-song-internet-cringes-hard-101735891005259.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/loveyapa-title-track-junaid-khan-and-khushi-kapoor-bring-2025s-first-bad-song-internet-cringes-hard-101735891005259.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 08:11:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sikandar EXCLUSIVE: Salman Khan was involved while working on teaser, says BGM composer Santhosh Narayanan; 'trying to elevate the phenomenon of...' - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sikandar's BGM Composer Santhosh Narayanan Discusses Salman Khan's Involvement in Teaser</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 03, 2025 &nbsp;|&nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p><div><img src='https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/2020533892_santhosh-narayanan-salman-khan.jpg' alt='Santhosh Narayanan and Salman Khan' title='Picture Courtesy: Santhosh Narayanan/Salman Khan/Instagram' /><figcaption>Picture Courtesy: Santhosh Narayanan/Salman Khan/Instagram</figcaption></div><p>In an exclusive conversation, Sikandar's BGM composer, Santhosh Narayanan, shares insights about the film's teaser and music, highlighting Salman Khan's involvement in the project.</p><ul><li>Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser released on December 28, 2024, receiving an enthusiastic response.</li><li>Santhosh Narayanan emphasized the importance of enhancing Salman Khan's personality in mass scenes.</li><li>The composer admires Salman Khan and aimed to blend modern electronic sounds with acoustic elements.</li><li>Santhosh noted that Salman appreciated the teaser music, stating it sounded different.</li><li>Sikandar is an upcoming action thriller featuring Rashmika Mandanna, directed by AR Murugadoss and produced by Sajid Nadiadwala, set for an Eid 2025 release.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am working to emote the story with an honest effort and also trying to elevate the phenomenon of Salman sir’s personality too in some ‘mass’ scenes.” - Santhosh Narayanan</blockquote><p>The collaboration between Santhosh Narayanan and Salman Khan is positioned as a pivotal factor in setting expectations for the film's upcoming release.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/sikandar-exclusive-salman-khan-was-involved-while-working-on-teaser-says-bgm-composer-santhosh-narayanan-trying-to-elevate-the-phenomenon-of-1365411</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/sikandar-exclusive-salman-khan-was-involved-while-working-on-teaser-says-bgm-composer-santhosh-narayanan-trying-to-elevate-the-phenomenon-of-1365411</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 08:05:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gaurav Taneja stuns Shark Tank India judges with claims that he made sales worth Rs 1 crore in an hour, Aman Gupta says, ‘That’s a dream’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gaurav Taneja stuns Shark Tank India judges with claims that he made sales worth Rs 1 crore in an hour, Aman Gupta says, ‘That’s a dream’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/gaurav-taneja-shark-tank.jpg?w=640" alt="Gaurav Taneja on Shark Tank India" width="640" height="356"><figcaption>Gaurav Taneja will appear on the fourth season of Shark Tank India.</figcaption><p>Shark Tank India is set to return for a fourth season on Monday, showcasing various entrepreneurs pitching their businesses to the panel of judges. Gaurav Taneja, a popular YouTuber, aims to impress with his whey protein brand and claims impressive sales figures.</p><ul><li>Gaurav Taneja's partner claims sales of Rs 1 crore in just one hour.</li><li>Aman Gupta expressed disbelief: “That is a dream for a lot of businesses.”</li><li>The season features new judges and exciting pitches from entrepreneurs across age groups.</li><li>Some valuations presented were astonishing, leading to shock among judges.</li><li>Bidding wars occurred, with Kunal Bahl proposing significant funding offers.</li></ul><blockquote>“Startup founders in our country have a certain impression, and you people are shattering it.” - Kunal Bahl</blockquote><p>The latest season promises intense competition and innovation among India's entrepreneurs, with Taneja's remarkable pitch setting the tone for what’s to come.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/television/gaurav-taneja-stuns-shark-tank-india-judges-sales-worth-rs-1-crore-in-an-hour-9757743/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/television/gaurav-taneja-stuns-shark-tank-india-judges-sales-worth-rs-1-crore-in-an-hour-9757743/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 07:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jhanak loses her memory and arrives in Gujarat, meeting Vihaan and his son - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jhanak Loses Her Memory and Meets Vihaan in Gujarat</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Friday, January 3, 2025 at 7:37 AM</p><figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/9923-jhanak-loses-her-memory-and-arrives-in-gujarat-meeting-vihaan-and-his-son.jpg" alt="Jhanak loses her memory and arrives in Gujarat, meeting Vihaan and his son" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Hiba Nawab as Jhanak from the show Jhanak. Image Courtesy: Star Plus</figcaption></figure><p>In the latest episode of <a href="https://www.indiaforums.com/show/jhanak_7098" title="Jhanak">Jhanak</a>, Jhanak faces a traumatic experience as she escapes from being kidnapped. After a perilous journey, she finds herself unconscious in a truck, where she is discovered by a crowd in Gujarat. Doctor Vihaan steps in to help her regain consciousness.</p><ul><li>Jhanak is kidnapped by Kulbhushan and his men.</li><li>She escapes from captivity and finds herself hiding in a truck.</li><li>Vihaan, a doctor, helps revive Jhanak when she is discovered by a crowd.</li><li>Jhanak struggles to remember her name and past.</li><li>Vihaan's friend, Akshay, is trying to console a crying baby, Ahaan.</li><li>Jhanak comforts the baby, impressing those around her.</li><li>Vihaan explains the situation regarding the baby's mother.</li><li>Jhanak is invited to a meal by Vihaan's friend after her recovery.</li></ul><blockquote>“Take your time and rest. We’ll get you some milk to regain strength.” - Vihaan</blockquote><p>The episode highlights themes of recovery and compassion as Jhanak navigates her memory loss and forms new bonds in a challenging situation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/jhanak-loses-her-memory-and-arrives-in-gujarat-meeting-vihaan-and-his-son_216310</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/jhanak-loses-her-memory-and-arrives-in-gujarat-meeting-vihaan-and-his-son_216310</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 07:41:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paatal Lok season 2 teaser out: Jaideep Ahlawat brings a new lore as Hathiram faces new demons from hell - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Paatal Lok Season 2 Teaser Out: Jaideep Ahlawat Brings a New Lore as Hathiram Faces New Demons from Hell</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 03, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/paatal_lok_season_2_teaser_1735888950952_1735888951158.png" alt="Jaideep Ahlawat in a still from the new teaser for Paatal Lok season 2." title="Jaideep Ahlawat in a still from the new teaser for Paatal Lok season 2."><figcaption>Jaideep Ahlawat in a still from the new teaser for Paatal Lok season 2.</figcaption><p>The highly-anticipated second season of the series Paatal Lok is set to premiere on Prime Video on January 17. The new teaser, featuring Jaideep Ahlawat as Hathiram Chaudhary, hints at a gripping continuation of the story.</p><ul><li>The teaser does not show actual footage from season 2 but sets the stage for a new adventure.</li><li>Hathiram enters a malfunctioning elevator and narrates a symbolic tale of courage and unintended consequences.</li><li>The new season will also feature returning cast members and new faces, including Ishwak Singh, Tillotama Shome, and Gul Panag.</li><li>The story is directed by Avinash Arun Dhaware and produced by Clean Slate Filmz alongside Eunoia Films LLP.</li></ul><blockquote>Sudip Sharma, the creator and showrunner, expressed excitement about amplifying the themes of crime, mystery, and suspense in this new chapter.</blockquote><p>The first season was widely praised for its intense storytelling and raw portrayal of Indian society, introducing audiences to the world of Inspector Hathiram Chaudhary.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/web-series/paatal-lok-season-2-teaser-out-jaideep-ahlawat-brings-a-new-lore-as-hathriram-faces-new-demons-from-hell-101735888844987.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/web-series/paatal-lok-season-2-teaser-out-jaideep-ahlawat-brings-a-new-lore-as-hathriram-faces-new-demons-from-hell-101735888844987.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 07:34:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today LIVE Updates on January 3, 2025 : Horoscope Tomorrow, January 04, 2025, read predictions for all sun signs - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNWXBHUXBqUlk0NGlNZzJhVGxya19fZ2xaSE5qNW9helNRbmV0Vk11MmgxcHotVXZIMWl5X2ppdkRBM3JiRC1MWC1qMi1KT01odXFRQjRxejliSGxrVnVVWnIwMjJtWm9UMUc4eVdwZThqNWlOV0RGZkk2WVZZU1FqR09MUGQ3dHR1enRvWG5qcHRBV2ZrQm8yV19KVmNpMEg4Ymlfbm5td1FFOWM5SERlcFBFcHpVUdIBuwFBVV95cUxNR0VNYzM0X2hKR2NxdnUxX25HRXFxaFBmWFV6OWJodnpTWldXVzhSRFVna3RHWkpBdzNUT3g3ck04MjhsbWpuaW4xNWdRRldza1RLcXlvcTh0SlBvVnFuRVhNTFBtaWtRa2ZFMVE3YlNCaTY4Zm55SEVqREJzRUJYcTh4NjY5WVVLODlqMERJUlVlUzlEWnhHeEJQMEZYYVd6b1YzcEoxZE1UVGxZX1VHbHNOMFhPOHRvclNF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNWXBHUXBqUlk0NGlNZzJhVGxya19fZ2xaSE5qNW9helNRbmV0Vk11MmgxcHotVXZIMWl5X2ppdkRBM3JiRC1MWC1qMi1KT01odXFRQjRxejliSGxrVnVVWnIwMjJtWm9UMUc4eVdwZThqNWlOV0RGZkk2WVZZU1FqR09MUGQ3dHR1enRvWG5qcHRBV2ZrQm8yV19KVmNpMEg4Ymlfbm5td1FFOWM5SERlcFBFcHpVUdIBuwFBVV95cUxNR0VNYzM0X2hKR2NxdnUxX25HRXFxaFBmWFV6OWJodnpTWldXVzhSRFVna3RHWkpBdzNUT3g3ck04MjhsbWpuaW4xNWdRRldza1RLcXlvcTh0SlBvVnFuRVhNTFBtaWtRa2ZFMVE3YlNCaTY4Zm55SEVqREJzRUJYcTh4NjY5WVVLODlqMERJUlVlUzlEWnhHeEJQMEZYYVd6b1YzcEoxZE1UVGxZX1VHbHNOMFhPOHRvclNF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 07:31:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Throwback: When Amitabh Bachchan declared he'd tolerate comments on Abhishek, not Aishwarya Rai - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Throwback: Amitabh Bachchan Defends Aishwarya Rai Against Tabloid Claims</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116907352,imgsize-30222,width-400,resizemode-4/116907352.jpg" alt="Throwback: When Amitabh Bachchan declared he'd tolerate comments on Abhishek, not Aishwarya Rai" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Amitabh Bachchan addressed false claims made about Aishwarya Rai.</figcaption><p>In 2010, Amitabh Bachchan strongly defended Aishwarya Rai Bachchan after a tabloid published false claims about her health, highlighting the importance of privacy within the family.</p><ul><li>Aishwarya Rai was reported to have health issues leading to public scrutiny.</li><li>Amitabh Bachchan expressed his disgust over the invasion of privacy on his blog.</li><li>He emphasized Aishwarya's dignity, stating she is like a daughter to him.</li><li>Past instances of media insensitivity were mentioned, particularly regarding an accident Aishwarya suffered in 2003.</li><li>The couple welcomed a daughter named Aaradhya Bachchan in 2011.</li></ul><blockquote>“I shall not tolerate it! If anyone will speak derogatorily about her, I shall fight for her till my last breath.” - Amitabh Bachchan</blockquote><p>The article underscores Amitabh Bachchan's protective attitude towards Aishwarya Rai and his advocacy for respect toward women within his family.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/throwback-when-amitabh-bachchan-declared-hed-tolerate-comments-on-abhishek-not-aishwarya-rai/articleshow/116907352.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/throwback-when-amitabh-bachchan-declared-hed-tolerate-comments-on-abhishek-not-aishwarya-rai/articleshow/116907352.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 07:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heightened tension, brand new games and return of the VIPs: What can we expect from Squid Game series 3 in 2025 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What to Expect from Squid Game Series 3 in 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 03, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/squid_1735886456919_1735886471391.webp" alt="Squid Game series 3 will release in 2025" title="Squid Game series 3 will release in 2025">
<figcaption>Squid Game series 3 will release in 2025</figcaption>
<p>Netflix has confirmed that Squid Game Series 3 will release in 2025, bringing fans new challenges and deeper emotional narratives.</p>
<ul>
<li>Series 3 is expected to continue from the cliffhanger ending of Series 2, where Gi-hun leads a rebellion.</li>
<li>Creator Hwang Dong-hyuk promises a narrative focusing on Gi-hun's guilt and the consequences of his actions.</li>
<li>New games and intensified character dynamics will be introduced, heightening the emotional stakes.</li>
<li>The VIPs will return, adding new layers of conflict to the story.</li>
<li>A teaser has hinted at unsettling twists, including the introduction of new characters.</li>
<li>The anticipated release window is set for summer or autumn 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Series 3 will introduce new games and push character dynamics further.” - Lee Jung-jae</blockquote>
<p>Fans are eagerly anticipating how Gi-hun's story will evolve in this gripping continuation of the Squid Game saga.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/heightened-tension-brand-new-games-and-return-of-the-vips-what-can-we-expect-from-squid-game-series-3-in-2025-101735885489114.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/heightened-tension-brand-new-games-and-return-of-the-vips-what-can-we-expect-from-squid-game-series-3-in-2025-101735885489114.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 07:07:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>