<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 13:31:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 13:31:29 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun's Father Meets Stampede Victim's Husband, Visits Injured Son In Hospital - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun's Father Meets Stampede Victim's Husband, Visits Injured Son In Hospital</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Allu Arjun's father visited the hospital to take stock of the child injured in the stampede." title="Allu Arjun's father visited the hospital to take stock of the child injured in the stampede."><figcaption>Allu Arjun's father visited the hospital to take stock of the child injured in the stampede.</figcaption><p>Allu Arjun’s father, Allu Aravind, visited a Hyderabad hospital to check on a child injured in the December 4 stampede during the screening of 'Pushpa 2: The Rule'. He also met with the family of the deceased woman.</p><ul><li>Allu Aravind visited the injured child in the hospital.</li><li>The health of the child is critical; he has suffered brain damage and is on ventilator support.</li><li>Telangana Health Secretary and Hyderabad Police Commissioner also visited and provided updates on the child's condition.</li><li>The stampede resulted in the death of a 35-year-old woman and severe injuries to her 9-year-old son.</li></ul><blockquote>“I remain deeply concerned about young Sri Tej, who is under constant medical care after the unfortunate incident. My prayers remain with them...” - Allu Arjun</blockquote><p>This incident has brought significant attention to safety measures during public events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjun-father-meets-stampede-victims-husband-visits-injured-son-in-hospital-9160522.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjun-father-meets-stampede-victims-husband-visits-injured-son-in-hospital-9160522.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Box Office: Allu Arjun’s Film Rules At #2 Beating Kalki 2898 AD, RRR & Every Other Indian Film In The Gulf, Guess Who’s At Top? - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office: Allu Arjun’s Film Rules At #2 Beating Kalki 2898 AD</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 5, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-box-office-01.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Box Office" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Box Office (UAE-GCC) Update! ( Photo Credit – Instagram )</figcaption><p>Pushpa 2 is a force to reckon with, not just in India but also in international circuits. Allu Arjun starrer has achieved massive milestones as it is amongst the highest-grossing Tollywood films in the Gulf countries. Scroll below for a detailed comparison with Kalki 2898 AD, RRR, Salaar and others!</p><h4><strong>Box Office Collection in UAE-GCC</strong></h4><p>As per the last update, Pushpa 2: The Rule has made box office collections of <strong>42.89 crores</strong> gross in the Gulf in 11 days since its release. It is only the second Indian film to have crossed the <strong>40 crore</strong> mark in history.</p><ul><li>Baahubali 2: <strong>87.28 crores</strong></li><li>Pushpa 2: <strong>42.89 crores</strong></li><li>RRR: <strong>39.60 crores</strong></li><li>Kalki 2898 AD: <strong>35.50 crores</strong></li><li>Saaho: <strong>23.77 crores</strong></li></ul><h4><strong>Conclusion</strong></h4><p>Pushpa 2’s unprecedented success in box office collections places it firmly behind only Baahubali 2: The Conclusion as the second-highest Tollywood grosser in the international market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-allu-arjuns-film-rules-at-2-beating-kalki-2898-ad-rrr-every-other-indian-film-in-the-gulf-guess-whos-at-top/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-allu-arjuns-film-rules-at-2-beating-kalki-2898-ad-rrr-every-other-indian-film-in-the-gulf-guess-whos-at-top/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:33:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: After Kill, Lakshya reunites with Karan Johar for an action film; Filming begins in 2025 - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-after-kill-lakshya-reunites-with-karan-johar-for-an-action-film-filming-begins-in-2025-1363298</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-after-kill-lakshya-reunites-with-karan-johar-for-an-action-film-filming-begins-in-2025-1363298</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 09:59:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Kriti Sanon joins Shahid Kapoor in Cocktail 2; Dinesh Vijan and Luv Ranjan join hands for the rom-com - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kriti Sanon Teams Up with Shahid Kapoor for Cocktail 2</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p>
<img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/1286280298_cocktail-2-main-image.jpg" alt="Cocktail 2" title="Cocktail 2" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Kriti Sanon joins Shahid Kapoor in Cocktail 2; Dinesh Vijan and Luv Ranjan collaborate for the rom-com.</figcaption>
<p>Cocktail 2 will star Shahid Kapoor and Kriti Sanon, directed by Homi Adajania, with filming set to begin in May 2025.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The movie is a sequel to the successful 2012 film Cocktail.</li>
  <li>It features Shahid Kapoor and Kriti Sanon in lead roles, while a third actress is being sought to complete the love triangle.</li>
  <li>The script is penned by Luv Ranjan, who is also involved in the creative process.</li>
  <li>The producer, Dinesh Vijan, aims to revive romantic comedies with this film.</li>
  <li>Cocktail 2 is described as a wholesome entertainer loaded with humor and emotional friendship.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Shahid Kapoor and Kriti Sanon are excited to venture into the world of this romantic comedy.”</blockquote>
<p>This upcoming film is anticipated to attract significant attention and aims to bring back the charm of romantic comedies in Bollywood.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-kriti-sanon-joins-shahid-kapoor-in-cocktail-2-dinesh-vijan-and-luv-ranjan-join-hands-for-the-rom-com-1363289</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-kriti-sanon-joins-shahid-kapoor-in-cocktail-2-dinesh-vijan-and-luv-ranjan-join-hands-for-the-rom-com-1363289</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 09:09:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Most Awaited Sequel on OTT: Big Disappointment? - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxOdzM4UDZ6NkduTDhNN0J2MDNSaTQxa0s0eEpWWUVXUUdRS3E4Nm1HY2tGemZQU0Y2MXoxeHlSdlRfSkZFVDBOc2RvNVB6TF9JQzZEb2kzc3BaS3ZacmRYUWhWVURKVWJ2QTdDYVdJSlh2VkdHQjdmMFk0UXhLTUNZUUR2ZXlqLUFEemk2UzJGT0xNZUs3VUZ1NG8wV3k5SXPSAaQBQVVfeXFMTm9qb0xFWmJUQ04tZVRoYkEwNWlXUk9Kek9aaHpxMlJHZ2xqQ1lseWdDOVpkRzlycEMwLWJRRDVQRTYtNlY1Y0FhaHBZcVFHVkcyZWlQU1BDMWZ0aC1ZZHNuS19kODhULVpTYXFXSXBFdHE3azJxQkRzcnBIbkhVaENubGFnaUFNd3ZPT1VFU0s5RllxQk9UTTktMGpKRGZZblZwWmI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxOdzM4UDZ6NkduTDhNN0J2MDNSaTQxa0s0eEpWWUVXUUdRS3E4Nm1HY2tGemZQU0Y2MXoxeHlSdlRfSkZFVDBOc2RvNVB6TF9JQzZEb2kzc3BaS3ZacmRYUWhWVURKVWJ2QTdDYVdJSlh2VkdHQjdmMFk0UXhLTUNZUUR2ZXlqLUFEemk2UzJGT0xNZUs3VUZ1NG8wV3k5SXPSAaQBQVVfeXFMTm9qb0xFWmJUQ04tZVRoYkEwNWlXUk9Kek9aaHpxMlJHZ2xqQ1lseWdDOVpkRzlycEMwLWJRRDVQRTYtNlY1Y0FhaHBZcVFHVkcyZWlQU1BDMWZ0aC1ZZHNuS19kODhULVpTYXFXSXBFdHE3azJxQkRzcnBIbkhVaENubGFnaUFNd3ZPT1VFU0s5RllxQk9UTTktMGpKRGZZblZwWmI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 09:07:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rashmika’s ‘Private’ Affairs with Bollywood Star - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rashmika's Private Affairs with Bollywood Star</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> M9 News</p>
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/rashmika-mandhana-private-affairs-with-bollywood-star-768x576.jpg" alt="Rashmika Mandhana" width="768" height="576">
<figcaption>Rashmika Mandhana in a pivotal role alongside Bollywood star Salman Khan.</figcaption>
<p>Rashmika Mandhana is gearing up for her upcoming Bollywood projects after her recent film 'Animal'. She is set to star in Vicky Kaushal’s 'Chhava' and Salman Khan’s 'Sikandar', directed by A. R. Murugadoss.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rashmika's anticipation for 'Sikandar' amid hopes for Salman Khan's comeback.</li>
  <li>Rashmika wishes to keep her conversations with Salman Khan private, adding to fans' curiosity.</li>
  <li>She emphasizes the importance of holding onto personal connections.</li>
  <li>This collaboration is expected to positively impact their careers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Whatever Salman sir and I talk about will always remain between us. I think it’s important to hold to these connections without flaunting them.” - Rashmika Mandhana</blockquote>
<p>With Rashmika's rising fame and the excitement surrounding her roles, this partnership with Salman Khan signals significant potential for both actors in the industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.m9.news/bollywood/rashmika-mandanna-private-affairs-with-bollywood-star-salman-khan/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.m9.news/bollywood/rashmika-mandanna-private-affairs-with-bollywood-star-salman-khan/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 08:53:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aamir Khan Productions breaks silence over ‘Laapataa Ladies’ Oscars 2025 snub - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aamir Khan Productions Reacts to 'Laapataa Ladies' Oscars 2025 Snub</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> December 18, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/entertainment/movies/1xyy1i/article68999602.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Copy%20of%20G2%20Cover.jpg" alt="Aamir Khan and Kiran Rao" />
<figcaption>Aamir Khan and Kiran Rao | Photo Credit: Getty Images/ PTI</figcaption>
<p>Aamir Khan Productions has issued an official statement following the exclusion of <i>Laapataa Ladies</i> from the Oscars 2025 shortlist for Best International Feature Film. The Film Federation of India’s decision to bypass the Kiran Rao-directed satire sparked significant backlash among cinephiles and industry figures alike.</p>
<ul>
<li>The film, which critiques the patriarchy in rural India, was critically acclaimed but not shortlisted for the Oscars.</li>
<li>Aamir Khan Productions expressed disappointment but emphasized gratitude for the support received.</li>
<li>The statement highlighted the honor of being considered among the finest films globally, despite the snub.</li>
<li>Critics have raised concerns about the selection criteria of the Film Federation of India.</li>
<li>The situation has drawn attention back to Payal Kapadia’s Cannes-winning film, <i>All We Imagine As Light</i>, viewed as India’s strongest contender.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Laapataa Ladies did not make it to the Academy Awards shortlist this year, and we are of course disappointed, but equally we are immensely grateful for the incredible support and belief we’ve received throughout this journey.”</blockquote>
<p>The exclusion of <i>Laapataa Ladies</i> adds another chapter to India’s contentious history with the Academy Awards.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/aamir-khan-productions-breaks-silence-over-laapataa-ladies-oscars-2025-snub/article68999606.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/aamir-khan-productions-breaks-silence-over-laapataa-ladies-oscars-2025-snub/article68999606.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 08:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rashmika Mandanna opens up about relationship with Vijay Deverakonda? Says her partner gives her comfort - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rashmika Mandanna confirms being in a relationship as she talks about her partner being her comfort place during her tough days.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/rashmika_1734507725205_1734507725519.jpg" alt="Amid dating rumours with Vijay Deverakonda, Rashmika Mandanna talks about getting comfort from her partner.(Instagram)"><figcaption>Amid dating rumours with Vijay Deverakonda, Rashmika Mandanna talks about getting comfort from her partner.(Instagram)</figcaption><p>Rashmika Mandanna has been the center of relationship rumors with actor Vijay Deverakonda. In a recent conversation, she discussed the importance of her partner in her life, emphasizing the comfort and empathy he provides.</p><ul><li>Rashmika confirms her relationship amidst ongoing speculation.</li><li>She attributes her strength during tough times to her partner.</li><li>Highlights the necessity of kindness and respect in a relationship.</li><li>Describes love as essential partnership and companionship.</li><li>Vijay Deverakonda has also acknowledged their relationship at a promotional event.</li></ul><blockquote>“My partner. I need my partner in every phase of my life. I need that comfort, security, and empathy.” - Rashmika Mandanna</blockquote><p>Rashmika will be starring in upcoming films including 'The Girlfriend' and projects alongside Salman Khan and Vicky Kaushal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/rashmika-mandanna-opens-up-about-relationship-with-vijay-deverakonda-says-her-partner-gives-her-comfort-101734505988866.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/rashmika-mandanna-opens-up-about-relationship-with-vijay-deverakonda-says-her-partner-gives-her-comfort-101734505988866.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 08:34:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kalki 2898 AD: Nag Ashwin overwhelmed by Japanese fans’ love - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kalki 2898 AD: Nag Ashwin overwhelmed by Japanese fans’ love</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 18, 2024 2:00 pm IST</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nag-Ashwin.jpg" alt="Nag Ashwin" width="440" height="422">
<figcaption>Director Nag Ashwin in Japan</figcaption>
<p>Japanese audiences have always had a special admiration for Tollywood films, and with Kalki 2898 AD set for a Japanese release, director Nag Ashwin's visit has caused quite a stir.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Director Nag Ashwin visited Japan to promote Kalki 2898 AD.</li>
  <li>Prabhas was unable to attend the promotional events due to a minor injury.</li>
  <li>The film is set to release in Japan on January 3, 2025.</li>
  <li>Nag Ashwin shared a touching moment with fans who wrote him letters in Telugu script.</li>
  <li>Filmmaker expressed deep appreciation for the love shown by Japanese fans.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“V rarely get overwhelmed… but Japanese love is like that. Diff level. They learned & wrote in Telugu script. Full love right back to you all. Arigato gozaimas.” - Nag Ashwin</blockquote>
<p>This visit is not only a promotional effort but symbolizes the growing love for Indian cinema in Japan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/kalki-2898-ad-nag-ashwin-overwhelmed-by-japanese-fans-love.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/kalki-2898-ad-nag-ashwin-overwhelmed-by-japanese-fans-love.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 13: Allu Arjun’s Franchise Total Surpasses Baahubali 1 + 2 & KGF: Chapter 1 + 2 – Decoding All Hindi Numbers! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 13: Allu Arjun’s Franchise Total Surpasses Baahubali 1 + 2 &amp; KGF</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-13-allu-arjuns-franchise-total-surpasses-baahubali-1-2-kgf-chapter-1-2-decoding-all-the-numbers-01.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 13" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Is Now The Highest-Grossing Dubbed South Indian Franchise In Hindi! (Photo Credit – Instagram)</figcaption><p>Allu Arjun has made history with the Hindi version of Pushpa 2, achieving a 13-day box office total of ₹601.50 crore, marking it as the fastest film to reach 600 crores in Indian Cinema.</p><ul><li>On day 13, the film earned ₹19.50 crore, only ₹1 crore less than the previous day.</li><li>The total box office collection for both Hindi parts of the franchise is ₹707.50 crore.</li><li>This franchise has surpassed the box office totals of both Baahubali films and KGF.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pushpa 2 is officially now the highest-grossing Hindi-dubbed South Indian franchise at the box office.”</blockquote><p>This record-breaking achievement highlights the franchise's immense popularity and the growing success of dubbed South Indian films in Hindi cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-13-allu-arjuns-franchise-total-surpasses-baahubali-1-2-kgf-chapter-1-2-decoding-all-hindi-numbers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-13-allu-arjuns-franchise-total-surpasses-baahubali-1-2-kgf-chapter-1-2-decoding-all-hindi-numbers/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 07:57:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Woman quits YouTube career after investing Rs 8 lakh, deletes 250 videos. Viral post - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>YouTuber Nalini Unagar Quits After Heavy Investment and No Returns</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/nalini-unagar-quits-youtube-photos-nalini-unagarx-184833271-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=Ebj3qncHKJgkz1h436_PZ1JCq.HRyKrk&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Nalini Unagar quits YouTube." title="Nalini Unagar quits YouTube."><figcaption>Nalini Unagar quits YouTube. (Photos: Nalini Unagar/X)</figcaption><p>Nalini Unagar, a YouTuber known for her cooking channel, announced she is quitting content creation after investing over Rs 8 lakh without any return on her investment. She has deleted all her videos and is selling her kitchen accessories and equipment.</p><ul><li>Nalini invested Rs 8 lakh over three years on her channel, 'Nalini's Kitchen Recipe'.</li><li>Despite creating over 250 videos, she received no income from YouTube.</li><li>Her decision to quit has sparked discussions about the challenges of online content creation.</li><li>Online users have expressed support and advice regarding her struggles.</li></ul><blockquote>“I failed in my YouTube career, so I’m selling all my kitchen accessories and studio equipment. If anyone is interested in buying, please let me know,” - Nalini Unagar.</blockquote><p>The discussion around her quitting has highlighted the difficulties content creators face in achieving success on platforms like YouTube, emphasizing the unpredictable nature of online fame.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/trending-news/story/nalini-unagar-quits-youtube-career-after-investing-rs-8-lakh-viral-x-post-2651613-2024-12-18</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/trending-news/story/nalini-unagar-quits-youtube-career-after-investing-rs-8-lakh-viral-x-post-2651613-2024-12-18</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 07:48:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Khanna’s half-hearted apology to Sonakshi Sinha amidst Ramayana row sparks outrage; ‘Not so ‘Sorry Shaktimaan’’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mukesh Khanna’s Half-Hearted Apology to Sonakshi Sinha Sparks Outrage</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/fhfhf_1734506107436_1734506118097.jpeg" alt="Sonakshi Sinha and Mukesh Khanna (as Shaktimaan)" title="Sonakshi Sinha and Mukesh Khanna (as Shaktimaan)"><figcaption>Sonakshi Sinha and Mukesh Khanna (as Shaktimaan)</figcaption><p>Mukesh Khanna has faced backlash following a social media apology regarding his comments on Sonakshi Sinha. The situation escalated after Khanna blamed her father for her performance on a famous quiz show, prompting a response from both Sonakshi and her father, Shatrughan Sinha.</p><ul><li>Khanna revisited Sonakshi’s 2019 appearance on <i>Kaun Banega Crorepati 11</i>.</li><li>Sonakshi Sinha reminded Khanna about the value of forgiveness, quoting Lord Rama.</li><li>Shatrughan Sinha defended his daughter publicly.</li><li>Khanna claimed he was trying to educate the younger generation with his remarks.</li><li>Social media users criticized Khanna’s apology, calling it insincere.</li></ul><blockquote>“Not so ‘Sorry Shaktimaan’,” commented a user on social media, highlighting Khanna's lack of genuine remorse.</blockquote><p>The public reaction indicates that Khanna’s attempt to stay relevant may have backfired, leaving him with diminished respect among fans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/mukesh-khanna-s-half-hearted-apology-to-sonakshi-sinha-on-kbc-row-shatrughan-sinha-shaktimaans-mukesh-khanna-apology-101734504322857.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/mukesh-khanna-s-half-hearted-apology-to-sonakshi-sinha-on-kbc-row-shatrughan-sinha-shaktimaans-mukesh-khanna-apology-101734504322857.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 07:43:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Laapataa Ladies team disappointed after Kiran Rao's film exits Oscars 2025 race: ‘For us, this is not the end’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Laapataa Ladies Team Disappointed After Oscars 2025 Exit</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/Laapataa_Ladies_2_1710153378318_1734506709331.jpg" alt="Laapataa Ladies' makers react after film fails to get shortlisted for Oscars 2025." title="Laapataa Ladies' makers react after film fails to get shortlisted for Oscars 2025."><figcaption>Laapataa Ladies' makers react after film fails to get shortlisted for Oscars 2025.</figcaption><p>The team behind the film Laapataa Ladies expressed their disappointment after the film did not make the shortlist for the Best International Feature at the Oscars 2025. Despite the setback, they thanked the Academy and celebrated the recognition as India’s official entry.</p><ul><li>The film failed to secure a position in the Oscars 2025 shortlist.</li><li>Makers expressed gratitude to the Academy and FFI jury.</li><li>The film's story revolves around two newly-wed brides exchanged during a train ride.</li><li>Filmmaker Hansal Mehta criticized the Film Federation of India for its selection process.</li><li>Fans and critics expressed disappointment on social media regarding the film's exclusion.</li></ul><blockquote>“For us, this is not the end but a step forward. We remain committed to bringing more powerful stories to life.”</blockquote><p>The Laapataa Ladies team is determined to continue their journey in filmmaking, despite the Oscars disappointment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/laapataa-ladies-team-disappointed-after-kiran-raos-film-exits-oscars-2025-race-101734506301654.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/laapataa-ladies-team-disappointed-after-kiran-raos-film-exits-oscars-2025-race-101734506301654.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 07:41:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prabhas' 'The Raja Saab' Release Date Postponed - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE81MjRFeWlvcF91NVZGSTFBaDh5RnNhVlZpUEczbG4yOWNfMkdfbzMzTlFmajYtRXZFdTZwVnhkc3VCX3BHdUVpRE5Vbzd5czVIcnZJZURVWGVTZ1puTFU0Tl9CZkJMRDFtbk1TNU5MRVpaZkIwN0VDNWRQR1BBZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE81MjRFeWlvcF91NVZGSTFBaDh5RnNhVlZpUEczbG4yOWNfMkdfbzMzTlFmajYtRXZFdTZwVnhkc3VCX3BHdUVpRE5Vbzd5czVIcnZJZURVWGVTZ1puTFU0Tl9CZkJMRDFtbk1TNU5MRVpaZkIwN0VDNWRQR1BBZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 07:08:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naga Chaitanya DROPS's first big announcement after his wedding with Sobhita Dhulipala: 'Can’t wait to share with...' - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/south/naga-chaitanya-dropss-first-big-announcement-after-his-wedding-with-sobhita-dhulipala-cant-wait-to-share-with-1363263</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/south/naga-chaitanya-dropss-first-big-announcement-after-his-wedding-with-sobhita-dhulipala-cant-wait-to-share-with-1363263</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:58:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mufasa Early Reviews: Brakes on Pushpa 2? - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxPelBNdm9HVVlfdG1DZlQ3cEtLVENtMVMyUTF4UnA5WnJFNWRjZ2NPSUxDYmJBV1NJN3ZEYTNNN2hTY2lYejRXWkJKUUJUbndIY3dvUTVkWkhhTmNBWjQwbENyWWdjOFR4YnNMeVlUaTZub2M2elRjNllqU3RMNUd6NjZfd0VKVTFtc3hpaE1uVWFqNHp0b1pNV9IBngFBVV95cUxOb25IRHdBb1RMcE44andsR0dzQU1DNmZCSG1oTC1qN1BzMS1adGRGbXFSTFk5alhjY1VsZ2Fab3l2em83bTJqZy03cHB5cDV3MGR0MUJWb05EbkxaSUozUTVFV1BjY0dLWEtYNU93Ql9oN3BSYVRxa2pVaDR4RTZjM2JZS3pUM0NabFFsb1lFQ0wxdlM3ejFMQWxMWk9HQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxPelBNdm9HVVlfdG1DZlQ3cEtLVENtMVMyUTF4UnA5WnJFNWRjZ2NPSUxDYmJBV1NJN3ZEYTNNN2hTY2lYejRXWkJKUUJUbndIY3dvUTVkWkhhTmNBWjQwbENyWWdjOFR4YnNMeVlUaTZub2M2elRjNllqU3RMNUd6NjZfd0VKVTFtc3hpaE1uVWFqNHp0b1pNV9IBngFBVV95cUxOb25IRHdBb1RMcE44andsR0dzQU1DNmZCSG1oTC1qN1BzMS1adGRGbXFSTFk5alhjY1VsZ2Fab3l2em83bTJqZy03cHB5cDV3MGR0MUJWb05EbkxaSUozUTVFV1BjY0dLWEtYNU93Ql9oN3BSYVRxa2pVaDR4RTZjM2JZS3pUM0NabFFsb1lFQ0wxdlM3ejFMQWxMWk9HQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:56:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rashmika: I Need Him All the Time - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rashmika Mandanna Discusses Love and Relationships</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> M9 News</p>
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/rashmika-mandanna-relationship-768x576.jpg" alt="rashmika-mandanna-relationship">
<figcaption>Rashmika Mandanna reflects on the importance of love and support in her life.</figcaption>
<p>With a successful couple of years in cinema, Rashmika Mandanna has become a national sensation. Recently, she shared insights into her love life and the qualities she values in relationships.</p>
<ul>
<li>Rashmika Mandanna has starred in blockbuster films like <em>Animal</em> (2023) and <em>Pushpa 2</em> (2024).</li>
<li>She emphasizes the role of her partner as a source of comfort and support.</li>
<li>Kindness and respect are non-negotiable qualities for her in a relationship.</li>
<li>Rashmika views love as companionship and partnership.</li>
<li>Despite her fame, her expectations about love remain practical and relatable.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If you don’t have them then what’s the point of having this life?”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Rashmika Mandanna's perspective on love reflects a desire for deep connection and support, showing that her values remain grounded despite her celebrity status.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.m9.news/movienews/rashmika-mandanna-i-need-him-all-the-time/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.m9.news/movienews/rashmika-mandanna-i-need-him-all-the-time/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:47:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai: Armaan accepts Kaveri's challenge to convince Abhira or lose her - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai: Armaan accepts Kaveri's challenge to convince Abhira or lose her</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Wednesday, December 18, 2024 at 6:37 AM</p><figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/8367-yeh-rishta-kya-kehlata-hai-armaan-accepts-kaveris-challenge-to-convince-abhira-or-lose-her.jpg" width="640" height="360" alt="Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai: Armaan accepts Kaveri's challenge to convince Abhira or lose her"><figcaption>Armaan and Kaveri from Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai. Image Courtesy: Star Plus</figcaption></figure><p>The upcoming episode of Yeh Rishta Kya Kehlata Hai takes an emotional turn as Armaan faces a life-altering challenge. Following shocking revelations about family dynamics and past decisions, he must convince Abhira to reconsider their divorce.</p><ul><li>Abhira expresses her belief in divorce as their fate.</li><li>Kaveri challenges Armaan to win her over in 8 days.</li><li>Manish initiates divorce proceedings, raising questions about the couple's future.</li><li>Armaan seems determined to keep his marriage intact despite the turmoil.</li></ul><blockquote>“Every relationship is shaped by fate, and for her and Armaan, the fate is divorce.”</blockquote><p>The episode promises intense drama as Armaan takes on Kaveri's challenge, with the clock ticking. Will he be able to change Abhira's heart in time?</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/yeh-rishta-kya-kehlata-hai-armaan-accepts-kaveris-challenge-to-convince-abhira-or-lose-her_215565</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/yeh-rishta-kya-kehlata-hai-armaan-accepts-kaveris-challenge-to-convince-abhira-or-lose-her_215565</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:39:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sameer Wankhede addresses Aryan Khan case, calls Shah Rukh’s Jawan dialogues ‘cheap, third rate’: ‘Smallest case of my career’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sameer Wankhede addresses Aryan Khan case, calls Shah Rukh’s Jawan dialogues ‘cheap, third rate’: ‘Smallest case of my career’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Smaeer-Wankhede.jpg?w=640' alt='Smaeer Wankhede' width='640' height='360'><figcaption>Smaeer Wankhede talks about Aryan Khan drug case. (Photo: Pooja Dadlani/Sameer Wankhede/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Sameer Wankhede, the former Zonal Director of the Narcotics Control Bureau, has addressed the controversies surrounding the Aryan Khan case, expressing that it was minor in his career and criticizing related remarks from Shah Rukh Khan's dialogue in 'Jawan'.</p><ul><li>In October 2021, Aryan Khan was detained for 25 days over drug-related charges.</li><li>Sameer Wankhede faced accusations during the investigation but stated he has handled many other cases.</li><li>Wankhede minimized the Aryan Khan case, calling it 'the smallest case of my career'.</li><li>He rejected Shah Rukh Khan's dialogue as 'cheap and third rated'.</li><li>Wankhede remains under judicial obligation not to discuss details of the ongoing legal matter.</li></ul><blockquote>“People see me as someone, who only gets hold of so-called celebrities... I only did my duty.” - Sameer Wankhede</blockquote><p>Wankhede emphasizes his professionalism and the seriousness of his work, insisting he follows legal protocols while addressing public speculation around the ongoing case.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/sameer-wankhede-addresses-aryan-khan-case-calls-shah-rukhs-jawan-dialogues-cheap-third-rate-smallest-case-of-my-career-9731418/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/sameer-wankhede-addresses-aryan-khan-case-calls-shah-rukhs-jawan-dialogues-cheap-third-rate-smallest-case-of-my-career-9731418/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:32:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Radhika Apte talks about her ‘shocking’ pregnancy, says she struggled to embrace how she looked: ‘Never seen myself put on so much weight’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Radhika Apte Opens Up About Her Pregnancy Struggles</h1><p><strong>Date: December 2024</strong><br><strong>Source: The Indian Express</strong></p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Radhika-Apte.jpg?w=640" alt="Radhika Apte" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Radhika Apte talks about her pregnancy struggles. (Photo: Radhika Apte/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Actress Radhika Apte shares her emotional journey through an unexpected pregnancy, discussing body image struggles and societal expectations surrounding pregnancy.</p><ul><li>Radhika Apte recently revealed her pregnancy at the BFI London Film Festival.</li><li>She described her pregnancy journey as tough and unexpected.</li><li>Radhika struggled with body image and weight gain during pregnancy.</li><li>She emphasized the need for open conversations about the challenges of pregnancy.</li><li>Plans to remain in London until February before returning to India to work.</li></ul><blockquote>“I struggled to embrace how I looked at the time. ... I know I will cherish these photos forever.”</blockquote><p>Radhika's candid reflections challenge the idealized narrative of pregnancy, advocating for a more nuanced understanding of the experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/radhika-apte-talks-about-her-shocking-pregnancy-says-she-struggled-to-embrace-how-she-looked-never-seen-myself-put-on-so-much-weight-9731160/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/radhika-apte-talks-about-her-shocking-pregnancy-says-she-struggled-to-embrace-how-she-looked-never-seen-myself-put-on-so-much-weight-9731160/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:22:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Siddhu’s Jack takes Prabhas’ The Raja Saab release date - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Siddhu’s Jack Takes Prabhas’ The Raja Saab Release Date</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 11:41 am IST</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Prabhas-Siddhu-.jpg" alt="Prabhas and Siddhu" width="550" height="367"><figcaption>Prabhas and Siddhu in a promotional image.</figcaption><p>Prabhas fans are eagerly awaiting updates about his next release, The Raja Saab, directed by Maruthi. Malavika Mohanan plays the main female lead in this movie.</p><p>DJ Tillu fame Siddhu Jonnalagadda is working on a movie called Jack, directed by Bommarillu Bhaskar. Produced by BVSN Prasad, the movie has locked its release for April 10, 2025, coinciding with the release date of Prabhas’ The Raja Saab.</p><p>When Anushka Shetty’s Ghaati was locked for April 18, 2025, many speculated that The Raja Saab might be postponed. Now, with Jack taking The Raja Saab’s release date, it seems that the movie’s postponement is confirmed.</p><p>A new release date might be announced soon for the horror-comedy drama, which is produced by People Media Factory on a grand scale. We will have to wait and see what other films will lock their release dates in April 2025 as The Raja Saab gets postponed.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/siddhus-jack-takes-prabhas-the-raja-saab-release-date.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/siddhus-jack-takes-prabhas-the-raja-saab-release-date.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CONFIRMED! Shahid Kapoor and Vishal Bhardwaj’s next to release on December 5, 2025 - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CONFIRMED! Shahid Kapoor and Vishal Bhardwaj’s next to release on December 5, 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p><p><img src="https://stat5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Shahid_Kapoor_Vishal_Release_Date.jpg" alt="CONFIRMED! Shahid Kapoor and Vishal Bhardwaj’s next to release on December 5, 2025"><figcaption>Shahid Kapoor and Vishal Bhardwaj’s upcoming film scheduled for December 5, 2025</figcaption></p><p>Shahid Kapoor is reuniting with filmmaker Vishal Bhardwaj for an action-packed film, set to begin filming on January 6, 2025, and releasing December 5, 2025.</p><ul><li>The film is produced by Sajid Nadiadwala under Nadiadwala Grandson Entertainment.</li><li>Shahid Kapoor hints at an edgy gangster role in the film.</li><li>Shahid previously collaborated with Bhardwaj on acclaimed projects like <em>Haider</em> and <em>Kaminey</em>.</li><li>Actress Triptii Dimri will also star in the film, anticipated to be a commercial entertainer.</li></ul><blockquote>“Prep time ... Naya saal naya maal ..... Next character next film what can I do that I haven't before ....... lost in the woods.... Sliding into the edgy nasty gangster 90s.” - Shahid Kapoor</blockquote><p>Fans and industry insiders are excited about the reunion and the potential of the film to deliver a compelling narrative filled with action and drama.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/confirmed-shahid-kapoor-vishal-bhardwajs-next-release-december-5-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/confirmed-shahid-kapoor-vishal-bhardwajs-next-release-december-5-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 05:55:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangalore Woman Beefing With Armed Security Guard After He Asked Her To 'Move' For Nita Ambani's Exit - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AJBVV95cUxQYXhTRmFmQndvbEtfMElNYmRtUkFXcE80V0tocjhucmx4VkpIN3o0LUVmRGFlVkZsdTNNVEctOVNWU2g5MWEwblJsaTJBN2owdHU1Y2hnMkRiX1A5QUlraFpxZnZWQlpBNkk1U1hMd3p1VjlvYjV4eER1R1lCYjlRNWtkaG9ta3FVTmhTdlJOQUtIeGtBdm1yQVZzSWIyRE1PRlJpa0hXcVRIdFdZMzBjbG1MQ3hRUDFJWE10Ui14aUlWXzhkb1RmM09uNWJxc2piMU1QYTVna0F0aVNpa05QZVJXbG9JR01LUjBxT3c1QW1tSkpuSS1BTHp2aHZmeGw3Y2lLb0Y0M1RzbTA0b01RNXRLOWU4ZERNc1dCb2txOENIRFY4UlEzRzdWaXBqZENsV0NrSmEyVmlCelpTUTJDcF9oOWkxVzlGRWh0NUpBcTFpVVdhUXZpQdIB3gJBVV95cUxOYWpaWlktUzJ0a0NoNjEwU0tqX1hORU5CV1BfSThpUmI5Tm1jMmlhei1QUDhlQjdiWEF2Uy1JZVlyNFk4VEFuOHROY0RNRU1CUzF6VWVhS0dBOXl3QTlKZGpGNTFZRlBoRnpnTFlrb1FpWjJXZXY1TnR5b25EZ0dlY2JlcGdyRTd0YmUwYWtHN19qZnJ5alllU3ZoalNVU1oyMmlNb21nU095QVppNzYxZTNNVjhKaFZCU0tLLUJBSmNhRzlvQkFFMXJiVkZ4TFAwZDlqMXdaVUhyY2VoejEzLVh5am5LZi1VZ3NWNHNNNVpTNWlZNks3d1FwZi0xUnNYMV8tdVRuLWc1OS1WX0xuWDBXRV9DSE1qa2NSTG5idXNxR3Z0dkZPci1uaU44STBBRmZhOG01cWdHQ3RiN20yUkVZblZya3hfSTVzV1RqLVUtZ3ZpQnZ2VWxKR3A3QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AJBVV95cUxQYXhTRmFmQndvbEtfMElNYmRtUkFXcE80V0tocjhucmx4VkpIN3o0LUVmRGFlVkZsdTNNVEctOVNWU2g5MWEwblJsaTJBN2owdHU1Y2hnMkRiX1A5QUlraFpxZnZWQlpBNkk1U1hMd3p1VjlvYjV4eER1R1lCYjlRNWtkaG9ta3FVTmhTdlJOQUtIeGtBdm1yQVZzSWIyRE1PRlJpa0hXcVRIdFdZMzBjbG1MQ3hRUDFJWE10Ui14aUlWXzhkb1RmM09uNWJxc2piMU1QYTVna0F0aVNpa05QZVJXbG9JR01LUjBxT3c1QW1tSkpuSS1BTHp2aHZmeGw3Y2lLb0Y0M1RzbTA0b01RNXRLOWU4ZERNc1dCb2txOENIRFY4UlEzRzdWaXBqZENsV0NrSmEyVmlCelpTUTJDcF9oOWkxVzlGRWh0NUpBcTFpVVdhUXZpQdIB3gJBVV95cUxOYWpaWlktUzJ0a0NoNjEwU0tqX1hORU5CV1BfSThpUmI5Tm1jMmlhei1QUDhlQjdiWEF2Uy1JZVlyNFk4VEFuOHROY0RNRU1CUzF6VWVhS0dBOXl3QTlKZGpGNTFZRlBoRnpnTFlrb1FpWjJXZXY1TnR5b25EZ0dlY2JlcGdyRTd0YmUwYWtHN19qZnJ5alllU3ZoalNVU1oyMmlNb21nU095QVppNzYxZTNNVjhKaFZCU0tLLUJBSmNhRzlvQkFFMXJiVkZ4TFAwZDlqMXdaVUhyY2VoejEzLVh5am5LZi1VZ3NWNHNNNVpTNWlZNks3d1FwZi0xUnNYMV8tdVRuLWc1OS1WX0xuWDBXRV9DSE1qa2NSTG5idXNxR3Z0dkZPci1uaU44STBBRmZhOG01cWdHQ3RiN20yUkVZblZya3hfSTVzV1RqLVUtZ3ZpQnZ2VWxKR3A3QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 05:40:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Peeping Moon EXCLUSIVE: Shahid Kapoor to romance Rashmika Mandanna in Dinesh Vijan’s Cocktail 2 - PeepingMoon]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxQal9MWjJSQjcwSnQ5MkJKa1JKSktUTW5PTWlKVWNpV19hR1pUbzYtbmJZaVg4c0RNZ3ZhZ01sN1NWOU9pZ096MGRNaU5TSE5kLXBWeW5KeXJMVXp6N2wwX0FOT1RpQW5SaUZBa2lFR1d0dmswc0VhUnJnckppM0JRY01ITWdkRFNPNUZuTUt5LU5YeHRYcTh4MFVZeUdfb1VYbkw3OFVwdkNPLUoyY3QyZGNTRTc4cDd5S3lFOGlIMFNBbVBiQzVZeklxSGR5X2xEb0w0N2N4b2tqNWJZMlpTSUNNdWY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxQal9MWjJSQjcwSnQ5MkJKa1JKSktUTW5PTWlKVWNpV19hR1pUbzYtbmJZaVg4c0RNZ3ZhZ01sN1NWOU9pZ096MGRNaU5TSE5kLXBWeW5KeXJMVXp6N2wwX0FOT1RpQW5SaUZBa2lFR1d0dmswc0VhUnJnckppM0JRY01ITWdkRFNPNUZuTUt5LU5YeHRYcTh4MFVZeUdfb1VYbkw3OFVwdkNPLUoyY3QyZGNTRTc4cDd5S3lFOGlIMFNBbVBiQzVZeklxSGR5X2xEb0w0N2N4b2tqNWJZMlpTSUNNdWY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 05:17:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anurag Kashyap puts dupatta on daughter Aaliyah's head as she registers marriage with Shane Gregoire. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anurag Kashyap puts dupatta on daughter Aaliyah's head as she registers marriage with Shane Gregoire. Watch</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 10:45 AM IST | Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/aali_1734494318972_1734494339514.jpg" alt="Anurag Kashyap fixes daughter Aaliyah Kashyap's dupatta as she registers her marriage with Shane Gregoire.(Instagram)"><figcaption>Anurag Kashyap fixes daughter Aaliyah Kashyap's dupatta as she registers her marriage with Shane Gregoire.(Instagram)</figcaption><p>Anurag Kashyap's daughter Aaliyah Kashyap tied the knot with longtime boyfriend Shane Gregoire. Recently, Aarti Bajaj shared photos from the marriage registry, capturing Anurag Kashyap fixing his daughter's dupatta.</p><ul><li>Aaliyah Kashyap married Shane Gregoire on December 11.</li><li>Aarti Bajaj shared photos and videos from the marriage registry.</li><li>Anurag Kashyap was seen fixing Aaliyah's dupatta in a heartwarming moment.</li><li>Imtiaz Ali was present at the registered marriage.</li></ul><blockquote>Anurag sir is soo pookie, my god.</blockquote><p>The couple posed with family and friends, and Instagram users congratulated them and commented on Anurag Kashyap's gesture.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/anurag-kashyap-puts-dupatta-on-daughter-aaliyahs-head-as-she-registers-marriage-with-shane-gregoire-watch-101734493784431.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/anurag-kashyap-puts-dupatta-on-daughter-aaliyahs-head-as-she-registers-marriage-with-shane-gregoire-watch-101734493784431.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 05:15:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nora Fatehi surprises fans by dancing with singer Karan Aujla at his second show In Delhi - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/nora-fatehi-surprises-fans-by-dancing-with-singer-karan-aujla-at-his-second-show-in-delhi-article-12892422.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/nora-fatehi-surprises-fans-by-dancing-with-singer-karan-aujla-at-his-second-show-in-delhi-article-12892422.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 05:12:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahira Khan recalls backlash over smoking with Ranbir Kapoor photo: I remember reading it and thinking, Is my career over? - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahira Khan Reflects on Career Impact After Backlash from Smoking Photo</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <br> <strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p>
<img src="https://media5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ranbir-Kapoor-1.jpg" alt="Mahira Khan recalls backlash over smoking with Ranbir Kapoor photo: 'I remember reading it and thinking, 'Is my career over?''" width="620" height="450">
<figcaption>Mahira Khan reflects on her past controversy.</figcaption>
<p>Pakistani actress Mahira Khan discusses the backlash she faced after a controversial photo of her smoking with Ranbir Kapoor went viral.</p>
<ul>
<li>Mahira Khan recalls emotional turmoil, questioning her career after the incident.</li>
<li>She cites significant personal and professional impacts from the backlash.</li>
<li>Support from brands helped her navigate the challenging time.</li>
<li>Currently, she is focused on upcoming projects, including a Netflix series.</li>
<li>Mahira emphasizes her role as a mother and prioritizes her son's well-being.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I told myself, 'Are you mad? This is going to end,' but I won't lie — that time was very tough.” - Mahira Khan</blockquote>
<p>Despite the struggles, Mahira Khan is looking forward to new opportunities while reflecting on her journey through adversity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/mahira-khan-recalls-backlash-smoking-ranbir-kapoor-photo-remember-reading-thinking-career/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/mahira-khan-recalls-backlash-smoking-ranbir-kapoor-photo-remember-reading-thinking-career/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 04:58:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun’s Pushpa 2 beats Shah Rukh Khan’s Jawan as second biggest film in Hindi - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun’s Pushpa 2 beats Shah Rukh Khan’s Jawan as second biggest film in Hindi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Allu Arjun's highly anticipated film, Pushpa 2, has surpassed Shah Rukh Khan's blockbuster Jawan to become the second biggest film in the Hindi language, showcasing the evolving landscape of the Indian film industry.</p><ul><li>Pushpa 2 has officially emerged as the second largest Hindi film.</li><li>It has outperformed Jawan, which was previously a benchmark for popular Hindi cinema.</li><li>This shift may indicate changing audience preferences and the impact of regional films.</li></ul><blockquote>"Pushpa 2's success signals a new era for Hindi cinema."</blockquote><p>This development underlines the increasing popularity of regional films among Hindi-speaking audiences, marking a significant trend in the industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/allu-arjuns-pushpa-2-beats-shah-rukh-khans-jawan-as-second-biggest-film-in-hindi/articleshow/116421479.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/allu-arjuns-pushpa-2-beats-shah-rukh-khans-jawan-as-second-biggest-film-in-hindi/articleshow/116421479.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 04:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Khanna replies to Sonakshi Sinha after she slams him for not knowing Ramayana, writes: I regret... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/mukesh-khanna-replies-to-sonakshi-sinha-after-she-slams-him-for-not-knowing-ramayana-writes-i-regret-that-i-article-12892394.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/mukesh-khanna-replies-to-sonakshi-sinha-after-she-slams-him-for-not-knowing-ramayana-writes-i-regret-that-i-article-12892394.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 04:39:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Khanna replies to Sonakshi Sinha after she slams him for not knowing Ramayana, writes: I regret that I ....' - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/mukesh-khanna-replies-to-sonakshi-sinha-after-she-slams-him-for-not-knowing-ramayana-writes-i-regret-that-i-article-12892394.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/mukesh-khanna-replies-to-sonakshi-sinha-after-she-slams-him-for-not-knowing-ramayana-writes-i-regret-that-i-article-12892394.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 04:39:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>