<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 10:27:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 10:27:53 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diljit Dosanjh announces he won't do shows in India until this happens - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diljit Dosanjh won't perform in India until concert infrastructure improves</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 16, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/Diljit_Dosanjh_1734331500392_1734331511195.jpg" alt="Diljit Dosanjh has been performing in India for several weeks now." title="Diljit Dosanjh has been performing in India for several weeks now.">
<figcaption>Diljit Dosanjh has been performing in India for several weeks now.</figcaption>
<p>In a recent announcement during his Chandigarh concert, singer Diljit Dosanjh revealed that he will not hold concerts in India until the country's concert infrastructure is properly developed.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Diljit made the announcement during a show in Chandigarh on December 14, 2024.</li>
  <li>He emphasized the lack of infrastructure for live shows, which he sees as a significant source of revenue and employment.</li>
  <li>During the concert, he dedicated his performance to India's FIDE World Champion, Gukesh Dommaraju.</li>
  <li>Prior to the show, an advisory from the Chandigarh Commission for Protection of Child Rights urged Diljit to avoid alcohol-themed songs.</li>
  <li>His upcoming show in Guwahati on December 29 will conclude his tour in India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Here we don't have infrastructure for live shows. This is a source of big revenue, many people get work and are able to work here...I'll try next time that the stage is at the centre so that you can be around it. Till this happens, I won't do shows in India, that's for sure.”</blockquote>
<p>Until improvements are made, Diljit remains firm on his decision not to perform in India, illustrating the need for better concert facilities to enhance the live music experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/diljit-dosanjh-announces-he-wont-do-shows-in-india-until-this-happens-101734330054287.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/diljit-dosanjh-announces-he-wont-do-shows-in-india-until-this-happens-101734330054287.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:58:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kannappa: Mohanlal is introduced as Kirata - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kannappa: Mohanlal is introduced as Kirata</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 16, 2024</strong></p>
<img src='https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Kannappa.jpg' alt='' width='320' height='453'>
<figcaption>Mohanlal as Kirata in 'Kannappa'</figcaption>
<p>Kannappa is the ambitious dream project of Tollywood actor Vishnu Manchu, set to release on April 25, 2025. Directed by Mukesh Kumar Singh, this multilingual epic promises to be a visual treat.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film features a stellar cast including Mohan Babu, Sarath Kumar, and Prabhas.</li>
  <li>Mohanlal plays Kirata, a legendary guardian with a captivating look.</li>
  <li>The music is composed by Stephen Devassy and Mani Sharma.</li>
  <li>Character posters are being released weekly as part of the promotion.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This powerful role of Kirata has captivated audiences, building anticipation.”</blockquote>
<p>Stay tuned for more updates on this extraordinary venture.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/kannappa-mohanlal-is-introduced-as-kirata.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/kannappa-mohanlal-is-introduced-as-kirata.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zakir Hussain: Legendary tabla player dies at 73 - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zakir Hussain: Legendary Tabla Player Dies at 73</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News Agency</p><p>Zakir Hussain, one of the world's greatest tabla players, has died at the age of 73 due to idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis.</p><ul><li>Hussain was a four-time Grammy award winner and received the Padma Vibhushan.</li><li>He transformed the tabla into a globally loved solo instrument.</li><li>Tributes have started pouring in following his death.</li><li>Nayan Ghosh described him as a pathbreaker and an icon who elevated tabla on the world stage.</li></ul><blockquote>“He was a pathbreaker, a game-changer, an icon who put tabla and Indian music on the world map...” - Nayan Ghosh</blockquote><p>This legendary musician, born in Mumbai in 1951, has left an indelible mark on classical music.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c2exzm9r043o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c2exzm9r043o</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 8 Telugu: Fans of Gautam cry foul on makers - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 8 Telugu: Fans of Gautam cry foul on makers</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 10:01 am IST</p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Goutham-Bigg-Boss.jpg" alt="Gautam from Bigg Boss 8" width="500" height="329">
<figcaption>Gautam from Bigg Boss 8</figcaption>
<p>Bigg Boss 8 Telugu has reached its conclusion, with Nikhil Maliyakkal emerging as the winner amidst controversy from fans of runner-up Gautam Krishna.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nikhil Maliyakkal wins Bigg Boss 8 Telugu.</li>
  <li>Gautam Krishna was the runner-up and entered as a wild card contestant.</li>
  <li>Fans accuse the show makers of favoritism towards Nikhil due to his connections with the channel.</li>
  <li>The audience showed a regional preference for Gautam, who is a Telugu native.</li>
  <li>Gautam joined six weeks late, which impacted his competition.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Fans are upset over the results, claiming Gautam should have won.”</blockquote>
<p>The fan reaction seems to indicate a deep divide and dissatisfaction with the show’s outcome, raising questions about the fairness of the voting process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/bigg-boss-8-telugu-fans-of-gautam-cry-foul-on-makers.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/bigg-boss-8-telugu-fans-of-gautam-cry-foul-on-makers.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 11: Allu Arjun film earns Rs 1322 cr, highest earner ever after Dangal and Baahubali 2 - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 11</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 15, 2024 | Source: Indian Express</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-11.jpg?w=640" alt="Pushpa 2 box office collection day 11: Allu Arjun starrer is third highest earning Indian film ever." width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Pushpa 2 box office collection day 11: Allu Arjun's film makes more than Rs 900 crores in India. (Photo: Mythri Movies / Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>The film <strong>Pushpa 2: The Rule</strong>, starring Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna, has shattered box office records, achieving a total worldwide collection of Rs 1322 crore by its 11th day of release.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Earned Rs 100 crore on the 11th day.</li>
  <li>Total Indian collection (all languages) now stands at Rs 900.5 crores.</li>
  <li>Massive spike of 73.90% in box office collections on the second Saturday.</li>
  <li>Hindi version grossed Rs 55 crores on December 15.</li>
  <li>Film surpassed RRR's record, although it's yet to exceed Baahubali 2 and Dangal.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“#Pushpa2TheRule crosses Massive 1292 CRORES GROSS in 10 days 💥💥”</blockquote>
<p>This phenomenal success is attributed to strong word of mouth and high occupancy rates across various regions, particularly in Hyderabad and Vijayawada.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-11-allu-arjun-film-earns-rs-1322-cr-highest-earner-ever-after-dangal-and-baahubali-2-9727126/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-11-allu-arjun-film-earns-rs-1322-cr-highest-earner-ever-after-dangal-and-baahubali-2-9727126/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Keerthy Suresh-Antony Thattil white wedding pictures: Couple start their happily ever after with a kiss - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Keerthy Suresh and Antony Thattil Celebrate Their White Wedding</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Keerthy-Suresh-Antony-Thattils-Christian-wedding.jpg?w=640" alt="Keerthy Suresh-Antony Thattil's Christian wedding" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Keerthy Suresh and Antony Thattil's wedding celebration took place in Goa. (Photo: Keerthy Suresh/Instagram)</figcaption><p>The National Award-winning actor Keerthy Suresh married her longtime boyfriend and entrepreneur Antony Thattil on December 12 in Goa. The couple exchanged vows again in a white wedding on December 15, sharing joyous moments online.</p><ul><li>Keerthy shared the photos with a special hashtag, “#ForTheLoveOfNyke”, celebrating both their love and her dog, Nyke.</li><li>The couple had a traditional South Indian wedding before their white wedding ceremony.</li><li>Keerthy walked down the aisle accompanied by her father and her pet dog Nyke.</li><li>The couple was spotted celebrating on the dance floor after the vows.</li><li>Celebrity guests included Thalapathy Vijay, Trisha Krishnan, and Atlee, among others.</li></ul><blockquote>“So beautiful,” commented Varun Dhawan on the wedding photos shared by Keerthy.</blockquote><p>This marriage marks a significant relationship milestone after a 15-year courtship, surprising many fans who were unaware of her private life details.</p><p>The ceremony reflects a blend of personal happiness and cultural tradition, showcasing the joy of love and community celebration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/tamil/keerthy-suresh-antony-thattil-white-wedding-pics-couple-start-their-happily-ever-after-with-a-kiss-9727144/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/tamil/keerthy-suresh-antony-thattil-white-wedding-pics-couple-start-their-happily-ever-after-with-a-kiss-9727144/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 03:47:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ustad Zakir Hussain tribute: Tabla loses its vibrant voice - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ustad Zakir Hussain tribute: Tabla loses its vibrant voice</h1>
<p><strong>Published Date & Source:</strong> <span>December 16, 2024</span></p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/e2ye02/article68990650.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/_DSC7801.jpg" alt="Tabla maestro Zakir Hussain, during an interaction with The Hindu, in 2023" title="Tabla maestro Zakir Hussain, during an interaction with The Hindu, in 2023">
<figcaption>Tabla maestro Zakir Hussain, during an interaction with The Hindu, in 2023 | Photo Credit: K. Murali Kumar</figcaption>
<p>The tabla fell silent as Ustad Zakir Hussain, one of the greatest ambassadors of Indian classical music, passed away on December 16, 2024, after a brief illness in San Francisco, California. He transformed the modest tabla into a voice for universal peace and humanity.</p>
<ul>
<li>Hussain was renowned for his speed, dexterity, and creativity, mesmerizing audiences worldwide.</li>
<li>He played a crucial role in popularizing the tabla on a global scale.</li>
<li>A child prodigy, he gave his first professional performance at the age of 12.</li>
<li>Among his notable achievements are three Grammy Awards received in one night.</li>
<li>Hussain blended musical traditions, collaborating with artists across various genres and cultures.</li>
<li>He was also an actor, famously appearing in commercials that brought classical music into mainstream culture.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I haven’t played good enough to quit.”</blockquote>
<p>Ustad Zakir Hussain’s legacy will continue to inspire future generations of musicians and audiences as a testament to the power of music.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/music/zakir-hussain-death-tabla-maestro-tribute-obituary/article68990646.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/music/zakir-hussain-death-tabla-maestro-tribute-obituary/article68990646.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 03:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer overseas bookings are now open, Ram Charan announces - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer overseas bookings are now open, Ram Charan announces</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 16, 2024 8:01 am IST</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Game-Changer-1.jpg" alt="Game Changer Movie Poster" width="360" height="450"><figcaption>Game Changer Movie Poster</figcaption><p>Actor Ram Charan took to X on Sunday evening to announce that overseas bookings for the highly anticipated pan-India political drama 'Game Changer' are now open.</p><ul><li>The film is set for theatrical release on January 10, 2025, coinciding with the Sankranti festival.</li><li>Ram Charan is featured in a dual role as father and son.</li><li>It is produced by Dil Raju with a soundtrack composed by Thaman.</li><li>Advance bookings started in key overseas markets like the UK and North America.</li><li>The cast includes Kiara Advani, SJ Suryah, Anjali, and others.</li></ul><blockquote>A massive global storm has begun! #GameChanger overseas bookings are now open! Experience it in cinemas worldwide from 10-01-2025!</blockquote><p>Expectations are high for the film, which has generated significant hype due to the star power of Ram Charan and director Shankar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/gamechanger-overseas-bookings-are-now-open-ram-charan-announces.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/gamechanger-overseas-bookings-are-now-open-ram-charan-announces.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 02:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Backlash On Bail 'Celebrations', Allu Arjun's Post For Injured Boy - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After Backlash On Bail 'Celebrations', Allu Arjun's Post For Injured Boy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="After Backlash On Bail 'Celebrations', Allu Arjun's Post For Injured Boy" alt="After Backlash On Bail 'Celebrations', Allu Arjun's Post For Injured Boy" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/gd423iro_allu-arjun-news_625x300_14_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>Allu Arjun's message for the injured boy.</figcaption><p>Telugu actor Allu Arjun expresses deep concern for Sri Tej, a boy critically injured in a stampede at a Hyderabad theater screening of 'Pushpa 2'. Following backlash for celebrating his bail, Arjun emphasizes his support for the boy and his family during this difficult time.</p><ul><li>On December 4, a stampede occurred when Allu Arjun made an unscheduled visit to a theater showing 'Pushpa 2'.</li><li>Tragically, a woman died and her son, Sri Tej, suffered critical injuries during the incident.</li><li>Allu Arjun cannot visit the boy due to ongoing legal proceedings but expressed his prayers and commitment to assist with medical and family needs.</li><li>His previous social media celebrations after being granted bail faced backlash online.</li><li>Sri Tej is currently receiving medical care and is in stable but serious condition.</li></ul><blockquote>“I remain deeply concerned about young Sri Tej, who is under constant medical care after the unfortunate incident. My prayers remain with them and I remain committed to taking responsibility for addressing the medical and family needs.” - Allu Arjun</blockquote><p>The incident raises questions about crowd management and responsibilities of celebrities during public appearances, highlighting the need for better safety protocols at events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/allu-arjun-deeply-concerned-about-boy-injured-in-pushpa-2-screening-stampede-in-hyderabad-7257665</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/allu-arjun-deeply-concerned-about-boy-injured-in-pushpa-2-screening-stampede-in-hyderabad-7257665</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 02:21:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cops Reveal Why Kidnappers Did Not Go After Actor Shakti Kapoor - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cops Reveal Why Kidnappers Did Not Go After Actor Shakti Kapoor</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Cops Reveal Why Kidnappers Did Not Go After Actor Shakti Kapoor" alt="Cops Reveal Why Kidnappers Did Not Go After Actor Shakti Kapoor" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8kqd4v98_shakti-kapoor_625x300_16_December_24.jpeg"><figcaption>Cops Reveal Why Kidnappers Did Not Go After Actor Shakti Kapoor</figcaption><p>The police have arrested four individuals involved in a kidnapping plot that targeted actor Mushtaq Khan, who was taken hostage after being invited to an event. They initially planned to kidnap veteran actor Shakti Kapoor but their plans fell through due to financial disputes.</p><ul><li>Four gang members arrested in connection to actor Mushtaq Khan's kidnapping at Delhi airport.</li><li>Gang planned to kidnap Shakti Kapoor under the pretext of inviting him to an event.</li><li>Mushtaq Khan was kidnapped and held for ransom; his bank details were obtained by the kidnappers.</li><li>The gang sought ₹ 5 lakh to make the kidnapping of Shakti Kapoor happen, but their plan fell through.</li><li>Police traced the gang's operations and are seeking to identify other potential victims.</li></ul><blockquote>“The gang was involved in kidnapping film stars by sending advance payments and air tickets under the guise of event invitations.”</blockquote><p>Authorities are investigating the gang’s broader operations and have made additional arrests related to other kidnapping incidents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/actor-mushtaq-khans-kidnappers-also-planned-to-take-shakti-kapoor-hostage-cops-7257503</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/actor-mushtaq-khans-kidnappers-also-planned-to-take-shakti-kapoor-hostage-cops-7257503</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:36:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gang That Held 'Welcome' Actor Hostage Also Planned To Kidnap Shakti Kapoor - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cops Reveal Why Kidnappers Did Not Go After Actor Shakti Kapoor</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img title="Cops Reveal Why Kidnappers Did Not Go After Actor Shakti Kapoor" alt="Cops Reveal Why Kidnappers Did Not Go After Actor Shakti Kapoor" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8kqd4v98_shakti-kapoor_625x300_16_December_24.jpeg" />
<figcaption>File photo</figcaption>
<p>The arrest of four gang members involved in kidnapping actor Mushtaq Khan sheds light on their plans to target Shakti Kapoor, which ultimately did not materialize due to high advance payment demands.</p>
<ul>
<li>Four gang members were arrested for kidnapping Mushtaq Khan from Delhi airport.</li>
<li>The kidnappers intended to target Shakti Kapoor under the pretext of inviting him to an event.</li>
<li>The gang used advance payments and air tickets to lure film stars.</li>
<li>Mushtaq Khan managed to escape after his bank account was accessed by the kidnappers.</li>
<li>Police recovered ₹1.04 lakh from the arrested gang members.</li>
<li>Shakti Kapoor was offered ₹5 lakh to attend an event, but the deal fell through.</li>
<li>Authorities are investigating potential links to other kidnappings of film stars.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The gang was involved in kidnapping film stars by sending advance payments and air tickets under the guise of event invitations.”</blockquote>
<p>The investigation continues as police seek to uncover further connections to the gang and other possible victims.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/actor-mushtaq-khans-kidnappers-also-planned-to-take-shakti-kapoor-hostage-cops-7257503</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/actor-mushtaq-khans-kidnappers-also-planned-to-take-shakti-kapoor-hostage-cops-7257503</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:36:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Vivian Dsena nominates Karan Veer Mehra; says ‘main tera dost nahi hu’ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18: Vivian Dsena nominates Karan Veer Mehra; says ‘main tera dost nahi hu’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [date unspecified] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116349277,imgsize-31642,width-400,resizemode-4/116349277.jpg" alt="Bigg Boss 18: Vivian Dsena nominates Karan Veer Mehra; says ‘main tera dost nahi hu’" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Vivian Dsena during the nomination task</figcaption><p>In the upcoming episode of <em>Bigg Boss 18</em>, relationships are set to shift dramatically during the nomination task as Vivian Dsena makes a bold move.</p><ul><li>Vivian Dsena nominates Karan Veer Mehra and Shilpa Shirodkar, ending his friendship with Karan.</li><li>During the nomination, Vivian declared, “Dosti, frenemy, let me make it clear… main tera dost nahi hu.”</li><li>Nouran, Vivian's wife, criticized him for being too loyal and not assertive enough.</li><li>The nominations could lead to major shifts in house dynamics and confrontations.</li></ul><blockquote>“You having a soft corner for him boils my blood. He’s been using you since the third week.” - Nouran</blockquote><p>This decisive move by Vivian signals a turning point in the game as fans eagerly await the upcoming developments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-vivian-dsena-nominates-karan-veer-mehra-says-main-tera-dost-nahi-hu/articleshow/116349279.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-vivian-dsena-nominates-karan-veer-mehra-says-main-tera-dost-nahi-hu/articleshow/116349279.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' box office collection Day 11: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna starrer crosses Rs 900 crore ma - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-11-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-crosses-rs-900-crore-mark-beats-rrr-to-record-3rd-highest-worldwide-gross-for-indian-movie/articleshow/116349347.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-11-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-crosses-rs-900-crore-mark-beats-rrr-to-record-3rd-highest-worldwide-gross-for-indian-movie/articleshow/116349347.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tabla Maestro Zakir Hussain Dies At 73, Confirms Family - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tributes Pour In As Tabla Maestro Zakir Hussain Passes Away At 73</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Unspecified News Source</p><p>Zakir Hussain, the celebrated tabla maestro, passed away due to complications from idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. He is mourned by his family and music lovers worldwide.</p><ul><li>Zakir Hussain died in a San Francisco hospital at the age of 73.</li><li>He was known as the greatest tabla player of his time, leaving behind a rich legacy.</li><li>Hussain had been hospitalized for two weeks prior to his death.</li><li>His collaborations with both Indian and international artists significantly influenced the world of music.</li><li>Hussain received multiple prestigious awards, including four Grammy Awards and several Padma honors.</li><li>Messages of condolence and tributes highlighted his humility and immense contributions to music.</li></ul><blockquote>“He leaves behind an extraordinary legacy cherished by countless music lovers around the globe.”</blockquote><p>Hussain's impact on both Indian classical music and Western music through innovative collaborations is celebrated, with his influence expected to resonate for generations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/tabla-maestro-zakir-hussain-dies-at-73-report-7257284</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/tabla-maestro-zakir-hussain-dies-at-73-report-7257284</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:00:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today, December 16, 2024: Check here Astrological prediction for all zodiac signs - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAJBVV95cUxPb09wTlJKMWNhY2V3NzFsX0VFTkl5N3RCTXpBOHRfODZqZEFUU095S2NhVDA5MTV3Y0ZLdnF4eE55M0E0WThFSy1VcFpEX01iN2Q1QTU2SlVEdE16Zkxndk9JckxCZ0tyVjZzU0RsbW8tc1RPTmdVUl9ibWZ6SUl2S1QyVnEwTzRURjIteklMMzliMXM5WnVjOXVyVWlYZ05rYUtGY1VHNml1NjJ4cExjMW03X3l6cVNobVR4ZU1HT3p6RDFCdTU3Qzh6TzFuNDJNZEVjaG5SUF9EdUJIUWpFaGNjTXhib2pKLTM5ZXR4aUlRQ29vYUlUbzduUUx4SGlzRlBBLXM2dWdBeUNHMWxrQdIBlgJBVV95cUxPX1MyZC1xc2x2TkIycUlYWG8zMXFoMWszeFB0VDhpd2ZSN3ZjRkI0M19aZDU1X1MyWTRGZFVTQk1RdHU5YzFiWDhyWHdCdjNib2JTODYxbnVTM19CZmczZFdzVTRYVlJ2eVBaX1VWRTAxTXVaYUNHWThBaGJZbUNJQ29pb1V5UlI0dmxFS1RPRUhCRlZ0andOM0pMalM1aEs4czVxSlFxbXNiT2EyWWJLLXVkWEY5eTBOcnVFcFNRYTZ5NFdiajliYk0zTmNIUHpQemZvRThHUGM3S2NQMkQ0aWpKUlY2eWNnNU00TUdvQ3ItZVJMRVRsbV8tQl93Nmt4dm9ZUWdrd0JoSTZHM3JOMS1DcGZ3QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAJBVV95cUxPb09wTlJKMWNhY2V3NzFsX0VFTkl5N3RCTXpBOHRfODZqZEFUU095S2NhVDA5MTV3Y0ZLdnF4eE55M0E0WThFSy1VcFpEX01iN2Q1QTU2SlVEdE16Zkxndk9JckxCZ0tyVjZzU0RsbW8tc1RPTmdVUl9ibWZ6SUl2S1QyVnEwTzRURjIteklMMzliMXM5WnVjOXVyVWlYZ05rYUtGY1VHNml1NjJ4cExjMW03X3l6cVNobVR4ZU1HT3p6RDFCdTU3Qzh6TzFuNDJNZEVjaG5SUF9EdUJIUWpFaGNjTXhib2pKLTM5ZXR4aUlRQ29vYUlUbzduUUx4SGlzRlBBLXM2dWdBeUNHMWxrQdIBlgJBVV95cUxPX1MyZC1xc2x2TkIycUlYWG8zMXFoMWszeFB0VDhpd2ZSN3ZjRkI0M19aZDU1X1MyWTRGZFVTQk1RdHU5YzFiWDhyWHdCdjNib2JTODYxbnVTM19CZmczZFdzVTRYVlJ2eVBaX1VWRTAxTXVaYUNHWThBaGJZbUNJQ29pb1V5UlI0dmxFS1RPRUhCRlZ0andOM0pMalM1aEs4czVxSlFxbXNiT2EyWWJLLXVkWEY5eTBOcnVFcFNRYTZ5NFdiajliYk0zTmNIUHpQemZvRThHUGM3S2NQMkQ0aWpKUlY2eWNnNU00TUdvQ3ItZVJMRVRsbV8tQl93Nmt4dm9ZUWdrd0JoSTZHM3JOMS1DcGZ3QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tabla maestro Zakir Hussain dies at 73 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tabla Maestro Zakir Hussain Passes Away at 73</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024<br /><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/a6gqb7/article68989781.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_15_2024_000279B.jpg" alt="Ustad Zakir Hussain performs during the 100th birth anniversary of his father Ustad Alla Rakha, in Ahmedabad." title="Ustad Zakir Hussain performs during the 100th birth anniversary of his father Ustad Alla Rakha, in Ahmedabad."><figcaption>Ustad Zakir Hussain performs during the 100th birth anniversary of his father Ustad Alla Rakha, in Ahmedabad. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>Tabla maestro Zakir Hussain has passed away at the age of 73 due to complications from idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis.</p><ul><li>He was hospitalized for the last two weeks before being moved to the ICU.</li><li>Hussain was a four-time Grammy Award winner, with three awards received at the 66th Grammy Awards earlier in 2024.</li><li>His career spanned six decades, collaborating with many renowned artists and blending Indian classical music with jazz.</li><li>He was awarded the Padma Shri in 1988, Padma Bhushan in 2002, and Padma Vibhushan in 2023.</li></ul><blockquote>“He defined the sound of the tabla and brought it into the international music scene.”</blockquote><p>The passing of Zakir Hussain marks a significant loss for music lovers and the cultural landscape of India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/music/tabla-maestro-zakir-hussain-dies-at-73/article68990583.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/music/tabla-maestro-zakir-hussain-dies-at-73/article68990583.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Antony weds Keerthy: All about Keerthy Suresh's breathtaking Christian wedding gown - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Antony weds Keerthy: All about Keerthy Suresh's breathtaking Christian wedding gown</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116342443,imgsize-25666,width-400,resizemode-4/116342443.jpg" alt="Antony weds Keerthy: All about Keerthy Suresh's breathtaking Christian wedding gown">
<figcaption>Keerthy Suresh in her breathtaking wedding gown.</figcaption>
<p>Keerthy Suresh has recently married her long-time partner, Antony Thattil, in a beautiful destination wedding in Goa, celebrating their love with a blend of personal and cultural traditions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Keerthy and Antony were in a relationship for 15 years before tying the knot.</li>
  <li>The wedding included both a traditional South Indian ceremony and a Christian wedding.</li>
  <li>Keerthy wore a stunning lace white gown with a turtle neck and keyhole cut-out, complemented by a transparent veil.</li>
  <li>Antony was elegantly dressed in a satin silver tuxedo.</li>
  <li>Their wedding celebrations captured joyful moments, including a memorable kiss and dance at the after-party.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The couple's wedding was a beautiful blend of traditions, love, and celebration.”</blockquote>
<p>The wedding of Keerthy and Antony not only marked a significant personal milestone but also delighted fans with its intimate and picturesque celebration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/fashion/celeb-style/antony-weds-keerthy-all-about-keerthy-sureshs-breathtaking-christian-wedding-gown/articleshow/116342443.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/fashion/celeb-style/antony-weds-keerthy-all-about-keerthy-sureshs-breathtaking-christian-wedding-gown/articleshow/116342443.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paatal Lok-Season 2 OTT release: Jaideep Ahlawat's thriller to stream on THIS platform; check plot, crew and more | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Paatal Lok-Season 2 OTT release: Jaideep Ahlawat’s thriller to stream on THIS platform; check plot, crew and more</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The web series continues the story of inspector Haathi Ram Choudhary as he navigates a high-profile conspiracy. Season 2 promises to delve deeper into the underworld's connection to power and corruption.</p><h2>About Paatal Lok Season 2:</h2><p>The announcement for season 2 was made earlier this year, introducing new characters including Tillotama Shome and Anurag Arora.</p><h2>First Look:</h2><blockquote>"Two seemingly disconnected cases get Hathiram and Ansari to work together again, sending them down the track of a nebulous conspiracy."</blockquote><h2>Jaideep Ahlawat's Post:</h2><blockquote>"HaathiRam is Back ❤️❤️❤️" — Jaideep Ahlawat</blockquote><p>Fans are buzzing with excitement over the upcoming season and expressing their anticipation on social media.</p><h2>Fans React:</h2><ul><li>Some fans expressed concern over the long wait for new episodes.</li><li>Others are eager for the return of beloved characters.</li></ul><p>For more updates, stay tuned to Live Mint.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/paatal-lok-season-2-ott-release-jaideep-ahlawats-thriller-to-feature-on-this-platform-check-plot-crew-and-more-11734168771082.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/paatal-lok-season-2-ott-release-jaideep-ahlawats-thriller-to-feature-on-this-platform-check-plot-crew-and-more-11734168771082.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 23:53:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun Meets Chiranjeevi After Walking Out Of Jail In Fan's Death Case | Photo - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjun-meets-chiranjeevi-after-walking-out-of-jail-in-fans-death-case-photo-9156963.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjun-meets-chiranjeevi-after-walking-out-of-jail-in-fans-death-case-photo-9156963.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 23:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Varun Dhawan Reveals Why Baby John Differs From Thalapathy Vijay’s Theri: 'It’s More Of An Adaptation' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Varun Dhawan Talks About 'Baby John' Being an Adaptation of 'Theri'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Varun Dhawan confirms Baby John is an adaptation of Theri, offering a fresh storyline with themes of parenting and women’s safety." title="Varun Dhawan confirms Baby John is an adaptation of Theri, offering a fresh storyline with themes of parenting and women’s safety."><figcaption>Varun Dhawan confirms Baby John is an adaptation of Theri, offering a fresh storyline with themes of parenting and women’s safety.</figcaption><p>Varun Dhawan is excited about his upcoming film, Baby John, clarifying it as an adaptation of the Tamil hit Theri. He emphasizes the differences in storyline and themes, notably focusing on parenting and women's safety.</p><ul><li>Varun Dhawan clarifies that Baby John is not a direct remake of Theri but an adaptation.</li><li>The film will feature a new storyline with a focus on modern parenting and women's safety issues in India.</li><li>The project includes a stellar cast and special appearances, enhancing its appeal.</li><li>Dhawan's character is depicted as a dedicated father balancing his job as a police officer.</li><li>The film is set to release on December 25, 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>“If someone comes in expecting a book-by-book remake, they will be disappointed because that’s not what the film is. It’s an adaptation.” - Varun Dhawan</blockquote><p>The movie, produced by Jio Studios and others, aims to deliver a unique cinematic experience during the holiday season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/varun-dhawan-reveals-why-baby-john-differs-from-thalapathy-vijays-theri-its-more-of-an-adaptation-9156927.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/varun-dhawan-reveals-why-baby-john-differs-from-thalapathy-vijays-theri-its-more-of-an-adaptation-9156927.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Triptii Dimri Avoids Paps As She Gets Spotted With Rumoured BF Sam Merchant, Says ‘Jao Please’ | Watch - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Triptii Dimri Avoids Paps As She Gets Spotted With Rumoured BF Sam Merchant, Says ‘Jao Please’ | Watch</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> December 15, 2024, 20:22 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Triptii Dimri and Sam Merchant spotted in the city" title="Triptii Dimri and Sam Merchant spotted in the city"><figcaption>Triptii Dimri and Sam Merchant spotted in the city</figcaption></figure><p>Triptii Dimri was recently spotted with her rumoured boyfriend Sam Merchant. Despite frequently getting attention from the paparazzi, she made it clear that she prefers her privacy.</p><ul><li>Triptii Dimri was last seen in the film Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3.</li><li>She was papped leaving a restaurant, wearing a black t-shirt and denim.</li><li>In a viral video, she requested the paparazzi, ‘Jao jao please’.</li><li>She attended a recent Bryan Adams concert where she shared moments on her social media.</li></ul><blockquote>“Jao jao please” - Triptii Dimri when asked to pose for the paparazzi.</blockquote><p>This incident showcases the ongoing interest in her personal life and her desire to maintain a level of privacy amid public curiosity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/triptii-dimri-avoids-paps-as-she-gets-spotted-with-rumoured-bf-sam-merchant-says-jao-please-watch-9156921.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/triptii-dimri-avoids-paps-as-she-gets-spotted-with-rumoured-bf-sam-merchant-says-jao-please-watch-9156921.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inside Ranbir Kapoor-Alia Bhatt's Massive Kitchen: Photos With Raha, Centralised AC And More | Watch - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Inside Ranbir Kapoor-Alia Bhatt's Massive Kitchen: Photos With Raha, Centralised AC And More | Watch</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> December 15, 2024, 20:22 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="A look at Ranbir Kapoor and Alia Bhatt's kitchen. "><figcaption>A look at Ranbir Kapoor and Alia Bhatt's kitchen.</figcaption></figure><p>A video from Ranbir Kapoor and Alia Bhatt’s home has surfaced online, offering a glimpse into their expansive kitchen. The couple has kept the design simple yet personalized, featuring handmade artwork with their daughter Raha and fridge magnets of animated animals.</p><ul><li>The kitchen has centralised AC and a stove hood for efficient cooking.</li><li>Brightly lit with a massive window.</li><li>The new house is under construction, with the couple frequently checking on progress.</li><li>Their previous bungalow on Pali Hill has been replaced with a planned 8-storey building.</li></ul><blockquote>“The kitchen is simply filled with appliances that they need for everyday use.”</blockquote><p>Ranbir and Alia’s love nest reflects their personal touches while maintaining practicality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/inside-ranbir-kapoor-alia-bhatts-massive-kitchen-photos-with-raha-centralised-ac-and-more-watch-9156895.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/inside-ranbir-kapoor-alia-bhatts-massive-kitchen-photos-with-raha-centralised-ac-and-more-watch-9156895.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Vivian Dsena’s Wife Slams Karan Veer Mehra, Calls Him a ‘Junior Artist’ - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nouran Aly’s fiery response to Karan’s ‘Junior Artist’ remark sparks Vivian Dsena’s comeback era</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Sunday, December 15, 2024 at 10:10 PM</p><figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/8036-bb18.jpg" width="640" height="360" alt="bb18" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Source: JioCinema</figcaption></figure><p>Nouran Aly, an Egyptian journalist, provided Vivian Dsena with direct feedback during an episode of <a href="https://www.indiaforums.com/show/bigg-boss-18_7251" title="Bigg Boss 18">Bigg Boss 18</a>, urging him to be more assertive in the game and confront his opponents instead of playing safe. She strongly criticized his gameplay and highlighted concerns about his relationships in the house.</p><ul><li>Nouran criticized Vivian for not standing up for himself and being too passive.</li><li>She accused fellow contestant Avinash Mishra of misleading Vivian to advance his own game.</li><li>Nouran mentioned Karan Veer Mehra's earlier comments, referring to him as a 'Junior Artist' and emphasized her disapproval of him.</li><li>The criticism came after both Salman Khan and Farah Khan expressed disappointment in Vivian's gameplay.</li></ul><blockquote>“Karan has stated clearly that he’s not your friend. I don’t want to be friends with someone like him, not even an enemy.” - Nouran Aly</blockquote><p>This candid feedback and the surrounding drama have fans speculating about possible shifts in Vivian's strategy moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/bigg-boss-18-vivian-dsenas-wife-slams-karan-veer-mehra-calls-him-a-junior-artist_215452</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/bigg-boss-18-vivian-dsenas-wife-slams-karan-veer-mehra-calls-him-a-junior-artist_215452</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:44:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 predicts good news - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Aquarius_1728478944944_1734286874591.jpg" alt="Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Stay away from office romance which may impact productivity as well as the domestic life." title="Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Stay away from office romance which may impact productivity as well as the domestic life.">
<figcaption>Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Stay away from office romance which may impact productivity as well as the domestic life.</figcaption>
<p>Today is a good day for Aquarius individuals as they are predicted to be star performers. Relationship issues should be resolved for better opportunities in career.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Minor monetary issues will not affect routine life.</li>
  <li>Be cordial with team members to boost professional performance.</li>
  <li>It’s a good time to discuss marriage or long-term commitments in relationships.</li>
  <li>Businessmen may find new partnerships that help expand trade.</li>
  <li>Health may have minor issues, but overall well-being remains stable.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Today is good to discuss marriage. A vacation to a hill station can do wonders in your relationship.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the horoscope suggests a productive day with numerous opportunities, emphasizing the importance of conflict resolution in personal and professional spheres.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/aquarius-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-good-news-101734284244636.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/aquarius-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-good-news-101734284244636.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:40:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 predicts signing new deals - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 predicts signing new deals</h1><p><strong>Date: December 16, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Capricorn_1728478974232_1734286841070.jpg" alt="Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Diplomatic handling of professional challenges will help you achieve official targets today." title="Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Diplomatic handling of professional challenges will help you achieve official targets today."><figcaption>Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Diplomatic handling of professional challenges will help you achieve official targets today.</figcaption></figure><p>Today is a promising day for Capricorns, with confidence helping to overcome professional challenges. Enhancements in love and minor financial matters are advised.</p><ul><li>Handle wealth carefully and make safe monetary decisions.</li><li>Businessmen will successfully sign new deals to expand their ventures.</li><li>Consider romantic outings or surprises for loved ones.</li><li>Health remains positive without major issues on the horizon.</li></ul><blockquote>“Diplomatic handling of professional challenges will help you achieve official targets today.”</blockquote><p>In summary, today’s predictions encourage strategic handling of relationships and finances, while highlighting opportunities for growth in various aspects of life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/capricorn-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-signing-new-deals-101734284234394.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/capricorn-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-signing-new-deals-101734284234394.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 predicts new love - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 predicts new love</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Sagittarius_1728479012112_1734286819761.jpg" alt="Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Be careful while you make statements as this can lead to tremors in the love affair." title="Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Be careful while you make statements as this can lead to tremors in the love affair."><figcaption>Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Be careful while you make statements as this can lead to tremors in the love affair.</figcaption></figure><p>Today's horoscope emphasizes the importance of open communication in love and career, encouraging Sagittarius natives to make smart decisions.</p><ul><li>Today, Sagittarius may find new love or make significant progress in existing relationships.</li><li>Proper communication is vital to avoid misunderstandings in love.</li><li>Career opportunities are on the rise, with new responsibilities expected.</li><li>Financial prospects look good, with recommendations for smart investments.</li><li>Health is stable; maintaining a healthy diet is advised.</li></ul><blockquote>"Single Sagittarius natives may find new love today. Married females may also conceive today."</blockquote><p>The horoscope suggests a balanced day ahead, with numerous opportunities for growth in personal, professional, and financial aspects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/sagittarius-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-new-love-101734284226616.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/sagittarius-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-new-love-101734284226616.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 predicts an offer letter - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scorpio Daily Horoscope for December 16, 2024: An Offer Letter Awaits</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/scorpio_1728479075489_1734286796608.jpg" alt="Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Be active at the office and also stay cool even while having tough deadlines." title="Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Be active at the office and also stay cool even while having tough deadlines."><figcaption>Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Be active at the office and also stay cool even while having tough deadlines.</figcaption></figure><p>This daily horoscope for Scorpio highlights emotional management, the promise of financial success, and significant opportunities in career and love life today.</p><ul><li>Scorpios are advised to handle emotions efficiently.</li><li>Career opportunities are favorable, with successful interviews likely leading to job offers.</li><li>Positive financial prospects are anticipated, with recommendations to save for future needs.</li><li>Health warnings are noted for those with heart-related issues.</li><li>Romantic prospects are good, with opportunities for proposals and resolving relationship issues.</li></ul><blockquote>"Those who have interviews lined up will be successful in grabbing an offer letter today."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Scorpios should leverage today's auspicious energies in both their professional and personal lives while caring for their health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/scorpio-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-an-offer-letter-101734284220309.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/scorpio-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-an-offer-letter-101734284220309.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Libra Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 predicts new assignments - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Libra Daily Horoscope for December 16, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Libra_1728479045617_1734286760515.jpg" alt="Libra Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. At the office, handle new assignments to gain better professional growth." title="Libra Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. At the office, handle new assignments to gain better professional growth.">
<figcaption>Libra Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. At the office, handle new assignments to gain better professional growth.</figcaption>
<p>The Libra horoscope for today suggests focusing on new assignments at work and balancing personal relationships. Financial prospects are bright, with recommendations to make strategic decisions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Focus on professional growth by handling new assignments at work.</li>
  <li>Success in personal relationships is possible; consider taking love affairs to the next level.</li>
  <li>Warning against office politics and disputes; maintain a professional demeanor.</li>
  <li>Financial health is stable, possibly leading to major purchases like a car.</li>
  <li>Minor health issues may arise but overall well-being is positive.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Bring happiness to the lives of people around." - Dr. J.N. Pandey</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, today's horoscope emphasizes the importance of maintaining a positive attitude in both personal and professional aspects, taking advantage of incoming opportunities while being cautious with relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/libra-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-new-assignments-101734284208757.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/libra-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-new-assignments-101734284208757.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:36:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 predicts best performance - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 predicts best performance</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 <br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Virgo_1728479056525_1734286740124.jpg" alt="Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Take up new roles at the office and give the best performance."><figcaption>Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Take up new roles at the office and give the best performance.</figcaption></figure><p>Today’s horoscope predicts that Virgos should focus on positive goals and productivity at work while addressing minor relationship issues.</p><ul><li>Minor relationship issues may arise; it's vital to address them.</li><li>Financial prosperity is likely, but health requires special attention.</li><li>Avoid office politics and focus on personal performance.</li><li>Investments should be approached with caution.</li><li>Viral illnesses and minor health concerns may be prevalent today.</li></ul><blockquote>"Settle the monetary issue involving a friend or sibling today."</blockquote><p>The day offers good potential for career advancements and addressing financial matters, making it a balanced day for Virgos.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/virgo-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-best-performance-101734284199353.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/virgo-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-best-performance-101734284199353.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:35:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leo Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 predicts new responsibilities - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Leo Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024 Predicts New Responsibilities</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Leo_1728478322188_1734286722415.jpg" alt="Leo Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Be ready to crack job interviews today and businessmen can launch new ideas." title="Leo Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Be ready to crack job interviews today and businessmen can launch new ideas."><figcaption>Leo Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 16, 2024. Be ready to crack job interviews today and businessmen can launch new ideas.</figcaption></figure><p>The Leo horoscope for December 16, 2024, emphasizes taking on new responsibilities and utilizing confidence as a key asset. Financial stability is highlighted, though health issues may arise.</p><ul><li>Confidence will help with job interviews and business ventures.</li><li>Resolution of minor love life issues is necessary.</li><li>Professional discipline and facing competition at work are crucial.</li><li>Financial caution is advised; saving is prioritized.</li><li>Health concerns should be addressed promptly.</li></ul><blockquote>"Resolve the minor issues in the love life and take up new responsibilities to prove the mettle at the workplace."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Leo individuals should embrace new tasks and maintain a healthy lifestyle while navigating professional challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/leo-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-new-responsibilities-101734284189975.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/leo-daily-horoscope-today-dec-16-2024-predicts-new-responsibilities-101734284189975.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:34:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>