<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 02:50:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 02:50:25 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE SmackDown Results – 12/20/24 (Women’s Tag Titles on the line, and more!) - Wrestleview.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WWE SmackDown Results – December 20, 2024</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Wrestleview.com</p><p><em>Location:</em> Hartford, Connecticut (XL Center)</p><p>This episode of WWE SmackDown featured exciting matches leading up to the end of the year, including a Women’s Tag Team Championship match and confrontations between major wrestlers.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The Bloodline defeated LA Knight, Apollo Crews, and Andrade.</li><li>Carmelo Hayes won against Braun Strowman via count-out.</li><li>Johnny Gargano defeated Alex Shelley in a grudge match.</li><li>The main event featured Bianca Belair and Naomi defending their titles against Nia Jax and Candice LeRae.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes:</h2><blockquote>“Good match here between Gargano and Shelley. Commercial break and slightly goofy finish aside, a bit of fun seeing this DIY-MCMG feud continue.” — Wrestleview.com</blockquote><p>As the year closes, WWE continues to build thrilling storylines and matches, promising an exciting transition into the new year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wrestleview.com/top-story/336664-wwe-smackdown-results-12-20-24-womens-tag-titles-on-the-line-and-more/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wrestleview.com/top-story/336664-wwe-smackdown-results-12-20-24-womens-tag-titles-on-the-line-and-more/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 01:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' box office collection day 16: The Allu Arjun starrer crosses Rs 1000 crore at the box office, - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Collection Day 16: The Allu Arjun Starrer Crosses Rs 1000 Crore at the Box Office</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here]<strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>This article discusses the box office performance of 'Pushpa 2', which has now crossed the significant milestone of Rs 1000 crore in collections, with expectations to surpass 'Baahubali 2'.</p><ul><li>After 16 days of release, 'Pushpa 2' has achieved a box office collection of over Rs 1000 crores.</li><li>The film, starring Allu Arjun, is expected to set new records in Indian cinema.</li><li>Comparisons are being made with previous blockbusters like 'Baahubali 2'.</li></ul><blockquote>"Pushpa 2 is on track to become one of the highest-grossing films in Indian history."</blockquote><p>This growth signifies a positive trend in the Indian film industry, emphasizing the popularity of regional cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-16-the-allu-arjun-starrer-crosses-rs-1000-crore-at-the-box-office-on-its-way-to-beat-baahubali-2/articleshow/116520534.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-16-the-allu-arjun-starrer-crosses-rs-1000-crore-at-the-box-office-on-its-way-to-beat-baahubali-2/articleshow/116520534.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai Bachchan shields daughter Aaradhya from flashlights while leaving with Abhishek Bachchan, s - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan Shields Daughter Aaradhya from Flashlights</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 25, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/7452dd94a4a1ceb1e3ed6a9ef6111ecb.jpg" alt="Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and Aaradhya" /><figcaption>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and daughter Aaradhya shielding from cameras.</figcaption><p>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan was seen shielding her daughter Aaradhya from flash photography while departing with husband Abhishek Bachchan, leading to mixed reactions online.</p><ul><li>Viewers expressed polarized opinions on whether a 13-year-old should be protected from media attention.</li><li>The incident sparked discussions about celebrity privacy and the ethics of photographing children.</li><li>Comments ranged from support for the protective behavior to criticism of the overreaction.</li></ul><blockquote>“She is 13, not 3,” commented one user, highlighting the divide in perspectives.</blockquote><p>This incident underscores the ongoing debate surrounding celebrity privacy and the protection of minors in the public eye.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aishwarya-rai-bachchan-shields-daughter-aaradhya-from-flashlights-while-leaving-with-abhishek-bachchan-sparks-mixed-reactions-online-she-is-13-not-3/articleshow/116517638.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aishwarya-rai-bachchan-shields-daughter-aaradhya-from-flashlights-while-leaving-with-abhishek-bachchan-sparks-mixed-reactions-online-she-is-13-not-3/articleshow/116517638.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 22:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai Bachchan's caring moment for mother Vrinda Rai at Aaradhya Bachchan's school annual functio - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan's Caring Moment for Mother Vrinda Rai at Aaradhya Bachchan's School Annual Function Wins Hearts</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided]<strong> Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p>
<p>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan was spotted sharing a touching moment with her mother, Vrinda Rai, during her daughter Aaradhya's school annual function, which has evoked a heartwarming response from fans.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan attended her daughter Aaradhya's school annual function.</li>
  <li>She was seen caring for her mother, Vrinda Rai, during the event.</li>
  <li>The moment captured was received warmly by attendees and fans alike.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Seeing Aishwarya with her mother at such a special occasion truly warms the heart.”</blockquote>
<p>This heartfelt gesture resonates with fans, showcasing the importance of family bonds.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aishwarya-rai-bachchans-caring-moment-for-mother-vrinda-rai-at-aaradhya-bachchans-school-annual-function-wins-hearts/articleshow/116515875.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aishwarya-rai-bachchans-caring-moment-for-mother-vrinda-rai-at-aaradhya-bachchans-school-annual-function-wins-hearts/articleshow/116515875.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 19:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ram Kapoor Surprises Fans With A Drastic Weight Loss Transformation | Check Pics Inside - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ram Kapoor Surprises Fans With A Drastic Weight Loss Transformation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='Ram Kapoor hinted that he lost 42 kgs.' title='Ram Kapoor hinted that he lost 42 kgs.' loading='eager'><figcaption>Ram Kapoor hinted that he lost 42 kgs.</figcaption></figure><p>Actor Ram Kapoor wowed his fans with a selfie showcasing his impressive weight loss transformation. After a hiatus from social media, he reemerged looking fit and healthy.</p><ul><li>Best known for his role in 'Bade Achhe Lagte Hai', Ram Kapoor shared his transformation on Instagram.</li><li>In a recent outing, he was seen with his wife, Gautami Kapoor, flaunting his new look.</li><li>Ram hinted that he has lost 42 kgs, although he did not specify the methods used to achieve this.</li><li>His transformation has drawn admiration and compliments from fans and celebrities alike.</li></ul><blockquote>“Hi guys, sorry for the slightly long absence from Insta, was working on myself quite extensively.”</blockquote><p>Ram Kapoor's drastic weight loss transformation has both surprised and inspired many of his fans, leading to widespread praise across social media.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-ram-kapoor-surprises-fans-with-a-drastic-weight-loss-transformation-check-pics-inside-9162646.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-ram-kapoor-surprises-fans-with-a-drastic-weight-loss-transformation-check-pics-inside-9162646.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 19:03:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adrija Roy replaces Alisha Parveen to play new female lead in Anupamaa - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Adrija Roy Takes Over as Female Lead in Anupamaa</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Friday, December 20, 2024 at 6:46 PM <strong>Source:</strong> <a href="https://www.indiaforums.com/channel/star-plus_1">Star Plus</a></p><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/8671-adrija-roy.jpg" width="640" height="359" alt="Adrija roy"><figcaption>Adrija Roy</figcaption><p>The popular show Anupamaa continues to make headlines as actress Alisha Praveen, who played the character Rahi, is replaced by Adrija Roy.</p><ul><li>Alisha Praveen was reportedly surprised and disappointed to be replaced without prior notice.</li><li>Adrija Roy has been approached to take over the role of Rahi.</li><li>Adrija has conducted a mock shoot for the character and is poised to step into the role soon.</li><li>She is known for her previous work in Imlie and Kundali Bhagya.</li></ul><blockquote>“I did not leave the show by choice,” - Alisha Praveen on her replacement.</blockquote><p>With Adrija's entry into Anupamaa, fans anticipate how her portrayal of Rahi will resonate with the show's audience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/adrija-roy-replaces-alisha-parveen-to-play-new-female-lead-in-anupamaa_215705</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/adrija-roy-replaces-alisha-parveen-to-play-new-female-lead-in-anupamaa_215705</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:51:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive - Bigg Boss 18: Digvijay Singh Rathee joins Salman Khan on WKV after eviction; Karan Veer Mehra - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Exclusive - Bigg Boss 18: Digvijay Singh Rathee joins Salman Khan on WKV after eviction; Karan Veer Mehra and Chum Darang blame Shrutika Arjun for his elimination</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>After being evicted from Bigg Boss 18, Digvijay Singh Rathee joins Salman Khan on Weekend Ka Vaar. Fellow contestants Karan Veer Mehra and Chum Darang point fingers at Shrutika Arjun for his exit.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Digvijay Singh Rathee participated in Bigg Boss 18.</li>
  <li>He was recently evicted from the show.</li>
  <li>Salman Khan hosts Weekend Ka Vaar where he gives insights on the show.</li>
  <li>Karan Veer Mehra and Chum Darang accuse Shrutika Arjun of playing a role in Rathee's elimination.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There were many factors that contributed to Digvijay’s elimination, and Shrutika played a significant part in it,” - Karan Veer Mehra.</blockquote>
<p>This season of Bigg Boss continues to surprise with unexpected eliminations and contestant dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/exclusive-bigg-boss-18-digvijay-singh-rathee-joins-salman-khan-on-wkv-after-eviction-karan-veer-mehra-and-chum-darang-blame-shrutika-arjun-for-his-elimination/articleshow/116513797.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/exclusive-bigg-boss-18-digvijay-singh-rathee-joins-salman-khan-on-wkv-after-eviction-karan-veer-mehra-and-chum-darang-blame-shrutika-arjun-for-his-elimination/articleshow/116513797.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Box Office: 'UI', 'Marco', And 'Viduthalai Part - 2' Opening Day Early Estimates - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOZ2VwdngzV0E4OG9vR1VDZmFzODd3dElfMjhicFgzdDdYZ2FsNmhCZDZ0QWJ4Tkx6OHlLQ1BlUjBJbXBNdkNwdXhvR2JFOXFIenhud0E2RllGUmtsWmE4WjZOaUR2RjNfZmxZT2tjTEQ5Q3FiVUY4M09iU2hQNDNTZDZPZ3RvQWJrLUloekZvd05LVkNNU2VUenptSFlqYnNP?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOZ2VwdngzV0E4OG9vR1VDZmFzODd3dElfMjhicFgzdDdYZ2FsNmhCZDZ0QWJ4Tkx6OHlLQ1BlUjBJbXBNdkNwdXhvR2JFOXFIenhud0E2RllGUmtsWmE4WjZOaUR2RjNfZmxZT2tjTEQ5Q3FiVUY4M09iU2hQNDNTZDZPZ3RvQWJrLUloekZvd05LVkNNU2VUenptSFlqYnNP?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:35:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marco Box Office Collection Day 1 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE5jQnZlbHE4LXJSRVJXdDBETTVSMVhacldsTllVajdmTmRPSGlmeW95TWR2Sm9nWTBnRFJmeEw4OUlIdW1Genh6WG1yU2wwdzNCb2RBNnFmTmFqNFJTNzNwU1NHNlp4QjhHRzE0NGRYUWgtdko0TEs3NGhaWkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE5jQnZlbHE4LXJSRVJXdDBETTVSMVhacldsTllVajdmTmRPSGlmeW95TWR2Sm9nWTBnRFJmeEw4OUlIdW1Genh6WG1yU2wwdzNCb2RBNnFmTmFqNFJTNzNwU1NHNlp4QjhHRzE0NGRYUWgtdko0TEs3NGhaWkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:55:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 The Rule box office collection day 16: Allu Arjun film glides past ₹1000 crore mark as it enters 3rd week - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 The Rule box office collection day 16</h1> <p><strong>Date: December 20, 2024 | Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p> <figure> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Pushpa_box_office_day_16_1734709891869_1734709907326.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 The Rule" title="Allu Arjun plays a red sanders smuggler called Pushpa Raj in the film."> <figcaption>Allu Arjun plays a red sanders smuggler called Pushpa Raj in the film.</figcaption> </figure> <p>Sukumar's Pushpa 2: The Rule continues to perform exceptionally well at the box office, crossing the ₹1000 crore mark in just 16 days.</p> <ul> <li>The film collected approximately ₹12.11 crore on day 16, totaling around ₹1002.71 crore net in India.</li> <li>In its first week, the film made ₹725.8 crore net, followed by ₹264.8 crore in the second week.</li> <li>Despite a 63.52% decrease in collections from week one to week two, the film's performance remains impressive.</li> <li>It grossed ₹632.50 crore net from Hindi markets alone in its first 15 days.</li> <li>World-wide, the film surpassed ₹1500 crore within 14 days.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“Enjoy the Biggest Film #Pushpa2 only on the Big Screens in this Biggest Holiday Season.”</blockquote> <p>In conclusion, Pushpa 2: The Rule is not only a commercial success but also a significant cultural phenomenon, resonating widely with audiences across various demographics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-the-rule-box-office-collection-day-16-allu-arjun-film-glides-past-1000-crore-mark-as-it-enters-3rd-week-101734709644304.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-the-rule-box-office-collection-day-16-allu-arjun-film-glides-past-1000-crore-mark-as-it-enters-3rd-week-101734709644304.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:37:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brad Pitt faces allegations of hiding 'embezzled property' amid War of Rose with Angelina Jolie - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Brad Pitt Faces Allegations of Hiding Embezzled Property in Legal Battle with Angelina Jolie</h1><p><strong>Publication Date & Source:</strong> December 2024, Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Shiloh-Jolie-Name-Change-0_1722329550914_1734711634318.jpg" alt="In a legal battle over Chateau Miraval, Brad Pitt is accused of embezzling assets by diverting funds for personal projects. (AP Photo/File)(AP)" title="In a legal battle over Chateau Miraval, Brad Pitt is accused of embezzling assets by diverting funds for personal projects. (AP Photo/File)(AP)"><figcaption>In a legal battle over Chateau Miraval, Brad Pitt is accused of embezzling assets by diverting funds for personal projects. (AP Photo/File)(AP)</figcaption></figure><p>Brad Pitt has been accused of hiding “embezzled assets” amid a legal dispute with Angelina Jolie over Chateau Miraval, the French winery they purchased together. The ongoing court battle highlights serious allegations of financial misconduct related to the ownership and management of the winery.</p><ul><li>Pitt is accused of concealing funds and diverting them for personal use instead of business purposes.</li><li>The legal dispute began in 2022, following Jolie's intent to exit their business partnership.</li><li>Jolie countersued for $250 million, claiming Pitt froze her out of operations.</li><li>Tenute del Mondo has alleged Pitt's team misappropriated funds intended for the winery.</li><li>Legal negotiations have involved claims and counterclaims between both parties regarding asset ownership.</li></ul><blockquote>“[Brad] caused Chateau Miraval’s funds and assets to be spent on his personal expenses and to be diverted to his other business ventures rather than be paid out as dividends.”</blockquote><p>The allegations have escalated the ongoing conflict, with both parties seeking to protect their financial interests in the winery. The outcome of this dispute may have lasting implications on their business dealings and personal lives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/brad-pitt-faces-allegations-of-hiding-embezzled-property-amid-war-of-rose-with-angelina-jolie-101734704893910.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/brad-pitt-faces-allegations-of-hiding-embezzled-property-amid-war-of-rose-with-angelina-jolie-101734704893910.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:21:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Joyful Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and Abhishek Bachchan attend Aaradhya Bachchan’s annual day with Vrinda Rai - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and Abhishek Bachchan Attend Aaradhya's School Event</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116510602,imgsize-25638,width-400,resizemode-4/116510602.jpg" alt="Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan at Aaradhya's school event"><figcaption>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and Abhishek Bachchan at their daughter Aaradhya's annual day celebration.</figcaption><p>On Friday evening, Bollywood couple Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and Abhishek Bachchan attended their daughter Aaradhya's school event alongside Aishwarya's mother, Vrinda Rai. This appearance comes after recent rumors of estrangement between the couple.</p><ul><li>Abhishek and Aishwarya were seen entering Dhirubhai Ambani International School in Mumbai.</li><li>The couple appeared proud, recording Aaradhya's performance on their phones during the event.</li><li>The annual day celebration attracted Bollywood's elite, including Shah Rukh Khan, Kareena Kapoor, and Saif Ali Khan.</li></ul><blockquote>Amitabh Bachchan expressed his pride, stating, “Children .. their innocence and desire to be at their best in the presence of parents .. such a delight.”</blockquote><p>The Bachchan family showcases their strong bond and support for Aaradhya through these public appearances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/joyful-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-and-abhishek-bachchan-attend-aaradhya-bachchans-annual-day-with-vrinda-rai-on-day-2-at-ambani-school/articleshow/116510614.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/joyful-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-and-abhishek-bachchan-attend-aaradhya-bachchans-annual-day-with-vrinda-rai-on-day-2-at-ambani-school/articleshow/116510614.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Joyful Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and Abhishek Bachchan attend Aaradhya Bachchan’s annual day with Vrinda Rai on day 2 at Ambani school - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and Abhishek Bachchan Attend Aaradhya’s Annual Day</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>On the second day of Aaradhya Bachchan's annual day celebrations at the Ambani school, Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and Abhishek Bachchan attended with their daughter Aaradhya, joined by grandmother Vrinda Rai.</p><ul><li>Aishwarya and Abhishek were spotted enjoying the event.</li><li>Aaradhya's school is known for hosting impressive annual showcases.</li><li>Family moments were highlighted during the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s a joy to be part of Aaradhya’s milestone,” expressed Abhishek Bachchan.</blockquote><p>This event reflects the close-knit family values cherished by the Bachchans, celebrating their daughter’s important moments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/joyful-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-and-abhishek-bachchan-attend-aaradhya-bachchans-annual-day-with-vrinda-rai-on-day-2-at-ambani-school/articleshow/116510614.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/joyful-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-and-abhishek-bachchan-attend-aaradhya-bachchans-annual-day-with-vrinda-rai-on-day-2-at-ambani-school/articleshow/116510614.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bibek Pangeni death: Wife Srijana Subedi’s unwavering devotion has the internet in tears - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nepali Influencer Bibek Pangeni's Death: A Tribute to His Wife Srijana Subedi</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 19, 2024<p><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</strong></p>
<p>Bibek Pangeni, a beloved social media influencer and PhD candidate, passed away after a courageous battle with a brain tumor. His wife, Srijana Subedi, exemplified unwavering support throughout his illness, touching the hearts of many.</p>
<h2>Key Points</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Bibek Pangeni lost his battle with cancer on December 19, 2024.</li>
  <li>His wife, Srijana Subedi, was a dedicated caregiver, showcasing unconditional love.</li>
  <li>The couple shared their journey on social media, offering insight into their struggles.</li>
  <li>Numerous tributes highlighted Srijana's devotion and the couple's bond.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Death leaves a deep pain that cannot be healed, love leaves behind precious memories that can never be taken away.”</blockquote>
<p>This tragedy sparked an emotional response from the public, reflecting the deep impact of their story.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/bibek-pangeni-death-wife-srijana-subedis-unwavering-devotion-has-the-internet-in-tears/articleshow/116509507.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/bibek-pangeni-death-wife-srijana-subedis-unwavering-devotion-has-the-internet-in-tears/articleshow/116509507.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nepali influencer Bibek Pangeni death: Wife Srijana Subedi’s unwavering devotion has the internet in tears - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxNMGJjZW0wTnhxSG5USTVybkc2TTNsSkxEaFFfZ3pkRm9sQ0NXdWNsajU3b182STg3WXRBM1o2d0FxTjFZcTVYcXI4cGFObFl0cjRwUlVrOHJqaTFmZ2hoVFB4d1dSSTgzMmJ0YkhXbVRlRGFVOWZ3b28tV1NxQ0Y4S1lUTUw0X1FESzVUem93N2ZLRndTYnJhVjZzRDRyMHgzSzMtOTRZRW1LZnRSWEVlUzQ3aUs4VUh4SUtWSzNhTVotd1RFcUNpZ0NkLWJiekVwR01YcmxqNVVuV0R6c0FkVVRKYWQ3aDBlSnpJbU1zVdIB9AFBVV95cUxQd19QdUxTTUpsLTltLWRiRFpKd3JqRzI5SFJ1aXJMamtRbFhHRnVINUh3RUI3LWFrcElmVFdvZ2pCTkF1UzN1MXFIU0RMNklHeEFrcGI1eXpjNVVYTW1DOWFuU0w0akdGVkVIM0JNODZqZjdrSjZFWHMzU29lN3gyZGF2eUg0NWdDSEYyNXNleUI4bHE2XzZ3VWNaU3UtWElNelpHX2pQZGRWemo4R0QwSmxoNW5kaDdVaHdTY0dDbUgwdWRTM0NZMlYzTjlvNUFVWWgtMmxoT3R1WlpjVmVFa3BzYzRCcHZ2MkhodXdadEZPdGJF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxNMGJjZW0wTnhxSG5USTVybkc2TTNsSkxEaFFfZ3pkRm9sQ0NXdWNsajU3b182STg3WXRBM1o2d0FxTjFZcTVYcXI4cGFObFl0cjRwUlVrOHJqaTFmZ2hoVFB4d1dSSTgzMmJ0YkhXbVRlRGFVOWZ3b28tV1NxQ0Y4S1lUTUw0X1FESzVUem93N2ZLRndTYnJhVjZzRDRyMHgzSzMtOTRZRW1LZnRSWEVlUzQ3aUs4VUh4SUtWSzNhTVotd1RFcUNpZ0NkLWJiekVwR01YcmxqNVVuV0R6c0FkVVRKYWQ3aDBlSnpJbU1zVdIB9AFBVV95cUxQd19QdUxTTUpsLTltLWRiRFpKd3JqRzI5SFJ1aXJMamtRbFhHRnVINUh3RUI3LWFrcElmVFdvZ2pCTkF1UzN1MXFIU0RMNklHeEFrcGI1eXpjNVVYTW1DOWFuU0w0akdGVkVIM0JNODZqZjdrSjZFWHMzU29lN3gyZGF2eUg0NWdDSEYyNXNleUI4bHE2XzZ3VWNaU3UtWElNelpHX2pQZGRWemo4R0QwSmxoNW5kaDdVaHdTY0dDbUgwdWRTM0NZMlYzTjlvNUFVWWgtMmxoT3R1WlpjVmVFa3BzYzRCcHZ2MkhodXdadEZPdGJF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai, Abhishek Bachchan accompany her mom to Aaradhya's school event. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan accompany her mom to Aaradhya's school event</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Aisarya_Rai_Abhishek_Bachchan_1734704703032_1734704710294.jpg" alt="Abhishek Bachchan and Aishwarya Rai with her mother Brindya Rai." title="Abhishek Bachchan and Aishwarya Rai with her mother Brindya Rai.">
<figcaption>Abhishek Bachchan and Aishwarya Rai with her mother Brindya Rai.</figcaption>
<p>Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan were recently spotted together at Aaradhya's school event, accompanied by Aishwarya's mother, Brindya. This marks a significant public portrayal of unity amidst recent rumors of marital strife.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The event took place at the Dhirubhai Ambani International School in Mumbai.</li>
  <li>Aishwarya and Abhishek's joint appearance has delighted fans, occurring just two days after their first public outing.</li>
  <li>Previous rumors about their relationship were fueled by separate poses at a recent wedding, but this appearance seems to curb those speculations.</li>
  <li>Many Bollywood celebrities were present at the annual day event.</li>
  <li>Amitabh Bachchan described the experience as exhilarating in his blog post.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Children .. their innocence and desire to be at their best in the presence of parents .. such a delight .. and when they are in the company of thousands performing for you .. it is the most exhilarating experience ..Today was one such.” - Amitabh Bachchan</blockquote>
<p>This joint appearance by Aishwarya and Abhishek underscores their family bond and puts to rest recent separation rumors, much to the joy of their fans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aishwarya-rai-abhishek-bachchan-accompany-her-mom-to-aaradhyas-school-event-watch-101734704531688.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/aishwarya-rai-abhishek-bachchan-accompany-her-mom-to-aaradhyas-school-event-watch-101734704531688.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:59:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nita Ambani to Kareena Kapoor Khan: Best dressed at annual day of Dhirubhai Ambani School - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Best Dressed Celebrities at Dhirubhai Ambani School Annual Day</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> TimesOfIndia.com</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116503645.jpg?imgsize=1167029&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="Nita Ambani to Kareena Kapoor Khan: Best dressed at annual day of Dhirubhai Ambani School">
<figcaption>Nita Ambani to Kareena Kapoor Khan: Best dressed at annual day of Dhirubhai Ambani School</figcaption>
<p>The Dhirubhai Ambani International School hosted its annual meet in Mumbai, featuring many Bollywood stars and business icons flaunting their fashion choices.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nita Ambani wore a stunning cream and white sari.</li>
<li>Isha Ambani showcased a casual emerald kurta set with Valentino heels.</li>
<li>Kareena Kapoor Khan arrived in a cutout-printed black and red wrap dress.</li>
<li>Suhana Khan opted for a black sleeveless dress with block heels.</li>
<li>Gauri Khan went for an ivory embroidered kurta set.</li>
<li>Aishwarya Rai chose a black flowy Anarkali set by Manish Malhotra.</li>
<li>Genelia Deshmukh wore a denim-on-denim co-ord set.</li>
<li>Mira Rajput Kapoor also sported a denim-on-denim look.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Let’s see who wore what at this stylish annual meet." - Piyali Bhadra</blockquote>
<p>The event highlighted the intersection of fashion and prominence, showcasing the striking styles of various celebrities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/fashion/web-stories/nita-ambani-to-kareena-kapoor-khan-best-dressed-at-annual-day-of-dhirubhai-ambani-school/photostory/116503628.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/fashion/web-stories/nita-ambani-to-kareena-kapoor-khan-best-dressed-at-annual-day-of-dhirubhai-ambani-school/photostory/116503628.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ambani School Annual Day: Nita Ambani, Kareena Kapoor, And Aishwarya Rai Make Dazzling Statements - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ambani School Annual Day: Nita Ambani, Kareena Kapoor, And Aishwarya Rai Make Dazzling Statements</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Nita Ambani and Kareena Kapoor attended the annual day event at Ambani School."><figcaption>Nita Ambani and Kareena Kapoor attended the annual day event at Ambani School.</figcaption><p>Last night, the Dhirubhai Ambani International School in Mumbai hosted its annual day, showcasing a star-studded attendance by celebrities to support their children.</p><ul><li>The event featured attendees like Aishwarya Rai, Kareena Kapoor, and Abhishek Bachchan.</li><li>Nita Ambani made a stunning appearance in a cream saree with gold embellishments.</li><li>Kareena Kapoor opted for a stylish printed wrap dress.</li><li>Aishwarya Rai showcased a classic black anarkali kurta.</li><li>Gauri Khan attended in an ivory embroidered kurta set alongside her daughter Suhana in a chic black dress.</li></ul><blockquote>"It was a star-studded night..."</blockquote><p>The annual day highlighted not just the students but also the glamorous styles of their celebrity parents, making it a memorable occasion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/ambani-school-annual-day-nita-ambani-kareena-kapoor-and-aishwarya-rai-make-dazzling-statements-9162493.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/ambani-school-annual-day-nita-ambani-kareena-kapoor-and-aishwarya-rai-make-dazzling-statements-9162493.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:26:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Viduthalai Part 2’ movie review: Vijay Sethupathi powers Vetri Maaran’s sequel where ideology outweighs intimate storytelling - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Viduthalai Part 2’ movie review: Vijay Sethupathi powers Vetri Maaran’s sequel where ideology outweighs intimate storytelling</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> December 20, 2024 07:44 pm IST<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/entertainment/movies/oatpem/article69009523.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/viduthalai%202%20review.jpg" alt="Vijay Sethupathi in a still from ‘Viduthalai Part 2’" title="Vijay Sethupathi in a still from ‘Viduthalai Part 2’"><figcaption>Vijay Sethupathi in a still from ‘Viduthalai Part 2’ | Photo Credit: Special Arrangement</figcaption><p>The film explores the character of Perumal Vaathiyaar, played by Vijay Sethupathi, as he transforms from an unassuming teacher to a leader of a separatist group in a politically charged narrative.</p><ul><li>The sequel focuses on the systemic oppression faced by characters and the political environment.</li><li>Vetri Maaran’s direction is praised for its technical aspects, especially during action sequences.</li><li>The film runs for 170 minutes and features a strong performance from Vijay Sethupathi.</li><li>The narrative suffers from preachiness and lacks the emotional depth of its predecessor.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite a strong political core that puts out a message that’s unfortunately relevant even in today’s world, the sequel lacks the emotions that worked wonders with the first part.”</blockquote><p>Overall, while the film tackles significant themes and performances, it struggles with pacing and depth compared to the original.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/viduthalai-part-2-movie-review-vijay-sethupathi-powers-vetri-maarans-sequel-where-ideology-outweighs-intimate-storytelling/article69009222.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/viduthalai-part-2-movie-review-vijay-sethupathi-powers-vetri-maarans-sequel-where-ideology-outweighs-intimate-storytelling/article69009222.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honey Singh recalls ‘wishing for death' as he talks about fighting mental illness in his documentary: ‘I saw hell’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Honey Singh talks about fighting bipolar disorder, ‘wishing for his death everyday’ in his documentary Yo Yo Honey Singh Famous.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 08:10 PM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/78a0aed0-ab2c-46e9-aa41-89ba4a2d87f4_1734702666088_1734702683971.jpg" alt="Honey Singh talks about fighting mental illness in his documentary." title="Honey Singh talks about fighting mental illness in his documentary."><figcaption>Honey Singh talks about fighting mental illness in his documentary.</figcaption><p>Honey Singh's documentary, 'Yo Yo Honey Singh: Famous,' released on Netflix, addresses his ongoing struggles with mental health, including a discussion about his experiences with bipolar disorder.</p><ul><li>The documentary reveals Honey's journey through mental illness, where he described feeling like he was living in hell.</li><li>He recounted moments during a tour that triggered his symptoms of paranoia and depression.</li><li>Honey Singh explained the psychological impact of his illness, describing hallucinations and severe anxiety.</li><li>He emphasized the depth of his struggles, highlighting how he wished for death every day.</li><li>The film provides an intimate look at his personal and professional life, showing the support from family, friends, and collaborators.</li></ul><blockquote>“I saw hell. I wished for death every day.” - Honey Singh</blockquote><p>The documentary serves as a deeply personal portrayal of a talented artist’s battle with mental health and his journey towards recovery.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/honey-singh-recalls-wishing-for-death-as-he-talks-about-fighting-mental-illness-in-his-documentary-i-saw-hell-101734702424568.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/honey-singh-recalls-wishing-for-death-as-he-talks-about-fighting-mental-illness-in-his-documentary-i-saw-hell-101734702424568.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:07:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai, Abhishek Bachchan Arrive Together For Aaradhya’s School Annual Day Amid Divorce Rumours - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan Appear Together at Aaradhya’s School Event Amid Divorce Speculations</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='Aishwarya and Abhishek spotted ' /><figcaption>Aishwarya and Abhishek spotted</figcaption><p>Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan were seen attending their daughter Aaradhya’s school annual day, amidst ongoing divorce rumors. The couple showcased a united front, capturing the attention of fans on social media.</p><ul><li>Abhishek and Aishwarya danced together during the event, creating a memorable moment.</li><li>Both dressed stylishly, with Aishwarya wearing a black outfit and Abhishek in casual green.</li><li>The annual day function attracted many Bollywood stars supporting their children.</li><li>The couple's divorce rumors have been prevalent for several months, causing concern among their fans.</li><li>Amitabh Bachchan previously addressed the speculation, emphasizing the need for privacy and the nature of unverified claims.</li></ul><blockquote>“Speculations are speculations… they are speculated untruths, without verifications…” - Amitabh Bachchan</blockquote><p>This event highlights their apparent togetherness and dedication as parents, despite swirling rumors surrounding their marriage.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/aishwarya-rai-abhishek-bachchan-arrive-together-for-aaradhyas-school-annual-day-amid-divorce-rumours-9163230.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/aishwarya-rai-abhishek-bachchan-arrive-together-for-aaradhyas-school-annual-day-amid-divorce-rumours-9163230.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:41:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2 The Rule surpasses Stree 2, Jawan, Baahubali 2 to become biggest Hindi net grosser in just 15 days - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2 The Rule surpasses Stree 2, Jawan, Baahubali 2 to become biggest Hindi net grosser in just 15 days</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/GfPjTWaagAA9UKO_1734699427730_1734699452480.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2 The Rule becomes the biggest Hindi nett of all time.(Twitter)" title="Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2 The Rule becomes the biggest Hindi nett of all time.(Twitter)">
<figcaption>Allu Arjun's Pushpa 2 The Rule becomes the biggest Hindi nett of all time.(Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna's Pushpa 2 The Rule has achieved a remarkable milestone by becoming the biggest Hindi net grosser of all time, grossing ₹621 crore in just 15 days.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film surpasses Baahubali 2, KGF Chapter 2, Stree 2, Jawan, Pathaan, and Animal in terms of Hindi box office gross.</li>
  <li>In its second week, the total collection stands at ₹264.8 crore, with major contributions from the Hindi language.</li>
  <li>Pushpa 2 is directed by Sukumar and is a sequel to the hit Pushpa The Rise.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The film is now eyeing to surpass Baahubali 2 The Conclusion's worldwide collection to secure its place among India's highest-grossing films.”</blockquote>
<p>Pushpa 2 continues to captivate audiences and set new records at the box office.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/allu-arjuns-pushpa-2-the-rule-surpasses-stree-2-jawan-baahubali-2-to-become-biggest-hindi-net-grosser-in-just-15-days-101734699243639.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/allu-arjuns-pushpa-2-the-rule-surpasses-stree-2-jawan-baahubali-2-to-become-biggest-hindi-net-grosser-in-just-15-days-101734699243639.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:34:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abhishek Bachchan-Aishwarya Rai come together for Aaradhya's annual day, Virat Kohli scolds paparazzi for - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Abhishek Bachchan and Aishwarya Rai at Aaradhya's event; Virat Kohli confronts paparazzi</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Bollywood stars Abhishek Bachchan and Aishwarya Rai attended their daughter Aaradhya's annual day event, showcasing a united family front. Meanwhile, cricketer Virat Kohli took a stand against paparazzi for invading the privacy of kids Akaay and Vamika.</p><ul><li>Abhishek and Aishwarya were spotted together at their daughter's annual day.</li><li>Virat Kohli expressed his discontent with paparazzi filming children.</li><li>The event highlighted parental concerns regarding children's privacy in the public eye.</li></ul><blockquote>“We need to respect kids' privacy; they deserve a normal upbringing.” - Virat Kohli</blockquote><p>This occasion brings attention to the ongoing debate around celebrity children's privacy and public scrutiny.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/abhishek-bachchan-aishwarya-rai-come-together-for-aaradhyas-annual-day-kareena-kapoor-shahid-kapoor-recreate-jab-we-met-moment-to-virat-kohli-scolds-paparazzi-for-filming-kids-akaay-and-vamika-top-5-entertainment-news-of-the-day/articleshow/116505752.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/abhishek-bachchan-aishwarya-rai-come-together-for-aaradhyas-annual-day-kareena-kapoor-shahid-kapoor-recreate-jab-we-met-moment-to-virat-kohli-scolds-paparazzi-for-filming-kids-akaay-and-vamika-top-5-entertainment-news-of-the-day/articleshow/116505752.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Soha Ali Khan shares glimpse of Inaaya's bond with Taimur, their ‘cute’ journey as cousins on his birthday. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Soha Ali Khan's cute video featuring Taimur Ali Khan and daughter Inaaya melts the hearts of the social media users.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/taimur_1734697940961_1734697992299.jpg" alt="Soha Ali Khan shares glimpse of Taimur and Inaaya's bond.(Instagram)"><figcaption>Soha Ali Khan shares glimpse of Taimur and Inaaya's bond.(Instagram)</figcaption><p>Soha Ali Khan shared a heartwarming birthday tribute to her nephew Taimur Ali Khan, showcasing the special bond between Taimur and her daughter Inaaya through an adorable video.</p><ul><li>Taimur Ali Khan celebrates his eighth birthday.</li><li>The video shows Taimur and Inaaya having fun, jumping on a bed, swimming, and enjoying pizza.</li><li>Soha wrote a sweet birthday message, highlighting their journey as cousins.</li><li>Kareena Kapoor and Saif Ali Khan organized a sporty birthday bash for Taimur.</li></ul><blockquote>“From jumping on the bed to racing freestyle we have come a long way - here's to a lifetime of family, food and prezzies !! Happy Birthday Tim bhai.”</blockquote><p>The video has received numerous positive reactions on social media, with fans expressing delight over the adorable moments captured.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/soha-ali-khan-shares-glimpse-of-inaayas-bond-with-taimur-their-cute-journey-as-cousins-on-his-birthday-watch-101734695801064.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/soha-ali-khan-shares-glimpse-of-inaayas-bond-with-taimur-their-cute-journey-as-cousins-on-his-birthday-watch-101734695801064.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:49:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Aravind to lobby in Delhi for son?.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Aravind to Lobby in Delhi for Son?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p>
<img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/alluarvinddd1734698784.jpeg" alt="Allu Aravind to lobby in Delhi for son?">
<figcaption>Allu Aravind is expected to lobby for his son in Delhi.</figcaption>
<p>Tollywood superstar Allu Arjun faces ongoing legal issues related to a tragic incident that occurred during the premiere of his film. His father, Allu Aravind, is reportedly planning to travel to New Delhi to seek intervention from Congress leaders.</p>
<ul>
<li>Allu Arjun has been granted interim bail for four weeks.</li>
<li>The Telangana police are actively pursuing the case against him.</li>
<li>There are concerns regarding the health of a woman’s son, which could complicate matters further.</li>
<li>Allu Aravind aims to prevent another arrest of his son by lobbying with political figures.</li>
<li>Sources indicate discussions will focus on the circumstances surrounding the incident.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“He would explain them the circumstances that led to the tragic incident, that was totally unexpected,” sources said.</blockquote>
<p>The outcome of Allu Aravind's lobbying efforts may significantly impact Allu Arjun’s legal situation and peace of mind.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/allu-aravind-to-lobby-in-delhi-for-son-142879</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/allu-aravind-to-lobby-in-delhi-for-son-142879</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:46:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bachhala Malli Box Office Collection Day 1 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPZlpEd09GUzVOWnRwXzg3TVdsSVBkdXdsWUk3MHV2bW1KVWFYb2Rrc3d1dDRZS3hIVFo0WXhJSTZCNzlROURkTlFBSDYyWXQ5U0xvcGxVSXFQZEE2alU2TTEwMGtvWTl4OEppU0J4YjFQd0lZR1dVZzdYMFM4MDFkYzFMWE11eUFj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPZlpEd09GUzVOWnRwXzg3TVdsSVBkdXdsWUk3MHV2bW1KVWFYb2Rrc3d1dDRZS3hIVFo0WXhJSTZCNzlROURkTlFBSDYyWXQ5U0xvcGxVSXFQZEE2alU2TTEwMGtvWTl4OEppU0J4YjFQd0lZR1dVZzdYMFM4MDFkYzFMWE11eUFj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BookMyShow 2024 throwback report: RECORD 2.3 million tickets sold on Singham Again and Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3’s release date; 10.8 lakh people saw Pushpa 2 alone; Kalki 2898 AD, Stree 2, Devara, Hanuman, GOAT, Amaran gets MAXIMUM repeat audienc - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BookMyShow 2024 Throwback Report Reveals Record Ticket Sales</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p>
<img src="https://stat4.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/BookMyShow-2024-throwback-report-RECORD-2.3-million-tickets-sold-on-Singham-Again-and-Bhool-Bhulaiyaa-3s-release-date-10.8-lakh-people-saw-Pushpa-2-alone-Kalki-2898-AD-Stree-2-Devara-Hanuman-GOAT-Amaran-gets-MAXIMUM-rep.jpg" alt="BookMyShow 2024 Throwback Report">
<figcaption>BookMyShow 2024 throwback report highlights record ticket sales and audience insights.</figcaption>
<p>As 2024 comes to a close, BookMyShow released a report detailing significant ticket sales and trends from the year.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Record 2.3 million tickets sold on the release day of <em>Singham Again</em> and <em>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</em>.</li>
  <li>10.8 lakh viewers watched <em>Pushpa 2</em> solo, setting a notable attendance trend.</li>
  <li>A viewer named Gaurav reportedly saw <em>Stree 2</em> 29 times.</li>
  <li>The most watched Indian films included <em>Kalki 2898 AD, Stree 2,</em> and <em>Pushpa 2</em>.</li>
  <li>Popular Hollywood films among Indian viewers were <em>Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</em> and <em>Kung Fu Panda 4</em>.</li>
  <li>Top re-releases on the platform included films like <em>Tumbbad</em> and <em>Kal Ho Naa Ho</em>.</li>
  <li>Mumbai residents made up 21% of ticket bookings for Coldplay's gig, with lower interest from other regions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The most watched movies show a clear interest in repeat viewings by dedicated fans."</blockquote>
<p>This report showcases the evolving trends of cinema-goers in India and highlights the significant box office impact of popular films in 2024.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/bookmyshow-2024-throwback-report-record-2-3-million-tickets-sold-singham-bhool-bhulaiyaa-3s-release-date-10-8-lakh-people-saw-pushpa-2-alone-kalki-2898-ad-stree-2-devara-ha/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/features/bookmyshow-2024-throwback-report-record-2-3-million-tickets-sold-singham-bhool-bhulaiyaa-3s-release-date-10-8-lakh-people-saw-pushpa-2-alone-kalki-2898-ad-stree-2-devara-ha/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:30:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small-budget Tamil film overtakes mighty Baahubali 2 in China - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Small-budget Tamil film overtakes mighty Baahubali 2 in China</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 20, 2024 6:00 pm IST</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Maharaja-Baahubali-2.jpg" alt="Maharaja a Tamil film" width="500" height="333"><figcaption>Maharaja a Tamil film</figcaption><p>Tamil suspense thriller Maharaja, headlined by Vijay Sethupathi, has emerged as a blockbuster in China, overtaking Baahubali 2 to become the all-time highest South Indian grosser in the country.</p><ul><li>Maharaja earned over Rs. 100 crores in its initial release.</li><li>The film has grossed Rs. 86 crores in China.</li><li>Its worldwide gross is around Rs. 193 crores.</li><li>Directed by Nithilan Saminathan, the film has received praise for its screenplay.</li><li>Starring Vijay Sethupathi, Anurag Kashyap, and others, it has a notable run in China.</li></ul><blockquote>“Maharaja is now in the tenth position among top Indian grossers in China.”</blockquote><p>This achievement showcases the growing appeal of regional cinema in international markets, marking a significant milestone for the Tamil film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/small-budget-tamil-film-overtakes-mighty-baahubali-2-in-china.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/small-budget-tamil-film-overtakes-mighty-baahubali-2-in-china.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nepali social media influencer Bibek Pangeni dies at 32 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nepali Social Media Influencer Bibek Pangeni Dies at 32</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent News Source</p>
<p>Bibek Pangeni, a popular Nepali social media influencer, has passed away at the young age of 32, leaving behind a significant impact on his community.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pangeni was known for his vibrant and engaging content on platforms like Instagram and YouTube.</li>
  <li>His sudden death has shocked his followers and the wider social media community in Nepal.</li>
  <li>Fans and fellow influencers have expressed their condolences and shared memories of his inspirational content.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Bibek was not just an influencer, he was a beacon of positivity and creativity,” said a fellow influencer.</blockquote>
<p>This tragic news underlines the importance of mental health awareness among influencers and the pressures they face.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/social/nepali-social-media-influencer-bibek-pangeni-dies-at-32/articleshow/116504140.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/social/nepali-social-media-influencer-bibek-pangeni-dies-at-32/articleshow/116504140.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Under control of army’: Go and visit paradise, says Diljit Dosanjh after Kashmir trip - Free Press Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://freepresskashmir.news/2024/12/20/under-control-of-army-go-and-visit-paradise-says-diljit-dosanjh-after-kashmir-trip/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://freepresskashmir.news/2024/12/20/under-control-of-army-go-and-visit-paradise-says-diljit-dosanjh-after-kashmir-trip/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:41:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>