<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:19:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:19:43 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Baby John' box office collection day 3: The Varun Dhawan starrer struggles to maintain opening day pace; - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAJBVV95cUxQVUJYR0FpQVVpVWZvbGVlS0lRSk1GdElpVTNLa2hIeUxCWHR4cy03QjdpcUVWQUlLXzBGQm84eWxsQU5QZVZ6VWtSVkZHRnhjMnRBSVY0dnJ6RWtiTlNoQ0ZEYllsSWdoNnM2eFFBc3o2bXZldFd0eFI3VnRvbV8ydDg4UDBjVlVSLUdmeU5LUkxMeHdiZVlvLW9rdFdQdE83NW5mM2ZjUElUUjB3VVUyTGNWaXJ5dzJGaVRIOU14S2hOcmotMmFySVlTMVlxVzNhclFuaWVndVJCMHB5Z2I1NUZiQ1M4N3dEbVlDY0lidTMxOEFGcnMzdHl4WFNPQS1CQW16VG1zMUhoZ3Z3UlFwZ3h2SXV6bWdhUTJaTHBicERLMldiY0Z5UzBMaHdpLU1ER05yMGc0SWtJR013ZG1kVHV0MFFaMWIxYW9BNg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAJBVV95cUxQVUJYR0FpQVVpVWZvbGVlS0lRSk1GdElpVTNLa2hIeUxCWHR4cy03QjdpcUVWQUlLXzBGQm84eWxsQU5QZVZ6VWtSVkZHRnhjMnRBSVY0dnJ6RWtiTlNoQ0ZEYllsSWdoNnM2eFFBc3o2bXZldFd0eFI3VnRvbV8ydDg4UDBjVlVSLUdmeU5LUkxMeHdiZVlvLW9rdFdQdE83NW5mM2ZjUElUUjB3VVUyTGNWaXJ5dzJGaVRIOU14S2hOcmotMmFySVlTMVlxVzNhclFuaWVndVJCMHB5Z2I1NUZiQ1M4N3dEbVlDY0lidTMxOEFGcnMzdHl4WFNPQS1CQW16VG1zMUhoZ3Z3UlFwZ3h2SXV6bWdhUTJaTHBicERLMldiY0Z5UzBMaHdpLU1ER05yMGc0SWtJR013ZG1kVHV0MFFaMWIxYW9BNg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 18:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viduthalai Part - 2 Box Office Collection Day 8 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOVkdyU0NJQmltSWhmb29icWFCZVJwSGhQYVpSRjJrMTVMOXlwSWNoSG90QVJMUERIZDF3clltTkRMdFc0aHc3N1ZESFlxUk50dnBsRUo4cVVQeEhwVEpCRFpmNzByVXhxMlRxRTdYYlQ3RTdjVDRVdDBydGVSV0M0dk1QcFBxS2ZzSzMxNy1R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOVkdyU0NJQmltSWhmb29icWFCZVJwSGhQYVpSRjJrMTVMOXlwSWNoSG90QVJMUERIZDF3clltTkRMdFc0aHc3N1ZESFlxUk50dnBsRUo4cVVQeEhwVEpCRFpmNzByVXhxMlRxRTdYYlQ3RTdjVDRVdDBydGVSV0M0dk1QcFBxS2ZzSzMxNy1R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:45:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby John box office collection day 3: Varun Dhawan film fails to sustain opening day momentum - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baby John box office collection day 3: Varun Dhawan film fails to sustain opening day momentum</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/Baby-John_1735312525353_1735312533741.jpeg" alt="Baby John box office collection day 3: The action thriller is a a remake of Theri." title="Baby John box office collection day 3: The action thriller is a a remake of Theri." /><figcaption>Baby John box office collection day 3: The action thriller is a remake of Theri.</figcaption></figure><p>Varun Dhawan's latest outing, Baby John, initially had a promising box office performance but has seen a significant decline in collections over the first three days.</p><ul><li>Baby John opened on Christmas with a strong day one collection of ₹11.25 crore.</li><li>By day three, collections dropped to ₹3.65 crore, totaling ₹19.65 crore (nett).</li><li>The film suffered a 57.78% decline in collections from day one to day two.</li><li>Despite being Varun's biggest opening in five years, the film is struggling against competition from other releases.</li></ul><blockquote>“Overall, there’s nothing much that makes Baby John stand out apart from the action.”</blockquote><p>The film's decline in box office performance highlights the challenges faced by new releases in a competitive market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/baby-john-box-office-collection-day-3-varun-dhawan-film-fails-to-sustain-opening-day-momentum-101735312510105.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/baby-john-box-office-collection-day-3-varun-dhawan-film-fails-to-sustain-opening-day-momentum-101735312510105.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Orry shares unseen video of Janhvi Kapoor, Shikhar Pahariya, Khushi Kapoor, Vedang Raina, and Ananya Pand - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Orry shares unseen video of Janhvi Kapoor, Shikhar Pahariya, Khushi Kapoor, Vedang Raina, and Ananya Panday making weird faces: 'I should have deleted it'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p>
<img src="" alt="" />
<p>In a light-hearted moment, Orry shared a video featuring Janhvi Kapoor and her friends making fun faces, joking about the need to delete it.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Orry shares a humorous video with celebrity friends.</li>
  <li>Participants include Janhvi Kapoor, Shikhar Pahariya, Khushi Kapoor, Vedang Raina, and Ananya Panday.</li>
  <li>Orry humorously remarks, 'I should have deleted it.'</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>'I should have deleted it.'</blockquote>
<p>This amusing video showcases the fun side of Bollywood personalities, highlighting their playful interactions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/orry-shares-unseen-video-of-janhvi-kapoor-shikhar-pahariya-khushi-kapoor-vedang-raina-and-ananya-panday-making-weird-faces-i-should-have-deleted-it/articleshow/116720861.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/orry-shares-unseen-video-of-janhvi-kapoor-shikhar-pahariya-khushi-kapoor-vedang-raina-and-ananya-panday-making-weird-faces-i-should-have-deleted-it/articleshow/116720861.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Producer shares interesting details about Chiranjeevi & Srikanth Odela’s film - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Producer shares interesting details about Chiranjeevi &amp; Srikanth Odela’s film</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 27, 2024 9:09 pm IST</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Chiranjeevi-Srikanth.jpg" alt="Chiranjeevi & Srikanth Odela" width="360" height="450">
<figcaption>Chiranjeevi & Srikanth Odela</figcaption>
<p>Megastar Chiranjeevi has announced a collaboration with the new-age filmmaker Srikanth Odela, known for his debut film 'Dasara'. The upcoming film, tentatively titled 'Mega156', is set to be a period drama.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sudhakar Cherukuri will produce the film.</li>
  <li>The film is a period piece, similar to Odela's ongoing project 'The Paradise'.</li>
  <li>There are rumors about the absence of a heroine and songs in the film, which the producer has denied.</li>
  <li>The director of photography and music director have been finalized.</li>
  <li>The script is currently in the development stage.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>“There is no truth in what is being circulated on social media. We locked the DOP and music director.” - Sudhakar Cherukuri</p></blockquote>
<p>This collaboration is highly anticipated and is expected to generate significant buzz in the Telugu film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/producer-shares-interesting-details-about-chiranjeevi-srikanth-odelas-film.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/producer-shares-interesting-details-about-chiranjeevi-srikanth-odelas-film.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani Re-Release Box Office: 9.97 Crores Away From Achieving A Milestone, Ranbir Kapoor & Deepika Padukone’s Blockbuster - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani Re-Release Box Office: 9.97 Crores Away From Achieving A Milestone</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p>
<img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/yeh-jawaani-hai-deewani-box-office.jpg" alt="Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani Re-Release Box Office: To Achieve A Big Milestone?" width="1200" height="630">
<figcaption>Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani Re-Release Box Office: To Achieve A Big Milestone? (Photo Credit – Instagram)</figcaption>
<p>For all Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani Hai fans, there’s exciting news as the modern-age cult romantic drama is all set to re-release in theatres. The film is tremendously popular, and over the years, it has built a loyal fan base. No doubt it will enjoy a solid response from the moviegoers amid the trend of re-releases. And if it manages to rake in 9.97 crores at the Indian box office, it will achieve a big milestone. Keep reading to know about the milestone!</p>
<ul>
<li>Directed by Ayan Mukerji, the film originally starred Ranbir Kapoor, Deepika Padukone, Aditya Roy Kapur, and Kalki Koechlin.</li>
<li>The film was a major success upon its original release in 2013, amassing 190.03 crore net at the Indian box office.</li>
<li>The re-release is set for January 3, 2025, coinciding with the trend of successful Bollywood film re-releases.</li>
<li>The film needs 9.97 crores to achieve the 200 crore milestone.</li>
<li>Box office numbers are estimates and have not been independently verified.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"If Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani gets a good screen/show count and meets a good response from the audience, it’ll be able to hit big numbers."</blockquote>
<p>Stay tuned to Koimoi for more box office stories & updates!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/yeh-jawaani-hai-deewani-re-release-box-office-9-97-crores-away-from-achieving-a-milestone-ranbir-kapoor-deepika-padukones-blockbuster/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/yeh-jawaani-hai-deewani-re-release-box-office-9-97-crores-away-from-achieving-a-milestone-ranbir-kapoor-deepika-padukones-blockbuster/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:35:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boman Irani: My trip to London with Shyam Benegal ji is among my fondest memories - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Boman Irani Remembers Shyam Benegal: A Fond Trip to London</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/bomanshyam_1735312969774_1735312984372.jpg" alt="Boman Irani and Shyam Benegal" title="Boman Irani and Shyam Benegal">
<figcaption>Boman Irani and Shyam Benegal</figcaption>
<p>Actor Boman Irani reflects on his memories with the late filmmaker Shyam Benegal, who passed away on December 23, 2024. Irani recalls their special trip to London together for a film festival.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shyam Benegal was a pivotal figure in Indian parallel cinema, renowned for his realistic portrayals.</li>
  <li>Irani worked with Benegal on the film <em>Well Done Abba</em> in 2009.</li>
  <li>Irani describes the trip to London as one of his fondest memories with Benegal.</li>
  <li>The actor emphasizes the knowledge and conversational skills of Benegal, whom he admired greatly.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I have never left a film set in my life sobbing. I did, from this one shamelessly. I had to be consoled.” - Boman Irani</blockquote>
<p>This article highlights the deep bond between Boman Irani and Shyam Benegal, showcasing how personal connections in the film industry can leave a lasting impact on one's life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/boman-irani-my-trip-to-london-with-shyam-benegal-ji-is-among-my-fondest-memories-101735312276224.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/boman-irani-my-trip-to-london-with-shyam-benegal-ji-is-among-my-fondest-memories-101735312276224.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:26:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Katrina Kaif has a sweet wish for Salman Khan on his 59th birthday: ‘May all the wonderful things…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Katrina Kaif Wishes Salman Khan a Happy 59th Birthday</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/Katrina_Kaif_Salman_Khan_1735311134971_1735311154471.jpg" alt="Katrina Kaif and Salman Khan have worked on numerous films together." title="Katrina Kaif and Salman Khan have worked on numerous films together.">
<figcaption>Katrina Kaif and Salman Khan have worked on numerous films together.</figcaption>
<p>Katrina Kaif wished her friend and co-star Salman Khan a happy 59th birthday on Twitter and Instagram. Amidst a flood of celebrity wishes, her heartfelt message stood out.</p>
<ul>
<li>Katrina shared a monochrome picture of Salman on her Instagram stories.</li>
<li>She captioned the image, “Happiest Birthday @beingsalmankhan. May all the wonderful things of life be with you this year and always.”</li>
<li>The duo has had a long association, rumored to have dated before becoming close friends.</li>
<li>They have starred together in numerous films, including the Tiger franchise.</li>
<li>Katrina recently appeared in Merry Christmas and announced her next project, Jee Le Zaraa.</li>
<li>Salman is set to star in an upcoming film, Sikandar, with the teaser being postponed due to a significant event.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Katrina has often referred to Salman as her mentor during the early stages of her career.”</blockquote>
<p>This birthday wish not only highlights their enduring friendship but also reflects the strong bonds within the Bollywood community.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/katrina-kaif-has-a-sweet-wish-for-salman-khan-on-his-59th-birthday-may-all-the-wonderful-things-101735310834899.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/katrina-kaif-has-a-sweet-wish-for-salman-khan-on-his-59th-birthday-may-all-the-wonderful-things-101735310834899.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:06:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Singham Again on OTT: Ajay Devgn, Kareena Kapoor, Deepika Padukone fail to impress; trolls compare it to ‘maggie dosa’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Singham Again on OTT: Ajay Devgn, Kareena Kapoor, Deepika Padukone fail to impress; trolls compare it to ‘maggie dosa’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/Singham_Again_1735309420164_1735309451346.jpg" alt="Deepika Padukone, Kareena Kapoor Khan and Ajay Devgn in a still from Singham Again" title="Deepika Padukone, Kareena Kapoor Khan and Ajay Devgn in a still from Singham Again"><figcaption>Deepika Padukone, Kareena Kapoor Khan and Ajay Devgn in a still from Singham Again</figcaption></figure><p>After two months since its theatrical release, 'Singham Again' has debuted on OTT. The film, directed by Rohit Shetty, has received mixed reviews from audiences, with many expressing disappointment at its execution.</p><ul><li>The film features a star-studded cast including Ajay Devgn, Kareena Kapoor, Deepika Padukone, and others.</li><li>Viewers have taken to social media to share their unfiltered reactions, comparing the film unfavorably to earlier installments and other foods like 'maggie dosa'.</li><li>Kareena Kapoor's performance has particularly faced heavy criticism, with social media users leveling harsh comments.</li><li>Salman Khan makes a special cameo as Chulbul Pandey, which some fans are looking forward to.</li></ul><blockquote>“If Singham -1 was masala Dosa, other Singham versions are like schezwan dosa, pav bhaji Dosa, Maggie Dosa, paneer Dosa!! But the original masala dosa still is the best one !!”</blockquote><p>The film's reception highlights the challenges of meeting audience expectations for sequels and the importance of storytelling in maintaining franchise integrity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/singham-again-on-ott-ajay-devgn-kareena-kapoor-deepika-padukone-fail-to-impress-trolls-compare-it-to-maggie-dosa-101735309235945.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/singham-again-on-ott-ajay-devgn-kareena-kapoor-deepika-padukone-fail-to-impress-trolls-compare-it-to-maggie-dosa-101735309235945.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:38:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honey Singh Finally Speaks On His Decade Long Feud With Rapper Badshah, Says ‘He Is The One To…’ - News24]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Honey Singh Finally Speaks On His Decade Long Feud With Rapper Badshah</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India Today Digital</p><p>In an interview, Honey Singh addressed his long-standing feud with Badshah, highlighting the rivalry that has existed for over a decade.</p><ul><li>The feud began during their time in the rap group Mafia Mundeer.</li><li>Honey Singh accused Badshah of mocking him publicly and through songs.</li><li>Despite the ongoing conflict, Singh remains skeptical about any reconciliation.</li></ul><blockquote>“He is one of those who spit and then licks it back; just watch, he’ll flip again,” - Honey Singh on Badshah.</blockquote><p>The tensions between the two rappers seem to persist, adding intrigue to their story.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news24online.com/entertainment/honey-singh-finally-speaks-on-his-decade-long-feud-with-rapper-badshah-says-tumhe-dekh-lunga/420050/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news24online.com/entertainment/honey-singh-finally-speaks-on-his-decade-long-feud-with-rapper-badshah-says-tumhe-dekh-lunga/420050/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:30:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' worldwide box office collection day 22: The Allu Arjun-Rashmika Mandanna starrer surpasses Rs - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 worldwide box office collection day 22: The Allu Arjun-Rashmika Mandanna starrer surpasses Rs 1719 crore</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116666603,width-1070,height-580,imgsize-66604,resizemode-75,overlay-toi_sw,pt-32,y_pad-40/photo.jpg' alt='Pushpa 2 Box Office Image'><figcaption>Image related to Pushpa 2 Box Office Collection</figcaption><p>Pushpa 2, starring Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna, has crossed Rs 1719 crore globally at the box office. The film maintains its strong performance despite challenges.</p><ul><li>Surpassed Rs 1719 crore in global box office collection.</li><li>Maintained top position in ticket sales even against new releases.</li><li>Continued discussions about its impact on Indian cinema.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pushpa 2 is redefining box office expectations in India and abroad.”</blockquote><p>This film continues to captivate audiences and sets a new benchmark for blockbuster success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-22-the-allu-arjun-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-surpasses-rs-1719-crore/articleshow/116717155.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-22-the-allu-arjun-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-surpasses-rs-1719-crore/articleshow/116717155.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mika Singh removed Katrina Kaif's name from a song on Salman Khan's request? Singer responds - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mika Singh discusses removing Katrina Kaif's name from a song on Salman Khan's request</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/mika_1735306750852_1735306765831.jpg" alt="Mika Singh talks about his friendship with Salman Khan." title="Mika Singh talks about his friendship with Salman Khan.">
<figcaption>Mika Singh talks about his friendship with Salman Khan.</figcaption>
<p>Mika Singh recently opened up about his friendship with Salman Khan, revealing he changed lyrics in his song at Salman’s request.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Mika Singh revealed he altered song lyrics to maintain his friendship with Salman Khan.</li>
    <li>He changed the name 'Katrina' to 'Jacquelina' in the song 'Loot'.</li>
    <li>Mika supports Salman amid receiving threats and expressed his loyalty during a stage performance.</li>
    <li>He shared insights into their first meeting and how Salman prefers late-night calls.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Mika said, “I changed the word ‘Katrina’ to ‘Jacquelina’ at his request.”</blockquote>
<p>This experience showcases the strong bond between the singer and the actor, indicating the influence they have on each other's work.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/mika-singh-removed-katrina-kaifs-name-from-a-song-on-salman-khans-request-singer-responds-101735306395044.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/mika-singh-removed-katrina-kaifs-name-from-a-song-on-salman-khans-request-singer-responds-101735306395044.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Promising News About ‘Squid Game’ Season 3 - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Promising News About ‘Squid Game’ Season 3</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Forbes</p><figure role="presentation"><img src="https://specials-images.forbesimg.com/imageserve/676ead4880e103b90b011daa/squid2/960x0.jpg?fit=scale" alt="squid2"><figcaption>Squid Game</figcaption></figure><p>Squid Game is back after three long years for season 2, and upon finishing these seven new episodes, you are probably wondering if and when season 3 is coming. Well, there are two bits of good news there, and I’m happy to share them with you.</p><ul><li>Season 3 of Squid Game is confirmed and will be the final season of the show.</li><li>It is set to release in 2025, significantly sooner than the previous season.</li></ul><p>Creator Hwang Dong-hyuk mentioned, “I wrote seasons two and three at the same time...currently we are in the post-production process for season three.”</p><blockquote>“I’m so exhausted. I’m so tired. In a way, I have to say, I’m so sick of ‘Squid Game,’” - Hwang Dong-hyuk</blockquote><p>This timeline showcases Netflix's effort to avoid long gaps between seasons. Despite the announcement, there are still concerns about maintaining quality without further delays.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/12/27/the-promising-news-about-squid-game-season-3/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/12/27/the-promising-news-about-squid-game-season-3/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:38:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Netizens come out in support of Karan Veer Mehra after Sara Arfeen Khan gets violent in the - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18: Netizens come out in support of Karan Veer Mehra after Sara Arfeen Khan gets violent in the task</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source]</p><p>This article discusses the recent incident in Bigg Boss 18 where Karan Veer Mehra received public support following an altercation with Sara Arfeen Khan during a task.</p><ul><li>Karan Veer Mehra faced aggression from Sara Arfeen Khan during a task.</li><li>Netizens quickly rallied to support Karan on social media.</li><li>The incident highlights reactions from fans and the impact of reality TV on social interactions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Everyone deserves respect, Karan handled the situation well.” - A netizen's comment.</blockquote><p>This incident showcases how reality TV can influence public opinion and fan engagement in ongoing narrative arcs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-netizens-come-out-in-support-of-karan-veer-mehra-after-sara-arfeen-khan-gets-violent-in-the-task/articleshow/116717386.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-netizens-come-out-in-support-of-karan-veer-mehra-after-sara-arfeen-khan-gets-violent-in-the-task/articleshow/116717386.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Priyanka Chopra locked for Mahesh Babu’s next with SS Rajamouli; Filming begins in April 2025 - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>EXCLUSIVE: Priyanka Chopra locked for Mahesh Babu’s next with SS Rajamouli; Filming begins in April 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Updated on Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p>
<img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/513897697_peecee-6.jpg" alt="EXCLUSIVE: Priyanka Chopra locked for Mahesh Babu’s next with SS Rajamouli" title="Picture courtesy: Mahesh Babu/Instagram (L); Priyanka Chopra/Instagram (C); Netflix India/YouTube (R)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Picture courtesy: Mahesh Babu/Instagram (L); Priyanka Chopra/Instagram (C); Netflix India/YouTube (R)</figcaption>
<p>Priyanka Chopra is set to return to the Indian Film Industry after six years in SS Rajamouli's next film alongside Mahesh Babu, which will begin filming in April 2025.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film is an African Jungle Adventure, with Mahesh Babu playing an explorer inspired by Lord Hanuman.</li>
  <li>Priyanka Chopra’s character will involve significant action scenes and a well-crafted role.</li>
  <li>The film's production will occur in India, the US, and African forests, aiming for a theatrical release in 2027.</li>
  <li>Rajamouli is negotiating with global studios like Disney and Sony for collaboration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Priyanka Chopra is excited to collaborate with a maverick like SS Rajamouli and partner with Mahesh Babu to create an adventure like never before.”</blockquote>
<p>This film marks a significant comeback for Priyanka Chopra, and its anticipation indicates a major cinematic event in the near future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-priyanka-chopra-locked-for-mahesh-babus-next-with-ss-rajamouli-filming-begins-in-april-2025-1364588</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/exclusives/exclusive-priyanka-chopra-locked-for-mahesh-babus-next-with-ss-rajamouli-filming-begins-in-april-2025-1364588</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:57:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mufasa: The Lion King Box Office Collection Day 8 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxONWtDa0c2TEZ2N0RfRXRFalhpX2d3SkR6V1ZDRGk5ZXY4ckVpRWxMbkdNRHh4ejRKQ1phYlhXZ1J3MTl6R1VIaXZFT0pGRDNCMHhHYmMzd0NrbEstdmVfSmhiRUhtU2JVenQwb215eUVXemVtUHJWdXppNFlaQVd3eEdFeWhqUy1FZHhmdlV3bDE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxONWtDa0c2TEZ2N0RfRXRFalhpX2d3SkR6V1ZDRGk5ZXY4ckVpRWxMbkdNRHh4ejRKQ1phYlhXZ1J3MTl6R1VIaXZFT0pGRDNCMHhHYmMzd0NrbEstdmVfSmhiRUhtU2JVenQwb215eUVXemVtUHJWdXppNFlaQVd3eEdFeWhqUy1FZHhmdlV3bDE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zayed Khan Net Worth: Despite A Passable Film Career, Main Hoon Na Actor Enjoys Stellar 1000 Crore+ Assets, Higher Than Some A-Listers - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/fashion-lifestyle/zayed-khan-net-worth-despite-a-passable-film-career-main-hoon-na-actor-enjoys-stellar-1000-crore-assets-higher-than-some-a-listers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/fashion-lifestyle/zayed-khan-net-worth-despite-a-passable-film-career-main-hoon-na-actor-enjoys-stellar-1000-crore-assets-higher-than-some-a-listers/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:06:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viduthalai Part - 2 Box Office Collection Day 7 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQTlQ1NF9KNXVPY1FUOEVtY0tJUUd0TFFtM2g3UFJNMmR4Z25OX0o5TmdPRGo2bzl6eERJamhQWDh2RTBMU1FGaHJmaDZtbnl2RmJ1ODAwRFBjcG9KaS1nSUM0M2paNTFVbkV1RGQ0Zm5TVEZ0V2F1cjhPSGdNVjJ5ZWczeEJsLXktM1IyU1dn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQTlQ1NF9KNXVPY1FUOEVtY0tJUUd0TFFtM2g3UFJNMmR4Z25OX0o5TmdPRGo2bzl6eERJamhQWDh2RTBMU1FGaHJmaDZtbnl2RmJ1ODAwRFBjcG9KaS1nSUM0M2paNTFVbkV1RGQ0Zm5TVEZ0V2F1cjhPSGdNVjJ5ZWczeEJsLXktM1IyU1dn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:04:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hina Khan, Battling Cancer, Spends Christmas In Abu Dhabi: "Most Amazing Memories" - NDTV Movies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPN2ltbnJIYzhVMjcxTzJzNDE4M1pQNzRHRHYxY2xLYW56Z0ZJLURHSUVHQWJmM3V6amJnMXRDaUlhNnI3VUo1NjgzOVRLOFZLM21mdllQNE1sUmpjcDAybDNxWlIxcGRLQWNpbWFzWGEtQlBsc1JDdnpRNXVaS2ZvQ3hnQmJ1MEMwa1FhUGNNdTcwcEVwUUsxUjVTb0pSTTVLZFVzU2lSWUlkZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPN2ltbnJIYzhVMjcxTzJzNDE4M1pQNzRHRHYxY2xLYW56Z0ZJLURHSUVHQWJmM3V6amJnMXRDaUlhNnI3VUo1NjgzOVRLOFZLM21mdllQNE1sUmpjcDAybDNxWlIxcGRLQWNpbWFzWGEtQlBsc1JDdnpRNXVaS2ZvQ3hnQmJ1MEMwa1FhUGNNdTcwcEVwUUsxUjVTb0pSTTVLZFVzU2lSWUlkZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:50:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Agent Bhaijaan in Baby John to Tiger in Pathaan: Celebrating Salman Khan’s power-packed cameos on his 59th birthday - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Celebrating Salman Khan's Iconic Cameos on His 59th Birthday</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/Salman_Khan_cameoas_1735298140465_1735298166787.jpg" alt="Salman Khan and his epic cameos over the years" title="Salman Khan and his epic cameos over the years">
<figcaption>Salman Khan and his epic cameos over the years</figcaption>
<p>As we celebrate Bollywood's Bhaijaan Salman Khan's 59th birthday, we look back at his impressive cameos that never fail to thrill audiences and showcase his star power.</p>
<ul>
<li>Salman Khan's cameo in <i>Baby John</i> as Agent Bhaijaan stunned audiences and received rave reviews.</li>
<li>In <i>Singham Again</i>, Salman appears as Chulbul Pandey, creating a memorable moment at the end of the film.</li>
<li>His role as Tiger in <i>Pathaan</i> was a highlight and brought fans into a frenzy during his fight scene with Shah Rukh Khan.</li>
<li>The actor made a significant impact in <i>ZERO</i> and <i>Ajab Prem Ki Ghazab Kahani</i> with his engaging performances.</li>
<li>Known for charming cameo roles, he left a mark in iconic films like <i>Kuch Kuch Hota Hai</i> and <i>Saawariya</i>.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Even with his cameos, Salman Khan manages to send crowds roaring.”</blockquote>
<p>Salman Khan continues to be a beloved figure in Bollywood, and fans eagerly await his future projects both as a lead and in guest appearances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/baby-john-s-bhaijaan-pathaan-s-tiger-singham-again-s-chulbul-revisiting-salman-khan-s-badass-cameos-on-his-birthday-101735290604173.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/baby-john-s-bhaijaan-pathaan-s-tiger-singham-again-s-chulbul-revisiting-salman-khan-s-badass-cameos-on-his-birthday-101735290604173.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:27:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mika Singh reveals he removed the word 'Katrina' from a song to maintain his equation with Salman Khan; r - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mika Singh Discusses His Relationship with Salman Khan and Song Changes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not mentioned<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116714283,imgsize-52758,width-400,resizemode-4/116714283.jpg" alt="Mika Singh and Salman Khan" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Mika Singh reveals insights about his relationship with Salman Khan and changes he made to his song.</figcaption><p>Mika Singh shares personal anecdotes and professional interactions with Bollywood star Salman Khan, highlighting his respect for their friendship and the adjustments he makes, including changing lyrics in his songs to maintain their bond.</p><ul><li>Mika Singh reflects on his first meeting with Salman Khan in the 1990s.</li><li>He recalls interactions and how he never got Salman's number.</li><li>Discussed how Salman enjoyed his song 'Jhumme Ki Raat' despite Mika's self-criticism.</li><li>Mika changed a lyric in a song from 'Katrina' to 'Jacquelina' for respect towards Salman.</li><li>Revealed that the secret to getting biryani at Salman’s home is patience and timing.</li></ul><blockquote>“I changed the word ‘Katrina’ to ‘Jacquelina.”</blockquote><p>Mika Singh's anecdotes showcase the importance of personal relationships in the music industry, illustrating how friendships can influence creative decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mika-singh-reveals-he-removed-the-word-katrina-from-a-song-to-maintain-his-equation-with-salman-khan-reveals-the-key-to-getting-biryani-at-his-house-galaxy-apartments/articleshow/116714299.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mika-singh-reveals-he-removed-the-word-katrina-from-a-song-to-maintain-his-equation-with-salman-khan-reveals-the-key-to-getting-biryani-at-his-house-galaxy-apartments/articleshow/116714299.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024 Box Office Report Card: Bollywood struggles outside of Stree 2, Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3, Munjya and Shaitaan; Collects Rs 2500 crore - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2024 Box Office Report Card: Bollywood struggles outside of Stree 2, Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3, Munjya and Shaitaan; Collects Rs 2500 crore</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Updated on Dec 27, 2024 | <a href="https://www.pinkvilla.com/author/himesh-mankad">Himesh Mankad</a></p><img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/447427248_bollywood-report-card-2024-main.jpg" width="855" height="855" alt="2024 Box Office Report Card" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>2024 Box Office Report Card</figcaption><p>2024 has been a challenging year for Bollywood, with only 32 major films released and a total box office collection of approximately 2500 crore. This is the weakest theatrical year for the industry since 2012.</p><ul><li>The biggest grosser was Stree 2, earning Rs 585 crore.</li><li>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3 followed closely, grossing Rs 247 crore.</li><li>Franchise films dominated the box office, while original content struggled.</li><li>Failures included major stars in films like Merry Christmas and Chandu Champion.</li></ul><blockquote>"It's a drop of 43 percent over 2023, where the Hindi Film Industry collected Rs 4418 crore."</blockquote><p>Filmmakers are urged to diversify their genres to attract audiences back to theaters in 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/2024-box-office-report-card-bollywood-struggles-outside-of-stree-2-bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-munjya-and-shaitaan-collects-rs-2500-crore-1364570</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/2024-box-office-report-card-bollywood-struggles-outside-of-stree-2-bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-munjya-and-shaitaan-collects-rs-2500-crore-1364570</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:14:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UI (2024) Box Office Collection Day 7 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE92SzFXbjhia3Jqa3Z1YWZMRWdTZHpaLXMwY0gzZ0E3SXR4SWFLcm93bFJWc2FUX3VhOVpMQVhteTBXQm9Pa3VOSFVhdjhfUjhLdDVBR0tDbWlfbHE5aWluaHB0dWVOZzA1cGI5LUQ4Qlp4bjJyejJ4aQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE92SzFXbjhia3Jqa3Z1YWZMRWdTZHpaLXMwY0gzZ0E3SXR4SWFLcm93bFJWc2FUX3VhOVpMQVhteTBXQm9Pa3VOSFVhdjhfUjhLdDVBR0tDbWlfbHE5aWluaHB0dWVOZzA1cGI5LUQ4Qlp4bjJyejJ4aQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:08:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' box office collection week 3 wrap up: The Allu Arjun starrer collects Rs 129 crore in third we - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Pushpa 2' Box Office Collection Week 3 Wrap Up</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116713208,imgsize-76668,width-400,resizemode-4/116713208.jpg" alt="'Pushpa 2' box office collection week 3 wrap up: The Allu Arjun starrer collects Rs 129 crore in third week, total collection crosses Rs 1100 crore" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>'Pushpa 2' continues to dominate the box office.</figcaption>
<p>'Pushpa 2: The Rule' has made history by surpassing the previous box office record held by 'Baahubali 2'. In its third week alone, the film collected an impressive ₹ 129.5 crore, bringing the total gross to ₹ 1122.54 crore.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film has broken records previously held by 'Stree 2', 'Jawan', and 'Gadar 2'.</li>
  <li>In its third week, approximately ₹ 103.05 crore of the total collection came from the Hindi version.</li>
  <li>Despite a 50% drop from the previous week's collection of ₹ 264 crore, it achieved significant milestones.</li>
  <li>The movie's total net collection in India as of now is ₹ 1122.54 crore.</li>
  <li>'Pushpa 2' remains unaffected by the release of Varun Dhawan's 'Baby John' on Christmas.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"To cross ₹ 100 crore in its third week is not a small feat for a movie."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, 'Pushpa 2' has not only set a new benchmark for box office collections in Indian cinema but also demonstrated exceptional staying power in its third week.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-week-3-wrap-up-the-allu-arjun-starrer-collects-rs-129-crore-in-third-week-total-collection-crosses-rs-1100-crore/articleshow/116713122.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-week-3-wrap-up-the-allu-arjun-starrer-collects-rs-129-crore-in-third-week-total-collection-crosses-rs-1100-crore/articleshow/116713122.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All We Imagine As Light on OTT: When and where to watch Payal Kapadia's film - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>All We Imagine As Light on OTT: When and where to watch Payal Kapadia's film</h1>
<p><strong>Published On: </strong>Dec 27, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source: </strong>India Today</p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/all-we-imagine-as-light-035837478-16x9_3.jpg?VersionId=kThM4cah170cn.XFQAT62aY19o8IuKBB&amp;size=690:388" alt="All We Imagine As Light" title="A poster of All We Imagine As Light" width="690" height="388">
<figcaption>A poster of All We Imagine As Light.</figcaption>
<p>Payal Kapadia's award-winning film <em>All We Imagine As Light</em> is finally set to release on OTT, starring Kani Kusruti, Divya Prabha, Chhaya Kadam and Hridhu Haroon. The film will be available on Disney+ Hotstar starting January 3.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film explores the intertwined lives of two Malayali nurses in Mumbai.</li>
  <li>It has received multiple accolades including the Grand Prix at Cannes Film Festival and Golden Globe nominations.</li>
  <li>Director Payal Kapadia expresses excitement over its streaming release after a successful theatrical run.</li>
  <li>The film has been highly acclaimed, topping the BFI’s Sight and Sound poll for the best film of 2024.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I am thrilled at the love All We Imagine as Light has received from all of you.” - Payal Kapadia</blockquote>
<p>The film continues to build on its legacy as a significant release of the year, showcasing powerful performances by the cast.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/movies/story/all-we-imagine-as-light-ott-release-when-and-where-to-watch-payal-kapadia-kani-kusruti-film-2656254-2024-12-27</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/movies/story/all-we-imagine-as-light-ott-release-when-and-where-to-watch-payal-kapadia-kani-kusruti-film-2656254-2024-12-27</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:28:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Mai Hoon Na’ actor turned businessman's net worth surpasses that of Allu Arjun, Ranbir Kapoor, and Prabhas | Who is he? | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zayed Khan's Net Worth Surpasses Bollywood Stars</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> ET Now</p><p>Zayed Khan, known for his role in <i>Mai Hoon Na</i>, has seen his net worth soar to ₹1,500 crore, surpassing that of several Bollywood icons.</p><ul><li>Despite a series of box-office failures, Zayed Khan's business ventures have significantly increased his wealth.</li><li>His net worth is reportedly higher than that of Ranbir Kapoor (₹550 crore), Prabhas (₹400 crore), and Allu Arjun (₹350 crore).</li><li>Zayed emphasizes the importance of living within one's means to maintain financial stability.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are in the age of social media, where your image is… You’re probably living a life you cannot afford.”</blockquote><p>The rise of Zayed Khan as a businessman highlights the diverse paths actors can take after their film careers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/mai-hoon-na-actor-turned-businessmens-net-worth-surpasses-that-of-allu-arjun-ranbir-kapoor-and-prabhas-who-is-he-11735291907684.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/mai-hoon-na-actor-turned-businessmens-net-worth-surpasses-that-of-allu-arjun-ranbir-kapoor-and-prabhas-who-is-he-11735291907684.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:10:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin: Rajat seeks Isha's help to repair his relationship with Savi - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin: Rajat Seeks Isha's Help to Repair His Relationship with Savi</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Friday, December 27, 2024 at 10:05 AM</p><figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/9360-ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-rajat-seeks-ishas-help-to-convince-savi.jpg" width="640" height="360" alt="Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin: Rajat seeks Isha's help to convince Savi" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Isha and Rajat from Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin. Image courtesy: Star Plus</figcaption></figure><p>The upcoming episodes of <a href="https://www.indiaforums.com/show/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin_6570" title="Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin">Ghum Hai Kisikey Pyaar Meiin</a> take an emotional turn as Rajat struggles with guilt and seeks forgiveness from Savi.</p><ul><li>Rajat's jealousy leads to destructive behavior, including reckless driving and accusations against Savi.</li><li>In a drunken state, he severely crosses boundaries, leading to escalating tensions between them.</li><li>Rajat seeks Isha's help to reconcile with Savi after realizing the gravity of his mistakes.</li><li>Isha finds herself torn between helping Rajat and understanding Savi's pain.</li><li>Savi chooses to distance herself from Rajat, complicating the reconciliation efforts.</li></ul><blockquote>“Determined to make amends, Rajat goes to meet Savi, but she refuses to talk to him.”</blockquote><p>The storyline promises a rollercoaster of emotions as Rajat attempts to win back Savi's trust while he grapples with his own guilt.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-rajat-seeks-ishas-help-to-repair-his-relationship-with-savi_216006</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/ghum-hai-kisikey-pyaar-meiin-rajat-seeks-ishas-help-to-repair-his-relationship-with-savi_216006</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:06:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mika Singh recollects KRK's feud with Kapil Sharma, Honey Singh: ‘Kapil broke glass at his house, Honey pulled his hair’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mika Singh Discusses KRK's Feuds with Kapil Sharma and Honey Singh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/Mika_Singh_KRK_1735290531531_1735290531901.jpg" alt="Back in 2012, Kapil Sharma created a ruckus at KRK's house." title="Back in 2012, Kapil Sharma created a ruckus at KRK's house."><figcaption>Back in 2012, Kapil Sharma created a ruckus at KRK's house.</figcaption></figure><p>Mika Singh recently recalled the controversial encounters between Kamaal R Khan (KRK) and celebrities Kapil Sharma and Honey Singh during an interview.</p><ul><li>Mika describes his close relationship with KRK, calling him 'like a son' and a 'lovely human being.'</li><li>He shared an incident where Honey Singh reacted to KRK's comments with aggression.</li><li>In another incident, Kapil Sharma went to confront KRK but ended up causing chaos at his home.</li></ul><blockquote>“He is like my son. He is a very pyara insaan (lovely person).” – Mika Singh</blockquote><p>This reflection on past encounters highlights the tumultuous relationships in the Bollywood industry, particularly as it relates to KRK's notorious reputation for controversy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mika-singh-recollects-krks-feud-with-kapil-sharma-honey-singh-kapil-broke-glass-at-his-house-honey-pulled-his-hair-101735290378805.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/mika-singh-recollects-krks-feud-with-kapil-sharma-honey-singh-kapil-broke-glass-at-his-house-honey-pulled-his-hair-101735290378805.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:01:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Box Office Collections: Allu Arjun film tops 1500cr worldwide, nears USD 30M overseas - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Collections: Allu Arjun film tops 1500cr worldwide, nears USD 30M overseas</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 27, 2024 | Source: Pinkvilla</strong></p>
<p><img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/1970309933_pushpa-5.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2," title="Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"></p>
<figcaption>Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)</figcaption>
<p>Pushpa 2 hit another milestone as it surpassed the Rs. 1500 crore worldwide gross, becoming the fastest to achieve this milestone. The film has garnered significant collections both domestically and overseas.</p>
<ul>
<li>The film collected Rs. 1505 crore worldwide in 22 days, faster than Baahubali 2.</li>
<li>The domestic collection stands at Rs. 1257.50 crore, while overseas earnings reached USD 29.4 million.</li>
<li>Pushed by the Christmas holidays, the overseas collection is set to exceed USD 31 million.</li>
<li>The best-performing overseas market for the film is Nepal, where it has become the highest-grossing Indian film of all time.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The overseas business has been subpar in markets like the United States, which grossed USD 10.90 million against expectations of over USD 15 million.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Pushpa 2's success marks a significant achievement in Indian cinema, showcasing the film's strong domestic demand and potential for future earnings globally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collections-allu-arjun-film-tops-1500cr-worldwide-nears-usd-30m-overseas-1364549</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collections-allu-arjun-film-tops-1500cr-worldwide-nears-usd-30m-overseas-1364549</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sikandar’s teaser delay: The UNTOLD story on how Salman Khan and Sajid Nadiadwala prioritized respect over celebration on his birthday amid national mourning - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Salman Khan Delays Sikandar Teaser Out of Respect Amid National Mourning</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p><img src="https://stat4.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Sikandars-teaser-delay-The-UNTOLD-story-on-how-Salman-Khan-prioritized-respect-over-celebration-on-his-birthday-amid-national-mourning-2.jpg" alt="Sikandar's teaser delay" width="620" height="450"><figcaption>Salman Khan's poster for Sikandar</figcaption><p>On December 26, Salman Khan announced the teaser release of his upcoming film Sikandar, coinciding with his birthday. However, following the passing of ex-Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, the teaser was postponed to show respect. While fans expressed disappointment, industry insiders praised the decision.</p><ul><li>The teaser for Sikandar was originally set to release on December 27, coinciding with Salman Khan’s birthday.</li><li>Following the death of Manmohan Singh, the teaser release was postponed by 24 hours.</li><li>Industry insiders commend Salman Khan and producer Sajid Nadiadwala for prioritizing respect over celebration.</li><li>The film, directed by A R Murugadoss, is set to release on Eid 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“It wouldn’t be right to bring the teaser at a time when the country is mourning.” - Insider on Khan's decision</blockquote><p>This decision highlights the importance of empathy in the entertainment industry, balancing fan expectations with societal respect.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/sikandars-teaser-delay-untold-story-salman-khan-prioritized-respect-celebration-birthday-amid-national-mourning/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/sikandars-teaser-delay-untold-story-salman-khan-prioritized-respect-celebration-birthday-amid-national-mourning/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:31:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>