<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:24:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:24:27 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max (Kannada) First Day Advance Booking Report - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxPR3N3a3VVbF9McXNhTFFvaldxeVlfWXpqTFV1dFIxNTFOLVp5RmRkUEFZZWRURUJzQ1EyWVBkei0yV1VWMlYxbHNZaHZtalBVcVZ1ZmJZcGpCTWl0TDJVaWRBOUVpQXhsVXhQc0tvR1BnSktUdkItWDNIZF84WXNVaDZxZ2RIRzlZMXpF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxPR3N3a3VVbF9McXNhTFFvaldxeVlfWXpqTFV1dFIxNTFOLVp5RmRkUEFZZWRURUJzQ1EyWVBkei0yV1VWMlYxbHNZaHZtalBVcVZ1ZmJZcGpCTWl0TDJVaWRBOUVpQXhsVXhQc0tvR1BnSktUdkItWDNIZF84WXNVaDZxZ2RIRzlZMXpF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:32:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Love and Relationship Horoscope for December 24, 2024 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Love and Relationship Horoscope for December 24, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/pavitra_1615623290582_1734981932087.JPG" alt="Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope 2024: Find out love predictions for December 24." title="Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope 2024: Find out love predictions for December 24.">
<figcaption>Daily Love and Relationship Horoscope 2024: Find out love predictions for December 24.</figcaption>
<p>The horoscope for December 24, 2024, highlights various aspects of love for each zodiac sign, encouraging individuals to embrace their emotions, communicate openly, and appreciate the relationships they have.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Aries:</strong> Embrace your feelings and communicate with your partner.</li>
<li><strong>Taurus:</strong> Appreciate romantic moments and engage deeply in your relationships.</li>
<li><strong>Gemini:</strong> Honesty is key; express your feelings to strengthen connections.</li>
<li><strong>Cancer:</strong> Kindness and compassion will open your heart to love.</li>
<li><strong>Leo:</strong> Let love develop naturally without controlling it.</li>
<li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Accept love when it comes, don’t overanalyze it.</li>
<li><strong>Libra:</strong> Genuine actions will strengthen bonds; patience is essential for singles.</li>
<li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Focus on personal growth in your relationship.</li>
<li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> Appreciate unspoken connections and be open to new experiences.</li>
<li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Apologize and show commitment to resolve misunderstandings.</li>
<li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Discuss future goals to build a stable foundation with your partner.</li>
<li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Reflect on past loves and value the lessons learned.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Though people change or break up, their experiences remain valuable and help in the process of development.”</blockquote>
<p>This horoscope encourages individuals to reflect on their relationships and be open to both love and the journey it entails.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/love-and-relationship-horoscope-for-december-24-2024-101734981571760.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/love-and-relationship-horoscope-for-december-24-2024-101734981571760.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:30:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prashanth Neel reveals he was 'a little disappointed' Prabhas' Salaar box office performance: 'I'm going - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prashanth Neel reveals he was 'a little disappointed' Prabhas' Salaar box office performance: 'I'm going to make up for it'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>Prashanth Neel, the director of the highly anticipated film 'Salaar', expressed his disappointment regarding the film's box office performance. In an interview, Neel acknowledged that he expected better results and committed to making up for it in future projects.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Prashanth Neel's remarks came following the release of 'Salaar'.</li>
  <li>Despite high expectations, the film's performance did not meet the anticipated box office numbers.</li>
  <li>Neel expressed determination to improve his future works in response to the current outcome.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I'm going to make up for it" - Prashanth Neel on his future projects.</blockquote>
<p>Neel's candid reflection reminds stakeholders in the film industry of the pressures surrounding box office success and the rapid response often required from filmmakers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/telugu/movies/news/prashanth-neel-reveals-he-was-a-little-disappointed-prabhas-salaar-box-office-performance-im-going-to-make-up-for-it/articleshow/116571040.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/telugu/movies/news/prashanth-neel-reveals-he-was-a-little-disappointed-prabhas-salaar-box-office-performance-im-going-to-make-up-for-it/articleshow/116571040.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE Raw Results – 12/23/24 (Drew McIntyre kicks off the show, Women’s Intercontinental Title Tournament continues) - Wrestleview.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WWE Raw Results</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <br> <strong>Source:</strong> Wrestleview.com</p>
<figure>
<img decoding="async" width="1000" height="640" src="https://www.wrestleview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image-13.png" alt="WWE Raw Highlights">
<figcaption>Highlights from WWE Raw on December 23, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This week's WWE Raw saw Drew McIntyre kick off the show with a powerful promo reflecting on his struggles and the lack of support from his fellow wrestlers, leading to a confrontation with Sami Zayn. The Women’s Intercontinental Championship Tournament also progressed with IYO SKY securing a victory.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Drew McIntyre opens the show addressing his injuries and personal loss.</li>
  <li>Controversy arose as Sami Zayn challenged McIntyre following their heated exchange.</li>
  <li>IYO SKY won a triple threat match against Alba Fyre and Natalya to advance in the Women's Intercontinental Championship Tournament.</li>
  <li>Damian Priest faced off against Dominik Mysterio, leading to a chaotic brawl involving the Judgment Day and the War Raiders.</li>
  <li>Seth Rollins expressed his eagerness for his upcoming match against CM Punk in an interview segment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Awesome segment with Drew McIntyre and Sami Zayn. McIntyre's heel promos work so well because in some way he has a point, but it's just so skewed and twisted.” — Wrestleview.com</blockquote>
<p>This episode highlighted the ongoing storylines and rivalries within WWE, setting the stage for future matches and developments as the new year approaches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wrestleview.com/wwe-raw-results/336889-live-wwe-raw-results-december-23-2024-boston/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wrestleview.com/wwe-raw-results/336889-live-wwe-raw-results-december-23-2024-boston/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:16:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diljit Dosanjh, Bryan Adams: Indians angry at concert facilities - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian fans fed up with paying top prices for stinking toilets and traffic jams at concerts</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>October 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>BBC News</p><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/470a/live/c2a0b9a0-bea1-11ef-90b7-79c53aaf0e8f.jpg.webp" alt="Diljit Dosanjh concert" /><figcaption>Crowds at Diljit Dosanjh's recent concert in Chandigarh complained of poor facilities</figcaption><p>Indian concertgoers are growing increasingly frustrated with the poor facilities at major music events. Attendees at recent concerts, including those by Diljit Dosanjh and Bryan Adams, have voiced complaints regarding sanitation, crowd control, and the high cost of tickets.</p><ul><li>Concert attendees reported minimal crowd control and unsanitary conditions at venues.</li><li>Overloaded mobile networks hindered communication and raised safety concerns during events.</li><li>Many fans expressed dissatisfaction with transport logistics, facing severe traffic jams after shows.</li><li>Despite the burgeoning concert industry in India, facilities have failed to keep pace with growing demand.</li><li>Concerts generate significant revenue, with expectations for a growth increase of 25% by 2025.</li><li>High-profile artists have hinted at refusing to perform again unless infrastructure improves.</li></ul><blockquote>“You pay so much for a ticket and what do you get in return? A possible urinary infection and a bad headache with some bouts of music.” - Amrita Kaur</blockquote><p>As the Indian concert scene anticipates upcoming performances from major artists, fans hope for improved facilities and experiences at future events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy480kly9zo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy480kly9zo</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 23:44:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mufasa: The Lion King Box Office Collection Day 4 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxOQzRsUGdFV1BPV19ldENnLU40WFQ4VmNEZGpIUGp6QzhyblQ5N2ZkeWtrRTdpMlk2Wl93TkticHZxcWhUWm9LNTNEM3BNWkEtMDV5RlNYbnJIRzBVeWhES01RZ3VsampwNGJ6NmxnQm1EN2paU0xTSHg5bThucEZrWTFBYlFLblZ4dE92YW5pRkg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxOQzRsUGdFV1BPV19ldENnLU40WFQ4VmNEZGpIUGp6QzhyblQ5N2ZkeWtrRTdpMlk2Wl93TkticHZxcWhUWm9LNTNEM3BNWkEtMDV5RlNYbnJIRzBVeWhES01RZ3VsampwNGJ6NmxnQm1EN2paU0xTSHg5bThucEZrWTFBYlFLblZ4dE92YW5pRkg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 23:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pisces Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 24, 2024 predicts reflection and growth - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pisces Daily Horoscope Today, December 24, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/Pisces_1728478870554_1734973486753.jpg" alt="Pisces Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 24, 2024. Expressing your feelings can deepen your connection and bring you closer together." />
  <figcaption>Pisces Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 24, 2024. Expressing your feelings can deepen your connection and bring you closer together.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Today focuses on reflection and growth for Pisces. It emphasizes embracing change and trusting intuition to guide personal development.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Today is a day to reflect and grow personally.</li>
  <li>Opportunities for personal development are abundant; be open to them.</li>
  <li>In love, open communication with a partner is encouraged.</li>
  <li>At work, sharing creative ideas will lead to recognition.</li>
  <li>Financially, today is a day for careful budgeting and planning for future stability.</li>
  <li>Health should be prioritized with a balanced diet and regular exercise.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Expressing your feelings can deepen your connection and bring you closer together." - Dr. J.N. Pandey</blockquote>
<p>The day offers a chance for Pisces to foster connection and growth in various life aspects. Trusting oneself and remaining open to change will lead to enriching experiences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/pisces-daily-horoscope-today-dec-24-2024-predicts-reflection-and-growth-101734970393655.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/pisces-daily-horoscope-today-dec-24-2024-predicts-reflection-and-growth-101734970393655.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:41:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, Dec 24, 2024 predicts embracing new ideas - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 24, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/Aquarius_1728478944944_1734973446494.jpg" alt="Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, October 10, 2024. Be careful while handling challenges at work but there will be success." />
<figcaption>Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, October 10, 2024. Be careful while handling challenges at work but there will be success.</figcaption>
<p>Today presents opportunities for growth and new experiences, enhancing both personal and professional aspects of life. Stay open to change and trust your instincts.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Aquarius should explore fresh paths and perspectives.</li>
    <li>Financial stability allows focus on relationships and self-care.</li>
    <li>Embracing new ideas fosters personal growth.</li>
    <li>In love, deepen connections through new activities.</li>
    <li>Work relationships are strengthened by sharing innovative ideas.</li>
    <li>Maintain a balanced health regimen, including diet and exercise.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Trust your instincts when making decisions, as they will lead you in the right direction.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Aquarius individuals are encouraged to embrace the day's opportunities with optimism and openness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/aquarius-daily-horoscope-today-dec-24-2024-predicts-embracing-new-ideas-101734970386601.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/aquarius-daily-horoscope-today-dec-24-2024-predicts-embracing-new-ideas-101734970386601.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:40:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today, December 24, 2024: Check astrological prediction for Gemini, Scorpio and other signs - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Horoscope Today, December 24, 2024: Check astrological prediction for Gemini, Scorpio and other signs</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/31_06497b.jpg?w=640" alt="horoscope" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Horoscope Today, December 24, 2024: Leo, Pisces, Cancer, Libra and other sun signs, check your horoscope for today (Tuesday) (Source: Canva)</figcaption><p>Today’s horoscope offers insights for various sun signs, from Aries to Pisces, highlighting opportunities and challenges to anticipate.</p><ul><li><strong>Aries:</strong> Expect shocks and surprises.</li><li><strong>Taurus:</strong> Use this time to settle emotional matters.</li><li><strong>Gemini:</strong> A major ambition is set to progress.</li><li><strong>Cancer:</strong> Value friendships and support.</li><li><strong>Leo:</strong> Focus on health and exercise.</li><li><strong>Virgo:</strong> Monitor financial situations carefully.</li><li><strong>Libra:</strong> Navigate through changing moods and events.</li><li><strong>Scorpio:</strong> Be prudent and focus on necessary tasks.</li><li><strong>Sagittarius:</strong> Focus on positive relationships despite financial concerns.</li><li><strong>Capricorn:</strong> Family matters demand attention.</li><li><strong>Aquarius:</strong> Address personal emotions effectively.</li><li><strong>Pisces:</strong> Start your new personal cycle positively.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's important that you start your new personal cycle on the right foot.”</blockquote><p>Overall, today’s horoscope encourages self-reflection and interaction with others, paving the way for personal growth and clarity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/horoscope/horoscope-today-december-24-2024-9740625/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/horoscope/horoscope-today-december-24-2024-9740625/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 21:30:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jay-Z ready to ‘throw’ Sean ‘Diddy’ Combs ‘under the bus’ to stay out of jail amid rape lawsuit - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jay-Z ready to ‘throw’ Sean ‘Diddy’ Combs ‘under the bus’ to stay out of jail amid rape lawsuit</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/Sexual-Misconduct-Diddy-Jay-Z-1_1734984613309_1734984628363.jpg" alt="Jay-Z reportedly plans to distance himself from Diddy, focusing on clearing his name from serious rape allegations. (AP Photo/Kathy Willens, File)(AP)" />
<figcaption>Jay-Z reportedly plans to distance himself from Diddy, focusing on clearing his name from serious rape allegations. (AP Photo/Kathy Willens, File)(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Jay-Z is reportedly distancing himself from longtime friend Sean 'Diddy' Combs amid the music mogul's ongoing legal troubles. Sources suggest that Jay-Z would not hesitate to sever ties with Diddy if it meant clearing his name of serious rape allegations currently facing him.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jay-Z is allegedly ready to sever ties with Diddy amid ongoing rape allegations.</li>
<li>The lawsuit accuses both of raping a 13-year-old after the 2000 MTV Video Music Awards.</li>
<li>Sources state that Jay-Z is more focused on clearing his name rather than supporting Diddy.</li>
<li>Diddy is reportedly pleased that Jay-Z is fighting against the same accuser.</li>
<li>Jay-Z's legal team plans to have the lawsuit dismissed, emphasizing the goal of clearing his name.</li>
<li>Diddy’s trial is scheduled for May 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Jay-Z would absolutely throw Diddy under the bus if that is what it took to clear his name.”</blockquote>
<p>In summary, Jay-Z is prioritizing his personal reputation in light of serious allegations, demonstrating a willingness to distance himself from Diddy as crises unfold.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/jayz-ready-to-throw-sean-diddy-combs-under-the-bus-to-stay-out-of-jail-amid-rape-lawsuit-101734984138521.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/jayz-ready-to-throw-sean-diddy-combs-under-the-bus-to-stay-out-of-jail-amid-rape-lawsuit-101734984138521.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 20:11:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deepika Padukone-Ranveer Singh's daughter Dua's introduction meet with shutterbugs 'was nothing short of magical' reveal paps; say, little one's face is 'perfect blend of her parents' features' - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Deepika Padukone-Ranveer Singh's daughter Dua's introduction meet with shutterbugs 'was nothing short of magical'</h1><p><strong>Updated on Dec 24, 2024 | Source: Pinkvilla</strong></p><div><img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/1085656237_aph-min.jpg" alt="Deepika Padukone and Ranveer Singh" title="PC: APH Images" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>PC: APH Images</figcaption></div><p>On December 23, 2024, Bollywood couple Ranveer Singh and Deepika Padukone hosted a special meet-and-greet with the paparazzi to introduce their daughter, Dua. The event featured delicious food and sweets for the attending photographers, leaving a magical impression on everyone.</p><ul><li>The couple's daughter, Dua Singh Padukone, was described as having a perfect blend of her parents' features.</li><li>While the event was in honor of Dua, she was initially half-asleep but occasionally opened her eyes, captivating the attendees.</li><li>The paparazzi were treated to home-cooked food from Deepika’s favorite place, and a warm welcome by Ranveer.</li><li>Guests were asked to refrain from loud noises and were requested not to publish pictures of Dua until the family was ready.</li></ul><blockquote>The entire meeting was nothing short of magical and will remain etched in our hearts forever.</blockquote><p>Ultimately, the event spotlighted not only Dua but also the thoughtful and protective nature of her parents, as they navigate fame and family.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/news/deepika-padukone-ranveer-singhs-daughter-duas-introduction-meet-with-shutterbugs-was-nothing-short-of-magical-reveal-paps-her-face-is-perfect-blend-of-her-parents-features-1364075</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/news/deepika-padukone-ranveer-singhs-daughter-duas-introduction-meet-with-shutterbugs-was-nothing-short-of-magical-reveal-paps-her-face-is-perfect-blend-of-her-parents-features-1364075</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:49:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope Today: Astrological prediction for December 24, 2024 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Horoscope Today: Astrological prediction for December 24, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/horoscope_1672156308727_1734943443891.jpg" alt="Horoscope Today: Astrological prediction for December 24, 2024. (Pixabay)">
<figcaption>Horoscope Today: Astrological prediction for December 24, 2024. (Pixabay)</figcaption>
<p>This article provides daily astrological predictions for all zodiac signs, helping individuals understand what to expect as they navigate their day.</p>
<ul>
<li>Aries: Manage finances carefully; avoid sharing business plans.</li>
<li>Taurus: Potential for profitable deals; prioritizing health is advised.</li>
<li>Gemini: Expect payments; a new project progresses smoothly.</li>
<li>Cancer: Opportunities for income increase; travel plans materializing.</li>
<li>Leo: Financial troubles may resolve; a promotion is possible.</li>
<li>Virgo: Additional responsibilities may arise; travel may be required.</li>
<li>Libra: Financial gains anticipated; health improves with lifestyle changes.</li>
<li>Scorpio: Financially strong; potential property investments.</li>
<li>Sagittarius: Returns on loans expected; positive academic acknowledgment.</li>
<li>Capricorn: Avoid laziness; cheerful home life enhances happiness.</li>
<li>Aquarius: Recognition at work; potential for new romance.</li>
<li>Pisces: Attention needed to finances; planning for property transactions advised.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Love Focus: Be mindful of your partner’s feelings today." - Daily Horoscope</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the daily horoscope offers valuable insights into individual zodiac signs, allowing readers to prepare for their day with a better understanding of potential challenges and opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-astrological-prediction-for-december-24-2024-101734943407710.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/horoscope-today-astrological-prediction-for-december-24-2024-101734943407710.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:30:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It was very uncomfortable shooting for the ‘Peelings’ song-Rashmika - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rashmika Describes Uncomfortable Experience While Shooting 'Peelings' Song</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 24, 2024, by 123telugu</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Peelings.jpg" alt="Peelings Song Image" width="445" height="450"><figcaption>Rashmika in 'Peelings'</figcaption><p>Rashmika Mandanna shares her experiences shooting the song "Peelings," revealing her discomfort with the dance steps and the trolling she faced from audiences.</p><ul><li>Rashmika is a leading actress in Indian cinema, known for her role in <i>Pushpa 2</i>.</li><li>The song "Peelings" has been well-received, though some criticize its choreography.</li><li>Rashmika expressed surprise at the dance steps during rehearsals.</li><li>She found the shooting process more challenging than it seemed.</li><li>Despite initial discomfort, she gained confidence through her director and co-star.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was uncomfortable shooting for the song, but I trusted the team.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Rashmika's candid reflections highlight the pressures actors face in delivering performances that satisfy audience expectations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/it-was-very-uncomfortable-shooting-for-the-peelings-song-rashmika.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/it-was-very-uncomfortable-shooting-for-the-peelings-song-rashmika.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Baldoni's apology to wife Emily resurfaces amid Blake Lively's sexual harassment lawsuit - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Baldoni Apologizes to Wife Emily Amid Blake Lively's Sexual Harassment Lawsuit</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/ends_with_us_1723611147612_1734980346813.png" alt="Blake Lively and Justin Baldoni in It Ends With Us" title="Blake Lively and Justin Baldoni in It Ends With Us"><figcaption>Blake Lively and Justin Baldoni in It Ends With Us</figcaption><p>Justin Baldoni's wedding vows, where he apologized to his wife Emily, have resurfaced in the context of Blake Lively's ongoing sexual harassment lawsuit against him.</p><ul><li>Baldoni publicly acknowledged his shortcomings during his wedding vows.</li><li>The resurfacing of the clip coincides with Lively's serious allegations against Baldoni.</li><li>Lively claims harassment and a hostile work environment during the filming of 'It Ends With Us.'</li><li>Lively's lawsuit also mentions a smear campaign against her, which Baldoni's lawyer refutes.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’m sorry for all my faults, my shortcomings, for my insecurities and my ego...” - Justin Baldoni</blockquote><p>This unfolding drama highlights issues in Hollywood regarding workplace conduct and personal accountability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/justin-baldonis-apology-to-wife-emily-resurfaces-amid-blake-livelys-sexual-harassment-lawsuit-101734978885546.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/justin-baldonis-apology-to-wife-emily-resurfaces-amid-blake-livelys-sexual-harassment-lawsuit-101734978885546.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:00:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress Leader Files Complaint Against Allu Arjun Over Scene In 'Pushpa 2' - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxNWmlvNUZMM3JBeGg3ZUpxOHBxOEFVdUMyQTFOVnVnblU0OS1xSmFPVXB0cm90dEtrSEhDQ2RRVl9CSGNHUU9zVDFxX3ZZX0tJWnNXaHJNaWtSM2tuOGl1X21VZHlfbTV5cEpDSXdOM3dwNG1hb0hpWk92RW5EdkpVd0hRdnI3Wk40SmRhVG1yVkVPcjY4NFEtd2lsMHBlMU5hMjFGYUFvekxfVlVIcm0wcE1MM3JDS3BhdGxpYV8wM015UTDSAcsBQVVfeXFMT1ZTb1dDblZReDZ4LVVPOHFFZFFNMnNTb1dUczZ1WjZ5OU12enoySVBaaWZQSlEzNGQzRFdYeVBnRm1MUXplNk1STlF6RUt5ZVl3QXJqOFVaMWFhTzk0QkNSWlNzN3AxNWh4RF9VMUZudEhmUTVIMGtIaVRKbnk5cUY2OHRYSjJhUFpUd2kwbXhpeHBXOW93UjRUSEhPRXYtVVJvaUpZZjd5bUg1MEd4bWtCNHZOZUo4WDZ5WTZvdkNnVDB5VzRLUXJ3YVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxNWmlvNUZMM3JBeGg3ZUpxOHBxOEFVdUMyQTFOVnVnblU0OS1xSmFPVXB0cm90dEtrSEhDQ2RRVl9CSGNHUU9zVDFxX3ZZX0tJWnNXaHJNaWtSM2tuOGl1X21VZHlfbTV5cEpDSXdOM3dwNG1hb0hpWk92RW5EdkpVd0hRdnI3Wk40SmRhVG1yVkVPcjY4NFEtd2lsMHBlMU5hMjFGYUFvekxfVlVIcm0wcE1MM3JDS3BhdGxpYV8wM015UTDSAcsBQVVfeXFMT1ZTb1dDblZReDZ4LVVPOHFFZFFNMnNTb1dUczZ1WjZ5OU12enoySVBaaWZQSlEzNGQzRFdYeVBnRm1MUXplNk1STlF6RUt5ZVl3QXJqOFVaMWFhTzk0QkNSWlNzN3AxNWh4RF9VMUZudEhmUTVIMGtIaVRKbnk5cUY2OHRYSjJhUFpUd2kwbXhpeHBXOW93UjRUSEhPRXYtVVJvaUpZZjd5bUg1MEd4bWtCNHZOZUo4WDZ5WTZvdkNnVDB5VzRLUXJ3YVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:40:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moushumi Chatterjee Calls Rajesh Khanna An 'Egoistic' Star: 'How Can He Stay Away From...' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Moushumi Chatterjee Calls Rajesh Khanna An 'Egoistic' Star: 'How Can He Stay Away From...'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Moushumi Chatterjee has worked with Rajesh Khanna." />
<figcaption>Moushumi Chatterjee has worked with Rajesh Khanna.</figcaption>
<p>Moushumi Chatterjee opened up about yesteryear superstar Rajesh Khanna in a new interview, revealing that he had a significant ego due to his success.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Moushumi described Rajesh Khanna as an egoistic man but qualified that this was justified because of his remarkable success with 17 consecutive hits.</li>
  <li>She recalled her fond memories of meeting him, particularly in his final days, where he praised her in front of her daughter.</li>
  <li>Rajesh Khanna, known as Bollywood’s first superstar, passed away in 2012 and is remembered for his many classic films.</li>
  <li>Moushumi also commented on Amitabh Bachchan, noting changes in his behavior after he became a superstar.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“During our time, one hero who was an egoist was Rajesh Khanna. And rightfully so. He gave so many hits. How can he stay away from success getting into his head?”</blockquote>
<p>The commentary by Moushumi highlights the complexities of fame and the personal relationships within the film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/moushumi-chatterjee-calls-rajesh-khanna-an-egoistic-star-how-can-he-stay-away-from-9165245.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/moushumi-chatterjee-calls-rajesh-khanna-an-egoistic-star-how-can-he-stay-away-from-9165245.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:35:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jhanak: Arshi’s death to bring dramatic turn in Jhanak and Aniruddha’s life post leap - India Forums]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jhanak Faces Major Changes After Arshi's Death Post Leap</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> Monday, December 23, 2024 at 5:51 PM</p>
<figure><img src="https://img.indiaforums.com/media/640x0/62/8894-jhanak.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Jhanak"><figcaption>Arshi to die post leap in Jhanak</figcaption></figure>
<p>The upcoming leap in the show Jhanak is set to introduce significant changes in the relationships among Jhanak, Aniruddh, and Arshi, following a period of decline in the show's ratings.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Recent buzz indicates a five-year leap in the storyline.</li>
  <li>Arshi reveals her pregnancy with Aniruddh's child, shocking Jhanak.</li>
  <li>After the leap, Arshi's character will pass away, leaving Aniruddh to raise their son alone.</li>
  <li>Jhanak will focus on work while feeling the void left by Aniruddh.</li>
  <li>The storyline emphasizes emotional distance and past memories as key themes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The show kicked off with a strong start but has since slipped out of the top 5 contenders, prompting a major twist.”</blockquote>
<p>This dramatic turn of events aims to rejuvenate viewer interest as the characters navigate their complex relationships and individual struggles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiaforums.com/article/jhanak-arshis-death-to-bring-dramatic-turn-in-jhanak-and-aniruddhas-life-post-leap_215796</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiaforums.com/article/jhanak-arshis-death-to-bring-dramatic-turn-in-jhanak-and-aniruddhas-life-post-leap_215796</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:56:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024 Was the Year of Sex Onscreen - Rolling Stone]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2024 Was the Year of Sex Onscreen</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Rolling Stone</p><figure><img src="https://www.rollingstone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/s-ex-positive-television-film-2024.jpg?w=1581&amp;h=1054&amp;crop=1" alt="Challengers, Industry, Babygirl" /><figcaption><cite>Niko Tavernise/Amazon MGM Studios; Liam Daniel/HBO; Niko Tavernise/A24</cite></figcaption></figure><p>In 2024, Hollywood witnessed a resurgence of sex in film and television after several years of retreat from eroticism. Unlike prior narratives about young people's sexual behavior, recent cultural trends indicate a bold embrace of sexually explicit content.</p><ul><li>2024 has seen a significant comeback in onscreen sexual content.</li><li>Shows and movies like <em>Challengers</em>, <em>Industry</em>, and <em>Babygirl</em> have highlighted sexual themes intertwined with power dynamics.</li><li>Despite a historical decline in sex scenes, recent productions have embraced explicit depictions and themes of desire.</li><li>Notable films explore the juxtaposition of sexual expression with personal power struggles.</li></ul><blockquote>“Everything in the world is about sex, except sex. Sex is about power.”</blockquote><p>The return of sex onscreen signifies a notable shift in cultural conversations, presenting a nuanced exploration of intimacy, power, and human relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-features/sex-scenes-in-film-and-tv-2024-1235215960/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-features/sex-scenes-in-film-and-tv-2024-1235215960/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:55:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shyam Benegal dies: Akshay Kumar, Manoj Bajpayee and Shekhar Kapur mourn demise of veteran filmmaker, call him 'legend' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shyam Benegal dies: Akshay Kumar, Manoj Bajpayee and Shekhar Kapur mourn demise of veteran filmmaker, call him 'legend'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/shyam_benegal_1734974405371_1734974405846.jpg" alt="Shyam Benegal was suffering from a chronic kidney disease." title="Shyam Benegal was suffering from a chronic kidney disease."><figcaption>Shyam Benegal was suffering from a chronic kidney disease.</figcaption><p>Shyam Benegal, celebrated Indian filmmaker, passed away on December 23 at the age of 90. His death has prompted an outpouring of tributes from Bollywood celebrities who remembered him as a legend and visionary in Indian cinema.</p><ul><li>Benegal had recently celebrated his 90th birthday.</li><li>He was known for his pioneering work in Indian parallel cinema.</li><li>His daughter confirmed his passing, citing the great loss it represents.</li><li>He won multiple National Awards and was honored with Padma Shri and Padma Bhushan.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pained to know of Shyam Benegal ji’s demise. One of the finest filmmakers in our country, truly a legend. Om Shanti.” - Akshay Kumar</blockquote><blockquote>“A heartbreaking loss for Indian cinema...his legacy will live on in the stories he told and the lives he touched.” - Manoj Bajpayee</blockquote><p>Benegal's influence on Indian cinema is celebrated widely, and his legacy as a storyteller will continue to inspire future generations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shyam-benegal-dies-akshay-kumar-manoj-bajpayee-and-shekhar-kapur-mourn-demise-of-veteran-filmmaker-call-him-legend-101734973894146.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shyam-benegal-dies-akshay-kumar-manoj-bajpayee-and-shekhar-kapur-mourn-demise-of-veteran-filmmaker-call-him-legend-101734973894146.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:31:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 19 Early Trends: History Has Been Created, Allu Arjun Inaugurates 700 Crore Club! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 19 Early Trends: History Has Been Created, Allu Arjun Inaugurates 700 Crore Club</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-day-19-et-bo-001.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 19 Early Trends" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 19 Early Trends (Photo Credit – Facebook)</figcaption><p>Ahead of the Christmas vacation and New Year festivity, Pushpa 2 (Hindi) is setting itself to explode like anything at the Indian box office. After enjoying the rush for 18 straight days, it was expected to slow down on the third Monday, but it remains strong, flirting with the 10 crore mark and creating history by becoming the first Hindi film to enter the 700 crore club.</p><ul><li>Pushpa 2 has broken numerous records in Hindi cinema.</li><li>It surpassed Stree 2’s collection of 627.50 crores to become the highest-grossing Hindi film.</li><li>The film maintained strong occupancy rates despite weekend fluctuations.</li><li>Day 19 projections suggest earnings between 9-10 crores.</li><li>Total box office collection so far lies between 701.50-702.50 crores.</li></ul><blockquote>“Allu Arjun has inaugurated the 700 crore club.”</blockquote><p>This remarkable performance indicates potential future earnings, possibly setting the stage for the next milestone in Hindi film collections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-19-early-trends-history-has-been-created-allu-arjun-inaugurates-700-crore-club/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-19-early-trends-history-has-been-created-allu-arjun-inaugurates-700-crore-club/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:22:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“It’s Not Finished Yet, But…“: James Gunn Teases How Long ‘Superman’ Will Be - Collider]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>“It’s Not Finished Yet, But…”: James Gunn Teases How Long ‘Superman’ Will Be</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified <strong>Source:</strong> Collider</p>
<div><img src="https://static1.colliderimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/copy-of-collider-template-91.jpg" alt="David Corenswet as Superman" /><figcaption>Image via Warner Bros</figcaption></div>
<p>The highly anticipated first trailer for James Gunn's 'Superman' has collected over 250 million views in just 24 hours. Gunn hinted at a runtime of "under two and a half hours" for the film, generating excitement and expectations among fans.</p>
<h2>Key Points</h2>
<ul>
  <li>The trailer for 'Superman' gained over 250 million views in 24 hours.</li>
  <li>James Gunn stated the film's runtime will be "under two and a half hours".</li>
  <li>The story focuses on Clark Kent reconciling his heritage and human upbringing.</li>
  <li>The cast includes David Corenswet as Superman and Rachel Brosnahan as Lois Lane.</li>
  <li>The film is set to be released on July 11, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It’s not finished yet so I don’t know. Under two and a half hours.” — James Gunn</blockquote>
<p>The new 'Superman' film promises action and character depth, appealing to both established fans and new audiences alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://collider.com/superman-runtime-james-gunn/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collider.com/superman-runtime-james-gunn/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UI (UI The Movie) BO Collection Day 4 Early Updates: Upendra's Film Crosses Significant Milestone, DEETS - Filmibeat]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UI (UI The Movie) BO Collection Day 4 Early Updates</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Monday, December 23, 2024, 22:21 [IST]</p><img src="https://images.filmibeat.com/img/2024/12/newproject-2024-12-23t215953-390-1734971400.jpg" alt="UI UI The Movie BO Collection Day 4 Early Updates" width="600" height="338"><figcaption>UI UI The Movie BO Collection Day 4 Early Updates</figcaption><p>UI the movie, released on December 20, has garnered significant buzz due to its intriguing plot and star cast. As it steps into day 4, the film has seen a dip but crossed a significant box office milestone.</p><ul><li>The film earned Rs. 1.91 Cr as of 10 PM on day 4.</li><li>First Sunday earnings were Rs. 5.95 Cr, with a -19.42% dip from the opening day earnings of Rs. 6.95 Cr.</li><li>Total earnings in India reached Rs. 20.41 Cr nett.</li><li>The film achieved a gross collection of Rs. 21.65 Cr in India and Rs. 22.50 Cr worldwide.</li><li>Kannada version contributed Rs. 16.3 Cr, Telugu version Rs. 2.07 Cr, Tamil Rs. 0.09 Cr, and Hindi Rs. 0.04 Cr.</li><li>The film is directed by Upendra and stars Upendra, Sunny Leone, and others.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite seeing a dip, the movie has crossed the Rs. 20 Cr milestone at the box office.”</blockquote><p>The film's ability to maintain a strong position at the box office highlights its popularity despite fluctuations in daily earnings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.filmibeat.com/kannada/news/2024/ui-ui-the-movie-box-office-collection-day-4-early-updates-upendras-film-crosses-significant-mile-434987.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.filmibeat.com/kannada/news/2024/ui-ui-the-movie-box-office-collection-day-4-early-updates-upendras-film-crosses-significant-mile-434987.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:51:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viduthalai Part - 2 Box Office Collection Day 4 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQMHpSWEdYcFM0MEFSR3c2WGZxaV9MUWpNdk1MMzlsR2tGMDVJLUwzLWVnV0VIUGhYWE5LQmJhZzZ4N19ib1pIVWlhOTVqaW9tazg2WnJFcUVRTHBsNUNrZGJlcW9Gb3pnalB2SktldV9US05FZHJ3WDV2R2NNNFlzVmVnNEtES3pLTzl2Z2ln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQMHpSWEdYcFM0MEFSR3c2WGZxaV9MUWpNdk1MMzlsR2tGMDVJLUwzLWVnV0VIUGhYWE5LQmJhZzZ4N19ib1pIVWlhOTVqaW9tazg2WnJFcUVRTHBsNUNrZGJlcW9Gb3pnalB2SktldV9US05FZHJ3WDV2R2NNNFlzVmVnNEtES3pLTzl2Z2ln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:44:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karthik Subbaraj to give a solid treat to Suriya fans for Christmas - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karthik Subbaraj to give a solid treat to Suriya fans for Christmas</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 23, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source:</strong> 123 Telugu</p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Surya44.jpg" alt="Suriya44" width="300" height="450">
<figcaption>Promotional image for Suriya44</figcaption>
<p>Director Karthik Subbaraj is set to delight Suriya fans with the release of the title teaser for his upcoming movie, Suriya44, on Christmas Day. The film marks a significant project for Suriya, who is coming off a series of less successful outings.</p>
<ul>
<li>The title teaser of Suriya44 will be released on December 25, 2024.</li>
<li>Suriya44 is a love story infused with action elements.</li>
<li>Pooja Hegde stars as the female lead, with Shriya Saran contributing a special song.</li>
<li>The film is anticipated to release on April 10, 2025.</li>
<li>Music for the film is composed by Santosh Narayanan, and it is produced by Suriya's 2D Entertainment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The One’s Xmass Gift 🎁 #Suriya44 #TheOneXmass #LoveLaughterWar” — Karthik Subbaraj</blockquote>
<p>This film gives Suriya fans much to look forward to as Karthik Subbaraj aims to make a significant comeback for the actor.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/karthik-subbaraj-to-give-a-solid-treat-to-suriya-fans-for-christmas.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/karthik-subbaraj-to-give-a-solid-treat-to-suriya-fans-for-christmas.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mastermind Of Kidnapping Gang Targeting Celebs Arrested In UP Encounter - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxPdUJnUXJSR0c4Um5iQTB0TUV5REZNejg5MWYtWnExMzU0Y3hFNndKNzlaMjJ2MGFKSFNWRGEwdXdNNmt3R3ZrQ3IyRGpKOGhWQ0NGYzhVakVZVi1ueEg1YVZEcHhHdWZkVzg4M0xFRjl2Uy1salMwTVNyTVpfY1NBVmVlR0lRMmFrUVVUWWhTMy1GSHFaZ3pWMHIwNnh0OVQtMDlaREVBRmRXWFd5WHYxbGt4VDRmLTRiU0NjZWFLc0w2QVNSSHlBbUV1VnpES2VHbTlBYWEtTkNHUdIB4gFBVV95cUxOUE1IM0pPdUJtalBQTGhENXZRZDRmellDNWttRzNrNVRrU2RXdV9Vc216Z1J3NDU1UGdPVENXajdLa1ZMVkpCVFBLNkYtcU5BYmlNNnE0S09QTVVjXzFxWXF4MHBFOWQycC01TW84UUxuMnJOekwxYmdRZkMzckZ6VUd3MU1SZTNUNWozUmxzV1o3VzY4YWhMR19nNDVPUXlOX0s2N2NYcTJEQjczemptNjlQbjVIbmRYM1ZGdWVLMGU3Wl9tT1duRkhSNnpnTDJ5UXVJaHFfMF8tY0VMT29ybFl3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxPdUJnUXJSR0c4Um5iQTB0TUV5REZNejg5MWYtWnExMzU0Y3hFNndKNzlaMjJ2MGFKSFNWRGEwdXdNNmt3R3ZrQ3IyRGpKOGhWQ0NGYzhVakVZVi1ueEg1YVZEcHhHdWZkVzg4M0xFRjl2Uy1salMwTVNyTVpfY1NBVmVlR0lRMmFrUVVUWWhTMy1GSHFaZ3pWMHIwNnh0OVQtMDlaREVBRmRXWFd5WHYxbGt4VDRmLTRiU0NjZWFLc0w2QVNSSHlBbUV1VnpES2VHbTlBYWEtTkNHUdIB4gFBVV95cUxOUE1IM0pPdUJtalBQTGhENXZRZDRmellDNWttRzNrNVRrU2RXdV9Vc216Z1J3NDU1UGdPVENXajdLa1ZMVkpCVFBLNkYtcU5BYmlNNnE0S09QTVVjXzFxWXF4MHBFOWQycC01TW84UUxuMnJOekwxYmdRZkMzckZ6VUd3MU1SZTNUNWozUmxzV1o3VzY4YWhMR19nNDVPUXlOX0s2N2NYcTJEQjczemptNjlQbjVIbmRYM1ZGdWVLMGU3Wl9tT1duRkhSNnpnTDJ5UXVJaHFfMF8tY0VMT29ybFl3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:27:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shyam Benegal — the boy from Alwal who put Hyderabad on national movie map - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shyam Benegal — the boy from Alwal who put Hyderabad on national movie map</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 23, 2024 at 09:55 pm IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ql6utt/article69020292.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/hykvg-shyam__4_.JPG" alt="Film director Shyam Benegal during his visit to Indywood Film Carnival 2016 in Hyderabad. File photo" /><figcaption>Film director Shyam Benegal during his visit to Indywood Film Carnival 2016 in Hyderabad. Photo Credit: K.V.S. GIRI</figcaption><p>Shyam Benegal, a significant figure in Indian cinema, passed away recently, leaving behind a legacy of films shot in and around Hyderabad, which shaped the national film landscape.</p><ul><li>Benegal was born in Alwal on December 14, 1934, and witnessed India's Freedom Struggle.</li><li>His films often spotlighted social issues, including the Telangana Armed Struggle.</li><li>Notable films include <i>Ankur</i>, <i>Nishant</i>, and <i>Well Done Abba</i>.</li><li>He collaborated with famous playwrights and actors, elevating the status of parallel cinema in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“He always responded to messages and calls, so when there was no response on December 15 for the birthday greetings, I was expecting the worst.”</blockquote><p>Shyam Benegal's contributions to film have had a lasting impact, influencing generations of filmmakers and audiences alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/shyam-benegal-the-boy-from-alwal-who-put-hyderabad-on-national-movie-map/article69020258.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/shyam-benegal-the-boy-from-alwal-who-put-hyderabad-on-national-movie-map/article69020258.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horoscope For Each Zodiac Sign On December 24, 2024 — Jupiter Squares Saturn - YourTango]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Horoscope For Each Zodiac Sign On December 24, 2024 — Jupiter Squares Saturn</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> YourTango</p>
<img src="https://www.yourtango.com/logo.png" alt="YourTango Logo">
<figcaption>YourTango Logo</figcaption>
<p>On December 24, 2024, each zodiac sign's daily horoscope reflects the influence of Jupiter, the harbinger of expansion, as it meets Saturn, the master of refinement.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jupiter in Gemini squares Saturn in Pisces, highlighting the need for meaningful growth through shedding the unnecessary.</li>
<li>Each zodiac sign's daily horoscope prompts individuals to evaluate their growth and whether their current structures support their spiritual mission.</li>
<li>Horoscopes encourage self-reflection and adjustments in personal and professional life.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Meaningful growth demands shedding the unnecessary."</blockquote>
<p>This cosmic alignment prompts a reassessment of various aspects of life as individuals prepare for transitions and growth opportunities heading into the new year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.yourtango.com/2024381476/horoscope-each-zodiac-sign-december-24-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yourtango.com/2024381476/horoscope-each-zodiac-sign-december-24-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:03:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digvijay Rathee to Jasmine Bhasin; Unfair evictions of Bigg Boss - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Digvijay Rathee to Jasmine Bhasin; Unfair evictions of Bigg Boss</h1><p><strong>Updated: Dec 23, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Times of India</strong></p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/imgsize-39098,msid-116606020,width-600,height-335,resizemode-75/116606020.jpg" alt="Digvijay Rathee to Jasmine Bhasin; Unfair evictions of Bigg Boss"><figcaption>Digvijay Rathee to Jasmine Bhasin; Unfair evictions of Bigg Boss</figcaption><p>The article discusses the impact of evictions in the popular reality show Bigg Boss, highlighting various contestants including Digvijay Rathee and Jasmine Bhasin. It raises concerns over the fairness of these evictions and the reactions from fans.</p><ul><li>Digvijay Rathee faced eviction amid controversies regarding the fairness of the decision.</li><li>Fans believe Rathee was a strong contender who deserved to stay longer on the show.</li><li>Other contestants like Umar Riaz and Zeeshan Khan also faced similar calls for their evictions being politically motivated.</li><li>The discussion extends to Jasmine Bhasin and other notable contestants who have made significant impacts during their time on the show.</li></ul><blockquote>"Many believe he was a strong contender who deserved to stay longer, leading to widespread calls for his return to the show."</blockquote><p>The controversies surrounding evictions on Bigg Boss continue to generate significant discussion among fans, suggesting a deeper engagement with the show's politics and contestant dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/digvijay-rathee-to-jasmine-bhasin-unfair-evictions-of-bigg-boss/photostory/116606001.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/digvijay-rathee-to-jasmine-bhasin-unfair-evictions-of-bigg-boss/photostory/116606001.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:38:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marco Box Office Collection Day 4 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTFB0SUhWdkNCY0NpWVBGLU55RXNEdnc4YU1Ja2wtaWpVZ2Q3dFN4dmtwUjNpVUEyeTVUeGg5a251OXZOcVdKUkl4OG1TaTN2Q2dfazJTdDRFak5OaXpsX2hreS1vRl94Y1phYWN0TEExdFBQX2lsSmh6QmZmQ28?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTFB0SUhWdkNCY0NpWVBGLU55RXNEdnc4YU1Ja2wtaWpVZ2Q3dFN4dmtwUjNpVUEyeTVUeGg5a251OXZOcVdKUkl4OG1TaTN2Q2dfazJTdDRFak5OaXpsX2hreS1vRl94Y1phYWN0TEExdFBQX2lsSmh6QmZmQ28?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shyam Benegal, Indias parallel cinema pioneer, dies at 90 - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxPb1ZZSDExQXhsMFd0UGU3ZUFfMm56Z09adXdQZ1hJWEZvU3VlY2dWdUluVGprNGkycDNHaUstS1pKVVNERWZJZHdnRDZxUFZLUmhEVnhEOFNhdFZCYVJTb3YwMWhJc0E5emROeUpvUHhkdHFVbWVKRXBNaV9MR2RZamhIQ080d1NDb243a0l1X1l1OGlHcDVvak85WXg3c19BMGtuY1VVYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxPb1ZZSDExQXhsMFd0UGU3ZUFfMm56Z09adXdQZ1hJWEZvU3VlY2dWdUluVGprNGkycDNHaUstS1pKVVNERWZJZHdnRDZxUFZLUmhEVnhEOFNhdFZCYVJTb3YwMWhJc0E5emROeUpvUHhkdHFVbWVKRXBNaV9MR2RZamhIQ080d1NDb243a0l1X1l1OGlHcDVvak85WXg3c19BMGtuY1VVYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:59:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>