<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Entertainment Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:15:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Entertainment.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:15:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 10: Allu Arjun Creates History Surpassing Stree 2’s 2nd Saturday – 3 Unbelievable Records Destroyed! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 10: Allu Arjun Creates History Surpassing Stree 2’s 2nd Saturday – 3</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-01.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 10: Allu Arjun Creates History Surpassing Stree 2" width="1200" height="630">
    <figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 10: 3 Unbelievable Records Destroyed! (Photo Credit – YouTube)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Allu Arjun has set a new record at the box office with Pushpa 2, becoming the second South Indian film to cross the 500 crore mark, following Baahubali 2.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Pushpa 2 has grossed a total of 507.50 crore after 10 days.</li>
    <li>On its tenth day, the film earned 46.50 crore, marking a 69% increase from the previous day.</li>
    <li>The second weekend collections total 74 crore.</li>
    <li>Highest earnings for Day 10 are recorded at 46 crore, surpassing Stree 2's 33.80 crore on its second Saturday.</li>
    <li>Pushpa 2 is the fastest Hindi film to achieve the 500 crore milestone.</li>
    <li>It is the seventh Hindi film to join the 500 crore club.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Allu Arjun’s biggie has scored <strong>39%</strong> higher earnings than Stree 2 on the second Saturday."</blockquote>
<p>Key statistics show that Pushpa 2 is approaching the 600 crore club, likely achieving this in just a couple of days. The film's impressive performance highlights its popularity and strong box office presence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-10-allu-arjun-creates-history-surpassing-stree-2s-2nd-saturday-3-unbelievable-records-destroyed/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-10-allu-arjun-creates-history-surpassing-stree-2s-2nd-saturday-3-unbelievable-records-destroyed/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:06:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Political slugfest over Allu Arjun continues as Congress defends Pushpa 2 star's arrest - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Political slugfest over Allu Arjun continues as Congress defends Pushpa 2 star's arrest</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/ANI-20241214233-0_1734242864718_1734242891463.jpg" alt="Actor Allu Arjun greets during the press conference on being released from Chanchalguda Central Jail after the Telangana High Court granted him interim bail.(ANI)">
<figcaption>Actor Allu Arjun greets during the press conference on being released from Chanchalguda Central Jail after the Telangana High Court granted him interim bail.(ANI)</figcaption>
<p>The arrest of Telugu actor Allu Arjun has incited a major political debate in Telangana, with various parties reacting differently to the incident tied to a tragic stampede during the premiere of "Pushpa 2: The Rule".</p>
<ul>
    <li>Allu Arjun was arrested in connection with a woman's death due to a stampede at the Sandhya Theatre during the film's premiere.</li>
    <li>Congress defended the arrest, emphasizing that it is lawful and that the party supports adherence to the legal process.</li>
    <li>Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw criticized Congress, claiming they disrespect the creative industry and misplace blame for poor theater arrangements.</li>
    <li>YS Jagan Mohan Reddy, Andhra Pradesh opposition leader, condemned the arrest, suggesting it was unfair to hold Arjun accountable for the stampede.</li>
    <li>Arjun was initially sent to 14-day judicial custody but was later granted interim bail by the Telangana High Court.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "The cases filed against Arjun are within the purview of law and the court granted him bail." - B Mahesh Kumar Goud, Telangana Congress president
</blockquote>
<p>The incident has highlighted tensions between political factions in Telangana, with stark differences in how they view responsibility for the tragedy and their attitudes toward the film industry. As reactions continue to unfold, it remains crucial to balance accountability with fair treatment of individuals involved.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/political-slugfest-over-allu-arjun-continues-as-congress-defends-pushpa-2-actor-arrest-over-sandhya-theatre-stampede-101734242246141.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/political-slugfest-over-allu-arjun-continues-as-congress-defends-pushpa-2-actor-arrest-over-sandhya-theatre-stampede-101734242246141.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:34:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breaking: Allu Arjun to meet Chiranjeevi at his home - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Breaking: Allu Arjun to meet Chiranjeevi at his home</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 15, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source:</strong> 123telugu</p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Chiranjeevi-AlluArjun.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun and Chiranjeevi" width="500" height="333">
<figcaption>Allu Arjun and Chiranjeevi</figcaption>
<p>Allu Arjun is scheduled to meet his uncle Chiranjeevi today at the latter’s home following his recent arrest related to a tragic incident during a movie premiere.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Allu Arjun was arrested after a stampede occurred during the premiere of <strong>Pushpa 2</strong>, which resulted in two fatalities.</li>
    <li>He was granted bail and released from jail just yesterday.</li>
    <li>Several industry figures have visited Allu Arjun since his release.</li>
    <li>The meeting with Chiranjeevi is highly anticipated, as he has not publicly commented on the situation yet.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This meeting is expected to be a major topic of discussion today."</blockquote>
<p>Fans are eagerly awaiting updates from this meeting, particularly to hear Chiranjeevi's perspective on recent events. Stay tuned for more updates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/breaking-allu-arjun-to-meet-chiranjeevi-at-his-home.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/breaking-allu-arjun-to-meet-chiranjeevi-at-his-home.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vikrant Massey reveals PM Narendra Modi had tears in his eyes after watching The Sabarmati Report: 'Woh bhi bhavuk the' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vikrant Massey reveals PM Narendra Modi had tears in his eyes after watching The Sabarmati Report: 'Woh bhi bhavuk the'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Vikrant_Massey_1734240956478_1734240972871.jpg" alt="Vikrant Massey spoke about PM Modi and The Sabarmati Report." title="Vikrant Massey spoke about PM Modi and The Sabarmati Report." />
<figcaption>Vikrant Massey spoke about PM Modi and The Sabarmati Report.</figcaption>
<p>Actor Vikrant Massey shared that Prime Minister Narendra Modi became emotional during the screening of his film, The Sabarmati Report, highlighting a heartfelt moment they shared.</p>
<ul>
    <li>PM Modi expressed that he loved the film and appreciated the efforts behind it.</li>
    <li>Massey noted that both he and PM Modi were equally emotional during the screening.</li>
    <li>Vikrant shared that the PM complimented his acting, which he cherishes.</li>
    <li>The screening was dubbed by Massey as the "highest point" of his career, attended by several notable figures.</li>
    <li>PM Modi praised the film for revealing the truth behind the 2002 Godhra train incident.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "Unko film pasand aya, humara prayas acha laga. Uss film ki screening ke time jitna main bhavuk tha, shayad woh bhi uss time utne hi bhavuk the." 
</blockquote>
<p>The Sabarmati Report is centered on the tragic events surrounding a train fire in Gujarat in 2002 and aims to reveal historical truths.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/vikrant-massey-reveals-pm-narendra-modi-had-tears-in-his-eyes-after-watching-the-sabarmati-report-woh-bhi-bhavuk-the-101734239353932.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/vikrant-massey-reveals-pm-narendra-modi-had-tears-in-his-eyes-after-watching-the-sabarmati-report-woh-bhi-bhavuk-the-101734239353932.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:47:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss Telugu 8 Winner: Not Gautham, Nikhil Emerges Victorious In Nagarjuna's Show? - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss Telugu 8 Winner: Not Gautham, Nikhil Emerges Victorious In Nagarjuna's Show?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> OneIndia</p>
<img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2024/12/bigg-boss-telugu-winner-03-1734238679.jpg" alt="Bigg Boss Telugu 8 Winner Not Gautham Nikhil Lifts The Trophy" width="600" height="338">
<figcaption>Bigg Boss Telugu 8 Winner Not Gautham Nikhil Lifts The Trophy</figcaption>
<p>The curtains for Bigg Boss Telugu 8 are about to drop, with rumors suggesting Nikhil has won the grand finale, despite Gautham being a strong contender.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The grand finale of Bigg Boss Telugu 8 is set for Sunday, featuring finalists Gautham, Nikhil, Nabeel, Prerana, and Avinash.</li>
    <li>According to the Bigg Boss Telugu 8 Wikipedia page, Nikhil is expected to win, with Gautham finishing as runner-up.</li>
    <li>Online voting results show Gautham leading with 318,791 votes (45%), while Nikhil trails with 212,617 votes (30%).</li>
    <li>Nabeel secured third place with 101,932 votes (14%), followed by Prerana with 49,067 votes (7%), and Avinash with 25,113 votes (4%).</li>
    <li>The anticipation for the winner has sparked mixed reactions among fans, especially considering Gautham's popularity.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"If Nikhil indeed takes the title, it will be an unexpected twist in the season's climax."</blockquote>
<p>With the finale just hours away, fans are eager for the official announcement that will confirm the winner of Bigg Boss Telugu 8.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/entertainment/bigg-boss-telugu-8-winner-not-gautham-nikhil-emerges-victorious-in-nagarjunas-show-4016115.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/entertainment/bigg-boss-telugu-8-winner-not-gautham-nikhil-emerges-victorious-in-nagarjunas-show-4016115.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:03:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 box office collection day 10: Allu Arjun’s film sees massive jump, mints Rs 824.5 crore - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Collection Day 10: Allu Arjun’s Film Sees Massive Jump, Mints Rs 824.5 Crore</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Pushpa-3.jpg?w=640" alt="Pushpa 2 box office collection day 10" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Pushpa 2 box office collection day 10: Allu Arjun's film sees massive jump. (Photo: Pushpa/X)</figcaption>

<p>Pushpa 2 has been dominating the box office, achieving significant revenue in its first ten days. The film saw a remarkable increase in collections, largely influenced by recent events surrounding its lead actor.</p>

<ul>
    <li>The film recorded a 71% increase in collections on day 10, earning Rs 62.3 crore.</li>
    <li>Domestic box office collection stands at Rs 824.5 crore.</li>
    <li>The Hindi version has been a major contributor with Rs 498.1 crore.</li>
    <li>Globally, the film has grossed Rs 1,190 crore, becoming the highest-grossing film of 2024.</li>
    <li>Promotional strategies included events in major Indian cities and releasing trailers in various locations.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>“We’re extremely sorry for the family, and I will personally be there to support them in whatever way. It’s purely accidental.” - Allu Arjun</blockquote>

<p>Despite its success, the film's release was marred by a tragic incident that claimed a life, leading to Allu Arjun's temporary arrest.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-10-allu-arjuns-film-sees-massive-jump-mints-rs-824-5-crore-9725593/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-10-allu-arjuns-film-sees-massive-jump-mints-rs-824-5-crore-9725593/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:48:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun’s Pushpa 2 becomes the third biggest hit of Indian Cinema, displacing Ram Charan and NTR Jr's - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/allu-arjuns-pushpa-2-becomes-the-third-biggest-hit-of-indian-cinema-displacing-ram-charan-and-ntr-jrs-rrr/articleshow/116331564.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/allu-arjuns-pushpa-2-becomes-the-third-biggest-hit-of-indian-cinema-displacing-ram-charan-and-ntr-jrs-rrr/articleshow/116331564.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Internet angry at Allu Arjun's 'celebration' after prison release as boy injured in Pushpa 2 stampede remains critical - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Internet angry at Allu Arjun's 'celebration' after prison release as boy injured in Pushpa 2 stampede remains critical</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 09:44 AM IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Allu_Arjun_1734235230505_1734235230770.jpg" alt="Vijay Deverakonda met actor Allu Arjun after the latter was released from a Hyderabad jail on Saturday." title="Vijay Deverakonda met actor Allu Arjun after the latter was released from a Hyderabad jail on Saturday.">
    <figcaption>Vijay Deverakonda met actor Allu Arjun after the latter was released from a Hyderabad jail on Saturday.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Allu Arjun's celebratory return home from prison following a high-profile arrest has sparked outrage online, particularly as a young victim from the associated stampede remains in critical condition.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Allu Arjun was arrested concerning a fan's death during the premiere of his film <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/justice-done-allu-arjun-fans-celebrate-after-actor-is-granted-interim-bail-in-pushpa-2-stampede-case-101734093105639.html">Pushpa 2: The Rule</a>.</li>
    <li>After his release, he was celebrated at home with significant industry support, which many deemed inappropriate given the ongoing tragedy.</li>
    <li>Many social media users criticized the celebrations, calling it a PR stunt and questioning the lack of support for the deceased's family by Arjun.</li>
    <li>The incident occurred during a large crowd gathering at Sandhya Theatre, leading to a stampede that resulted in significant casualties.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "Today's non-stop celebrity visits and the publicity around it has tilted the scales in favour of Revanth Reddy... It should have been a day of introspection, not celebration."
</blockquote>
<p>The critic response reflects a broader sentiment that celebrity culture can overshadow genuine human tragedy, urging a consideration of the consequences of such public displays amidst personal loss.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/internet-angry-at-allu-arjuns-celebration-after-prison-release-as-boy-injured-in-pushpa-2-stampede-remains-critical-101734234928326.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/internet-angry-at-allu-arjuns-celebration-after-prison-release-as-boy-injured-in-pushpa-2-stampede-remains-critical-101734234928326.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:14:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE| Saif Ali Khan on meeting PM Modi with Kapoor family: Asked how much rest he got, he said three hours a night - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>EXCLUSIVE| Saif Ali Khan on meeting PM Modi with Kapoor family: Asked how much rest he got, he said three hours a night.</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/SAIFKAREENAMODI_1734205562222_1734205594307.jpg" alt="Saif Ali Khan poses with PM Narendra Modi at the recent meeting in Delhi." title="Saif Ali Khan poses with PM Narendra Modi at the recent meeting in Delhi.">
<figcaption>Saif Ali Khan poses with PM Narendra Modi at the recent meeting in Delhi.</figcaption>
<p>Actor Saif Ali Khan recently met Prime Minister Narendra Modi in Delhi along with the Kapoor family. The meeting was held in memory of the late Raj Kapoor, and Khan shared insights about the engaging encounter.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Saif Ali Khan attended the meeting with the Kapoor family in memory of Raj Kapoor.</li>
    <li>He described PM Modi as attentive and charming despite a long day in Parliament.</li>
    <li>The meeting was attended by Kareena Kapoor, Karisma Kapoor, Ranbir Kapoor, Alia Bhatt, and others.</li>
    <li>PM Modi inquired about Saif's parents and signed a paper for Saif's children, Taimur and Jehangir.</li>
    <li>Saif noted that PM Modi mentioned he gets about three hours of sleep a night.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I asked him how much rest he got and he said about three hours a night. It was a special day for me.” - Saif Ali Khan</blockquote>
<p>This meeting not only commemorated Raj Kapoor's legacy but also highlighted the personal connection and respect between the Kapoor family and the Prime Minister. Saif expressed gratitude for the time spent with Modi, emphasizing the importance of family and legacy.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/exclusive-saif-ali-khan-on-meeting-pm-modi-with-kapoor-family-asked-how-much-rest-he-got-he-said-three-hours-a-night-101734204335107.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/exclusive-saif-ali-khan-on-meeting-pm-modi-with-kapoor-family-asked-how-much-rest-he-got-he-said-three-hours-a-night-101734204335107.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:06:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE Saturday Night’s Main Event Results – 12/14/24 (Cody Rhodes vs. Kevin Owens for the Undisputed WWE Championship) - Wrestleview.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wrestleview.com/wwe-wrestling-results/wwe-snme-results/336101-wwe-snme-results-december-14-2024-long-island/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wrestleview.com/wwe-wrestling-results/wwe-snme-results/336101-wwe-snme-results-december-14-2024-long-island/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 03:27:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 10: Allu Arjun's movie mints a massive ₹1190 crore gross | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-10-allu-arjuns-movie-mints-a-massive-rs-1190-crore-gross-11734224771037.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-10-allu-arjuns-movie-mints-a-massive-rs-1190-crore-gross-11734224771037.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 01:42:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun was normal in jail, had rice and vegetable curry in dinner: Official - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun was normal in jail, had rice and vegetable curry in dinner: Official</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Allu_Arjun_1734159671454_1734223389722.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun arrives to speak with the media at his residence after he was released from the jail, in Hyderabad, Saturday. (PTI Photo)" title="Allu Arjun arrives to speak with the media at his residence after he was released from the jail, in Hyderabad, Saturday. (PTI Photo)">
<figcaption>Allu Arjun arrives to speak with the media at his residence after he was released from the jail, in Hyderabad, Saturday. (PTI Photo)</figcaption>
<p>Actor Allu Arjun, who was jailed following an incident at a film premiere, spent a normal night in prison and had rice and vegetable curry for dinner, according to an official from Telangana's prisons department.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Allu Arjun spent a night in Chanchalguda Central Prison after being arrested in the 'Pushpa 2' stampede case.</li>
    <li>The actor was granted a four-week interim bail on the day of his arrest but was not released until the following morning.</li>
    <li>During his time in jail, he did not request any special privileges and was treated as a special prisoner as per court order.</li>
    <li>The delay in his release was due to procedural issues, as inmates are not typically released after 7 PM.</li>
    <li>The incident at the movie premiere resulted in the death of a woman, leading to charges against Arjun and his security team.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“He was quite normal and did not appear depressed. Normally, the dinner time is 5:30 pm. However, late admissions are also served food. He had rice and vegetable curry.”</blockquote>
<p>The situation highlights the challenges faced during high-profile releases and the implications of crowd management at events.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/allu-arjun-was-normal-in-jail-had-rice-and-vegetable-curry-in-dinner-official-101734223378332.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/allu-arjun-was-normal-in-jail-had-rice-and-vegetable-curry-in-dinner-official-101734223378332.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 01:39:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Vivian Dsena’s wife Nouran Aly poses tough questions to him, says ‘It boils my blood…’ - Bollywood Life]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bigg Boss 18: Vivian Dsena&rsquo;s wife Nouran Aly poses tough questions to him, says &lsquo;It boils my blood&rsquo;</h1>
<p><strong>Published: December 15, 2024 7:01 AM IST | Source: BollywoodLife</strong></p>

<p>The drama in Bigg Boss 18 intensifies as Vivian Dsena faces tough questions from his wife, Nouran Aly, challenging his gameplay and emotional state.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Weekend Ka Vaar episodes with Salman Khan bring significant changes and evaluations for contestants.</li>
    <li>Nouran Aly enters the show, questioning Vivian's feelings and performance, revealing he promised to win the trophy.</li>
    <li>She expresses frustration over his friendship with fellow contestant Karan Veer Mehra, who has stated he is not a friend.</li>
    <li>The conversation appears to impact Vivian, leading to a potential reconsideration of his strategy in the game.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
    <p>It's so emotional yrrr ?? And Nouran ma'am is giving all the feedback that Vivian needed ???</p>
    <footer>— ??????? (@devil_nahyan) <a href="https://twitter.com/devil_nahyan/status/1867987886395596865?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 14, 2024</a></footer>
</blockquote>

<p>With Salman Khan pointing out Vivian's lack of heroism on-screen, viewers are left curious about the potential changes in Vivian's behavior moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodlife.com/bigg-boss/bigg-boss-18-vivian-dsena-wife-nouran-aly-asks-tough-questions-to-him-about-karan-veer-mehra-3038528/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodlife.com/bigg-boss/bigg-boss-18-vivian-dsena-wife-nouran-aly-asks-tough-questions-to-him-about-karan-veer-mehra-3038528/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 01:31:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bigg Boss 18: Vivian Dsena’s wife Nouran questions him over his bond with Karan Veer Mehra; says, “You ha - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-vivian-dsenas-wife-nouran-questions-him-over-his-bond-with-karan-veer-mehra-says-you-having-a-soft-corner-for-him-boils-my-blood/articleshow/116325268.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/bigg-boss-18-vivian-dsenas-wife-nouran-questions-him-over-his-bond-with-karan-veer-mehra-says-you-having-a-soft-corner-for-him-boils-my-blood/articleshow/116325268.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' box office collection day 10: The film sees huge growth of 71 percent on Saturday, post Allu A - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Pushpa 2' box office collection day 10: The film sees huge growth of 71 percent on Saturday, post Allu Arjun's arrest; crosses Rs 820 crore</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116329329,imgsize-41224,width-400,resizemode-4/116329329.jpg" alt="'Pushpa 2' box office collection day 10" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Allu Arjun in 'Pushpa 2'</figcaption>
<p>Allu Arjun's 'Pushpa 2' has been breaking box office records, achieving a remarkable 71 percent growth in collections on its tenth day, despite the recent arrest of its star.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The film grossed Rs 62.3 crore on its second Saturday.</li>
    <li>Of the total, Rs 46 crore came from the Hindi version and Rs 13 crore from the Telugu version.</li>
    <li>The total box office collection now stands at Rs 824 crore in India across all languages.</li>
    <li>The Hindi version of the film has so far collected Rs 498 crore, surpassing its Telugu counterpart.</li>
    <li>The film has outperformed previous hits like 'Jawan' and 'RRR' in terms of total collection.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "This kind of growth is just unprecedented."
</blockquote>
<p>The success of 'Pushpa 2' continues to defy expectations, with further growth anticipated as the film remains in the spotlight following its controversies and increasing ticket sales.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-10-the-film-sees-huge-growth-of-71-percent-on-saturday-post-allu-arjuns-arrest-crosses-rs-820-crore/articleshow/116329338.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-10-the-film-sees-huge-growth-of-71-percent-on-saturday-post-allu-arjuns-arrest-crosses-rs-820-crore/articleshow/116329338.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shashi Kapoor, Shammi Kapoor Loved Raj Kapoor 'Like A Father Figure': 'He Was A Complete Family Man' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shashi Kapoor, Shammi Kapoor Loved Raj Kapoor 'Like A Father Figure': 'He Was A Complete Family Man'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The legendary Kapoor brothers." />
    <figcaption>The legendary Kapoor brothers.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As the Kapoor family honors Raj Kapoor’s legacy on his 100th birth anniversary, Aditya Raj Kapoor shares insights about the deep familial bond they shared.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Aditya Raj Kapoor is the son of Shammi Kapoor, Raj Kapoor’s brother.</li>
    <li>Raj Kapoor was described as a complete family man who prioritized family gatherings.</li>
    <li>Shashi and Shammi Kapoor regarded Raj Kapoor as a father figure.</li>
    <li>Aditya praised Raj Kapoor's storytelling ability and his unique approach to filmmaking.</li>
    <li>The Raj Kapoor Film Festival is currently showcasing his most celebrated films in Mumbai.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Raj Saab started with a thought... he believed in his thoughts and the guts of his determination.” - Aditya Raj Kapoor</blockquote>
<p>The Kapoor family continues to celebrate and remember Raj Kapoor’s profound impact on cinema as they showcase his iconic films during the festival.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/shashi-kapoor-shammi-kapoor-loved-raj-kapoor-like-a-father-figure-he-was-a-complete-family-man-9156177.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/shashi-kapoor-shammi-kapoor-loved-raj-kapoor-like-a-father-figure-he-was-a-complete-family-man-9156177.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 23:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dilip Kumar Stood Beside Raj Kapoor, Asked Him To 'Wake Up' After He Suffered Cardiac Arrest: 'Acting Mat K - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dilip Kumar Stood Beside Raj Kapoor, Asked Him To 'Wake Up' After He Suffered Cardiac Arrest: 'Acting Mat Kar'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024, 21:02 IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Dilip Kumar was by Raj Kapoor's side when he breathed his last." title="Dilip Kumar was by Raj Kapoor's side when he breathed his last.">
    <figcaption>Dilip Kumar was by Raj Kapoor's side when he breathed his last.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Veteran actress Saira Banu commemorated Raj Kapoor on his centenary, sharing touching memories of his friendship with Dilip Kumar, especially during challenging times.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Saira Banu shared a video on Instagram recalling the bond between Raj Kapoor and Dilip Kumar.</li>
    <li>The video included light-hearted moments of the two actors, such as playing cricket and joking around.</li>
    <li>Banu emphasized that despite perceptions of rivalry, they were childhood friends from Peshawar.</li>
    <li>She recounted a poignant moment when Dilip Kumar rushed to Raj Kapoor's side after his cardiac arrest, expressing deep emotions.</li>
    <li>Dilip Kumar whispered to Raj Kapoor, urging him to wake up and reminiscing about their joyous times together.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “Raj, wake up! I’ve brought the ‘khushboo’ of Chapli Kebabs. Let’s walk through the bazaar, like we used to eating kebabs, laughing, and reminiscing. Bas ab acting mat kar; take me back to Peshawar.” – Dilip Kumar
</blockquote>
<p>This heartfelt tribute from Saira Banu highlights the enduring friendship and affection between two legends of Indian cinema, reminding fans of the depth of human connections beyond fame.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/dilip-kumar-stood-beside-raj-kapoor-asked-him-to-wake-up-after-he-suffered-cardiac-arrest-acting-mat-kar-9156203.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/dilip-kumar-stood-beside-raj-kapoor-asked-him-to-wake-up-after-he-suffered-cardiac-arrest-acting-mat-kar-9156203.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 23:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Pisces, December 15 to 21, 2024 advices avoiding these expenses - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Pisces, December 15 to 21, 2024 advises avoiding these expenses</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Pisces_1728478870554_1734199927065.jpg" alt="Pisces Weekly Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024" title="Pisces Weekly Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024">
<figcaption>Pisces Weekly Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, Pisces will learn new things about their emotions and how it will help them grow personally and romantically.</figcaption>
<p>This week's horoscope for Pisces emphasizes emotional clarity, career opportunities, and the importance of financial prudence while focusing on personal growth.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Pisces will experience emotional growth and new love connections while prioritizing health.</li>
    <li>Career opportunities may arise that require quick decision-making and proactive networking.</li>
    <li>Financial caution is advised; avoid impulsive spending and consider future financial goals.</li>
    <li>Balanced mental and physical health is essential, highlighting exercise and diet.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Take a look at your budget and make sure you are spending in line with your long-term goals." - Dr. J. N. Pandey</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this week encourages Pisces to navigate their emotional landscape with wisdom while remaining vigilant in career and financial matters for a balanced and fulfilling life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-pisces-december-15-to-21-2024-advices-avoiding-these-expenses-101734199812404.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-pisces-december-15-to-21-2024-advices-avoiding-these-expenses-101734199812404.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:41:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Aquarius, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts personal growth - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Aquarius, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts personal growth</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Aquarius_1728478944944_1734200858261.jpg" alt="Aquarius Daily Horoscope" title="Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, Aquarius, the fresh start is here with opportunities for growth and development.">
<figcaption>Aquarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, Aquarius, the fresh start is here with opportunities for growth and development.</figcaption>
<p>This week, Aquarians can expect new opportunities, introspection, and personal growth. It's a time to be open-minded and adaptable to change.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Embrace new opportunities and be flexible in challenges.</li>
    <li>Strengthen emotional connections in love, be open to honest conversations.</li>
    <li>Innovative ideas will be valued in the workplace; don't hesitate to share.</li>
    <li>Financially, focus on long-term goals and avoid impulsive spending.</li>
    <li>Maintain a balanced health routine and prioritize mental well-being.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Be open minded and flexible to tackle challenges, and build connections for personal and professional success."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this week presents a promising opportunity for Aquarians to grow both personally and professionally, emphasizing the importance of connections and balanced health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-aquarius-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-personal-growth-101734200625586.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-aquarius-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-personal-growth-101734200625586.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:40:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Capricorn, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts a positive shift - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Capricorn, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts a positive shift</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Capricorn_1728478974232_1734201631763.jpg" alt="Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, Capricorns will experience personal growth, relationship enhancement, and professional breakthroughs while keeping their finances stable and taking care of their overall well-being." title="Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, Capricorns will experience personal growth, relationship enhancement, and professional breakthroughs while keeping their finances stable and taking care of their overall well-being.">
<figcaption>Capricorn Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, Capricorns will experience personal growth, relationship enhancement, and professional breakthroughs while keeping their finances stable and taking care of their overall well-being.</figcaption>
<p>This week, Capricorns will experience personal growth, positive shifts in relationships, and professional breakthroughs while maintaining financial stability and focusing on overall well-being.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Capricorns can expect a positive shift with personal and professional growth.</li>
    <li>Relationships will strengthen; communication is key for those in partnerships.</li>
    <li>Career opportunities may arise; being proactive may lead to promotions.</li>
    <li>Financial stability is likely, but cautious spending is advised.</li>
    <li>Health should be prioritized through exercise, diet, and stress management.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This week is all about love and relationships. If you’re single, you might meet someone who matches your values.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this week offers Capricorns opportunities for growth across personal, professional, and financial aspects, encouraging mindfulness and proactive behavior.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-capricorn-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-a-positive-shift-101734201392891.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-capricorn-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-a-positive-shift-101734201392891.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:39:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Sagittarius, Dec 15 to 21, 2024 predicts luck this full moon - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Sagittarius, Dec 15 to 21, 2024 predicts luck this full moon</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 04:08 AM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Sagittarius_1728479012112_1734202957555.jpg" alt="Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, a wave of potential in various areas of your life comes your way" title="Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, a wave of potential in various areas of your life comes your way">
<figcaption>Sagittarius Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, a wave of potential in various areas of your life comes your way</figcaption>
<p>This week, Sagittarius is poised to experience significant opportunities in love, career, and finances, while also emphasizing personal well-being.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Sagittarius will experience open communication in love, strengthening connections.</li>
    <li>Sudden unexpected professional opportunities may arise; seizing them is crucial.</li>
    <li>This week is beneficial for financial evaluations and thoughtful decision-making.</li>
    <li>Health should be prioritized with a balanced routine incorporating exercise and healthy meals.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>"Meaningful conversations and shared experiences will blossom your love life. This is a great time to be vulnerable and build trust with your partner or a potential love interest."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the week offers a wave of potential across various life aspects, encouraging Sagittarius to embrace changes and foster deeper connections.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-sagittarius-dec-15-to-21-2024-predicts-luck-this-full-moon-101734202396008.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-sagittarius-dec-15-to-21-2024-predicts-luck-this-full-moon-101734202396008.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:38:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Scorpio, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts prosperity on this day - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Scorpio, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts prosperity on this day</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/scorpio_1728479075489_1734204273202.jpg" alt="Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: You will experience a combination of personal and professional growth." title="Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: You will experience a combination of personal and professional growth.">
<figcaption>Scorpio Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: You will experience a combination of personal and professional growth.</figcaption>
<p>This week, Scorpios can expect transformative opportunities and personal insights that encourage growth and a fulfilling journey ahead.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Scorpios will experience personal and professional growth, with new opportunities to explore.</li>
    <li>In love, focus on deepening bonds through open communication and vulnerability.</li>
    <li>Career opportunities may arise; be flexible and trust your intuition.</li>
    <li>Financial caution is advised; save rather than spend and evaluate investment opportunities thoroughly.</li>
    <li>Health-wise, maintain a balanced lifestyle with regular exercise and mindfulness practices.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Change and growth are on the horizon for Scorpios this week.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, Scorpios have a week filled with potential for prosperity and transformation, urging them to embrace new opportunities and maintain balance in all areas of life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-scorpio-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-prosperity-on-this-day-101734204031985.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-scorpio-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-prosperity-on-this-day-101734204031985.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:37:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Libra, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts luck with the end of retrograde - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Libra, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts luck with the end of retrograde</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Libra_1728479045617_1734203575785.jpg" alt="Libra Weekly Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: For the week, focus on balance in love, career, finances, and health for optimal harmony and personal growth." title="Libra Weekly Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: For the week, focus on balance in love, career, finances, and health for optimal harmony and personal growth.">
<figcaption>Libra Weekly Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: For the week, focus on balance in love, career, finances, and health for optimal harmony and personal growth.</figcaption>
<p>This week's horoscope for Libras encourages finding balance in all areas of life, including love, career, finances, and health, promising opportunities and positive outcomes.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Focus on achieving balance in personal and professional aspects for growth.</li>
    <li>Opportunities in career will arise; collaboration and organization are key.</li>
    <li>Financial planning is crucial; avoid unnecessary risks and seek expert advice.</li>
    <li>Prioritize health with routines that include rest, exercise, and mindfulness.</li>
    <li>Importance of communication in relationships is emphasized for deeper connections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Maintain balance will always lead to positive outcomes."</blockquote>
<p>The horoscope outlines an encouraging week for Libras, highlighting the significance of balance and planning to ensure success in multiple facets of life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-libra-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-luck-with-the-end-of-retrograde-101734203457256.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-libra-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-luck-with-the-end-of-retrograde-101734203457256.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:36:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Virgo, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts promotion on the cards - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Virgo, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts promotion on the cards</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Virgo_1728479056525_1734203276153.jpg" alt="Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: this week should be about clear communication and thoughtful planning." title="Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: this week should be about clear communication and thoughtful planning.">
<figcaption>Virgo Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: this week should be about clear communication and thoughtful planning.</figcaption>
<p>This week's horoscope for Virgos highlights opportunities in love and career, emphasizing the importance of clear communication and careful planning.</p>
<ul>
    <li>This week encourages Virgos to remain grounded and open to new possibilities in both personal and professional areas.</li>
    <li>In love, Virgos can expect harmonious relationships and potential new connections, stressing the importance of communication.</li>
    <li>Career-wise, new opportunities may arise, including the potential for promotions, and careful decision-making is advised.</li>
    <li>Financially, prudent management and careful budgeting are crucial, with opportunities for earnings urging thoughtful consideration.</li>
    <li>Health-wise, Virgos are advised to focus on balance and moderation, paying attention to both physical and mental well-being.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Approach these possibilities with diligence and clear focus, whether it’s a potential promotion or a chance to lead a new project."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Virgos are encouraged to embrace this week with an open mind, prioritizing clear communication and strategic planning to make the most of the opportunities that arise.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-virgo-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-promotion-on-the-cards-101734203052733.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-virgo-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-promotion-on-the-cards-101734203052733.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:35:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Cancer, Dec 15 to 21, 2024 predicts a week of transformation - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Cancer, Dec 15 to 21, 2024 predicts a week of transformation</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Cancer_1728477955472_1734201897699.jpg" alt="Cancer Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, a wave of transformation welcomes you." title="Cancer Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, a wave of transformation welcomes you.">
<figcaption>Cancer Daily Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, a wave of transformation welcomes you.</figcaption>
<p>This week for Cancer is marked by positive change and growth. It's an opportunity to balance personal, professional, and emotional aspects of your life while embracing new beginnings.</p>
<ul>
  <li>This week introduces transformative opportunities in personal and professional life.</li>
  <li>Clear communication is essential in relationships, especially for those in love.</li>
  <li>Expect changes in your career that may lead to advancement and new ideas.</li>
  <li>Financially, this week suggests cautious optimism and careful spending habits.</li>
  <li>Emphasizing health through balance in work and relaxation is crucial for mental and physical well-being.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Stay open minded, and you will be able to use the potential of the upcoming changes effectively."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, focus on transformation this week will foster growth in various aspects of a Cancer's life, from romance to finances, encouraging a well-rounded approach for a fulfilling week ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-cancer-dec-15-to-21-2024-predicts-a-week-of-transformation-101734201730400.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-cancer-dec-15-to-21-2024-predicts-a-week-of-transformation-101734201730400.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:33:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Horoscope Taurus, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts positive developments - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekly Horoscope Taurus, December 15 to 21, 2024 predicts positive developments</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Taurus_1728477354135_1734200473779.jpg" alt="Taurus Weekly Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, Taurus natives can expect positive developments across various aspects of life." title="Taurus Weekly Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, Taurus natives can expect positive developments across various aspects of life." />
<figcaption>Taurus Weekly Horoscope Today, December 15 to 21, 2024: This week, Taurus natives can expect positive developments across various aspects of life.</figcaption>
<p>This week's horoscope for Taurus highlights significant positive changes in love, career, and finances, encouraging Taurus individuals to remain open to new opportunities.</p>
<ul>
    <li>This week promises positive energies for Taurus across various life aspects.</li>
    <li>Opportunities for growth in love, career, and finances are highlighted.</li>
    <li>Single Taurus individuals may encounter new romantic interests.</li>
    <li>Professional encounters may lead to new projects and roles.</li>
    <li>Financially, a careful approach to budgeting and informed spending is advised.</li>
    <li>Health recommendations emphasize balancing physical activity with relaxation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Stay open to new opportunities and keep an optimistic outlook." - Dr. J.N. Pandey</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the week is set to be productive and promising for Taurus natives, urging them to embrace changes and maintain a positive mindset.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-taurus-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-positive-developments-101734200215555.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/weekly-horoscope-taurus-december-15-to-21-2024-predicts-positive-developments-101734200215555.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:31:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ram Charan’s performance as Appanna in Game Changer will shock everyone – Srikanth - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ram Charan’s performance as Appanna in Game Changer will shock everyone – Srikanth</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 15, 2024, 2:59 am IST</p>
<img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Game-Changer-1.jpg" alt="Game Changer Movie" width="550" height="367">
<figcaption>Ram Charan in Game Changer</figcaption>
<p>Ram Charan's upcoming dual role in the political drama Game Changer, directed by Shankar, is generating significant buzz, particularly regarding his performance as Appanna, which is expected to surprise audiences.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Ram Charan plays dual roles: a father (farmer Konidela Appanna) and son (IAS officer Konidela Ram Nandan).</li>
    <li>The film is set for release on January 10, 2025, during the Sankranthi festival.</li>
    <li>Srikanth, a senior character actor in the film, claims Charan's performance will shock viewers.</li>
    <li>Kiara Advani, SJ Suryah, Anjali, and others are part of the cast alongside Ram Charan.</li>
    <li>The music for the film is composed by Thaman, produced by Dil Raju.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Charan’s characters in Game Changer will look quite different and refreshing.” – Srikanth</blockquote>
<p>The anticipation for Game Changer builds as Ram Charan takes on these diverse roles, and fans are eager to see his unique portrayal of Appanna.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/ram-charans-performance-as-appanna-in-game-changer-will-shock-everyone-srikanth.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/ram-charans-performance-as-appanna-in-game-changer-will-shock-everyone-srikanth.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 21:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 10 (Early Trends): Enters 500 Crore Club Defying All Norms With A Massive 70% Jump! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 10 (Early Trends): Enters 500 Crore Club Defying All Norms With A Massive 70% Jump</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p>
<img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-10-early-trends-01.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 10 (Early Trends): Enters 500 Crore Club Defying All Norms" width="1200" height="630">
<figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Beasts On The 2nd Saturday ( Photo Credit – Instagram )</figcaption>
<p>Pushpa 2 has achieved remarkable box office success, entering the 500 crore club in just 10 days, demonstrating a significant increase in earnings.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The film’s total earnings after 10 days are estimated at <strong>509 crore</strong>.</li>
    <li>On Day 10, it earned an estimated <strong>46 to 48 crore</strong>, marking a 70% increase from the previous day's earnings of <strong>27 crore</strong>.</li>
    <li>The film had an impressive opening with <strong>72 crore</strong> and achieved a total of <strong>291 crore</strong> over an extended 4-day weekend.</li>
    <li>In its first week, the box office collection reached <strong>434.50 crore</strong>.</li>
    <li>Pushpa 2 is now the sixth highest-grossing Hindi film, surpassing KGF: Chapter 2.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>"It was expected that the film would enter the 500 crore club on Sunday, but it defied all expectations..."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Pushpa 2's box office performance defies expectations and has set new benchmarks in the Hindi film industry, showcasing its widespread popularity and commercial success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-10-early-trends-enters-500-crore-club-defying-all-norms-with-a-massive-70-jump/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-10-early-trends-enters-500-crore-club-defying-all-norms-with-a-massive-70-jump/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:13:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samanta Calls Naga Chaitanya, Sobhita Dhulipala ‘Most Dignified Couple’; Drops UNSEEN Pics From Their Weddi - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samanta Calls Naga Chaitanya, Sobhita Dhulipala ‘Most Dignified Couple’; Drops UNSEEN Pics From Their Wedding</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024, 19:01 IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Samanta says Sobhita Dhulipala and Naga Chaitanya's wedding was an emotional moment for her." />
    <figcaption>Samanta says Sobhita Dhulipala and Naga Chaitanya's wedding was an emotional moment for her.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Sobhita Dhulipala and Naga Chaitanya recently tied the knot in a traditional ceremony, and Samanta Dhulipala has shared unseen photos from their wedding, expressing her emotions and admiration for the couple.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The wedding took place on December 4 at Annapurna Studios in Hyderabad.</li>
    <li>Samanta shared heartfelt messages alongside newly released images from the wedding celebration.</li>
    <li>She described the wedding as an emotional moment, praising her sister and Naga Chaitanya as the most dignified couple she knows.</li>
    <li>The photos include Sobhita looking stunning in traditional attire and enjoying pre-wedding festivities.</li>
    <li>The couple made their first public outing after marriage at Srisailam Temple.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “This was such an emotional moment for me.. love you so much Akka Only I know how you love and how much you do for the people in your life. To the most dignified couple I know Akka and Chay." - Samanta Dhulipala
</blockquote>
<p>The wedding of Sobhita Dhulipala and Naga Chaitanya has not only brought joy to their families but has also captured the hearts of fans, who are eagerly sharing and celebrating the couple's special moments.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/samanta-calls-naga-chaitanya-sobhita-dhulipala-most-dignified-couple-drops-unseen-pics-from-their-wedding-9156089.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/samanta-calls-naga-chaitanya-sobhita-dhulipala-most-dignified-couple-drops-unseen-pics-from-their-wedding-9156089.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:08:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohan Babu Says Anticipatory Bail NOT Rejected In Journalist Assault Case: 'False Propaganda' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohan Babu Says Anticipatory Bail NOT Rejected In Journalist Assault Case: 'False Propaganda'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Mohan Babu sets record straight on his bail." title="Mohan Babu sets record straight on his bail." />
<figcaption>Mohan Babu sets record straight on his bail.</figcaption>
<p>Veteran actor Mohan Babu has clarified that his anticipatory bail petition has not been rejected, countering false reports circulating in media.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Mohan Babu clarified via social media that his anticipatory bail has not been rejected.</li>
    <li>He stated he is currently under medical care and requested accurate reporting from the media.</li>
    <li>The statement follows reports claiming a rejection by the Telangana High Court regarding his bail plea related to an attack on a journalist.</li>
    <li>Mohan Babu apologized for the incident, which he described as “unfortunate,” asserting he acted in self-defense against anti-social elements.</li>
    <li>He expressed regret for the injury sustained by the journalist in the incident he described.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “False propaganda is being circulated! Anticipatory bail has NOT been rejected and currently, I am under medical care in my home. I request the media to get the facts right."
</blockquote>
<p>The actor's statement aims to clear misconceptions regarding his legal situation, emphasizing the need for factual reporting amid ongoing legal challenges.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/mohan-babu-says-anticipatory-bail-not-rejected-in-journalist-assault-case-false-propaganda-9156060.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/mohan-babu-says-anticipatory-bail-not-rejected-in-journalist-assault-case-false-propaganda-9156060.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:07:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>