<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:19:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:19:20 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study of matrix modifications by nano-clay on the mechanical properties of AA3003 honeycomb sandwich panels - Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxNdnFncnZyTUdPa195QVRlWUJ2QXRGdjBmSTRZeTFGVHA0WGFjbmlWSHVfaU9mMUg3R3VTenNYdEtLYUJoYlpsbVNFbHJPRDRDQ05DSXpwYkZqSlI1X1dLUFJuN2R4UUhNTHZVbGJfRE0yYmRyVnhmSTJYYzE4dy13bjlJdVNzS2djVHh1VmtfdFlXeG9IUVZxdDJYWnNxYXhjTm9MNXFQQjlDNVNrU1poRnlTUnpwamhqM0Iza1FkTTBfNWtCV0FyUUxNS1gyUHJSRkFpY0dHQnVBNGs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxNdnFncnZyTUdPa195QVRlWUJ2QXRGdjBmSTRZeTFGVHA0WGFjbmlWSHVfaU9mMUg3R3VTenNYdEtLYUJoYlpsbVNFbHJPRDRDQ05DSXpwYkZqSlI1X1dLUFJuN2R4UUhNTHZVbGJfRE0yYmRyVnhmSTJYYzE4dy13bjlJdVNzS2djVHh1VmtfdFlXeG9IUVZxdDJYWnNxYXhjTm9MNXFQQjlDNVNrU1poRnlTUnpwamhqM0Iza1FkTTBfNWtCV0FyUUxNS1gyUHJSRkFpY0dHQnVBNGs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:03:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will GTA 6 Be Delayed? Here's How Rockstar-Owner Take Two Still Offers Hope For 2025 Release - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<html>
<head>
<title>GTA 6 Release Timeline: Take-Two Confirms 2025 Launch, Hypes Upcoming Titles</title>
</head>
<body>
<h1>GTA 6 Release Timeline: Take-Two Confirms 2025 Launch, Hypes Upcoming Titles</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Article Publish Date, <strong>Source: </strong>Abplive</p>
<img src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QdBZY2fkU-0?si=gb0QhuzJ5BNJ6weX" alt="Take-Two Interactive CEO Strauss Zelnick discussing GTA 6"><figcaption>Take-Two Interactive CEO Strauss Zelnick discussing GTA 6</figcaption>
<p>GTA fans worldwide awaited the GTA 6 trailer on December 27, but it didn't materialize. However, Take-Two Interactive, Rockstar Games' parent company, has reassured fans that GTA 6 will indeed release in the fall of 2025.</p>
<h2>Key Points</h2>
<ul>
  <li>GTA 6 is confirmed to release in Q3/Q4 2025</li>
  <li>Take-Two expects GTA 6 to set new industry benchmarks, following the success of GTA V (205 million copies) and Red Dead Redemption 2 (62 million copies)</li>
  <li>Upcoming Take-Two titles include Civilization 7, WWE 2K25, Borderlands 4, and Mafia: The Old Country</li>
</ul>
<h2>Notable Quote</h2>
<blockquote>
  Strauss Zelnick, CEO of Take-Two Interactive: "With many exciting new titles coming in Fiscal 2026 – including Grand Theft Auto VI, Borderlands 4, and Mafia: The Old Country – we expect to create long-term value for our shareholders."
</blockquote>
</body>
</html>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/gaming/gta-6-release-date-trailer-2-rockstar-games-take-two-announcement-lineup-1740716</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/gaming/gta-6-release-date-trailer-2-rockstar-games-take-two-announcement-lineup-1740716</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:31:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Soon, WhatsApp web will allow reverse image search through Google: Details - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp Web to Introduce Reverse Image Search via Google</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source: Dec 30 2024 | 3:00 PM IST, Business Standard</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" title="Whatsapp" alt="Whatsapp" width="826" height="465"><figcaption>WhatsApp (Photo: Shutterstock)</figcaption>
<p>Meta is reportedly working with Google to tackle misinformation on WhatsApp. The reverse image search feature, first tested on Android, is now being explored for the WhatsApp web client. This feature will allow users to search an image on the web using Google, helping them gather more context and determine if the image has been manipulated. The feature is expected to be available soon on both WhatsApp Android app and WhatsApp Web.</p>
<ul><li>The feature will allow users to upload a photo to Google to perform a reverse image search.</li><li>It is expected to be available on both WhatsApp Android app and WhatsApp Web in the coming weeks.</li><li>The feature is akin to Google's existing reverse image search but more convenient as it's integrated within WhatsApp.</li></ul>
<blockquote>While Meta has not officially confirmed the availability of the new reverse image search feature, it is expected to be available soon.</blockquote>
<p>Source: Business Standard</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/soon-whatsapp-web-will-allow-reverse-image-search-through-google-details-124123000506_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/soon-whatsapp-web-will-allow-reverse-image-search-through-google-details-124123000506_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:30:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govt starts countervailing duty probe on Vietnamese chemical | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Initiates Countervailing Duty Probe on Subsidized Vietnamese Chemical Imports</h1>
<p><strong>New Delhi, Dec 30 (PTI)</strong></p>
<img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='DGTR Logo' width='200'><figcaption>DGTR Logo</figcaption>
<p>India has started a countervailing duty investigation into increased imports of Calcium Carbonate Filler Masterbatch, a chemical used in the plastic industry, from Vietnam. The move follows a complaint from domestic manufacturers who allege that the increased imports are subsidized, causing material injury to their businesses.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Directorate General of Trade Remedies (DGTR) has initiated the probe.</li>
<li>Domestic manufacturers have alleged that producers/exporters in Vietnam have received actionable subsidies from various levels of the Vietnamese government.</li>
<li>Countervailing duties are country-specific duties imposed to safeguard domestic industries against unfair trade subsidies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"On the basis of the duly substantiated written application filed by the domestic industry...on the basis of the prima facie evidence submitted by the domestic industry, about the subsidization of the product...the authority, hereby, initiates an investigation."</blockquote>
<p>Vietnam is a key trading partner of India, with exports and imports reaching USD 5.47 billion and USD 9.34 billion respectively in 2023-24.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/govt-starts-countervailing-duty-probe-on-vietnamese-chemical-11735550275334.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/govt-starts-countervailing-duty-probe-on-vietnamese-chemical-11735550275334.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:17:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp Web to get reverse image search feature soon to help users identify fake photos - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp Web to get reverse image search feature soon to help users identify fake photos</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/12/20241224123954_WhatsApp-Image-2024-11-13-at-13.42.06.jpeg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="WhatsApp" title="WhatsApp" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>WhatsApp</figcaption>
<p>WhatsApp is introducing a new reverse image search feature to tackle the spread of fake information. This will allow WhatsApp users to authenticate received images via Google and provide a more reliable way to judge the authenticity of shared images.</p>
<ul>
<li>Meta plans to help users identify fake photos on WhatsApp using reverse image search.</li>
<li>Users can tap any image in a chat to initiate a reverse image search.</li>
<li>The 'Search on the web' option will be available in the three-dot menu for selected images.</li>
<li>This feature was previously spotted in the Android beta application.</li>
<li>Google's database will help verify the authenticity of shared images.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The popular messaging platform WhatsApp has often been used for escalating various fake or misleading information across its millions of users."</blockquote>
<p>This new feature aims to combat the spread of misinformation and help users verify the images they receive.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/whatsapp-web-to-get-reverse-image-search-feature-soon-to-help-users-identify-fake-photos-article-12900225.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/whatsapp-web-to-get-reverse-image-search-feature-soon-to-help-users-identify-fake-photos-article-12900225.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:51:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Owner Bought Maruti Invicto But Got Innova Hycross Instead - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Owner Converts Maruti Invicto into Toyota Innova Hycross</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> MotorOctane</p><figure><img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Maruti-Suzuki-Invicto-into-hycross-.jpg.webp" alt="Maruti Invicto Modified Into Toyota Innova Hycross"><figcaption>Maruti Invicto Modified Into Toyota Innova Hycross</figcaption></figure><p>The article details the story of a car owner who bought a Maruti Invicto but decided to modify it to resemble a Toyota Innova Hycross. This is notable due to the long waiting periods for the Innova Hycross and the popularity it enjoys.</p><ul><li>Toyota Innova Hycross has a significant waiting period and is more expensive than Maruti Invicto.</li><li>The owner transformed the Invicto by modifying the exterior and interior to resemble the Innova Hycross.</li><li>Exterior modifications include a new grille, bumper, alloy wheels, and rear lights resembling those of the Innova Hycross.</li><li>Interior changes involved replacing the Suzuki logo with Toyota, adding new steering wheel features, and upgrading the audio system.</li><li>The transformation was revealed in a video by Indian AutoZone.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Indian Motor Vehicle Act states that any modification on the car outside the OEM factory premise is considered illegal.”</blockquote><p>This transformation highlights the demand for the Innova Hycross and the lengths owners might go to acquire its aesthetic appeal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/281510-owner-bought-maruti-invicto-but-got-innova-hycross-instead</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/281510-owner-bought-maruti-invicto-but-got-innova-hycross-instead</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Days Sale at Vijay Sales: iPhones, MacBooks, iPads, and more at unbeatable prices - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Days Sale at Vijay Sales: iPhones, MacBooks, iPads, and more at unbeatable prices</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>December 29th, 2024 - January 5th, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source: </strong>Financial Express</p>
<img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/gold-bull-backgrounds-graphics-elements-related-financial-sector-1-1-1-3.jpg?w=300" alt="Sale Announcement Image" />
<figcaption>Incredible discounts on Apple products</figcaption>
<p>Vijay Sales has launched its “Apple Days Sale,” offering discounts up to Rs 10,000 on various Apple products.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The sale runs from December 29th, 2024, to January 5th, 2025.</li>
  <li>Instant discounts available with bank cards and trade-in deals.</li>
  <li>Highlights include iPhone 13 at Rs 42,900 and up to Rs 10,000 off on MacBooks.</li>
  <li>Accessories like Apple Watches and AirPods also on sale with significant discounts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Grab an iPhone 13 for as low as Rs 42,900 after a Rs 1,000 instant discount...”</blockquote>
<p>Don’t miss out on these limited-time offerings during the festival sale!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-apple-days-sale-at-vijay-sales-iphones-macbooks-ipads-and-more-at-unbeatable-prices-3703283/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-apple-days-sale-at-vijay-sales-iphones-macbooks-ipads-and-more-at-unbeatable-prices-3703283/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:22:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma on Yashasvi Jaiswal’s controversial DRS dismissal: ’Don’t know how umpires want to use technology’ - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Questions Umpires After Jaiswal's Controversial DRS Dismissal</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>India captain Rohit Sharma expressed his confusion over the use of technology after Yashasvi Jaiswal was controversially dismissed during the fourth Test against Australia.</p><p>Jaiswal, who was batting at 84, seemed to have made no contact with the ball, a fact supported by the snickometer, but the third umpire ruled him out based on inconclusive evidence.</p><ul><li>Jaiswal was dismissed after a review from Australian skipper Pat Cummins.</li><li>Rohit indicated that technology often fails to provide clear answers.</li><li>India lost the match by 184 runs, placing them in a difficult spot for the World Test Championship final.</li></ul><blockquote>“I don’t know how the umpires want to use the technology.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>This decision has heightened scrutiny over DRS technology and its interpretation by umpires in crucial matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/rohit-sharma-on-yashasvi-jaiswal-controversial-drs-dismissal-dont-know-how-umpires-want-to-use-technology-ind-vs-aus-11735545280830.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/rohit-sharma-on-yashasvi-jaiswal-controversial-drs-dismissal-dont-know-how-umpires-want-to-use-technology-ind-vs-aus-11735545280830.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:15:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun stampede case: Decision on counter police affidavit opposing the bail pushed to January 3 - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun Stampede Case Update: Bail Decision Delayed to January 3</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116792657,imgsize-151344,width-400,resizemode-4/116792657.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun stampede case: Decision on counter police affidavit opposing the bail pushed to January 3" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Allu Arjun related to the stampede case.</figcaption><p>A Hyderabad court has postponed the verdict on the bail application of actor Allu Arjun in connection to the Pushpa 2 stampede case to January 3.</p><ul><li>Allu Arjun was involved in a stampede incident during the premiere of 'Pushpa-2' where a woman died and her son was injured.</li><li>The actor appeared via video conference as the hearing for his bail came up.</li><li>He was arrested on December 13 and granted interim bail on December 14.</li><li>The police sought time to oppose his bail, leading to a new hearing date set for December 30.</li></ul><blockquote>“A 35-year-old woman died and her eight-year-old son was injured on December 4 during a stampede-like situation.”</blockquote><p>The court's decision on this high-profile case is anticipated as it involves serious allegations and public interest.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/telugu/movies/news/allu-arjun-stampede-case-decision-on-counter-police-affidavit-opposing-the-bail-pushed-to-january-3/articleshow/116792667.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/telugu/movies/news/allu-arjun-stampede-case-decision-on-counter-police-affidavit-opposing-the-bail-pushed-to-january-3/articleshow/116792667.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ministry issues draft guidelines on establishing EV charging infrastructure under PM E-DRIVE - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ministry Issues Draft Guidelines for EV Charging Infrastructure</h1>
<figure><img src="https://bl-i.thgim.com/public/todays-paper/tp-others/9s22sb/article69020708.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Electric-car-voGNSDOPFS8.5.jpg.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: A man charges an electric vehicle (EV) at a charging hub in Gurugram."><figcaption>FILE PHOTO: A man charges an electric vehicle (EV) at a charging hub in Gurugram. | Photo Credit: Anushree Fadnavis</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Updated - December 30, 2024 at 01:34 PM, <em>The Hindu Business Line</em></p>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> The Ministry of Heavy Industries (MHI) has issued draft guidelines for setting up electric vehicle (EV) charging infrastructure under the Prime Minister Electric Drive Revolution in Innovative Vehicle Enhancement (PM E-DRIVE) Scheme.</p>
<ol>
<li>The scheme aims to set up over 22,000 EV chargers for electric four wheelers and 1,800 chargers for e-buses.</li>
<li>It also includes provisions for charging infrastructure for light EVs like electric two-wheelers and electric three-wheelers.</li>
<li>The government aims to involve various stakeholders, including charge point operators, EV charger manufacturers, and other government bodies.</li>
<li>The scheme offers an 80% subsidy on upstream infrastructure, with an outlay of ₹2,000 crore.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Notable Quote:</strong> According to the draft guidelines, central-level Ministries and State governments are encouraged to carry out feasibility studies to identify suitable locations for EV charging stations.</p>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The draft guidelines for EV charging infrastructure aim to expand public charging facilities, involving various stakeholders and offering significant subsidies to promote EV adoption in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/economy/policy/ministry-issues-draft-guidelines-for-setting-up-ev-charging-infrastructure-under-pm-e-drive/article69042550.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/economy/policy/ministry-issues-draft-guidelines-for-setting-up-ev-charging-infrastructure-under-pm-e-drive/article69042550.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:03:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi polls: Kejriwal announces scheme to give ₹18,000 per month to priests, granthis - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxQaEtNbzU4OXhFLUJ6eFNOaVZkVDhBTm9McXVlYU1XWldldl9EczVpb1lIbVVJb2o1OGZkdGU5ZEFPRGlPb2x2SUJtVHBzejh6U3BYUXZ1MXl4UWtwS0tiX1Z0dWZmRzgyLW1FdFlYUGlYU1I1M2ZwaDFSdGc5OTdNWVlUUEFCcmlid2h6U0VrTnB4R1VxdmZFRnBMelk4d2pvUllJc2dQbktQOXZBZU9xajROOFEzR3o3cEVMVDdRWjFub3Zzc0hWY2VRdmwtMXN5ajl30gHYAUFVX3lxTFBSMkJDM0sxbmp4MGRyc2RKdm1SU1ZRTy1tdWQ0TEN2NUlFVkJwSVVZUGNYWXRhUHUxVk53VHJoVHNkbldGQWRaX25WZUNZOE9fOWRzNmhIOWhJZm9ibHhva3pCUHh3Z19abTFqdlZ4WW93TElIS0ZRejdxU0wwS2NlXzI0T19CYmh0cDRvQUtkaWpBNWRfWUxnMy05bnhBbkZZX1JYN1pNUmk4ZjVTRWpmY1RGaGt3azN6X1ppYnJ3TGkzMGNDX0NnMFZ4R2N4Z0p5ZTMxbzBaTA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxQaEtNbzU4OXhFLUJ6eFNOaVZkVDhBTm9McXVlYU1XWldldl9EczVpb1lIbVVJb2o1OGZkdGU5ZEFPRGlPb2x2SUJtVHBzejh6U3BYUXZ1MXl4UWtwS0tiX1Z0dWZmRzgyLW1FdFlYUGlYU1I1M2ZwaDFSdGc5OTdNWVlUUEFCcmlid2h6U0VrTnB4R1VxdmZFRnBMelk4d2pvUllJc2dQbktQOXZBZU9xajROOFEzR3o3cEVMVDdRWjFub3Zzc0hWY2VRdmwtMXN5ajl30gHYAUFVX3lxTFBSMkJDM0sxbmp4MGRyc2RKdm1SU1ZRTy1tdWQ0TEN2NUlFVkJwSVVZUGNYWXRhUHUxVk53VHJoVHNkbldGQWRaX25WZUNZOE9fOWRzNmhIOWhJZm9ibHhva3pCUHh3Z19abTFqdlZ4WW93TElIS0ZRejdxU0wwS2NlXzI0T19CYmh0cDRvQUtkaWpBNWRfWUxnMy05bnhBbkZZX1JYN1pNUmk4ZjVTRWpmY1RGaGt3azN6X1ppYnJ3TGkzMGNDX0NnMFZ4R2N4Z0p5ZTMxbzBaTA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma on Yashasvi Jaiswal's dismissal: 'In all fairness, it looked like he touched it' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Comments on Yashasvi Jaiswal's Dismissal Controversy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a recent discussion, Indian cricket captain Rohit Sharma addressed the controversial dismissal of Yashasvi Jaiswal during a match, suggesting that it appeared Jaiswal may have touched the ball.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma expressed his views on the contentious call made by the umpires.</li><li>The dismissal sparked debates among fans and analysts alike.</li><li>Sharma emphasized fairness in decision-making in cricket.</li></ul><blockquote>“In all fairness, it looked like he touched it,” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the ongoing challenges of officiating in cricket, as similar controversies often lead to heated discussions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rohit-sharma-on-yashasvi-jaiswals-dismissal-in-all-fairness-it-looked-like-he-touched-it/articleshow/116791542.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rohit-sharma-on-yashasvi-jaiswals-dismissal-in-all-fairness-it-looked-like-he-touched-it/articleshow/116791542.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revolutionary HIV Drug: Lenacapavir Signals New Hope - Devdiscourse]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQeGJncWkxXzZWbllKTHdxYWFURW50MTdUY3A2Ri1wdVRjcklqSmhmQ0hYNHZvUHlNcTNaUzlDMW1SN0NvVnZKdU1rRWxKUHRUUURNc2h3eXg5V0l4M3BIM19scnd0dS1NMk9JNXdwUVpWVFMzVXRETkh1WTJJamVLSVBMa3kwdllFbllNX3Exek5DNmxtUEpGajdEaHk3SFFWd2Q2VFhR0gGrAUFVX3lxTE5vWmQ4UG1McE1uWlN3dnRJcE1BcUhva19FOVVFbURGQzlTbWEtUFRlOEx2anh3X0d6Y29ZbDRHdkJmQmFUY01WYzBkMzhSc0RGX0RoYzdfQjhPTlhXWHc4TzF5TmswczVKM0V1LVl2YkpvNHRDYUk1Y3BjenRyWVNUY2Jobk9TN2JsREVWRGMwWktIRFNXa3RfRHBMbmtyUUpVa1hDRjIxVS1sbw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQeGJncWkxXzZWbllKTHdxYWFURW50MTdUY3A2Ri1wdVRjcklqSmhmQ0hYNHZvUHlNcTNaUzlDMW1SN0NvVnZKdU1rRWxKUHRUUURNc2h3eXg5V0l4M3BIM19scnd0dS1NMk9JNXdwUVpWVFMzVXRETkh1WTJJamVLSVBMa3kwdllFbllNX3Exek5DNmxtUEpGajdEaHk3SFFWd2Q2VFhR0gGrAUFVX3lxTE5vWmQ4UG1McE1uWlN3dnRJcE1BcUhva19FOVVFbURGQzlTbWEtUFRlOEx2anh3X0d6Y29ZbDRHdkJmQmFUY01WYzBkMzhSc0RGX0RoYzdfQjhPTlhXWHc4TzF5TmswczVKM0V1LVl2YkpvNHRDYUk1Y3BjenRyWVNUY2Jobk9TN2JsREVWRGMwWktIRFNXa3RfRHBMbmtyUUpVa1hDRjIxVS1sbw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:24:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Year-ender | Top space exploration moments and discoveries of 2024 - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Space Exploration Moments and Discoveries of 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: Not specified</strong> <br> <strong>Source: CNBC TV18</strong></p>
<img src='https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&width=640&height=360' alt='' title='' loading='lazy' width='640' height='360'><figcaption>2024 was a pivotal year in space exploration. From first-ever samples of the moon dust from the lunar south to the first all-civilian spacewalk, here are some of the highlights of this year in space. (Image: space zone india)</figcaption>
<p>2024 saw significant advancements in space exploration, with notable achievements including Japan's successful moon landing, the first private spacecraft to land on the moon, the retrieval of lunar samples, evidence of ancient microbial life on Mars, the first all-civilian spacewalk, and a mission to Jupiter's icy moon Europa. These milestones push the boundaries of human and robotic space exploration and pave the way for future discoveries.</p>
<ul>
<li>Japan becomes the fifth country to land on the moon.</li>
<li>Intuitive Machines' Odysseus spacecraft becomes the first private spacecraft to land on the moon.</li>
<li>China's Chang'e 6 mission retrieves lunar samples from the far side of the moon.</li>
<li>NASA's Perseverance rover finds evidence of ancient microbial life on Mars.</li>
<li>SpaceX conducts the first all-civilian spacewalk.</li>
<li>Boeing's Starliner spacecraft has issues with its thrusters, delaying the return of astronauts Sunita Williams and Butch Wilmore.</li>
<li>NASA's Europa Clipper begins its journey to Jupiter's icy moon Europa.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>These achievements highlight the progress and innovation happening in space exploration and set the stage for even more fascinating discoveries in the coming years.</blockquote>
<p>While these discoveries and milestones are exciting, they also raise important questions about the future of space exploration, such as how to ensure safe and sustainable exploration, the role of private companies in space, and how to protect our planet's unique environment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/technology/year-ender-top-space-exploration-moments-and-discoveries-of-2024-19530899.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/technology/year-ender-top-space-exploration-moments-and-discoveries-of-2024-19530899.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:10:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abhishek Bachchan, Amitabh Bachchan, Jaya Bachchan attend a wedding; fans miss Aishwarya Rai Bachchan as - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Abhishek Bachchan, Amitabh Bachchan, Jaya Bachchan attend a wedding; fans miss Aishwarya Rai Bachchan as PIC goes viral</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116787977,imgsize-119652,width-400,resizemode-4/116787977.jpg" alt="Bachchan Family Wedding"><figcaption>Abhishek Bachchan and family at a recent wedding.</figcaption><p>Abhishek, Amitabh, and Jaya Bachchan attended a wedding, generating buzz online as fans noted the absence of Aishwarya Rai Bachchan.</p><ul><li>The wedding was for Rajesh Yadav's son in Varanasi, closely linked with the Bachchan family.</li><li>The family was spotted celebrating together, while Aishwarya was notably missing.</li><li>Fans reacted to pictures of Abhishek in traditional attire, including a viral image of him in a pink turban.</li><li>Amitabh Bachchan addressed rumors of a divorce between Abhishek and Aishwarya, referring to them as 'speculated untruths' on his blog.</li></ul><blockquote>“Speculated untruths” - Amitabh Bachchan on recent rumors.</blockquote><p>This event underscores the public interest in the Bachchan family's personal lives and their appearances together.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/abhishek-bachchan-amitabh-bachchan-jaya-bachchan-attend-a-wedding-fans-miss-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-as-pic-goes-viral/articleshow/116788073.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/abhishek-bachchan-amitabh-bachchan-jaya-bachchan-attend-a-wedding-fans-miss-aishwarya-rai-bachchan-as-pic-goes-viral/articleshow/116788073.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australia v India: fourth men’s cricket Test, day five – as it happened - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/live/2024/dec/30/australia-vs-india-boxing-day-test-cricket-day-5-scores-results-start-time-melbourne-mcg</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/sport/live/2024/dec/30/australia-vs-india-boxing-day-test-cricket-day-5-scores-results-start-time-melbourne-mcg</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australia v India: fourth men’s cricket Test, day five – as it happened - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/live/2024/dec/30/australia-vs-india-boxing-day-test-cricket-day-5-scores-results-start-time-melbourne-mcg</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/sport/live/2024/dec/30/australia-vs-india-boxing-day-test-cricket-day-5-scores-results-start-time-melbourne-mcg</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 Superfoods That Will Help In Your Weight Loss Transformation 2025 - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>9 Superfoods That Will Help In Your Weight Loss Transformation 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Dec 30, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Times Now</p><img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116788725/116788725.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=35640" alt="9 Superfoods That Will Help In Your Weight Loss Transformation 2025"><figcaption>Credit: iStock</figcaption><p>This article outlines nine superfoods that can aid in weight loss through their nutritional benefits and ability to help control appetite.</p><ul><li>Avocados: High in monounsaturated fats and fiber, helping control hunger.</li><li>Oats: A source of soluble fiber that keeps you full and lowers cholesterol.</li><li>Chia Seeds: Packed with fiber and protein, promoting a feeling of fullness.</li><li>Green Tea: Contains catechins that enhance metabolism and aid weight loss.</li><li>Lentils: An excellent source of plant-based protein and fiber for stabilizing blood sugar.</li><li>Sweet Potatoes: Low in calories and high in fiber, providing a healthy carbohydrate option.</li><li>Greek Yogurt: High in protein and supports gut health.</li><li>Apples: High in water and fiber, naturally sweet, and help reduce calorie intake.</li><li>Spinach: Low in calories and rich in nutrients, great for anyone trying to lose weight.</li></ul><blockquote>“Losing weight isn’t just about cutting calories; it’s about nourishing your body with the right foods that enhance metabolism, curb cravings, and provide essential nutrients.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, incorporating these nine superfoods into your diet may significantly aid in weight loss and overall health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/health/9-superfoods-that-will-help-in-your-weight-loss-transformation-2025/photostory/116788698.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/health/9-superfoods-that-will-help-in-your-weight-loss-transformation-2025/photostory/116788698.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Row Over Schemes, Kejriwal Launches New 'Yojana' For Priests, To Give Rs 18,000 A Month - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arvind Kejriwal's 'Pujari Granthi Samman Yojana': Rs 18k Honorarium for Priests and Granthis</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Last Updated: December 30, 2024, 18:42 IST, <a href="https://www.news18.com/">News18</a></p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&width=360&height=270" alt="Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)" title="Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)">
<figcaption>Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)</figcaption>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Ahead of the upcoming Delhi Assembly polls, Arvind Kejriwal, the chief of Aam Aadmi Party (AAP), has announced the 'Pujari Granthi Samman Yojana', which promises a monthly honorarium of nearly Rs 18,000 to priests of temples and 'granthis' of the Gurudwara.</p>
<ul><li>Kejriwal's announcement comes amidst a row surrounding the 'Mahila Samman Yojana', another welfare scheme by AAP.</li><li>The BJP has criticized the new scheme, calling it 'deception'.</li></ul>
<blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="hi">... (Kejriwal's tweet on the scheme)</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The implementation of this scheme, if AAP wins the elections, would mark a significant step towards recognizing and rewarding the contributions of priests and granthis in Delhi's religious and cultural landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/elections/delhi-polls-arvind-kejriwal-announces-pujari-granthi-samman-yojana-benefits-rs-18000-as-monthly-honorarium-9172376.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/elections/delhi-polls-arvind-kejriwal-announces-pujari-granthi-samman-yojana-benefits-rs-18000-as-monthly-honorarium-9172376.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:59:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Science News | ⚡Know Dates of Lunar Eclipse, Solar Eclipse Set To Occur in 2025 - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Know Dates of Lunar Eclipse, Solar Eclipse Set To Occur in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>In 2025, four major eclipses will occur, including two solar and two lunar eclipses. India will only witness a full lunar eclipse in September, alongside other celestial events like meteor showers and supermoons.</p><ul><li>Four major eclipses will occur in 2025.</li><li>India will experience a full lunar eclipse in September.</li><li>Other celestial events include meteor showers and supermoons.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQazhTQlB3UGZkNmRzYXNXQ3ZCRjBpdVk5VnNheWNxcEpCSlJfR3lHLUZCblBfWmZBSU1xSWRqTzA1OVBraUI5MWJBRzJzRFV1VEtfdFNjSk1ma0lubUVFTnVPZm80TDg4MHFadkNxdVh2Z1pEWXViZjduXzh3UjhiWjhvM2xNQ2J4T1ZCRS0xdy1tYlhsMDU3ZnZJZFdPSnpaMVpjTi0wT2dwY25IRnRRbG9WX083Wmc1aDlGVlFoTllESDc2RVHSAcYBQVVfeXFMUGs4U0JQd1BmZDZkc2FzV0N2QkYwaXVZOVZzYXljcXBKQkpSX0d5Ry1GQm5QX1pmQUlNcUlkak8wNTlQa2lCOTFiQUcyc0RVdVRLX3RTY0pNZmtJbm1FRU51T2ZvNEw4ODBxWnZDcXVYdmdaRFl1YmY3bl84d1I4Ylo4bzNsTUNieE9WQkUtMXctbWJYbDA1N2Z2SWRXT0p6WjFaY04tME9ncGNuSEZ0UWxvVl9PN1pnNWg5RlZRaE5ZREg3NkVR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQazhTQlB3UGZkNmRzYXNXQ3ZCRjBpdVk5VnNheWNxcEpCSlJfR3lHLUZCblBfWmZBSU1xSWRqTzA1OVBraUI5MWJBRzJzRFV1VEtfdFNjSk1ma0lubUVFTnVPZm80TDg4MHFadkNxdVh2Z1pEWXViZjduXzh3UjhiWjhvM2xNQ2J4T1ZCRS0xdy1tYlhsMDU3ZnZJZFdPSnpaMVpjTi0wT2dwY25IRnRRbG9WX083Wmc1aDlGVlFoTllESDc2RVHSAcYBQVVfeXFMUGs4U0JQd1BmZDZkc2FzV0N2QkYwaXVZOVZzYXljcXBKQkpSX0d5Ry1GQm5QX1pmQUlNcUlkak8wNTlQa2lCOTFiQUcyc0RVdVRLX3RTY0pNZmtJbm1FRU51T2ZvNEw4ODBxWnZDcXVYdmdaRFl1YmY3bl84d1I4Ylo4bzNsTUNieE9WQkUtMXctbWJYbDA1N2Z2SWRXT0p6WjFaY04tME9ncGNuSEZ0UWxvVl9PN1pnNWg5RlZRaE5ZREg3NkVR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:47:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Assembly polls: Arvind Kejriwal announces Rs 18k per month for temple priests, gurdwara granthis if AAP wins - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Assembly polls: Arvind Kejriwal announces Rs 18k per month for temple priests, gurdwara granthis if AAP wins</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Indian-Express-67-3.jpg?w=640" alt="AAP" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Kejriwal said he would visit the Hanuman Mandir in Connaught Place on Tuesday to oversee the registration process for priests there. (@AAP/X)</figcaption><p>Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) national convenor Arvind Kejriwal announced a new welfare scheme targeting pandits and granthis ahead of the upcoming Delhi Assembly polls, promising Rs 18,000 per month to these religious service providers if AAP returns to power.</p><ul><li>The scheme, named Pujari Granthi Samman Rashi Scheme, aims to win the support of Pandit and Sikh voters, who comprise around 20% of the electorate.</li><li>Kejriwal highlighted that this is the first initiative of its kind in India, emphasizing respect for those who maintain cultural traditions.</li><li>The registration for the scheme will start at the Hanuman Temple in Connaught Place, with further rollout planned across all constituencies.</li><li>Amidst this announcement, protestors demanded unpaid salaries from the government, indicating the broader issues of religious leader remuneration.</li><li>Polls are scheduled for February 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“These are people who have been serving God for generations... I will not call this amount a salary but it is our respect towards them,” - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote><p>This initiative may reshape voter dynamics as AAP seeks to bolster its support among key religious communities in Delhi.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/delhi/pujari-granthi-samman-yojana-aap-temple-gurdwara-priest-allowance-kejriwal-9751267/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/delhi/pujari-granthi-samman-yojana-aap-temple-gurdwara-priest-allowance-kejriwal-9751267/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 4th Test Day 5 LIVE Score: AUS beat IND by 184 runs, take 2-1 lead in Border-Gavaskar Trophy - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-live-score-today-4th-test-day-5-ind-vs-aus-border-gavaskar-trophy-latest-scorecard-update-melbourne-101735484230688.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-live-score-today-4th-test-day-5-ind-vs-aus-border-gavaskar-trophy-latest-scorecard-update-melbourne-101735484230688.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:39:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2 solar, lunar eclipses in 2025; India to witness only THIS eclipse - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxQeFRuRF9vdHVlX0Uta0JMZlUxc0FEamdSSm1fTFh2bktqb0ktNi1KQXdoRXhLeElWZ0ppTUUyNjc1WjN6S20zbmJpaWVtWkZ3S3plZTBpWlhETzJDaVFoejJfdkNGcXFSZFJNTVRtbFRfbWZNemVpMTZZbW9oalpvMGVpQ3ZSMWJleFRpbU9DU1Eyc2k0eEhveXk1bGFlSVNIQXlKbm1ldWctWmNIYmk3Wg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxQeFRuRF9vdHVlX0Uta0JMZlUxc0FEamdSSm1fTFh2bktqb0ktNi1KQXdoRXhLeElWZ0ppTUUyNjc1WjN6S20zbmJpaWVtWkZ3S3plZTBpWlhETzJDaVFoejJfdkNGcXFSZFJNTVRtbFRfbWZNemVpMTZZbW9oalpvMGVpQ3ZSMWJleFRpbU9DU1Eyc2k0eEhveXk1bGFlSVNIQXlKbm1ldWctWmNIYmk3Wg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Squid Game Season 2 ENDING Explained: Gi-Hun's Failed Rebellion, Front Man's Real Plan And More Cliffhanger Qu - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Squid Game Season 2 ENDING Explained: Gi-Hun's Failed Rebellion, Front Man's Real Plan And More Cliffhanger Questions</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The News Network</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116789379,thumbsize-76558,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116789379.jpg" alt="Squid Game Season 2 ENDING Explained" title="Squid Game Season 2 ENDING Explained">
<figcaption>Squid Game Season 2 ENDING Explained</figcaption>
<p>Squid Game Season 2 has unleashed mayhem on Netflix with its gripping storyline. This season follows Seong Gi-hun, who returns to the deadly game amidst chaos and strategic conflicts.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gi-hun plans a rebellion against the game but ends up without backup.</li>
  <li>The stakes rise as players face dire consequences, with numerous casualties.</li>
  <li>Hwang In-ho reveals his true identity as the Front Man and backstabs Gi-hun.</li>
  <li>The season ends with unresolved cliffhangers, leaving viewers eager for the next installment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“While we need to wait to get answers in its final season in 2025, here are some burning questions that have left us wondering.”</blockquote>
<p>The unresolved nature of the ending and the revelations about the characters heighten the anticipation for future episodes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/web-series/squid-game-season-2-ending-explained-gi-huns-failed-rebellion-front-mans-real-plan-and-more-cliffhanger-questions-article-116786421</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/web-series/squid-game-season-2-ending-explained-gi-huns-failed-rebellion-front-mans-real-plan-and-more-cliffhanger-questions-article-116786421</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:31:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[While Rohit Sharma has decided to retire after Sydney Test, shouldn't he be saying goodbye right away? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma's Retirement: A Timely Goodbye?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116788985,imgsize-76074,width-400,resizemode-4/116788985.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma walks back after being dismissed cheaply in the second innings at Melbourne Cricket Ground." title="Rohit Sharma walks back after being dismissed cheaply in the second innings at Melbourne Cricket Ground." decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Rohit Sharma walks back after being dismissed cheaply in the second innings at Melbourne Cricket Ground. (Getty Images)</figcaption>
<p>Rohit Sharma has decided to retire after the Sydney Test, prompting discussions on whether he should step down immediately due to his poor performance in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Rohit has scored only 31 runs in the ongoing BGT across five innings.</li>
    <li>His batting average has struggled, raising questions about his place in the team.</li>
    <li>Selectors are reportedly aware of his retirement decision, but the timing remains unclear.</li>
    <li>The need for a smooth transition in the team is emphasized, comparing it to MS Dhoni's retirement approach.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When and where the announcement happens is anybody's guess but it's highly unlikely that the Indian captain will continue after the BGT.”</blockquote>
<p>The article highlights the significance of Rohit's performance and the implications of his retirement, suggesting that his immediate exit might facilitate the integration of emerging players into the team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/while-rohit-sharma-has-decided-to-retire-after-sydney-test-shouldnt-he-be-saying-goodbye-right-away/articleshow/116788767.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/while-rohit-sharma-has-decided-to-retire-after-sydney-test-shouldnt-he-be-saying-goodbye-right-away/articleshow/116788767.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 4th Test Day Highlights: Australia Beat India In Drama-Filled Final Day, Take 2-1 Lead - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia 4th Test Day Highlights: Australia Beat India In Drama-Filled Final Day, Take 2-1 Lead</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>A thrilling conclusion to the 4th Test match saw Australia narrowly defeat India, taking the series lead at 2-1. The final day was filled with suspense and high-stakes cricket action.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Australia secured a dramatic victory against India in the 4th Test match.</li>
  <li>The result leaves Australia with a 2-1 lead in the series.</li>
  <li>Key players contributed significantly to the match outcome.</li>
  <li>Fans witnessed an intense battle, showcasing the resilience of both teams.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"It was a nail-biting finish, credit to the players for their fighting spirit!" – Commentator during the match highlights.</blockquote>
<p>The match's outcome has significant implications for the series, with both teams aiming to clinch the title in the upcoming matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-5-live-score-updates-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-7358026</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-5-live-score-updates-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-7358026</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:23:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Unprovoked fire on multiple border posts': Pakistan forces, Taliban locked in tit-for-tat battle - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Unprovoked fire on multiple border posts': Pakistan forces, Taliban locked in tit-for-tat battle</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> October 2023 | Source: Unknown</p><p>This article details the ongoing conflict between Pakistani forces and the Taliban, highlighting recent unprovoked attacks on border posts that have escalated tensions between the two factions.</p><ul><li>Recent unprovoked fire on multiple border posts has been reported.</li><li>The conflict is characterized by tit-for-tat exchanges between Pakistan forces and the Taliban.</li><li>The situation raises concerns about regional stability and security.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a troubling escalation of hostilities.”</blockquote><p>As the conflict continues, observers are increasingly worried about the broader implications for security in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/unprovoked-fire-on-multiple-border-posts-pakistan-forces-taliban-locked-in-tit-for-tat-battle/articleshow/116787752.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/unprovoked-fire-on-multiple-border-posts-pakistan-forces-taliban-locked-in-tit-for-tat-battle/articleshow/116787752.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Days Sale: Vijay Sales brings deals on iPhones, iPads, Macs, more - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Days Sale: Vijay Sales brings deals on iPhones, iPads, Macs, more</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> Dec 30 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" title="Vijay Sales Apple Days Sale" alt="Vijay Sales Apple Days Sale" width="826" height="465"><figcaption>Vijay Sales Apple Days Sale</figcaption><p>Vijay Sales has launched the "Apple Days Sale," offering significant discounts on various Apple products, including the latest iPhone models and MacBooks, from December 29, 2024, to January 5, 2025.</p><ul><li>Discounts of up to Rs 10,000 available with bank offers from ICICI, SBI, and Kotak Bank.</li><li>Trade-in deals for older devices with bonuses of up to Rs 10,000.</li><li>Offers on display units of select Apple products, such as the iPhone 13 starting at Rs 32,900.</li><li>Discounted prices on iPhone 16 series: effective prices range from Rs 57,490 to Rs 127,650.</li><li>MacBook discounts: Effective prices for MacBook Air start from Rs 63,890.</li></ul><blockquote>"During the Apple Days Sale, we aim to provide exciting offers and discounts to our customers on premium Apple products." - Vijay Sales spokesperson</blockquote><p>This sale presents an opportunity for Apple fans to purchase products at reduced prices, making high-quality technology more accessible.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/apple-days-sale-vijay-sales-brings-deals-on-iphones-ipads-macs-more-124123000256_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/apple-days-sale-vijay-sales-brings-deals-on-iphones-ipads-macs-more-124123000256_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Yashasvi Jaiswal Victim Of Huge DRS Controversy, Confronts Umpires At MCG - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watch: Yashasvi Jaiswal Victim Of Huge DRS Controversy, Confronts Umpires At MCG</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/sfndu94g_l_625x300_30_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Watch: Yashasvi Jaiswal Victim Of Huge DRS Controversy, Confronts Umpires At MCG"><figcaption>Yashasvi Jaiswal's dismissal resulted in a big controversy.</figcaption><p>In a heated moment during the fourth Test match against Australia, Yashasvi Jaiswal was controversially dismissed following a DRS review that overturned the on-field decision.</p><ul><li>Jaiswal was in excellent form when he was caught behind off Pat Cummins’ bowling.</li><li>The umpire initially did not see an edge, but Australia opted for a DRS review.</li><li>The third umpire ruled there was clear deviation due to contact with Jaiswal's glove.</li><li>Jaiswal confronted the umpires after his dismissal, showing his displeasure at the decision.</li><li>Former players and commentators, including Sunil Gavaskar and Ricky Ponting, weighed in on the controversial call.</li></ul><blockquote>“There was no spike on the snickometer or any distinct sound that showed that the ball came in contact with Yashasvi's bat.”</blockquote><p>This incident has sparked discussions about the effectiveness of DRS and the interpretations made by officials during crucial moments in matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/watch-yashasvi-jaiswal-in-heated-chat-with-umpires-over-controversial-drs-decision-7361524</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/watch-yashasvi-jaiswal-in-heated-chat-with-umpires-over-controversial-drs-decision-7361524</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:01:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Snowfall And Sub-Zero Temperatures In Kashmir: Doctors Warn Of Heart Attack And Stroke Risk! - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kashmir's Winter Warnings: Heart Attack and Stroke Risks Spike Amid Snowfall and Cold Temperatures</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116787712,thumbsize-77282,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116787712.jpg" alt="Snowfall And Sub-Zero Temperatures In Kashmir: Doctors Warn Of Heart Attack And Stroke Risk!" title="Snowfall And Sub-Zero Temperatures In Kashmir: Doctors Warn Of Heart Attack And Stroke Risk!"><figcaption>Snowfall And Sub-Zero Temperatures In Kashmir: Doctors Warn Of Heart Attack And Stroke Risk! (Image Credits: iStock)</figcaption><p>As temperatures in Kashmir plunge below freezing, health experts warn of heightened risks for heart attacks and strokes. The Department of Cardiology at GMC Srinagar has issued an advisory for residents, especially those at higher risk, to take precautions.</p><ul><li>Heart-related emergencies, such as Myocardial Infarction (MI), are leading causes of death worldwide.</li><li>30% of adults in Kashmir suffer from hypertension, significantly increasing risk factors.</li><li>Cold weather increases blood pressure and stresses the heart due to vasoconstriction.</li></ul><blockquote>“Increased consumption of salt... and reliance on processed foods contribute to elevated blood pressure,” - Dr Irfan Ahmed Bhat.</blockquote><p>Preventative measures include staying warm, modifying outdoor activities, and regular health monitoring to manage risks effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxNMXNqNElKZVJQbjZtU0xYa3ZldUNlNHd1WVhDeXNfX1RBYlowTHo4bHkxUmtTUXRsTzFWWTMxV2JYU0MyQjlQM0JjVFIyazRqX0dqZ3ZEVmphZFRfTGFqMDI5SWs2VllUZkU4UHJOT3R6ajc1aUN2ZHB2V3lGcmx6RW5xUkpmenU4eWJhYWJDUE5tdWlZdjlqYUZzMnJBQ0t3a3N5ekNTbk4tNmZfY0ZOblMxM0V2M2NrMTlNaHlaVWxlRHVScTZjdmdWTnlHVDcxZlh3RXoyVi1KVnpY0gHiAUFVX3lxTE9FNEFQS0lnWW9wSXp3dmR3SDVDMHJySmctbUJMd09vNEsxR3lZRy1xNUhlU0hiR0Nhem5GQUNBbDdLLVlSZlFUODF5NkFFMWprVDJRZk15bGNqNTdnVG95Tl9lS0pCeTBpTEFlTVBMSkNTeHo1TVl0UmxYYzlXZmN4RnFFd3JxeUpRbHFxVnZWQk9tNjctU3Z0aVdyajVKRFVSbXZDZk4tV3dhNlpoSFdjN1VYNFppTnVaZC1YcDlGRm1rLWllb050YjNvU2JubEExUnBuQVlpU0JhNmlLUTVpMFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxNMXNqNElKZVJQbjZtU0xYa3ZldUNlNHd1WVhDeXNfX1RBYlowTHo4bHkxUmtTUXRsTzFWWTMxV2JYU0MyQjlQM0JjVFIyazRqX0dqZ3ZEVmphZFRfTGFqMDI5SWs2VllUZkU4UHJOT3R6ajc1aUN2ZHB2V3lGcmx6RW5xUkpmenU4eWJhYWJDUE5tdWlZdjlqYUZzMnJBQ0t3a3N5ekNTbk4tNmZfY0ZOblMxM0V2M2NrMTlNaHlaVWxlRHVScTZjdmdWTnlHVDcxZlh3RXoyVi1KVnpY0gHiAUFVX3lxTE9FNEFQS0lnWW9wSXp3dmR3SDVDMHJySmctbUJMd09vNEsxR3lZRy1xNUhlU0hiR0Nhem5GQUNBbDdLLVlSZlFUODF5NkFFMWprVDJRZk15bGNqNTdnVG95Tl9lS0pCeTBpTEFlTVBMSkNTeHo1TVl0UmxYYzlXZmN4RnFFd3JxeUpRbHFxVnZWQk9tNjctU3Z0aVdyajVKRFVSbXZDZk4tV3dhNlpoSFdjN1VYNFppTnVaZC1YcDlGRm1rLWllb050YjNvU2JubEExUnBuQVlpU0JhNmlLUTVpMFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>