<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:17:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:17:36 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech wrap Dec 27: Lava Yuva 2 launched, Redmi 14C, Samsung Galaxy Unpacked - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-wrap-dec-27-lava-yuva-2-launched-redmi-14c-samsung-galaxy-unpacked-124122700825_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-wrap-dec-27-lava-yuva-2-launched-redmi-14c-samsung-galaxy-unpacked-124122700825_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA spacecraft Parker Solar Probe ‘safe’ after closest-ever approach to the Sun - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Parker Solar Probe Safely Completes Historic Close Approach to the Sun</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/SPACE-EXPLORATION-SUN-0_1735306250088_1735306353427.JPG" alt="A 2018 artist's concept shows the Parker Solar Probe spacecraft flying into the Sun's outer atmosphere, called the corona, on a mission to help scientists learn more about the Sun. (via REUTERS)"><figcaption>A 2018 artist's concept shows the Parker Solar Probe spacecraft flying into the Sun's outer atmosphere, called the corona, on a mission to help scientists learn more about the Sun. (via REUTERS)</figcaption><p>NASA's Parker Solar Probe has successfully completed its closest approach to the Sun, coming within 3.8 million miles (6.1 million km) of the solar surface and entering the corona. The spacecraft is reported to be in good health and operational.</p><ul><li>The Parker Solar Probe transmitted a beacon signal confirming its status after the record-breaking approach.</li><li>The mission aims to enhance understanding of how solar material heats to millions of degrees and the origin of solar wind.</li><li>Traveling at speeds of up to 430,000 mph, the probe endured extreme temperatures of 1,800°F (982°C).</li><li>Mission Operations Manager Nick Pinkine noted the unprecedented nature of the probe's journey into uncharted territory.</li></ul><blockquote>“This close-up study of the Sun allows Parker Solar Probe to take measurements that help scientists better understand how material in this region gets heated to millions of degrees.” – NASA</blockquote><p>This successful mission marks a significant step in solar exploration and understanding the dynamics of our nearest star.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/science/nasa-spacecraft-parker-solar-probe-safe-after-closest-ever-approach-to-the-sun-101735306115792.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/science/nasa-spacecraft-parker-solar-probe-safe-after-closest-ever-approach-to-the-sun-101735306115792.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:09:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pollution Curbs Under GRAP-3 Revoked In Delhi As Air Quality Improves - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pollution Curbs Under GRAP-3 Revoked In Delhi As Air Quality Improves</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>The pollution curbs in Delhi under GRAP-3 have been lifted due to improvements in air quality following continuous rains. The AQI has shown a downward trend and is expected to remain in the 'poor' category for the next few days.</p><ul><li>Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) 3 curbs lifted as air quality improves.</li><li>Continuous rains have contributed to a decrease in the AQI levels.</li><li>Restrictions on diesel generators and construction activities are being eased, but some areas remain under closure orders.</li><li>Stage I & II of the revised GRAP will remain in effect to monitor air quality.</li></ul><blockquote>“Actions under Stage I & II of the revised GRAP shall remain invoked and be implemented, monitored and reviewed by all the agencies concerned in the entire NCR.”</blockquote><p>This move marks a shift in response to improved environmental conditions, as the seasonal pollution issues are still anticipated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pollution-curbs-under-grap-3-revoked-in-delhi-as-air-quality-improves-7345132</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pollution-curbs-under-grap-3-revoked-in-delhi-as-air-quality-improves-7345132</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:04:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier dissolves parliament, calls early election for February 23 after - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier dissolves parliament, calls early election for February 23 after Scholz's coalition falls apart</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Major News Outlet</p><p>In a significant political move, German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier has dissolved the parliament and announced early elections scheduled for February 23, following the collapse of Chancellor Olaf Scholz's coalition government.</p><ul><li>The coalition, comprised of the Social Democrats, Greens, and Free Democrats, fell apart due to internal disagreements.</li><li>Steinmeier's decision comes after unsuccessful attempts to stabilize the government.</li><li>This early election marks a pivotal moment in German politics and could reshape the political landscape.</li></ul><blockquote>“The decision to call an early election reflects the necessity of restoring stability and trust in our democratic institutions.” - Frank-Walter Steinmeier</blockquote><p>This unprecedented move underscores the challenges facing the current government and the potential for significant changes in the upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/german-president-dissolves-parliament-calls-early-election-for-february-23/articleshow/116711830.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/german-president-dissolves-parliament-calls-early-election-for-february-23/articleshow/116711830.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Popular sleeping pill linked to reduced Alzheimer's protein buildup, study reveals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Popular sleeping pill linked to reduced Alzheimer's protein buildup, study reveals</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Annals of Neurology</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116717852,imgsize-31514,width-400,resizemode-4/116717852.jpg" alt="Popular sleeping pill linked to reduced Alzheimer's protein buildup, study reveals" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Image depicting research study process.</figcaption><p>A new study suggests that taking sleeping pills may help lower the risk of Alzheimer's disease by reducing the accumulation of key proteins associated with the condition.</p><ul><li>Researchers found that those who took suvorexant, a common insomnia medication, for two nights showed a reduction in amyloid-beta and tau proteins.</li><li>The study involved 38 middle-aged participants who were monitored for protein levels while accounting for sleep quality.</li><li>Results indicated a 10-20% decrease in amyloid-beta levels for those on the medication compared to the placebo group.</li><li>There are concerns about the indiscriminate use of sleep medications without further research.</li></ul><blockquote>“If you can reduce tau phosphorylation, potentially there would be less tangle formation and less neuronal death,” said neurologist Brendan Lucey.</blockquote><p>This research highlights the potential link between sleep quality and the risk of developing Alzheimer's disease, suggesting that improving sleep might be beneficial.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/popular-sleeping-pill-linked-to-reduced-alzheimers-protein-buildup-study-reveals/articleshow/116717846.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/popular-sleeping-pill-linked-to-reduced-alzheimers-protein-buildup-study-reveals/articleshow/116717846.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4th Test, Day 2: Steve Smith Century, Yashasvi Jaiswal Run Out Deflate India At MCG - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>4th Test, Day 2: Steve Smith Century, Yashasvi Jaiswal Run Out Deflate India At MCG</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Steve Smith (left) and Yashasvi Jaiswal (AP Photo)" />
<figcaption>Steve Smith (left) and Yashasvi Jaiswal (AP Photo)</figcaption>
<p>A crucial moment unfolded when Yashasvi Jaiswal’s run-out sparked a collapse for India, who ended day two of the fourth Test against Australia at 164/5, chasing a first innings score of 474.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jaiswal scored 82 runs from 118 balls before his run-out, which triggered a poor performance from Indian batsmen.</li>
<li>Steve Smith scored his 34th Test century, contributing significantly to Australia's score.</li>
<li>India needs 111 more runs to avoid a follow-on, struggling at 310 runs behind.</li>
<li>Jaiswal and Kohli's partnership yielded 102 runs before the unfortunate dismissal.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This moment will be one for posterity as Kohli looked down and perhaps felt that he could have at least said a loud ‘No’.”</blockquote>
<p>The day concluded with Australia firmly in control, leaving India with a challenging path ahead in the Test match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-2-steve-smith-century-yashasvi-jaiswal-run-out-virat-kohli-scott-boland-steve-smith-9169668.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-2-steve-smith-century-yashasvi-jaiswal-run-out-virat-kohli-scott-boland-steve-smith-9169668.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:30:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Serbia reports 1st mpox case in Kosovo region - Xinhua]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Serbia Reports First Mpox Case in Kosovo Region</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec. 27</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Xinhua</p><p>The first confirmed case of mpox in the Kosovo region of Serbia has been reported, involving a 30-year-old man who recently traveled from West Africa. He was hospitalized with symptoms, including fever and skin lesions.</p><ul><li>A 30-year-old man is the first confirmed mpox case in Kosovo.</li><li>The patient was hospitalized on Dec. 24 and is in stable condition.</li><li>All close contacts have been traced and infection control guidelines issued.</li><li>Serbia confirmed its first mpox case in June 2022.</li><li>The World Health Organization classifies the mpox outbreak as a public health emergency.</li><li>Recent reports indicate imported cases may continue in Europe but sustained transmission remains low.</li></ul><blockquote>“The likelihood of sustained transmission in Europe remains very low.” - European Centre for Disease Prevention and Control</blockquote><p>This case underscores ongoing public health concerns related to mpox and the importance of monitoring travel-related infections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://english.news.cn/20241227/50c4a33a638d464c8b3f01363ef0f7a7/c.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://english.news.cn/20241227/50c4a33a638d464c8b3f01363ef0f7a7/c.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:24:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madras High Court Takes Suo Motu Cognizance Of Alleged Sexual Assault Of Student At Anna University - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Madras High Court Takes Suo Motu Cognizance Of Alleged Sexual Assault Of Student At Anna University</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Madras High Court</p><p>The Madras High Court has taken cognizance of the alleged sexual assault of a second-year engineering student at Anna University in Chennai, following a letter from Advocate R Varalakshmi.</p><ul><li>The incident happened on December 23 when the accused allegedly recorded a video of the girl and her male friend before assaulting her.</li><li>The bench noted the need for procedural adherence before action can be taken and awaits formal orders from the Chief Justice.</li><li>The Advocate General assured the court that the state would file a status report on the investigation.</li><li>Concerns have been raised regarding campus safety and the history of the accused, who has previous sexual assault cases against him.</li><li>The National Commission for Women has also responded, calling for stricter punishments related to leakage of FIR details.</li></ul><blockquote>“We've made an attempt to get orders from the Chief Justice...There's a procedure to be followed. So we'll have to wait for the official orders,” said the court.</blockquote><p>The court's reaction highlights the ongoing issues surrounding campus security and the legal processes to ensure justice and safety for students.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/madras-high-court/madras-high-court-anna-university-sexual-harassment-case-suo-motu-cognisance-279528</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/madras-high-court/madras-high-court-anna-university-sexual-harassment-case-suo-motu-cognisance-279528</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:22:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China defends plan to build world's largest dam over Brahmaputra River in Tibet - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Defends the Construction of the World's Largest Dam Over the Brahmaputra River</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/Dam_1735304527810_1735304534430.jpg" alt="China said it will continue to maintain communication with countries in the lower reaches. (Representational)" title="China said it will continue to maintain communication with countries in the lower reaches. (Representational)">
<figcaption>China said it will continue to maintain communication with countries in the lower reaches. (Representational)</figcaption>
<p>The Chinese foreign ministry announced plans for a $137 billion dam on the Brahmaputra River in Tibet, asserting that it will not adversely affect neighboring countries along the river.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The dam is part of a major infrastructure project in the ecologically sensitive Himalayan region.</li>
  <li>China claims it has conducted extensive studies to ensure the project's safety and environmental impact.</li>
  <li>Work on the dam aims to foster international cooperation on disaster prevention and relief.</li>
  <li>Construction will take at least a decade and will connect to the grid further east.</li>
  <li>Concerns have been raised about potential water flow reductions affecting downstream countries, especially India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Everybody downstream is going to be concerned about what it means if water flow is reduced. I know India is very anxious about it.” - David Fishman, energy consulting firm</blockquote>
<p>This ambitious project highlights the complexities of managing international rivers and the geopolitical implications for neighboring nations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/china-defends-plan-to-build-worlds-largest-dam-over-brahmaputra-river-in-tibet-101735304422074.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/china-defends-plan-to-build-worlds-largest-dam-over-brahmaputra-river-in-tibet-101735304422074.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 Dead, 26 hurt as bus plunges into drain in Punjab - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Dead, 26 hurt as bus plunges into drain in Punjab</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>A tragic bus accident in Punjab has resulted in 8 fatalities and left 26 others injured after the bus plunged into a drain. Emergency services responded quickly to the incident, aiding the injured and conducting rescue operations.</p><ul><li>The bus accident occurred early in the morning.</li><li>The victims include both passengers and the bus driver.</li><li>Authorities have launched an investigation into the cause of the accident.</li><li>Eyewitnesses reported that the bus lost control before plunging into the drain.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a heartbreaking incident that has affected many families,” said a local official.</blockquote><p>This accident highlights ongoing safety concerns regarding public transport in the region, which often faces scrutiny over regulations and infrastructure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/over-20-injured-as-bus-plunges-few-feet-down-from-bridge-in-punjabs-bathinda/articleshow/116713996.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/over-20-injured-as-bus-plunges-few-feet-down-from-bridge-in-punjabs-bathinda/articleshow/116713996.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heavy Rain In Delhi Causes Severe Waterlogging, 'Orange' Alert Issued: Latest Weather Updates - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Heavy Rain In Delhi Causes Severe Waterlogging, 'Orange' Alert Issued: Latest Weather Updates</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Delhi Weather Updates" loading="eager"><figcaption>Delhi Weather Updates: Temperature in Delhi stood at 13 degree Celsius at 7:23am as the weather department forecast heavy rain and strong winds for December 27th and 28th.</figcaption><p>Delhi experienced heavy rainfall and lightning today as the cold wave intensified. The India Meteorological Department (IMD) has predicted thunderstorms, hailstorms, and moderate rainfall across northwestern and central India on December 27 and 28 due to an active western disturbance.</p><ul><li>Temperature in Delhi stood at 13 degree Celsius at 7:23am.</li><li>The maximum temperature expected to reach 20 degrees Celsius, with a minimum of 12 degrees Celsius.</li><li>Heavy rain and strong winds forecasted for December 27th and 28th.</li><li>IMD issued warnings for hailstorms in several northern states.</li><li>Delhi’s air quality remains ‘very poor’, with some improvement expected.</li></ul><blockquote>“On December 27 and 28, Madhya Pradesh is likely to face similar conditions.”</blockquote><p>The weather department's warnings indicate serious impacts on daily life in Delhi and surrounding areas, highlighting the need for precautionary measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/cold-wave-intensifies-in-delhi-as-national-capital-wakes-up-to-rain-latest-updates-9169409.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/cold-wave-intensifies-in-delhi-as-national-capital-wakes-up-to-rain-latest-updates-9169409.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:39:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On Virat Kohli-Sam Konstas Clash, BCCI President Roger Binny Makes Feelings Clear: "You Have To..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI President Roger Binny Comments on Kohli-Konstas On-Field Clash</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jju9ipd8_virat-kohli-sam-konstas-usman-khawaja_625x300_26_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="On Virat Kohli-Sam Konstas Clash, BCCI President Roger Binny Makes Feelings Clear: &quot;You Have To...&quot;" width="639" height="479"><figcaption>On Virat Kohli-Sam Konstas Clash, BCCI President Roger Binny Makes Feelings Clear</figcaption><p>Virat Kohli and Sam Konstas had a noticeable altercation during the first day of the fourth Test at the MCG, with BCCI's Roger Binny commenting on the incident.</p><ul><li>Roger Binny addressed the on-field clash between Virat Kohli and Sam Konstas, emphasizing that such incidents are part of cricket.</li><li>Kohli was fined 20% of his match fee and received a demerit point for the altercation.</li><li>Konstas downplayed the incident, stating it was an accidental bump while he was adjusting his gloves.</li><li>Binny praised India's performance in the final session, highlighting their four wickets and expressing confidence in the batters.</li></ul><blockquote>“I did not see the incident, but these things happen on the cricket ground. You have to accept it and carry on.” - Roger Binny</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the clash highlighted the competitive nature of cricket, but both players and officials agreed that it's part of the game.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/on-virat-kohli-sam-konstas-clash-bcci-president-roger-binny-makes-feelings-clear-you-have-to-7343275</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/on-virat-kohli-sam-konstas-clash-bcci-president-roger-binny-makes-feelings-clear-you-have-to-7343275</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:28:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["External Interference" Caused Plane Crash In Kazakhstan: Azerbaijan Airlines - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kazakhstan Plane Crash Linked to External Interference, Says Azerbaijan Airlines</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>Azerbaijan Airlines stated that "external physical and technical interference" was responsible for a tragic plane crash in Kazakhstan that resulted in 38 fatalities out of 67 passengers.</p><ul><li>The Embraer 190 aircraft diverted and crashed in Aktau, Kazakhstan, after being denied landing in Grozny due to fog.</li><li>There are reports suggesting a possible accidental missile strike from Russian air defenses.</li><li>An investigation is ongoing, with evidence of missile damage noted by experts.</li><li>A passenger reported a loud bang before the aircraft began to behave erratically.</li><li>Azerbaijan Airlines announced the suspension of flights to multiple Russian airports for safety reasons.</li></ul><blockquote>“I thought the plane was going to fall apart,” - Subhonkul Rakhimov, passenger.</blockquote><p>The situation around the crash emphasizes the ongoing tensions involving air travel and defense systems in politically sensitive regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/external-interference-caused-plane-crash-in-kazakhstan-azerbaijan-airlines-7344416</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/external-interference-caused-plane-crash-in-kazakhstan-azerbaijan-airlines-7344416</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:24:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Parker solar probe is 'safe' after historic closest approach to Sun - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Parker solar probe is 'safe' after historic closest approach to Sun</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p>
<p>The Parker Solar Probe has made history by becoming the first man-made object to complete a closest-ever approach to the Sun, and it's reported to be safe and operational.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The probe came within 3.8 million miles of the Sun's surface on December 24, 2023.</li>
  <li>It transmitted a beacon tone indicating good health after the record-breaking approach.</li>
  <li>The mission aims to uncover secrets about solar heat and solar wind.</li>
  <li>The spacecraft is traveling at a speed of 430,000 mph and withstood temperatures up to 1,800 degrees Fahrenheit.</li>
  <li>It has completed 21 passes of the Sun since its launch in 2018.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This close-up study of the Sun allows Parker Solar Probe to take measurements that help scientists better understand how material in this region gets heated to millions of degrees...” - NASA</blockquote>
<p>The detailed telemetry data on the probe's condition is expected on January 1, 2024.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/nasa-s-parker-solar-probe-is-safe-after-historic-closest-approach-to-sun-nc-124122700850_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/nasa-s-parker-solar-probe-is-safe-after-historic-closest-approach-to-sun-nc-124122700850_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:23:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Virat Kohli definitely would've made it': Sunil Gavaskar shares verdict on Yashasvi Jaiswal's run-out - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingJBVV95cUxOMUdvdG0yZ0U4RlJlZ1I2a0MyeUlNS21uakFnVGg2RlkyaTVRUl8ycXdCRzk1WVNKZm0xZGY4QUxsSDAxcEs1SFZsRkRVVWx1XzluQVR4SFZMbWR1c1VxNlcwcEgzZkc5dGUwdThkS3Mtc3VpSXdVWEhaSXZzTk12OWZkNzUxUkNrRkg5b05VemxfYTJ1ZXRRSllLRVU4ZEd3TjRMSWE3Nk1RVGNCcFo0dWNiX3dYTEIxQzZSNENWcVdOVEpuLThxbkI4aG1GZFEzbEdKcnpyNm9xN2Y2cS1vZ1hVZzFkTEJRaC1iV1hkYW5POW1tUGVSendGaEx3bTNjb2Z6ZVowUEdqSXp6RkNzNGdncVlObVFUZ0s3ajhR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingJBVV95cUxOMUdvdG0yZ0U4RlJlZ1I2a0MyeUlNS21uakFnVGg2RlkyaTVRUl8ycXdCRzk1WVNKZm0xZGY4QUxsSDAxcEs1SFZsRkRVVWx1XzluQVR4SFZMbWR1c1VxNlcwcEgzZkc5dGUwdThkS3Mtc3VpSXdVWEhaSXZzTk12OWZkNzUxUkNrRkg5b05VemxfYTJ1ZXRRSllLRVU4ZEd3TjRMSWE3Nk1RVGNCcFo0dWNiX3dYTEIxQzZSNENWcVdOVEpuLThxbkI4aG1GZFEzbEdKcnpyNm9xN2Y2cS1vZ1hVZzFkTEJRaC1iV1hkYW5POW1tUGVSendGaEx3bTNjb2Z6ZVowUEdqSXp6RkNzNGdncVlObVFUZ0s3ajhR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pregnancy Myths Busted: Fun Facts About The Myths - NDTV Doctor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pregnancy Myths Busted: Let's dive into some of the most common pregnancy myths, bust them with facts, and uncover the truth about what really matters during this special time.</h1><p><strong>By: Aayushi Singh Chauhan</strong> <strong>Updated: Dec 27, 2024 05:19 IST</strong></p><p><img width='620' src='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7l78fe6o_nigeria-pregnancy-scam-istock_625x300_28_November_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=620,height=350?q=50' alt='Pregnancy Myths Busted: Fun Facts About The Myths'><figcaption>Women's Health: Facts To Bust Most Common Pregnancy Myths</figcaption></p><p>Pregnancy is a transformative journey filled with excitement, curiosity, and, often, an overwhelming amount of advice. While some of this advice is rooted in cultural traditions or personal experiences, much of it stems from myths that have no scientific basis. These myths can create unnecessary stress or confusion for expectant mothers.</p><h2>Most uncommon facts about pregnancy</h2><ul><li><strong>Myth 1:</strong> You're eating for two. <em>Fact:</em> Most women only need an additional 300–500 calories per day during the second and third trimesters.</li><li><strong>Myth 2:</strong> Heartburn means your baby will have a lot of hair. <em>Fact:</em> While associated, not every case guarantees this outcome.</li><li><strong>Myth 3:</strong> You should avoid exercise during pregnancy. <em>Fact:</em> Exercise is safe and beneficial unless advised otherwise.</li><li><strong>Myth 4:</strong> Morning sickness only happens in the morning. <em>Fact:</em> It can strike at any time of the day.</li><li><strong>Myth 5:</strong> Carrying low means you're having a boy. <em>Fact:</em> Carrying depends on factors other than the baby's sex.</li><li><strong>Myth 6:</strong> Spicy food induces labour. <em>Fact:</em> There's no scientific evidence for this claim.</li><li><strong>Myth 7:</strong> You shouldn't dye your hair during pregnancy. <em>Fact:</em> Most research shows that hair dye is safe.</li><li><strong>Myth 8:</strong> Pregnant women should avoid caffeine entirely. <em>Fact:</em> Moderate intake is considered safe.</li><li><strong>Myth 9:</strong> The shape of your belly can predict the baby's gender. <em>Fact:</em> Gender predictions based on belly shape are myths.</li><li><strong>Myth 10:</strong> You can't fly during pregnancy. <em>Fact:</em> Air travel is safe until about 36 weeks.</li></ul><p>By separating fact from fiction, you can focus on what truly matters for your health and your baby's development. Always rely on advice from trusted medical professionals.</p><p><i>Disclaimer: Always consult a specialist or your own doctor for more information.</i></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://doctor.ndtv.com/pregnancy/womens-health-facts-to-bust-most-common-pregnancy-myths-7344178</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doctor.ndtv.com/pregnancy/womens-health-facts-to-bust-most-common-pregnancy-myths-7344178</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:04:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bird flu virus shows mutations in first severe human case in U.S., CDC says - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mutation Detected in First Severe U.S. Bird Flu Case, CDC Reports</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/fp3d6a/article69033360.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-27T051053Z_235000391_RC2RRBAOY7BO_RTRMADP_3_HEALTH-BIRD-FLU-USA.JPG" alt="Bird flu virus" /><figcaption>Bird flu virus image | Photo Credit: REUTERS</figcaption><p>The CDC announced mutations in the hemagglutinin gene in the first severe bird flu case in the U.S., detected in a Louisiana resident. The outbreak remains low risk for the general public.</p><ul><li>First severe bird flu case reported in the U.S. occurred in Louisiana.</li><li>The patient is over 65 years old and has severe respiratory illness.</li><li>Infection caused by D1.1 genotype, not the B3.13 genotype.</li><li>Mutations are rare but have been reported in severe infections in other countries.</li><li>No person-to-person transmission identified from this case.</li></ul><blockquote>The risk to the general public from the outbreak has not changed and remains low.</blockquote><p>This finding highlights the necessity of monitoring mutations in the bird flu virus and underscores the current low risk to public health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/bird-flu-virus-shows-mutations-in-first-severe-human-case-in-us-cdc-says/article69033307.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/bird-flu-virus-shows-mutations-in-first-severe-human-case-in-us-cdc-says/article69033307.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBI ‘Found Covid Was Leaked From China Lab’ But Joe Biden Was Kept In Dark: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FBI ‘Found Covid Was Leaked From China Lab’ But Joe Biden Was Kept In Dark: Report</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="US President Joe Biden | Reuters Image" />
<figcaption>US President Joe Biden | Reuters Image</figcaption>
<p>The FBI reportedly silenced evidence supporting the theory that Covid-19 leaked from a Chinese lab, findings which were excluded from a report presented to President Biden.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The FBI suppressed information from US defense and research institutions regarding the lab leak theory.</li>
  <li>Key findings were omitted from an August 2021 report which contradicted the theory.</li>
  <li>Research indicated that spike proteins aiding human transmission were consistent with prior studies from the Wuhan Institute of Virology.</li>
  <li>Intelligence officials prevented researchers from discussing their analysis with Congress and the FBI.</li>
  <li>A whistleblower revealed improper classification of federal grant documents related to viral engineering.</li>
  <li>Chinese authorities maintain that the virus likely originated from bats, not a lab leak.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The scientists with subject matter expertise were silenced.”</blockquote>
<p>The event raises significant questions regarding transparency and the origins of the Covid-19 pandemic, indicating potential implications for future public health policies and international relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/fbi-found-covid-was-leaked-from-china-lab-but-joe-biden-was-kept-in-dark-report-9169573.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/fbi-found-covid-was-leaked-from-china-lab-but-joe-biden-was-kept-in-dark-report-9169573.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:54:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Current account deficit narrows to $11.2 billion in Q2FY25 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Current account deficit at $11.2 billion in July-September</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Economic Times</p><p>The current account deficit for the July-September quarter stood at $11.2 billion, representing 1.2% of GDP, slightly lower than the revised figure of $11.3 billion for the same period last year.</p><ul><li>The deficit was $9.7 billion, or 1.1% of GDP, in the preceding quarter.</li><li>The figures are reported by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI).</li></ul><blockquote>“The current account deficit was $11.2 billion in the reporting quarter.”</blockquote><p>This slight reduction in the deficit indicates a marginal improvement in the balance of payments situation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/indicators/current-account-deficit-at-11-2-billion-in-july-september/articleshow/116714960.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/indicators/current-account-deficit-at-11-2-billion-in-july-september/articleshow/116714960.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:52:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Akin To B-21 Raider’s Broad-Spectrum Stealth, China’s New 6th-Gen Stealth Fighters Bound To Rattle U.S. Military - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Unveils New 6th-Generation Stealth Fighters</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Eurasian Times</p><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/China-sixth-generation-1.jpg" alt="China’s 6th-Gen Aircraft" width="696" height="392"><figcaption>File Image: China’s 6th-Gen Aircraft</figcaption><p>China has recently unveiled two new stealth fighter prototypes, featuring broad-spectrum stealth technology that enhances their ability to evade radar detection across various frequencies.</p><ul><li>Broad-spectrum stealth minimizes detectability to both high and low-frequency radars.</li><li>This technology was previously seen only in strategic bombers, marking a significant leap for fighter jets.</li><li>The introduction of these fighters positions China ahead in global stealth capabilities.</li><li>The larger fighter, possibly the J-36, has enhanced payload capacity and stealth features.</li><li>The smaller fighter, likely from SAC, is designed for agility and air superiority roles.</li><li>Capabilities of the new fighters may include optional manning and next-generation power plants.</li></ul><blockquote>“China’s rapid advancement in military aviation technology is unquestionable.”</blockquote><p>The prototypes reveal China's significant progress in military technology but actual capabilities will be assessed as they develop further.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/akin-to-b-21-raiders-broad-spectrum-stealth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/akin-to-b-21-raiders-broad-spectrum-stealth/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:40:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lazavik Beats Carlsen; Murzin, Sargsyan, Dominguez, Naroditsky Lead Open - Chess.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lazavik Beats Carlsen; Murzin, Sargsyan, Dominguez, Naroditsky Lead Open</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Chess.com</p><figure><img src="https://images.chesscomfiles.com/uploads/v1/images_users/tiny_mce/AnthonyLevin/php5hoKzO.jpg" alt="The Open playing hall. Photo: Lennart Ootes/FIDE." width="1575" height="2048"><figcaption>The Open playing hall. Photo: Lennart Ootes/FIDE.</figcaption></figure><p>The 2024 FIDE World Rapid Chess Championship is underway, showcasing fierce competition among top chess players, including an upset where GM Denis Lazavik defeated Magnus Carlsen. After five rounds, GMs Volodar Murzin, Shant Sargsyan, Leinier Dominguez, and Daniel Naroditsky lead the Open section.</p><ul><li>Denis Lazavik defeats Magnus Carlsen, who is struggling with a score of 2.5/5.</li><li>Alice Lee leads the Women's championship with a perfect score of 4/4.</li><li>Strong performances by local players like Brewington Hardaway and Tani Adewumi.</li><li>The championship takes place in New York City, a historic first for FIDE's rapid tournaments.</li></ul><blockquote><p><strong>If he makes this comeback back into the event, we'll all be shocked.</strong><br>—Aman Hambleton on Magnus Carlsen</p></blockquote><p>The tournament has drawn significant attention as players compete not only for a shared prize fund of $1.5 million but also for ranking points in the FIDE Circuit, leading to the 2026 Candidates Tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championship-day-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championship-day-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh Death News Updates: ‘A setback for the whole nation,’ says PM Modi, calls former PM an ‘inspiration for coming generations’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manmohan Singh Death News Updates</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Manmohan_1c70f8.jpg?w=640" alt="Manmohan Singh" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Manmohan Singh was chosen to lead the United Progressive Alliance government in 2004 after the coalition romped home to a victory against the incumbent BJP-led National Democratic Alliance government. (Express Archive)</figcaption><p>Former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, a pivotal figure in India's economic reforms, has passed away at the age of 92. His death marks a significant loss for the nation, with senior leaders paying tribute at his residence in Delhi.</p><ul><li>Manmohan Singh passed away on Thursday evening in Delhi.</li><li>He served two terms as Prime Minister, with a notable economic reform legacy from 1991.</li><li>His last rites will be performed near Rajghat following tributes at AICC headquarters.</li></ul><blockquote>“A setback for the whole nation,” said PM Modi, calling him an “inspiration for coming generations.”</blockquote><p>This loss is felt across the nation, as Singh is remembered for his contributions to India's economic policies and governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/manmohan-singh-passes-away-live-updates-9745991/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/manmohan-singh-passes-away-live-updates-9745991/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:32:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh death latest updates: AAP convenor Arvind Kejriwal pays final respects to ex-PM - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manmohan Singh's Last Rites Announced Following His Death at 92</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/PTI12-27-2024-000006A-0_1735286529797_1735286538345.jpg" alt="Manmohan Singh Death News: Dr Manmohan Singh passed away at age 92" title="Manmohan Singh Death News: Dr Manmohan Singh passed away at age 92" width="360" height="202" loading="lazy" decoding="async">
<figcaption>Manmohan Singh Death News: Dr Manmohan Singh passed away at age 92</figcaption>
<p>Former Prime Minister Dr. Manmohan Singh passed away at the age of 92 at AIIMS, Delhi, on December 26, 2024. His last rites will be performed at Nigambodh Ghat in Delhi on December 28 at 11:45 AM.</p>
<ul>
<li>Dr. Singh was confirmed dead after being treated for age-related medical conditions at AIIMS.</li>
<li>His contributions as Prime Minister, particularly in economic reforms, have been highlighted across the nation.</li>
<li>The Congress Working Committee held a meeting to pay tribute to his legacy and contributions.</li>
<li>Leaders from across the political spectrum and global leaders expressed their condolences and shared memories of his tenure.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“His life and work profoundly shaped India's destiny,” said the Congress Working Committee.</blockquote>
<p>Dr. Singh's passing marks a significant moment in India's political history, with many expressing their admiration for his quiet yet impactful leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/manmohan-singh-death-live-updates-india-former-prime-minister-latest-news-today-101735233013066.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/manmohan-singh-death-live-updates-india-former-prime-minister-latest-news-today-101735233013066.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:31:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 Energy-Boosting Superfoods You Can't Miss - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>9 Energy-Boosting Superfoods You Can't Miss</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116708564/116708564.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=1330426" alt="9 Energy-Boosting Superfoods You Can't Miss">
<figcaption>Credit: iStock</figcaption>
<p>Feeling drained and sluggish? Revitalize yourself with these nine energy-boosting superfoods that can help power you through your day.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bananas:</strong> A powerhouse of quick-acting carbs, potassium, and vitamin B6, perfect for pre- or post-workout snacks.</li>
<li><strong>Oats:</strong> High in fiber and slow-releasing carbs, they provide long-lasting energy without spikes in blood sugar.</li>
<li><strong>Almonds:</strong> Rich in healthy fats, protein, and magnesium, they help fight fatigue and support muscle function.</li>
<li><strong>Spinach:</strong> Loaded with iron and B vitamins, it enhances oxygen flow to reduce tiredness.</li>
<li><strong>Sweet Potatoes:</strong> Packed with complex carbs and antioxidants, offering a steady energy release.</li>
<li><strong>Eggs:</strong> A complete source of protein and essential amino acids, helping to maintain energy levels throughout the day.</li>
<li><strong>Greek Yogurt:</strong> High in protein and probiotics, it keeps you full and aids digestion for sustained energy.</li>
<li><strong>Dark Chocolate:</strong> Contains flavonoids and caffeine that improve alertness and focus.</li>
<li><strong>Chia Seeds:</strong> Nutrient-dense, providing omega-3 fatty acids and a gradual energy release.</li>
</ul>
<p>Keep these superfoods in mind to boost your energy levels naturally!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/health/9-energy-boosting-superfoods-you-cant-miss/photostory/116708489.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/health/9-energy-boosting-superfoods-you-cant-miss/photostory/116708489.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ajit Agarkar To Speak To Rohit Sharma On Test Future, India Captain Might Retire If...: Report - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ajit Agarkar To Speak To Rohit Sharma On Test Future, India Captain Might Retire If...: Report</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> No specific date provided, Source: PTI</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116714223,thumbsize-46866,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116714223.jpg" alt="Ajit Agarkar To Speak To Rohit Sharma On Test Future, India Captain Might Retire If...:Report" title="Ajit Agarkar To Speak To Rohit Sharma On Test Future, India Captain Might Retire If...:Report"><figcaption>Photo: AP</figcaption><p>As India plays against Australia in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy, concerns are growing regarding Rohit Sharma's future in Test cricket after a string of poor performances.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma has scored just 19 runs in the series and 155 runs in 8 Tests at an average of 11.07.</li><li>Ajit Agarkar, the chairman of selectors, is expected to have a conversation with Rohit about his future in Test matches.</li><li>If India does not qualify for the World Test Championship 2025 final, the fifth Test may mark Rohit's last appearance in red-ball cricket.</li><li>Rohit felt uncomfortable batting in the middle order, leading to Shubman Gill's exclusion from the playing XI.</li><li>Rohit replaced KL Rahul in the opening spot, but was dismissed for just 5 runs in the match.</li></ul><blockquote>“His stay lasted only five balls, as he top-edged a short ball from Pat Cummins.”</blockquote><p>The future of Rohit Sharma in Test cricket hangs in the balance as selectors assess performance ahead of key tournaments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/ajit-agarkar-to-speak-to-rohit-sharma-on-test-future-india-captain-might-retire-if-india-fail-to-qualify-for-wtc-2025-final-report-article-116711358</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/ajit-agarkar-to-speak-to-rohit-sharma-on-test-future-india-captain-might-retire-if-india-fail-to-qualify-for-wtc-2025-final-report-article-116711358</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:28:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24: Non-food items lead household spending trends; rent major contributor - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Consumption Expenditure Survey 2023-24: Non-food items lead household spending trends; rent major contributor</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Ministry of Statistics and Programme Implementation</p> <p>The 2023-24 Consumption Expenditure Survey reveals a narrowing urban-rural gap in consumption expenditure, with non-food items dominating household spending.</p> <ul> <li>The urban-rural gap in monthly per capita consumption expenditure (MPCE) decreased to 70% in 2023-24.</li> <li>Average MPCE was ₹4,122 in rural and ₹6,996 in urban areas, rising to ₹4,247 and ₹7,078 when including government welfare benefits.</li> <li>Sikkim had the highest MPCE, while Chhattisgarh recorded the lowest.</li> <li>Non-food items account for 53% of rural and 60% of urban household expenditures.</li> <li>The Gini coefficient for inequality declined in both rural (0.237) and urban (0.284) areas.</li> <li>Rent constitutes around 7% of urban non-food expenditure.</li></ul> <blockquote>“Rent with a share of around 7% is another major constituent of households’ non-food expenditure in urban India.”</blockquote> <p>Overall, the survey highlights significant trends in consumption patterns and a decrease in inequality, impacting economic indicators such as GDP and CPI.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/business-news/economy/consumption-expenditure-survey-2023-24-non-food-items-lead-household-spending-trends-rent-major-contributor/article-137312/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/business-news/economy/consumption-expenditure-survey-2023-24-non-food-items-lead-household-spending-trends-rent-major-contributor/article-137312/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:22:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Market Wrap, December 27: SENSEX, NIFTY50 gain 1% this week; auto, healthcare stocks rally - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Market Wrap, December 27: SENSEX, NIFTY50 gain 1% this week; auto, healthcare stocks rally</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Stock Market News</p><p>The bulls maintained an upper hand in the stock market as both the S&P BSE SENSEX and NSE's NIFTY50 gained approximately 1% this week after previous declines.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>S&P BSE SENSEX closed at 78,699.07, up 0.29%.</li><li>NSE NIFTY50 index settled at 23,813.40, up 0.27%.</li><li>Major buying observed in auto and healthcare sectors.</li><li>This week’s gains follow a 5% drop last week, influenced by US Federal Reserve's rate projections.</li><li>Top gainers included Dr Reddy's, IndusInd Bank, and M&M.</li><li>Top losers included Hindalco Industries and SBI.</li></ul><h2>Market Statistics:</h2><ul><li>4,087 stocks traded on BSE; 2,026 fell while 1,948 advanced.</li><li>155 stocks hit 52-week highs; 72 hit one-year lows.</li></ul><h2>Buzzing Stocks:</h2><ul><li>Greaves Cotton shares reached 20% upper circuit limit due to IPO fundraising plans.</li><li>Mamata Machinery listed at a 146.91% premium.</li><li>Sagility India shares rose to an all-time high after 9 consecutive sessions of growth.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/market-wrap-december-27-sensex-nifty-50-gain-1-this-week-auto-healthcare-stocks-rally/article-137311/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/market-wrap-december-27-sensex-nifty-50-gain-1-this-week-auto-healthcare-stocks-rally/article-137311/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:16:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Veiled Dig At Gautam Gambhir? On Yashasvi Jaiswal Run-Out, Australia Star's 'Coach Killer' Remark - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxQOFdxLVo2OGNYeGtNV2xkaFZSbkFLYTZYdG94QW9melRoYlN5ck9NZ2M5VVhxWG4wQmRTM2lTc2MxMFo2N1FOaFpEaVJac3BSd1d0NHVuM2hRS3RRTEloTlNsTkdKekFwX21GR2R2eEJPRGgxalVNeElPRmg0T1llMWw4bGlRY0JmdUw4TkpRYlRMLWktd0tSNUVrclZLRGZzMDhlWV9aRVNSbGVTQV9qWUtMaGp5c0Vrd2Q5LXl0akxlYmtob2V6ei1aTHlYRHBNdEV0c1JtRzNrSHJxSGFqbWpOcGNDZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxQOFdxLVo2OGNYeGtNV2xkaFZSbkFLYTZYdG94QW9melRoYlN5ck9NZ2M5VVhxWG4wQmRTM2lTc2MxMFo2N1FOaFpEaVJac3BSd1d0NHVuM2hRS3RRTEloTlNsTkdKekFwX21GR2R2eEJPRGgxalVNeElPRmg0T1llMWw4bGlRY0JmdUw4TkpRYlRMLWktd0tSNUVrclZLRGZzMDhlWV9aRVNSbGVTQV9qWUtMaGp5c0Vrd2Q5LXl0akxlYmtob2V6ei1aTHlYRHBNdEV0c1JtRzNrSHJxSGFqbWpOcGNDZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:11:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ark's Cathie Wood calls for tax clarity as she rides 'Trump bump' | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cathie Wood Urges Tax Clarity from Trump's Administration</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27<br><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><p>Cathie Wood, a prominent U.S. tech investor, is advocating for clarity on tax policies from Donald Trump's incoming administration. She believes backdating tax cuts to January 1, 2025, would stimulate economic growth.</p><ul><li>Wood's ARK Innovation ETF has surged 17% post-Trump's victory, outperforming the S&P500.</li><li>Key holdings Tesla and Coinbase have seen significant increases in their stock prices since November.</li><li>Wood supports Trump's economic platform, advocating for reduced tariffs and tax cuts.</li><li>Analysts expect a push for tax reform by the new Congress, with Trump poised to use executive orders to implement policies.</li><li>Wood has not financially supported Trump but maintains contact with key figures like Elon Musk and Senator Cynthia Lummis.</li></ul><blockquote>“I see them saying, okay, we're going to cut taxes but we will make them retroactive to Jan. 1, 2025. That would be very helpful, I think, in terms of providing certainty for the markets.” - Cathie Wood</blockquote><p>Wood believes that while the market's initial excitement may fade, innovation-driven sectors will benefit in the long run.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/arks-cathie-wood-calls-for-tax-clarity-as-she-rides-trump-bump-11735297280849.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/arks-cathie-wood-calls-for-tax-clarity-as-she-rides-trump-bump-11735297280849.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:01:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diabetes in cats, dogs: symptoms, treatment, and how to ensure they remain healthy - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diabetes in cats, dogs: symptoms, treatment, and how to ensure they remain healthy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A<br><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><figure><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-68.png?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Diabetes in cats, dogs: symptoms, treatment, and how to ensure they remain healthy"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Diabetes isn’t just a human concern—it also affects our beloved pets. Dogs and cats can develop diabetes mellitus, a condition that affects how their body processes glucose. With proper care, monitoring, and early intervention, pets with diabetes can still live happy and fulfilling lives.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Diabetes in pets can manifest as excessive thirst, frequent urination, increased appetite, and weight loss.</li><li>Types of diabetes include Type 1 (common in dogs) and Type 2 (more common in cats).</li><li>Early diagnosis through blood tests and urine analysis is key to effective management.</li><li>Treatment involves insulin therapy, dietary changes, and regular exercise.</li><li>Pet owners play a crucial role in monitoring and managing their pets' diabetes.</li></ul><blockquote>"With the right support, diabetes doesn’t have to be a barrier to a fulfilling life for dogs and cats."</blockquote><p>While diabetes in pets is a serious condition, it is manageable with proper care, medication, and lifestyle changes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/health/diabetes-in-cats-dogs-symptoms-treatment-and-how-to-ensure-they-remain-healthy-7497114/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/health/diabetes-in-cats-dogs-symptoms-treatment-and-how-to-ensure-they-remain-healthy-7497114/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>