<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:17:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:17:07 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jio's 5.5G arrives in India, offering 1 Gbps speed on OnePlus 13 Series smartphones - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jio's 5.5G arrives in India, offering 1 Gbps speed on OnePlus 13 Series smartphones</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert publication date here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert source here]</p><img src='https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/jio-5-1736318204.webp' alt='Jio 5.5G' width='1200' height='675'><figcaption>Jio 5.5G</figcaption><p>OnePlus has launched the OnePlus 13 Series in India, featuring advanced AI capabilities and the first smartphones to support Jio's 5.5G technology.</p><ul><li>The OnePlus 13 Series includes OnePlus 13 and OnePlus 13R models.</li><li>5.5G technology allows devices to connect to multiple network cells simultaneously.</li><li>Impressive downlink speeds of 1,014.86 Mbps achieved on Jio's 5.5G network.</li><li>5.5G is a step up from traditional 5G, promising better speeds, lower latency, and improved reliability.</li></ul><blockquote>"The cutting-edge 5.5G technology enables faster connectivity and improved overall performance." - James Paterson, Senior Global PR Manager at OnePlus</blockquote><p>This launch marks a significant step in India's technological advancements, enhancing connectivity and user experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/jio-s-5-5g-arrives-in-india-offering-1-gbps-speed-on-oneplus-13-series-smartphones-2025-01-08-970173</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/jio-s-5-5g-arrives-in-india-offering-1-gbps-speed-on-oneplus-13-series-smartphones-2025-01-08-970173</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:38:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICC rates SCG pitch as 'satisfactory' - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICC rates SCG pitch as 'satisfactory'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Wed, Jan 8, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p><img height="396" width="595" alt="The SCG Test lasted less than three days." title="The SCG Test lasted less than three days." src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c597923/the-scg-test-lasted-less-than.jpg"><figcaption>The SCG Test lasted less than three days. © AFP</figcaption><p>The Sydney Cricket Ground (SCG) pitch, used for the recent fifth and final Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy (BGT), has received a 'Satisfactory' rating from the International Cricket Council (ICC). The world body has rated all other four BGT venues as 'Very Good.'</p><ul><li>The SCG pitch faced criticism for its condition, lasting less than three days.</li><li>Only 191 overs were bowled, with 685 runs scored and 15 wickets falling on the second day.</li><li>Cricket Australia noted improvements towards achieving a more competitive surface.</li><li>Former players, including Sunil Gavaskar and Usman Khawaja, heavily criticized the pitch conditions.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is not the ideal Test match pitch that you want because you want it to go into a fourth and fifth day.” - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote><p>The ICC pitch ratings indicate a need for further improvements at SCG to meet international standards, ensuring more competitive and enduring matches in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/133055/icc-rates-scg-pitch-as-satisfactory</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/133055/icc-rates-scg-pitch-as-satisfactory</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:35:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA proposes cheaper, quicker way to get Mars rocks and soil to Earth - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Proposes Cheaper and Faster Method to Retrieve Mars Samples</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Tuesday, March 6, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC</p>
<img alt="NASA proposes cheaper, quicker way to get Mars rocks and soil to Earth" title="NASA proposes cheaper, quicker way to get Mars rocks and soil to Earth" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" decoding="async" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360">
<figcaption>NASA proposes a revised plan to return samples from Mars.</figcaption>
<p>NASA has unveiled a new plan aimed at returning rock and soil samples from Mars in a more cost-effective and timely manner, after previous estimates soared to $11 billion.</p>
<ul>
<li>NASA's Administrator Bill Nelson presented the revised plan, which aims to ensure samples from Mars are returned by the 2030s.</li>
<li>The previous plan was deemed too expensive and projected returns by 2040 or later.</li>
<li>New options are estimated to cost between $6 billion to $7 billion and involve innovative designs by commercial partners.</li>
<li>The mission aims to return 30 titanium tubes containing samples collected by the Perseverance rover.</li>
<li>Both proposed options will clean the sample tubes on Mars before the return journey to Earth.</li>
<li>NASA is considering a traditional landing method with a sky crane or a private company-developed system.</li>
<li>The final decision on the plan will be made after engineering studies are completed next year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We want to return 30 titanium tubes as soon as possible at the cheapest price.” - Bill Nelson</blockquote>
<p>The revised proposals reflect an urgent need to move forward with Mars exploration, emphasizing efficiency in the sample return process while adapting to budget constraints.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/science/nasa-proposes-cheaper-quicker-way-to-get-mars-rocks-and-soil-to-earth-19536411.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/science/nasa-proposes-cheaper-quicker-way-to-get-mars-rocks-and-soil-to-earth-19536411.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:26:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CES 2025: Panasonic's new flagship OLED TV has Amazon Fire TV built-in - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CES 2025: Panasonic's New Flagship OLED TV With Amazon Fire TV Built-In</h1><p><strong>Date: January 2025 | Source: Business Standard</strong></p><p>The Panasonic Z95B Series OLED TV, launched at CES 2025, integrates Amazon Fire TV, Apple AirPlay, and advanced display technology for an enhanced viewing experience.</p><ul><li>Available in 55-inch, 65-inch, and 77-inch sizes</li><li>Features Primary RGB Tandem display for brighter visuals</li><li>Powered by HCX Pro AI Processor MK II with 4K Remaster Engine</li><li>Supports Dolby Vision IQ and Dolby Atmos</li><li>Integrates live streaming with Amazon Fire TV for content discovery</li><li>Compatible with Apple AirPlay and Home</li><li>Enhanced for gaming with support for AMD FreeSync and NVIDIA G-SYNC</li></ul><blockquote>“The Z95B series introduces Calman and ISFccc calibration, delivering professional-grade tools to fine-tune colour accuracy and display performance.”</blockquote><p>The Panasonic Z95B Series OLED TV aims to elevate home entertainment by integrating cutting-edge technology and streaming capabilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/ces-2025-panasonic-s-new-flagship-oled-tv-has-amazon-fire-tv-built-in-125010800376_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/ces-2025-panasonic-s-new-flagship-oled-tv-has-amazon-fire-tv-built-in-125010800376_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:17:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yash stuns with his swag in TOXIC birthday Peek - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yash Stuns with His Swag in TOXIC Birthday Peek</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Wednesday</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/toxic21736316436.jpg" alt="Yash stuns with his swag in TOXIC birthday Peek"><figcaption>Yash in his swag as seen in the birthday peek.</figcaption><p>Yash celebrated his 39th birthday by treating fans to a surprise video from his upcoming film "Toxic - A Fairy Tale for Grown-Ups" on Instagram.</p><ul><li>The 25-second video features Yash dressed in a retro white suit and fedora, making a bold entrance in a club.</li><li>Director Geetu Mohandas describes the film as unconventional, aiming to provoke thought and emotion.</li><li>The teaser presents Yash in a light that emphasizes his commanding presence and artistic vision.</li><li>Mohandas expresses admiration for Yash's creative process and the film's transformative narrative.</li></ul><blockquote>“When you let go of who you are, you become what you might be” - Rumi.</blockquote><p>This film, co-produced by Venkat K. Narayana and Yash, promises a unique cinematic experience that transcends cultural boundaries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/yash-stuns-with-his-swag-in-toxic-birthday-peek-143285</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/yash-stuns-with-his-swag-in-toxic-birthday-peek-143285</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:07:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“HMPV not a threat”: Health experts urge as 7 HMPV virus cases reported in India in 2 days - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>“HMPV not a threat”: Health experts urge as 7 HMPV virus cases reported in India in 2 days</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117041312,imgsize-1277744,width-400,resizemode-4/117041312.jpg" alt="HMPV not a threat”>
<figcaption>“HMPV not a threat”: Health experts urge caution</figcaption>
<p>Health experts have reported seven cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in India in just two days, but they urge the public not to panic as the virus typically causes mild infections.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Five cases were reported recently, primarily affecting infants and toddlers.</li>
  <li>Former AIIMS chief Dr. Randeep Guleria emphasized that HMPV is a common virus that is self-limiting.</li>
  <li>Union Health Minister JP Nadda reassured that health authorities are monitoring the situation closely.</li>
  <li>WHO notes that HMPV is common during winter and spring, with no unusual outbreak patterns reported.</li>
  <li>States are preparing measures to tackle any potential outbreak while advising the public to remain calm.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It is not a very worrying virus. It is not the one that is prevalent in China.” - Karnataka Chief Minister Siddaramaiah</blockquote>
<p>The overall consensus among health officials is to maintain vigilance but also to practice normal safety measures without inducing fear.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/hmpv-virus-in-india-hmpv-not-a-threat-health-experts-urge-as-5-hmpv-virus-cases-reported-in-india-in-2-days/articleshow/117041335.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/hmpv-virus-in-india-hmpv-not-a-threat-health-experts-urge-as-5-hmpv-virus-cases-reported-in-india-in-2-days/articleshow/117041335.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nitin Gadkari announces nationwide cashless treatment scheme for road accident victims - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitin Gadkari announces nationwide cashless treatment scheme for road accident victims</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/uvuz6d/article68687703.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI09_26_2024_000152A.jpg" alt="Minister Nitin Gadkari addressing the seminar"/><figcaption>Bengaluru: Union Minister for Road Transport & Highways Nitin Gadkari addresses an international seminar on ‘Advances in Bridge Management’ organised by Indian Roads Congress, in Bengaluru, Karnataka, Thursday, Sept. 26, 2024. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>The Central government is set to implement a cashless treatment scheme for road accident victims, allowing up to ₹1.5 lakh per person for medical care.</p><ul><li>The scheme will be applicable for all road accidents involving motor vehicles.</li><li>The National Health Authority will coordinate the implementation with various agencies.</li><li>It will function via a new IT platform integrating existing applications for accident management.</li><li>The pilot programme previously launched in Chandigarh will be expanded nationwide by March 2025.</li><li>Additional discussions on driver fatigue and vehicle safety measures were highlighted during the recent workshop.</li></ul><blockquote>“The broad contours of the pilot programme are -- victims entitled to cashless treatment up to a maximum of ₹1.5 lakh per accident per person for a maximum period of 7 days from the date of the accident.” - Nitin Gadkari</blockquote><p>This initiative aims to provide timely medical assistance to accident victims across India, addressing critical needs in emergency response.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/nitin-gadkari-announces-modified-cashless-treatment-scheme-for-road-accident-victims-nationwide/article69075166.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/nitin-gadkari-announces-modified-cashless-treatment-scheme-for-road-accident-victims-nationwide/article69075166.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Unpacked: Pre-reserve open for Galaxy S25 series in India - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-pre-reserve-open-for-galaxy-s25-series-in-india-125010800302_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-pre-reserve-open-for-galaxy-s25-series-in-india-125010800302_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:23:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Unpacked: Pre-reserve open for Galaxy S25 series in India - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-pre-reserve-open-for-galaxy-s25-series-in-india-125010800302_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-pre-reserve-open-for-galaxy-s25-series-in-india-125010800302_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:23:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13R launched in India at Rs.42999: Check out specifications and features - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13R Launched in India at Rs. 42999: Specifications and Features</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/13r_1736313475717_1736313485295.png" alt="OnePlus 13R launched in India with a starting price of just Rs.42999. (OnePlus)" /><figcaption>OnePlus 13R launched in India with a starting price of just Rs.42999. (OnePlus)</figcaption></figure><p>The OnePlus 13R has officially launched in India, aimed at the mid-range smartphone market with impressive specifications and features.</p><ul><li>Powered by Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 SoC</li><li>Equipped with a 6000mAh battery</li><li>Features a 50MP telephoto lens and a 6.77-inch ProXDR display</li><li>Offers up to 16GB RAM and 512GB storage</li><li>Price starts at Rs. 42999 with sales commencing on January 13, 2025</li></ul><blockquote>“The new-gen has a new processor, a telephoto lens instead of a macro lens, a better battery, and a pleasing design.”</blockquote><p>The OnePlus 13R is positioned as a strong competitor in the mid-range smartphone segment, providing significant upgrades over its predecessor.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/oneplus-13r-launched-in-india-at-rs-42999-check-out-specifications-and-features-101736313452409.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/oneplus-13r-launched-in-india-at-rs-42999-check-out-specifications-and-features-101736313452409.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:21:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Railways unveils Vande Bharat, specially designed for winters in J-K, for Katra-Srinagar route - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQUFlXeVBmbmIzODZWX25jaHVIdTJRVHI3NzJrckU5QnBBTm9kY0ZUb29tX1RlUkN2SnNUdXRKbUZ6MzVJYWZ5Rm5iYTlzTDgzcmJGbTFsYjlaaGZORVFSMWRpT1RXZ3A0WXlvMkJyYlBhdmw0X0pPSHJVVkxHOW1aVnlZeVhndF9SYjl0NG9JX2gzeDd6SV9yUG1raWl3U0Vybl9wd2piVHZNSURWXzVBQm9ub0ZyME1IOTZtek5qbm9FdGJGMVVwWXRxLWUxQjZvVFHSAdcBQVVfeXFMT0d2LU1MckJ6V0xuaTBha29ENkJGUmhZUy11M0JaYVJjWWh2cFVwS0FzLUZGeHN1dmVjUUlNcnhGVHdmQUdmeUttUXdXN2RHa2JfVVVwUy1zdUJBbkhfRGlCQTZObWRNNWZGYi1TZEk0Ty1jX08zQkNFZ2xpUzZ4RnFxbXlodmVWNGpRMHZwSVpmYm1CYVQzZllrLWFFbkpGMVdlYXRjall1UzZNdURESkRWSW1Ea1VkckgzcVpBcjlHZGk1cmxBc2o1VGxMS0dzR3c2ZDEySzA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQUFlXeVBmbmIzODZWX25jaHVIdTJRVHI3NzJrckU5QnBBTm9kY0ZUb29tX1RlUkN2SnNUdXRKbUZ6MzVJYWZ5Rm5iYTlzTDgzcmJGbTFsYjlaaGZORVFSMWRpT1RXZ3A0WXlvMkJyYlBhdmw0X0pPSHJVVkxHOW1aVnlZeVhndF9SYjl0NG9JX2gzeDd6SV9yUG1raWl3U0Vybl9wd2piVHZNSURWXzVBQm9ub0ZyME1IOTZtek5qbm9FdGJGMVVwWXRxLWUxQjZvVFHSAdcBQVVfeXFMT0d2LU1MckJ6V0xuaTBha29ENkJGUmhZUy11M0JaYVJjWWh2cFVwS0FzLUZGeHN1dmVjUUlNcnhGVHdmQUdmeUttUXdXN2RHa2JfVVVwUy1zdUJBbkhfRGlCQTZObWRNNWZGYi1TZEk0Ty1jX08zQkNFZ2xpUzZ4RnFxbXlodmVWNGpRMHZwSVpmYm1CYVQzZllrLWFFbkpGMVdlYXRjall1UzZNdURESkRWSW1Ea1VkckgzcVpBcjlHZGk1cmxBc2o1VGxMS0dzR3c2ZDEySzA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:04:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Is Trump Threatening To Take Greenland, Panama Canal, Canada? His Imperialist Agenda Explained - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-is-trump-threatening-to-take-greenland-panama-canal-canada-his-imperialist-agenda-explained-9181542.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-is-trump-threatening-to-take-greenland-panama-canal-canada-his-imperialist-agenda-explained-9181542.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Is Trump Threatening To Take Greenland, Panama Canal, Canada? His Imperialist Agenda Explained - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-is-trump-threatening-to-take-greenland-panama-canal-canada-his-imperialist-agenda-explained-9181542.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-is-trump-threatening-to-take-greenland-panama-canal-canada-his-imperialist-agenda-explained-9181542.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Oh Canada!’: Donald Trump shares distorted unified US-Canada map, Justin Trudeau's Liberal Party responds - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-distorted-unified-us-canada-map-justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-responds-101736311061282.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-distorted-unified-us-canada-map-justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-responds-101736311061282.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:47:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Oh Canada!’: Donald Trump shares distorted unified US-Canada map, Justin Trudeau's Liberal Party responds - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-distorted-unified-us-canada-map-justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-responds-101736311061282.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-distorted-unified-us-canada-map-justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-responds-101736311061282.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:47:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Game Will Stagnate...": India Team Management Member Warns Rohit Sharma, Virat Kohli - Report - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"Game Will Stagnate...": India Team Management Member Warns Rohit Sharma, Virat Kohli - Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8bnni5p_virat-kohli-rohit-sharma-x_625x300_30_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Rohit Sharma and Virat Kohli"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma and Virat Kohli © AFP</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team's poor performance during the Test series against Australia has led to criticisms, especially towards the senior players Rohit Sharma and Virat Kohli. A team management source emphasizes the need for these players to actively engage in domestic cricket to regain their form.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma scored only 31 runs in three matches and dropped himself from the final Test.</li><li>Virat Kohli struggled throughout the series, finishing with just 190 runs at an average of under 24.</li><li>Suggestions from cricket legends Sunil Gavaskar and Irfan Pathan encourage playing domestic games for better preparation.</li><li>A member of the team management highlighted the importance of regularly playing longer formats to avoid stagnation in their game.</li></ul><blockquote>“Without game time in the middle, their game will stagnate…”</blockquote><p>Ravi Shastri weighs in on Kohli and Sharma's current situations, noting Kohli's issues with spin and technical faults. He believes that Kohli can still contribute significantly if he shares his experience with younger players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/game-will-stagnate-india-team-management-member-warns-rohit-sharma-virat-kohli-report-7424971</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/game-will-stagnate-india-team-management-member-warns-rohit-sharma-virat-kohli-report-7424971</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:47:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles wildfire: Pacific Palisades declares emergency, President Joe Biden approves aid | Updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wildfire in Pacific Palisades Forces 30,000 to Evacuate</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-70_1736307148546_1736307193321.jpg" alt="Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)" title="Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)"><figcaption>Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>A dangerous wildfire has ravaged the Pacific Palisades area of Los Angeles, destroying nearly 3,000 acres of land and forcing over 30,000 residents to evacuate. The situation has been exacerbated by hurricane-force winds.</p><ul><li>The fire erupted midmorning amid seasonal Santa Ana winds.</li><li>Firefighters are working on the ground and from the air to contain the blaze.</li><li>As of Tuesday evening, over 28,300 households were without power.</li></ul><blockquote>“There are no immediate reports of any deaths or injuries.” - Kristin Crowley, Chief of Los Angeles Fire Department</blockquote><p>This wildfire marks a significant emergency in the region, prompting federal aid approval from President Joe Biden.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:30:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[V. Narayanan, who is set to take over as ISRO Chairman, terms his new assignment ‘a great responsibility’ - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>V. Narayanan Set to Lead ISRO with Great Responsibility</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/kerala/p9rmlm/article69075001.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/nara1.jpg" alt="V. Narayanan, who will take over as ISRO Chairman from January 14, poses near a model of the Chandrayaan-3 moon lander." title="V. Narayanan, who will take over as ISRO Chairman from January 14, poses near a model of the Chandrayaan-3 moon lander."><figcaption>V. Narayanan, who will take over as ISRO Chairman from January 14, poses near a model of the Chandrayaan-3 moon lander.</figcaption><p>V. Narayanan, a rocket propulsion expert, will take over as the Chairman of ISRO on January 14, 2025. He describes this new role as a significant responsibility and opportunity to lead ISRO during a transformative time in India's space sector.</p><ul><li>Succeeds S. Somanath as ISRO Chairman.</li><li>ISRO has several major projects lined up including Gaganyaan, Chandrayaan-4, and an Indian space station.</li><li>Dr. Narayanan emphasizes the importance of increasing India's presence in space and the role of private sector reforms in achieving this goal.</li><li>He has a substantial background in rocket propulsion, having been with ISRO since 1984.</li></ul><blockquote>“Towards January-end we have the GSLV Mk-II/IRNSS-1 K mission... we have our hands full.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Dr. Narayanan's extensive experience and vision for reform will be crucial as ISRO embarks on its ambitious future projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/v-narayanan-who-is-set-to-take-over-as-isro-chairman-terms-his-new-assignment-as-a-great-responsibility/article69075005.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/v-narayanan-who-is-set-to-take-over-as-isro-chairman-terms-his-new-assignment-as-a-great-responsibility/article69075005.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ramesh Bidhuri to be replaced? Unease in BJP ahead of Delhi election: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unease in BJP Over Ramesh Bidhuri's Controversial Remarks Ahead of Delhi Elections</h1><p><strong>January 08, 2025</strong> - <strong>Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Ramesh-Bidhuri---ANI-_1736303205780_1736303230986.jpg" alt="BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri. (ANI)(HT_PRINT)"><figcaption>BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri. (ANI)(HT_PRINT)</figcaption><p>BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri’s recent controversial remarks about Delhi chief minister Atishi and Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra have sparked a backlash, leading to discussions within the party about replacing him with a woman candidate for the upcoming assembly election.</p><ul><li>There have been at least two organisational meetings regarding Bidhuri's candidacy.</li><li>His remarks led to a reprimand from BJP leader JP Nadda.</li><li>Potential women replacements for Bidhuri are being discussed.</li><li>Bidhuri commented on Atishi's family name change, which drew criticism.</li></ul><blockquote>“Not just against Atishi, Rameshji’s statement on Priyanka Gandhi Vadra led to his being reprimanded by Naddaji within minutes,” a BJP source stated.</blockquote><p>The situation highlights internal tensions in the BJP as it prepares for the February 5 assembly election.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ramesh-bidhuri-to-be-replaced-unease-in-bjp-ahead-of-delhi-election-report-101736299967107.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ramesh-bidhuri-to-be-replaced-unease-in-bjp-ahead-of-delhi-election-report-101736299967107.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:11:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SEBI ‘warning’ letter on social media to Ola CEO Bhavish Aggarwal: You have failed to … - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SEBI Warns Ola CEO Bhavish Aggarwal on Social Media Compliance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 23, 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/109343604.cms" alt="Ola logo"><figcaption>Ola's CEO Bhavish Aggarwal.</figcaption><p>The Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) issued a warning letter to Ola CEO Bhavish Aggarwal regarding the company's non-compliance with social media guidelines. The regulatory body highlighted concerns over the misleading information shared through various platforms.</p><ul><li>SEBI's concern stems from multiple reports of customer grievances that went unaddressed.</li><li>Ola's rapid expansion has raised questions about its commitment to regulatory standards.</li><li>This warning could have implications for other tech companies operating in India.</li></ul><blockquote>'Businesses must adhere to the highest standards of transparency and accountability,' stated a SEBI official.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, moving forward, it will be crucial for Ola to enhance its communication strategies and ensure compliance with regulatory frameworks to maintain its reputation in the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/sebi-warning-letter-on-social-media-to-ola-ceo-bhavish-aggarwal-you-have-failed-to-/articleshow/117040668.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/sebi-warning-letter-on-social-media-to-ola-ceo-bhavish-aggarwal-you-have-failed-to-/articleshow/117040668.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Body Recovered From Inundated Coal Mine In Assam, Several Still Trapped - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Body Recovered From Inundated Coal Mine In Assam, Several Still Trapped</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>A body was recovered from a coal mine in Assam's Dima Hasao, two days after water gushed into it, trapping nine workers.</p><ul><li>Rescue operations are ongoing involving 21 Para Divers, navy, army, NDRF, and SDRF personnel.</li><li>Divers conducted a recce before entering the quarry to retrieve the body.</li><li>De-watering pumps have been deployed to help with the rescue efforts.</li><li>Chief Minister Himanta Biswa Sarma indicated the mine may be illegal and announced an arrest in connection to the incident.</li><li>The water level inside the quarry has risen to nearly 100 feet.</li></ul><blockquote>“The mine appears to be illegal,” said Chief Minister Himanta Biswa Sarma.</blockquote><p>Rescue operations are expected to be further supported by a team from Coal India starting Wednesday.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/body-recovered-from-inundated-coal-mine-in-assam-several-still-trapped-7424717</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/body-recovered-from-inundated-coal-mine-in-assam-several-still-trapped-7424717</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:48:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Body recovered from Assam coal mine; efforts on to trace others - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Body Recovered from Assam Coal Mine; Ongoing Search for Others</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/The-workers-are-believed-to-be-trapped-300-feet-un_1736308059537.jpg" alt="The workers are believed to be trapped 300 feet under the ground in the flooded coal mine. (PTI)"><figcaption>The workers are believed to be trapped 300 feet under the ground in the flooded coal mine. (PTI)</figcaption><p>Rescuers recovered a body early on Wednesday from the coal mine in Assam’s Dima Hasao district nearly 48 hours after at least nine workers were trapped there due to flooding.</p><ul><li>Rescue teams are led by divers from various agencies, including the army and navy.</li><li>A total of nine to fifteen workers are believed to be trapped in the mine.</li><li>The mine appears to be operating illegally, leading to one arrest and charges of culpable homicide.</li><li>Rescue operations are complicated by ongoing rainfall in the area.</li></ul><blockquote>“21 Para divers have just recovered a lifeless body from the bottom of the well. Our thoughts and prayers are with the grieving family,” Assam Chief Minister Himanta Biswa Sarma posted on X.</blockquote><p>The recovery operation continues amid considerable uncertainties regarding the number of trapped workers and the conditions they face.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/body-recovered-from-assam-coal-mine-efforts-on-to-trace-others-101736308066541.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/body-recovered-from-assam-coal-mine-efforts-on-to-trace-others-101736308066541.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:47:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Divers Recover Body From Inundated Coal Mine In Assam, Many Still Trapped - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Divers Recover Body From Inundated Coal Mine In Assam, Many Still Trapped</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>A body was recovered from a coal mine in Assam's Dima Hasao, two days after water gushed into it, trapping nine workers. 21 Para Divers retrieved one body from the bottom of the mine's well in Umrangso's 3 Kilo, while navy, army, NDRF and SDRF personnel continued rescue operations.</p><ul><li>Divers from Visakhapatnam conducted a recce before entering the quarry.</li><li>Rescue operations include de-watering pumps from SDRF and ONGC, with the latter poised for deployment.</li><li>Chief Minister Himanta Biswa Sarma announced Coal India's involvement in the rescue efforts.</li><li>Trapped workers were identified, and investigations suggest the mine may be illegal.</li></ul><blockquote>The Navy team is now spearheading the rescue efforts. — Himanta Biswa Sarma (@himantabiswa)</blockquote><p>This tragic incident highlights the dangers associated with illegal mining operations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/body-recovered-from-inundated-coal-mine-in-assam-several-still-trapped-7424717</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/body-recovered-from-inundated-coal-mine-in-assam-several-still-trapped-7424717</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:44:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka opt to field in 37-overs-a-side contest after long rain delay - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Theekshana hat-trick keeps NZ to 255</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p><p>An impressive performance by Maheesh Theekshana, who claimed a hat-trick, restricted New Zealand to a total of 255 runs in the first ODI against Sri Lanka, after a solid partnership between Rachin Ravindra and Mark Chapman.</p><ul><li>New Zealand scored 255 for 9, with Ravindra top-scoring with 79 and Chapman contributing 62 runs.</li><li>A 112-run partnership between Ravindra and Chapman formed the backbone of the innings.</li><li>Theekshana's late hat-trick brought New Zealand's innings to a close, finishing with figures of 4 for 44.</li><li>Sri Lanka's fielding was exceptional, highlighted by Charith Asalanka's athletic catch.</li><li>Ravindra and Chapman showcased effective run-scoring, particularly through leg-side shots.</li></ul><blockquote>“What was most impressive about the Ravindra-Chapman stand was how comfortable both batters made brisk run-scoring appear.”</blockquote><p>The match highlights the competitive spirit and potential of Sri Lanka, even as New Zealand set a challenging total.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2024-25-1443537/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2nd-odi-1443547/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2024-25-1443537/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2nd-odi-1443547/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:28:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tibet earthquake aftermath: Thousands of homes destroyed, 126 killed as rescue efforts continue - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tibet earthquake aftermath: Thousands of homes destroyed, 126 killed as rescue efforts continue</h1><p><strong>Published: January 08, 2025 08:53 am IST</strong></p><p><strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/v6jbl5/article69075120.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/tibet.jpg" alt="Rescue efforts in Tibet" /><figcaption>Rescue efforts in Tibet</figcaption><p>A powerful 7.1 magnitude earthquake struck Tibet, leading to significant destruction and loss of life, with multiple rescue operations ongoing to find survivors trapped under rubble.</p><ul><li>The earthquake occurred on January 7, 2025, with its epicenter in Tingri, Tibet, about 80 km north of Mount Everest.</li><li>More than 400 people have been rescued from trapped locations, with over 30,000 residents relocated.</li><li>At least 126 casualties have been reported, with 188 injured on the Tibetan side of the border.</li><li>3,609 homes were destroyed, impacting a population of around 800,000 in the Shigatse region.</li><li>Rescue teams face challenges due to freezing temperatures dropping to minus 18 degrees Celsius.</li><li>An extensive aftershock sequence has been noted, with over 500 aftershocks recorded post-earthquake.</li></ul><blockquote>"More than 500 aftershocks with magnitudes of up to 4.4 had followed the quake…"</blockquote><p>The ongoing rescue efforts and relief operations are crucial in addressing the aftermath of this devastating earthquake and ensuring the safety of affected residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/tibet-earthquake-several-killed-houses-destroyed-updates-january-8/article69074939.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/tibet-earthquake-several-killed-houses-destroyed-updates-january-8/article69074939.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viral video: NASA astronaut shares rare footage of 'flying over aurora', but skeptics call it ‘fake’ - Indiatimes.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nasa astronaut shares rare footage of 'flying over aurora', but skeptics call it ‘fake’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indiatimes</p><p><img src='https://im.indiatimes.in/content/2023/Oct/big-test-min_6528266ce9a76.jpeg?w=32&h=32&cc=1&webp=1&q=75' alt='Aurora' /><figcaption>A breathtaking view captured by the NASA astronaut.</figcaption></p><p>A recent video shared by a NASA astronaut showcases an aurora from the International Space Station, stirring awe and skepticism among viewers.</p><ul><li>The astronaut shared a mesmerizing video showing the aurora's dark green hues, which many found stunning.</li><li>Despite the widespread admiration, some viewers claimed the video appeared fake and suggested it could be artificially generated.</li><li>The aurora phenomenon occurs when solar particles interact with the Earth's atmosphere, creating spectacular light displays.</li><li>The aurora near the North Pole is called Aurora Borealis, while the one near the South Pole is known as Aurora Australis.</li></ul><blockquote>“Flying over aurora; intensely green.” — Don Pettit</blockquote><p>The debate continues on social media about the authenticity of the footage, with some praising its beauty and others questioning its legitimacy.</p><p>This incident highlights the persistent skepticism around space visuals and calls for an increased dialogue about authenticity in visual technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatimes.com/trending/social-relevance/viral-video-nasa-astronaut-shares-rare-footage-of-flying-over-aurora-649971.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatimes.com/trending/social-relevance/viral-video-nasa-astronaut-shares-rare-footage-of-flying-over-aurora-649971.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:20:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earth’s Rotation Day 2025 Messages and Images: Netizens Share Posts, Quotes, Wishes, and Wallpapers to - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AJBVV95cUxPZW9UeldscFczbTBTcld5MEZDOTA3TEYtakFoRDZEMzcwSWUxQWJMYnRzc1ZIZHdtTS02eTNlWUxyLW9TeE1ZanNjYzFkSHZOYm0xX1J3UUs2eHAyQ1BZOWpScVdtX0FuZ0hoVFZIZVRFS3A4RHc1OGJ1cnVtRmNSaXM2eV9VdFFQdjAxLVNfT2tKdkRtbVlwTElpLWhUb2ZnamJCbzVsb2NVZV8tcW0wTGZBUUxvdFVpaWRzNGw2TmhzYlRpanZXZVNVTHVSSjJrSnVqX1ptdWpoVjhiSUNYYjl2eUZ3MFI5bWczUFBSbXBTU0dlQVZQSFNYbnI1Vloza0FpN3l1LTA4YjhDanhWTm1xSXRGR3REeWRGZ0dLYWY2aHlqLVMtbVNZbG82c3gwSzRsZW5YVTdFUFVYY1VqTmZyWjdQamFyWFd4WnZKaGNPRUZEMUpqYlNmMzVSS2Jx0gHmAkFVX3lxTE51b2V1XzdibjlsX0VMZUdZOERDNHdBWk5EWERaN3lTZUp6ZnNYaVlZSzlKMDYzQVhOZzlUbjYzYzJhRlp1MTUtb3NOQ08tdFNDcFZKV2dNZ3JiRnhnYi10S0ljekl0Mi1SSkVjTmxhSFg2blUtQTM1M0J0LXd0OVlMZ196MzFQZ3l5clFTQ2N6NTJqblhuUWx1cm9wWnlGOThjcW9keEZMaTBCWE8zc1RpbGt0Wlo3MXFJRHl3dUQtWXB2ME9zUmpEZHBKTGpTTDVQN1JtTE9PNWFvd1hyZ0xQcS1nSms2WFpzTU9FSVNjNXhQWEFURXFwZThMeExaTWlfX082YUFpbWVnc0k3UWFaaGJfZzVnLVZBWjkyM0U2cTFrdHNvd2U5MWw0WjF4dE93cWtDM2RYZkI5YXlobExneUFxSF90ZXphb2plYUFpWW1iS0tPZkdRdXFfWFgzeVhKbHZKLXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AJBVV95cUxPZW9UeldscFczbTBTcld5MEZDOTA3TEYtakFoRDZEMzcwSWUxQWJMYnRzc1ZIZHdtTS02eTNlWUxyLW9TeE1ZanNjYzFkSHZOYm0xX1J3UUs2eHAyQ1BZOWpScVdtX0FuZ0hoVFZIZVRFS3A4RHc1OGJ1cnVtRmNSaXM2eV9VdFFQdjAxLVNfT2tKdkRtbVlwTElpLWhUb2ZnamJCbzVsb2NVZV8tcW0wTGZBUUxvdFVpaWRzNGw2TmhzYlRpanZXZVNVTHVSSjJrSnVqX1ptdWpoVjhiSUNYYjl2eUZ3MFI5bWczUFBSbXBTU0dlQVZQSFNYbnI1Vloza0FpN3l1LTA4YjhDanhWTm1xSXRGR3REeWRGZ0dLYWY2aHlqLVMtbVNZbG82c3gwSzRsZW5YVTdFUFVYY1VqTmZyWjdQamFyWFd4WnZKaGNPRUZEMUpqYlNmMzVSS2Jx0gHmAkFVX3lxTE51b2V1XzdibjlsX0VMZUdZOERDNHdBWk5EWERaN3lTZUp6ZnNYaVlZSzlKMDYzQVhOZzlUbjYzYzJhRlp1MTUtb3NOQ08tdFNDcFZKV2dNZ3JiRnhnYi10S0ljekl0Mi1SSkVjTmxhSFg2blUtQTM1M0J0LXd0OVlMZ196MzFQZ3l5clFTQ2N6NTJqblhuUWx1cm9wWnlGOThjcW9keEZMaTBCWE8zc1RpbGt0Wlo3MXFJRHl3dUQtWXB2ME9zUmpEZHBKTGpTTDVQN1JtTE9PNWFvd1hyZ0xQcS1nSms2WFpzTU9FSVNjNXhQWEFURXFwZThMeExaTWlfX082YUFpbWVnc0k3UWFaaGJfZzVnLVZBWjkyM0U2cTFrdHNvd2U5MWw0WjF4dE93cWtDM2RYZkI5YXlobExneUFxSF90ZXphb2plYUFpWW1iS0tPZkdRdXFfWFgzeVhKbHZKLXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:13:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ola Electric shares in focus after SEBI warns of disclosure norm violations - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNeGRfUjBaYUx6eGVWT1F2d3pHWDgtTjFCT0FtM1pvSlp0ZDExRmR5bC1wYVlBeENBc1cyOGtCWUlJYTVwRlVocmI0TTZtNDdXWU9reVRTbmw4SUNNYXczOVVyajVvZmgtWUpSRzV6cGo0REs0eW15VV9rZ3FEdXAtaXlZNXJudDBKeHZXNC1qdUM2dFd5eWFrYk5Td1JGR09pSGhjZ1B2RVNxaTE2WE5SNXZ0Wng5VE5WNjl2UDB2QUF2ZjlabWcxUlBlNk1sRmpfN2dES1p6R3NqbWk5cm1xc29ZWdIB6AFBVV95cUxNa0hKNXV6NFBFdlA2V0U3SU9saHhGN04tUGI1aE1kczFYNFFnMVBIVnpyS3Q4STFpTVBVX1FMRHJGVG9NYy0xbXJFSlU0djZaUzRGUEFXUHZxci00bkEta1FWUnhNLTBCQWZ5YTZua25pMGE2cTdYNC1LNjRZanhWdHdwY0lZT1FKMnpDYXlZa1o1dnVxbjE4ZVZIUjIySF9zSnhMNy0zOTN3NnJsQUFUT25qZlhTV3hyNjJzZkhXcl80UkJwNkJlVDM4V3F4NVMxOWl4ZDMtWDFnQkpjVmI0bmlYcWI2bWpa?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNeGRfUjBaYUx6eGVWT1F2d3pHWDgtTjFCT0FtM1pvSlp0ZDExRmR5bC1wYVlBeENBc1cyOGtCWUlJYTVwRlVocmI0TTZtNDdXWU9reVRTbmw4SUNNYXczOVVyajVvZmgtWUpSRzV6cGo0REs0eW15VV9rZ3FEdXAtaXlZNXJudDBKeHZXNC1qdUM2dFd5eWFrYk5Td1JGR09pSGhjZ1B2RVNxaTE2WE5SNXZ0Wng5VE5WNjl2UDB2QUF2ZjlabWcxUlBlNk1sRmpfN2dES1p6R3NqbWk5cm1xc29ZWdIB6AFBVV95cUxNa0hKNXV6NFBFdlA2V0U3SU9saHhGN04tUGI1aE1kczFYNFFnMVBIVnpyS3Q4STFpTVBVX1FMRHJGVG9NYy0xbXJFSlU0djZaUzRGUEFXUHZxci00bkEta1FWUnhNLTBCQWZ5YTZua25pMGE2cTdYNC1LNjRZanhWdHdwY0lZT1FKMnpDYXlZa1o1dnVxbjE4ZVZIUjIySF9zSnhMNy0zOTN3NnJsQUFUT25qZlhTV3hyNjJzZkhXcl80UkJwNkJlVDM4V3F4NVMxOWl4ZDMtWDFnQkpjVmI0bmlYcWI2bWpa?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:13:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘All hell will break…’: Donald Trump warns Hamas as he sets deadline for hostages' release - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Issues Stark Warning to Hamas Over Hostages Ahead of Inauguration</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Jan 08, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US-PRESIDENT-ELECT-TRUMP-HOLDS-PRESS-CONFERENCE-AT_1736303409052_1736303409570.jpg" alt="Donald Trump also refused to rule out the use of military force to take control of the Panama Canal(Getty Images via AFP)" title="Donald Trump also refused to rule out the use of military force to take control of the Panama Canal(Getty Images via AFP)">
<figcaption>Donald Trump also refused to rule out the use of military force to take control of the Panama Canal(Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption>
<p>US President-elect Donald Trump delivered a stern warning during a press conference in Florida, stating “all hell will break out in the Middle East” if Hamas does not release its hostages in Gaza before his inauguration on January 20.</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump's warning highlights the escalating tensions in the Middle East regarding the hostage situation.</li>
<li>He expressed that the situation would be detrimental not only to Hamas but to everyone involved.</li>
<li>Trump appointed Steve Witkoff as special envoy to the Middle East, who noted a cautiously optimistic view on ceasefire talks.</li>
<li>The Biden administration officials are reportedly leading negotiations, with Trump’s team being kept informed.</li>
<li>Trump also hinted at the potential use of military force regarding territorial claims over the Panama Canal and Greenland.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It will not be good for Hamas and it will not be good, frankly, for anyone. All hell will break out.” - Donald Trump</blockquote>
<p>The press conference reflects Trump's aggressive stance on foreign policy and his ongoing involvement in international negotiations prior to taking office.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/all-hell-will-break-donald-trump-warns-hamas-as-he-sets-deadline-for-hostages-release-january-20-inauguration-101736303112432.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/all-hell-will-break-donald-trump-warns-hamas-as-he-sets-deadline-for-hostages-release-january-20-inauguration-101736303112432.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:03:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah's Champions Trophy fate in balance - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah's Champions Trophy Fate in Balance</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> CHENNAI <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117038838,imgsize-35554,width-400,resizemode-4/117038838.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah's Champions Trophy fate in balance" title="Jasprit Bumrah" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah during a match.</figcaption><p>The future of pacer Jasprit Bumrah for the upcoming Champions Trophy hangs in the balance after he suffered injury during a Test match in Sydney. His condition will determine his participation in the tournament set to begin on February 20 in Dubai.</p><ul><li>Bumrah suffered back spasms during the Test match, affecting his ability to bowl.</li><li>The provisional squad for the Champions Trophy will be announced soon.</li><li>If Bumrah's injury is a simple spasm, he may recover in time; a stress fracture would mean a longer rehabilitation.</li><li>Former players and trainers have differing opinions on whether Bumrah will be fit.</li><li>The condition of Bumrah's back will be closely monitored by his medical team.</li></ul><blockquote>"It does depend on the final diagnosis of the injury. Back spasm is normally an orange light, it tells you that something worse could be in store..."</blockquote><p>Jasprit Bumrah's ability to recover from this injury is crucial not only for the Champions Trophy but also for the upcoming IPL season, where his performance will be critical for Mumbai Indians.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/jasprit-bumrahs-champions-trophy-fate-in-balance/articleshow/117038804.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/jasprit-bumrahs-champions-trophy-fate-in-balance/articleshow/117038804.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>