<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 19:13:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 19:13:32 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Parker Solar Probe Makes History With Closest Pass to Sun - Science@NASA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe Makes History With Closest Pass to Sun</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NASA Science</p>
<img src="https://science.nasa.gov/_nuxt/404-bg.B-eOJ4h_.jpg" alt="NASA Parker Solar Probe" />
<figcaption>Parker Solar Probe image</figcaption>
<p>The Parker Solar Probe has accomplished a historic milestone by making the closest-ever approach to the Sun.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Parker Solar Probe traveled within a remarkable distance of the Sun's surface.</li>
  <li>This mission aims to gather data on solar winds and the Sun's atmosphere.</li>
  <li>The probe's findings could enhance understanding of solar behavior and its impact on Earth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This mission represents a groundbreaking achievement in solar exploration,” said a NASA spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>This event marks a significant step in space exploration, providing insights that could shape future solar research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://science.nasa.gov/science-research/heliophysics/nasas-parker-solar-probe-makes-history-with-closest-pass-to-sun/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://science.nasa.gov/science-research/heliophysics/nasas-parker-solar-probe-makes-history-with-closest-pass-to-sun/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 18:22:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Parker Solar Probe survives close brush with Sun’s scorching surface - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxNbkZMRmlraHZheC1SNDJ2enpTckJiNk93blJDdF9iVmZqQlFuck9OX3plV3JmOFkwbFpwQ0RKMERwXzJWVzBDamVLUDJaLUdpV2dQc1g5Wlk1TEVFSHAzMmNsU2YtM2pyaGZrbGE1R24yWVNzRzYyc2RsQlV6b09Ya2hxLVJhU3MwWGpKRWU2YXdhRE1pZHNidFR1Rlk0QXZCZHZHTzlxTFBDTk5BMUtneGpKdC01N1I0ZDFiOUpwZVNvLUt1WWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxNbkZMRmlraHZheC1SNDJ2enpTckJiNk93blJDdF9iVmZqQlFuck9OX3plV3JmOFkwbFpwQ0RKMERwXzJWVzBDamVLUDJaLUdpV2dQc1g5Wlk1TEVFSHAzMmNsU2YtM2pyaGZrbGE1R24yWVNzRzYyc2RsQlV6b09Ya2hxLVJhU3MwWGpKRWU2YXdhRE1pZHNidFR1Rlk0QXZCZHZHTzlxTFBDTk5BMUtneGpKdC01N1I0ZDFiOUpwZVNvLUt1WWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:28:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blood transfusions can help save heart attack patients with anemia: Study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Blood transfusions can help save heart attack patients with anemia: Study</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> NEJM Evidence</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116721814,imgsize-44544,width-400,resizemode-4/116721814.jpg" alt="Blood transfusions can help save heart attack patients with anemia: Study"><figcaption>Blood transfusions can save lives for heart attack patients with anemia.</figcaption><p>A recent study indicates that blood transfusions are life-saving for anemic individuals after a heart attack, showing a reduced risk of death within six months for those receiving more transfusions.</p><ul><li>Anemia affects about one-third of congestive heart failure cases and raises heart attack risk.</li><li>Patients with fewer transfusions had a 9.3% death rate within 30 days compared to 8.1% for those receiving more transfusions.</li><li>Heart-related deaths were 5.5% for fewer transfusions vs. 3.7% for those with more transfusions.</li><li>Over 4,300 patients' data from four trials were analyzed for the study.</li></ul><blockquote>“The results of this analysis show that giving more blood to anemic patients with heart attacks can save lives at six months.” - Dr. Jeffrey Carson</blockquote><p>While blood transfusions can significantly benefit anemic heart attack patients, caution is advised due to potential risks such as infection or fluid buildup.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/blood-transfusions-can-help-save-heart-attack-patients-with-anemia-study/articleshow/116721765.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/blood-transfusions-can-help-save-heart-attack-patients-with-anemia-study/articleshow/116721765.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Parker Solar Probe ‘safe’ after record-breaking brush with scorching surface, ‘phones home’ after several days | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe ‘safe’ after record-breaking brush with scorching surface, ‘phones home’ after several days</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent Update | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>The Parker Solar Probe has successfully survived its closest approach to the Sun, reaching within 6 million kilometers of the star’s surface. NASA confirmed that the spacecraft is safe and continues to operate normally after its historic flyby.</p><ul><li>The Parker Solar Probe flew within 3.8 million miles (approximately 6 million kilometers) of the solar surface, marking the closest approach ever made by a human-made object.</li><li>The probe reported back to NASA on December 26, confirming its health and operational status after a brief period of silence during the flyby.</li><li>Launched in 2018, the Parker Solar Probe aims to study the Sun’s corona and the solar wind, contributing to our understanding of solar dynamics.</li><li>The spacecraft is equipped with a heat shield capable of withstanding temperatures up to 1370°C.</li><li>Scientists are hopeful that data collected during this mission will illuminate longstanding questions regarding the Sun's atmospheric temperatures and dynamics.</li></ul><blockquote>“Parker Solar Probe has phoned home! After passing just 3.8 million miles from the solar surface... we have received Parker Solar Probe’s beacon tone confirming the spacecraft is safe,” NASA stated.</blockquote><p>The successful operations and data collection from the Parker Solar Probe contribute valuable insights into solar physics, aiming to unravel mysteries about the Sun that affect space weather and, by extension, life on Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/news/nasas-parker-solar-probe-safe-after-record-breaking-brush-with-scorching-surface-phones-home-after-several-days-11735315988675.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/news/nasas-parker-solar-probe-safe-after-record-breaking-brush-with-scorching-surface-phones-home-after-several-days-11735315988675.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IDF launches new raid on north Gaza hospital, asserting Hamas operatives returned - The Times of Israel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesofisrael.com/idf-launches-new-raid-on-north-gaza-hospital-asserting-hamas-operatives-returned/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesofisrael.com/idf-launches-new-raid-on-north-gaza-hospital-asserting-hamas-operatives-returned/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:58:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh’s funeral at Nigambodh ghat, Congress calls it deliberate insult to first Sikh PM - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manmohan Singh’s funeral at Nigambodh ghat, Congress calls it deliberate insult to first Sikh PM</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 27, 2024 - <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ogmcjb/article69034679.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241227232L.jpg" alt="Congress leaders paid their last respects to former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh, who passed away at the age of 92, at Bidhan Bhavan in Kolkata on Friday." title="Congress leaders paid their last respects to former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh, who passed away at the age of 92, at Bidhan Bhavan in Kolkata on Friday."><figcaption>Congress leaders paid their last respects to former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh.</figcaption><p>The Ministry of Home Affairs has ordered a State funeral for former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh at Nigambodh Ghat, which has sparked controversy with the Congress party calling it a deliberate insult to Singh's legacy.</p><ul><li>Dr Manmohan Singh passed away at the age of 92.</li><li>The Congress demanded a funeral location suitable for a memorial.</li><li>The decision for Nigambodh Ghat was made after discussions between Congress leaders and government officials.</li><li>Senior Congress leaders expressed that the choice of location is viewed as disrespectful.</li><li>Dr Singh was a highly revered figure, recognized for his significant contributions to India.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is nothing but a deliberate insult to the first Sikh Prime Minister of India, Dr. Manmohan Singh,” said Congress communication chief Jairam Ramesh.</blockquote><p>The government's decision has sparked a broader discussion about how national leaders are honored in death and the significance of memorials for their contributions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manmohan-singhs-final-journey-on-december-28-cremation-at-nigambodh-ghat/article69034552.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manmohan-singhs-final-journey-on-december-28-cremation-at-nigambodh-ghat/article69034552.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby John box office collection day 3: Varun Dhawan film fails to sustain opening day momentum - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baby John box office collection day 3: Varun Dhawan film fails to sustain opening day momentum</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/Baby-John_1735312525353_1735312533741.jpeg" alt="Baby John box office collection day 3: The action thriller is a a remake of Theri." title="Baby John box office collection day 3: The action thriller is a a remake of Theri." /><figcaption>Baby John box office collection day 3: The action thriller is a remake of Theri.</figcaption></figure><p>Varun Dhawan's latest outing, Baby John, initially had a promising box office performance but has seen a significant decline in collections over the first three days.</p><ul><li>Baby John opened on Christmas with a strong day one collection of ₹11.25 crore.</li><li>By day three, collections dropped to ₹3.65 crore, totaling ₹19.65 crore (nett).</li><li>The film suffered a 57.78% decline in collections from day one to day two.</li><li>Despite being Varun's biggest opening in five years, the film is struggling against competition from other releases.</li></ul><blockquote>“Overall, there’s nothing much that makes Baby John stand out apart from the action.”</blockquote><p>The film's decline in box office performance highlights the challenges faced by new releases in a competitive market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/baby-john-box-office-collection-day-3-varun-dhawan-film-fails-to-sustain-opening-day-momentum-101735312510105.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/baby-john-box-office-collection-day-3-varun-dhawan-film-fails-to-sustain-opening-day-momentum-101735312510105.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani Re-Release Box Office: 9.97 Crores Away From Achieving A Milestone, Ranbir Kapoor & Deepika Padukone’s Blockbuster - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani Re-Release Box Office: 9.97 Crores Away From Achieving A Milestone</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p>
<img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/yeh-jawaani-hai-deewani-box-office.jpg" alt="Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani Re-Release Box Office: To Achieve A Big Milestone?" width="1200" height="630">
<figcaption>Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani Re-Release Box Office: To Achieve A Big Milestone? (Photo Credit – Instagram)</figcaption>
<p>For all Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani Hai fans, there’s exciting news as the modern-age cult romantic drama is all set to re-release in theatres. The film is tremendously popular, and over the years, it has built a loyal fan base. No doubt it will enjoy a solid response from the moviegoers amid the trend of re-releases. And if it manages to rake in 9.97 crores at the Indian box office, it will achieve a big milestone. Keep reading to know about the milestone!</p>
<ul>
<li>Directed by Ayan Mukerji, the film originally starred Ranbir Kapoor, Deepika Padukone, Aditya Roy Kapur, and Kalki Koechlin.</li>
<li>The film was a major success upon its original release in 2013, amassing 190.03 crore net at the Indian box office.</li>
<li>The re-release is set for January 3, 2025, coinciding with the trend of successful Bollywood film re-releases.</li>
<li>The film needs 9.97 crores to achieve the 200 crore milestone.</li>
<li>Box office numbers are estimates and have not been independently verified.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"If Yeh Jawaani Hai Deewani gets a good screen/show count and meets a good response from the audience, it’ll be able to hit big numbers."</blockquote>
<p>Stay tuned to Koimoi for more box office stories & updates!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/yeh-jawaani-hai-deewani-re-release-box-office-9-97-crores-away-from-achieving-a-milestone-ranbir-kapoor-deepika-padukones-blockbuster/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/yeh-jawaani-hai-deewani-re-release-box-office-9-97-crores-away-from-achieving-a-milestone-ranbir-kapoor-deepika-padukones-blockbuster/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:35:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DGCA suspends two top officials at Akasa Air over “training lapses” - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>DGCA Suspends Two Akasa Air Officials Over Training Lapses</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/iw7ov4/article69034466.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_FILE_PHOTO__An_Akasa_2_1_DODECEL2.jpg" alt="Photo used for representation purpose only." title="Photo used for representation purpose only." /><figcaption>Photo used for representation purpose only. | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>The Directorate General of Civil Aviation (DGCA) has suspended the head of operations and head of training at Akasa Air for six months due to training lapses related to the use of an uncertified simulator for pilot training.</p><ul><li>DGCA conducted a regulatory audit that revealed significant training violations.</li><li>Capt. Floyd Gracious and Neeraj Bhatia are suspended and must be replaced by suitable candidates.</li><li>Previous fines and penalties for Akasa Air indicate ongoing compliance issues.</li></ul><blockquote>The DGCA noted that the airline's response to earlier violations was unsatisfactory.</blockquote><p>This suspension highlights the ongoing scrutiny faced by Akasa Air concerning pilot training and operational compliance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/dgca-suspends-two-top-officials-at-akasa-air-over-training-lapses/article69034349.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/dgca-suspends-two-top-officials-at-akasa-air-over-training-lapses/article69034349.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan lose their way after Bosch bash hands South Africa advantage - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxOUmJxNzhpazgxamtVanBWM2IxTHZWVVl5Sk9TNUIxeTBkSEtldkxUY2Z5Ni1hZFRqSDRzMFYxOC1qNFpFdnRSeFp6X3B1Y1VKWm1CVVIzamdON2s1VEZ6d3ZKY0YtRnMwLXpBcDNtcnJzMFdDZVJ6NXNBYWZ0TUtVaDhsdEpaN2xxV25CNVdaRHpJVXl3V2NGeXIxYzZJeU1fdWdkTzU1dnNqUEZOR0VWcEs4WlRUR0JEOUs1SzJDU0NsckRRYnJEOGxRTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxOUmJxNzhpazgxamtVanBWM2IxTHZWVVl5Sk9TNUIxeTBkSEtldkxUY2Z5Ni1hZFRqSDRzMFYxOC1qNFpFdnRSeFp6X3B1Y1VKWm1CVVIzamdON2s1VEZ6d3ZKY0YtRnMwLXpBcDNtcnJzMFdDZVJ6NXNBYWZ0TUtVaDhsdEpaN2xxV25CNVdaRHpJVXl3V2NGeXIxYzZJeU1fdWdkTzU1dnNqUEZOR0VWcEs4WlRUR0JEOUs1SzJDU0NsckRRYnJEOGxRTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:33:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Societal inequality may reduce brain health: Study - The Hans India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxNOEtSY0pYV3JWNUVGbFdENGNiYk5zWXAxUWxNbFN2WUU0clBZaUNKMzJkcWtTNWk2RUJRQWxHMThDNkhYV0V4eXJMWmtjQVZTTm03OUZBWEZGcEl2RktlSi15WWYzVjNTRXktdEM3WWVEVGJYR21qS0dLYzRBWDdoS25CZ24tY19SQWphNjY2alhRNzFt0gGaAUFVX3lxTE5xNkFEcU1HbWRzRjJVcmwzM2VWOFBrX1ZIMUE5aG54VTJPZjZHTUNvdW5NaG9jaG83S29tRnZaQlRYbmV2Rk1iekFmQkxqNkhUajFuYXYzenlRU2lyajUtSnR3dVJxQmlNZG1hNE0zc1NpQ29CNmNaT3B3Z2xKVkNCTk5fbFFCeThqZUNBU3dnaGt3d0FLLVJPa3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxNOEtSY0pYV3JWNUVGbFdENGNiYk5zWXAxUWxNbFN2WUU0clBZaUNKMzJkcWtTNWk2RUJRQWxHMThDNkhYV0V4eXJMWmtjQVZTTm03OUZBWEZGcEl2RktlSi15WWYzVjNTRXktdEM3WWVEVGJYR21qS0dLYzRBWDdoS25CZ24tY19SQWphNjY2alhRNzFt0gGaAUFVX3lxTE5xNkFEcU1HbWRzRjJVcmwzM2VWOFBrX1ZIMUE5aG54VTJPZjZHTUNvdW5NaG9jaG83S29tRnZaQlRYbmV2Rk1iekFmQkxqNkhUajFuYXYzenlRU2lyajUtSnR3dVJxQmlNZG1hNE0zc1NpQ29CNmNaT3B3Z2xKVkNCTk5fbFFCeThqZUNBU3dnaGt3d0FLLVJPa3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:15:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Societal inequality may reduce brain health: Study - Morung Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxNdE81SzRNaTd2TGduU2NFY0I0Ni1pMlprMHpBemJidVNWak5BQThLZTNSOGI2eUJRaDVCRGxkRTRBQzRodVZ3ZXM2RW0teUFWLUl5Ty1XV0ItbVpQdXdEc1I1S1lXNExHUFhma0NWQVVGdUpHdDdLUXNOMG9uaHVLVw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxNdE81SzRNaTd2TGduU2NFY0I0Ni1pMlprMHpBemJidVNWak5BQThLZTNSOGI2eUJRaDVCRGxkRTRBQzRodVZ3ZXM2RW0teUFWLUl5Ty1XV0ItbVpQdXdEc1I1S1lXNExHUFhma0NWQVVGdUpHdDdLUXNOMG9uaHVLVw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:58:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JSW Neo Energy to acquire O2 Power at enterprise value of $1.47 billion | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JSW Neo Energy to Acquire O2 Power for $1.47 Billion</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>JSW Neo Energy, a subsidiary of JSW Energy Ltd, is set to acquire O2 Power at an enterprise value of $1.47 billion, subject to necessary approvals.</p>
<ul>
  <li>O2 Power has a capacity of 4.7 GW in renewable energy.</li>
  <li>The ownership of O2 Power is currently held by EQT and Temasek, who will exit after the acquisition.</li>
  <li>This acquisition will increase JSW Neo Energy's planned generation capacity by 23%.</li>
  <li>JSW Energy aims to strengthen its position in the Indian energy sector with this deal.</li>
  <li>CEO Parag Sharma expressed excitement about the new partnership and focus on renewable energy goals.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This marks the beginning of the next phase for O2 Power... We look forward to working with JSW Neo Energy for the next phase.” - Parag Sharma, CEO of O2 Power</blockquote>
<p>The acquisition signifies a strategic expansion for JSW Neo Energy in the renewable sector, aligning with India's energy goals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/jsw-neo-energy-o2-power-acquisition-renewable-energy-thermal-power-power-generation-capacity-cci-11735306895620.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/jsw-neo-energy-o2-power-acquisition-renewable-energy-thermal-power-power-generation-capacity-cci-11735306895620.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:55:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Driver who killed 35 in China car ramming sentenced to death - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Man Sentenced to Death for China Car Ramming Attack that Killed 35</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: Today, Source: State Media</strong></p><img src="https://example.com/image_url" alt="Fan Weiqiu" width="300" height="200"><figcaption>Fan Weiqiu, the convicted driver</figcaption><p>A man who deliberately drove through a crowd of people exercising outside a sports complex in Zhuhai, China, killing 35, has been sentenced to death. The 62-year-old, Fan Weiqiu, was found guilty of venting his anger over a broken marriage and personal frustrations. The attack, which occurred on November 11, was the deadliest in China since 2014.</p><ol><li>The defendant was tried and sentenced on the same day, with the court citing the extreme nature of the crime and its severe consequences.</li><li>Fan pleaded guilty in front of victims' families, officials, and members of the public.</li><li>The attack has sparked anger and discussion online, with some calling for immediate execution.</li></ol><blockquote>Fan decided to vent his anger over a broken marriage and personal frustrations, leading to the deadly attack.</blockquote><p>The sentencing comes amid a string of mass casualty incidents in China this year, challenging the country's reputation for good public security.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1881454/driver-who-killed-35-in-china-car-ramming-sentenced-to-death</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1881454/driver-who-killed-35-in-china-car-ramming-sentenced-to-death</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:53:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi pollution: CAQM revokes GRAP 3 measures as rain improves air quality - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Pollution: CAQM Revokes GRAP 3 Measures as Rain Improves Air Quality</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/PTI12-27-2024-000298A-0_1735310726237_1735310749963.jpg" alt="People move amid rain at Vijay Chowk, in New Delhi.(PTI)"><figcaption>People move amid rain at Vijay Chowk, in New Delhi.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Delhi's air pollution levels showed a declining trend, prompting the Centre's anti-pollution panel to revoke Stage 3 curbs under the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) due to improved air quality brought on by rain.</p><ul><li>The 24-hour average air quality index (AQI) was 324 at 7 PM.</li><li>CAQM stated that air quality shifted from 'severe' to 'poor', allowing the withdrawal of Stage 3 measures.</li><li>Stage 1 and 2 measures will remain in effect to prevent further deterioration.</li><li>The significant impact of rain is expected to continue improving air quality in the city.</li><li>GRAP Stage 3 included bans on non-essential construction, hybrid schooling for younger students, and restrictions on certain vehicles.</li></ul><blockquote>"Delhi's air quality has shifted from the 'severe' category to the 'poor' range. As a result, measures under Stage III, implemented earlier, are now being withdrawn." - CAQM</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the recent rainfall in Delhi has led to a notable improvement in air quality, prompting authorities to ease certain pollution control measures while maintaining vigilance to ensure continued air quality management.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-pollution-caqm-revokes-grap-3-measures-as-rain-improves-air-quality-101735310373594.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-pollution-caqm-revokes-grap-3-measures-as-rain-improves-air-quality-101735310373594.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:44:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13 vs Samsung Galaxy S25: Price In India, Launch Date, Specs And More - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 vs Samsung Galaxy S25: Price In India, Launch Date, Specs And More</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116718913/116718913.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=990505" alt="OnePlus 13 vs Samsung Galaxy S25" />
<figcaption>Credit: Times Now Digital</figcaption>
<p>This article compares the upcoming OnePlus 13 and Samsung Galaxy S25, discussing their specifications, expected prices in India, and launch dates.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The OnePlus 13 features a 6.82-inch quad-curved OLED display with 1440p and 120Hz refresh rate.</li>
  <li>Samsung Galaxy S25 is likely to come with a Dynamic AMOLED 2X LTPO display.</li>
  <li>Camera on OnePlus 13 includes a Hasselblad triple-camera setup with three 50MP sensors.</li>
  <li>Galaxy S25 may feature a 50MP primary camera alongside upgraded ultrawide and telephoto lenses.</li>
  <li>OnePlus 13 runs on Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chip and ColorOS 15.</li>
  <li>Galaxy S25 expected to use Snapdragon 8 Elite chip with One UI 7.1 based on Android 15.</li>
  <li>Battery capacity: OnePlus 13 has 6000 mAh with 100W wired and 50W wireless charging; Galaxy S25 may have a 4000 mAh battery with 25W charging.</li>
  <li>Expected launch price: OnePlus 13 Rs 67,000–70,000; Galaxy S25 starting at Rs 75,000.</li>
  <li>OnePlus 13 is set to launch on January 7, 2024, while Galaxy S25 on January 22, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The OnePlus 13 is expected to deliver powerful specs at a competitive price, while the Galaxy S25 continues Samsung's tradition of premium flagship devices."</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the competition between OnePlus and Samsung in the premium smartphone market is intensifying, with both devices promising exciting features for consumers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/oneplus-13-vs-samsung-galaxy-s25-price-in-india-launch-date-specs-and-more/photostory/116718876.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/oneplus-13-vs-samsung-galaxy-s25-price-in-india-launch-date-specs-and-more/photostory/116718876.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:39:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS 4th Test Match, Melbourne Weather Updates: Will rain impact India vs Australia Boxing Day Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS 4th Test Match, Melbourne Weather Updates: Will rain impact India vs Australia Boxing Day Test on Day 3?</h1><p><strong>Date: December 28, 2023</strong> | <strong>Source: Times of India</strong></p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116718718,imgsize-184236,width-400,resizemode-4/116718718.jpg" alt="Melbourne Cricket Ground" title="Melbourne Cricket Ground (AP Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Melbourne Cricket Ground (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>Day 3 of the 4th Test between India and Australia at the iconic Melbourne Cricket Ground could face disruptions due to rain, impacting the match's outcome.</p><ul><li>The visitors, India, are trailing by 310 runs, battling to avoid the follow-on.</li><li>There is a 79% chance of rain during the afternoon on December 28.</li><li>Showers are expected during the critical middle session; temperatures forecasted at 23°C and wind gusts up to 48 km/h.</li><li>Humidity at 58% could benefit swing bowlers, complicating batting conditions.</li><li>Steve Smith scored 140 for Australia, and Jasprit Bumrah took 4 wickets for India.</li><li>India ended Day 2 at 164/5, with Jaiswal scoring 82.</li></ul><blockquote>“The looming possibility of rain could halt their momentum and may even tempt Australia to enforce the follow-on if the situation demands.”</blockquote><p>As the match progresses, the unpredictable weather makes it crucial for India to capitalize while minimizing disruptions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-match-melbourne-weather-updates-will-rain-impact-india-vs-australia-boxing-day-test-on-day-3/articleshow/116718244.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-match-melbourne-weather-updates-will-rain-impact-india-vs-australia-boxing-day-test-on-day-3/articleshow/116718244.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech wrap Dec 27: Lava Yuva 2 launched, Redmi 14C, Samsung Galaxy Unpacked - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-wrap-dec-27-lava-yuva-2-launched-redmi-14c-samsung-galaxy-unpacked-124122700825_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-wrap-dec-27-lava-yuva-2-launched-redmi-14c-samsung-galaxy-unpacked-124122700825_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Audit reveals lapses: DGCA suspends two senior Akasa pilots in-charge of operations & training - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>DGCA Suspends Two Senior Akasa Pilots Over Audit Findings</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><img src='[Image not provided]' alt='Image of Akasa Airlines' /><div><p>An audit conducted by the DGCA has led to the suspension of two senior pilots from Akasa Airlines who were responsible for operations and training. The audit unveiled several lapses that necessitated immediate action to ensure safety in operations.</p><ul><li>The DGCA's audit revealed significant operational lapses.</li><li>The suspended pilots were in charge of training and operational oversight.</li><li>This action is part of a broader effort by the DGCA to enforce safety regulations in the aviation sector.</li></ul><blockquote>“Safety is our top priority, and these measures are essential to uphold our standards,” said a DGCA spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This suspension reflects the DGCA's commitment to maintaining high safety standards in the aviation industry, emphasizing its proactive role in oversight.</p></div>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/audit-reveals-lapses-dgca-suspends-two-senior-akasa-pilots-in-charge-of-operations-training/articleshow/116718537.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/audit-reveals-lapses-dgca-suspends-two-senior-akasa-pilots-in-charge-of-operations-training/articleshow/116718537.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress Seeks Space For Memorial To Manmohan Singh, Writes To PM - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Seeks Space For Memorial To Manmohan Singh, Writes To PM</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Congress Party Statement</p>
<p>Following the passing of former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, Congress chief Mallikarjun Kharge has reached out to Prime Minister Narendra Modi to discuss the possibility of building a memorial at the site of his last rites.</p>
<ul>
<li>Manmohan Singh passed away at the age of 92 due to age-related issues.</li>
<li>He served two terms as Prime Minister from 2004 to 2014 under the UPA government.</li>
<li>The last rites are scheduled to take place on December 28, 2024, at Nigambodh Ghat in Delhi.</li>
<li>Kharge emphasized that this request aligns with traditions of memorializing leaders at their funeral sites.</li>
<li>Singh is credited with vital economic reforms that greatly improved India's economic stability.</li>
<li>He had a significant role in ushering in various landmark policies like the NREGS and the RTI.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When the nation was in the throes of grave economic crisis, it was Dr. Manmohan Singh who took India out of the crisis and also led the country towards prosperity.” — Mallikarjun Kharge</blockquote>
<p>This request seeks to honor Singh's legacy as a statesman and a national leader.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/manmohan-singhs-last-rites-should-be-held-at-a-place-where-a-memorial-can-be-built-m-kharge-writes-to-pm-modi-7345275</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/manmohan-singhs-last-rites-should-be-held-at-a-place-where-a-memorial-can-be-built-m-kharge-writes-to-pm-modi-7345275</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:22:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' worldwide box office collection day 22: The Allu Arjun-Rashmika Mandanna starrer surpasses Rs - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Pushpa 2' Earns Over Rs 1719 Crore Worldwide in 22 Days</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116717155,imgsize-51404,width-400,resizemode-4/116717155.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 box office collection" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>'Pushpa 2' continues to break records at the box office.</figcaption>
<p>Pushpa 2, starring Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna, has surpassed Rs 1719 crore in worldwide box office collections by its 22nd day. The film, directed by Sukumar, is on track to possibly break Baahubali 2's record.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pushpa 2 has earned over Rs 1719.5 crore worldwide by day 22.</li>
  <li>The film grossed over Rs 1002 crore within the first 6 days.</li>
  <li>It crossed Rs 1400 crore in 11 days and reached Rs 1508 crore by day 14.</li>
  <li>After a tragic incident during its premiere, actor Allu Arjun and theatre management faced legal scrutiny.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There is no stopping #Pushpa2TheRule at the box office. Becomes the fastest Indian film to cross 1719.5 CRORES WORLDWIDE in 22 days.”</blockquote>
<p>As the film approaches Baahubali 2's record, audiences are eager to see if it will achieve even greater success in the weeks to come.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-22-the-allu-arjun-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-surpasses-rs-1719-crore/articleshow/116717155.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-22-the-allu-arjun-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-surpasses-rs-1719-crore/articleshow/116717155.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ola Electric’s CTO, CMO quit adding to top-level exodus - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxNcktTa3VfdFhRYVNMSTBTTktFeWVibVJwVDJvelNZQWtONnltRnh1S0xKTGpieGFLcUxhWG1ibGtGZHl5bFZETTNTbTNLbDhRX3lmb1BDQ3RaMXZEYmRoWkR1cmNMQ2JoWDItTXdnTEpqMGg3RzQzaE4zRzZoWHJOMGY3NzZZNkdOeWxYVXJpbXpTRW43dEJnX0dKb1I1c2QzVU1uYW9FYTJRY1VJTFMxWjlya1hCczZJMGVOOF9RbEHSAcYBQVVfeXFMTS1EUG9vbmtxRTVSMy1YQXEya291cTBWY1gxeWpJMnNsRGpNcGdoZEVXRXk0UjFKZlNpeWJCLXFueE42VGN2ZWt3S2xyd0tHWEZFMGxSOGV5TVZPLU9YdEJVbDhiREpZb1d3N2Vqdi1qOFpDQ3RvRl9zUmQwU3kxZFRYM1ZBQldsN1NiTHNIOElhUU5MaWMwa1IwaW1peW8td0FTT3FHckdnR01TQ0ZzQ1J4eWpKOXBINzVpMDQwV25za1JnLVlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxNcktTa3VfdFhRYVNMSTBTTktFeWVibVJwVDJvelNZQWtONnltRnh1S0xKTGpieGFLcUxhWG1ibGtGZHl5bFZETTNTbTNLbDhRX3lmb1BDQ3RaMXZEYmRoWkR1cmNMQ2JoWDItTXdnTEpqMGg3RzQzaE4zRzZoWHJOMGY3NzZZNkdOeWxYVXJpbXpTRW43dEJnX0dKb1I1c2QzVU1uYW9FYTJRY1VJTFMxWjlya1hCczZJMGVOOF9RbEHSAcYBQVVfeXFMTS1EUG9vbmtxRTVSMy1YQXEya291cTBWY1gxeWpJMnNsRGpNcGdoZEVXRXk0UjFKZlNpeWJCLXFueE42VGN2ZWt3S2xyd0tHWEZFMGxSOGV5TVZPLU9YdEJVbDhiREpZb1d3N2Vqdi1qOFpDQ3RvRl9zUmQwU3kxZFRYM1ZBQldsN1NiTHNIOElhUU5MaWMwa1IwaW1peW8td0FTT3FHckdnR01TQ0ZzQ1J4eWpKOXBINzVpMDQwV25za1JnLVlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:10:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA spacecraft Parker Solar Probe ‘safe’ after closest-ever approach to the Sun - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Parker Solar Probe Safely Completes Historic Close Approach to the Sun</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/SPACE-EXPLORATION-SUN-0_1735306250088_1735306353427.JPG" alt="A 2018 artist's concept shows the Parker Solar Probe spacecraft flying into the Sun's outer atmosphere, called the corona, on a mission to help scientists learn more about the Sun. (via REUTERS)"><figcaption>A 2018 artist's concept shows the Parker Solar Probe spacecraft flying into the Sun's outer atmosphere, called the corona, on a mission to help scientists learn more about the Sun. (via REUTERS)</figcaption><p>NASA's Parker Solar Probe has successfully completed its closest approach to the Sun, coming within 3.8 million miles (6.1 million km) of the solar surface and entering the corona. The spacecraft is reported to be in good health and operational.</p><ul><li>The Parker Solar Probe transmitted a beacon signal confirming its status after the record-breaking approach.</li><li>The mission aims to enhance understanding of how solar material heats to millions of degrees and the origin of solar wind.</li><li>Traveling at speeds of up to 430,000 mph, the probe endured extreme temperatures of 1,800°F (982°C).</li><li>Mission Operations Manager Nick Pinkine noted the unprecedented nature of the probe's journey into uncharted territory.</li></ul><blockquote>“This close-up study of the Sun allows Parker Solar Probe to take measurements that help scientists better understand how material in this region gets heated to millions of degrees.” – NASA</blockquote><p>This successful mission marks a significant step in solar exploration and understanding the dynamics of our nearest star.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/science/nasa-spacecraft-parker-solar-probe-safe-after-closest-ever-approach-to-the-sun-101735306115792.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/science/nasa-spacecraft-parker-solar-probe-safe-after-closest-ever-approach-to-the-sun-101735306115792.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:09:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JSW Neo Energy to Acquire O2 Power for ₹125 Billion - Mercom India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JSW Neo Energy to Acquire O2 Power for ₹125 Billion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Mercom India</p><img alt="thumbnail" src="https://d382rz2cea0pah.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/JSW-Neo-Energy-to-Acquire-O2-Power-for-%E2%82%B9125-Billion.jpg" decoding="async"><figcaption>JSW Neo Energy to Acquire O2 Power for ₹125 Billion</figcaption><p>JSW Neo Energy has entered into a definitive agreement to acquire a 4,696 MW renewable energy platform from O2 Power Pooling.</p><ul><li>The enterprise valuation of the platform is approximately ₹124.68 billion (~$1.46 billion).</li><li>The acquisition includes O2 Power Midco Holdings and O2 Energy SG, pending regulatory approvals.</li><li>O2 Power operates a renewable energy platform with 4,696 MW capacity, with 2,259 MW expected operational by June 2025.</li><li>JSW’s generation capacity will increase by 23% from 20,012 MW to 24,708 MW.</li></ul><blockquote>“The platform offers a blended average tariff of ₹3.37 (~$0.039)/kWh and an average operational life of approximately 23 years.”</blockquote><p>This acquisition enhances JSW Energy's position in the renewable energy sector, positioning it for future growth in clean energy generation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mercomindia.com/jsw-neo-acquire-o2-power-125-billion</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mercomindia.com/jsw-neo-acquire-o2-power-125-billion</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:07:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pollution Curbs Under GRAP-3 Revoked In Delhi As Air Quality Improves - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pollution Curbs Under GRAP-3 Revoked In Delhi As Air Quality Improves</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>The pollution curbs in Delhi under GRAP-3 have been lifted due to improvements in air quality following continuous rains. The AQI has shown a downward trend and is expected to remain in the 'poor' category for the next few days.</p><ul><li>Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) 3 curbs lifted as air quality improves.</li><li>Continuous rains have contributed to a decrease in the AQI levels.</li><li>Restrictions on diesel generators and construction activities are being eased, but some areas remain under closure orders.</li><li>Stage I & II of the revised GRAP will remain in effect to monitor air quality.</li></ul><blockquote>“Actions under Stage I & II of the revised GRAP shall remain invoked and be implemented, monitored and reviewed by all the agencies concerned in the entire NCR.”</blockquote><p>This move marks a shift in response to improved environmental conditions, as the seasonal pollution issues are still anticipated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pollution-curbs-under-grap-3-revoked-in-delhi-as-air-quality-improves-7345132</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pollution-curbs-under-grap-3-revoked-in-delhi-as-air-quality-improves-7345132</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:04:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier dissolves parliament, calls early election for February 23 after - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier dissolves parliament, calls early election for February 23 after Scholz's coalition falls apart</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Major News Outlet</p><p>In a significant political move, German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier has dissolved the parliament and announced early elections scheduled for February 23, following the collapse of Chancellor Olaf Scholz's coalition government.</p><ul><li>The coalition, comprised of the Social Democrats, Greens, and Free Democrats, fell apart due to internal disagreements.</li><li>Steinmeier's decision comes after unsuccessful attempts to stabilize the government.</li><li>This early election marks a pivotal moment in German politics and could reshape the political landscape.</li></ul><blockquote>“The decision to call an early election reflects the necessity of restoring stability and trust in our democratic institutions.” - Frank-Walter Steinmeier</blockquote><p>This unprecedented move underscores the challenges facing the current government and the potential for significant changes in the upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/german-president-dissolves-parliament-calls-early-election-for-february-23/articleshow/116711830.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/german-president-dissolves-parliament-calls-early-election-for-february-23/articleshow/116711830.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Popular sleeping pill linked to reduced Alzheimer's protein buildup, study reveals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Popular sleeping pill linked to reduced Alzheimer's protein buildup, study reveals</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Annals of Neurology</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116717852,imgsize-31514,width-400,resizemode-4/116717852.jpg" alt="Popular sleeping pill linked to reduced Alzheimer's protein buildup, study reveals" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Image depicting research study process.</figcaption><p>A new study suggests that taking sleeping pills may help lower the risk of Alzheimer's disease by reducing the accumulation of key proteins associated with the condition.</p><ul><li>Researchers found that those who took suvorexant, a common insomnia medication, for two nights showed a reduction in amyloid-beta and tau proteins.</li><li>The study involved 38 middle-aged participants who were monitored for protein levels while accounting for sleep quality.</li><li>Results indicated a 10-20% decrease in amyloid-beta levels for those on the medication compared to the placebo group.</li><li>There are concerns about the indiscriminate use of sleep medications without further research.</li></ul><blockquote>“If you can reduce tau phosphorylation, potentially there would be less tangle formation and less neuronal death,” said neurologist Brendan Lucey.</blockquote><p>This research highlights the potential link between sleep quality and the risk of developing Alzheimer's disease, suggesting that improving sleep might be beneficial.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/popular-sleeping-pill-linked-to-reduced-alzheimers-protein-buildup-study-reveals/articleshow/116717846.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/popular-sleeping-pill-linked-to-reduced-alzheimers-protein-buildup-study-reveals/articleshow/116717846.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Physical, technical external interference': Azerbaijan Airlines after preliminary investigation into pla - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Physical, technical external interference: Azerbaijan Airlines after preliminary investigation into plane crash</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Azerbaijan Airlines Incident" /><figcaption>Azerbaijan Airlines Incident</figcaption><p>Azerbaijan Airlines is conducting a preliminary investigation into a recent plane crash, suggesting possible physical and technical external interference as contributing factors.</p><ul><li>An exploratory assessment has flagged interference as a potential cause for the crash.</li><li>The airline is expected to provide detailed findings in subsequent reports.</li><li>This incident raises serious safety concerns for aviation standards.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are committed to ensuring the highest safety standards and will investigate all potential causes thoroughly.” - Azerbaijan Airlines spokesperson</blockquote><p>The investigation's results will likely have implications for air travel regulations and safety protocols moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/physical-technical-external-interference-azerbaijan-airlines-after-preliminary-investigation-into-plane-crash/articleshow/116717588.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/physical-technical-external-interference-azerbaijan-airlines-after-preliminary-investigation-into-plane-crash/articleshow/116717588.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[T-Minus: Counting down the top 10 space stories of 2024 - Freethink]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Counting down the top 10 space stories of 2024</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Freethink</p><figure><img src="https://www.freethink.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/T-Minus-10-small.png?quality=75&amp;w=900" alt="T:10 written in the style of a digital clock"><figcaption>T:10 Countdown</figcaption></figure><p>This article provides a recap of the top 10 space stories of 2024, showcasing significant achievements in space exploration and technology.</p><ul><li><strong>SLIM's Moon Landing:</strong> Japan's Smart Lander achieved a precise lunar landing on January 19, 2024.</li><li><strong>Ingenuity's Final Flight:</strong> NASA's Mars helicopter completed its final mission with a record 72 flights.</li><li><strong>Return of the Space Factory:</strong> Varda Space Industries marked the return of its first space factory, potentially starting a new era of off-world manufacturing.</li><li><strong>Polaris Dawn Spacewalk:</strong> Featured the first private spacewalk conducted by a civilian crew, led by Jared Isaacman.</li><li><strong>Vulcan Centaur's First Flight:</strong> United Launch Alliance's new heavy-lift rocket completed its inaugural launch on January 8, 2024.</li><li><strong>Intuitive Machines' Moon Landing:</strong> The Odysseus lander successfully reached the lunar surface, marking a milestone for commercial space exploration.</li><li><strong>Europa Clipper Launch:</strong> Launched on October 14, 2024, this NASA mission aims to explore Jupiter's moon Europa.</li><li><strong>Chang’e 6's Round-Trip Mission:</strong> China's mission successfully returned lunar samples from the far side of the moon.</li><li><strong>Starliner's Troubled ISS Flight:</strong> Boeing's Starliner faced challenges during its first crewed flight to the ISS.</li><li><strong>SpaceX's Mechazilla Recovery:</strong> SpaceX successfully used its mechazilla system to recover a Falcon Heavy booster.</li></ul><blockquote>“Video of this first-of-its-kind rocket recovery is a must-see for anyone with a remote interest in aerospace.”</blockquote><p>2024 proved to be a groundbreaking year in space exploration, with various milestones achieved across different missions and countries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freethink.com/space/top-space-news-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freethink.com/space/top-space-news-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["You Can't Hang A Man...": India And Australia Ex-Cricketers Argue Over Virat Kohli's Fine For Sam K.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxOMWxFeWVnXzJJNV9ibF9Fbnc2TzNTQS1BbXBIY2VpbnFXMlpqYXRMaGtjVGRrNGEtSU1FSEtteUNKSHJFaTlTQnV1NEJaWHZwQ0dsNkt2dkRqLV9SNUxWMnVjVXU5Umw3NzBnc3NhVGV5S09PSXp3SDdHd0lTaDh2STItNGJwYXU4c19oR3kyRUx2Sm1yS2RBQUFKSzdWZklyRHNZTXRZekF3eGo5U25vMWRBSlU2bWd2S0RDM20tbUtzR0Njb094eXhuRUpyTS0yOUkxTHhkWjZEN1NvUVNMdVkwVE5BN2pNY2RzTm9YQllvS0F0WGfSAf4BQVVfeXFMUHgwQlhsWkM4Z3hrclhId3Z6LW1ZTGZLdW5MRWxyb2NtUjR0VEpMRDZUU1JZN1JKX1lENjBEMXpoeFVVY0hWODdEeUR5WHk0Z2dEY3d3LUhKUDRfQS1OTU4zS2lDcFQxcTFZREphdTdRUUxPRy1nMkZvZXpJWlI1VHRQaXFlekE1VzN5dWhpQkcyMGtzZ3NlQlhBS0kweThfWUtCUGVZNTJrZVpEZVJSaXRBajJaVk9TNkl3aENvTW83bzE0Qjl3OTBoX2xyaFd6cmZmalU2SzRfMjBpbTlCdXJLOUtRS3VGeFNKT25kVDF5MElKWlllOFdUVmEtc3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxOMWxFeWVnXzJJNV9ibF9Fbnc2TzNTQS1BbXBIY2VpbnFXMlpqYXRMaGtjVGRrNGEtSU1FSEtteUNKSHJFaTlTQnV1NEJaWHZwQ0dsNkt2dkRqLV9SNUxWMnVjVXU5Umw3NzBnc3NhVGV5S09PSXp3SDdHd0lTaDh2STItNGJwYXU4c19oR3kyRUx2Sm1yS2RBQUFKSzdWZklyRHNZTXRZekF3eGo5U25vMWRBSlU2bWd2S0RDM20tbUtzR0Njb094eXhuRUpyTS0yOUkxTHhkWjZEN1NvUVNMdVkwVE5BN2pNY2RzTm9YQllvS0F0WGfSAf4BQVVfeXFMUHgwQlhsWkM4Z3hrclhId3Z6LW1ZTGZLdW5MRWxyb2NtUjR0VEpMRDZUU1JZN1JKX1lENjBEMXpoeFVVY0hWODdEeUR5WHk0Z2dEY3d3LUhKUDRfQS1OTU4zS2lDcFQxcTFZREphdTdRUUxPRy1nMkZvZXpJWlI1VHRQaXFlekE1VzN5dWhpQkcyMGtzZ3NlQlhBS0kweThfWUtCUGVZNTJrZVpEZVJSaXRBajJaVk9TNkl3aENvTW83bzE0Qjl3OTBoX2xyaFd6cmZmalU2SzRfMjBpbTlCdXJLOUtRS3VGeFNKT25kVDF5MElKWlllOFdUVmEtc3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:41:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>