<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:21:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:21:07 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament session LIVE: 'Congress distorting facts,' says Amit Shah on Ambedkar remark row - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament session LIVE: 'Congress distorting facts,' says Amit Shah on Ambedkar remark row</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>December 18, 2024 | <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/Shah_presser_1734523675355_1734523687762.png" alt="Parliament session LIVE: Amit Shah addresses press conference" title="Parliament session LIVE: Amit Shah addresses press conference" width="360" height="202" loading="lazy" decoding="async"><figcaption>Parliament session LIVE: Amit Shah addresses press conference</figcaption></div><p>The Congress party has strongly criticized Union Home Minister Amit Shah for his comments regarding Dr. BR Ambedkar, demanding an apology amid ongoing tensions in Parliament.</p><ul><li>The Winter Session of Parliament is nearing its end, concluding on December 20, with multiple bills on the agenda.</li><li>Amit Shah accused Congress of distorting facts and misrepresenting his comments on Ambedkar during recent debates.</li><li>Shah emphasized that he had praised Ambedkar's contributions while alleging that the Congress party has historically insulted him.</li><li>Opposition members have called for Shah's resignation over his remarks, prompting protests.</li><li>Shah declared that the uproar is an attempt by Congress to deflect attention from its electoral failures.</li></ul><blockquote>“The people who denied Babasaheb Ambedkar are the ones trying to protest in his name,” Amit Shah stated.</blockquote><p>As the session unfolds, tensions escalate, with Congress leaders continuing their demands for accountability from the BJP.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-session-live-rajya-sabha-lok-sabha-amit-shah-one-nation-one-election-bill-latest-updates-today-december-18-101734492559242.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-session-live-rajya-sabha-lok-sabha-amit-shah-one-nation-one-election-bill-latest-updates-today-december-18-101734492559242.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 13:46:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2 dead after ferry with passengers capsizes near Gateway of India in Mumbai; rescue operations underway - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ferry Capsizes Near Gateway of India, Resulting in Two Fatalities</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> <em>October 24, 2023</em> | <strong>Source:</strong> <em>Times of India</em></p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Ferry capsizing" />
<figcaption>Ferry capsizing near Gateway of India.</figcaption>
<p>A tragic incident occurred when a ferry with passengers capsized near the Gateway of India in Mumbai, leading to the death of two individuals. Rescue operations are currently underway to assist any survivors.</p>
<ul>
<li>The incident took place in the afternoon, and the ferry was reportedly overloaded.</li>
<li>Emergency services and local authorities swiftly initiated a rescue operation.</li>
<li>Witnesses described scenes of panic and chaos as the ferry capsized.</li>
<li>Authorities are investigating the cause of the incident.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We are doing everything we can to rescue those who are still unaccounted for,” said a local official.</blockquote>
<p>This incident has sparked discussions about safety regulations for passenger ferries in Mumbai.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ferry-with-passengers-capsizes-near-gateway-of-india-in-mumbai-rescue-operations-underway/articleshow/116438808.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ferry-with-passengers-capsizes-near-gateway-of-india-in-mumbai-rescue-operations-underway/articleshow/116438808.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foxconn has discussed making bid for Nissan | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPSFM4WUxWQUUyc0pXbGJYWmJLenQwMjE4a09kQUJCa0hSbXkxcXRHaDNxcXI5dEZnUWw1aW5RYTU1ejM1RXRNNDJfNENyR0llS2JGbDQ1MEcyemdSQzhieGdZLUl6R2twOW12OVpHdlZ4TnpkaElnMzBIeTNPV19tdUh1dWVBby1ZZWVFYl8wNXQzWFFGVUEtZmNUaklNczB5MzZQX3JR0gGrAUFVX3lxTE5JVDJaSHpkaEJMcm8zTGlIREVpUnlidks3MTE2MDlmQk1lWTJPcE45T3pXR0ZpcS1EX2J2clFFM1JEb2NkOUFvcTJWeWVHdml0bENXakFwWko4dFNSSWprSURrTlVIS3g3SHE0OWRfZDk0b1hiOGxybHZneV9RSFVnX0c0VWtEczV3OXFWV3JoOGpsUS1sMFJ5OG0zWVlRbThIczZ0MEJ5V2pMYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPSFM4WUxWQUUyc0pXbGJYWmJLenQwMjE4a09kQUJCa0hSbXkxcXRHaDNxcXI5dEZnUWw1aW5RYTU1ejM1RXRNNDJfNENyR0llS2JGbDQ1MEcyemdSQzhieGdZLUl6R2twOW12OVpHdlZ4TnpkaElnMzBIeTNPV19tdUh1dWVBby1ZZWVFYl8wNXQzWFFGVUEtZmNUaklNczB5MzZQX3JR0gGrAUFVX3lxTE5JVDJaSHpkaEJMcm8zTGlIREVpUnlidks3MTE2MDlmQk1lWTJPcE45T3pXR0ZpcS1EX2J2clFFM1JEb2NkOUFvcTJWeWVHdml0bENXakFwWko4dFNSSWprSURrTlVIS3g3SHE0OWRfZDk0b1hiOGxybHZneV9RSFVnX0c0VWtEczV3OXFWV3JoOGpsUS1sMFJ5OG0zWVlRbThIczZ0MEJ5V2pMYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:25:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA schedules return of Starliner crew in March - Daily Excelsior]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxQU2tXVzVudUh4Xy1wM2w1S1ltanZxTWt5WUpWZVVtRkFuM3R3NzJvWnc1czF5M01lNnlzNENNeUNGMzA1aDA2ZDk5SFZEWEItdDlQdUZfNi10WFo2RVhwSnRnRE1QUGdnb3RyeFFOZ1o1NnEzOFFoeHJ4cmhrZHdJS0RxSmIyQ1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxQU2tXVzVudUh4Xy1wM2w1S1ltanZxTWt5WUpWZVVtRkFuM3R3NzJvWnc1czF5M01lNnlzNENNeUNGMzA1aDA2ZDk5SFZEWEItdDlQdUZfNi10WFo2RVhwSnRnRE1QUGdnb3RyeFFOZ1o1NnEzOFFoeHJ4cmhrZHdJS0RxSmIyQ1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:09:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More than 500 species infected, 300 billion birds dead due to avian flu H5N1: WHO - Down To Earth Magazine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Over 500 Species Infected and 300 Billion Birds Dead from H5N1: WHO Warns</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 18 Dec 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> World Health Organization</p><p>The Highly Pathogenic Avian Influenza (HPAI) H5N1 has infected over 500 species and led to over 300 billion bird deaths globally. The UN has reported that the virus poses significant risks to both wildlife and human livelihoods, particularly in poultry-dependent regions.</p><ul><li>HPAI H5N1 has spread to 108 countries and has infected numerous wildlife species.</li><li>The virus poses a threat to food security and livelihoods, especially for poultry farmers.</li><li>Seventy-six human cases of H5N1 have been reported in 2024, primarily among farm workers.</li><li>The WHO urges increased surveillance and preventive measures regarding the virus.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no evidence so far that the H5N1 viruses have adapted to spread between people,” said Maria Van Kerkhove, WHO.</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the need for a multi-sectoral approach to address avian influenza's spread.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/health/more-than-500-species-infected-300-billion-birds-dead-due-to-avian-flu-h5n1-who</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.downtoearth.org.in/health/more-than-500-species-infected-300-billion-birds-dead-due-to-avian-flu-h5n1-who</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1 dead after ferry with passengers capsizes near Gateway of India in Mumbai; rescue operations underway - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2 dead after ferry with passengers capsizes near Gateway of India in Mumbai; rescue operations underway</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date]</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Name]</p>
<p>A ferry capsized near the Gateway of India in Mumbai, resulting in the deaths of two individuals. Rescue operations are currently in progress to locate survivors and assist passengers.</p>
<ul>
<li>The ferry was reportedly carrying a number of passengers when it capsized.</li>
<li>Rescue teams have been deployed to search for missing passengers.</li>
<li>The incident has raised safety concerns regarding ferry operations in the area.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>''This tragic incident has shaken the community, and our thoughts are with the victims' families.''</blockquote>
<p>The authorities are investigating the cause of the capsizing as rescue efforts continue.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ferry-with-passengers-capsizes-near-gateway-of-india-in-mumbai-rescue-operations-underway/articleshow/116438808.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ferry-with-passengers-capsizes-near-gateway-of-india-in-mumbai-rescue-operations-underway/articleshow/116438808.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' box office collection day 14 (Updated Live): The Allu Arjun starrer expected to remain steady - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Pushpa 2' Box Office Collection Day 14: Allu Arjun Starrer Crosses Rs 950 Crore</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 6, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116435278,imgsize-40976,width-400,resizemode-4/116435278.jpg' alt='Pushpa 2' Box Office Collection' decoding='async' fetchpriority='high'><figcaption>'Pushpa 2' Box Office Collection Day 14</figcaption><p>'Pushpa 2' has broken numerous records since its release and is projected to cross Rs 1000 crore net at the domestic box office in the coming days, having already surpassed this figure worldwide.</p><ul><li>The film's Day 14 collection so far is Rs 9.64 crore, with expectations to reach Rs 20 crore by the end of the day.</li><li>Total domestic collection to date is Rs 962.04 crore.</li><li>Despite a dip in Monday's earnings, the film performed strongly over the weekend.</li><li>The upcoming holiday period may boost numbers further.</li></ul><blockquote>'Pushpa 2' made Rs 26.95 crore on Monday and Rs 23.35 crore on Tuesday.</blockquote><p>As the holiday season approaches, the film is expected to draw larger crowds, despite potential competition from 'Baby John' released during Christmas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-14-updated-live-the-allu-arjun-starrer-expected-to-remain-steady-on-wednesday-crosses-rs-950-crore/articleshow/116435339.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-14-updated-live-the-allu-arjun-starrer-expected-to-remain-steady-on-wednesday-crosses-rs-950-crore/articleshow/116435339.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activist claims that Abujhmad encounter was fake, four children injured - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Activist Claims Abujhmad Encounter Was Fake; Four Children Injured</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Recent</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/Bastar-police-issued-a-statement-claiming-that-sev_1734522110579.jpg" alt="Bastar police issued a statement claiming that seven suspected Maoists were killed in a joint operation by security forces in the Abujhmaad jungles (HT file photo)"><figcaption>Bastar police issued a statement claiming that seven suspected Maoists were killed in a joint operation by security forces in the Abujhmaad jungles (HT file photo)</figcaption></figure><p>Activists and villagers in Abujhmad allege that seven individuals killed by police were not Maoists but local villagers, with four children injured during the incident.</p><ul><li>Activists claim that five of the seven killed were villagers working in fields.</li><li>Four children sustained serious injuries and reportedly did not receive medical help for three days.</li><li>Police deny the claims, stating that the children were used as human shields by Maoists.</li><li>The incident occurred in the villages of Kummam and Lekawada under Rekhawaya Panchayat, Narayanpur district.</li><li>Human rights activists express concern over the ongoing incidents affecting tribal children in the region.</li></ul><blockquote>“The deaths and injuries of tribal children in this ongoing campaign by security forces in Bastar should alarm the nation.” - Rinchin, Human Rights Activist</blockquote><p>The incident has raised serious concerns over police conduct and the safety of villagers in the ongoing conflict with Maoists.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/activist-claims-that-abujhmad-encounter-was-fake-four-children-injured-101734522118586.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/activist-claims-that-abujhmad-encounter-was-fake-four-children-injured-101734522118586.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:41:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starlink Device Found In Manipur Not Working, Incompatible: Forensics - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxQT3lrTnVWZGZiMzU4TjNfcXlCRWZoN19EcDYwQkNPenBDMUZXQXJLWW1kcF9lbGJEM29ONy1IYXM1YU95Mk5hRVZfOHgzaTF2OXpkTGdJQVJqaXhKU0lDUWFZdVJDbW5ILURqQVRWYm83eVhDdFRzcWwxM2F2dTlnOFh2N0VDZzIxUEN4Qkl1NkdzZDdENXBQSTlBMWdjNFVIN0U2MUNidjBoQUU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxQT3lrTnVWZGZiMzU4TjNfcXlCRWZoN19EcDYwQkNPenBDMUZXQXJLWW1kcF9lbGJEM29ONy1IYXM1YU95Mk5hRVZfOHgzaTF2OXpkTGdJQVJqaXhKU0lDUWFZdVJDbW5ILURqQVRWYm83eVhDdFRzcWwxM2F2dTlnOFh2N0VDZzIxUEN4Qkl1NkdzZDdENXBQSTlBMWdjNFVIN0U2MUNidjBoQUU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:36:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Box Office: Allu Arjun’s Film Rules At #2 Beating Kalki 2898 AD, RRR & Every Other Indian Film In The Gulf, Guess Who’s At Top? - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office: Allu Arjun’s Film Rules At #2 Beating Kalki 2898 AD, RRR & Every Other Indian</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 5, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-box-office-01.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Box Office" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Box Office (UAE-GCC) Update! ( Photo Credit – Instagram )</figcaption><p>Pushpa 2 has emerged as a significant contender at the box office, achieving impressive milestones both in India and internationally, especially in the Gulf markets.</p><ul><li>Pushpa 2 has grossed <strong>42.89 crores</strong> in the Gulf markets in just 11 days.</li><li>It is the second Indian film to surpass the <strong>40 crore</strong> milestone.</li><li>The film ranks as the second-highest Tollywood grosser globally, behind Baahubali 2.</li><li>Pushpa 2 has surpassed Kalki 2898 AD, RRR, and Salaar in box office collections.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is also one of the longest Indian films made, with a runtime of over 200 minutes.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Pushpa 2's significant box office achievement solidifies its position as one of the leading Tollywood films internationally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-allu-arjuns-film-rules-at-2-beating-kalki-2898-ad-rrr-every-other-indian-film-in-the-gulf-guess-whos-at-top/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-allu-arjuns-film-rules-at-2-beating-kalki-2898-ad-rrr-every-other-indian-film-in-the-gulf-guess-whos-at-top/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:33:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US faces risk of losing to China in second moon race - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Faces Risk of Losing to China in Second Moon Race</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> December 18, 2024 05:02 pm IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Conversation</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/m3js0i/article69000213.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/China_Space_02609.jpg" alt="Chinese astronauts for the Shenzhou-18 mission, from right, Ye Guangfu, Li Cong, and Li Guangsu wave as they attend a send-off ceremony for their manned space mission at the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center in northwestern China, April 25, 2024." title="Chinese astronauts for the Shenzhou-18 mission, from right, Ye Guangfu, Li Cong, and Li Guangsu wave as they attend a send-off ceremony for their manned space mission at the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center in northwestern China, April 25, 2024.">
<figcaption>Chinese astronauts for the Shenzhou-18 mission, from right, Ye Guangfu, Li Cong, and Li Guangsu wave as they attend a send-off ceremony for their manned space mission.</figcaption>
<p>As both the US and China prepare to return humans to the Moon, the US lunar program faces delays, while China is projected to land astronauts by 2030. This article explores the implications of a potential new Moon race and the challenges both nations face.</p>
<ul>
<li>12 Americans landed on the Moon between 1969 and 1972.</li>
<li>The US lunar program is behind schedule due to unprepared equipment.</li>
<li>China intends to land astronauts on the Moon by 2030, backed by a smooth-running space program.</li>
<li>Nasa's Artemis program aims to land humans on the Moon by 2026, with several milestones including Artemis I and II.</li>
<li>Critics suggest Artemis is overly complicated compared to China’s direct approach.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Rushing back to the Moon could be costly, both financially and in the risk to human life.”</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming Moon missions highlight competitive international space efforts and the importance of responsible exploration principles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/us-faces-risk-of-losing-to-china-in-second-moon-race/article69000225.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/us-faces-risk-of-losing-to-china-in-second-moon-race/article69000225.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poco M7 Pro and C75 5G smartphones launched in India: Check price, offers - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/gadgets/poco-m7-pro-and-c75-5g-smartphones-launched-in-india-check-price-offers-124121800741_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/gadgets/poco-m7-pro-and-c75-5g-smartphones-launched-in-india-check-price-offers-124121800741_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:30:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Insolence': Uddhav Thackeray lambasts Amit Shah over Ambedkar remark - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Uddhav Thackeray Criticizes Amit Shah Over Ambedkar Comments</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/PTI11-19-2024-000249A-0_1734520383723_1734520409294.jpg" alt="Shiv Sena (UBT) chief Uddhav Thackeray(PTI file photo)" title="Shiv Sena (UBT) chief Uddhav Thackeray(PTI file photo)">
<figcaption>Shiv Sena (UBT) chief Uddhav Thackeray(PTI file photo)</figcaption>
<p>Shiv Sena (UBT) leader Uddhav Thackeray condemned union minister Amit Shah's remarks about Dr. B.R. Ambedkar, labeling them as 'insolent' and questioned the NDA's response to the controversy.</p>
<ul>
<li>Thackeray criticized Shah for saying that taking Ambedkar's name had become fashionable.</li>
<li>He demanded action from Prime Minister Modi against Shah for his comments.</li>
<li>The remarks led to protests by several MPs from the opposition INDIA bloc in Parliament.</li>
<li>Kiren Rijiju, minister for parliamentary affairs, defended Shah, accusing the Congress of insulting Ambedkar.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The manner in which Amit Shah spoke in the Parliament yesterday, he displayed insolence... Who are you? Ambedkar ji is a personality not bound by any side." - Uddhav Thackeray</blockquote>
<p>This controversy highlights ongoing tensions between the BJP and opposition parties over representation and respect for historical figures like Dr. Ambedkar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/uddhav-thackeray-lambasts-amit-shah-over-ambedkar-remark-101734520113632.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/uddhav-thackeray-lambasts-amit-shah-over-ambedkar-remark-101734520113632.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:14:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Andrew Tate can have over $2.5 million seized from him in tax dispute, British court says | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/andrew-tate-can-have-over-2-5-million-seized-from-him-in-tax-dispute-british-court-says-11734520153609.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/andrew-tate-can-have-over-2-5-million-seized-from-him-in-tax-dispute-british-court-says-11734520153609.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:09:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia Develops New MRNA Cancer Vaccine, Set For Free Distribution By 2025 - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxNZngyenVPdEtNVHcyS3VLdW1WWHQ1NHhwTlYtaHFPSGx2dVdUcWlWU2hCN3VTckx5RURBOVJyYnF6S0pKRXotNG5DZEtsYWxWY2tpai1UQjdFRy1nclZWUENZMFlHRGRYLXFqcnBKTTdCSHJSV2RrbnVNaGEzT2dwWWhiXzc4bnN4ejJQSG5zSlN1UzlERFZ1dWlicUhMMnRuWUNxUHhTR3VHYnRnYndvd29ZTknSAboBQVVfeXFMTVVER2Y4dm45dDR1Y3ZaRkltMWdSd0FpOU1LNHN2Mkx4Y3Z6LXRwQ1lYcldHbHVpX2tMeDJ4QjhUd1ZNU1I5M05RWGtmajluUXd5YVl1OEZEdzBOSXcxQXJFcTJTSEF4RlFObE04SGstMEoySUsxTHRFd2xFZWdFeXh6SDNzQkRzYkwwWEw0ckp6cHd2Y2pncktXZjZDcjk0cm9QUmVSdTJ6SWVDQmMyNFA5ME5saWthNWlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxNZngyenVPdEtNVHcyS3VLdW1WWHQ1NHhwTlYtaHFPSGx2dVdUcWlWU2hCN3VTckx5RURBOVJyYnF6S0pKRXotNG5DZEtsYWxWY2tpai1UQjdFRy1nclZWUENZMFlHRGRYLXFqcnBKTTdCSHJSV2RrbnVNaGEzT2dwWWhiXzc4bnN4ejJQSG5zSlN1UzlERFZ1dWlicUhMMnRuWUNxUHhTR3VHYnRnYndvd29ZTknSAboBQVVfeXFMTVVER2Y4dm45dDR1Y3ZaRkltMWdSd0FpOU1LNHN2Mkx4Y3Z6LXRwQ1lYcldHbHVpX2tMeDJ4QjhUd1ZNU1I5M05RWGtmajluUXd5YVl1OEZEdzBOSXcxQXJFcTJTSEF4RlFObE04SGstMEoySUsxTHRFd2xFZWdFeXh6SDNzQkRzYkwwWEw0ckp6cHd2Y2pncktXZjZDcjk0cm9QUmVSdTJ6SWVDQmMyNFA5ME5saWthNWlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:05:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun's Father Meets Stampede Victim's Husband, Visits Injured Son In Hospital - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjun-father-meets-stampede-victims-husband-visits-injured-son-in-hospital-9160522.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjun-father-meets-stampede-victims-husband-visits-injured-son-in-hospital-9160522.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:58:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sensex crashes 2,000 points in 3 days; 5 factors why Indian stock market is falling | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/sensex-crashes-2-000-points-in-3-days-5-factors-why-indian-stock-market-is-falling-11734512739179.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/sensex-crashes-2-000-points-in-3-days-5-factors-why-indian-stock-market-is-falling-11734512739179.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:48:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two soldiers die while loading ammunition during training exercise in Bikaner - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tragic Incident Claims Lives of Two Soldiers During Training in Bikaner</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/_99b01acc-ca90-11ea-81b2-abeeb3468286_1734517536196.png" alt="(Representative image) The accident came to light when a sudden explosion was heard during a training exercise.(HT FILE PHOTO)"><figcaption>(Representative image) The accident came to light when a sudden explosion was heard during a training exercise.(HT FILE PHOTO)</figcaption></figure><p>Two soldiers of the Indian Army tragically died due to an explosion while loading ammunition during a training exercise in Bikaner.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred at Mahajan field firing range.</li><li>A sudden explosion happened as soldiers were loading ammunition, resulting in two fatalities and one serious injury.</li><li>The deceased soldiers are Ashutosh Mishra from Deoria and Jitendra from Dausa.</li><li>This marks the second fatal incident in the Bikaner range within days.</li><li>A court of inquiry has been initiated to investigate the cause of the explosion.</li></ul><blockquote>“The charger exploded while the soldiers were loading the ammunition,” said the defence spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This sad occurrence highlights the risks associated with military training exercises and has led to renewed calls for safety measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/two-soldiers-die-while-loading-ammunition-during-training-exercise-in-bikaner-101734515531022.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/two-soldiers-die-while-loading-ammunition-during-training-exercise-in-bikaner-101734515531022.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:46:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Gainers and Losers today on 18 December, 2024: Trent, Dr Reddys Laboratories, Tata Motors, Power Grid Corporation Of India among most active stocks; Check full list here | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/top-gainers-and-losers-today-on-18-december-2024-trent-dr-reddys-laboratories-tata-motors-power-grid-corporation-of-india-among-most-active-stocks-check-full-list-here-11734517993728.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/top-gainers-and-losers-today-on-18-december-2024-trent-dr-reddys-laboratories-tata-motors-power-grid-corporation-of-india-among-most-active-stocks-check-full-list-here-11734517993728.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:33:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["No Chat With BCCI...": Report Claims R Ashwin's Retirement May've Been Hastened Due To This Player'.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxQcnBxOGhtMVktbDlRV0NnbVdEV2dhdXBOU0lxbnQ0U1hKQmJ3dWhvNGlPYkxsY3dPbUxWTnZ6M3VvcmpEdFQyR2JUb091bGhQa2tPQ2podnN1eVhwVmJfbmtQZkcwUVprWWFZakhFZXZEVko1c2pYOE9QWWZQREJvYV9QdFZ5VU5BT2RwYmZuVWdqaUJGUWppOE1ISy1DTkE0cWdNR3IyNjlnZmJTd1ViRmU4Wl9vekZaTTAyaUpuT25vM1dFekdfY0dVd2NxeGo2aEVOcUNPc080akxtYVhJc3k1cDJYNU1NcWFVbDBCNNIB9wFBVV95cUxOT1J1VlYxYlVxcFJFcEdVQklaUUlnZlN6QURmVllHZGdra1RENl9QRFJ5bFI2X2E5TEFoOV9FV0FnLXZ1TEtnSjFOeXYyTTZYZjVpaDNhS3N5cXcwXzBlcy1TQTZPYU55akNNZ1ROVjZuN3NXMVZpSkxPdEtseFYxampLeHJ4YV9DMjM4TWczeUVZQ2ZhdDFya1g4eXVpN1lvNVNtVXY4TURKeXliSDRScGYxVURscW1CSW1OTjBOUFJmT1JYOXRZOUc0WVoxZHNHbkFMYXJZcGRtX1A3QzZPSmgtM1JEdVliblZtajRzX3FDc0hjcE9J?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxQcnBxOGhtMVktbDlRV0NnbVdEV2dhdXBOU0lxbnQ0U1hKQmJ3dWhvNGlPYkxsY3dPbUxWTnZ6M3VvcmpEdFQyR2JUb091bGhQa2tPQ2podnN1eVhwVmJfbmtQZkcwUVprWWFZakhFZXZEVko1c2pYOE9QWWZQREJvYV9QdFZ5VU5BT2RwYmZuVWdqaUJGUWppOE1ISy1DTkE0cWdNR3IyNjlnZmJTd1ViRmU4Wl9vekZaTTAyaUpuT25vM1dFekdfY0dVd2NxeGo2aEVOcUNPc080akxtYVhJc3k1cDJYNU1NcWFVbDBCNNIB9wFBVV95cUxOT1J1VlYxYlVxcFJFcEdVQklaUUlnZlN6QURmVllHZGdra1RENl9QRFJ5bFI2X2E5TEFoOV9FV0FnLXZ1TEtnSjFOeXYyTTZYZjVpaDNhS3N5cXcwXzBlcy1TQTZPYU55akNNZ1ROVjZuN3NXMVZpSkxPdEtseFYxampLeHJ4YV9DMjM4TWczeUVZQ2ZhdDFya1g4eXVpN1lvNVNtVXY4TURKeXliSDRScGYxVURscW1CSW1OTjBOUFJmT1JYOXRZOUc0WVoxZHNHbkFMYXJZcGRtX1A3QzZPSmgtM1JEdVliblZtajRzX3FDc0hjcE9J?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:27:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amit Shah’s comment on Ambedkar: This disrespect has crossed all limits of tolerance, says Uddhav Thackeray - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/maharashtra/uddhav-thackeray-amit-shah-ambedkar-disrespecting-maharashtra-icons/article68999976.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/maharashtra/uddhav-thackeray-amit-shah-ambedkar-disrespecting-maharashtra-icons/article68999976.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Updated World Test Championship Table After India vs Australia Brisbane Test Ends In A Draw - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Updated World Test Championship Table After India vs Australia Brisbane Test Ends In A Draw</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/109dtgm_r-ashwin-afp_625x300_18_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Updated World Test Championship Table After India vs Australia Brisbane Test Ends In A Draw"><figcaption>Picture from India vs Australia 3rd Test. © AFP</figcaption><p>India secured a vital draw against Australia in the rain-affected third Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy, keeping the series level at 1-1.</p><ul><li>Both teams saw their WTC points percentages dip, with India now at 55.88% and Australia at 58.89%.</li><li>South Africa leads the standings with a 63.33% PCT and is well-positioned for the WTC final in June 2025.</li><li>India must win both remaining Tests against Australia to stay in contention for the final.</li><li>The outcome of matches involving Sri Lanka will also influence India's chances of qualification.</li></ul><blockquote>If India wins each of the remaining Tests, their PCT could rise to 60.52, surpassing Australia even with a 2-0 victory against Sri Lanka.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, India’s path to the WTC final requires winning both Tests against Australia, while relying on external results to bolster their chances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/updated-world-test-championship-table-after-india-vs-australia-brisbane-test-ends-in-a-draw-7276631</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/updated-world-test-championship-table-after-india-vs-australia-brisbane-test-ends-in-a-draw-7276631</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:20:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breaking | Umar Khalid Gets 7 Days Interim Bail In Delhi Riots Larger Conspiracy Case - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Umar Khalid Granted 7 Days Interim Bail in Delhi Riots Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Courts</p><p>A Delhi Court has granted interim bail to Umar Khalid for a week, allowing him to attend a family wedding amidst allegations related to the 2020 North-East Delhi riots. The bail comes with several conditions aimed at ensuring compliance during this period.</p><ul><li>The bail is valid for 7 days.</li><li>Khalid must not contact any witness or individuals connected to the case.</li><li>He is prohibited from using social media during this timeframe.</li><li>Meetings are restricted to family and friends, and he must remain at home or wedding venues.</li></ul><p>Khalid is required to surrender by the evening of January 3, 2025. His previous bail application had been rejected, leading to ongoing legal proceedings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/umar-khalid-bail-delhi-riots-278744</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/umar-khalid-bail-delhi-riots-278744</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:14:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gainers & Losers: 10 stocks that moved the most on December 18 - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/photos/business/markets/gainers-losers-10-stocks-that-moved-the-most-on-december-18-2-12892959.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/photos/business/markets/gainers-losers-10-stocks-that-moved-the-most-on-december-18-2-12892959.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:12:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravichandran Ashwin retirement reactions LIVE: Virat Kohli shares emotional note; ‘Had a long journey together since 2010,’ says Rohit Sharma - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravichandran Ashwin retirement reactions LIVE: Virat Kohli shares emotional note; ‘Had a long journey together since 2010,’ says Rohit Sharma</h1><p><strong>Published: </strong> December 18, 2024, <strong>Source: </strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/sjyf0t/article68999235.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_18_2024_000034B.jpg" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin retirement"/><figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin's retirement announcement.</figcaption><p>India’s key spinner Ravichandran Ashwin announced his retirement from international cricket on December 18, 2024, following the third Test match of the Border-Gavaskar series against Australia.</p><ul><li>Ashwin is the second-fastest player to achieve 500 Test wickets, reaching this milestone in 98 matches.</li><li>Throughout his career, he has taken 765 wickets and holds 37 five-wicket hauls.</li><li>Notable reactions include heartfelt messages from Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma, highlighting the impact Ashwin had on their careers.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’ve played with you for 14 years and when you told me today you’re retiring, it made me a bit emotional.” - Virat Kohli</blockquote><p>The cricket community pays tribute to Ashwin's remarkable contributions to the sport.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sport/ravichandran-ashwin-retirement-indian-spinner-live-updates-december-18-2024/article68999215.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sport/ravichandran-ashwin-retirement-indian-spinner-live-updates-december-18-2024/article68999215.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Courts doors always open’: Supreme Court on protesting farmers refusing talks with Punjab govt panel - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Courts doors always open’: Supreme Court on protesting farmers refusing talks with Punjab govt panel</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/A-view-of-the-Supreme-Court-building--the-apex-jud_1734461661311_1734516031274.jpg" alt="The Supreme Court has welcomed any suggestions by the farmers to be directly addressed to them"><figcaption>The Supreme Court has welcomed any suggestions by the farmers to be directly addressed to them</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court affirmed that its doors are open to the protesting farmers after they rejected discussions with a Punjab government committee.</p><ul><li>The court emphasized that farmers can directly present their demands.</li><li>The Punjab government reported ongoing efforts to engage with farmer leaders.</li><li>Jagjit Singh Dallewal, a key farmer leader, is on a hunger strike, pressing for a legal guarantee of Minimum Support Price (MSP) on crops.</li><li>The Supreme Court noted the health concerns of Dallewal and instructed medical assistance from the Punjab government.</li></ul><blockquote>“We clarify that court's doors are always open to any suggestion or demand by farmers directly or through their authorised representative.”</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the ongoing tension between the Punjab farmers and the state government, with the Supreme Court offering a potential avenue for resolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/supreme-court-says-doors-open-to-punjab-farmers-demands-after-government-talks-fail-101734515068569.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/supreme-court-says-doors-open-to-punjab-farmers-demands-after-government-talks-fail-101734515068569.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:11:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Priyanka Gandhi Vadra likely to be part of simultaneous polls JPC: Sources - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Priyanka Gandhi Vadra likely to join JPC for simultaneous polls</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/ANI-20241216210-0_1734516439351_1734516451854.jpg" alt="Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra speaks in Lok Sabha. (File photo)" title="Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra speaks in Lok Sabha. (File photo)"><figcaption>Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra speaks in Lok Sabha. (File photo)</figcaption><p>Congress party leaders are expected to participate in a Joint Parliamentary Committee to evaluate the introduction of legislation for simultaneous elections.</p><ul><li>Priyanka Gandhi Vadra and other Congress MPs are likely to represent the party.</li><li>The bills concerning simultaneous elections were introduced in Lok Sabha after significant debate.</li><li>Opposition groups have expressed concerns, labeling the legislation as anti-constitutional.</li><li>Support for the legislation comes from 32 political parties, while 15 oppose it.</li><li>Amit Shah announced that the bill would be handed over to a JPC for further discussion.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is against the federalism of our nation. We are opposing the bill,” said Priyanka Gandhi Vadra.</blockquote><p>The deliberations in the JPC will be vital as the government aims to push through the simultaneous election legislation amid differing opinions within the political landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/priyanka-gandhi-vadra-likely-to-be-part-of-simultaneous-polls-jpc-sources-101734516076364.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/priyanka-gandhi-vadra-likely-to-be-part-of-simultaneous-polls-jpc-sources-101734516076364.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:08:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA alert! Giant 84-foot asteroid 2024 XS3 to pass Earth today; will the asteroid collide? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Alert: Giant 84-Foot Asteroid 2024 XS3 Passes Earth Safely</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116434652,imgsize-49122,width-400,resizemode-4/116434652.jpg" alt="NASA alert! Giant 84-foot asteroid 2024 XS3 to pass Earth today; will the asteroid collide?" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>A giant 84-foot asteroid 2024 XS3 passing Earth.</figcaption><p>Today, the Apollo NEO asteroid, 2024 XS3, will safely pass Earth at a distance of approximately 3.3 million kilometers. Discovered on December 3, 2024, it poses no collision risk.</p><ul><li>The asteroid follows an elliptical orbit with a perihelion of 0.89 AU and an aphelion of 2.58 AU.</li><li>It is part of the Apollo asteroid group, taking approximately 833 days to complete one revolution around the Sun.</li><li>Scientists assure that after today, 2024 XS3 won't come closer than 45 million kilometers until 2027.</li><li>Asteroids like 2024 XS3 hold vital information about the solar system's formation.</li><li>NASA monitors Near-Earth Objects using advanced radar systems to track potential threats.</li><li>Ongoing efforts include missions aimed to detect and deflect hazardous asteroids.</li></ul><blockquote>"Asteroid 2024 XS3 serves as a reminder of the importance of asteroid monitoring and planetary defense."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while this encounter presents no threat, it highlights the ongoing need for monitoring of NEOs to ensure Earth's safety from future cosmic dangers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-alert-giant-84-foot-asteroid-2024-xs3-to-pass-earth-today-will-the-asteroid-collide/articleshow/116434446.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-alert-giant-84-foot-asteroid-2024-xs3-to-pass-earth-today-will-the-asteroid-collide/articleshow/116434446.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA alert: 84-foot asteroid to pass close to Earth today - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Alert: 84-Foot Asteroid to Pass Close to Earth Today</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Today</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>This article discusses the close approach of an 84-foot asteroid to Earth, highlighting its proximity and any potential implications for our planet.</p><ul><li>NASA has issued an alert regarding the close passage of the asteroid.</li><li>The asteroid measures approximately 84 feet in diameter.</li><li>This event occurs today, with minimal risk to Earth.</li></ul><blockquote>"NASA monitors near-Earth objects to ensure the safety of the planet."</blockquote><p>The passage of this asteroid serves as a reminder of the importance of monitoring celestial objects that come close to Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/nasa-alert-84-foot-asteroid-to-pass-close-to-earth-today/articleshow/116434559.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/nasa-alert-84-foot-asteroid-to-pass-close-to-earth-today/articleshow/116434559.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R India Launch Date Officially Confirmed; Check Expected Specs, Price - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R India Launch Date Officially Confirmed</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>January 7, 2025 | <strong>Source: </strong>Zee News</p>
<p>The OnePlus 13 series, including the OnePlus 13 and OnePlus 13R, is set to launch globally with a special event in India.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The launch event will commence at 9:00 pm IST on January 7, 2025, coinciding with OnePlus's 11th anniversary.</li>
  <li>The smartphones will be available via Amazon and OnePlus India e-store.</li>
  <li>Globally, the OnePlus 13 has already been released in China.</li>
  <li>The expected price for OnePlus 13 is around Rs 65,000.</li>
  <li>Specifications include a 6.82-inch Quad-HD+ AMOLED display, Snapdragon 8 Elite SoC, and a triple camera setup.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The event will be live-streamed on OnePlus’s official channels.”</blockquote>
<p>For more updates, stay tuned to official sources regarding the OnePlus 13 series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/technology/oneplus-13-oneplus-13r-india-launch-amazon-check-expected-specs-price-2833283.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/technology/oneplus-13-oneplus-13r-india-launch-amazon-check-expected-specs-price-2833283.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:03:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>