<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 23:16:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 23:16:08 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires live: 3 out of 6 active fires in Los Angeles 100% contained, Palisades continues to burn - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires: Major Fires in Los Angeles Contained Amid Devastation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-79_1736720709551_1736720732338.jpg" alt="A fire fighting helicopter drops water as the Palisades fire grows" title="A fire fighting helicopter drops water as the Palisades fire grows"><figcaption>A fire fighting helicopter drops water as the Palisades fire grows.</figcaption><p>The California wildfires have wreaked havoc, with at least 16 confirmed deaths and over 12,000 structures damaged. As of now, three of the six active fires in Los Angeles have been contained, but the Palisades fire continues to burn.</p><strong>Key Points:</strong><ul><li>The Palisades Fire spread to an additional 1,000 acres, prompting ongoing firefighting efforts.</li><li>Evacuation orders affect approximately 153,000 residents, with many additional residents warned to prepare for evacuation.</li><li>Governor Gavin Newsom announced significant containment progress for several fires, with different percentages confirmed.</li><li>President Biden has been coordinating relief efforts and addressing state officials regarding the crisis.</li><li>International aid is on the way, with offers from Canada and Ukraine for firefighting assistance.</li></ul><blockquote>“The fires are still raging in L.A. This is one of the worst catastrophes in the history of our Country.” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical with adverse weather predicted, and officials continue to emphasize the importance of safety and evacuation compliance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 22:28:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Satellite mission will closely monitor changes on Earth's surface - Earth.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Satellite Mission Will Closely Monitor Changes on Earth's Surface</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Image Credit: NASA/JPL-Caltech'>
<figcaption>Image Credit: NASA/JPL-Caltech</figcaption>
<p>The upcoming U.S.-India NISAR mission aims to enhance our understanding of Earth’s ongoing changes through advanced satellite technology.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The NISAR mission will launch in a few months, utilizing dual-band radar to observe various Earth features.</li>
  <li>The L-band radar penetrates vegetation for larger features, while the S-band focuses on finer surface details.</li>
  <li>NISAR will monitor glaciers, forests, and wetlands, providing critical data for climate change studies.</li>
  <li>The mission reflects an international partnership between NASA and ISRO, emphasizing global cooperation.</li>
  <li>Data generated by NISAR will be freely accessible, benefitting both scientists and decision-makers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The planet’s surfaces never stop changing – in some ways small and subtle, and in other ways monumental and sudden.” - Paul Rosen, NISAR Project Scientist at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory.</blockquote>
<p>The NISAR mission represents a significant step in Earth observation technology, highlighting the importance of global collaboration in tackling environmental challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.earth.com/news/satellite-mission-will-closely-monitor-changes-on-earths-surface/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.earth.com/news/satellite-mission-will-closely-monitor-changes-on-earths-surface/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 21:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On L&T Chief's 90-Hour Workweek Call, Adar Poonawalla Says 'Even My Wife...' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Adar Poonawalla Responds to L&T Chief's 90-Hour Workweek Suggestion</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Adar Poonawalla agreed with Anand Mahindra, and said that his wife (Natasha Poonawalla) loves staring at him on Sundays." loading="eager">
<figcaption>Adar Poonawalla agreed with Anand Mahindra, and said that his wife (Natasha Poonawalla) loves staring at him on Sundays.</figcaption>
<p>Adar Poonawalla, CEO of Serum Institute of India, recently discussed the importance of work-life balance in response to remarks made by Larsen & Toubro Chairman SN Subrahmanyan advocating for a 90-hour work week.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Poonawalla affirmed the need for work-life balance, highlighting his agreement with Mahindra Group Chairman Anand Mahindra.</li>
  <li>Subrahmanyan's suggestion drew significant backlash from various sectors, prompting reactions from industrialists and celebrities.</li>
  <li>Other leaders echoed the sentiment that extreme work hours could lead to burnout and emphasized the quality of work over quantity.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Even my wife loves staring at me on Sundays.” - Adar Poonawalla</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the debate around work-life balance versus demanding work schedules continues, with Poonawalla and others advocating for the former.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/on-lt-chiefs-90-hour-workweek-call-adar-poonawalla-says-even-my-wife-9186136.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/on-lt-chiefs-90-hour-workweek-call-adar-poonawalla-says-even-my-wife-9186136.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 20:09:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real Madrid vs Barcelona LIVE Score, Spanish Super Cup 2025 Final: Alejandro Balde Scores | Real Madrid 1-4 Barcelona - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Real Madrid vs Barcelona LIVE Updates, Spanish Super Cup 2025 Final</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p><p>In a thrilling Spanish Super Cup final, Barcelona emerged victorious against Real Madrid with a stunning 5-2 win, showcasing their dominance in El Clasico.</p><ul><li>Barcelona played with ten men but managed to secure a convincing victory.</li><li>This match marks a significant achievement for Barcelona in the 2025 season.</li><li>Real Madrid struggled to capitalize on their chances despite a strong start.</li></ul><blockquote>“This victory is a testament to our resilience and teamwork,” said Barcelona's manager after the match.</blockquote><p>Barcelona's performance not only secures them the Super Cup title but also boosts their confidence moving forward in the season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/football/real-madrid-vs-barcelona-live-score-spanish-super-cup-2024-final-football-el-clasico-live-scorecard-updates-7458349</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/football/real-madrid-vs-barcelona-live-score-spanish-super-cup-2024-final-football-el-clasico-live-scorecard-updates-7458349</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 20:01:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025: Underwater drones, AI cameras, NSG commandos part of security detail; over 45 crore visitors expected - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh 2025: Underwater drones, AI cameras, NSG commandos part of security detail; over 45 crore visitors expected</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>January 13, 2025 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/mahakumbh_1736700393552_1736700393846.jpg" alt="Prayagraj: Commandos conduct a mock drill ahead of the Mahakumbh 2025, in Prayagraj, Saturday, Jan. 11, 2025. (PTI Photo)(PTI)" title="Prayagraj: Commandos conduct a mock drill ahead of the Mahakumbh 2025, in Prayagraj, Saturday, Jan. 11, 2025. (PTI Photo)(PTI)">
<figcaption>Prayagraj: Commandos conduct a mock drill ahead of the Mahakumbh 2025, in Prayagraj, Saturday, Jan. 11, 2025. (PTI Photo)(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>The Prayagraj police have made extensive security arrangements for the upcoming Mahakumbh 2025, expecting over 45 crore visitors from January 13 to February 26.</p>
<ul>
<li>Uttar Pradesh Police has established a multi-layered security system including 102 checkpoints along critical routes.</li>
<li>Over 1,000 police personnel along with additional security forces will ensure the safety of attendees.</li>
<li>Advanced technology such as underwater drones and AI-enabled cameras is being utilized to enhance surveillance.</li>
<li>Mock drills conducted in collaboration with the NSG and other security agencies are in place to ensure preparedness.</li>
<li>Main bathing rituals will occur on auspicious dates during the event.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We are committed to ensuring the safety of all participants.” - DGP Prashant Kumar</blockquote>
<p>The Mahakumbh, celebrated once every 12 years, will attract millions to the holy confluence of rivers at Prayagraj.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-2025-underwater-drones-ai-cameras-nsg-commandos-part-of-security-detail-over-45-crore-visitors-expected-101736663127056.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-2025-underwater-drones-ai-cameras-nsg-commandos-part-of-security-detail-over-45-crore-visitors-expected-101736663127056.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samples of 2 Nagpur kids test positive for HMPV at AIIMS too, but unfit for genome sequencing - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nagpur Kids Test Positive for HMPV at AIIMS, Not Eligible for Genome Sequencing</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>The recent testing at AIIMS has revealed that two children from Nagpur have tested positive for Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV); however, their samples are deemed unfit for genome sequencing, posing challenges in tracking the virus.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Two children from Nagpur confirmed positive for HMPV.</li>
  <li>Samples not suitable for genome sequencing.</li>
  <li>Raises concerns about monitoring the virus's strain.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This finding underlines the need for better facilities for sample analysis.”</blockquote>
<p>This situation highlights the importance of effective testing protocols for emerging viruses and the need for proper sequencing capabilities to understand the spread of HMPV.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/nagpur/samples-of-2-nagpur-kids-test-positive-for-hmpv-at-aiims-too-but-unfit-for-genome-sequencing/articleshow/117181194.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/nagpur/samples-of-2-nagpur-kids-test-positive-for-hmpv-at-aiims-too-but-unfit-for-genome-sequencing/articleshow/117181194.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Find New Galaxy Forming At Tip Of Tidal Tail Stretching 1.27 Million Light-Years - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/scientists-find-new-galaxy-forming-at-tip-of-tidal-tail-str-hing-1-27-million-light-years-aa-9185533.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/scientists-find-new-galaxy-forming-at-tip-of-tidal-tail-str-hing-1-27-million-light-years-aa-9185533.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK PM Keir Starmer under pressure to sack Hasina’s niece Tulip Siddiq - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UK PM Keir Starmer under pressure to sack Hasina’s niece Tulip Siddiq</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Times</p><p>This article discusses the growing pressure on UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer to dismiss Tulip Siddiq, a member of Parliament and niece of Bangladesh’s Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p><ul><li>Tulip Siddiq has faced scrutiny due to her familial ties and political actions.</li><li>Starmer's leadership is being tested as he navigates between party loyalty and public opinion.</li><li>The situation has sparked discussions about political accountability and ethics.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is time for clear accountability and transparency in political appointments.”</blockquote><p>The ongoing discourse highlights the complexities of modern political landscapes where personal connections can lead to significant implications for public service.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/uk-pm-keir-starmer-under-pressure-to-sack-hasinas-niece-tulip-siddiq/articleshow/117180871.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/uk-pm-keir-starmer-under-pressure-to-sack-hasinas-niece-tulip-siddiq/articleshow/117180871.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 Goes Live for Prime Members: Best Deals on Mobiles, Electronics - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 Is Live: Best Deals</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<p>Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 is live for Prime members, with deals opening to all from 12pm on January 13, 2025. The sale features discounts on popular electronics including mobile phones, laptops, and Amazon devices.</p>
<img src='image_url_here' alt='Amazon Great Republic Day Sale' />
<figcaption>Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 offers great discounts on top products.</figcaption>
<ul>
  <li>iPhone 15 (128GB) for Rs. 55,499 after bank offers.</li>
  <li>Samsung Galaxy M35 5G down to Rs. 13,999 after bank offers.</li>
  <li>Oppo F27 Pro+ 5G available for Rs. 23,400 with exchange offers.</li>
  <li>Best offers on Amazon devices like Fire TV Stick starting at Rs. 2,799.</li>
  <li>Lenovo IdeaPad Pro 5 priced at Rs. 1,03,990 during the sale.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Amazon is offering exciting discounts and bundled offers – SBI credit card users can get an additional 10% off.”</blockquote>
<p>The Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025 provides substantial savings on a range of electronic products, with special offers for Prime members and various exchange deals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/features/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-2025-best-deals-mobile-phones-electronics-amazon-devices-7459289</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/features/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-2025-best-deals-mobile-phones-electronics-amazon-devices-7459289</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:48:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How a breast cancer doctor faced the disease she helped others battle - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxOTDhOdmRiS3NIR2pTTkdzN0hYdmNiZlptbjVveUxnbVI4a2RMNTg4R19xdkR1N1Izejl5cVc3ZlhDejRxRmctaFA4QUVPY3UzTFE1Y2xjNWtYcXJYd2lSMFVqcmliMFlnX0doNjI0ZVQtSFBHaVlocm5LYWxyTC1uTjlWSEp6anZsN2dzV0N5QUM2V3pxY0NxZHRWcUQzZFQ0T2Z1UDlGY0RUWUFoTmQ5ZnIyemNEZnBvWXlXVUlYaHhRUmd6eTQ5Rm01bVJHcHg2bWUyTXZYd3B4b0pmNjUtaUpET19qMHhCandSenFSNnNlYmtrOFhHaXdhbDU2d9IBgwJBVV95cUxNaDJuUXgtbE16WU93ZV9IckNvOWZLTVNRa2p6OWlVaGVzS3Q2a1c0enNwNTdFOGgwWHJtbVRtSDhXbG84cF9KUlBoaFJOa3M2YmZUQXNqUkRRYks3S1lEYXFsTk9Gdm04bjRvdXU2dnVkcml3V0FvWndoMHhZczA5VnY0ZGhkXzR2NWpXdW1oUXNueVFfaFNGTjFBblU3dWpydWJsR3VENnVSb1dPQU82SHZjWmdLbm93TGJRU0FpcXNwTDVxUlNsVkUxd2luU3hFbWR1a3hzaHFNb1VoZU9pSGFsSTByZ0dPOGE2Skp3SnFTSU41eW9UNk1yTDZlcVJHOEJN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxOTDhOdmRiS3NIR2pTTkdzN0hYdmNiZlptbjVveUxnbVI4a2RMNTg4R19xdkR1N1Izejl5cVc3ZlhDejRxRmctaFA4QUVPY3UzTFE1Y2xjNWtYcXJYd2lSMFVqcmliMFlnX0doNjI0ZVQtSFBHaVlocm5LYWxyTC1uTjlWSEp6anZsN2dzV0N5QUM2V3pxY0NxZHRWcUQzZFQ0T2Z1UDlGY0RUWUFoTmQ5ZnIyemNEZnBvWXlXVUlYaHhRUmd6eTQ5Rm01bVJHcHg2bWUyTXZYd3B4b0pmNjUtaUpET19qMHhCandSenFSNnNlYmtrOFhHaXdhbDU2d9IBgwJBVV95cUxNaDJuUXgtbE16WU93ZV9IckNvOWZLTVNRa2p6OWlVaGVzS3Q2a1c0enNwNTdFOGgwWHJtbVRtSDhXbG84cF9KUlBoaFJOa3M2YmZUQXNqUkRRYks3S1lEYXFsTk9Gdm04bjRvdXU2dnVkcml3V0FvWndoMHhZczA5VnY0ZGhkXzR2NWpXdW1oUXNueVFfaFNGTjFBblU3dWpydWJsR3VENnVSb1dPQU82SHZjWmdLbm93TGJRU0FpcXNwTDVxUlNsVkUxd2luU3hFbWR1a3hzaHFNb1VoZU9pSGFsSTByZ0dPOGE2Skp3SnFTSU41eW9UNk1yTDZlcVJHOEJN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[President Biden and Israeli PM Netanyahu discuss ceasefire, hostage deal: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden and Netanyahu Discuss Ceasefire and Hostage Release</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 13, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/-LEBANON-CONFLICT-POLITICS-B_1736704488180_1736704488418.jpg" alt="President Biden and PM Netanyahu discussed a ceasefire deal involving the Gaza conflict(Jim Watson/AFP)"><figcaption>President Biden and PM Netanyahu discussed a ceasefire deal involving the Gaza conflict(Jim Watson/AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>US President Joe Biden and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu discussed a potential ceasefire and hostage release deal in Gaza amid ongoing negotiations.</p><ul><li>Biden and Netanyahu spoke during a phone call regarding a ceasefire deal being mediated in Doha.</li><li>National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan indicated that they are "very close" to reaching a deal.</li><li>Outgoing President Biden is receiving regular updates about the talks and aims to use remaining days in office to finalize the agreement.</li><li>Roughly 100 hostages are currently held by Hamas, and over 46,000 people have reportedly died in Gaza, according to health ministry statistics.</li><li>Future negotiations may involve perspectives from the incoming Trump administration, which promises a new approach to Middle East peace.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are still determined to use every day we have in office to get this done...” - Jake Sullivan</blockquote><p>The discussion highlights the urgency of addressing the hostages and the humanitarian crisis in Gaza, even as the political landscape shifts with the imminent transition in the US administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/president-biden-and-israeli-pm-netanyahu-discuss-ceasefire-hostage-deal-report-101736704157514.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/president-biden-and-israeli-pm-netanyahu-discuss-ceasefire-hostage-deal-report-101736704157514.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee to breach 86/$, RBI governor faces 1st major challenge - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee to breach 86/$, RBI governor faces 1st major challenge</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [News Source]</p><p>The Indian rupee is expected to breach the 86/$ mark, presenting a significant challenge for the RBI governor amidst rising economic pressures. This development may have broader implications for the Indian economy and monetary policy.</p><ul><li>The rupee's depreciation could impact inflation and economic growth.</li><li>Market analysts express concerns over foreign investment and trade balances.</li><li>This situation tests the capabilities of the RBI in managing currency fluctuations.</li></ul><blockquote>“The impact of crossing this threshold could resonate through various sectors,” analysts warn.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the potential breach of the 86/$ mark by the rupee marks a critical juncture for India's economic stability, necessitating careful monitoring and responsive policy measures from the RBI.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/rupee-to-breach-86/-rbi-governor-faces-1st-major-challenge/articleshow/117180163.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/rupee-to-breach-86/-rbi-governor-faces-1st-major-challenge/articleshow/117180163.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real Madrid vs Barcelona Live Streaming Supercopa De Espana Final Live Telecast: When And Where To Watch - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Real Madrid vs Barcelona Live Streaming Supercopa De Espana Final Live Telecast: When And Where To Watch</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>This article provides essential information regarding the live streaming and telecast details of the Supercopa De Espana Final featuring Real Madrid and Barcelona, outlining when and where viewers can watch the match.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Supercopa De Espana final between Real Madrid and Barcelona</li>
  <li>Details on live streaming and telecast</li>
  <li>Timing and platforms for viewing</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"When and where to watch the Supercopa De Espana final."</blockquote>
<p>This final match promises to be an exciting showdown between two top teams, marking an important event in the football calendar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/football/real-madrid-vs-barcelona-live-streaming-supercopa-de-espana-final-live-telecast-when-and-where-to-watch-7458186</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/football/real-madrid-vs-barcelona-live-streaming-supercopa-de-espana-final-live-telecast-when-and-where-to-watch-7458186</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:03:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real Madrid vs Barcelona LIVE score, Spanish Super Cup final: Mbappe, Yamal in starting lineup for RMA v FCB - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/football/real-madrid-vs-barcelona-live-score-updates-spanish-super-cup-final-el-clasico-watch-rma-v-fcb-highlights-streaming-info/article69092976.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/football/real-madrid-vs-barcelona-live-score-updates-spanish-super-cup-final-el-clasico-watch-rma-v-fcb-highlights-streaming-info/article69092976.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real Madrid vs Barcelona LIVE score, Spanish Super Cup final: Mbappe, Yamal in starting lineup for RMA v FCB - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/football/real-madrid-vs-barcelona-live-score-updates-spanish-super-cup-final-el-clasico-watch-rma-v-fcb-highlights-streaming-info/article69092976.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/football/real-madrid-vs-barcelona-live-score-updates-spanish-super-cup-final-el-clasico-watch-rma-v-fcb-highlights-streaming-info/article69092976.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arsenal vs Manchester United HIGHLIGHTS, FA Cup 2024-25: ARS 1-1 MNU; 10-man United wins in penalty shoot-out (5-3) - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAJBVV95cUxOWUlVVUxLcXVkZTNmS3NSTG5WSmFoeHlFNklOakFyZi1VSG5qV3FSR21FeXhWWGJTWXd5anI5dnk5ZlZuYTNoX3kxdTZyS3JqWmJkZS1MRnFsTTJoVUlTNFNHRk85MlJZWWVwMnRhRm0xVFg3ZGdmamZFTFV1V2JTTDdadHNrLTFEdm9PRWtqT3E3NDJoSWY2N2NiZlRiSnZQVkp5Y3VHdjA0d1NDeXZTZi1Va3NZdkJxOEhmNktpNE44cll4S2FrdXNNQkt5dGoxX0hqWXVXMHB6THJQYlFoNm5XcGVHSVM3c1EwN3l4VHNfTEtCUG1ubWdDVF9YalotZl8wX3B5R3FwY2dVdUhkcHNsSE4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAJBVV95cUxOWUlVVUxLcXVkZTNmS3NSTG5WSmFoeHlFNklOakFyZi1VSG5qV3FSR21FeXhWWGJTWXd5anI5dnk5ZlZuYTNoX3kxdTZyS3JqWmJkZS1MRnFsTTJoVUlTNFNHRk85MlJZWWVwMnRhRm0xVFg3ZGdmamZFTFV1V2JTTDdadHNrLTFEdm9PRWtqT3E3NDJoSWY2N2NiZlRiSnZQVkp5Y3VHdjA0d1NDeXZTZi1Va3NZdkJxOEhmNktpNE44cll4S2FrdXNNQkt5dGoxX0hqWXVXMHB6THJQYlFoNm5XcGVHSVM3c1EwN3l4VHNfTEtCUG1ubWdDVF9YalotZl8wX3B5R3FwY2dVdUhkcHNsSE4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:55:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First phase of Bima Sugam project likely to be rolled out mid-2025 - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Phase of Bima Sugam Project Likely to be Rolled Out Mid-2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" alt="insurance" width="826" height="465"><figcaption>The platform aims to democratise insurance in India.</figcaption><p>The first phase of the Bima Sugam project, designed to create an Amazon-like platform for insurance, is set to be launched in mid-2025 after missing prior deadlines.</p><ul><li>The project was initially proposed for launch in January 2023.</li><li>It aims to simplify buying, selling, and servicing of insurance policies.</li><li>Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India (Irdai) chairman Debasish Panda indicated a launch in April 2025, but sources suggest a mid-2025 rollout.</li><li>The initiative has faced multiple delays since its inception in 2022.</li></ul><blockquote>“The idea aims to democratise insurance in India, potentially becoming the first of its kind globally.”</blockquote><p>This project is a significant step toward enhancing insurance access and efficiency in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/finance/insurance/first-phase-of-bima-sugam-project-likely-to-be-rolled-out-mid-2025-125011200268_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/finance/insurance/first-phase-of-bima-sugam-project-likely-to-be-rolled-out-mid-2025-125011200268_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:38:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Motivates Youth To Take Ownership Of 'Viksit Bharat', Warns Against 'Chalta Hai' Attitude - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Motivates Youth To Take Ownership Of 'Viksit Bharat', Warns Against 'Chalta Hai' Attitude</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi addresses the Viksit Bharat Young Leaders Dialogue 2025." title="Prime Minister Narendra Modi addresses the Viksit Bharat Young Leaders Dialogue 2025."><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi addresses the Viksit Bharat Young Leaders Dialogue 2025.</figcaption></figure><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi, during the Viksit Bharat Young Leaders Dialogue 2025, emphasized the importance of youth taking ownership of the nation's development and warned against complacency.</p><ul><li>Modi expressed his faith in the youth to help India become a developed nation.</li><li>He criticized a 'chalta hai' attitude as detrimental to progress.</li><li>Modi highlighted the need for collective effort among citizens to achieve big goals.</li><li>The PM linked personal responsibility to national ownership of 'Viksit Bharat.'</li><li>He commemorated Swami Vivekananda's belief in youth as problem solvers.</li><li>Modi pledged to achieve developed nation status by 2047.</li></ul><blockquote>“Setting and achieving big goals is not just the work of any one government machinery, it is a must that every citizen of the country joins it.” - PM Modi</blockquote><p>In conclusion, PM Modi's address serves as a call to action for young Indians to actively participate in the country's growth efforts, reinforcing that their involvement is crucial for the vision of a developed India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-motivates-youth-to-take-ownership-of-viksit-bharat-warns-against-chalta-hai-attitude-9186253.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-motivates-youth-to-take-ownership-of-viksit-bharat-warns-against-chalta-hai-attitude-9186253.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:37:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV outbreak: Amid global concern, Chinese official says cases in northern China declining - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV outbreak: Amid global concern, Chinese official says cases in northern China declining</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/hmpv-3-1736703321.webp" alt="HMPV" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>Representational image.</figcaption>
<p>The recent outbreak of human metapneumovirus (HMPV) in northern China has sparked concerns about a potential pandemic; however, a health official reports declining rates of infection.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The human metapneumovirus, known for causing flu-like symptoms, is not new and has been present for decades.</li>
  <li>Infections have been rising, but improvements in detection methods have contributed to increased reported cases.</li>
  <li>Reports indicate that the rate of positive HMPV cases is declining, particularly among children aged 14 and below.</li>
  <li>Concerns about the outbreak intensified after images of overwhelmed hospitals circulated in media.</li>
  <li>Experts assert that HMPV differs from COVID-19 in that most people develop some immunity to the virus over time.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The human metapneumovirus is not a new virus, and has been with humans for at least several decades.” - Wang Liping</blockquote>
<p>As of now, there are no vaccines or specific treatments for HMPV. Experts recommend preventive measures to curb the spread of the virus.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/news/world/hmpv-outbreak-amid-global-concern-chinese-official-says-cases-in-northern-china-declining-2025-01-12-970939</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/news/world/hmpv-outbreak-amid-global-concern-chinese-official-says-cases-in-northern-china-declining-2025-01-12-970939</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:35:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Box Office: 'Daaku Maharaaj' Opening Day Early Estimates - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxOQjdzTUdTTEFIcXB5X2FVckFocEJNLVM4S2RnSzJsUkkwY3pZVkhHS2MwNEJ4WmtJWnQ3ZGJiSFkyc055RlZZMFo0eVVxTlFtcTY2dVQtWUxUbDF1NzVOZEJrSHlDY0tiX0stbkNHa1ZhOXdIWXp2RXpwSnI0bUR5NkdjVTJXS1N6TkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxOQjdzTUdTTEFIcXB5X2FVckFocEJNLVM4S2RnSzJsUkkwY3pZVkhHS2MwNEJ4WmtJWnQ3ZGJiSFkyc055RlZZMFo0eVVxTlFtcTY2dVQtWUxUbDF1NzVOZEJrSHlDY0tiX0stbkNHa1ZhOXdIWXp2RXpwSnI0bUR5NkdjVTJXS1N6TkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:34:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer Hindi Box Office Day 3 (Early Trends): Concludes Opening Weekend In The Vicinity Of 25 Crores, All Eyes On Sankranti Holiday! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Hindi Box Office Day 3 (Early Trends)</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2025/01/game-changer-hindi-box-office-day-3-early-trends.jpg" alt="Game Changer Hindi Box Office Day 3"><figcaption>Game Changer Hindi Box Office Day 3 Early Estimates! (Photo Credit – Instagram)</figcaption><p>Ram Charan and Kiara Advani's film, Game Changer, had a promising start but has seen a decline in box office collections as it concludes its opening weekend.</p><ul><li>The film collected approximately <strong>7.80-8.20 crores</strong> on Day 3, showing about a 7-3% drop from Day 2's <strong>8.43 crores</strong>.</li><li>Total collections for the opening weekend stand between <strong>24.87-25.27 crores</strong>.</li><li>Despite a strong opening, the film's performance is falling short compared to other regional releases, particularly <strong>Devara</strong>.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Box office numbers are based on estimates and various sources. Numbers have not been independently verified by Koimoi.”</p></blockquote><p>As the Sankranti holiday approaches, there could be an uptick in viewership, but the film’s fate will depend on its performance during the regular working days that follow.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/game-changer-hindi-box-office-day-3-early-trends-concludes-opening-weekend-in-the-vicinity-of-25-crores-all-eyes-on-sankranti-holiday/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/game-changer-hindi-box-office-day-3-early-trends-concludes-opening-weekend-in-the-vicinity-of-25-crores-all-eyes-on-sankranti-holiday/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:32:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daaku Maharaaj success party: Balayya kisses Bobby - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daaku Maharaaj success party: Balayya kisses Bobby</h1><p><strong>Published on Jan 12, 2025</strong> | Source: 123Telugu</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/balajkrishna.jpg" alt="Balayya and Bobby at the success party" width="541" height="550"><figcaption>Balayya kisses director Bobby at the success party.</figcaption><p>Daaku Maharaaj has taken a solid start at the box office, and the team is overwhelmed with the response, celebrating the success with a party in Hyderabad.</p><ul><li>Director Bobby shared a viral picture of Balayya kissing him, showcasing their joy over the film’s success.</li><li>Naga Vamsi produced the film on a grand scale.</li><li>Balakrishna's unique avatar in the film has won the hearts of many.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s no surprise that the team is celebrating in style.”</blockquote><p>With its great start at the box office, Daaku Maharaaj not only sets a precedent for future projects but also highlights the synergy between the cast and crew.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/daaku-maharaaj-success-party-balayya-kisses-bobby.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/daaku-maharaaj-success-party-balayya-kisses-bobby.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra: 8 dead, several injured as tempo rams into truck carrying iron rods in Nashik - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxNQ3Y4VXNUNWFLV0VtdzlwVlJXN3dCTDg0emo5NzlTS2RtSUtxMHlXXzE4eXJTa3lOMHBQNV8wdm04b3FoYjB0OGlHejlTbnpKNHpkbnVkNldrZDlJb1I1eERzeklHR0V1WVNQNzhPTVZOVURlTXZfQlhQOEVCbjF6VWJKYXhtV2tvQWd3U1plRTZRdUFtb2R2cEp1WjI1RVNQZmNUY0NDLWpTaUs3T1VpWlZ5V2ktaWRZdUx3U0p3SXZGYkh5MUs2NTNwdXlZVjM2eXFFbHJjUXpFa1BsNlpZN3g2Rk4wd9IB6wFBVV95cUxPcG9GTzVQT3gtRWRkSkhYbno3SUp6VGJHdHVoX2JiLW5mOUlPcTdJdVloRGxrTkJzTTRqRkI3NWN2Wk5XdGJLam1MNDZwbkx1X2FMMkpOcXdqZ0VXNTVOM2pOQ2JSakNwVDlxQTdGNjRUd0FCYnVSNDNWdHFXdGVQSy1ld1R5ZXlzbGFUNTRIZWN6Q053dFhXVnN2UTgyNVJOaTdKUHdGemczSFJydGNaZlZHUEZxcmRXbkx5anMwZFdGeExoc2xzVzgxUVp1bnMyYldhQkZaUXZILXE2NUpGM3pfbVlqOS1rNVhz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxNQ3Y4VXNUNWFLV0VtdzlwVlJXN3dCTDg0emo5NzlTS2RtSUtxMHlXXzE4eXJTa3lOMHBQNV8wdm04b3FoYjB0OGlHejlTbnpKNHpkbnVkNldrZDlJb1I1eERzeklHR0V1WVNQNzhPTVZOVURlTXZfQlhQOEVCbjF6VWJKYXhtV2tvQWd3U1plRTZRdUFtb2R2cEp1WjI1RVNQZmNUY0NDLWpTaUs3T1VpWlZ5V2ktaWRZdUx3U0p3SXZGYkh5MUs2NTNwdXlZVjM2eXFFbHJjUXpFa1BsNlpZN3g2Rk4wd9IB6wFBVV95cUxPcG9GTzVQT3gtRWRkSkhYbno3SUp6VGJHdHVoX2JiLW5mOUlPcTdJdVloRGxrTkJzTTRqRkI3NWN2Wk5XdGJLam1MNDZwbkx1X2FMMkpOcXdqZ0VXNTVOM2pOQ2JSakNwVDlxQTdGNjRUd0FCYnVSNDNWdHFXdGVQSy1ld1R5ZXlzbGFUNTRIZWN6Q053dFhXVnN2UTgyNVJOaTdKUHdGemczSFJydGNaZlZHUEZxcmRXbkx5anMwZFdGeExoc2xzVzgxUVp1bnMyYldhQkZaUXZILXE2NUpGM3pfbVlqOS1rNVhz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:55:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Khanna reveals media misquoted his statement about Amitabh Bachchan and Tiger Shroff - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mukesh-khanna-reveals-media-misquoted-his-statement-about-amitabh-bachchan-and-tiger-shroff/articleshow/117178804.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mukesh-khanna-reveals-media-misquoted-his-statement-about-amitabh-bachchan-and-tiger-shroff/articleshow/117178804.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 killed after bus plunges 100 metres into gorge in Uttarakhand - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 killed after bus plunges 100 metres into gorge in Uttarakhand</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/uttarakhand-accident.jpg?w=640' alt='Uttarakhand bus accident' width='640' height='360'><figcaption>The bus was travelling from Pauri to Dehalchauri with 22 passengers on board. (Express photo)</figcaption><p>Six people died and several were injured after a private bus fell into a gorge in Uttarakhand’s Pauri Garhwal district on Sunday evening.</p><ul><li>The bus was carrying 28 passengers from Pauri to Dehalchauri.</li><li>Emergency services were alerted around 4:30 pm when the bus lost control and fell 100 metres.</li><li>Rescue work was immediately initiated by the State Disaster Response Force and local police.</li><li>The injured were taken to a district hospital; some were referred to Srinagar hospital.</li><li>The deceased included Sunita (25), Pramila, Priyanshu (17), Nagendra, Sulochna, and Prem (70).</li></ul><blockquote>“The deeply tragic news of the bus accident... I pray to the Almighty to grant peace to the departed souls and give strength to the grieving families.” - Chief Minister Pushkar Singh Dhami</blockquote><p>This tragic accident highlights the risks associated with mountainous travel and the urgency for improved road safety measures in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/uttarakhand-bus-accident-five-killed-pauri-garhwal-district-9775116/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/uttarakhand-bus-accident-five-killed-pauri-garhwal-district-9775116/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer worldwide box office collection Day 2: Ram Charan’s film sees massive dip, collects Rs 72.5 crore - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer worldwide box office collection Day 2: Ram Charan’s film sees massive dip, collects Rs 72.5 crore</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 12, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Kiara-Advani-Ram-Charan.jpg?w=640" alt="Game Changer Box Office Collection Day 2" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Game Changer Box Office Collection Day 2: Kiara Advani and Ram Charan's Game Changer disappoints with box office collection. (Photo: Ram Charan/Instagram)</figcaption><p>The political action film Game Changer, starring Ram Charan and Kiara Advani, faced a significant decline in box office collections on its second day, totaling Rs 72.5 crore in India.</p><ul><li>The film earned Rs 51 crore on its opening day.</li><li>Day 2 saw a dip of 57.84% with a collection of Rs 21.5 crore.</li><li>The Telugu version grossed Rs 53.95 crore, while the Hindi version brought in Rs 14.5 crore.</li><li>The film has been accused of inflating its box office numbers.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“The king’s arrival is setting the box office ablaze 🤙🏼 #GameChanger takes a blockbuster opening at the BOX OFFICE 💥💥 GROSSES 186 CRORES WORLDWIDE on Day 1 ❤‍🔥” — Game Changer (@GameChangerOffl)</p></blockquote><p>The film is directed by S Shankar and features a notable cast, including Nassar and Brahmanandam.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-2-ram-charan-film-sees-massive-dip-9774114/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/game-changer-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-2-ram-charan-film-sees-massive-dip-9774114/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arsenal vs Manchester United LIVE Score, FA Cup 2024-25: ARS 1-1 MNU; Dalot sees red; Bayindir denies Odegaard from the spot - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAJBVV95cUxOWUlVVUxLcXVkZTNmS3NSTG5WSmFoeHlFNklOakFyZi1VSG5qV3FSR21FeXhWWGJTWXd5anI5dnk5ZlZuYTNoX3kxdTZyS3JqWmJkZS1MRnFsTTJoVUlTNFNHRk85MlJZWWVwMnRhRm0xVFg3ZGdmamZFTFV1V2JTTDdadHNrLTFEdm9PRWtqT3E3NDJoSWY2N2NiZlRiSnZQVkp5Y3VHdjA0d1NDeXZTZi1Va3NZdkJxOEhmNktpNE44cll4S2FrdXNNQkt5dGoxX0hqWXVXMHB6THJQYlFoNm5XcGVHSVM3c1EwN3l4VHNfTEtCUG1ubWdDVF9YalotZl8wX3B5R3FwY2dVdUhkcHNsSE4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAJBVV95cUxOWUlVVUxLcXVkZTNmS3NSTG5WSmFoeHlFNklOakFyZi1VSG5qV3FSR21FeXhWWGJTWXd5anI5dnk5ZlZuYTNoX3kxdTZyS3JqWmJkZS1MRnFsTTJoVUlTNFNHRk85MlJZWWVwMnRhRm0xVFg3ZGdmamZFTFV1V2JTTDdadHNrLTFEdm9PRWtqT3E3NDJoSWY2N2NiZlRiSnZQVkp5Y3VHdjA0d1NDeXZTZi1Va3NZdkJxOEhmNktpNE44cll4S2FrdXNNQkt5dGoxX0hqWXVXMHB6THJQYlFoNm5XcGVHSVM3c1EwN3l4VHNfTEtCUG1ubWdDVF9YalotZl8wX3B5R3FwY2dVdUhkcHNsSE4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:41:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karun Nair went six months without playing to becoming one of the top performers of the Vijay Hazare Trophy — now selectors are interested - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karun Nair's Remarkable Comeback in the Vijay Hazare Trophy</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<p>Karun Nair, a notable figure in Indian cricket, has made a stellar comeback after a six-month hiatus from the game, becoming one of the top performers in the Vijay Hazare Trophy. With several centuries to his name, he has drawn the attention of national selectors during a pivotal transitional phase for the Indian Test team.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nair went six months without playing, focusing on improving his skills during this time.</li>
  <li>He scored his fifth century in the ongoing Vijay Hazare Trophy, helping Vidarbha secure a place in the semi-finals.</li>
  <li>Despite being overlooked previously, his recent performances have put him back on the selectors' radar.</li>
  <li>He set a record for the most runs in List A cricket between dismissals, making a remarkable 542 runs before being dismissed.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Dear cricket, give me one more chance.” — Karun Nair</blockquote>
<p>In summary, Nair's dedication and hard work in overcoming a challenging period have led to significant achievements, demonstrating his potential for a return to the national team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/karun-nair-comeback-six-months-vidarbha-vijay-hazare-trophy-selectors-interest-9775306/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/karun-nair-comeback-six-months-vidarbha-vijay-hazare-trophy-selectors-interest-9775306/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:33:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab Kings Announce New Captain For IPL 2025: "We Had Identified..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Punjab Kings Announce New Captain For IPL 2025: "We Had Identified..."</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> 26 November 2024, NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/b2jckqm8_punjab-kings_625x300_26_November_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Punjab Kings captain announcement" />
<figcaption>Representational image © BCCI</figcaption>
<p>The Punjab Kings have officially named Shreyas Iyer as their captain for the upcoming IPL 2025 season, in a unique announcement made by Bollywood star Salman Khan on 'Bigg Boss'.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shreyas Iyer has been chosen as captain after a successful stint in 2024, including victories in the Ranji Trophy and IPL.</li>
  <li>The decision was publicly made on a popular reality TV show, adding excitement to the announcement.</li>
  <li>Iyer expressed gratitude and optimism for the future, aiming to help the team secure its first title.</li>
  <li>Head Coach Ricky Ponting and Punjab Kings CEO Satish Menon highlighted Iyer's proven leadership and vision for the team.</li>
  <li>Iyer was acquired for a record Rs 26.75 crore, marking him as one of the most expensive players in the IPL auction.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I am honoured that the team has reposed its faith in me. ... I hope to repay the faith shown by the management to deliver our maiden title.” – Shreyas Iyer</blockquote>
<p>Punjab Kings are optimistic about their season ahead with a strong combination of experienced and young talent under Iyer's leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/ipl-2025/punjab-kings-announce-new-captain-for-ipl-2025-we-had-identified-7458632</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/ipl-2025/punjab-kings-announce-new-captain-for-ipl-2025-we-had-identified-7458632</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:30:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five killed as bus falls into 100-metre gorge in Uttarakhand's Pauri Garhwal - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Five killed as bus falls into 100-metre gorge in Uttarakhand's Pauri Garhwal</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023-10-28 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/0aeb5eef7121b1b18b717662a4a03b25.jpeg' alt='Bus Accident in Uttarakhand'><figcaption>Bus fell into a gorge</figcaption><p>A tragic incident occurred in Uttarakhand when a bus fell into a 100-metre gorge, resulting in the deaths of five passengers and injuring many others.</p><ul><li>The accident took place in Pauri Garhwal district.</li><li>Authorities are investigating the cause of the accident.</li><li>The bus was carrying a mix of locals and tourists.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a devastating incident, and we are doing everything possible to provide aid,” stated a local official.</blockquote><p>This unfortunate event raises concerns about road safety in hilly regions and the need for improved infrastructure to prevent such tragedies in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/five-killed-as-bus-falls-into-100-metre-gorge-in-uttarakhands-pauri-garhwal/articleshow/117178174.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/five-killed-as-bus-falls-into-100-metre-gorge-in-uttarakhands-pauri-garhwal/articleshow/117178174.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>