<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:19:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:19:49 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple to ‘clarify’ AI-generated summaries after BBC flags factual errors - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/artificial-intelligence/apple-to-clarify-ai-generated-summaries-after-bbc-flags-factual-errors-9767582/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/artificial-intelligence/apple-to-clarify-ai-generated-summaries-after-bbc-flags-factual-errors-9767582/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple to ‘clarify’ AI-generated summaries after BBC flags factual errors - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/artificial-intelligence/apple-to-clarify-ai-generated-summaries-after-bbc-flags-factual-errors-9767582/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/artificial-intelligence/apple-to-clarify-ai-generated-summaries-after-bbc-flags-factual-errors-9767582/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:33:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Squad For Champions Trophy And England ODIs Live Updates: Mohammed Shami's Return Date Confirmed? - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Squad For Champions Trophy And England ODIs Live Updates: Mohammed Shami's Return Date Confirmed?</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>Cricket fans are eagerly awaiting updates regarding the Indian squad for the upcoming Champions Trophy and England ODIs, particularly focusing on the return of Mohammed Shami.</p>
<ul>
<li>Mohammed Shami's comeback date is under discussion.</li>
<li>Live updates are being provided as developments occur.</li>
<li>The Indian cricket team's preparations are highlighted in anticipation of their upcoming matches.</li>
</ul>
<p>This live update covers significant changes and news related to the players and the team's strategy as they gear up for international competitions.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-india-vs-england-odi-t20-full-squads-announcement-live-updates-england-tour-of-india-7413646</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-india-vs-england-odi-t20-full-squads-announcement-live-updates-england-tour-of-india-7413646</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:23:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real or Fake? NASA astronaut captures aurora from space, netizens say 'Looks like AI' | Viral video | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Real or Fake? NASA astronaut captures aurora from space, netizens say ’Looks like AI’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Auroras are once again captivating attention after astronaut Donald Pettit shared a mesmerizing video of the phenomenon from the International Space Station. The visually stunning clip has ignited debate online regarding its authenticity.</p><blockquote>“Flying over aurora; intensely green.” — Don Pettit</blockquote><img src='https://t.co/leUufKFnBB' alt='Aurora from ISS' /><figcaption>NASA astronaut Don Pettit captures the breathtaking view of auroras.</figcaption><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The 9-second video features swirling green lights across Earth’s atmosphere.</li><li>Social media reactions are mixed, with some praising the visuals and others doubting their authenticity.</li><li>Users expressed awe and skepticism, questioning the altitude and image quality of the aurora.</li></ul><h2>What are auroras?</h2><p>Auroras occur when charged particles from the Sun collide with Earth's atmospheric atoms, resulting in beautiful displays of light in various colors.</p><p>The phenomenon has sparked discussions about natural beauty versus technological manipulation among social media users.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/real-or-fake-nasa-astronaut-captures-aurora-from-space-netizens-say-looks-like-ai-viral-video-11736336114776.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/real-or-fake-nasa-astronaut-captures-aurora-from-space-netizens-say-looks-like-ai-viral-video-11736336114776.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:15:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Roadmap Clear For Chandrayaan-4’: What Dr V Narayanan Said After Becoming New ISRO Chief - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Roadmap Clear For Chandrayaan-4: Insights from New ISRO Chief Dr. V Narayanan</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="New ISRO Chief Dr V Narayanan speaks to reporters. (Photo: News18)"><figcaption>New ISRO Chief Dr V Narayanan speaks to reporters. (Photo: News18)</figcaption><p>Rocket Scientist Dr V Narayanan has been appointed the new chief of the Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO), emphasizing his commitment to enhancing the lives of Indians through advancements in technology and science.</p><ul><li>Narayanan takes over for S Somanath, commencing his two-year term on January 14, 2025.</li><li>He expressed confidence in India's future space missions, including Chandrayaan-4, Gaganyan, and Venus orbital missions.</li><li>The IIT-Karakpur alumnus highlighted a clear roadmap for ISRO's upcoming projects.</li><li>Narayanan credits his team and predecessors for inspiring his work and success.</li></ul><blockquote>“To be frank, I didn’t even imagine that I would be in such a position.” - Dr. V Narayanan</blockquote><p>With nearly four decades of experience at ISRO, Narayanan aims to address significant national needs through space technology, including climate studies and disaster management.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/roadmap-clear-for-chandrayaan-4-what-dr-v-narayanan-said-after-becoming-new-isro-chief-9181943.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/roadmap-clear-for-chandrayaan-4-what-dr-v-narayanan-said-after-becoming-new-isro-chief-9181943.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:12:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi holds roadshow, unveils projects worth ₹2 lakh crore in Andhra Pradesh's Visakhapatnam - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-holds-roadshow-unveils-projects-worth-rs-2-lakh-crore-in-andhra-pradeshs-visakhapatnam-101736338440544.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-holds-roadshow-unveils-projects-worth-rs-2-lakh-crore-in-andhra-pradeshs-visakhapatnam-101736338440544.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:53:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Industry Leaders Address Concerns Over Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in India - Elets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOSjFCcDhIckhWVURTNXBfUVJZNDlodHhvQk5LVlZBZ1RVQTJ5bE9Ba2RxUFpuUWdyVHR5V2gtdkFwZHlDY1ZzX240VzY2QThMZGJDQ0x0VGl0ckxvXy1ib1RvMC1palZHMHpUa0RTaVV2ZTNtalM4SmF4aW5rVWcyMVAwb2wtUUdDWjZEbHZYWHAzVkRtUFZmOXZHUmxjci0yd2pQbUt6RU1TUXJqT3JYWmJwVDBNUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOSjFCcDhIckhWVURTNXBfUVJZNDlodHhvQk5LVlZBZ1RVQTJ5bE9Ba2RxUFpuUWdyVHR5V2gtdkFwZHlDY1ZzX240VzY2QThMZGJDQ0x0VGl0ckxvXy1ib1RvMC1palZHMHpUa0RTaVV2ZTNtalM4SmF4aW5rVWcyMVAwb2wtUUdDWjZEbHZYWHAzVkRtUFZmOXZHUmxjci0yd2pQbUt6RU1TUXJqT3JYWmJwVDBNUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:39:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13 vs OnePlus 12: How OnePlus’ latest flagship smartphone compares against its predecessor - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 vs OnePlus 12: How OnePlus’ latest flagship smartphone compares against its predecessor</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>In this article, we explore how the OnePlus 13 compares to its predecessor, the OnePlus 12, analyzing the upgrades, features, and performance differences between the two models.</p><ul><li>The OnePlus 13 offers enhanced camera capabilities over the OnePlus 12.</li><li>Performance improvements include a faster processor and increased RAM.</li><li>Battery life has been extended, allowing for longer usage times.</li><li>New design elements differentiate the OnePlus 13 from its predecessor.</li></ul><blockquote>One notable upgrade in the OnePlus 13 is its improved AI capabilities for photography.</blockquote><p>Ultimately, the OnePlus 13 presents significant advancements over the OnePlus 12, catering to both photography enthusiasts and power users.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/mobiles-tabs/oneplus-13-vs-oneplus-12-how-oneplus-latest-flagship-smartphone-compares-against-its-predecessor/articleshow/117057706.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/mobiles-tabs/oneplus-13-vs-oneplus-12-how-oneplus-latest-flagship-smartphone-compares-against-its-predecessor/articleshow/117057706.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV: WHO says no report of any unusual outbreak pattern - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV: WHO says no report of any unusual outbreak pattern</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 08, 2025 07:01 pm IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/91jrtw/article69076786.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/AFP__20250107__36T93AN__v1__HighRes__IndiaHealthVirus.jpg" alt="Image for representation." title="Image for representation."><figcaption>Image for representation. | Photo Credit: AFP</figcaption><p>The World Health Organisation (WHO) is monitoring HMPV and has stated that there have been no unusual outbreak patterns reported from China. The Chinese health care system remains stable with no emergency responses triggered.</p><ul><li>WHO is in regular contact with Chinese health officials.</li><li>No reports of health system overload or emergency declarations in China.</li><li>WHO monitors respiratory illnesses through collaborative surveillance systems.</li><li>Recent weeks saw an increase in seasonal respiratory infections, including HMPV.</li><li>The increase in detections falls within expected seasonal trends.</li><li>HMPV is common and usually causes mild symptoms similar to the common cold.</li></ul><blockquote>“HMPV is a common respiratory virus found to circulate in many countries in winter through to spring, although not all countries routinely test and publish data on trends in HMPV.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while respiratory illnesses have increased in China, the WHO emphasizes that the situation remains manageable and within expected ranges for this time of year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/hmpv-who-in-contact-with-chinese-health-officials-says-no-report-of-any-unusual-outbreak-pattern/article69076798.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/hmpv-who-in-contact-with-chinese-health-officials-says-no-report-of-any-unusual-outbreak-pattern/article69076798.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Triptii Dimri's exit from Aashiqui 3 allegedly due to her bold image in Animal, Kangana Ranaut on censor - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Triptii Dimri Exits Aashiqui 3 Amid Bold Image Concerns and Kangana Ranaut's Censor Board Controversy</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117056950,imgsize-52370,width-400,resizemode-4/117056950.jpg" alt="Triptii Dimri's exit from Aashiqui 3" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Triptii Dimri during a previous event.</figcaption>
<p>This article covers the latest news in the entertainment industry, focusing on Triptii Dimri's exit from Aashiqui 3, the reaction of Kangana Ranaut to the censor board's cuts of her film Emergency, and other significant events in Bollywood.</p>
<ul>
<li>Triptii Dimri exits Aashiqui 3, allegedly due to her bold image perceived after her role in Animal.</li>
<li>Kangana Ranaut responds to the censor board cutting scenes from her directorial film Emergency, emphasizing the film's respectful portrayal of historical events.</li>
<li>A man has been arrested for stealing diamond jewelry and cash from actress Poonam Dhillon's home.</li>
<li>Manoj Bajpayee reflects on his bond with late actor Sushant Singh Rajput.</li>
<li>Fans express excitement over a potential collaboration between Shah Rukh Khan and his son Aryan Khan after a recent photoshoot.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Kangana Ranaut stated, "The film was not intended to mock anyone... it’s meant to convey historical events with respect." </blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the entertainment industry is buzzing with news about key developments, reflecting both personal struggles and broader societal issues faced by its stars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/triptii-dimris-exit-from-aashiqui-3-being-due-to-her-image-kangana-ranaut-on-censor-board-cutting-scenes-from-emergency-accused-in-poonam-dhillons-home-robbery-case-arrested-top-5-entertainment-news-of-the-day/articleshow/117056950.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/triptii-dimris-exit-from-aashiqui-3-being-due-to-her-image-kangana-ranaut-on-censor-board-cutting-scenes-from-emergency-accused-in-poonam-dhillons-home-robbery-case-arrested-top-5-entertainment-news-of-the-day/articleshow/117056950.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Nation, One Election meet: Opposition MPs question simultaneous polls, BJP members defend - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>One Nation, One Election meet: Opposition MPs question simultaneous polls, BJP members defend</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Lok_Sabha_1736342017982_1736342018260.jpg" alt="On December 18, 2024, The Constitution (129th Amendment) Bill and the Union Territories Laws (Amendment) Bill were introduced by the Centre in Lok Sabha during the Winter Session of Parliament(ANI file)" title="On December 18, 2024, The Constitution (129th Amendment) Bill and the Union Territories Laws (Amendment) Bill were introduced by the Centre in Lok Sabha during the Winter Session of Parliament(ANI file)">
<figcaption>On December 18, 2024, The Constitution (129th Amendment) Bill and the Union Territories Laws (Amendment) Bill were introduced by the Centre in Lok Sabha during the Winter Session of Parliament(ANI file)</figcaption>
<p>The first meeting of the Joint Parliamentary Committee (JPC) on ‘One Nation, One Election’ bills featured a debate between opposition members and BJP MPs regarding the implications of simultaneous elections.</p>
<ul>
<li>The JPC discussed the Constitution (129th Amendment) Bill and the Union Territories Laws (Amendment) Bill.</li>
<li>Opposition MPs, including Congress' Priyanka Gandhi Vadra, questioned the claim that simultaneous polls will reduce expenditure.</li>
<li>BJP members defended the bills, citing past instances of simultaneous polls and claiming public support for the idea.</li>
<li>Several opposition parties alleged that the proposed laws threaten federalism and undermine regional representation.</li>
<li>Concerns were raised about the impact on local issues and the engagement of elected representatives with their constituents.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Upholding people's democratic rights is more important than saving money.” - TMC MP</blockquote>
<p>The meeting highlighted significant divisions between government and opposition views on electoral reform and its effects on democratic processes in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/one-nation-one-election-meet-opposition-mps-question-simultaneous-polls-bjp-members-defend-101736340661818.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/one-nation-one-election-meet-opposition-mps-question-simultaneous-polls-bjp-members-defend-101736340661818.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:23:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World's first wooden satellite sent to Earth's orbit - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/science-tech/worlds-first-wooden-satellite-sent-to-earths-orbit-8602411</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/science-tech/worlds-first-wooden-satellite-sent-to-earths-orbit-8602411</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:11:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World's first wooden satellite sent to Earth's orbit - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/science-tech/worlds-first-wooden-satellite-sent-to-earths-orbit-8602411</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/science-tech/worlds-first-wooden-satellite-sent-to-earths-orbit-8602411</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:11:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cricket, Security & Aid: What Foreign Secretary Misri Discussed With Taliban Minister In Dubai - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cricket, Security & Aid: What Foreign Secretary Misri Discussed With Taliban Minister In Dubai</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Indian foreign secretary Vikram Misri with Acting Foreign Minister of Afghanistan Mawlawi Amir Khan Muttaqi (of the Taliban) in Dubai." title="Indian foreign secretary Vikram Misri with Acting Foreign Minister of Afghanistan Mawlawi Amir Khan Muttaqi (of the Taliban) in Dubai."><figcaption>Indian foreign secretary Vikram Misri with Acting Foreign Minister of Afghanistan Mawlawi Amir Khan Muttaqi (of the Taliban) in Dubai.</figcaption></figure><p>Indian foreign secretary Vikram Misri met Taliban Defence Minister Muttaqi in Dubai, marking one of the first high-level discussions between New Delhi and the Taliban government.</p><ul><li>Misri and Muttaqi discussed India’s ongoing humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan.</li><li>They evaluated bilateral issues and the regional security situation.</li><li>India reaffirmed its commitment to aid the Afghan people, including support for health sectors and refugee rehabilitation.</li><li>Cricket cooperation was also a topic, reflecting its popularity among Afghan youth.</li><li>The use of Chabahar port was discussed to enhance trade and humanitarian aid.</li></ul><blockquote>“India reiterated its commitment to continue to provide humanitarian & development assistance to the Afghan people.” – Randhir Jaiswal</blockquote><p>The meeting highlights ongoing efforts by India to maintain a relationship with Afghanistan despite its complex political landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/indian-foreign-secretary-misri-meets-taliban-defence-minister-muttaqi-in-dubai-9182290.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/indian-foreign-secretary-misri-meets-taliban-defence-minister-muttaqi-in-dubai-9182290.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:10:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real Northern Lights or AI: Intensely green aurora video from NASA astronaut amazes internet. Why are crit - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAJBVV95cUxNeF85dHdZQnFCY2RPSFMwbjNPd3I5X0h2Q2M0TEdOSW52ZW1ZbXhac2VYYjNkOFQ1WVdabzlxbmxUdUF3X2hJbWlYdjE5WnUzdGltMGRJR01TUHRkRDNOcXNKaFoxR2VmS2FDMmU3OVdGaUQ4eTVOWmZ5ZWhfTTYxMjZmcXA4aHhDTUFBT1p6VlQtY1E3cXRfcDVyM24zajFRamJCb0tEQ2tDenJVeW1OcmJyajJLOXBKakhuSVI1Z2tQS2tUNkNKeTR4UkhyLThkeFJTZVQxRlFBSkprVG5XV2J6TXZGU2puWTB2M1BRbmg5ak02ZjVVU2NHdndEMGpEbE1OakpZVkZpRjhEU3d5ZTdHbW1iQ24xTW45UkRDMjXSAaYCQVVfeXFMTlQtdV8xdWNNQUhQRTFIbWhfVVlTQnhSOW53Uy1Rdk5odkxFRkZIa2hTYXpxMDZvMzlLRzFMTU9xU2ZKSjFZNTFBNktFUDVOb21OT29saktveHc5eUd5dXlVODZlelpLOTAwMl9aakpkNnl0YS1IdmhCWklESkZGSFFOWFQxUTNjdnZTY29lSUloWUFjWDRvNXhlc1NuUndMTXlrRDlnMElMSDk1c0tWS1RpazFQREF5ZDc0a1JMeTMtc2c4WTVPQnlCbEVuaDRnU1l4WU1yWTFQc1hvZDBUeDI5YXFINlZRbjNfbWZBLUd5VGNScTRGNGtQMG9oaEJDdEliNTFNRWpBVHBkUHVzbnp4b1hZU2ltYzFHOHgtNjA0OXAyNlRn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAJBVV95cUxNeF85dHdZQnFCY2RPSFMwbjNPd3I5X0h2Q2M0TEdOSW52ZW1ZbXhac2VYYjNkOFQ1WVdabzlxbmxUdUF3X2hJbWlYdjE5WnUzdGltMGRJR01TUHRkRDNOcXNKaFoxR2VmS2FDMmU3OVdGaUQ4eTVOWmZ5ZWhfTTYxMjZmcXA4aHhDTUFBT1p6VlQtY1E3cXRfcDVyM24zajFRamJCb0tEQ2tDenJVeW1OcmJyajJLOXBKakhuSVI1Z2tQS2tUNkNKeTR4UkhyLThkeFJTZVQxRlFBSkprVG5XV2J6TXZGU2puWTB2M1BRbmg5ak02ZjVVU2NHdndEMGpEbE1OakpZVkZpRjhEU3d5ZTdHbW1iQ24xTW45UkRDMjXSAaYCQVVfeXFMTlQtdV8xdWNNQUhQRTFIbWhfVVlTQnhSOW53Uy1Rdk5odkxFRkZIa2hTYXpxMDZvMzlLRzFMTU9xU2ZKSjFZNTFBNktFUDVOb21OT29saktveHc5eUd5dXlVODZlelpLOTAwMl9aakpkNnl0YS1IdmhCWklESkZGSFFOWFQxUTNjdnZTY29lSUloWUFjWDRvNXhlc1NuUndMTXlrRDlnMElMSDk1c0tWS1RpazFQREF5ZDc0a1JMeTMtc2c4WTVPQnlCbEVuaDRnU1l4WU1yWTFQc1hvZDBUeDI5YXFINlZRbjNfbWZBLUd5VGNScTRGNGtQMG9oaEJDdEliNTFNRWpBVHBkUHVzbnp4b1hZU2ltYzFHOHgtNjA0OXAyNlRn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:48:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who Is Geetu Mohandas: From Best Child Artist To Acclaimed Director Of Yashs Highly Anticipated Toxic - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who Is Geetu Mohandas: From Best Child Artist To Acclaimed Director Of Yash's Highly Anticipated Toxic</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Zee News</p><img src='https://english.cdn.zeenews.com/sites/default/files/2025/01/08/1628665-jh234-2025-01-08t153617.018.jpg?im=Resize=(400)' alt='Geetu Mohandas'><figcaption>Geetu Mohandas</figcaption><p>Geetu Mohandas is making headlines with the teaser of Yash starrer Toxic, showcasing the superstar's bold avatar. The filmmaker's remarkable journey is explored in this article.</p><ul><li>Geetu Mohandas, born on June 8, 1981, in Kerala, is an Indian director and former actress.</li><li>She debuted as a child artist in the film Onnu Muthal Poojyam Vare in 1996 and won the Kerala State Film Award for Best Child Artist.</li><li>Geetu married cinematographer Rajeev Ravi in 2009, and they have a daughter named Aradhana.</li><li>She became known for her role in the acclaimed film Liar's Dice, which was India's official Oscar entry.</li><li>Her latest project is directing the much-anticipated film Toxic, featuring Yash.</li></ul><blockquote>“Toxic - a fairy tale for grown-ups is a story that defies convention and is sure to provoke the chaos within us.” - Geetu Mohandas</blockquote><p>The excitement surrounding Geetu Mohandas and her upcoming film Toxic reflects her journey from a child artist to a critically acclaimed director, contributing significantly to Indian cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/photos/entertainment/who-is-geetu-mohandas-from-best-child-artist-to-acclaimed-director-of-yashs-highly-anticipated-toxic-2841174</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/photos/entertainment/who-is-geetu-mohandas-from-best-child-artist-to-acclaimed-director-of-yashs-highly-anticipated-toxic-2841174</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J&K sets up special ICU ward in Jammu amid HMPV concerns - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxNSk9NeDAxd1VvZ28wRkxtQTZUcG5YZW5ZS004aXRMWEczcmx6UHVQSlhOWXJpNldfbmh2dW5oLTU5WDJqSVhvOVpsRXY4anNNLVJONkVkbWhFa0NtZWE4Q1llWUhXUEZRN2NoT0tTazc1dUJwWDQ2M3puWlBjMDh1TTNhU1pld1JtMVAzY2JhQVA4YjlJY3h6TXU3emFJRGkzUk1lUnJBUkxWN2MzYU0wY2RUTXExWlk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxNSk9NeDAxd1VvZ28wRkxtQTZUcG5YZW5ZS004aXRMWEczcmx6UHVQSlhOWXJpNldfbmh2dW5oLTU5WDJqSVhvOVpsRXY4anNNLVJONkVkbWhFa0NtZWE4Q1llWUhXUEZRN2NoT0tTazc1dUJwWDQ2M3puWlBjMDh1TTNhU1pld1JtMVAzY2JhQVA4YjlJY3h6TXU3emFJRGkzUk1lUnJBUkxWN2MzYU0wY2RUTXExWlk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:28:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The curious case of Abhimanyu Easwaran: A perpetual wait for maiden India cap - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/the-curious-case-of-abhimanyu-easwaran-a-perpetual-wait-for-maiden-india-cap/articleshow/117055476.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/the-curious-case-of-abhimanyu-easwaran-a-perpetual-wait-for-maiden-india-cap/articleshow/117055476.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The curious case of Abhimanyu Easwaran: A perpetual wait for maiden India cap - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/the-curious-case-of-abhimanyu-easwaran-a-perpetual-wait-for-maiden-india-cap/articleshow/117055476.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/the-curious-case-of-abhimanyu-easwaran-a-perpetual-wait-for-maiden-india-cap/articleshow/117055476.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer (Hindi) Box Office Preview: Ram Charan, Kiara Advani starrer run time, screen count, advance booking & opening day - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer (Hindi) Box Office Preview</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p><img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/421829640_game-changer-shankar-ram-charan-theatrical-main-1.jpg" alt="Game Changer (Hindi) Box Office Preview" title="Game Changer (Hindi) Box Office Preview: Ram Charan, Kiara Advani starrer run time, screen count, advance booking & opening day"><figcaption>Game Changer (Hindi) Box Office Preview: Ram Charan, Kiara Advani's Upcoming Film</figcaption><p>Game Changer, starring Ram Charan and Kiara Advani, is set to release on January 10, 2025, and is expected to earn between Rs 2.25 crore and Rs 3.00 crore on its opening day.</p><ul><li>The film is directed by Shankar and features a runtime of 2 hours and 44 minutes.</li><li>It aims for a wide release on over 2000 screens with a focus on mass belts and single screens.</li><li>Advance bookings indicate positive momentum with around 1000 tickets sold in major chains as of Wednesday afternoon.</li><li>The film's success heavily relies on word of mouth and audience turnout.</li></ul><blockquote>“A lot for Game Changer in Hindi will depend on the word of mouth, as a positive talk is a must for the film to recover the big investment.”</blockquote><p>The anticipation for this film hinges on its content, with high hopes for its performance at the box office.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/game-changer-hindi-box-office-preview-ram-charan-kiara-advani-starrer-run-time-screen-count-advance-booking-opening-day-1366267</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/game-changer-hindi-box-office-preview-ram-charan-kiara-advani-starrer-run-time-screen-count-advance-booking-opening-day-1366267</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:05:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘He never spoke about his cheeks’: Priyanka Gandhi reacts to Ramesh Bidhuri's remark - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxOV1ItVVFZQ0g5Qk5CekVNa0szMDNlekdRdjdYX094WVZoR2o2Nm5HTm5FSk5qUlpSWm9YY1NvanZTaEdPT1IwZksyMXdpYWIweGtoaVprWXFXZmVGS3UyTk02YjZ6bmhFaEoxdDBoZmM4aTZhMGJxTEx2VUI2cHpsb0FLY1MxdGRHY3puamtiakZqcF82SHlJNVI2TlhnQnNGbWJiMUI1YlBNT05wMVZrdkFHQTZFZTRLVjM1MVNULW5EWjNQM3Jlc0dFRW1aYU5NV3QwQU9yN3J5eGRyRDdadmdOVW5QOXBDaEc0SzlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxOV1ItVVFZQ0g5Qk5CekVNa0szMDNlekdRdjdYX094WVZoR2o2Nm5HTm5FSk5qUlpSWm9YY1NvanZTaEdPT1IwZksyMXdpYWIweGtoaVprWXFXZmVGS3UyTk02YjZ6bmhFaEoxdDBoZmM4aTZhMGJxTEx2VUI2cHpsb0FLY1MxdGRHY3puamtiakZqcF82SHlJNVI2TlhnQnNGbWJiMUI1YlBNT05wMVZrdkFHQTZFZTRLVjM1MVNULW5EWjNQM3Jlc0dFRW1aYU5NV3QwQU9yN3J5eGRyRDdadmdOVW5QOXBDaEc0SzlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:01:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Real or AI?’: NASA astronaut’s stunning aurora video sparks debate over authenticity - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Real or AI?’: NASA astronaut’s stunning aurora video sparks debate over authenticity</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Don Pettit</p><p>A recent video posted by NASA astronaut Don Petit shows a breathtaking aurora from the International Space Station, leading to online discussions about its authenticity.</p><ul><li>The video depicts an intensely green aurora, described by Petit as “Flying over aurora; intensely green.”</li><li>Viewers expressed mixed reactions, with some praising the footage while others doubted its authenticity, suspecting it might be AI-generated.</li><li>Critics pointed out that the ISS might not be that close to Earth for such clear footage.</li></ul><blockquote>“Flying over aurora; intensely green.” — Don Pettit</blockquote><p>Auroras are natural light displays resulting from solar particle interactions with Earth’s atmosphere, visible near the poles.</p><p>In conclusion, while the video captivates many, it also raises questions about the intersection of natural phenomena and technological manipulation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/nasa-astronaut-share-aurora-video-spark-debate-over-authenticity-viral-9767164/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/nasa-astronaut-share-aurora-video-spark-debate-over-authenticity-viral-9767164/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:00:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Formula E Race Case: Telangana High Court Permits KT Rama Rao's Lawyer To Watch ACB Interrogation Through ... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telangana High Court Allows KT Rama Rao's Lawyer to Observe ACB Interrogation in Formula E Case</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p><p>The Telangana High Court has permitted BRS MLA KT Rama Rao's lawyer to observe the interrogation proceedings at the Anti Corruption Bureau (ACB) in the Formula E race case. This ruling allows the lawyer to be present in a library opposite the interrogation room with visibility.</p><ul><li>The court clarified that the presence of a lawyer during interrogation is not a fundamental right.</li><li>Justice K Lakshman stated that the lawyer could observe the proceedings from a library room with a glass window.</li><li>The investigating officer was directed to ensure the visibility for the lawyer.</li><li>The court dismissed Rao's plea to quash the FIR regarding alleged irregularities during his tenure as Urban Development Minister.</li><li>Rao's counsel referred to a Supreme Court judgment allowing a lawyer's presence at a visible distance during interrogations.</li></ul><blockquote>“What is the problem in permitting? Petitioner and Investigating Officer will be in one room. Advocate will sit in the visitor's room. Only thing is you have to provide him with some visibility.” - Justice K Lakshman</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the court's decision aims to balance the rights of the accused with the investigative process, allowing for some level of lawyer supervision during the interrogation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/telangana-high-court/telangana-high-court-brs-mla-kt-rama-rao-lawyer-formula-e-race-case-interrogation-280328</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/telangana-high-court/telangana-high-court-brs-mla-kt-rama-rao-lawyer-formula-e-race-case-interrogation-280328</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:51:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Girl, you are no longer Canada's governor': Elon Musk's scathing dig at Justin Trudeau - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Girl, you are no longer Canada's governor: Elon Musk's scathing dig at Justin Trudeau</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250108114303_m.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Elon Musk and Justin Trudeau" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Elon Musk mocks Justin Trudeau via social media.</figcaption><p>Elon Musk took a jab at Justin Trudeau, stating he is no longer relevant following Trudeau's resignation as Prime Minister of Canada. This response came after Trudeau's stark rejection of claims that Canada could become part of the United States.</p><ul><li>Elon Musk referred to Trudeau as a 'girl' in a tweet.</li><li>Trudeau recently announced his resignation and dismissed Trump’s assertions regarding US taking over Canada.</li><li>Trudeau firmly stated, "There isn’t a snowball’s chance in hell that Canada would become part of the United States."</li></ul><blockquote>Girl, you're not the governor of Canada anymore, so doesn't matter what you say - Elon Musk (@elonmusk)</blockquote><p>This exchange highlights tensions between Canadian leadership and US political discourse.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/girl-you-no-longer-canada-s-governor-elon-musk-s-scathing-dig-at-justin-trudeau-12905977.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/girl-you-no-longer-canada-s-governor-elon-musk-s-scathing-dig-at-justin-trudeau-12905977.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:43:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rajnath Singh reaffirms India's support to Maldives to boost defence preparedness - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rajnath Singh Strengthens India's Defense Ties with Maldives</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Rajnath_Singh_1736334885459_1736334885861.jpg" alt="Defence Minister Rajnath Singh interacts with Maldives Defence Minister Mohammed Ghassan Maumoon, at Manekshaw Centre in New Delhi on Wednesday. (Rahul Singh/ANI)"><figcaption>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh interacts with Maldives Defence Minister Mohammed Ghassan Maumoon, at Manekshaw Centre in New Delhi on Wednesday. (Rahul Singh/ANI)</figcaption><p>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh reaffirmed India's commitment to enhancing defense preparedness in the Maldives, underscoring the strategic partnership between the two nations.</p><ul><li>During a recent meeting, India provided defense equipment to the Maldives at the request of the Muizzu government.</li><li>Both countries aim to strengthen their Comprehensive Economic and Maritime Security Partnership.</li><li>India offers support through capability enhancement, including training and infrastructure development.</li><li>The relationship experienced strain after Mohamed Muizzu's government demanded the withdrawal of Indian military personnel.</li></ul><blockquote>“India will continue to support the Maldives and the Maldives National Defence Force in their capacity-building efforts...” - Rajnath Singh</blockquote><p>The ongoing collaboration indicates a potential restoration of trust and cooperation between India and the Maldives following recent diplomatic tensions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rajnath-singh-reaffirms-indias-support-to-maldives-to-boost-defence-preparedness-101736334799412.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rajnath-singh-reaffirms-indias-support-to-maldives-to-boost-defence-preparedness-101736334799412.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:33:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bhima Koregaon: Bombay High Court grants bail to Rona Wilson, Sudhir Dhawale - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bombay High Court Grants Bail to Rona Wilson and Sudhir Dhawale in Bhima Koregaon Case</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-08T11:30:27.190Z">08 Jan 2025, 11:30 am</time></p><p>The Bombay High Court has granted bail to Rona Wilson and Sudhir Dhawale, two individuals accused in the 2018 Bhima Koregaon violence case, citing prolonged confinement and the need to examine numerous witnesses.</p><ul><li>Bail granted on the condition of ₹1 lakh bail bonds.</li><li>Accused are required to report to the National Investigation Agency every Monday.</li><li>Court previously denied default bail to the accused in July 2024.</li><li>Wilson has been in custody since July 2018 under the Unlawful Activities (Prevention) Act.</li><li>The Bhima Koregaon case originated from an event in 2017 that commemorated a significant clash involving Dalit soldiers.</li></ul><blockquote>“Prolonged incarceration, non-framing of charges, and the necessity to examine over 300 witnesses were key reasons for granting bail.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the bail decision reflects ongoing judicial scrutiny of the lengthy detention of the accused in the wake of complex and significant legal narratives surrounding the Bhima Koregaon case.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/bhima-koregaon-bombay-high-court-grants-bail-to-rona-wilson-sudhir-dhawale</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/bhima-koregaon-bombay-high-court-grants-bail-to-rona-wilson-sudhir-dhawale</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:30:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best 55 inch 4K TV for a cinematic experience at home: 10 options from top-selling TV brands - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Best 55 inch 4K TV for a Cinematic Experience at Home: 10 Options</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 - <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/smart_tvs_1736327919391_1736327926107.webp" alt="Check out the best 55 inch 4K TVs to upgrade to a better viewing experience." title="Check out the best 55 inch 4K TVs to upgrade to a better viewing experience."><figcaption>Check out the best 55 inch 4K TVs to upgrade to a better viewing experience.</figcaption></figure><p>This article highlights the transformative experience of watching movies on a 55-inch 4K TV, offering stunning visuals and advanced features for home entertainment.</p><ul><li>The purpose of a 55-inch 4K TV is to enhance home viewing experiences by delivering lifelike visuals and immersive sound.</li><li>4K resolution provides four times the detail of Full HD, with advanced HDR features that enhance brightness and contrast.</li><li>A curated list of top-selling 55-inch 4K TVs includes popular brands like Redmi, Samsung, Sony, and LG.</li></ul><blockquote>“4K TVs offer four times the resolution of Full HD TVs, providing sharper and more detailed images.”</blockquote><p>Each featured TV is evaluated based on specifications, user feedback on platforms like Amazon, and pros and cons, providing comprehensive buying guidance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/best-55-inch-4k-tv-for-a-cinematic-experience-at-home-10-options-from-top-selling-tv-brands-101736327069939.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/best-55-inch-4k-tv-for-a-cinematic-experience-at-home-10-options-from-top-selling-tv-brands-101736327069939.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:30:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Squad For Champions Trophy And England ODIs Live Updates: Misfiring Ravindra Jadeja To Be Axed? - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Squad For Champions Trophy And England ODIs Live Updates: Misfiring Ravindra Jadeja To Be Axed?</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong> Not specified, <strong>Source: </strong> NDTV</p>
<p>Live updates on the Indian squad for the upcoming Champions Trophy and England ODIs, speculating on the potential axing of Ravindra Jadeja due to poor performance.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The discussion focuses on the India's cricket squad preparations.</li>
    <li>Ravindra Jadeja's performance is under scrutiny with suggestions he might be dropped.</li>
    <li>Updates provided as team news continues to develop.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote> “The Indian cricket team is evaluating its options seriously as the new tournament approaches.”</blockquote>
<p>The article emphasizes the significance of team composition ahead of critical matches and the pressure on underperforming players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-india-vs-england-odi-t20-full-squads-announcement-live-updates-england-tour-of-india-7413646</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-india-vs-england-odi-t20-full-squads-announcement-live-updates-england-tour-of-india-7413646</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:27:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi election: Arvind Kejriwal accuses BJP of asking 7 MPs to make 'fake votes' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxPbWxVdVlPNXF5cE9XQXZPcDZHOEh1ZklrbWNKcHpXNUVPcjVua3FmV2FvS1g5dUV5d19OYWtMSGhFZmNKc19yVmUwSlN4VlZ3YUN4NHFmbEZjMHlBaGNVSXRjSVBReVlQY3N2NXJQcXM0N2huUDVCbllsTTRydG02N1dkdWR0TnRoOWpFVUlYNUlVMVN6YWp6aXMzRVFBMXhMWVlrYmRGNDBZSldzdXNmWGxrMWcwNWRkT2kyLUIxTURjemVjbkgwUEFzNFJqN0ZKNlR5Y0Vn0gHbAUFVX3lxTE5OUHh3cVp3UjR4cDlDa1hnN09pSFpwYlYyR1dsenFzRmo0b0cyT24xaGFBSkhSd0JUUmlBMW53Si1LQl9lblhDcHgtYkR1NTllLUUyY0RMdjRvVEdGUVU1YjZtYXo1YW5WbTI1b2Y5SXR4OE53UG1xNmJFbEdrVW05X1FEZlZqQUg2ZmVNQUNqV0dMbm5kZ3JNZFVMRnktZVMzR2VTSGVydGN6bXNUZm5KaHhNM3IzeTZyVmk0VHpqTHpTMUlZbXkteWVzcXZhWkpPZExHSnUxLUFVTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxPbWxVdVlPNXF5cE9XQXZPcDZHOEh1ZklrbWNKcHpXNUVPcjVua3FmV2FvS1g5dUV5d19OYWtMSGhFZmNKc19yVmUwSlN4VlZ3YUN4NHFmbEZjMHlBaGNVSXRjSVBReVlQY3N2NXJQcXM0N2huUDVCbllsTTRydG02N1dkdWR0TnRoOWpFVUlYNUlVMVN6YWp6aXMzRVFBMXhMWVlrYmRGNDBZSldzdXNmWGxrMWcwNWRkT2kyLUIxTURjemVjbkgwUEFzNFJqN0ZKNlR5Y0Vn0gHbAUFVX3lxTE5OUHh3cVp3UjR4cDlDa1hnN09pSFpwYlYyR1dsenFzRmo0b0cyT24xaGFBSkhSd0JUUmlBMW53Si1LQl9lblhDcHgtYkR1NTllLUUyY0RMdjRvVEdGUVU1YjZtYXo1YW5WbTI1b2Y5SXR4OE53UG1xNmJFbEdrVW05X1FEZlZqQUg2ZmVNQUNqV0dMbm5kZ3JNZFVMRnktZVMzR2VTSGVydGN6bXNUZm5KaHhNM3IzeTZyVmk0VHpqTHpTMUlZbXkteWVzcXZhWkpPZExHSnUxLUFVTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:27:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk 'calls' Canada's outgoing PM Justin Trudeau: Girl, you’re not the .... - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk 'calls' Canada's outgoing PM Justin Trudeau: Girl, you’re not the ....</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Publication Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117054619,imgsize-24490,width-400,resizemode-4/117054619.jpg" alt="Elon Musk and Justin Trudeau" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Elon Musk and Justin Trudeau</figcaption>
<p>In a recent post on X, Elon Musk addressed outgoing Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, questioning his relevance following Trudeau's comments on Canada's sovereignty.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Musk referred to Trudeau as “not the governor of Canada anymore.”</li>
  <li>Trudeau affirmed that Canada will not become part of the U.S., emphasizing the friendship between the two nations.</li>
  <li>Musk also interacted with MP Pierre Poilievre, endorsing the idea of a referendum for Canada's sovereignty.</li>
  <li>The comments stirred significant reactions on social media, with many users criticizing Musk's tone.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If this is how officials, leaders, and presidents choose to communicate in 2025, we may be bracing for one of the most tumultuous years in history marked by escalating conflicts and an alarming absence of resolution.”</blockquote>
<p>The exchange highlights the ongoing tension surrounding political discourse in Canada and the impact of social media in shaping public perception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-calls-canadas-former-pm-justin-trudeau-girl-youre-not-the-/articleshow/117054636.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-calls-canadas-former-pm-justin-trudeau-girl-youre-not-the-/articleshow/117054636.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>