<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 08:31:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 08:31:47 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session Live: Nehru jailed Majrooh Sultanpuri, Balraj Sahni, says Sitharaman - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament Winter Session Live: Cong MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra demands restoration of '71 war photo</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/Priyanka-Gandhi-was-speaking-at-the-Lok-Sabha-s-Qu_1734335798714_1734335941890.jpg" alt="Priyanka Gandhi was speaking at the Lok Sabha’s Question Hour during the ongoing winter session. (ANI file photo)" title="Priyanka Gandhi was speaking at the Lok Sabha’s Question Hour during the ongoing winter session. (ANI file photo)"><figcaption>Priyanka Gandhi was speaking at the Lok Sabha’s Question Hour during the ongoing winter session. (ANI file photo)</figcaption><p>During the Winter Session of Parliament, Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra raised the issue of restoring a historic photo from the 1971 war, emphasizing the need to acknowledge the sacrifices of Indian soldiers.</p><ul><li>The final week of the Winter Session features debates on key constitutional issues.</li><li>The government is likely to defer the constitutional amendment bill for simultaneous elections.</li><li>Priyanka Gandhi highlighted the bravery of soldiers and the leadership of Indira Gandhi during the 1971 conflict.</li></ul><blockquote>“I want to salute the brave soldiers who fought for us in the war of 1971,” said Priyanka Gandhi.</blockquote><p>The discussions reflect ongoing tensions regarding historical narratives and national memory within Indian politics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-constitution-debate-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-one-nation-one-election-101734312967322.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-constitution-debate-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-one-nation-one-election-101734312967322.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:40:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Highlights: Bad Light Forces Early Stumps But Advantage Australia - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Highlights: Bad Light Forces Early Stumps But Advantage Australia</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert publication date here] | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>The third day of the Test match between India and Australia was cut short due to bad light, giving Australia a significant advantage.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bad light halted play prematurely on Day 3.</li>
  <li>Australia maintains a strong position in the match.</li>
  <li>The game continues to be competitive with both teams showing resilience.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Australia looks poised to take control of the match as conditions favor them.”</blockquote>
<p>This match highlights the ongoing rivalry between India and Australia, underscoring the unpredictable nature of cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:35:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inventurus Knowledge Solutions IPO Day 3 Live Updates: Issue booked 7.19x so far, check IKS IPO GMP, review, more | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Inventurus Knowledge Solutions IPO Day 3 Updates: Subscribed 13.54x</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 16 Dec, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> HT Digital Streams Limited</p><figure><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2024/12/16/600x338/IKS_IPO_1734318732116_1734318740577.png" alt="Inventurus Knowledge Solutions IPO Day 3 Live Updates" title="Inventurus Knowledge Solutions IPO Day 3 Live Updates: IKS Health IPO was subscribed 2.65 times by the end of the second day of bidding on Friday. The IPO is set to end today, December 16."><figcaption>Inventurus Knowledge Solutions IPO Day 3 Live Updates: IKS Health IPO was subscribed 2.65 times by the end of the second day of bidding on Friday. The IPO is set to end today, December 16.</figcaption></figure><p>The IPO for Inventurus Knowledge Solutions has witnessed significant demand, being subscribed 13.54 times overall. The retail investor segment has seen a strong response, ensuring an impressive bidding process.</p><ul><li>The overall subscription rate reached 13.54 times.</li><li>Retail Individual Investors (RIIs) subscription was 9.13 times.</li><li>Qualified Institutional Buyers (QIBs) segment was subscribed 6.06 times.</li><li>The IPO price band is set at ₹1,265-1,329 per share.</li><li>Inventurus has raised ₹1,120 crore from anchor investors.</li><li>This IPO is an Offer For Sale (OFS) with no new issue of shares.</li><li>Notable players in the company's backing include Rekha Jhunjhunwala.</li></ul><blockquote>"The total addressable market for US enablement technology solutions providers is expected to reach USD 323 bn by CY28."</blockquote><p>As the IPO draws to a close today, market experts highlight it as a considerable opportunity for long-term investors looking into the expanding healthcare sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/inventurus-knowledge-solutions-ipo-day-3-live-updates-issue-booked-2-65x-so-far-check-gmp-subscription-status-more-11734317088436.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/ipo/inventurus-knowledge-solutions-ipo-day-3-live-updates-issue-booked-2-65x-so-far-check-gmp-subscription-status-more-11734317088436.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:25:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NSA Ajit Doval Likely To Visit China For Special Representative Talks: Sources - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NSA Ajit Doval Set to Visit China for Key Talks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="NSA Ajit Doval Likely To Visit China (AP Image)"><figcaption>NSA Ajit Doval Likely To Visit China (AP Image)</figcaption><p>National Security Advisor Ajit Doval is expected to visit China soon for Special Representative talks, according to sources.</p><ul><li>The visit comes after External Affairs Minister Dr. S Jaishankar discussed India-China relations in Parliament.</li><li>Jaishankar highlighted improvements in bilateral ties and full disengagement in eastern Ladakh.</li><li>He remarked on the ongoing diplomatic engagements that have set the stage for better Indo-China ties.</li><li>India and China have faced military tensions since May 2020 due to confrontations in the Galwan Valley.</li></ul><blockquote>“Recent developments that reflect continuous diplomatic engagements have set Indo-China ties in the direction of some improvement,” said Jaishankar.</blockquote><p>The upcoming talks are seen as a crucial step in consolidating progress in India-China relationships following prolonged military standoffs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/nsa-ajit-doval-likely-to-visit-china-for-special-representative-talks-sources-9157543.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/nsa-ajit-doval-likely-to-visit-china-for-special-representative-talks-sources-9157543.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:11:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Love avocados? They have these surprising side effects - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Surprising Side Effects of Eating Too Many Avocados</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified <strong>Source: </strong>Firstpost</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/webstories/uploads/2024/12/cropped-image-2024-12-d0d1fc303d1f507e90ccd83f3680e64e.png" alt="Avocado" />
<figcaption>Avocado - A delicious yet potentially problematic fruit.</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses various side effects that can occur from consuming avocados in excess, despite their many health benefits.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Allergic reactions:</strong> Individuals with latex allergies may have reactions similar to avocado consumption.</li>
<li><strong>Weight gain:</strong> Due to high fat content, overeating avocados can lead to weight gain.</li>
<li><strong>Gastrointestinal issues:</strong> Excessive amounts can cause bloating or diarrhea due to high fiber.</li>
<li><strong>High potassium levels:</strong> Overconsumption may lead to hyperkalemia, affecting heart health.</li>
<li><strong>Medication interference:</strong> Can interact with blood thinners due to vitamin K content.</li>
<li><strong>Nutrient imbalance:</strong> Dominating one's diet with avocados may crowd out other nutrients.</li>
<li><strong>Heartburn or acid reflux:</strong> Some may experience reflux symptoms post-consumption.</li>
<li><strong>Skin issues:</strong> Increased skin oiliness or breakouts can occur for some individuals.</li>
<li><strong>Environmental concerns:</strong> High demand has led to deforestation and unsustainable practices.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Avocados may interact with medications like blood thinners because of their vitamin K content.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while avocados are nutrient-rich, moderation is key to avoiding negative side effects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/web-stories/lifestyle/love-avocados-they-have-these-surprising-side-effects-25010.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/web-stories/lifestyle/love-avocados-they-have-these-surprising-side-effects-25010.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:08:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World chess champion D Gukesh to pay more taxes than MS Dhoni's current IPL salary - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/chess/world-chess-champion-d-gukesh-to-pay-more-taxes-than-ms-dhonis-current-ipl-salary/articleshow/116357057.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/chess/world-chess-champion-d-gukesh-to-pay-more-taxes-than-ms-dhonis-current-ipl-salary/articleshow/116357057.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Entertainment News Live Today December 16, 2024: Diljit Dosanjh announces he won't do shows in India until this happens - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>K-pop and K-drama Stars Nominated for 2nd Pinggyego Awards</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/park_shin_hye_-_lee_dong_wook_-_jennie_1734333329989_1734333337279.jpg" alt="Park Shin Hye, Lee Dong Wook, and Jennie nominated for 2nd Pinggyego Awards" title="Park Shin Hye, Lee Dong Wook, and Jennie nominated for 2nd Pinggyego Awards"><figcaption>Latest entertainment news on December 16, 2024: Park Shin Hye and Lee Dong Wook have been nominated for the Veteran Popular Star Award categories. Meanwhile, BLACKPINK's Jennie received a nod in the Rising Popular Star Award category.</figcaption><p>The 2nd Pinggyego Awards will take place on December 22, showcasing a star-studded list of nominees from the K-pop and K-drama industry.</p><ul><li>The nominations feature top K-pop and K-drama celebrities including Park Shin Hye, Lee Dong Wook, and BLACKPINK's Jennie.</li><li>This year's ceremony promises to highlight rising stars in addition to veteran artists.</li></ul><blockquote>“The 2nd Pinggyego Award will return on December 22.”</blockquote><p>The awards recognize and celebrate the achievements of artists in the Korean entertainment industry, particularly during a year filled with significant contributions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/latest-entertainment-today-live-updates-december-16-2024-101734311142718.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/latest-entertainment-today-live-updates-december-16-2024-101734311142718.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:58:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress Reacts After Omar Abdullah Junks Opposition's EVM Charge - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Reacts After Omar Abdullah Junks Opposition's EVM Charge</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Congress Reacts After Omar Abdullah Junks Opposition's EVM Charge" alt="Congress Reacts After Omar Abdullah Junks Opposition's EVM Charge" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ea9llbfg_rahul-omar-ani_625x300_16_December_24.jpeg"><figcaption>Image showing Congress's response to EVM allegations.</figcaption><p>The Congress party has criticized ally Omar Abdullah's stance on opposition issues, particularly regarding recent allegations of manipulation of Electronic Voting Machines (EVMs), after Abdullah dismissed these claims.</p><ul><li>Omar Abdullah's party, the National Conference, contested the Jammu and Kashmir elections alongside the Congress.</li><li>Congress parliamentarian Manickam Tagore highlighted differing views on EVMs among opposition parties following recent elections.</li><li>Recent opposition claims regarding EVM discrepancies were led by Sharad Pawar's NCP and Shiv Sena (UBT).</li><li>Congress's Working Committee has accused the Election Commission of partisan conduct and hinted at targeted manipulation.</li><li>Abdullah stated that political parties doubting EVMs should refrain from participating in elections.</li></ul><blockquote>Mr. Abdullah stated, "When you get a hundred plus members of parliament using the same EVMs, and you celebrate that... you can't... turn around and say... we don't like these EVMs because now the election results aren't going the way we would like them to."</blockquote><p>The debate over EVM integrity showcases significant differences within the opposition and raises questions about electoral processes in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/congress-reacts-after-omar-abdullah-junks-oppositions-evm-charge-7259008</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/congress-reacts-after-omar-abdullah-junks-oppositions-evm-charge-7259008</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:41:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session Day 17 LIVE Updates: Congress only made Amendments in Constitution to help the dynasty, says FM in RS; Priyanka Gandhi raises concern over human-animal conflict - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament Winter Session Day 17 LIVE Updates: Congress only made Amendments in Constitution to help the dynasty, says FM in RS; Priyanka Gandhi raises concern over human-animal conflict</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/8udn2h/article68990814.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241214408L.jpg" alt="Lok Sabha during the ongoing Winter Session of Parliament" />
<figcaption>Lok Sabha during the ongoing Winter Session of Parliament. File | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption>
<p>The Parliament session on December 16, 2024, saw significant discussions on constitutional amendments and challenges faced by citizens due to human-animal conflicts.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Congress MP Manickam Tagore raised an adjournment motion regarding the removal of a historical 1971 war photograph from Army HQ.</li>
  <li>Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman criticized Congress for amending the Constitution to protect political interests rather than strengthen democracy.</li>
  <li>Priyanka Gandhi highlighted the plight of citizens affected by wild animal attacks, specifically mentioning nearly 90 incidents in Wayanad.</li>
  <li>Sanjay Raut emphasized the government's actions counter to the Constitution during his speech in the Rajya Sabha.</li>
  <li>Debates continued around the historical significance of the Constitution and its ongoing relevance in contemporary politics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Amendments were not about strengthening democracy but protecting those in power,” Nirmala Sitharaman in Rajya Sabha.</blockquote>
<p>This session reflects ongoing tensions between political parties regarding governance and public safety, emphasizing the need for urgent dialogue on these pressing issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/parliament-winter-session-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-live-updates-on-december-16-2024/article68990725.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/parliament-winter-session-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-live-updates-on-december-16-2024/article68990725.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Rain Continues To Halt Play, Tomorrow's Forecast Is... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Score Updates: Bad Light Forces Australia To Deploy Spinners vs India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>On Day 3 of the 3rd Test between India and Australia, bad light has compelled the Australian team to resort to deploying spinners against the Indian batsmen, impacting the pace and dynamic of the game.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bad light conditions have disrupted play.</li>
  <li>Australia's strategy now involves using spinners more frequently.</li>
  <li>Current match analysis focusing on team performances and conditions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The changing conditions have made it tougher for fast bowlers, leading to a shift towards spin bowling."</blockquote>
<p>This development indicates how environmental factors can directly influence the game's strategy and outcomes, highlighting the ever-changing nature of cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:30:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Launches First Diabetes Biobank in Chennai - Adda247]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://currentaffairs.adda247.com/india-launches-first-diabetes-biobank-in-chennai/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://currentaffairs.adda247.com/india-launches-first-diabetes-biobank-in-chennai/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moment of the Weekend: Amad for Amorim - Manchester derby lit up by Diallo's magical strike - ESPN India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amad Diallo Shines in Manchester Derby with Stunning Goal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN</p><p>Amad Diallo's exceptional performance led Manchester United to a thrilling victory against Manchester City, highlighted by a magical strike that secured the win in the Manchester derby.</p><ul><li>Diallo displayed his relentless energy and skill throughout the match.</li><li>He won a penalty that was converted by Bruno Fernandes to equalize the game.</li><li>In the dying moments, Diallo scored the winning goal with a remarkable finish.</li><li>His captain, Fernandes, praised Diallo for his vital contributions.</li></ul><blockquote>“He showed again today he is always alive... He has been brilliant. When he is like this he is unstoppable.” - Bruno Fernandes</blockquote><p>This performance marks a significant moment in Diallo's career as he cements his place in the starting lineup under new coach Ruben Amorim.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espn.in/espn/story/_/id/42997856/amad-diallo-ruben-amorim-manchester-derby-lit-magical-strike-moment-weekend</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espn.in/espn/story/_/id/42997856/amad-diallo-ruben-amorim-manchester-derby-lit-magical-strike-moment-weekend</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple to revamp product lines with sleek iPhone, foldable iPad, and more - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/apple-to-revamp-product-lines-with-sleek-iphone-foldable-ipad-and-more-124121600306_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/apple-to-revamp-product-lines-with-sleek-iphone-foldable-ipad-and-more-124121600306_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:13:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani bribery case: Documents bolster US fraud case against Adani, extradition remains a challenge - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgJBVV95cUxPeFF0RkN3Ukh0UzVuTVVsRi1aM192dUNIdDBpQ0MzUWxicXNGTUJpQWlUV1p4RFpoa0M5aXFMcHRYWk9VS1JuTG1COTJ5U1VMWUt2N1dEUVktamNlRDlLQ2MxcEJtTTdnemRfQTFQaTBMQTA4NFBVc0o4RXNOa3ZKQ1VtbVZPdVVETElHbEg1T25Dd0xTNElMc05lU0tTMks1VWhHd1BqT2pRTjdZaG0zc2h1ajJLTUtkU1pmR1h1ODB0OFdTaFF4bThZM1ViWlRnSTQ0anJ5dTJQVkIydVJlM2phUXhRU2ZnY25jRVR1WDVoM2RydmlUOFV5Z1N0Y3MwNklBS3MwdUNpcnJrVTRpd0sxVzlKZ9IBmwJBVV95cUxQRzVHNVdyMDdENGc1UUtUNlJ0M3FPSVpPWUZEMHNqcUFtaHZOYjFTOEc1X1hjb2hrdzhNMWh0WHNzTC16RnFjd0NSLThVZkxPNjFjSkQxQllOejVTYllHdlJzZEhONkFSRV94MEVVZ0xmMldoaDRMb0NTekJYME1RQzBLN3lYT0g3ckJEUnp3alJ0OU5Id25Oa3VuVHhMVHBRNDdxSkd4TGwtQ00yTTQtMl9WQnY5VzNkZVF2Mm1YaFduRkVWalZIY3NDQUx6TDZKVEZaNUsxSDBpSkFfbGVsQmVUMGVhbUlyd0NPNUQxTzNmNGxmZGx1dFZnVDZDU044TVMyazl5TEM1R1UwUkNBcUx1Q1hoZHFuVzBF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgJBVV95cUxPeFF0RkN3Ukh0UzVuTVVsRi1aM192dUNIdDBpQ0MzUWxicXNGTUJpQWlUV1p4RFpoa0M5aXFMcHRYWk9VS1JuTG1COTJ5U1VMWUt2N1dEUVktamNlRDlLQ2MxcEJtTTdnemRfQTFQaTBMQTA4NFBVc0o4RXNOa3ZKQ1VtbVZPdVVETElHbEg1T25Dd0xTNElMc05lU0tTMks1VWhHd1BqT2pRTjdZaG0zc2h1ajJLTUtkU1pmR1h1ODB0OFdTaFF4bThZM1ViWlRnSTQ0anJ5dTJQVkIydVJlM2phUXhRU2ZnY25jRVR1WDVoM2RydmlUOFV5Z1N0Y3MwNklBS3MwdUNpcnJrVTRpd0sxVzlKZ9IBmwJBVV95cUxQRzVHNVdyMDdENGc1UUtUNlJ0M3FPSVpPWUZEMHNqcUFtaHZOYjFTOEc1X1hjb2hrdzhNMWh0WHNzTC16RnFjd0NSLThVZkxPNjFjSkQxQllOejVTYllHdlJzZEhONkFSRV94MEVVZ0xmMldoaDRMb0NTekJYME1RQzBLN3lYT0g3ckJEUnp3alJ0OU5Id25Oa3VuVHhMVHBRNDdxSkd4TGwtQ00yTTQtMl9WQnY5VzNkZVF2Mm1YaFduRkVWalZIY3NDQUx6TDZKVEZaNUsxSDBpSkFfbGVsQmVUMGVhbUlyd0NPNUQxTzNmNGxmZGx1dFZnVDZDU044TVMyazl5TEM1R1UwUkNBcUx1Q1hoZHFuVzBF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:09:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 cruciferous veggies that keep your bones strong, heart healthy - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/5-cruciferous-veggies-that-support-bone-liver-and-heart-health-health-benefits-of-broccoli-brussels-sprouts-asparagus-califlower-visual-story-2690509.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/5-cruciferous-veggies-that-support-bone-liver-and-heart-health-health-benefits-of-broccoli-brussels-sprouts-asparagus-califlower-visual-story-2690509.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:00:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024 Honda Amaze Review - Team-BHP]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNOExjMzYyYzJheWkxd1JJZlpNS2FYY1ViUE5oWHZic2t2bHhnd09FeUE3dkRKTUU3UklIU2lSckx3RUNORUdhSlc5T0pkeEN4RVg4aDQtOHNKdEhic1Q3UzdXSWpVZy0zaG5IVF8xVjVTRnNpLTZ4a0Vmb05fdnhzRjNsdl84dWR6b0QzQTV3V0hvZTVuLXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNOExjMzYyYzJheWkxd1JJZlpNS2FYY1ViUE5oWHZic2t2bHhnd09FeUE3dkRKTUU3UklIU2lSckx3RUNORUdhSlc5T0pkeEN4RVg4aDQtOHNKdEhic1Q3UzdXSWpVZy0zaG5IVF8xVjVTRnNpLTZ4a0Vmb05fdnhzRjNsdl84dWR6b0QzQTV3V0hvZTVuLXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:30:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zakir Hussain: Legendary tabla player dies at 73 - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zakir Hussain: Legendary Tabla Player Dies at 73</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News Agency</p><p>Zakir Hussain, one of the world's greatest tabla players, has died at the age of 73 due to idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis.</p><ul><li>Hussain was a four-time Grammy award winner and received the Padma Vibhushan.</li><li>He transformed the tabla into a globally loved solo instrument.</li><li>Tributes have started pouring in following his death.</li><li>Nayan Ghosh described him as a pathbreaker and an icon who elevated tabla on the world stage.</li></ul><blockquote>“He was a pathbreaker, a game-changer, an icon who put tabla and Indian music on the world map...” - Nayan Ghosh</blockquote><p>This legendary musician, born in Mumbai in 1951, has left an indelible mark on classical music.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c2exzm9r043o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c2exzm9r043o</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Rain Continues In Brisbane As Second Session Comes To An End - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Rain Continues To Halt Play, Tomorrow's Forecast Is...</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>Continuing rain has disrupted play in the ongoing 3rd Test match between India and Australia, with uncertainty surrounding tomorrow's weather forecast.</p><ul><li>The match on day 3 has seen multiple interruptions due to rain.</li><li>Officials are optimistic about resuming play depending on the weather.</li><li>Fans are hopeful for a clearer forecast to allow the match to proceed.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are monitoring the situation closely and hope for a timely return to play.”</blockquote><p>The anticipation for tomorrow hinges on weather conditions, which will ultimately decide if play can resume.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:10:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vishal Mega Mart IPO allotment to be finalised today: Steps to check status on BSE, NSE, KFin Tech - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vishal Mega Mart IPO Allotment Finalized Today: Steps to Check Status on BSE, NSE, KFin Tech</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 IST, CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Vishal Mega Mart IPO allotment to be finalised today" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Vishal Mega Mart IPO Allotment</figcaption><p>Supermarket chain Vishal Mega Mart is set to finalize the allotment of its initial public offering (IPO) today. The company's shares are scheduled to debut on the BSE and NSE on December 18.</p><ul><li>The IPO was open for subscription from December 11 to 13 and received a total subscription of 27.28 times.</li><li>The price band was set at ₹74-78 per share.</li><li>Qualified Institutional Buyers (QIBs) subscribed 80.75 times the shares reserved for them.</li><li>The non-institutional investors' portion was subscribed 14.24 times, while the retail portion was subscribed 2.31 times.</li><li>Allotted shares will be credited to demat accounts by December 17, and refunds for unsuccessful bids will also be initiated the same day.</li><li>Vishal Mega Mart raised ₹2,400 crore from anchor investors before the IPO.</li><li>Established in 2001, Vishal Mega Mart operates 645 stores across 414 cities in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“Allotted shares will be credited to the applicants' demat accounts.”</blockquote><p>This IPO is a significant step for Vishal Mega Mart as they continue to cater to middle- and lower-middle-income groups across India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/vishal-mega-mart-ipo-share-allotment-today-steps-to-check-online-bse-nse-kfin-tech-listing-19524656.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/vishal-mega-mart-ipo-share-allotment-today-steps-to-check-online-bse-nse-kfin-tech-listing-19524656.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:02:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study Says Flu Virus Remains In Refrigerated Raw Milk For Up To 5 Days - NDTV Food]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Flu Virus Found to Survive in Refrigerated Raw Milk for Up to 5 Days</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> August 29, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rqhr38f_milk_625x300_29_August_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=620,height=350" alt="Study Says Flu Virus Remains In Refrigerated Raw Milk For Up To 5 Days"><figcaption>Study Says Flu Virus Remains In Refrigerated Raw Milk For Up To 5 Days</figcaption><p>A recent study from Stanford University reveals that the influenza virus can remain infectious in refrigerated raw milk for up to five days, raising concerns amid outbreaks of bird flu.</p><ul><li>The flu virus H1N1 PR8 can survive in raw milk at refrigeration temperatures.</li><li>More than 14 million Americans consume raw milk annually, which is marketed as a healthier alternative to pasteurized milk.</li><li>The FDA has linked raw milk to over 200 illness outbreaks, highlighting significant health risks.</li><li>Flu virus RNA can remain detectable in raw milk for at least 57 days, posing challenges for food safety assessments.</li><li>Monitoring systems need improvement as bird flu spreads among livestock.</li></ul><blockquote>“This work highlights the potential risk of avian influenza transmission through consumption of raw milk and the importance of milk pasteurization.” - Alexandria Boehm, Senior Author</blockquote><p>The findings of this research emphasize significant health risks associated with raw milk consumption, particularly in light of ongoing bird flu infections in cattle.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://food.ndtv.com/news/study-says-flu-virus-remains-in-refrigerated-raw-milk-for-up-to-5-days-7258372</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://food.ndtv.com/news/study-says-flu-virus-remains-in-refrigerated-raw-milk-for-up-to-5-days-7258372</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:56:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru executive suicide: Atul Subhash's wife Nikita Singhania was living as paying guest in Gurgaon - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru Executive Suicide: Nikita Singhania's Adjusted Life as a Paying Guest</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Bengaluru Executive Suicide" /><figcaption>Bengaluru executive who tragically took his life</figcaption><p>The article discusses the tragic suicide of a Bengaluru executive, Atul Subhash, and how his wife, Nikita Singhania, is now living as a paying guest in Gurgaon, facing the aftermath of this loss.</p><ul><li>Atul Subhash, a Bengaluru executive, has died by suicide.</li><li>His wife, Nikita Singhania, is coping with the situation by living as a paying guest in Gurgaon.</li><li>The article sheds light on the challenges faced by families of suicide victims.</li></ul><blockquote>“This incident raises concerns about mental health and support systems available for individuals dealing with such crises.”</blockquote><p>The suicide of Atul Subhash highlights the critical importance of mental health awareness and support for families in distress.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/auto-execs-death-wife-2-more-arrested-sent-to-14-day-judicial-custody/articleshow/116345862.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/auto-execs-death-wife-2-more-arrested-sent-to-14-day-judicial-custody/articleshow/116345862.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh To Hold Elections In Late 2025 Or Early 2026: Muhammad Yunus - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh To Hold Elections In Late 2025 Or Early 2026: Muhammad Yunus</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br/><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>Bangladesh's interim leader Muhammad Yunus announced on Monday that general elections are expected to be held in late 2025 or early 2026 following a challenging political transition.</p><ul><li>Yunus was appointed as chief adviser after a student-led uprising that ousted former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</li><li>The interim government is facing pressure to establish a date for the elections amid calls for democratic reforms.</li><li>Yunus highlighted the need for electoral reforms before the elections can be scheduled.</li><li>The former prime minister, Hasina, fled to neighboring India amid protests against her rule, which was marked by allegations of human rights abuses.</li><li>Yunus hinted that elections could be moved up to November 2025 if parties agree to minimal reforms.</li></ul><blockquote>“Throughout, I have emphasised that reforms should take place first before the arrangements for an election,” Muhammad Yunus stated.</blockquote><p>The future of democracy in Bangladesh hangs in the balance as reforms are debated prior to the elections, which may shape the political landscape of the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-to-hold-elections-in-late-2025-or-early-2026-muhammad-yunus-7258366</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-to-hold-elections-in-late-2025-or-early-2026-muhammad-yunus-7258366</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:53:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes, December 16, 2024 edition: How to get free skins, weapons, and diamonds today - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes, December 16, 2024 edition: How to get free skins, weapons, and diamonds today</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p>
<img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/D-Gukesh-1.jpg?w=300" alt="D Gukesh" width="300" height="150">
<figcaption>From prodigy to champion: D Gukesh’s journey to becoming the youngest world chess champion</figcaption>
<p>Garena Free Fire MAX, a popular battle royale game that emerged after Free Fire's ban in India, offers daily redeem codes for players, enhancing engagement with free in-game items like skins, weapons, and diamonds.</p>
<ul>
<li>Players log in daily to claim free rewards, increasing excitement.</li>
<li>Codes only valid for 24 hours and limited to first 500 players.</li>
<li>Players can upgrade characters and access premium content at no cost.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Redeem codes for today: YFW2Y7NQFV9S, GXFT7YNWTQSZ, FFW4FST9FQY2...</blockquote>
<p>Players can easily redeem codes on the official site to receive rewards directly in their accounts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQb3lXOXdHZkQ2YTAxYjduVTVpMHc2RGVDWlhSbnpROWdrQUlta1ROUW5JN3FFb0thVzZyRl9JdktRYjhJakx3VkNhZW1CRTNsTmwtVEZlVkhMdjlsSE5BTFpOcTRCSDRKbExpZjBhNkN0RjJ5dXM5dUFXVFN0YWpHYld5aGc4cGJ5V3N0bnVWV3ZXSk5mazAyb1BQQWN6MnUzN3BORUQ5cmZITWJhUVBtaElXWVpBVjJFMFZGcHkwRTNRaXpycE9Dejc0QXhYZ0ZiN2tMajhabDN6NTVyQ3YzNmNKWGd2TVd0MU1Zb083Q204bWtXSlUzQ9IB_wFBVV95cUxQeTRRNU9TeTBNVldTZlFlRFdkWE5BSVBmWUZBZjBxNGdPVVlsVzdTMkFRWWdka2xiT3BfOXZmZlNtOG1jTGxreGduRVdMbUJFM25oNkI4YlF6aTZvRHFEWE1XUzdKYXBUUXdOSUlFYjJwNlU0TU5JWFc0U192NGtQQTM0WUlielZvNWh5OFN6c1BoSUZiSXFSVnZ5X3d1eE1XeVFzaWtRbmRCa2JYb3RTX2VxS3Zkd0RCbGJSY2FSdHlMNV95OWgxWk9JNjBsaUQzWGpNRm1GSFJNNFljYzJqbXhQUHVEX013S1JGN3Ayb0h1Q25SdnU0WEx1VUFvOVk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQb3lXOXdHZkQ2YTAxYjduVTVpMHc2RGVDWlhSbnpROWdrQUlta1ROUW5JN3FFb0thVzZyRl9JdktRYjhJakx3VkNhZW1CRTNsTmwtVEZlVkhMdjlsSE5BTFpOcTRCSDRKbExpZjBhNkN0RjJ5dXM5dUFXVFN0YWpHYld5aGc4cGJ5V3N0bnVWV3ZXSk5mazAyb1BQQWN6MnUzN3BORUQ5cmZITWJhUVBtaElXWVpBVjJFMFZGcHkwRTNRaXpycE9Dejc0QXhYZ0ZiN2tMajhabDN6NTVyQ3YzNmNKWGd2TVd0MU1Zb083Q204bWtXSlUzQ9IB_wFBVV95cUxQeTRRNU9TeTBNVldTZlFlRFdkWE5BSVBmWUZBZjBxNGdPVVlsVzdTMkFRWWdka2xiT3BfOXZmZlNtOG1jTGxreGduRVdMbUJFM25oNkI4YlF6aTZvRHFEWE1XUzdKYXBUUXdOSUlFYjJwNlU0TU5JWFc0U192NGtQQTM0WUlielZvNWh5OFN6c1BoSUZiSXFSVnZ5X3d1eE1XeVFzaWtRbmRCa2JYb3RTX2VxS3Zkd0RCbGJSY2FSdHlMNV95OWgxWk9JNjBsaUQzWGpNRm1GSFJNNFljYzJqbXhQUHVEX013S1JGN3Ayb0h1Q25SdnU0WEx1VUFvOVk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:50:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Big Blow To India, Pat Cummins Bags His First Wicket - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Rain Continues In Brisbane</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not provided<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p>
<p>Rain continues to disrupt play during the second session of the third Test match between India and Australia in Brisbane.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Heavy rain has affected the match schedule.</li>
    <li>Players have been waiting for clearance to resume.</li>
    <li>No play has been possible in the second session due to persistent rain.</li>
</ul>
<p>No notable quotes or statistics provided.</p>
<p>This ongoing weather issue has significant implications for the match outcome and player performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:44:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 11: Allu Arjun film earns Rs 1322 cr, highest earner ever after Dangal and Baahubali 2 - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Worldwide Box Office Collection Day 11</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 15, 2024 | Source: Indian Express</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-11.jpg?w=640" alt="Pushpa 2 box office collection day 11: Allu Arjun starrer is third highest earning Indian film ever." width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Pushpa 2 box office collection day 11: Allu Arjun's film makes more than Rs 900 crores in India. (Photo: Mythri Movies / Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>The film <strong>Pushpa 2: The Rule</strong>, starring Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna, has shattered box office records, achieving a total worldwide collection of Rs 1322 crore by its 11th day of release.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Earned Rs 100 crore on the 11th day.</li>
  <li>Total Indian collection (all languages) now stands at Rs 900.5 crores.</li>
  <li>Massive spike of 73.90% in box office collections on the second Saturday.</li>
  <li>Hindi version grossed Rs 55 crores on December 15.</li>
  <li>Film surpassed RRR in collections, although it has not yet overtaken Baahubali: The Conclusion and Dangal.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p>#Pushpa2TheRule crosses Massive 1292 CRORES GROSS in 10 days 💥💥<br>The HIGHEST GROSSER OF INDIAN CINEMA IN 2024 ❤‍🔥</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Strong word of mouth has contributed significantly to the film's performance, making it a major success in the Indian film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-11-allu-arjun-film-earns-rs-1322-cr-highest-earner-ever-after-dangal-and-baahubali-2-9727126/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/pushpa-2-worldwide-box-office-collection-day-11-allu-arjun-film-earns-rs-1322-cr-highest-earner-ever-after-dangal-and-baahubali-2-9727126/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How India Can Qualify For World Test Championship Final If Gabba Test vs Australia Is Washed Out - E.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_AFBVV95cUxNcG9EUmloQ0JYRlhSNl9HbmVYX003NUctUmtvNXVvOXhlc1lXaDdfb3JPYXJCTGhDWkVRNkFPSnpBZGdDQW9fVTVndXhKdXNJd1l5TkRvQ1VpLTRMdGp1QnV2ZHlnYWR2ZmdxS2VPRmFxdzNZMGVSQlpqUUJfS0xqQVNMUEoxM28tNk1Dc25PMmJJNmtZc2o4QXNBNXBoR0hPQVFSQ1lDQ3BiUGxuRnZCOXZVSWJaYVZvTVNhVjVESUhwMXljRjZvYzBiMW5kaGR4bk1hVl84RmJ4NGZLVVdDQXE2STBGQjdCaWdyS3pLaTV1MXIwZkZYQnJVMVrSAYQCQVVfeXFMT2xMa2dqQVRQNGdKbVIxWHJoM053WXFWT1VVeUpNdXR1VXozZmU0YzJvWXEwRW83UlVaa21nUFdDZWhwWFphNlpWXzh2blpGV0RnRldPd1ZzRW5oSkFWUFBDSUstUU9fUmJoNHJrWUl2UGpBTGxMeFBnalRKQjhDdG1aVjNKbzVRVFRtdXR3a1VCRzRIc0R4ZU5sNlUxT0oxSXlrZHlHX0h6MjMtSjlYY1VfclFHZVBUSXpkcjM4SUU5ZE9YaUFYeDR1RjZabTFhUk5paVZHejFZaEpBeERmMjl5TXlaWWdLTXluUG1nTTI5Zkhrc01hN3RVWDNPN2ZtbjI2am0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_AFBVV95cUxNcG9EUmloQ0JYRlhSNl9HbmVYX003NUctUmtvNXVvOXhlc1lXaDdfb3JPYXJCTGhDWkVRNkFPSnpBZGdDQW9fVTVndXhKdXNJd1l5TkRvQ1VpLTRMdGp1QnV2ZHlnYWR2ZmdxS2VPRmFxdzNZMGVSQlpqUUJfS0xqQVNMUEoxM28tNk1Dc25PMmJJNmtZc2o4QXNBNXBoR0hPQVFSQ1lDQ3BiUGxuRnZCOXZVSWJaYVZvTVNhVjVESUhwMXljRjZvYzBiMW5kaGR4bk1hVl84RmJ4NGZLVVdDQXE2STBGQjdCaWdyS3pLaTV1MXIwZkZYQnJVMVrSAYQCQVVfeXFMT2xMa2dqQVRQNGdKbVIxWHJoM053WXFWT1VVeUpNdXR1VXozZmU0YzJvWXEwRW83UlVaa21nUFdDZWhwWFphNlpWXzh2blpGV0RnRldPd1ZzRW5oSkFWUFBDSUstUU9fUmJoNHJrWUl2UGpBTGxMeFBnalRKQjhDdG1aVjNKbzVRVFRtdXR3a1VCRzRIc0R4ZU5sNlUxT0oxSXlrZHlHX0h6MjMtSjlYY1VfclFHZVBUSXpkcjM4SUU5ZE9YaUFYeDR1RjZabTFhUk5paVZHejFZaEpBeERmMjl5TXlaWWdLTXluUG1nTTI5Zkhrc01hN3RVWDNPN2ZtbjI2am0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:27:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 stunning images of our solar system captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Stunning Images of Our Solar System Captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> HT TECH</p><img src="https://images.hindustantimes.com/tech/img/2024/12/16/900x1600/g0f7f6ecaceb9b22b21751494494bef709049f5933f0353ac2_1734322360961_1734322361183.jpg" alt="Hubble Image" /><figcaption>Photo Caption: High-resolution image of the solar system captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope.</figcaption><p>The article explores five stunning images of our solar system captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, showcasing celestial wonders and interesting facts about our cosmic neighborhood.</p><ul><li>Our solar system is approximately 4.5 billion years old.</li><li>Only two NASA spacecraft have exited our solar system.</li><li>Experts estimate there are about 500,000 pieces of space junk orbiting Earth.</li><li>Alien aurorae on Uranus are caused by solar winds and moon volcanism.</li><li>Hubble captured auroras on Jupiter and Saturn, providing unique insights into their atmospheres.</li></ul><blockquote>“Hubble Telescope captured this image of the planet Mars in 2018. This high-resolution image was more powerful than the spacecraft that visited the planet.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the images captured by the Hubble Space Telescope not only highlight the beauty of our solar system but also enhance our understanding of its complexity and the mysteries that lie beyond.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tech.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/5-stunning-images-of-our-solar-system-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-71734322315820.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tech.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/5-stunning-images-of-our-solar-system-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-71734322315820.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:23:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for December 16: Steps to redeem codes and win free rewards - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for December 16: Steps to redeem codes and win free rewards</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Gamers' Hub</p><p>This article provides the latest redeem codes for Garena Free Fire MAX and explains how players can claim these codes to earn exciting in-game rewards.</p><ul><li>Redeem codes are valid until a specific date.</li><li>Instructions for redeeming codes are detailed.</li><li>Players can earn in-game currencies, skins, and other rewards.</li></ul><blockquote>“Winning free rewards can enhance your gaming experience significantly.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, redeeming codes offers players a great opportunity to enhance their gameplay in Garena Free Fire MAX.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-december-16-steps-to-redeem-codes-and-win-free-rewards/articleshow/116353379.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-december-16-steps-to-redeem-codes-and-win-free-rewards/articleshow/116353379.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indices extend losses; SENSEX down 500 pts, NIFTY50 slips below 24,650; Dixon Tech hits fresh record high - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Updates: SENSEX Drops 500 Points as NIFTY50 Falls Below 24,650</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Financial News</p><p>The equity market is showing declines with the S&P BSE SENSEX falling significantly, while Dixon Technologies reaches a new record high amid global market caution.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>S&P BSE SENSEX is down to 81,691.65, a drop of 441 points (0.54%).</li><li>NIFTY50 index falls to 24,634.75, down 133.5 points (0.54%).</li><li>47 out of 50 NIFTY50 constituents are trading lower.</li><li>Dixon Technologies sees a surge, hitting ₹18,739.95 due to a new joint venture with Vivo.</li><li>BSE MidCap index up by 0.58%; BSE SmallCap index up by 0.51%.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics</h2><blockquote>Shares of Dixon Technologies surged 4.35% to hit a fresh record high of ₹18,739.95 apiece.</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>The markets are under pressure from cautious global trends, but significant movements in specific stocks like Dixon Technologies indicate ongoing volatility and opportunities in the sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/sensex-down-250-pts-in-early-trade-nifty-50-trades-above-24-680-dixon-technologies-hits-fresh-record-high/article-135291/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/sensex-down-250-pts-in-early-trade-nifty-50-trades-above-24-680-dixon-technologies-hits-fresh-record-high/article-135291/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:18:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi shivers amid coldwave conditions as minimum drops to 4.5°C; AQI ‘very poor’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Coldwave: Minimum Temperature Falls to 4.5°C Amid 'Very Poor' Air Quality</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 16, 2024 | <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/People-gather-around-a-bonfire-on-a-cold-morning-i_1734322364632_1734322380792.jpg" alt="People gather around a bonfire on a cold morning in New Delhi.(Arvind Yadav/ HT Photo)"><figcaption>People gather around a bonfire on a cold morning in New Delhi.(Arvind Yadav/ HT Photo)</figcaption><p>Coldwave conditions continue to grip Delhi, with a recorded minimum temperature of 4.5°C, marking the joint lowest this season.</p><ul><li>Minimum temperature recorded at Safdarjung dropped to 4.5°C, four degrees below normal.</li><li>Shallow fog resulted in visibility of around 800 metres.</li><li>Air quality index (AQI) reached 'very poor' levels, averaging 351.</li><li>Experts link the deterioration in AQI to a drop in wind speed; similar conditions expected to persist.</li><li>Lowest minimum temperature was recorded at 3.5°C in Pusa and 4°C in Ayanagar.</li></ul><blockquote>“A feeble western disturbance is beginning to impact northwest India, which is slowing down winds. This should keep the AQI likely in the very poor range.” - Mahesh Palawat, Skymet</blockquote><p>The coldwave is set to continue, with temperatures predicted to hover around 5°C on Tuesday.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/delhi-news/delhi-shivers-amid-coldwave-conditions-as-minimum-drops-to-4-5-c-aqi-very-poor-101734321754948.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/delhi-news/delhi-shivers-amid-coldwave-conditions-as-minimum-drops-to-4-5-c-aqi-very-poor-101734321754948.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:02:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>