<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 23:15:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 23:15:56 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zepto IPO: Company To File Draft Papers In March-April; All You Need To Know - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zepto IPO: Company To File Draft Papers In March-April; All You Need To Know</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 04, 2025, 19:32 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Zepto IPO" title="Zepto IPO: Zepto is undergoing a significant operational overhaul, transitioning from a B2B model to a marketplace model under a newly established entity, Zepto Marketplace."><figcaption>Zepto IPO: Zepto is undergoing a significant operational overhaul, transitioning from a B2B model to a marketplace model under a newly established entity, Zepto Marketplace.</figcaption></figure><p>Zepto, a quick commerce platform, is preparing to file its initial public offering (IPO) draft papers by March or April 2025, following approval to relocate its base from Singapore to India.</p><ul><li>A critical board meeting on January 19 will discuss IPO specifics, including banker appointments and IPO size.</li><li>Grey market premium data will be available once IPO preparations begin, with pricing announced shortly before the IPO opening.</li><li>Zepto is set to become the first quick commerce startup to go public, following competitors like Zomato and Swiggy.</li><li>The company is shifting to a marketplace model for better quality control and service management.</li><li>Zepto reported a 120% increase in operating revenue to Rs 4,454 crore in FY24 and aims to expand operations to over 50 cities soon.</li></ul><blockquote>Zepto's valuation stands at USD 5 billion following a USD 350 million funding round in November 2024.</blockquote><p>The upcoming IPO is a significant step for Zepto in its expansion journey and transformation into a competitive marketplace model.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/ipo/zepto-ipo-company-likely-to-file-draft-papers-in-march-april-all-you-need-to-know-9176910.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/ipo/zepto-ipo-company-likely-to-file-draft-papers-in-march-april-all-you-need-to-know-9176910.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 21:00:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dangerous storm to unleash snow, ice, bitter cold across US - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dangerous Storm Set to Bring Snow, Ice, and Bitter Cold Across the US</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/US_weather_storm_1736022167138_1736022167437.jpg" alt="In this aerial view, morning snow covers the town of December 4, 2024 in Watertown, New York.(Getty Images/AFP)">
<figcaption>In this aerial view, morning snow covers the town of December 4, 2024 in Watertown, New York.(Getty Images/AFP)</figcaption>
<p>A colossal winter storm is set to hit the eastern half of the US, plunging more than 55 million people into a deep freeze with heavy snowfall, frigid temperatures, and hazardous travel conditions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Winter storm warnings issued from Montana to Maryland, Delaware, and Virginia.</li>
  <li>Heavy lake-effect snow expected in New York and Pennsylvania with totals possibly reaching two feet.</li>
  <li>Blizzard conditions forecast across Central Plains, with travel being extremely hazardous.</li>
  <li>Temperatures expected to drop below zero Fahrenheit in some areas, compounded by strong winds.</li>
  <li>Freezing rain and sleet predicted to create treacherous conditions from Kansas to Virginia.</li>
  <li>State emergencies declared in Missouri and Virginia due to hazardous weather risks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Governor Andy Beshear stated, "The storm will likely cause significant disruption and dangerous conditions on our roads and could cause significant power outages just 24 hours before it's going to get really cold in Kentucky." </blockquote>
<p>As the storm approaches, residents are urged to prepare for hazardous conditions and potential power outages.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/dangerous-storm-to-unleash-snow-ice-bitter-cold-across-us-101736022073273.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/dangerous-storm-to-unleash-snow-ice-bitter-cold-across-us-101736022073273.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 20:44:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 amazing images of Nebula captured by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Amazing Images of Nebula Captured by NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/twin-jet-nebula-1.jpg" alt="Twin Jet Nebula" />
<figcaption>Twin Jet Nebula captured by NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases stunning images of various nebulas captured by NASA, highlighting their beauty and scientific significance.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Red Spider Nebula is located 3000 light-years away in Sagittarius.</li>
    <li>The Spirograph Nebula, IC 418, lies 2000 light-years from Earth in Lepus.</li>
    <li>Light and shadow in the Carina Nebula reveal complex structures.</li>
    <li>The Twin Jet Nebula is a notable example of a bipolar planetary nebula.</li>
    <li>The Hourglass Nebula MyCn18 is about 8,000 light-years away and is captured by Hubble.</li>
    <li>The Crab Nebula offers the most detailed views ever.</li>
    <li>A nebula resembling a butterfly is detailed for its unique shape.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Crab Nebula is among the most interesting and well-studied objects in astronomy."</blockquote>
<p>The images celebrate the wonders of the universe and the role of NASA in cosmic exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-amazing-images-of-nebula-captured-by-nasa-7514879/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-amazing-images-of-nebula-captured-by-nasa-7514879/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 19:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kiara Advani Advised Rest Due to Exertion, Misses Game Changer Event with Ram Charan - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kiara Advani Takes a Break Due to Exhaustion, Misses Game Changer Event</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 04, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Kiara Advani will be seen in Game Changer." title="Kiara Advani will be seen in Game Changer."><figcaption>Kiara Advani will be seen in Game Changer.</figcaption></figure><p>Actress Kiara Advani, set to star alongside Ram Charan in the film Game Changer, is currently resting at home following advice to recover from exhaustion after a busy schedule.</p><ul><li>Ian a surprising turn, Kiara was initially reported to be hospitalized, but her spokesperson clarified she is at home resting.</li><li>Her absence was noted at a promotional event for Game Changer, generating concern among fans.</li><li>The film, directed by Shankar, is set to release on January 10, 2025.</li><li>Game Changer has completed its censorship formalities and received a U/A certificate from the CBFC.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kiara Advani has not been hospitalised, she’s been advised to rest due to exertion as she’s been working non-stop,” said the actress’ spokesperson.</blockquote><p>The upcoming film Game Changer has created significant buzz and features an impressive cast, including Ram Charan, making it one of the most anticipated releases of the month.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/kiara-advani-hospitalised-in-mumbai-skips-game-changer-event-with-ram-charan-9176931.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/kiara-advani-hospitalised-in-mumbai-skips-game-changer-event-with-ram-charan-9176931.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 19:31:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Couch potatoes beware! Sitting too much may lead to 19 serious health problems - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Couch potatoes beware! Sitting too much may lead to 19 serious health problems</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116950774,imgsize-38106,width-400,resizemode-4/116950774.jpg" alt="Couch potatoes beware! Sitting too much may lead to 19 serious health problems" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Couch potatoes beware! Sitting too much may lead to 19 serious health problems</figcaption>
<p>The dangers of a sedentary lifestyle are well-known, but a new study reveals a startling connection to 19 chronic conditions, urging individuals to adopt healthier habits.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The University of Iowa conducted a study on over 40,000 patients, linking inactivity to increased health risks.</li>
  <li>Only 60% of respondents met the recommended exercise guidelines.</li>
  <li>Active individuals showed significantly lower rates of obesity, depression, and hypertension.</li>
  <li>Patients with no physical activity had an average of 2.16 chronic conditions compared to 1.17 in active individuals.</li>
  <li>Chronic health conditions related to a sedentary lifestyle include obesity, diabetes, heart issues, and more.</li>
  <li>Tips to overcome sedentary habits include regular breaks, incorporating exercise into daily routines, and setting activity goals.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This two-question survey typically takes fewer than 30 seconds for a patient to complete, so it doesn’t interfere with their visit. But it can tell us a whole lot about that patient’s overall health.” - Lucas Carr</blockquote>
<p>Increasing awareness about the effects of inactivity is crucial. Through lifestyle changes, individuals can significantly improve their health and mitigate associated risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/couch-potatoes-beware-sitting-too-much-may-lead-to-19-serious-health-problems/articleshow/116950761.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/couch-potatoes-beware-sitting-too-much-may-lead-to-19-serious-health-problems/articleshow/116950761.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 19:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Intelligence now takes up almost twice as much room on your iPhone as it used to - TechRadar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Intelligence now takes up almost twice as much room on your iPhone as it used to</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 3, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> TechRadar</p><figure><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/UCWUybDHyY2w5ueXfmPVfV-320-80.jpg" alt="Apple Intelligence on iOS"><figcaption>Apple Intelligence is an optional extra (Image credit: Apple)</figcaption></figure><p>Apple Intelligence now requires 7GB of storage with the new iOS 18.2 update, up from 4GB in the previous version, due to added features and expected further increases in the future.</p><ul><li>Apple Intelligence now needs 7GB, an increase from 4GB.</li><li>This increase is attributed to new features in iOS 18.2.</li><li>Future requirements are projected to grow further.</li></ul><blockquote>"If you're running low on storage space on your device, then you may have to think twice about having Apple Intelligence enabled."</blockquote><p>Apple's focus on local AI processing enhances privacy but poses storage challenges for users. Those needing to manage their device's space may need to reconsider their use of Apple Intelligence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techradar.com/phones/iphone/apple-intelligence-now-takes-up-almost-twice-as-much-room-on-your-iphone-as-it-used-to</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techradar.com/phones/iphone/apple-intelligence-now-takes-up-almost-twice-as-much-room-on-your-iphone-as-it-used-to</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP's First List For Delhi Polls Out, Ex-MP Parvesh Verma To Take On Arvind Kejriwal - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/elections/delhi-polls-bjp-releases-first-list-of-29-candidates-fields-ex-mp-ramesh-bidhuri-against-atishi-9176954.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/elections/delhi-polls-bjp-releases-first-list-of-29-candidates-fields-ex-mp-ramesh-bidhuri-against-atishi-9176954.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 18:07:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yuzvendra Chahal shares cryptic post amid divorce rumours with Dhanashree Verma - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yuzvendra Chahal's Cryptic Post Fuels Divorce Rumours with Dhanashree Verma</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 4, 2025 | <strong>Published By:</strong> Diya Kakkar</p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/yuzvendra-chahal-with-wife-dhanashree-verma-103913931-16x9.jpeg?VersionId=ueo2WpRmYLDkcYnCfs4c4_J2gvaPz9iT&amp;size=690:388" alt="Yuzvendra Chahal with wife Dhanashree Verma"><figcaption>Yuzvendra Chahal with wife Dhanashree Verma (Dhanashree Verma Instagram Photo)</figcaption><p>Indian cricketer Yuzvendra Chahal has sparked speculation about his marriage to Dhanashree Verma with a cryptic Instagram post, amid reports of their potential separation.</p><ul><li>Chahal shared a cryptic message on Instagram, possibly reflecting on his personal struggles.</li><li>Reports indicate that Chahal and Dhanashree have unfollowed each other and deleted shared photos, which has intensified divorce speculations.</li><li>Sources suggest they have been living separately for months and their marriage appears to be crumbling.</li><li>The couple married in December 2020 after meeting during the pandemic.</li></ul><blockquote>“Hard work spotlights the character of people. You know your journey. You know your pain…”</blockquote><p>The ongoing silence from both parties regarding the rumors leaves fans uncertain about the future of their relationship.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/sports/cricket/story/yuzvendra-chahal-shares-cryptic-post-amid-divorce-rumors-with-dhanashree-verma-2659847-2025-01-04</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/sports/cricket/story/yuzvendra-chahal-shares-cryptic-post-amid-divorce-rumors-with-dhanashree-verma-2659847-2025-01-04</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 17:57:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Surgeon General urges cancer warnings for alcoholic drinks - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxOSHpjUlo4ZlNEZkJhR3Y0QVdLS2ROQmJtWU02bUFsMXZ2MmRKZlJJcnpwTUtoM0tTU0JCVFRVQjVBY1pXcDJ3bU5qUlFoU2Y5Tlc1WFBNUlJQWkFMTHljZUtUbmZIYXFNYnpWRnhXVnMwZEhxY3ZJY2RtcTVxWHJzaFNVNi1GNEg0YXJVSy1NYk9WcEJXSzJDMGVqbDI5eW05QmhUNkx30gGqAUFVX3lxTE5Mc1NPQXd3YVZZbWFxemhKNDNSZ1lRVVVDRnlDWXpROHA4dHpkWUlzcDBCLVZnbERHVTRscE5xN1hYSXRtRjVnSlVkRUZ5LThkejNBN0RMWXcwTWptQjQyeWlIME1COHZuTmhVSzdyRzVUNzhwWGJXejNpUERXbUo5QUJsZzMtMm9NcktrSTZtTlNjYkJMVXlUc2E4am1Td3Q1cmFwZ3pwb1B3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxOSHpjUlo4ZlNEZkJhR3Y0QVdLS2ROQmJtWU02bUFsMXZ2MmRKZlJJcnpwTUtoM0tTU0JCVFRVQjVBY1pXcDJ3bU5qUlFoU2Y5Tlc1WFBNUlJQWkFMTHljZUtUbmZIYXFNYnpWRnhXVnMwZEhxY3ZJY2RtcTVxWHJzaFNVNi1GNEg0YXJVSy1NYk9WcEJXSzJDMGVqbDI5eW05QmhUNkx30gGqAUFVX3lxTE5Mc1NPQXd3YVZZbWFxemhKNDNSZ1lRVVVDRnlDWXpROHA4dHpkWUlzcDBCLVZnbERHVTRscE5xN1hYSXRtRjVnSlVkRUZ5LThkejNBN0RMWXcwTWptQjQyeWlIME1COHZuTmhVSzdyRzVUNzhwWGJXejNpUERXbUo5QUJsZzMtMm9NcktrSTZtTlNjYkJMVXlUc2E4am1Td3Q1cmFwZ3pwb1B3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 17:38:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rickelton's marathon 259, Verreynne century thump hapless Pakistan - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxNN2F6ZmZWZmFtcTlqbnI2WnFRSHFvWXVFYXdnMmxkanptTk0yV0loSGljNVFvbGNRenUtZ3Q4T3FFMEY1QXlLdmVWLXJMampQdjZDNlNuZEFWUEMtUzdFLVhvcnF0emprT2owNFhjektWek8zN0tScnFjeWhSQjhxUlc4TVRrNDlfUkFrWm9wTHUxbDItd1FaSV9yZUlOYkR1UzF6bnI1S1RudWhKLW8zQnk0QU1PRGhidGY1VkNSNm56c3pRc0ZXUnFuOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxNN2F6ZmZWZmFtcTlqbnI2WnFRSHFvWXVFYXdnMmxkanptTk0yV0loSGljNVFvbGNRenUtZ3Q4T3FFMEY1QXlLdmVWLXJMampQdjZDNlNuZEFWUEMtUzdFLVhvcnF0emprT2owNFhjektWek8zN0tScnFjeWhSQjhxUlc4TVRrNDlfUkFrWm9wTHUxbDItd1FaSV9yZUlOYkR1UzF6bnI1S1RudWhKLW8zQnk0QU1PRGhidGY1VkNSNm56c3pRc0ZXUnFuOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 17:35:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Orleans attacker stored bomb materials, reserved truck weeks ahead, say officials - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Orleans attacker stored bomb materials, reserved truck weeks ahead, say officials</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>[Date of publication not provided], <strong>Source: </strong>[Source not provided]</p><p>This article discusses the recent developments in the investigation surrounding a New Orleans attacker who had stored bomb materials and reserved a truck weeks before the attack.</p><ul><li>The attacker had been accumulating bomb-making materials over a significant period.</li><li>A truck was reserved in advance, indicating premeditation.</li><li>Officials are investigating potential motives and connections.</li></ul><blockquote>“The planning involved shows a concerning level of intent,” said a law enforcement official.</blockquote><p>The incident raises alarms about security measures and public safety in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/new-orleans-attacker-stored-bomb-materials-reserved-truck-weeks-ahead-say-officials/articleshow/116947700.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/new-orleans-attacker-stored-bomb-materials-reserved-truck-weeks-ahead-say-officials/articleshow/116947700.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 17:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Went here and there…': On Lalu Yadav's offer, Bihar CM Nitish Kumar says won't repeat ‘mistake’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitish Kumar Rejects Lalu Yadav's Alliance Offer, Reflects on Bihar's Progress</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 04, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/fcee3594-f20f-11ec-be7e-df6703e802fb_1655891449199_1736010228154.jpg" alt="Bihar chief minister Nitish Kumar criticised the Lalu Prasad era government(PTI)"><figcaption>Bihar chief minister Nitish Kumar criticised the Lalu Prasad era government(PTI)</figcaption><p>Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar criticizes the previous government led by Lalu Prasad Yadav while rejecting an alliance offer, emphasizing Bihar's development since 2005.</p><ul><li>Nitish Kumar attacks Lalu Prasad's government pre-2005, citing poor conditions in Bihar.</li><li>He highlights significant improvements in education, health, and infrastructure under his leadership.</li><li>Kumar's review meeting underscores commitment to continuing development without alliances.</li><li>Lalu Yadav extended an invitation for partnership in the 'Mahagathbandan', but Kumar declined.</li><li>Tejashwi Yadav, Lalu's son, downplays Lalu's invitation, suggesting it was merely a response to media inquiries.</li></ul><blockquote>“Before the year 2005, Bihar ki halat kaafi kharab thi (the condition of Bihar was really bad).” - Nitish Kumar</blockquote><p>Kumar's remarks underline a significant political divide in Bihar as he positions himself as a leader focused on development without reliance on past alliances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/bihar-ki-haalat-kaafi-kharab-thi-bihar-cm-nitish-kumars-jibe-after-lalu-prasads-invite-101736008400131.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/bihar-ki-haalat-kaafi-kharab-thi-bihar-cm-nitish-kumars-jibe-after-lalu-prasads-invite-101736008400131.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 17:21:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aubrey Plaza’s husband, director Jeff Baena, 47, dies by suicide - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aubrey Plaza's Husband Jeff Baena Dies by Suicide at Age 47</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 04, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/88a6850dab0e4527a2f776c8980e6630-88a6850dab0e4527a_1736010035308_1736010035557.jpg" alt="Aubrey Plaza is grieving the death of her husband, director Jeff Baena, who died at 47.(Willy Sanjuan/Invision/AP)" title="Aubrey Plaza is grieving the death of her husband, director Jeff Baena, who died at 47.(Willy Sanjuan/Invision/AP)">
<figcaption>Aubrey Plaza is grieving the death of her husband, director Jeff Baena, who died at 47.(Willy Sanjuan/Invision/AP)</figcaption>
<p>Aubrey Plaza is mourning the loss of her husband, film director Jeff Baena, who was found dead in his Los Angeles home at the age of 47. Local authorities are currently investigating the circumstances surrounding his passing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jeff Baena was discovered dead by his assistant, prompting a police investigation.</li>
<li>Aubrey Plaza's representatives stated that the family is devastated and requests privacy.</li>
<li>The couple married in 2021 and had no children.</li>
<li>Baena's notable works include Joshy, Horse Girl, and co-writing I Heart Huckabees.</li>
<li>Plaza mentioned their spontaneous wedding during an appearance on The Ellen DeGeneres Show.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The family is devastated and asks for privacy at this difficult time.”</blockquote>
<p>This story is still developing as details emerge about Jeff Baena's death.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/aubrey-plaza-s-husband-director-jeff-baena-47-found-dead-in-suspected-suicide-101736009414071.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/aubrey-plaza-s-husband-director-jeff-baena-47-found-dead-in-suspected-suicide-101736009414071.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 17:01:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dense fog engulfs Delhi; flight operations hit at IGI airport - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dense Fog Engulfs Delhi; Flight Operations Hit at IGI Airport</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 04, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>Nearly 500 flights faced disruptions at Indira Gandhi International Airport due to severe fog impacting northern India.</p><img src="image_url_here" alt="Dense fog at IGI airport"><figcaption>Dense fog affecting flight operations at IGI airport.</figcaption><p>The dense fog has resulted in significant travel delays and cancellations, severely impacting air traffic across multiple states.</p><ul><li>412 flights delayed by over 45 minutes.</li><li>45 flights cancelled due to poor weather conditions.</li><li>19 flights diverted to alternate airports.</li><li>Zero visibility reported in New Delhi, especially between 11:30 p.m. and 8:30 a.m.</li><li>Intense fog conditions affected flights in multiple northern cities, including Chandigarh and Srinagar.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dense fog causing low visibility in northern belt continues to impact flight operations even during daytime hours,” - IndiGo.</blockquote><p>This weather phenomenon underscores the ongoing challenges posed by extreme fog in the winter months, emphasizing the need for improved infrastructural responses to such disruptions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/dense-fog-engulfs-delhi-flight-operations-hit-at-igi-airport/article69060262.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/dense-fog-engulfs-delhi-flight-operations-hit-at-igi-airport/article69060262.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 16:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah Ruled Fit To Bat, But Decision On Bowling To Be Made On Day 3 Morning: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-ruled-fit-to-bat-but-decision-on-bowling-to-be-made-on-day-3-morning-report-9177062.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-ruled-fit-to-bat-but-decision-on-bowling-to-be-made-on-day-3-morning-report-9177062.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 16:39:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 superfoods to make your legs stronger - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxQcV9fRWlxalV4Z0hXeHhvMThuRkJDb005RTh1RzFKLWwxTHpXbmZHLUNzejB1TERlQU1vNV9TY1lNMENhYlVKRHJvRDF1V005MDNsbl9Qa1B4SUcySlJmaE9kTVN2aXFHR0EtczdSeWYwUExncl9BRXZZNmNxTWc2SmdjeWF2NXJENHpMc1B0aWJzWHhaUzBBaXlfS2EtYUF1Wm9BNUM5dHVDejgydm4xMEl5bXRPM2NNN0l4Smp4ZExHM1djWU9IYVN2dGFpTElSR0JKOVRR0gHWAUFVX3lxTFBxX19FaXFqVXhnSFd4eG8xOG5GQkNvTTlFOHVHMUotbDFMelduZkctQ3N6MHVMRGVBTW81X1NjWU0wQ2FiVUpEcm9EMXVXTTkwM2xuX1BrUHhJRzJKUmZoT2RNU3ZpcUdHQS1zN1J5ZjBQTGdyX0FFdlk2Y3FNZzZKZ2N5YXY1ckQ0ekxzUHRpYnNYeFpTMEFpeV9LYS1hQXVab0E1Qzl0dUN6ODJ2bjEwSXltdE8zY003SXhKanhkTEczV2NZT0hhU3Z0YWlMSVJHQko5VFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxQcV9fRWlxalV4Z0hXeHhvMThuRkJDb005RTh1RzFKLWwxTHpXbmZHLUNzejB1TERlQU1vNV9TY1lNMENhYlVKRHJvRDF1V005MDNsbl9Qa1B4SUcySlJmaE9kTVN2aXFHR0EtczdSeWYwUExncl9BRXZZNmNxTWc2SmdjeWF2NXJENHpMc1B0aWJzWHhaUzBBaXlfS2EtYUF1Wm9BNUM5dHVDejgydm4xMEl5bXRPM2NNN0l4Smp4ZExHM1djWU9IYVN2dGFpTElSR0JKOVRR0gHWAUFVX3lxTFBxX19FaXFqVXhnSFd4eG8xOG5GQkNvTTlFOHVHMUotbDFMelduZkctQ3N6MHVMRGVBTW81X1NjWU0wQ2FiVUpEcm9EMXVXTTkwM2xuX1BrUHhJRzJKUmZoT2RNU3ZpcUdHQS1zN1J5ZjBQTGdyX0FFdlk2Y3FNZzZKZ2N5YXY1ckQ0ekxzUHRpYnNYeFpTMEFpeV9LYS1hQXVab0E1Qzl0dUN6ODJ2bjEwSXltdE8zY003SXhKanhkTEczV2NZT0hhU3Z0YWlMSVJHQko5VFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Janhvi Kapoor visits Tirumala Temple with rumoured boyfriend Shikhar Pahariya. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Janhvi Kapoor Visits Tirumala Temple with Rumoured Boyfriend Shikhar Pahariya</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 04, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/Janhvi_Kapoor_1736007580623_1736007580896.jpg" alt="Janhvi was surrounded by her security personnel and fans." title="Janhvi was surrounded by her security personnel and fans."><figcaption>Janhvi was surrounded by her security personnel and fans.</figcaption><p>Bollywood actor Janhvi Kapoor visited the Tirumala Temple to seek blessings, accompanied by her rumored boyfriend Shikhar Pahariya. She greeted her fans while leaving the temple and is set to star in the upcoming film 'Param Sundari'.</p><ul><li>Janhvi wore a purple saree during her visit.</li><li>She was surrounded by security and fans.</li><li>Upcoming movie 'Param Sundari' is a cross-cultural love story with Sidharth Malhotra, releasing on July 25, 2025.</li><li>First-look posters of the film have been shared on social media.</li></ul><blockquote>“North ka swag, South ki grace - two worlds collide and spark fly.”</blockquote><p>The visit highlights Janhvi Kapoor's connection to her fans and her upcoming cinematic projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/janhvi-kapoor-visits-tirumala-temple-with-rumoured-boyfriend-shikhar-pahariya-watch-101736007373157.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/janhvi-kapoor-visits-tirumala-temple-with-rumoured-boyfriend-shikhar-pahariya-watch-101736007373157.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 16:25:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metro section, first Namo Bharat connectivity: PM Modi to flag off big projects in Delhi on Jan 5 | Details - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxOemxMVVhyVWthZnRCU3EybS1sTk9pWlhqUXo0MmNvdUhEVFBvMUVDQU9HenR2d1JicFZBZzI2UmlZUzlwLVZQb0R6bERLemFGZGxsRHN4cU9pa2lzYkZlYjlTZTZFaTBXb0F1N2xQZmFJTHB6SEhUNEtpMy1RWXRVamlPLUV6YVBNd2tFUXRYbUFrZ1ZtZHhOQ2FoWVZKdHNGVWlBdVZoMndRelo2dzhGMTFMX3JwTG9UUHJJS2I4YTg2bDl3eFRhRE5BVXVpNWdQSW5sWmdWVGtKbUhuUE9OVDdIY1pvQTlDUWdQN0VRTWQxbnAzUXRqdFhn0gH_AUFVX3lxTFBUbUxsb0NNUGQ5Tm54blFwZk9BWldiT0I0aHZaSmF2RGJiZTBiYkdlYVpGcmpuM0h4dWlXWEgxLW1OQTNYdU1VMnY1WmV1d1NlUnFfZE1RcDBLUF9TX294amxWNzNYM200SmJrUkdjVUpGX3p1dHBCYVV2UWtzU28zd1U1Q0RSOHFKSVFMOS1nVG42OXIzMVFXZlpMRXM2Qzc1b2gxWDZqeVRBQ25yTkk4QmM1bTQzdTQtUjZmek5nSUlLZkJMZVJYYlFTMzdhTVpKOFBXb2pON19LZ1YyZXJkYTZaWktpS3FWSW1ubTNRTHc1Z3E3eHdpaXFmNzBCQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxOemxMVVhyVWthZnRCU3EybS1sTk9pWlhqUXo0MmNvdUhEVFBvMUVDQU9HenR2d1JicFZBZzI2UmlZUzlwLVZQb0R6bERLemFGZGxsRHN4cU9pa2lzYkZlYjlTZTZFaTBXb0F1N2xQZmFJTHB6SEhUNEtpMy1RWXRVamlPLUV6YVBNd2tFUXRYbUFrZ1ZtZHhOQ2FoWVZKdHNGVWlBdVZoMndRelo2dzhGMTFMX3JwTG9UUHJJS2I4YTg2bDl3eFRhRE5BVXVpNWdQSW5sWmdWVGtKbUhuUE9OVDdIY1pvQTlDUWdQN0VRTWQxbnAzUXRqdFhn0gH_AUFVX3lxTFBUbUxsb0NNUGQ5Tm54blFwZk9BWldiT0I0aHZaSmF2RGJiZTBiYkdlYVpGcmpuM0h4dWlXWEgxLW1OQTNYdU1VMnY1WmV1d1NlUnFfZE1RcDBLUF9TX294amxWNzNYM200SmJrUkdjVUpGX3p1dHBCYVV2UWtzU28zd1U1Q0RSOHFKSVFMOS1nVG42OXIzMVFXZlpMRXM2Qzc1b2gxWDZqeVRBQ25yTkk4QmM1bTQzdTQtUjZmek5nSUlLZkJMZVJYYlFTMzdhTVpKOFBXb2pON19LZ1YyZXJkYTZaWktpS3FWSW1ubTNRTHc1Z3E3eHdpaXFmNzBCQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 16:17:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Need to establish 5-6 more cooperatives like Amul: PM Modi - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Need to establish 5-6 more cooperatives like Amul: PM Modi</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 04 January 2025, 16:10 IST</p><p>In a speech at the Grameen Bharat Mahotsav, Prime Minister Narendra Modi emphasized the need to create additional large cooperatives similar to Amul, which he noted provides high returns to farmers.</p><ul><li>Modi called for the establishment of 5-6 more national cooperatives akin to Amul.</li><li>He highlighted Amul's success with a turnover of Rs 80,000 crore in 2023-24.</li><li>The Prime Minister urged for more Farmer Producer Organizations (FPOs) to ensure better prices for farmers.</li><li>According to Modi, 25 crore people have been lifted out of poverty in the last decade.</li><li>The event was organized to focus on building a resilient rural India by 2047.</li></ul><blockquote>“For the first time since independence, the expenditure on food in rural areas has fallen below 50%,” Modi stated, noting a positive shift in consumption patterns.</blockquote><p>The Prime Minister's call to action aims to enhance agricultural productivity and improve farmers' economic conditions, reinforcing the government's commitment to rural development.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/need-to-establish-5-6-more-cooperatives-like-amul-pm-modi-3341741</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/need-to-establish-5-6-more-cooperatives-like-amul-pm-modi-3341741</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 16:10:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China HMPV outbreak: Kerala, Telangana closely monitoring situation amid reports of massive flu surge - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxOQmttX1VTd2pSYXB6bG10M3FzTkc0M2lBVUhUcHZkODhiYXpJeXZEc1JvODV1SXctbGxLZXJRZ1RGd0Zob1Y2STdTYjE0Z1RobXh5dElfUFlkT1Fpb25oX25hYXRjQ0hDWkhVVFpmMmxPb1ZrVHc1RnY0SmVCbGMtaWJwVmhJN3dodHFhOU1wQUg4NVFjSy1remVjRzVDbmF5QlZnc3ZEdnFabHo4YzFMRkt3R0pFZjFQRzZVVW1aaVU0NWJLdU9UTmVoM1g2TFdmVlpQckVIbC1OSzdWcm1DWEpkUm84UFBmY1dnd09R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxOQmttX1VTd2pSYXB6bG10M3FzTkc0M2lBVUhUcHZkODhiYXpJeXZEc1JvODV1SXctbGxLZXJRZ1RGd0Zob1Y2STdTYjE0Z1RobXh5dElfUFlkT1Fpb25oX25hYXRjQ0hDWkhVVFpmMmxPb1ZrVHc1RnY0SmVCbGMtaWJwVmhJN3dodHFhOU1wQUg4NVFjSy1remVjRzVDbmF5QlZnc3ZEdnFabHo4YzFMRkt3R0pFZjFQRzZVVW1aaVU0NWJLdU9UTmVoM1g2TFdmVlpQckVIbC1OSzdWcm1DWEpkUm84UFBmY1dnd09R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 16:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aubrey Plaza said she was 'proud' of husband Jeff Baena in last Instagram post before his death - The Mirror US]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aubrey Plaza said she was 'proud' of husband in last post before his death</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Mirror</p><div><img src="https://i2-prod.themirror.com/incoming/article890430.ece/ALTERNATES/s615b/0_MAIN-Aubrey-Plazas-last-Instagram-post-with-husband-Jeff-Baena-before-his-death-showed-how-proud-she-was-of-him.jpg" alt="Aubrey Plaza and her husband" width="615" height="345"><figcaption>Aubrey Plaza shared a loving post about her husband</figcaption></div><p>Aubrey Plaza expressed her affection and pride for her husband Jeff Baena in an Instagram post just before his untimely death at 47.</p><ul><li>Jeff Baena was found dead in their Los Angeles home on Friday.</li><li>Aubrey's last Instagram post in May 2021 highlighted her pride in Jeff's movie projects.</li><li>Law enforcement continues to investigate the cause of Jeff's death.</li><li>Tributes from fans express condolences and sadness over his passing.</li></ul><blockquote>“So proud of my darling husband @jeffbaena for dreaming up another film that takes us to Italia to cause some more trouble,” said Aubrey in her last post.</blockquote><p>This tragic event highlights the sudden loss that can impact loved ones. Aubrey's heartfelt words bring attention to the profound relationships we cherish.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.themirror.com/entertainment/aubrey-plaza-jeff-baena-instagram-890428</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themirror.com/entertainment/aubrey-plaza-jeff-baena-instagram-890428</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 16:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Modi govt 3.0 is maintaining an arm’s length from protesting farmers - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why Modi govt 3.0 is maintaining an arm’s length from protesting farmers</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<p>Union Agriculture Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan has indicated a distant approach from the ongoing farmers' protests led by the Samyukta Kisan Morcha and Kisan Mazdoor Morcha, unlike the proactive measures taken during Modi's previous term.</p>
<ul>
<li>Farmers have been protesting since February 2024 at the Punjab-Haryana borders, demanding legal status for Minimum Support Price (MSP) and a farm debt waiver.</li>
<li>Chouhan has extended an open invitation for talks, yet has not engaged directly with the protesting farmers.</li>
<li>The government's previous attempts to resolve farmer grievances, particularly in 2020-21, led to escalated tensions and prolonged protests.</li>
<li>Current protests are more localized and lack the broad unity seen in earlier movements.</li>
<li>Jagjit Singh Dallewal, president of BKU Sidhupur, is on a hunger strike demanding response to farmers' issues from the government.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Currently, the Supreme Court is looking into this issue. Whatever directives the Supreme Court gives, will be followed.” - Shivraj Singh Chouhan</blockquote>
<p>This current strategy marks a significant shift in the government's handling of farmer-related issues, emphasizing a more detached stance in contrast to previous direct engagements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/modi-govt-protesting-farmers-msp-demands-farm-laws-9759720/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/modi-govt-protesting-farmers-msp-demands-farm-laws-9759720/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atul Subhash suicide case: Wife Nikita Singhania, her mother and brother get bail - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nikita Singhania, Family Granted Bail in Atul Subhash Suicide Case</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 4, 2025<br>Source: Times of India</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/b1825270da545fccb2ddaca231d35d6a.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="200"><figcaption>Nikita Singhania and her family after being granted bail.</figcaption>
<p>Nikita Singhania, the wife of Atul Subhash who allegedly committed suicide, along with her mother and brother, have been granted bail in the case. The Mumbai Sessions Court granted them bail on Tuesday, January 3, 2025.</p>
<ul>
<li>The court set a bail bond of Rs 10,000 each for Nikita and her family.</li>
<li>The court also imposed certain conditions, including that they do not leave the country without prior permission and that they cooperate with the investigation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>The court observed that the accused are not likely to abscond and will cooperate with the investigation.</p></blockquote>
<p>The next hearing in the case is scheduled for February 15, 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/atul-subhash-suicide-case-wife-nikita-singhania-her-mother-and-brother-get-bail/articleshow/116943940.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/atul-subhash-suicide-case-wife-nikita-singhania-her-mother-and-brother-get-bail/articleshow/116943940.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi fog: City sees season's longest zero visibility spell; 400 flights delayed - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNbW9RTUQ3T01NUnRXRzVVR0hEQWpFb012ZUt6UXdaVF9NbWM4cVBiM3hobmpPdFd3TFZ3anNRZ1V0NmhyMUJZVFdzQmx4ZldOLXVRQVFYb1pFRWRtaV84bXhUZlVHbTZUT2dQS2pzQWF4MF9FdzNkNVk1UzJ2SVRjNnNQZzVSTjVPMWVBa0VlaGRSU3dBYkplSDNEYk9ldDFiOXFwbjdDc1VGZTJ3UzZHb0pnSURtcXdsWWF2MURiZWNqRGV3dnN0akZzSGs3SWVjY0xJWVhIMNIB3AFBVV95cUxOMEdTMDQyQUNUTkstN00zTGktUnhDRUg1RWN2c18zT0YxSGJOQk13c2pMS3VHdXR5dmZqQ2hTd0dkcnJpWWJDbk93bUxoOHI5dkpTWXo0SUo2aDZjWDRMTjE4eHgwLVBlYjN1X2ktc3pMRm03Y1pFbEpmWXNXc1M3Tk04bkFleXlxb05PaXJ2UGZ6SHlPVUswUzZJcEhkVndnT1ZEWV9SOEhWcERNS1YxYmlHRWVPTWtWLUVGQnpiUXN2ajV1NHVtbHEzOEpiTi02bFhUdDVZYmZfUGFs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNbW9RTUQ3T01NUnRXRzVVR0hEQWpFb012ZUt6UXdaVF9NbWM4cVBiM3hobmpPdFd3TFZ3anNRZ1V0NmhyMUJZVFdzQmx4ZldOLXVRQVFYb1pFRWRtaV84bXhUZlVHbTZUT2dQS2pzQWF4MF9FdzNkNVk1UzJ2SVRjNnNQZzVSTjVPMWVBa0VlaGRSU3dBYkplSDNEYk9ldDFiOXFwbjdDc1VGZTJ3UzZHb0pnSURtcXdsWWF2MURiZWNqRGV3dnN0akZzSGs3SWVjY0xJWVhIMNIB3AFBVV95cUxOMEdTMDQyQUNUTkstN00zTGktUnhDRUg1RWN2c18zT0YxSGJOQk13c2pMS3VHdXR5dmZqQ2hTd0dkcnJpWWJDbk93bUxoOHI5dkpTWXo0SUo2aDZjWDRMTjE4eHgwLVBlYjN1X2ktc3pMRm03Y1pFbEpmWXNXc1M3Tk04bkFleXlxb05PaXJ2UGZ6SHlPVUswUzZJcEhkVndnT1ZEWV9SOEhWcERNS1YxYmlHRWVPTWtWLUVGQnpiUXN2ajV1NHVtbHEzOEpiTi02bFhUdDVZYmZfUGFs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:50:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govinda's wife Sunita Ahuja reveals Raveena Tandon still says 'Chichi, if I met you earlier, I would have - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Govinda's wife Sunita Ahuja reveals Raveena Tandon still says 'Chichi, if I met you earlier, I would have married you'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In a light-hearted revelation, Sunita Ahuja, wife of Indian actor Govinda, shared that actress Raveena Tandon often expresses her jest about possibly marrying Govinda if circumstances had been different.</p><ul><li>Sunita Ahuja mentions that Raveena expresses her feelings every time they meet.</li><li>The quote 'Chichi, if I met you earlier, I would have married you' reflects Raveena's playful sentiment.</li><li>Sunita's reaction to Raveena's remark includes humor, saying 'Le ja, pata chalega tereko' which adds to the light-heartedness of the situation.</li></ul><blockquote>“Chichi, if I met you earlier, I would have married you” - Raveena Tandon.</blockquote><p>This amusing exchange highlights the camaraderie between the two actresses and Govinda, showcasing a playful take on relationships in the film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/govindas-wife-sunita-ahuja-reveals-raveena-tandon-still-says-chichi-if-i-met-you-earlier-i-would-have-married-you-le-ja-pata-chalega-tereko/articleshow/116947077.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/govindas-wife-sunita-ahuja-reveals-raveena-tandon-still-says-chichi-if-i-met-you-earlier-i-would-have-married-you-le-ja-pata-chalega-tereko/articleshow/116947077.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space42's Thuraya 4 Satellite Successfully Launched Into Orbit - PR Newswire]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Space42's Thuraya 4 Satellite Successfully Launched Into Orbit</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> /PRNewswire/ </p><img src="https://mma.prnewswire.com/media/2590571/Space42_Logo_Logo.jpg" alt="Space42 Logo"><figcaption>Space42 Logo</figcaption><p>Space42 has successfully launched its Thuraya 4 telecommunications satellite into orbit aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket from Cape Canaveral, Florida. This satellite aims to enhance connectivity across multiple regions and support upcoming products in Space42’s portfolio.</p><ul><li>Thuraya 4 offers secure capacity, faster speeds, and wider coverage across Africa, Europe, Central Asia, and the Middle East.</li><li>The launch is a crucial step in Space42's plan to introduce 15 new products.</li><li>The satellite was deployed at 20:26 Eastern Time and will take months to reach its operational orbit.</li></ul><blockquote>His Excellency Mansoor Al Mansoori, Chairman of Space42, stated: "The successful launch of Thuraya 4 is a testament to our commitment to push innovation boundaries and strengthen the UAE's leadership in the SpaceTech sector globally."</blockquote><p>The launch highlights Space42's ambition to reshape connectivity and contribute to the UAE's National Space Strategy 2030.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.prnewswire.com/in/news-releases/space42s-thuraya-4-satellite-successfully-launched-into-orbit-302342300.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.prnewswire.com/in/news-releases/space42s-thuraya-4-satellite-successfully-launched-into-orbit-302342300.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘India well-prepared’: On HMPV, govt says situation in China is not unusual - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Preparedness Against Rising Respiratory Illnesses Amid China's HMPV Cases</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 04, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/india_health_ministry_hmpv_china__1736005149419_1736005149655.jpg" alt="Health Ministry Vigilance" title="The health ministry said that the health systems and surveillance networks remain vigilant.(Representative/Getty Images)">
<figcaption>The health ministry said that the health systems and surveillance networks remain vigilant.(Representative/Getty Images)</figcaption>
<p>The Union health ministry reassures the public that India is well-prepared to handle respiratory infections as reports of HMPV cases in China rise. The ministry describes the situation as not unusual.</p>
<ul>
  <li>A Joint Monitoring Group meeting was held to assess the rising respiratory illness cases.</li>
  <li>Experts from WHO, IDSP, and other organizations participated in the deliberations.</li>
  <li>The ministry attributes the surge to seasonal pathogens such as Influenza virus, RSV, and HMPV.</li>
  <li>No significant increase in Influenza Like Illness (ILI) or Severe Acute Respiratory Illness (SARI) cases in India.</li>
  <li>ICMR will enhance testing for HMPV and monitor trends throughout the year.</li>
  <li>Health systems are described as vigilant and prepared for any health challenges.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"There is nothing to be alarmed about in the present situation." - Dr. Atul Goel, DGHS</blockquote>
<p>In summary, India's health infrastructure is well-equipped to manage any respiratory illness increases, ensuring public health safety during the flu season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-well-prepared-on-hmpv-govt-says-situation-in-china-is-not-unusual-101736004987056.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-well-prepared-on-hmpv-govt-says-situation-in-china-is-not-unusual-101736004987056.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:44:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weather news live: Delhi witnesses season's longest zero visibility spell on Saturday, says IMD - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Experiences Longest Zero Visibility Spell of the Season</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 4, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/TOPSHOT-INDIA-WEATHER-2_1735994082366_1735994091332.jpg" alt="Dense fog covers Delhi" title="As intense cold weather conditions continued, dense fog covered Delhi and nearby states.">
<figcaption>Dense fog blankets Delhi and neighboring states, affecting visibility.</figcaption>
<p>Delhi witnessed a nine-hour stretch of zero visibility on Saturday, the longest of the season, according to the India Meteorological Department (IMD). This severe weather condition resulted in significant disruptions to flight and train operations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Flight operations at Delhi airport were severely impacted, with 91 trains delayed and 400 flights affected.</li>
  <li>IndiGo and Air India temporarily halted arrivals and departures due to thick fog.</li>
  <li>The IMD recorded zero visibility for nine hours at Palam and eight hours at Safdarjung.</li>
  <li>Dense fog also affected visibility in other regions like Punjab, Haryana, and Uttar Pradesh.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Zero visibility prevailed for nine hours at Palam between 6 pm and 3 am (UTC), marking the longest spell of the season," stated the IMD.</blockquote>
<p>This unusual weather phenomenon has drawn attention to the ongoing cold wave affecting many parts of northern India, prompting advisories from airlines and the government to ensure safety and manage operations effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/weather-live-updates-fog-cold-wave-delhi-airport-haryana-uttar-pradesh-january-4-2024-101735943715851.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/weather-live-updates-fog-cold-wave-delhi-airport-haryana-uttar-pradesh-january-4-2024-101735943715851.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:28:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Taken The Pants Of The Aussies": World Cup-Winner's Funny Praise For Rishabh Pant - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxNbnF0Vi1qendva2ZmMnc1UlNuemc1djVaUUZrVzBYVDBSaHg4ZTFnX0VURXI1MzgwZE9uWUxJNmJKanBCMkw5dFRueWplTVRKbzZXQ3FBQndiSENXS3dUSDBhaUdpcE5vNFNHVEFfNXRGNFN2SGhOT3pyQUlUWndoZEVhbEhqRUpSUXZ0RnRkOVYxS3VuXzJpNUlwU3MxemJoQnc2cHA5UUVkb2J6ZmJmaTBXZVg0bG1pVWtIQ1J4XzJUbGVELUZMemNfT0JjLUNEQXdBLW9uNkowd3lV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxNbnF0Vi1qendva2ZmMnc1UlNuemc1djVaUUZrVzBYVDBSaHg4ZTFnX0VURXI1MzgwZE9uWUxJNmJKanBCMkw5dFRueWplTVRKbzZXQ3FBQndiSENXS3dUSDBhaUdpcE5vNFNHVEFfNXRGNFN2SGhOT3pyQUlUWndoZEVhbEhqRUpSUXZ0RnRkOVYxS3VuXzJpNUlwU3MxemJoQnc2cHA5UUVkb2J6ZmJmaTBXZVg0bG1pVWtIQ1J4XzJUbGVELUZMemNfT0JjLUNEQXdBLW9uNkowd3lV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:09:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Box Office Collection Day 31: Allu Arjun movie’s gold rush normalises, mints ₹3.45 crore on Saturday | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Collection Day 31: Earnings Steady at ₹3.45 Crore</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>After a stellar run, 'Pushpa: The Rule' sees a slight dip in box office performance but remains competitive with ₹3.45 crore earned on Saturday, bringing its total domestic collection to ₹1196.95 crore.</p><ul><li>The film achieved ₹3.45 crore net at the Indian Box Office on Saturday.</li><li>Tollywood movie's occupancy rates were 13.48% for Telugu, 13.61% for Hindi, and 19.37% for Tamil.</li><li>Total gross worldwide collection in 28 days has reached ₹1,799 crores.</li><li>'Pushpa 2' aims to join the ₹800 crore Club after significant earnings in the fourth week.</li></ul><blockquote>“800 NOT OUT… #Pushpa2 is all set to inaugurate the ₹800 cr Club... The #AlluArjun starrer has amassed a huge ₹57.95 cr in Week 4, setting a new benchmark.” - Taran Adarsh</blockquote><p>This film, directed by Sukumar and featuring Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna, continues to break records and solidify its status as a leading grosser in Indian cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-31-allu-arjun-movie-s-gold-rush-normalises-mints-rs-3-45-crore-on-saturday-11736002598298.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-31-allu-arjun-movie-s-gold-rush-normalises-mints-rs-3-45-crore-on-saturday-11736002598298.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:08:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>