<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:20:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:20:58 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Constipation Awareness Month 2024: 10 Changes Everyone Can Make To Their Diet For Better Digestion - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Constipation Awareness Month 2024: 10 Changes Everyone Can Make To Their Diet For Better Digestion</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> April 2, 2024 by NDTV</p>
<img title="Constipation Awareness Month 2024: 10 Changes Everyone Can Make To Their Diet For Better Digestion" alt="Constipation Awareness Month 2024: 10 Changes Everyone Can Make To Their Diet For Better Digestion" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/c8uelv9_constipation_625x300_02_April_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400">
<figcaption>Constipation Awareness Month 2024 aims to educate about dietary changes that improve digestion.</figcaption>
<p>December is recognized as Constipation Awareness Month, focusing on educating the public about constipation, its causes, and prevention methods. Chronic constipation can lead to serious complications, and dietary changes play a key role in managing this condition.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Increase fibre intake with soluble and insoluble sources.</li>
  <li>Stay hydrated by drinking at least eight glasses of water daily.</li>
  <li>Incorporate probiotics through foods like yogurt and fermented vegetables.</li>
  <li>Limit processed foods to enhance digestive efficiency.</li>
  <li>Eat regular, balanced meals to support digestive health.</li>
  <li>Chew food thoroughly to aid in digestion.</li>
  <li>Avoid excessive caffeine and alcohol to prevent dehydration.</li>
  <li>Incorporate healthy fats for better nutrient absorption.</li>
  <li>Include natural laxative foods like kiwis and prunes.</li>
  <li>Practice mindful eating for improved digestion.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Implementing these dietary changes can lead to significant improvements in digestive health, reducing the incidence of constipation and enhancing overall well-being.”</blockquote>
<p>It's vital to introduce these changes gradually and consult healthcare professionals for personalized advice.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/health/constipation-awareness-month-2024-10-changes-everyone-can-make-to-their-diet-for-better-digestion-7312739</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/health/constipation-awareness-month-2024-10-changes-everyone-can-make-to-their-diet-for-better-digestion-7312739</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:03:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steering, Throttle Fault May Be Behind Mumbai Ferry Crash, Crew Knew: Sources - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Steering, Throttle Fault May Be Behind Mumbai Ferry Crash, Crew Knew: Sources</h1><p><strong>Published on December 18, Source: Mumbai News</strong></p><p>The recent collision between a Navy boat and a passenger ferry in Mumbai resulted in tragic losses, likely due to technical issues with the naval vessel.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred on December 18, resulting in 15 deaths.</li><li>A technical malfunction in the steering assembly and throttle quadrant is believed to be the cause.</li><li>The Navy boat was reportedly speeding and lost control before the collision.</li><li>The ferry was carrying over 100 passengers and sank in the Arabian Sea.</li><li>Of the 113 people on both vessels, 15 perished, and 98 were rescued.</li><li>The ferry was overloaded, surpassing its licensed passenger capacity.</li><li>The Maharashtra Maritime Board has initiated an investigation and cancelled the ferry's license.</li></ul><blockquote>“The crew was aware of the malfunction when the collision took place.” - Survivor from the Navy vessel</blockquote><p>The tragedy highlights significant safety concerns in maritime operations and calls for a thorough investigation into the events leading to the accident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/mumbai-ferry-crash-steering-fault-caused-mumbai-ferry-crash-navy-crew-was-aware-sources-7312550</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/mumbai-ferry-crash-steering-fault-caused-mumbai-ferry-crash-navy-crew-was-aware-sources-7312550</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:36:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Advanced center for Asthma care launched in Chennai - Healthcare Radius]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthcareradius.in/clinical/advanced-center-for-asthma-care-launched-in-chennai</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcareradius.in/clinical/advanced-center-for-asthma-care-launched-in-chennai</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:17:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan's batting sensation Saim Ayub joins Virat Kohli in this elite list - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/pakistans-batting-sensation-saim-ayub-joins-virat-kohli-in-this-elite-list/articleshow/116589098.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/pakistans-batting-sensation-saim-ayub-joins-virat-kohli-in-this-elite-list/articleshow/116589098.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp to end support for older Android phones from January 1, 2025: Full list here - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp to End Support for Older Android Phones Starting January 1, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified; <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p>
<p>In a significant move, Meta announced that WhatsApp will cease to support older Android devices beginning January 1, 2025. Users operating on Android KitKat and older versions will be unable to run the app, impacting millions globally.</p>
<figure>
<img src="path_to_image_if_available.jpg" alt="WhatsApp logo">
<figcaption>WhatsApp logo</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>Key Points</h2>
<ul>
  <li>WhatsApp support will end for all Android devices running KitKat or older.</li>
  <li>Users are encouraged to back up their data to newer devices.</li>
  <li>Affected brands include Samsung, Motorola, HTC, LG, and Sony.</li>
  <li>Meta previously announced similar plans for older iPhones.</li>
  <li>Important backup tips provided to help users transition smoothly.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>"If you are still using one of these devices as your daily driver, the logical way forward is to back up all your WhatsApp data to a newer device."</p></blockquote>
<p>As WhatsApp phases out support for older systems, users must take proactive measures to move their data to updated devices to avoid losing access to their chat histories.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-whatsapp-to-end-support-for-older-android-phones-from-january-1-2025-full-list-here-3697963/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-whatsapp-to-end-support-for-older-android-phones-from-january-1-2025-full-list-here-3697963/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:08:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Science News | ⚡Upcoming NASA Missions 2025: List of Major NASA Missions Scheduled for Next Year - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxOZmlTQkh3bjN1MDZMYTlGaEhUc2xYNU9ucHI0T0VwX04xRHhVYXlmVC13Y3dfMHl6NUFjMmtYNnFwRkdaaTJvZ2hwZHpFdjRpYkFDOU45MG5qR2tuZVNfdkp6N01FdVNQalJydDZSYkRhUWY5UkRLbEIzc1hqdEtHM3VBQmhWSXhOdXUyQlR6a2NLWkxFOXN3NU9SSUdnbnNkMktXTFNBc1N2d21LaUlqeW9ZRkV1VzVSMUtRN0o2bnpLVURuUDdBVW5nX0hMU2NiaElPMl9BdWFIZXN60gHcAUFVX3lxTE5maVNCSHduM3UwNkxhOUZoSFRzbFg1T25wcjRPRXBfTjFEeFVheWZULXdjd18weXo1QWMya1g2cXBGR1ppMm9naHBkekV2NGliQUM5TjkwbmpHa25lU192Sno3TUV1U1BqUnJ0NlJiRGFRZjlSREtsQjNzWGp0S0czdUFCaFZJeE51dTJCVHprY0taTEU5c3c1T1JJR2duc2QyS1dMU0FzU3Z3bUtpSWp5b1lGRXVXNVIxS1E3SjZuektVRG5QN0FVbmdfSExTY2JoSU8yX0F1YUhlc3o?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxOZmlTQkh3bjN1MDZMYTlGaEhUc2xYNU9ucHI0T0VwX04xRHhVYXlmVC13Y3dfMHl6NUFjMmtYNnFwRkdaaTJvZ2hwZHpFdjRpYkFDOU45MG5qR2tuZVNfdkp6N01FdVNQalJydDZSYkRhUWY5UkRLbEIzc1hqdEtHM3VBQmhWSXhOdXUyQlR6a2NLWkxFOXN3NU9SSUdnbnNkMktXTFNBc1N2d21LaUlqeW9ZRkV1VzVSMUtRN0o2bnpLVURuUDdBVW5nX0hMU2NiaElPMl9BdWFIZXN60gHcAUFVX3lxTE5maVNCSHduM3UwNkxhOUZoSFRzbFg1T25wcjRPRXBfTjFEeFVheWZULXdjd18weXo1QWMya1g2cXBGR1ppMm9naHBkekV2NGliQUM5TjkwbmpHa25lU192Sno3TUV1U1BqUnJ0NlJiRGFRZjlSREtsQjNzWGp0S0czdUFCaFZJeE51dTJCVHprY0taTEU5c3c1T1JJR2duc2QyS1dMU0FzU3Z3bUtpSWp5b1lGRXVXNVIxS1E3SjZuektVRG5QN0FVbmdfSExTY2JoSU8yX0F1YUhlc3o?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:08:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Which Continent Is 90% Covered By Ice? - Jagran Josh]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Which Continent Is 90% Covered By Ice?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 23, Dec 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> jagranjosh.com</p>
<img src="https://img.jagranjosh.com/webstories/118800/pexels-photo-13663494-1734932799.webp" alt="Which Continent Is 90% Covered By Ice?">
<figcaption>Which Continent Is 90% Covered By Ice?</figcaption>
<p>Antarctica, the coldest continent on Earth, is covered by ice that constitutes about 90% of its land area, playing a vital role in global climate regulation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Antarctica contains over 90% of its landmass under thick ice.</li>
  <li>It holds approximately 60% of the world's fresh water.</li>
  <li>Temperatures in Antarctica can drop below -60°C (-76°F).</li>
  <li>No permanent human settlements exist; only temporary research stations.</li>
  <li>Antarctica’s glaciers are critical for global sea levels.</li>
  <li>Diverse wildlife such as penguins and seals are adapted to the harsh conditions.</li>
  <li>Home to international research stations studying climate change and other scientific fields.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Antarctica is crucial for understanding Earth's climate and ecosystems."</blockquote>
<p>This article emphasizes Antarctica's significance in global climate systems and the extreme conditions that define its environment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jagranjosh.com/web-stories/which-continent-is-90-covered-by-ice-118800</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jagranjosh.com/web-stories/which-continent-is-90-covered-by-ice-118800</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:06:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Unique methods astronauts use to maintain hygiene at International Space Station - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Unique Methods Astronauts Use to Maintain Hygiene at the International Space Station</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>December 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>India.com</p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/NASA-Astronaut-2.jpg" alt="NASA Astronaut" height="768" width="1280"><figcaption>NASA Astronaut</figcaption><p>Astronauts on the International Space Station (ISS) face unique challenges when it comes to hygiene due to the lack of traditional bathing facilities. Here are five creative methods they use to stay clean while orbiting the Earth.</p><ul><li>Astronauts brush their teeth with minimal water and wipe off excess toothpaste.</li><li>They use no-rinse shampoo for their hair, rubbing it in and towel-drying it without rinsing.</li><li>No-rinse body wipes replace baths for personal cleaning.</li><li>Instead of washing clothes, they wear disposable ones which are thrown away after use.</li><li>The crew regularly disinfects surfaces in the spacecraft to prevent bacteria build-up.</li></ul><blockquote>They routinely wipe down the spacecraft’s surfaces with disinfectant wipes and vacuum-cleaner-like devices to prevent bacteria from building up.</blockquote><p>Maintaining hygiene in space is crucial for health and wellbeing, showcasing the innovative adaptations required for life beyond Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/science/5-unique-methods-astronauts-use-to-maintain-hygiene-at-international-space-station-7485450/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/science/5-unique-methods-astronauts-use-to-maintain-hygiene-at-international-space-station-7485450/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Marriages, Rs 1.25 Crore: How 'Looteri Dulhan' Targeted Rich Men - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>3 Marriages, Rs 1.25 Crore: How 'Looteri Dulhan' Targeted Rich Men</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/5nvp3cn8_kanpur-bride_625x300_23_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="3 Marriages, Rs 1.25 Crore: How 'Looteri Dulhan' Targeted Rich Men"><figcaption>Seema, the woman behind the multiple marriages.</figcaption><p>A woman has been arrested over a decade after marrying a series of men and extracting over ₹ 1.25 crore from them under the pretext of settlements.</p><ul><li>Seema, also known as Nikki, first married a businessman from Agra in 2013 and received ₹ 75 lakh after filing a case against his family.</li><li>In 2017, she married a software engineer from Gurugram, taking an additional ₹ 10 lakh after their separation.</li><li>Her latest marriage was to a businessman from Jaipur in 2023, from whom she fled with cash and jewellery worth ₹ 36 lakh.</li></ul><blockquote>“Police investigation revealed that Seema sought her victims on matrimonial sites, focusing on men who were divorced or widowed.”</blockquote><p>This case highlights the alarming trend of individuals exploiting matrimonial platforms for financial gain.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/looteri-dulhan-how-woman-targeted-rich-men-to-swindle-rs-1-25-crore-7312255</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/looteri-dulhan-how-woman-targeted-rich-men-to-swindle-rs-1-25-crore-7312255</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 05:49:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ousted Syrian President Assad’s Wife Unhappy With Life In Russia? What Led Her To File For Divorce - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxOa0swVnNRYS1LeDVyOEwwUm5yX3FRNjA4ZzB5Zm8yNmQwZVp6SERzWHIwM3QycHE5aDNDUEo5RHhrMEZYQkZReVRPQjRvRDk4cDdhcVZ0c3h5V3NEVC1FNExyZ2NsRUh3WURJNzNnS3RrdkZSSzQ0cGhyaUJtblJRVzVRTkpqQWkwdUJyWXB6RUFuMTlaclpseDZlbm5US1U2TmRnckEwYWZqSFlhSm8tZWFlZG50RG8xWW9qdXVwYzhxYm5ndGhBb2lHeXRDVkXSAdQBQVVfeXFMTy1RNUxPbXZkN1BoazI0SXk0SXhCakwzMzhrcGVUVTh2WGlXQk8yUDViZWJyOXRaSEU3eHk2aXVnNUJZMXNHODFYMnFmMVN4bUpsaTZuVFdseklCX1BFVWR5Q0MzUnlTbUl1enJHbl9YbHgwUFdJalU3UVN5T0FsaHZmdnNHZUYtejFOLXlpMDBYOHU5TjZXSWpwNjVxRnRKd3JqYzlBQVdzSU9lbFlfRmswV3JMbWd2WDNaLUl0NEpXSjZoU3Nva3pSMWVsZXpQOFJKM04?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxOa0swVnNRYS1LeDVyOEwwUm5yX3FRNjA4ZzB5Zm8yNmQwZVp6SERzWHIwM3QycHE5aDNDUEo5RHhrMEZYQkZReVRPQjRvRDk4cDdhcVZ0c3h5V3NEVC1FNExyZ2NsRUh3WURJNzNnS3RrdkZSSzQ0cGhyaUJtblJRVzVRTkpqQWkwdUJyWXB6RUFuMTlaclpseDZlbm5US1U2TmRnckEwYWZqSFlhSm8tZWFlZG50RG8xWW9qdXVwYzhxYm5ndGhBb2lHeXRDVkXSAdQBQVVfeXFMTy1RNUxPbXZkN1BoazI0SXk0SXhCakwzMzhrcGVUVTh2WGlXQk8yUDViZWJyOXRaSEU3eHk2aXVnNUJZMXNHODFYMnFmMVN4bUpsaTZuVFdseklCX1BFVWR5Q0MzUnlTbUl1enJHbl9YbHgwUFdJalU3UVN5T0FsaHZmdnNHZUYtejFOLXlpMDBYOHU5TjZXSWpwNjVxRnRKd3JqYzlBQVdzSU9lbFlfRmswV3JMbWd2WDNaLUl0NEpXSjZoU3Nva3pSMWVsZXpQOFJKM04?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 05:33:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zomato share price declines as it joins 30-share SENSEX; Here's how all constituents are performing - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zomato Share Price Declines as it Joins 30-Share SENSEX</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Upstox</p><img src="https://assets.upstox.com/content/assets/images/cms/20241223/zomat723rf.webp" alt="Zomato Share Price Declines"><figcaption>Zomato's performance on stock indices</figcaption><p>Zomato’s shares fell on its debut on the SENSEX index, experiencing a decline as it replaced JSW Steel in the index. Despite this, the company has shown substantial growth over the past year.</p><ul><li>Zomato's share price dropped 3% to ₹273.15 and closed down 0.37% at ₹280.80.</li><li>The stock has risen 38% in six months and 124.79% year-to-date.</li><li>In Q2 FY25, Zomato reported a 388.8% increase in consolidated profit after tax to ₹176 crore.</li><li>Revenue from operations increased by 68.5% to ₹4,799 crore.</li><li>The broader SENSEX was up 779 points, driven by major players like HDFC Bank and Reliance.</li></ul><blockquote>“Investors should note that past performance is not an indicator of future returns.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while Zomato’s entry into SENSEX was marked by an initial decline in stock price, the company shows significant growth potential based on its recent financial performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/zomato-share-price-declines-up-to-3-as-it-joins-30-share-sensex-here-s-how-all-constituents-are-performing/article-136550/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/zomato-share-price-declines-up-to-3-as-it-joins-30-share-sensex-here-s-how-all-constituents-are-performing/article-136550/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 05:05:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fact Check: Can bamboo layer and coconut oil make vitiligo disappear in a few days? - Medical Dialogues]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can Bamboo Layer and Coconut Oil Make Vitiligo Disappear in a Few Days?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Medical Dialogues</p><p>The article discusses a claim circulating on Instagram that a mixture of bamboo powder and coconut oil can cure vitiligo in just a few days. This claim is identified as false, with evidence showing that while bamboo and coconut oil may have some benefits for skin health, they do not cure vitiligo.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The claim that bamboo powder mixed with coconut oil can cure vitiligo is false.</li><li>Proper diagnosis and treatment are essential for vitiligo management.</li><li>Dr. Shireen Furtado explains evidence-based treatment options like topical corticosteroids and phototherapy.</li><li>No scientific evidence supports the use of bamboo powder for treating vitiligo.</li><li>Vitiligo is a complex condition that requires medical oversight.</li></ul><blockquote>Dr. Shireen Furtado: "No, such remedies are not scientifically proven to cure vitiligo. Effective treatments require time and medical guidance."</blockquote><p>The conclusion emphasizes the importance of consulting healthcare professionals for effective vitiligo treatments, as unverified remedies can be harmful.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://medicaldialogues.in/fact-check/skin-and-hair-care-fact-check/fact-check-can-bamboo-layer-and-coconut-oil-make-vitiligo-disappear-in-a-few-days-140009</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medicaldialogues.in/fact-check/skin-and-hair-care-fact-check/fact-check-can-bamboo-layer-and-coconut-oil-make-vitiligo-disappear-in-a-few-days-140009</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp will stop working on these Android smartphones from January 1: Is yours on list? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp to Stop Working on Older Android Smartphones from January 1</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/whatsapp-on-iphone.jpg?w=640" alt="WhatsApp on iPhone" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>WhatsApp is a cross-platform messaging app. (Image credit: Pixabay/HeikoAL)</figcaption>
<p>WhatsApp will discontinue support for over 20 older Android smartphones starting January 1, 2024, which primarily affects devices running Android KitKat or older. Users are advised to back up their chats to ensure data preservation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Over 20 Android devices will lose access to WhatsApp from January 1, 2024.</li>
  <li>Affected devices are mostly at least 10 years old.</li>
  <li>Other Meta apps like Facebook and Instagram are also likely to become unsupported on these devices.</li>
  <li>Brands affected include HTC and LG, which no longer manufacture smartphones.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We recommend you back up all the WhatsApp chats to a Google account to ensure easy restoration of all the chats to a new smartphone.”</blockquote>
<p>Users should consider upgrading their devices to maintain access to WhatsApp and other modern applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/whatsapp-will-stop-working-on-these-android-smartphones-from-january-1-9739917/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/whatsapp-will-stop-working-on-these-android-smartphones-from-january-1-9739917/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 04:54:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grenade attack in Gurdaspur: Three Khalistan Zindabad Force members gunned down in encounter in Pilibhit - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Grenade Attack in Gurdaspur: Encounter in Pilibhit Claims Lives of Three Khalistan Zindabad Force Suspects</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/xlulq8/article69017746.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_23_2024_000016B.jpg" alt="Police and security personnel after an encounter in Pilibhit, Uttar Pradesh, on December 23, 2024. Three criminals allegedly involved in a grenade attack in Gurdaspur were injured in an encounter with a joint team of Uttar Pradesh and Punjab police in Pilibhit." /><figcaption>Police and security personnel after an encounter in Pilibhit, Uttar Pradesh, on December 23, 2024. Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>Three terror suspects linked to a grenade attack in Gurdaspur were killed in a police encounter in Pilibhit, considered a significant victory against the Khalistan Zindabad Force.</p><ul><li>Suspects identified as Gurvinder Singh, Virender Singh, and Jaspreet Singh, all from Gurdaspur, Punjab.</li><li>The encounter occurred in Puranpur, Uttar Pradesh, early on December 23, 2024.</li><li>Weapons seized included two AK-47 rifles and two Glock pistols along with ammunition.</li><li>Punjab's Director General of Police highlighted this as a major breakthrough against the terror module.</li><li>All three suspects succumbed to injuries sustained in the encounter.</li><li>Investigation into their terror connections is ongoing.</li></ul><blockquote>“In a major breakthrough against a Pak-sponsored Khalistan Zindabad Force terror module, a joint operation led to an encounter with three module members.” – Gaurav Yadav, Punjab DGP</blockquote><p>This encounter marks a significant step in tackling terror activities associated with the Khalistan Zindabad Force in the region, furthering efforts to ensure public safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/grenade-attack-in-gurdaspur-three-khalistan-zindabad-force-members-gunned-down-in-encounter/article69017737.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/grenade-attack-in-gurdaspur-three-khalistan-zindabad-force-members-gunned-down-in-encounter/article69017737.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 04:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can homemade juice cause blood sugar spikes in diabetic patients? - Asianet Newsable ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can Homemade Juice Spike Blood Sugar in Diabetics?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Asianet Newsable</p><img src="https://static-gi.asianetnews.com/images/01jfppe11vj9fjecftx97gyzd8/Sugar-level-increase-with-natural-juice-1734854771771_720x1280xt.jpg" alt="Can homemade juice cause blood sugar spikes in diabetic patients?"><figcaption>Image illustrating the effects of homemade juice on blood sugar levels.</figcaption><p>This article discusses the potential risks of homemade juice for diabetic patients, emphasizing that it can lead to significant blood sugar spikes.</p><ul><li>Diabetics should avoid all types of juice, both homemade and store-bought, due to high glucose content.</li><li>Juicing fruits concentrates natural sugars, which can rapidly increase blood sugar levels.</li><li>Whole fruits contain fiber that helps regulate blood sugar; juice lacks this fiber, causing quicker absorption of sugar.</li><li>Juice empties the stomach faster than whole fruits, leading to increased hunger and more frequent eating.</li><li>Juicing reduces essential nutrients, such as fiber, vitamins, and minerals, making juice less nutritious.</li><li>Choosing whole fruits over juice is recommended for better blood sugar balance and sustained energy.</li></ul><blockquote>“Diabetics should choose whole fruits over juice for fiber and nutrients, balancing blood sugar and providing sustained energy.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while homemade juice may seem healthy, it poses risks for diabetics and is often less nutritious than whole fruits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOczJTM0s3M3psbEdZSV84dzhsUVJxLTcydV8xcGVJT1NWQnR3LWN4XzkwYnlCeVBIV1FoRHpyR2xJelZ5VDQzWG80LU5RWkU4SVctMExhOFRDa2tDU3NhUEY2ZGRrNm8wa1J2RGxrQ1VMTTJhZFNVeTJFbVIxN2R2UFlHX2NSN3B5bmtGTGxNQ0g2V0tTMWNVczBiZXdHRC1GNTB1ekFuMjZtWWxHcGRlYVNfekVrTzhmaUQ2aXNYQmVyWmRWTVZjR9IByAFBVV95cUxOczJTM0s3M3psbEdZSV84dzhsUVJxLTcydV8xcGVJT1NWQnR3LWN4XzkwYnlCeVBIV1FoRHpyR2xJelZ5VDQzWG80LU5RWkU4SVctMExhOFRDa2tDU3NhUEY2ZGRrNm8wa1J2RGxrQ1VMTTJhZFNVeTJFbVIxN2R2UFlHX2NSN3B5bmtGTGxNQ0g2V0tTMWNVczBiZXdHRC1GNTB1ekFuMjZtWWxHcGRlYVNfekVrTzhmaUQ2aXNYQmVyWmRWTVZjRw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOczJTM0s3M3psbEdZSV84dzhsUVJxLTcydV8xcGVJT1NWQnR3LWN4XzkwYnlCeVBIV1FoRHpyR2xJelZ5VDQzWG80LU5RWkU4SVctMExhOFRDa2tDU3NhUEY2ZGRrNm8wa1J2RGxrQ1VMTTJhZFNVeTJFbVIxN2R2UFlHX2NSN3B5bmtGTGxNQ0g2V0tTMWNVczBiZXdHRC1GNTB1ekFuMjZtWWxHcGRlYVNfekVrTzhmaUQ2aXNYQmVyWmRWTVZjR9IByAFBVV95cUxOczJTM0s3M3psbEdZSV84dzhsUVJxLTcydV8xcGVJT1NWQnR3LWN4XzkwYnlCeVBIV1FoRHpyR2xJelZ5VDQzWG80LU5RWkU4SVctMExhOFRDa2tDU3NhUEY2ZGRrNm8wa1J2RGxrQ1VMTTJhZFNVeTJFbVIxN2R2UFlHX2NSN3B5bmtGTGxNQ0g2V0tTMWNVczBiZXdHRC1GNTB1ekFuMjZtWWxHcGRlYVNfekVrTzhmaUQ2aXNYQmVyWmRWTVZjRw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 04:34:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SENSEX surges 500 pts in early trade on positive global cues, NIFTY50 tests 23,750; metal stocks rally - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxNbTZ0ak5lekNjX3hvOTRLLUZmZzJjM2VBZUluRmg1aC1qMTZVZW5HdElCRHRDVWNJckc5YmNyWWt3dG8tZE5iaDVBaWtoQm5JallTbnhyQmVVM2hMaEZnUElpQTJsS2pFSWJOZ3ZuanZQblU5Wk5lRUtQM1dCVjh1WXdJSDNmdTJKbU1qaFF5b3UxdDZlX3Nfckx4OWJXOWV4d2ZqR1NOY1pOVVBnTTg4alJUNUN3VlBHYlZKdER5RFNwQzBhMDlHS2pVdEJ0dnRNNGtFRTdRUnliOHZrd3FTSzRuM21CMmV2Z3ZLTnJIWDlfSzQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxNbTZ0ak5lekNjX3hvOTRLLUZmZzJjM2VBZUluRmg1aC1qMTZVZW5HdElCRHRDVWNJckc5YmNyWWt3dG8tZE5iaDVBaWtoQm5JallTbnhyQmVVM2hMaEZnUElpQTJsS2pFSWJOZ3ZuanZQblU5Wk5lRUtQM1dCVjh1WXdJSDNmdTJKbU1qaFF5b3UxdDZlX3Nfckx4OWJXOWV4d2ZqR1NOY1pOVVBnTTg4alJUNUN3VlBHYlZKdER5RFNwQzBhMDlHS2pVdEJ0dnRNNGtFRTdRUnliOHZrd3FTSzRuM21CMmV2Z3ZLTnJIWDlfSzQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 04:08:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Every square metre of Panama Canal is ours': President Mulino reacts to Trump's threat - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Every square metre of Panama Canal is ours': President Mulino reacts to Trump's threat</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [source not provided]</p>
<p>In response to recent threats from President Trump regarding the Panama Canal, President Mulino declared ownership and affirmed the country's position on the canal, emphasizing its sovereignty and importance.</p>
<ul>
<li>President Mulino emphasized that every square meter of the Panama Canal is under Panama's control.</li>
<li>The remarks come after President Trump's comments that stirred tensions.</li>
<li>Mulino plans to strengthen diplomatic efforts to ensure the canal's sovereignty is respected.</li>
<li>Public sentiment in Panama shows strong support for the government’s stance.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We will not allow any foreign power to dictate our rights over the canal.” - President Mulino</blockquote>
<p>This statement highlights the tensions between the US and Panama regarding control of the key maritime passage.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/every-square-meter-of-panama-canal-is-ours-president-mulino-reacts-to-trumps-threat/articleshow/116582744.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/every-square-meter-of-panama-canal-is-ours-president-mulino-reacts-to-trumps-threat/articleshow/116582744.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 04:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump appoints Indian American entrepreneur Sriram Krishnan as senior policy advisor on Artificial Intelligence - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Appoints Sriram Krishnan as Senior Policy Advisor on AI</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/nqa2ke/article69017706.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Sriram%20Krishnan.jpg" alt="Indian American entrepreneur Sriram Krishnan. Photo:X/@sriramk" title="Indian American entrepreneur Sriram Krishnan. Photo:X/@sriramk">
<figcaption>Indian American entrepreneur Sriram Krishnan. Photo: X/@sriramk</figcaption>
<p>U.S. President-elect Donald Trump has appointed Indian American entrepreneur Sriram Krishnan as Senior White House Policy Advisor on Artificial Intelligence.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sriram Krishnan previously worked at Microsoft, Twitter, Yahoo!, Facebook, and Snap.</li>
<li>He will collaborate with David O. Sacks, the White House AI & Crypto Czar.</li>
<li>Krishnan aims to ensure continued American leadership in AI and coordinate AI policy across the government.</li>
<li>His appointment has been positively received by the Indian American community.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I’m honored to be able to serve our country and ensure continued American leadership in AI working closely with David Sacks.” — Sriram Krishnan</blockquote>
<p>Krishnan's experience in public policy and technology is expected to benefit his role significantly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-appoints-indian-american-entrepreneur-sriram-krishnan-as-senior-policy-advisor-on-artificial-intelligence/article69017694.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-appoints-indian-american-entrepreneur-sriram-krishnan-as-senior-policy-advisor-on-artificial-intelligence/article69017694.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple’s app store puts kids a click away from a slew of inappropriate apps | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxOTENsY0Nlck92UkI3cnBOWXdmQlNoVkpuMEd3NVZQNDQ3RG11YW1Feng5Ymp3RTZxSFExUW1RYWdJbjJpVDZsTW1INFZyVWF5Z1FHaWh6Z0x2T29fdE8xUmxfM2lnZXZ2dXdMME1PbmRIbm9scWstQmZBbVQtRTJ4SFY2eFdMY3dnaUVBYmV1WEVGUGVHaTNhQkxzc0lXbzktREtiTDdLWU5KSXJoekRaZEFlZnVvZjEtSlR3dVI4WDVON1pMN05J0gHMAUFVX3lxTE5fQ2Jkc0c4LUF1X2dQc2hxakxvNmtJZHlydTFkbnc2R1JmX2Fuc0pjcDk2VlhIMUFZVV9IdVdIX3gyd044NkRSSTBDZXNBWlR1MEpFU05Ia3d4TmcycUMxY0h6RXR3clJsNDRrNUpYXzVWWUxaUF9reVBVZWdQTFZxR0VZa2k5NDFnNnJUXzg5bkJFMXdqRHk1OEp2aVkwUVlCV2F2YXFiS2hHSTB3bnZyYjNQb3pmQ1RtSl9Pd2hHY2ZJazJNYUU4dDdkVw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxOTENsY0Nlck92UkI3cnBOWXdmQlNoVkpuMEd3NVZQNDQ3RG11YW1Feng5Ymp3RTZxSFExUW1RYWdJbjJpVDZsTW1INFZyVWF5Z1FHaWh6Z0x2T29fdE8xUmxfM2lnZXZ2dXdMME1PbmRIbm9scWstQmZBbVQtRTJ4SFY2eFdMY3dnaUVBYmV1WEVGUGVHaTNhQkxzc0lXbzktREtiTDdLWU5KSXJoekRaZEFlZnVvZjEtSlR3dVI4WDVON1pMN05J0gHMAUFVX3lxTE5fQ2Jkc0c4LUF1X2dQc2hxakxvNmtJZHlydTFkbnc2R1JmX2Fuc0pjcDk2VlhIMUFZVV9IdVdIX3gyd044NkRSSTBDZXNBWlR1MEpFU05Ia3d4TmcycUMxY0h6RXR3clJsNDRrNUpYXzVWWUxaUF9reVBVZWdQTFZxR0VZa2k5NDFnNnJUXzg5bkJFMXdqRHk1OEp2aVkwUVlCV2F2YXFiS2hHSTB3bnZyYjNQb3pmQ1RtSl9Pd2hHY2ZJazJNYUU4dDdkVw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:57:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Time for PM to step aside': Canada's Trudeau faces internal revolt, calls for resignation grow - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Time for PM to step aside: Canada's Trudeau faces internal revolt, calls for resignation grow</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Protests against Trudeau" />
<figcaption>Protests calling for Trudeau's resignation are escalating.</figcaption>
<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau is confronting pressure to resign as dissent within his party grows, fueled by recent policy decisions and declining public support.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Calls for resignation intensify during a period of unpopularity.</li>
  <li>Internal party conflicts are surfacing over recent policy choices.</li>
  <li>Public protests demanding Trudeau’s departure are becoming more frequent.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It’s time for a change in leadership,” said one of the party's dissenting members.</blockquote>
<p>The situation highlights a significant moment for Canadian politics, as internal unity is tested and public sentiment shifts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/time-for-pm-to-step-aside-canadas-trudeau-faces-internal-revolt-calls-for-resignation-grow/articleshow/116584503.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/time-for-pm-to-step-aside-canadas-trudeau-faces-internal-revolt-calls-for-resignation-grow/articleshow/116584503.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market today: BSE Sensex surges over 500 points; Nifty50 above 23,750 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock market today: BSE Sensex surges over 500 points; Nifty50 above 23,750</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Today, Source not specified.</p><p>In an impressive rally, the BSE Sensex has surged over 500 points, with the Nifty50 crossing above 23,750, indicating strong investor sentiment and market recovery.</p><ul><li>The BSE Sensex increased significantly, showing confidence among investors.</li><li>The Nifty50 also saw gains, reflecting broader market trends.</li><li>Sectoral performances varied, with certain industries experiencing robust growth.</li></ul><blockquote>“The rally indicates a strong recovery in market sentiments post recent fluctuations.”</blockquote><p>This surge in the stock market suggests a positive outlook among investors, potentially signaling economic improvement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/stock-market-today-bse-sensex-nifty50-december-23-2024-dalal-street-indian-equities-global-markets/articleshow/116584207.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/stock-market-today-bse-sensex-nifty50-december-23-2024-dalal-street-indian-equities-global-markets/articleshow/116584207.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AP Dhillon fires another shot at Diljit Dosanjh, Badshah urges for ‘unity’: ‘Don’t make the mistakes that…’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AP Dhillon fires another shot at Diljit Dosanjh, Badshah urges for ‘unity’: ‘Don’t make the mistakes that…’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 23-12-2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Badshah-on-Diljit-Dosanjh-AP-Dhillon-Fight.jpg?w=640" alt="Badshah urges singers Diljit Dosanjh AP Dhillon to end their Fight" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Badshah reacts to Diljit Dosanjh AP Dhillon ongoing feud (Photos: Diljit Dosanjh, Badshah, AP Dhillon / Instagram)</figcaption><p>Amid rising tensions between Punjabi singers AP Dhillon and Diljit Dosanjh, rapper Badshah has called for unity, emphasizing the importance of staying together in the industry.</p><ul><li>AP Dhillon recently accused Diljit Dosanjh of blocking him on social media, which Diljit denied.</li><li>During a concert, AP Dhillon urged Diljit to unblock him, prompting a public exchange of comments.</li><li>Badshah expressed his concern via social media, advising them not to repeat past mistakes and to stay united for a successful future.</li><li>Diljit is currently on his 'Dil-luminati' tour, while AP’s 'The Brownprint Tour' recently concluded.</li></ul><blockquote>“Please don’t make the mistakes that we made. The world is ours for the taking. United we stand.” - Badshah</blockquote><p>This feud highlights the interpersonal dynamics among top Punjabi artists and the broader impact on their fan bases as they navigate conflicts in the public eye.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/ap-dhillon-fires-another-shot-at-diljit-dosanjh-badshah-urges-for-unity-dont-make-the-mistakes-that-9739746/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/ap-dhillon-fires-another-shot-at-diljit-dosanjh-badshah-urges-for-unity-dont-make-the-mistakes-that-9739746/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:44:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bharat Global Developers shares, which rose 2,300% in the last 12 months, are now suspended for trading - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bharat Global Developers shares now suspended for trading</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 9:09 AM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Bharat Global Developers shares, which rose 2,300% in the last 12 months, are now suspended for trading"><figcaption>Bharat Global Developers shares, which rose 2,300% in the last 12 months, are now suspended for trading</figcaption><p>Shares of Bharat Global Developers Ltd. have been suspended from trading following a dramatic rise in value over the past year, as ordered by the Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI).</p><ul><li>Shares surged 105x from November 2023 to 2024.</li><li>SEBI's order cites concerns over suspicious financial disclosures made by the company.</li><li>The company previously reported negligible revenue, with a sudden spike in the latest financial quarter.</li><li>Management overhaul in December 2023 led to claims of significant business expansion.</li><li>Noticees restricted from accessing capital markets and required to submit asset inventories.</li></ul><blockquote>SEBI noted potential attempts to mislead investors through false disclosures and fabricated contracts.</blockquote><p>The suspension highlights regulatory action against misleading financial practices in the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/bharat-global-developers-shares-suspended-for-trading-by-sebi-bonus-stock-split-financials-19528215.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/bharat-global-developers-shares-suspended-for-trading-by-sebi-bonus-stock-split-financials-19528215.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:39:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bharat Global Developers, set to issue eight bonus shares for every ten, split stock, suspended from trading - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bharat Global Developers shares now suspended for trading</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 9:09 AM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Bharat Global Developers shares, which rose 2,300% in the last 12 months, are now suspended for trading"><figcaption>Bharat Global Developers shares, which rose 2,300% in the last 12 months, are now suspended for trading</figcaption><p>Shares of Bharat Global Developers Ltd. have been suspended from trading following a dramatic rise in value over the past year, as ordered by the Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI).</p><ul><li>Shares surged 105x from November 2023 to 2024.</li><li>SEBI's order cites concerns over suspicious financial disclosures made by the company.</li><li>The company previously reported negligible revenue, with a sudden spike in the latest financial quarter.</li><li>Management overhaul in December 2023 led to claims of significant business expansion.</li><li>Noticees restricted from accessing capital markets and required to submit asset inventories.</li></ul><blockquote>SEBI noted potential attempts to mislead investors through false disclosures and fabricated contracts.</blockquote><p>The suspension highlights regulatory action against misleading financial practices in the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/bharat-global-developers-shares-suspended-for-trading-by-sebi-bonus-stock-split-financials-19528215.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/bharat-global-developers-shares-suspended-for-trading-by-sebi-bonus-stock-split-financials-19528215.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:39:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Khalistani Terrorists, Who Attacked Punjab Cops, Killed In UP Encounter - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/3-criminals-wanted-for-attack-on-punjab-police-post-injured-in-encounter-7311589</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/3-criminals-wanted-for-attack-on-punjab-police-post-injured-in-encounter-7311589</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:34:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun's Kids Allu Arha, Allu Ayaan Forced To Leave Home After Protestors Vandalise Home | Watch - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun's Kids Allu Arha, Allu Ayaan Forced To Leave Home After Protestors Vandalise Home | Watch</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>December 23, 2024</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Allu Arjun's kids leave their home after the property was vandalised." title="Allu Arjun's kids leave their home after the property was vandalised."><figcaption>Allu Arjun's kids leave their home after the property was vandalised.</figcaption></figure><p>Allu Arjun’s children, Allu Arha and Allu Ayaan, were forced to leave their Hyderabad home after it was vandalised by protesters demanding justice for a woman who died during a stampede.</p><ul><li>Protesters, part of the Osmania University Joint Action Committee, vandalised the property on Sunday.</li><li>A video captured the children leaving in a car as media surrounded them, showing a worried Arha.</li><li>Allu Arjun’s father condemned the attack and stated that the law will take its course.</li><li>Six individuals were arrested connected to the protest.</li><li>The vandalism is linked to recent tensions following a stampede at Sandhya Theatre during a film premiere.</li></ul><blockquote>Allu Aravind stated, “Now is not the right time for us to react to anything.”</blockquote><p>The incident highlights growing tensions surrounding public events and the responsibilities of individuals involved in such gatherings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjuns-kids-allu-arha-allu-ayaan-forced-to-leave-home-after-protestors-vandalise-home-watch-9165170.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjuns-kids-allu-arha-allu-ayaan-forced-to-leave-home-after-protestors-vandalise-home-watch-9165170.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:29:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Sunny Leone' Got Rs 1000/Month Under Chhattisgarh Scheme For Married Women - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPc1FBUDE2SGxFYm10T3MwZHFPWC1abmF4RlVsdUZZM2VsWms0WWdvREtGRlRHd0J4R2NDTkpUcWlfTTlYcmMyNG1CeXZmZTFaSWNENzNzMV9ySTlVd0FyRENMZEZQTU9zdlBUNFdxVVdpdnVYUXVxWFYtNmdVYjdROUllN0hlNjAxYVhuOVZSUUo3SEpfUzZ1MTZ3ZTNkMlRETVRhOW4yNDk5blBiT0Z5NnlSck9zdXpMdmhkVXBFLUhqZlJOSzJtd1RRMFFzT29W?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPc1FBUDE2SGxFYm10T3MwZHFPWC1abmF4RlVsdUZZM2VsWms0WWdvREtGRlRHd0J4R2NDTkpUcWlfTTlYcmMyNG1CeXZmZTFaSWNENzNzMV9ySTlVd0FyRENMZEZQTU9zdlBUNFdxVVdpdnVYUXVxWFYtNmdVYjdROUllN0hlNjAxYVhuOVZSUUo3SEpfUzZ1MTZ3ZTNkMlRETVRhOW4yNDk5blBiT0Z5NnlSck9zdXpMdmhkVXBFLUhqZlJOSzJtd1RRMFFzT29W?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:13:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 pro-Khalistan terrorists killed in police encounter in UP's Pilibhit - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>3 pro-Khalistan terrorists killed in police encounter in UP's Pilibhit</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Not Provided]</p><p>In a significant operation, three pro-Khalistan terrorists were killed during a police encounter in Pilibhit, Uttar Pradesh. This operation highlights ongoing security measures against separatist movements.</p><ul><li>The encounter took place during a police raid aimed at apprehending the suspects.</li><li>Authorities have intensified operations against pro-Khalistan elements in the region.</li><li>This incident raises questions about security and separatism in Uttar Pradesh.</li></ul><blockquote>"Police are committed to eliminating all forms of terrorism in the state."</blockquote><p>This police action underscores the government's determination to counter terrorism and maintain public safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/3-pro-khalistan-terrorists-killed-in-police-encounter-in-ups-pilibhit/articleshow/116583310.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/3-pro-khalistan-terrorists-killed-in-police-encounter-in-ups-pilibhit/articleshow/116583310.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JSW Steel, Tata Steel, Jindal Steel and Power: Steel stocks rally up to 2%; here is why - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Steel Stocks Rally as India Probes Increase in Steel Imports</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><p>Shares of leading steel manufacturers like JSW Steel, Tata Steel, and Jindal Steel saw gains of up to 2% following a government investigation into rising steel imports based on a complaint from the Indian Steel Association.</p><ul><li>JSW Steel shares traded 2% higher at ₹935.45.</li><li>Tata Steel shares increased by 2% reaching ₹143.42.</li><li>SAIL stocks rose 1.5% to ₹117.94.</li><li>The Directorate General of Trade Remedies (DGTR) initiated an investigation into 'Non-Alloy and Alloy Steel Flat Products'.</li><li>The investigation follows claims of significant injury to the domestic steel industry due to increased imports.</li><li>The Indian Steel Association has requested the imposition of a safeguard duty on these imports to protect local manufacturers.</li></ul><blockquote>The applicant has alleged that there is a 'recent, sudden, sharp, and significant' increase in the volume of imports, which has caused 'significant' injury to the domestic industry in India.</blockquote><p>This investigation aims to provide a level playing field for domestic stakeholders amid rising import volumes and potential impacts on the local market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/jsw-steel-tata-steel-jindal-steel-and-power-steel-stocks-likely-to-rise-today-here-is-why/article-136520/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/jsw-steel-tata-steel-jindal-steel-and-power-steel-stocks-likely-to-rise-today-here-is-why/article-136520/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:07:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pune: Three Dead, Six Injured in Wagholi as Drunken Driver’s Dumper Crushes People On Footpath - Punekar News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.punekarnews.in/pune-three-dead-six-injured-in-wagholi-as-drunken-drivers-dumper-crushes-people-on-footpath/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.punekarnews.in/pune-three-dead-six-injured-in-wagholi-as-drunken-drivers-dumper-crushes-people-on-footpath/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:06:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>