<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:20:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:20:02 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India summons top Bangladesh diplomat amid border fencing row - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-summons-top-bangladesh-diplomat-amid-border-fencing-row/articleshow/117199714.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-summons-top-bangladesh-diplomat-amid-border-fencing-row/articleshow/117199714.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 09:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sensex Crashes 1,100 Points, Investors Lose Over 14 Lakh Crore; Why Is Market Falling? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sensex Crashes 1,100 Points, Investors Lose Over 14 Lakh Crore; Why Is Market Falling?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Stock Market Crash"><figcaption>Stock Market Crash</figcaption></figure><p>Indian blue-chip indices, Sensex and Nifty, saw significant declines on Monday. The BSE Sensex dropped over 1,100 points, while the Nifty50 lost 350 points, responding to a stronger-than-expected US jobs report.</p><ul><li>US jobs report suggests delay in Federal Reserve rate cuts.</li><li>BSE Sensex fell to a low of 76,250; Nifty50 slid to 23,047.</li><li>Market capitalization of BSE-listed companies fell by Rs 14.54 lakh crore.</li><li>Foreign portfolio investors continued aggressive selling of Indian stocks.</li><li>Weakening rupee hit an all-time low of Rs 86.27 against the US dollar.</li></ul><blockquote>“Markets are under pressure due to multiple headwinds. The strong US jobs data has reduced expectations of rate cuts by the Fed in 2025.” - VK Vijayakumar, Chief Investment Strategist at Geojit Financial Services.</blockquote><p>The decline in Indian markets reflects a combination of domestic pressures and global economic conditions, presenting a challenging environment for investors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/markets/sensex-crashes-1100-points-investors-lose-over-14-lakh-crore-why-is-market-falling-9187199.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/markets/sensex-crashes-1100-points-investors-lose-over-14-lakh-crore-why-is-market-falling-9187199.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 09:32:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's Champions Trophy Squad: Big Surprises As Sunil Gavaskar, Irfan Pathan Announce Their Team - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Champions Trophy Squad: Big Surprises As Sunil Gavaskar, Irfan Pathan Announce Their Team</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>June 30, 2024</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/lf2dqos_virat-kohli-rohit-sharma-ani_640x480_30_June_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="India's Champions Trophy Squad Announcement" /><figcaption>File photo of Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma</figcaption><p>As Indian cricket fans await the big ICC Champions Trophy announcement from the BCCI, former cricketers like Irfan Pathan and Sunil Gavaskar have shared their preferences, highlighting key players they believe should be included in the squad.</p><ul><li>Gavaskar emphasizes the importance of including KL Rahul, Shreyas Iyer, and Rishabh Pant in the middle order.</li><li>Gavaskar suggests that Sanju Samson's recent performances necessitate his inclusion in the squad.</li><li>Irfan Pathan advocates for a spin-bowling duo of Ravindra Jadeja and Kuldeep Yadav.</li><li>Pathan also mentions the importance of Jasprit Bumrah and Mohammed Shami as key pace bowlers.</li><li>Both Gavaskar and Pathan omit notable players like Suryakumar Yadav and Axar Patel from their selections.</li></ul><blockquote>“If I am sitting there I will say who has done really well in the recent past. KL Rahul had a fantastic 50-over World Cup.” - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote><p>The selections made by Gavaskar and Pathan are generating discussions among fans as the official squad announcement approaches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-big-surprises-as-sunil-gavaskar-irfan-pathan-announce-their-team-7463048</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-big-surprises-as-sunil-gavaskar-irfan-pathan-announce-their-team-7463048</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 09:14:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kate Middleton eats THIS cholesterol-lowering superfood for breakfast - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kate Middleton eats THIS cholesterol-lowering superfood for breakfast</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> SurreyLive</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117196088,imgsize-101364,width-400,resizemode-4/117196088.jpg" alt="Kate Middleton eats THIS cholesterol-lowering superfood for breakfast" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Kate Middleton enjoying her breakfast.</figcaption>
<p>Kate Middleton embraces a nutritious breakfast of oatmeal to support her health amidst a challenging year. This choice aligns with her active lifestyle and nutritional needs as the princess of Wales.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kate opts for oatmeal for breakfast, a nutritious superfood.</li>
  <li>Oatmeal helps maintain energy levels and manage cholesterol.</li>
  <li>Rich in fiber and essential nutrients, oatmeal supports overall health.</li>
  <li>Kate's diet includes fruits, vegetables, and healthy snacks like olives.</li>
  <li>Despite her healthy choices, she enjoys desserts like sticky toffee pudding.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Catherine is said to favour slow-burn energy oats for breakfast.” - Robert Jobson</blockquote>
<p>Overall, Kate Middleton's breakfast choice reflects a commitment to health and well-being, showing that even royals prioritize nutritious eating.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/kate-middleton-eats-this-cholesterol-lowering-superfood-for-breakfast/articleshow/117196088.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/kate-middleton-eats-this-cholesterol-lowering-superfood-for-breakfast/articleshow/117196088.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 captivating images of Nebula captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Captivating Images of Nebula Captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Helix-Nebula.png" alt="Helix Nebula">
<figcaption>Helix Nebula captured by Hubble</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases stunning images of various nebulae captured by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting their beauty and scientific significance.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nebulae as images of the day from NASA.</li>
  <li>Features images like the Hourglass Nebula, Spirograph Nebula, and Crab Nebula, each with unique characteristics.</li>
  <li>Includes a mix of ultraviolet, visible, and infrared views in the images displayed.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A vibrant star-forming region where swirling gas and dust come together to craft a celestial masterpiece.”</blockquote>
<p>These incredible images not only showcase the beauty of the universe but also help scientists understand nebulae better.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-captivating-images-of-nebula-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7534066/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-captivating-images-of-nebula-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7534066/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 08:55:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires live updates: Death toll at 24; firefighters race to contain spread - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires Update: Death Toll Reaches 24 as Firefighters Work Overtime</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/CALIFORNIA-WILDFIRES--15_1736755524083_1736755678280.JPG" alt="A helicopter drops water on the Palisades Fire" title="A helicopter drops water on the Palisades Fire, one of several blazes across Los Angeles." loading="lazy" decoding="async"><figcaption>A helicopter drops water on the Palisades Fire, one of several blazes across Los Angeles.</figcaption></div><p>The unprecedented wildfires in Los Angeles have led to a death toll of 24, with many more residents displaced and mandatory evacuation orders in effect.</p><ul><li>Currently, 24 fatalities confirmed due to the fires.</li><li>Over 12,000 structures have been reported damaged or destroyed.</li><li>More than 100,000 residents ordered to evacuate; additional 87,000 warned of potential evacuations.</li><li>California Governor Gavin Newsom plans a “Marshall Plan” to rebuild affected areas.</li><li>Beyonce's foundation pledges $2.5 million for fire relief efforts.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s heartbreaking to see the place where I met my husband... just wiped out.” - Former Resident</blockquote><p>The wildfires continue to pose a threat as dangerous wind conditions are expected to return. Efforts to control the fires are ongoing, with further assessments planned to evaluate the extent of the damage.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 08:47:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hubble reveals ‘Bat Shadow’ around nebula - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hubble reveals ‘Bat Shadow’ around nebula</h1>
<p><strong>Published Date:</strong> 13 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Telangana Today</p>
<img width="1200" height="720" src="https://media.telanganatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/hubble.jpg" alt="Hubble reveals ‘Bat Shadow’ around nebula">
<figcaption>Hubble space telescope</figcaption>
<p>Astronomers have uncovered a fascinating shadow in space, captured by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope, reflecting the birth of planetary systems.</p>
<ul>
<li>The shadow, dubbed the ‘Bat Shadow’, is cast by a young star named HBC 672 located in the Serpens Nebula, about 1,300 light-years away.</li>
<li>This shadow spans approximately 200 times the length of our solar system.</li>
<li>Astronomers believe that our solar system may have once produced a similar shadow during its formation.</li>
<li>The shadow indicates an edge-on view of the disk, revealing its shape and gas content.</li>
<li>It provides valuable insights into the size and composition of dust grains in the protoplanetary disk.</li>
<li>Infrared observations allow scientists to see these shadows, which are otherwise invisible in visible light.</li>
<li>The discovery showcases the collaborative efforts of NASA and ESA in space exploration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The presence of a shadow means that the disk is being viewed nearly edge-on.”</blockquote>
<p>This remarkable discovery not only enhances our understanding of star formation but also reinforces the collaborative spirit of international space research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://telanganatoday.com/hubble-reveals-bat-shadow-around-nebula</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://telanganatoday.com/hubble-reveals-bat-shadow-around-nebula</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 08:42:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shreyas Iyer Set To Create History, Will Become 1st Indian Cricketer To Captain 3 IPL Teams - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shreyas Iyer to Make History as First Indian to Captain Three IPL Teams</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Shreyas Iyer will become first Indian player to captain three IPL teams. (Picture Credit: X/@PunjabKingsIPL and X/@ShreyasIyer15)"><figcaption>Shreyas Iyer will become first Indian player to captain three IPL teams. (Picture Credit: X/@PunjabKingsIPL and X/@ShreyasIyer15)</figcaption><p>Star Indian cricketer Shreyas Iyer has been appointed captain of Punjab Kings for the 2025 IPL season, making him the first Indian to lead three different IPL teams.</p><ul><li>Iyer will captain Punjab Kings starting from the IPL 2025 season, beginning March 21.</li><li>This marks Iyer's third team, following his previous roles with Delhi Capitals and Kolkata Knight Riders.</li><li>He has already won the IPL title with KKR in 2024 and led Delhi Capitals to the finals in 2020.</li><li>Iyer is now the 17th player to captain Punjab Kings in the IPL history.</li><li>He won 38 out of 70 matches as captain, ranking him as the sixth most successful captain in IPL history.</li></ul><blockquote>“Iyer created history as he became the first Indian player to captain three IPL teams.”</blockquote><p>This milestone highlights Iyer's significant impact on the league and showcases his leadership skills in one of cricket's most lucrative tournaments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/shreyas-iyer-set-to-create-history-will-become-1st-indian-cricketer-to-9186786.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/shreyas-iyer-set-to-create-history-will-become-1st-indian-cricketer-to-9186786.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 08:20:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another child tests positive for HMPV in Puducherry, undergoing treatment in JIPMER - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Another child tests positive for HMPV in Puducherry, undergoing treatment in JIPMER</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/HMPV.png?w=640" alt="Puducherry, HMPV cases, HMPV, Puducherry cases, HMPV Virus, Human Metapneumovirus, India cases, India HMPV" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>According to the Director of Health of Puducherry, the child was recovering well and all precautionary measures had been taken. (File Photo)</figcaption><p>One more child in Puducherry tested positive for Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) and is undergoing treatment in the centrally administered JIPMER here, a top official said.</p><ul><li>The girl child exhibited symptoms of fever, cough, and running nose.</li><li>She was admitted to JIPMER a few days ago and has been under treatment.</li><li>The child is recovering well, with all precautionary measures in place.</li><li>Puducherry reported its first HMPV case last week involving a three-year-old child, who has since recovered.</li><li>The Puducherry administration is taking steps in response to the virus.</li></ul><blockquote>“The child was recovering well and all precautionary measures had been taken.”</blockquote><p>The situation regarding HMPV in Puducherry is being actively monitored, with health officials ensuring proper care and preventive measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/hmpv-india-cases-puducherry-treatment-symptoms-9776030/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/hmpv-india-cases-puducherry-treatment-symptoms-9776030/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 08:00:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Violence level being orchestrated by epicentre of terror that is Pakistan': Army chief on J&K situation - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/60-of-terrorists-eliminated-last-year-80-of-those-remaining-in-jk-are-of-pakistani-origin-army-chief-upendra-dwivedi/articleshow/117195640.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/60-of-terrorists-eliminated-last-year-80-of-those-remaining-in-jk-are-of-pakistani-origin-army-chief-upendra-dwivedi/articleshow/117195640.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025 live: Nearly 60 lakh take holy dip on day 1; ‘Amrit Snan’ scheduled for tomorrow - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh 2025 Live: Nearly 60 Lakh Take Holy Dip on Day 1; ‘Amrit Snan’ Scheduled for Tomorrow</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/WhatsApp_Image_2025-01-13_at_10.55.14_1736747084339_1736747092564.jpeg" alt="Devotees took a holy dip in the Sangam during the Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, on Monday." title="Devotees took a holy dip in the Sangam during the Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, on Monday."><figcaption>Devotees took a holy dip in the Sangam during the Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, on Monday.</figcaption></div><p>The Mahakumbh 2025, a 45-day event, witnessed nearly 60 lakh devotees taking a holy dip at Sangam on its opening day. The event, projected to attract over 40 crore attendees, will culminate on February 26, 2025.</p><ul><li>60 lakh devotees attended the first day.</li><li>Amrit Snan scheduled for January 14 (Makar Sankranti).</li><li>Enhanced security with 40,000 personnel deployed.</li><li>Traffic arrangements in place to manage the large influx of attendees.</li><li>QR codes set up for easy navigation within the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“Maha Kumbh is a symbol of India's spiritual, cultural heritage,” said UP CM Yogi Adityanath.</blockquote><p>The Mahakumbh Mela serves as a remarkable display of cultural and spiritual unity, drawing massive crowds and extensive arrangements to ensure safety and comfort for participants.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-sangam-shahi-snan-paush-purnima-holy-dip-jan-13-2025-101736725472437.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-sangam-shahi-snan-paush-purnima-holy-dip-jan-13-2025-101736725472437.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:47:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trudeau's former ally Jagmeet Singh warns Trump: 'If you pick a fight with Canada...' - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxOSnZwSFZPRUNoaFlzQkJ5Yl9SLWlXYlFzSXJQeVhLV0hkVU5xXzQ4a0VVN1hNMHotTFZBT1Zobmc0cWc4bU1RTksxM0VTc2hlekpwU2RmS0dLYkNhQlVxZWhKMTMya01Sa09obGtuUnd6SzBZMHl5eHU3RTVqT2xTc2s5WGItT19fSThDeG91WXV0WTJqNTVWcC0zVGhnTHBBZ0o1em5zZEl3UVlrVEF0SmthanpmSnZFLWx6UzdhbTN3UXRsT0tpNjViTUpkd9IB0wFBVV95cUxQRC1TT1NTRXVxT2IwNmc5M2JIT1B2UDFzUnNWd0pySmowS243SWFBU0NKVVYzNWlFelFBQkxoekFDVVYwTldhN3p4UFc1M1M5cktqbDFqalJfajE3anZyV2xuWHVKYW5QZWxSOTFVOVlUTWViSTJqMWdHTUgzMTZNTF9fRTBMVHJOZUNFOXFuQ0R2eHJMVktBTUlvME1USFJmWDlnbk1leUJ4SFJYUjl2ZzNWdVNmRWF3clRJTGFzV0N1Q3RldDhCZm9oSTBrVWJZU0o0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxOSnZwSFZPRUNoaFlzQkJ5Yl9SLWlXYlFzSXJQeVhLV0hkVU5xXzQ4a0VVN1hNMHotTFZBT1Zobmc0cWc4bU1RTksxM0VTc2hlekpwU2RmS0dLYkNhQlVxZWhKMTMya01Sa09obGtuUnd6SzBZMHl5eHU3RTVqT2xTc2s5WGItT19fSThDeG91WXV0WTJqNTVWcC0zVGhnTHBBZ0o1em5zZEl3UVlrVEF0SmthanpmSnZFLWx6UzdhbTN3UXRsT0tpNjViTUpkd9IB0wFBVV95cUxQRC1TT1NTRXVxT2IwNmc5M2JIT1B2UDFzUnNWd0pySmowS243SWFBU0NKVVYzNWlFelFBQkxoekFDVVYwTldhN3p4UFc1M1M5cktqbDFqalJfajE3anZyV2xuWHVKYW5QZWxSOTFVOVlUTWViSTJqMWdHTUgzMTZNTF9fRTBMVHJOZUNFOXFuQ0R2eHJMVktBTUlvME1USFJmWDlnbk1leUJ4SFJYUjl2ZzNWdVNmRWF3clRJTGFzV0N1Q3RldDhCZm9oSTBrVWJZU0o0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:43:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balanced vegetarian diets for aspiring athletes: What you need to know - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Balanced Vegetarian Diets for Aspiring Athletes: What You Need to Know</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://indianexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/1_04cac4.jpg" alt="Balanced vegetarian diets for aspiring athletes: What you need to know" width="720" height="1280">
<figcaption>Balanced vegetarian diets for aspiring athletes: What you need to know</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses how vegetarian diets can effectively meet the nutritional needs of aspiring athletes, emphasizing critical nutrients for performance and recovery.</p>
<ul>
<li>Vegetarian athletes often struggle to meet protein, iron, calcium, vitamin B12, and omega-3 fatty acid needs.</li>
<li>Plant proteins from whole grains, quinoa, lentils, and beans can help fulfill protein requirements.</li>
<li>Combining vitamin C-rich foods with iron-rich meals can enhance iron absorption.</li>
<li>Vitamin B12 can be obtained from supplements or fortified foods like plant-based milks.</li>
<li>Sources of calcium and omega-3s include tofu, almonds, leafy greens, and flaxseeds.</li>
<li>A balanced vegetarian diet should focus on whole foods, seasonal fruits, healthy fats, and electrolyte-rich drinks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A balanced, whole-food-based vegetarian diet is crucial for aspiring athletes.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, athletes considering a vegetarian diet must be mindful of their nutritional intake to ensure optimal performance and recovery.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/web-stories/life-style/balanced-vegetarian-diets-for-aspiring-athletes-what-you-need-to-know/9774461/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/web-stories/life-style/balanced-vegetarian-diets-for-aspiring-athletes-what-you-need-to-know/9774461/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:30:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spacewalk Preps, Biology Research Wrap Up Week Aboard Station - Space Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQRFpnVFpWTU1jdkpFR2I2ZTF6ZWM0b0ZoVEdZbWpMSm53QldXVXJpM0gzVXdISC1KS0phYlA4NldDZkJONFNDdnktYkY3c2VTWUpnSXgwVG9RalBVVF91eGl4aUdrMEVScHVwYmlfUFFqa1ZBVEkwTVlYdmE1TGRnLU9nRVQ1WDZhZE81LVMwRGJiUmYyYlY5WkJ6U1VkYjREOGhHeF9VUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQRFpnVFpWTU1jdkpFR2I2ZTF6ZWM0b0ZoVEdZbWpMSm53QldXVXJpM0gzVXdISC1KS0phYlA4NldDZkJONFNDdnktYkY3c2VTWUpnSXgwVG9RalBVVF91eGl4aUdrMEVScHVwYmlfUFFqa1ZBVEkwTVlYdmE1TGRnLU9nRVQ1WDZhZE81LVMwRGJiUmYyYlY5WkJ6U1VkYjREOGhHeF9VUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Raises doubts about your bona fides’: Delhi High Court raps AAP government over CAG report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi High Court Criticizes AAP Government for Delaying CAG Report Discussion</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/PTI11-26-2024-000245B-0_1732622965039_1736752611352.jpg" alt="Delhi High Court reprimands AAP government for mishandling CAG report. (PTI FILE PHOTO)" title="Delhi High Court reprimands AAP government for mishandling CAG report. (PTI FILE PHOTO)">
<figcaption>Delhi High Court reprimands AAP government for mishandling CAG report. (PTI FILE PHOTO)</figcaption>
<p>The Delhi High Court has reprimanded the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) government for mishandling a report from the Comptroller and Auditor General (CAG), accusing it of delaying necessary discussions.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The court stated that the AAP government “dragged its feet” to prevent an assembly session from taking place.</li>
    <li>Justice Sachin Datta highlighted that reports should have been promptly forwarded to the Speaker for discussion.</li>
    <li>The Delhi government argued that upcoming elections hindered the holding of assembly sessions.</li>
    <li>Seven BJP MLAs petitioned to table 14 CAG reports in the assembly, claiming their right to engage with the documents.</li>
    <li>The court declined to immediately order a special assembly session, emphasizing the need for both parties to be heard first.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The way you have dragged your feet raises doubts about your bona fides.” – Justice Sachin Datta</blockquote>
<p>This judicial rebuke highlights concerns about government accountability and the implications for democratic processes leading up to elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/raises-doubts-about-your-bona-fides-delhi-high-court-raps-aap-government-over-cag-report-101736750967716.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/raises-doubts-about-your-bona-fides-delhi-high-court-raps-aap-government-over-cag-report-101736750967716.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:26:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[£190m case verdict against Imran Khan, Bushra Bibi postponed for third time - The Express Tribune]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Verdict on £190 Million Case Against Imran Khan and Bushra Bibi Postponed Again</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2024 - <strong>Source:</strong> Express News</p><img src="https://i.tribune.com.pk/media/thumbs/logo-tribune1588976358-0-450x300.webp" alt="tribune" title="tribune"><p>An accountability court in Rawalpindi has postponed the announcement of the verdict in the £190 million case involving former Prime Minister Imran Khan and his wife, Bushra Bibi, for the third time. The new date has been set for January 17, 2024.</p><ul><li>The court had previously postponed the verdict twice.</li><li>Imran Khan and Bushra Bibi failed to appear for the hearing.</li><li>The case involves allegations regarding the handling of funds transferred by the UK's National Crime Agency to the Pakistani government.</li></ul><blockquote>“Both Khan and Bushra Bibi failed to show up.”</blockquote><p>The trial, which has spanned over a year, has seen multiple judges presiding over the hearings and has included testimonies from 35 witnesses.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tribune.com.pk/story/2521776/190m-case-verdict-against-imran-khan-bushra-bibi-postponed-for-3rd-time</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tribune.com.pk/story/2521776/190m-case-verdict-against-imran-khan-bushra-bibi-postponed-for-3rd-time</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:24:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why was Steve Jobs's wife not allowed to touch Shivling in Kashi? Seer answers - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why was Steve Jobs's wife not allowed to touch Shivling in Kashi? Seer answers</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/ANI-20250112320-0_1736749881070_1736749891544.jpg" alt="Laurene Powell Jobs, wife of the late Apple co-founder Steve Jobs reaches Niranjani Akhara at Mahakumbh, in Prayagraj on Sunday. (ANI)" title="Laurene Powell Jobs, wife of the late Apple co-founder Steve Jobs reaches Niranjani Akhara at Mahakumbh, in Prayagraj on Sunday. (ANI)"><figcaption>Laurene Powell Jobs, wife of the late Apple co-founder Steve Jobs reaches Niranjani Akhara at Mahakumbh, in Prayagraj on Sunday. (ANI)</figcaption><p>Laurene Powell Jobs, wife of the late Apple co-founder Steve Jobs, visited the Kashi Vishwanath Temple but was not permitted to touch the Shivling due to temple traditions. Spiritual leader Swami Kailashanand Giri explained the strict protocols regarding non-Hindus touching the Shivling, highlighting her respect for Indian spirituality.</p><ul><li>Laurene Powell Jobs visited the Kashi Vishwanath Temple in Varanasi.</li><li>She was not allowed to touch the Shivling as per temple protocols.</li><li>Swami Kailashanand Giri emphasized that he must uphold traditions.</li><li>Laurene participated in rituals, received prasad and a garland.</li><li>The Mahakumbh festival is expected to attract over 40 crore devotees.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is a tradition that anyone other than a Hindu cannot touch Kashi Vishwanath.” - Swami Kailashanand Giri Maharaj</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Laurene Powell Jobs's visit to the Kashi Vishwanath Temple reflects her reverence for Indian culture while adhering to local traditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/why-was-steve-jobs-wife-not-allowed-to-touch-shivling-in-kashi-laurene-powell-jobs-101736748328520.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/why-was-steve-jobs-wife-not-allowed-to-touch-shivling-in-kashi-laurene-powell-jobs-101736748328520.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:23:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi inaugurates Z-Morh tunnel in J&K’s Sonamarg - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Inaugurates Z-Morh Tunnel in J&K’s Sonamarg</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/d2xah4/article69094931.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI01_13_2025_000133A.jpg" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the inauguration of the Z-Morh tunnel, in Jammu and Kashmir. on January 13, 2025." /><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the inauguration of the Z-Morh tunnel, in Jammu and Kashmir. on January 13, 2025.</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi inaugurated the Z-Morh tunnel in Kashmir’s Ganderbal district, enhancing all-weather connectivity to the tourist destination of Sonmarg.</p><ul><li>The inauguration took place from the East Portal amidst recent snowfall.</li><li>Mr. Modi was accompanied by several high-ranking officials, including Union Ministers and the Chief Minister.</li><li>The tunnel, costing over ₹2,700 crore, provides a two-lane bi-directional road.</li><li>It features a parallel 7.5-metre-wide escape passage for emergencies.</li><li>Located at an altitude of 8,650 feet, it aims to bypass landslides and avalanches.</li></ul><blockquote>Mr. Modi is scheduled to meet the construction workers who contributed to this engineering feat.</blockquote><p>This strategic tunnel significantly improves access between Srinagar and Sonamarg, highlighting the government's commitment to infrastructure development in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/prime-minister-narendra-modi-inaugurates-z-morh-tunnel-in-sonamarg-on-janury-13-2025/article69094897.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/prime-minister-narendra-modi-inaugurates-z-morh-tunnel-in-sonamarg-on-janury-13-2025/article69094897.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JVC marks India comeback with Google TV-based QLED TV range: Details here - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JVC marks India comeback with Google TV-based QLED TV range: Details here</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Press Release</p><p>JVC (Japan Victor Company) has re-entered the Indian market with a new range of smart QLED televisions manufactured locally. The series includes seven different sizes starting from Rs 11,999, available on Amazon India during its Republic Day Sale.</p><img src='jvc-qled-tv.jpg' alt='JVC QLED TV'><figcaption>JVC's new range of QLED TVs.</figcaption><p>The JVC TVs, known as the AI Vision series, feature Google TV, up to 4K UHD resolution, 60Hz refresh rate, and support for HDR10. They come with various connectivity options and advanced audio technologies.</p><ul><li>Available sizes: 32-inch to 75-inch</li><li>Starting price: Rs 11,999</li><li>Powered by Google TV</li><li>Up to 4K UHD resolution</li><li>Supports popular streaming services</li></ul><blockquote>“We are thrilled to introduce JVC’s cutting-edge television range to Indian consumers. India is one of the fastest-growing markets in the world...” – Pallavi Singh, JVC TV India.</blockquote><p>JVC aims to achieve Rs 500 crore in revenue over the next three years by expanding its product range and enhancing customer engagement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/gadgets/jvc-marks-india-comeback-with-google-tv-based-qled-tv-range-details-here-125011300371_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/gadgets/jvc-marks-india-comeback-with-google-tv-based-qled-tv-range-details-here-125011300371_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:16:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xiaomi Pad 7’s purple patch emerges from an unconventional generational transition - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Xiaomi Pad 7’s purple patch emerges from an unconventional generational transition</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/The-Xiaomi-Pad-7-tablet---Vishal-Mathur--HT-Photo-_1736751775977.jpg" alt="The Xiaomi Pad 7 tablet. (Vishal Mathur/ HT Photo)" title="The Xiaomi Pad 7 tablet. (Vishal Mathur/ HT Photo)">
<figcaption>The Xiaomi Pad 7 tablet. (Vishal Mathur/ HT Photo)</figcaption>
<p>The Xiaomi Pad 7 attempts to follow the success of its predecessor, the Pad 6, amidst high expectations. It introduces competitive pricing and a new specification while retaining features that appeal to users.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Pad 7 is priced at ₹26,999 for the 8GB+128GB variant.</li>
  <li>Offers a nano-texture display option for ₹31,999, enhancing visual experience.</li>
  <li>Competes with OnePlus Pad 2 and Honor Pad 9 in the Android tablet market.</li>
  <li>Increased display size to 11.2 inches with improved brightness.</li>
  <li>Switches to Snapdragon 7+ Gen3 chip while ensuring smooth performance.</li>
  <li>Battery life reaches up to days on a single charge.</li>
  <li>Proposed accessories include Focus Keyboard and Focus Pen, though keyboard performance may be lacking.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Xiaomi Pad 7 as a tablet … is absolutely worth your time and money.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while the Xiaomi Pad 7 shines as a tablet, its associated keyboard experience needs refinement. Overall, it represents a notable contribution to the Android tablet market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/xiaomi-pad-7-s-purple-patch-emerges-from-an-unconventional-generational-transition-101736751783233.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/xiaomi-pad-7-s-purple-patch-emerges-from-an-unconventional-generational-transition-101736751783233.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:03:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Situation sensitive but stable’: Army Chief on LAC disengagement, J-K infiltration bids - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Situation sensitive but stable’: Army chief on India-China disengagement along LAC</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/10/PTI10_22_2024_000099B.jpg?w=640" alt="india-china LAC agreement" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Chief of the Army Staff General Upendra Dwivedi during a press conference, in New Delhi. (PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>Army Chief General Upendra Dwivedi addressed the disengagement efforts along the India-China border, stating that the situation across the LAC remains "sensitive but stable." He highlighted that traditional patrolling and grazing in areas like Depsang and Demchok have resumed.</p><ul><li>The army’s deployment along the LAC is described as balanced and robust, capable of handling any situation.</li><li>Focus on enhancing border infrastructure and capability development is underway.</li><li>General Dwivedi noted ongoing cross-border terrorism support from Pakistan in Jammu and Kashmir.</li><li>The situation in Manipur is reportedly under control due to proactive measures by security forces.</li></ul><blockquote>“In the last year, 60 percent of the terrorists eliminated in Jammu and Kashmir were from Pakistan,” said General Dwivedi.</blockquote><p>The Indian Army continues to monitor and address threats while striving for stability and peace in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/army-chief-lac-jammu-kashmir-situation-stable-9776048/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/army-chief-lac-jammu-kashmir-situation-stable-9776048/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:49:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SENSEX, NIFTY50 continue to bleed, down 12% from record highs; top factors behind the market's free fall - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxQRllhSmZsbFdGQUJpRTZVM2RmZkRPbkZUY0xWdVlUa0Q3Uzg3aC01bTYtN3BwSjhyZGxVVkhoRFQtRHUtaXZxR0g1Sno5UnoxRWZKSzNzVVdwU0xzbUtmSVJlaGF6MUVEa3Nxb2dYd2lGd3FFelMxcTEyNTdEMGJZMlpwMGxDRWhlTGJmbmdXcEtwTV8zdHdwaV82anNod2F5NUR0MDg0NFktQVhycFQ0eHV3a2NMazFYUVZ3V0YxZ1pOU1Z1Q2hhMmVIbjVkMlZnZS1OVEZSeDRINENkcXphNm1uX0FpLVphR25JY3BTeHVPRkU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxQRllhSmZsbFdGQUJpRTZVM2RmZkRPbkZUY0xWdVlUa0Q3Uzg3aC01bTYtN3BwSjhyZGxVVkhoRFQtRHUtaXZxR0g1Sno5UnoxRWZKSzNzVVdwU0xzbUtmSVJlaGF6MUVEa3Nxb2dYd2lGd3FFelMxcTEyNTdEMGJZMlpwMGxDRWhlTGJmbmdXcEtwTV8zdHdwaV82anNod2F5NUR0MDg0NFktQVhycFQ0eHV3a2NMazFYUVZ3V0YxZ1pOU1Z1Q2hhMmVIbjVkMlZnZS1OVEZSeDRINENkcXphNm1uX0FpLVphR25JY3BTeHVPRkU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:46:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daaku Maharaaj Box Office Collections: Second biggest opening for a NBK film - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daaku Maharaaj Box Office Collections: Second biggest opening for a NBK film</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p><div><img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/1531299210_daku1.jpg" alt="Daaku Maharaaj," title="NBK in Daaku Maharaaj (image courtesy of Sithara Ent)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>NBK in Daaku Maharaaj (image courtesy of Sithara Ent)</figcaption></div><p>Daaku Maharaaj recorded the second-biggest opening for an NBK starrer at the Indian box office, amassing Rs. 26 crore approx. The film had an unconventional Sunday release but it is common for Telugu films to release on off days during the Sankranti period.</p><ul><li>The biggest opening for NBK in Telugu states is Rs. 30.25 crore from Veera Simha Reddy.</li><li>Almost all of the business for Daaku Maharaaj came from the Telugu states at Rs. 23 crore approx.</li><li>The film is expected to perform significantly well during the Sankranti period.</li><li>Overseas, it opened nearly USD 1 million on its first day in the United States.</li></ul><blockquote>“The initial reception seems to be decent enough.”</blockquote><p>Daaku Maharaaj's success at the box office indicates a strong interest in Telugu cinema, particularly during advantageous release periods.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/daaku-maharaaj-box-office-collections-second-biggest-opening-for-a-nbk-film-1367091</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/daaku-maharaaj-box-office-collections-second-biggest-opening-for-a-nbk-film-1367091</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:42:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Apocalyptic Theories About the End of the Universe - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Apocalyptic Theories About the End of the Universe</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/webstories/uploads/2025/01/cropped-12-2025-01-3289075d5a344b48511df3e7d0342da0.jpg" alt="Apocalyptic Theories" />
<figcaption>Discover fascinating theories about how the universe might end.</figcaption>
<p>This article explores ten fascinating apocalyptic theories regarding the possible end of the universe, including the Big Crunch and vacuum decay, while delving into the scientific explanations behind these cosmic scenarios.</p>
<ul>
  <li>1. <strong>Big Crunch:</strong> The universe stops expanding and collapses in reverse into a singularity.</li>
  <li>2. <strong>Big Freeze:</strong> Expansion continues forever, leaving a dark, cold universe as all stars burn out.</li>
  <li>3. <strong>Big Rip:</strong> Dark energy accelerates expansion, tearing apart atoms and galaxies.</li>
  <li>4. <strong>Heat Death:</strong> The universe reaches maximum entropy, becoming an inert, lifeless cosmos.</li>
  <li>5. <strong>Vacuum Decay:</strong> A quantum event triggers a destructive bubble at lightspeed.</li>
  <li>6. <strong>Multiverse Collision:</strong> Our universe collides with another, leading to cosmic obliteration.</li>
  <li>7. <strong>Black Hole Era:</strong> Only black holes remain, consuming everything until they evaporate.</li>
  <li>8. <strong>False Vacuum Theory:</strong> The universe suddenly transitions to a catastrophic form.</li>
  <li>9. <strong>Entropy Reversal:</strong> If time reverses, unpredictable outcomes could end life.</li>
  <li>10. <strong>End of Dark Energy:</strong> A reversal of dark energy may lead to cosmic collapse.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Explore the science behind these cosmic doomsday scenarios!”</blockquote>
<p>This article presents insightful theories on the potential fates awaiting the universe, sparking curiosity about cosmic phenomena.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/10-apocalyptic-theories-about-the-end-of-the-universe-visual-story-2752067.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/10-apocalyptic-theories-about-the-end-of-the-universe-visual-story-2752067.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:41:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee breaches 86 against US dollar on strengthening dollar, weak FII inflows - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why the Rupee Breached 86 Against the US Dollar</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>The rupee fell past 86 against the US dollar due to a strengthening dollar, higher crude oil prices, and weak foreign institutional investor inflows.</p><ul><li>The rupee opened at a record low of 86.12 and hit 86.31 during trading.</li><li>Factors contributing to the fall include a strong dollar and outflows from foreign investors.</li><li>US job reports indicated better-than-expected data with a notable Non-Farm Payroll increase.</li><li>Approximately $4.2 billion exited Indian markets in January 2025 due to rising US yields.</li><li>Brent crude prices surged, impacting India's fiscal situation as a net oil importer.</li><li>Future rupee trading is expected to be volatile between 85.80–86.50.</li></ul><blockquote>“This sustained decline reflects a combination of global and domestic pressures.” - Amit Pabari, Managing Director, CR Forex Advisors</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the combination of external pressures from the US economy and rising crude oil prices is significantly impacting the rupee's stability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/rupee-us-dollar-weak-fii-inflows-9775948/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/rupee-us-dollar-weak-fii-inflows-9775948/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man arrested for severing udders of 3 cows in Bengaluru - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/man-arrested-for-severing-udders-of-three-cows-in-bengaluru-9775799/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/man-arrested-for-severing-udders-of-three-cows-in-bengaluru-9775799/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man arrested for severing udders of 3 cows in Bengaluru - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/man-arrested-for-severing-udders-of-three-cows-in-bengaluru-9775799/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/man-arrested-for-severing-udders-of-three-cows-in-bengaluru-9775799/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Z-Morh tunnel: Thousands brave winter chill to attend inauguration by PM Modi in Sonamarg - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxQbU5tb3FQQl9hNHFiVmVhaFdkNmlTOWNETHpWczJSdjEwd3E1WjVhTWVITk11Sjd6UHM4Y21CN1YtQUZ3bm5uUGJjWUw2ZXk3YWg2ZDE5NjNPSUFWMUo5S0pITC1sN0haOEw1UEFfVnFLV3lwa3BycFJRVUZ4OEhNWGRYVUZtZTdXMVllakk5a2hoZXhOTWdoWjFGdXMxVEMtNmMzLUxfZVdjbS16MjZ6NTJpaUtPcXNJZkgwb0t5c0Y1c2E3YlE1SDZiMWLSAdIBQVVfeXFMTXpTWWcwMkFHZTE2Ymc5UFlyUzlZbEdoNmlubnlMYW8yVmtQQUdNN3FmWWgxX2ZBRjRsd2ZrYUpDMnloRW1hSlJjU1lMTGtIbTZOSkJnV09Nc3lJQUFLSEdZUlA4TkpfZXZmN0JyY0FrZHhNcExRRjNfYzNQUHMtUmlzbWJYdlBBeF8zelNVMmhyN3RLdklYaWNoTGd4eHpQSHZET2V0enFSUWZxaHl1bTRYLXRURWp5UkRYZGtNNV9oMVVKdEk2TFoycUVjLW4zWVVB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxQbU5tb3FQQl9hNHFiVmVhaFdkNmlTOWNETHpWczJSdjEwd3E1WjVhTWVITk11Sjd6UHM4Y21CN1YtQUZ3bm5uUGJjWUw2ZXk3YWg2ZDE5NjNPSUFWMUo5S0pITC1sN0haOEw1UEFfVnFLV3lwa3BycFJRVUZ4OEhNWGRYVUZtZTdXMVllakk5a2hoZXhOTWdoWjFGdXMxVEMtNmMzLUxfZVdjbS16MjZ6NTJpaUtPcXNJZkgwb0t5c0Y1c2E3YlE1SDZiMWLSAdIBQVVfeXFMTXpTWWcwMkFHZTE2Ymc5UFlyUzlZbEdoNmlubnlMYW8yVmtQQUdNN3FmWWgxX2ZBRjRsd2ZrYUpDMnloRW1hSlJjU1lMTGtIbTZOSkJnV09Nc3lJQUFLSEdZUlA4TkpfZXZmN0JyY0FrZHhNcExRRjNfYzNQUHMtUmlzbWJYdlBBeF8zelNVMmhyN3RLdklYaWNoTGd4eHpQSHZET2V0enFSUWZxaHl1bTRYLXRURWp5UkRYZGtNNV9oMVVKdEk2TFoycUVjLW4zWVVB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:10:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Stunning Images Of Nebulas Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Stunning Images of Nebulas Captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/117192558/117192558.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=725443" alt="Stunning Nebulas Captured by NASA" />
<figcaption>Credit: ESA/Hubble-NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases seven breathtaking images taken by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting various nebulae across the universe.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Includes captivating images and descriptions of different nebulae.</li>
  <li>Features the Hubble's observations of star formation in various cosmic regions.</li>
  <li>Describes the astronomical significance and beauty of these celestial phenomena.</li>
  <li>Provides insights into the locations and characteristics of each nebula.</li>
  <li>Spotlights the technological advancements of the Hubble Space Telescope.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Astronomers captured stunning images to mark the ongoing contributions of the Hubble Space Telescope.”</blockquote>
<p>The article emphasizes the importance of these celestial imagery in expanding our understanding of the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-stunning-images-of-nebulas-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/117192528.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-stunning-images-of-nebulas-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/117192528.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:03:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I tried OnePlus' new wireless charger on the OnePlus 13 and iPhone 16 Pro Max — here's the results - Tom's Guide]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus AIRVOOC 50W Magnetic Charger Review</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Tom's Guide</p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JHp9dXrXvwtj4KmJ3naeiB-1200-80.jpg" alt="OnePlus AIRVOOC 50W Magnetic Charger on a OnePlus 13 with a Sandstone Case"><figcaption>(Image credit: Tom's Guide)</figcaption><p>In this review, we explore the new OnePlus AIRVOOC 50W Magnetic Charger, testing its performance on the OnePlus 13 and iPhone 16 Pro Max.</p><ul><li>The AIRVOOC charger replaces the older charging stand and features a magnetic attachment suitable for various devices including iPhones.</li><li>The charger initially pulls 70W before stabilizing at around 36W, completing a full charge in approximately 70 minutes.</li><li>Charging performance is slower on the iPhone 16 Pro Max, achieving 50% charge in two hours.</li><li>The charger has a cooling fan that maintains a low temperature during use, which can benefit performance during intensive tasks.</li></ul><blockquote>“OnePlus' new charger is an expensive accessory for the OnePlus 13, but it does deliver the speeds it promises when used properly.”</blockquote><p>While the AIRVOOC Magnetic Charger is an effective pairing for the OnePlus 13, it requires additional purchases for the full experience, which could deter potential users.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tomsguide.com/phones/oneplus-phones/i-tried-oneplus-new-wireless-charger-on-the-oneplus-13-and-iphone-16-pro-max-heres-the-results</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tomsguide.com/phones/oneplus-phones/i-tried-oneplus-new-wireless-charger-on-the-oneplus-13-and-iphone-16-pro-max-heres-the-results</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>