<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 01:19:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 01:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia LIVE, 5th Test, Day 1: KL Rahul Disappoints As Mitchell Starc Draws 1st Blood - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia LIVE Score, 5th Test, Day 1: Kohli-Gill Fight Back After India Suffered Twin Blows Early</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>In the first day of the 5th Test match between India and Australia, India faced early setbacks but Kohli and Gill initiated a fight back.</p><ul><li>India suffered two early wickets.</li><li>Kohli and Gill showed resilience to stabilize the innings.</li><li>Live scores and updates are available online.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s crucial for us to build a good partnership after early wickets,” said a spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This match highlights the challenges and competitive spirit in international cricket as two top teams face off.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-5th-test-match-day-1-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-rohit-sharma-jasprit-bumrah-7385452</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-5th-test-match-day-1-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-rohit-sharma-jasprit-bumrah-7385452</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 23:57:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Over the counter, under the radar: can paracetamol become fatal? - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Over the Counter, Under the Radar: The Hidden Dangers of Paracetamol Poisoning</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 03, 2025 05:00 am IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><p>The recent death of a woman from paracetamol poisoning in Liverpool has highlighted a serious issue that claims thousands of lives annually, often unnoticed due to the drug's reputation as safe.</p><ul><li>Paracetamol poisoning leads to over 60,000 emergency visits and 500 deaths per year in the USA alone.</li><li>It is widely perceived as a safe drug but can be fatal in excessive doses.</li><li>Accidental poisonings are frequent among children and intentional overdoses often occur in women.</li><li>In India, self-medication and easy availability of paracetamol worsen the problem.</li><li>The antidote is N-acetylcysteine (NAC), which is effective if administered early.</li></ul><blockquote>“Awareness about the risks of overdose can significantly reduce these preventable deaths.”</blockquote><p>This article underscores the need for better regulation and public awareness to combat the rising incidence of paracetamol poisoning, often overlooked despite its serious implications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/over-the-counter-under-the-radar-can-paracetamol-become-fatal/article69049356.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/over-the-counter-under-the-radar-can-paracetamol-become-fatal/article69049356.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 23:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korean investigators head to Seoul in attempt to detain impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korean Investigators Seek to Detain Impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p>
<p>South Korean authorities are intensifying efforts to apprehend the recently impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol amid ongoing corruption allegations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The focus is on gathering evidence against Yoon Suk Yeol.</li>
  <li>Investigators are working closely with legal authorities.</li>
  <li>This situation could set a precedent for political accountability in South Korea.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We will pursue all available avenues to hold officials accountable.”</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing investigation reflects the evolving landscape of South Korean politics, where accountability is increasingly demanded by the public.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/south-asia/south-korean-investigators-head-to-seoul-in-attempt-to-detain-impeached-president-yoon-suk-yeol/articleshow/116897155.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/south-asia/south-korean-investigators-head-to-seoul-in-attempt-to-detain-impeached-president-yoon-suk-yeol/articleshow/116897155.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 23:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scamster Ketan Parekh back in Sebi net, banned from market - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scamster Ketan Parekh back in Sebi net, banned from market</h1><p><strong>Publication date:</strong> [Insert publication date here] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert source here]</p><p>Ketan Parekh, a notorious figure in the Indian stock market, has once again come under the scrutiny of the Securities and Exchange Board of India (Sebi), resulting in a ban from participating in the market.</p><ul><li>Parekh's previous market manipulation led to significant market downturns.</li><li>This latest action reaffirms Sebi's commitment to maintaining market integrity.</li><li>Investors are advised to proceed with caution and stay informed about market regulations.</li></ul><blockquote>"This action is a clear signal to all market participants that manipulation will not be tolerated." - Sebi Official</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Sebi's proactive measures against Ketan Parekh highlight the regulator's ongoing efforts to safeguard investors and uphold the integrity of the financial markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/scamster-ketan-parekh-back-in-sebi-net-banned-from-market/articleshow/116896158.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/scamster-ketan-parekh-back-in-sebi-net-banned-from-market/articleshow/116896158.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 22:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xiaomi Poco X7 Pro Iron Man Edition teased as latest Marvel-themed Android smartphone - Notebookcheck.net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Xiaomi Poco X7 Pro Iron Man Edition Teased as Latest Marvel-Themed Smartphone</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Notebookcheck</p><img src="fileadmin/_processed_/2/b/csm_poco-x7-pro-iron-man-edition-header_167dea6825.jpg" alt="The Poco X7 Pro Iron Man Edition is Xiaomi's latest Marvel collaboration. (Image source: Xiaomi)" loading="lazy" width="240" height="180"><figcaption>The Poco X7 Pro Iron Man Edition is Xiaomi's latest Marvel collaboration. (Image source: Xiaomi)</figcaption><p>Xiaomi has teased the release of a new Marvel-themed smartphone, the Poco X7 Pro Iron Man Edition, which will stand out with a unique design and is set to be unveiled globally on January 9.</p><ul><li>The Poco X7 Pro Iron Man Edition is part of Xiaomi's collaboration with Marvel.</li><li>Features cosmetic changes, including red accents around the camera lenses and power button.</li><li>Expected specifications include a Dimensity 8400 Ultra chipset, a 120 Hz AMOLED display, and a large battery.</li><li>Likely to have limited availability, similar to the previous Deadpool Edition of the Poco F6.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Poco X7 Pro Iron Man Edition will primarily stand out from the standard Poco X7 Pro with an eye-catching design.”</blockquote><p>The Poco X7 Pro Iron Man Edition is an exciting addition for fans of both Xiaomi and Marvel, showcasing collaboration in smartphone designs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.notebookcheck.net/Xiaomi-Poco-X7-Pro-Iron-Man-Edition-teased-as-latest-Marvel-themed-Android-smartphone.940180.0.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.notebookcheck.net/Xiaomi-Poco-X7-Pro-Iron-Man-Edition-teased-as-latest-Marvel-themed-Android-smartphone.940180.0.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 21:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[​Top vitamin deficiencies that can land you in hospital; how to resolve them - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Vitamin Deficiencies That Can Land You in Hospital and How to Resolve Them</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>This article discusses the most common vitamin deficiencies that can lead to hospitalization and offers solutions for addressing these gaps.</p><ul><li>Identification of key vitamin deficiencies.</li><li>Impact of these deficiencies on health.</li><li>Recommendations for dietary adjustments and supplements.</li></ul><blockquote>"Vitamin deficiencies can significantly compromise health, leading to serious consequences that may require hospitalization."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, being aware of vitamin deficiencies is crucial for maintaining overall health and can prevent severe health outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/top-vitamin-deficiencies-that-can-land-you-in-hospital-how-to-resolve-them/articleshow/116895184.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/top-vitamin-deficiencies-that-can-land-you-in-hospital-how-to-resolve-them/articleshow/116895184.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vegas Cybertruck explosion: Man shot himself in head before blast, officials say - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxOdkg3VjRlWkdJSkZzOGt5bFcwNVBIQ2Zna2NZQmxQUl9FMlAzQUl1OEd3R2NUR1BKUlJyS1lzSlBGQVF1SGFtcklFMHhUaHFBMWcyLUxMaWZBeDdXbndUZUE5V0hLQTJYd2o4SGNRLUlTVEtxYmwzbUpneWRtVDFuSFFUckhNY1pZZFVrcGJlcXhKc1Q5N000SHpQRjAtektjTjBjZ2VsTGtNT3pOVUZYejdFRGpLcTJCNG1qQkRQRHlRTFR2UWNSZFBCVUJjekFFN2l4YlN0Z0vSAd4BQVVfeXFMTjN4aHZOdlY3WHkxdmZOZ0JIM1VxamJBdDk3RzJrTzNTWGpNcVVUaVg3OURqNVlUSXNISW85RjlBQlY2ZGRjNWNibnlBV1RmQ1c1czBzUHMtRFFjS1VqUWtVclNBUmk1VDlfRFdmRzVfU1psUFFiR3dxazJqQkJkUGlHTWlycFlUYUNCSVpuclNBM3RJaGdaTlV5Y2R0cWF0aTZZdlZ0SU5mekFkOWEySXQ1bzB1TjVvdExCTTBtVmZNaUhuVm5OUkxGUU5XQmNSMUVycFBjbHFXZmlwdzlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxOdkg3VjRlWkdJSkZzOGt5bFcwNVBIQ2Zna2NZQmxQUl9FMlAzQUl1OEd3R2NUR1BKUlJyS1lzSlBGQVF1SGFtcklFMHhUaHFBMWcyLUxMaWZBeDdXbndUZUE5V0hLQTJYd2o4SGNRLUlTVEtxYmwzbUpneWRtVDFuSFFUckhNY1pZZFVrcGJlcXhKc1Q5N000SHpQRjAtektjTjBjZ2VsTGtNT3pOVUZYejdFRGpLcTJCNG1qQkRQRHlRTFR2UWNSZFBCVUJjekFFN2l4YlN0Z0vSAd4BQVVfeXFMTjN4aHZOdlY3WHkxdmZOZ0JIM1VxamJBdDk3RzJrTzNTWGpNcVVUaVg3OURqNVlUSXNISW85RjlBQlY2ZGRjNWNibnlBV1RmQ1c1czBzUHMtRFFjS1VqUWtVclNBUmk1VDlfRFdmRzVfU1psUFFiR3dxazJqQkJkUGlHTWlycFlUYUNCSVpuclNBM3RJaGdaTlV5Y2R0cWF0aTZZdlZ0SU5mekFkOWEySXQ1bzB1TjVvdExCTTBtVmZNaUhuVm5OUkxGUU5XQmNSMUVycFBjbHFXZmlwdzlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:33:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['All Of Us Should Be Ashamed': Madras HC Says Anna University Sexual Assault Case Being Politicised - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/anna-university-sexual-assault-case-being-used-for-political-motives-madras-high-court-9175174.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/anna-university-sexual-assault-case-being-used-for-political-motives-madras-high-court-9175174.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:26:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Matthew Livelsberger shot himself in head before car blew up: New details in Las Vegas Cybertruck explosi - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Matthew Livelsberger shot himself in head before car blew up: New details in Las Vegas Cybertruck explosion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Available upon access</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Available upon access</p><p>This article provides new details about a tragic incident involving Matthew Livelsberger, who shot himself before a significant explosion of a Cybertruck in Las Vegas.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred recently in Las Vegas, leading to the explosion of the involved vehicle.</li><li>Witnesses reported hearing a loud bang before the vehicle burst into flames.</li><li>The police are investigating the circumstances surrounding the incident, including details about the firearm involved.</li></ul><blockquote>"The sound was deafening, and then we saw flames shooting into the air," stated a witness.</blockquote><p>The situation poses many unanswered questions about Livelsberger's state of mind leading up to the incident and the safety of electric vehicles in such circumstances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/matthew-livelsberger-shot-himself-in-head-before-car-blew-up-new-details-in-las-vegas-cybertruck-explosion/articleshow/116895023.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/matthew-livelsberger-shot-himself-in-head-before-car-blew-up-new-details-in-las-vegas-cybertruck-explosion/articleshow/116895023.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Human Body Can Produce ‘Elixir’ That Slows Ageing, Research Reveals - Greek Reporter]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Human Body Can Produce 'Elixir' That Slows Ageing, Research Reveals</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> GreekReporter.com</p>
<img src="https://greekreporter.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/dna-spiral-public-domain-ai-generated.jpg" alt="DNA spiral" width="752" height="498">
<figcaption>Scientists in China have discovered an elixir in the human body that may slow ageing by mimicking the effects of calorie restriction. Credit: Public Domain</figcaption>
<p>Researchers have identified a natural elixir produced by the liver, known as lithocholic acid (LCA), that has shown the potential to improve muscle recovery, strengthen grip, and boost endurance by mimicking the anti-ageing effects associated with calorie restriction.</p>
<ul>
<li>LCA activates AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK), regulating energy use in the body.</li>
<li>The compound has been shown to extend lifespans in fruit flies and a microscopic worm species.</li>
<li>In experiments, LCA extended the average lifespan of worms from 22 to 27 days and increased lifespan in fruit flies.</li>
<li>Researchers aim to explore potential human applications and develop LCA into a pill for various ages and health conditions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“People have long sought an elixir for longevity. LCA is one possibility... activates AMPK, which in turn further induces metabolite changes in the blood.” - Lin Shengcai, metabolic biologist</blockquote>
<p>Despite promising results, further research is needed to confirm LCA’s effects in humans. The findings represent a significant breakthrough in ageing research and could lead to therapies that not only extend lifespans but also improve the quality of life in later years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://greekreporter.com/2025/01/02/human-body-elixir-slow-ageing/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://greekreporter.com/2025/01/02/human-body-elixir-slow-ageing/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:06:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 years after COVID, new epidemic in China which affecting children and elderly - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 years after COVID, new epidemic in China which affecting children and elderly</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116895014,imgsize-104284,width-400,resizemode-4/116895014.jpg" alt="A rise in respiratory illnesses in China, including influenza A and hMPV, is affecting children and the elderly. This increase is attributed to cold weather and the resumption of normal life post-COVID." decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>A rise in respiratory illnesses in China, including influenza A and hMPV, is affecting children and the elderly.</figcaption><p>This article discusses the rise of respiratory illnesses in China, including influenza A and hMPV, primarily affecting children and the elderly. This increase is related to colder weather and the return to normal life post-COVID.</p><ul><li>Respiratory illnesses are notably affecting children and the elderly due to seasonal changes and increased social interactions.</li><li>No formal alerts or declarations of emergencies have been issued by health authorities.</li><li>Rumors of overwhelmed hospitals are unsubstantiated and lack credible evidence.</li><li>The increase in cases is mostly seasonal and not indicative of a new pandemic.</li><li>Good hygiene practices and staying home when sick are recommended to prevent the spread.</li></ul><blockquote>Respiratory illnesses, including hMPV, are rising, particularly affecting children and the elderly, due to post-COVID factors and colder weather.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while there is a rise in respiratory illnesses, it remains a seasonal spike, and individuals are encouraged to maintain hygiene and health practices to mitigate risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/5-years-after-covid-new-epidemic-in-china-which-affecting-children-and-elderly/articleshow/116895014.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/5-years-after-covid-new-epidemic-in-china-which-affecting-children-and-elderly/articleshow/116895014.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma 'Opts Out' Of Sydney Test, Jasprit Bumrah To Captain India In BGT Finale: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-opts-out-of-sydney-test-jasprit-bumrah-to-captain-india-in-bgt-finale-report-9175340.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-opts-out-of-sydney-test-jasprit-bumrah-to-captain-india-in-bgt-finale-report-9175340.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 19:39:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Celebrity stylist Tanya Ghavri reveals Kareena Kapoor 'walks and talks luxury'; Katrina Kaif is 'a Perfec - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgJBVV95cUxORXhaSmJRTkF3WmtfdU9pM1U0MDZHemlDeUcydHZfdHlRVm5NSVRxeXI3dm80eDdGdE1wOXR3dzctSzlyNkNyOUpqd0ZNV0NVZkhaYVFpTlE5LXR5VjlnYXpUUEVZU0NCcC1kOHZBRHN4TWhvVXJwa3Z5VWp2LWtMY01YczB0ZEkxQi1TMmF4OG9oRlBxbUNaNzh6ck9jT2UxRTBKbFVzaWxqTVBZWE9sMm5CYWFlSXp0UjJCU3pZSm10cGdsaUdYdzd0THhsSGhhTWVZVHI0djU1VE05Yk1hYlllMGJmanJuNlFCVWhiZHl4UGJsWnVkdE1QbmdlUzZoOTk0QXVTeS1pZG1lMURkMjJmdDhCZTI5WnNfZ3dIZ05QYURQSldLSU0tUlZUZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgJBVV95cUxORXhaSmJRTkF3WmtfdU9pM1U0MDZHemlDeUcydHZfdHlRVm5NSVRxeXI3dm80eDdGdE1wOXR3dzctSzlyNkNyOUpqd0ZNV0NVZkhaYVFpTlE5LXR5VjlnYXpUUEVZU0NCcC1kOHZBRHN4TWhvVXJwa3Z5VWp2LWtMY01YczB0ZEkxQi1TMmF4OG9oRlBxbUNaNzh6ck9jT2UxRTBKbFVzaWxqTVBZWE9sMm5CYWFlSXp0UjJCU3pZSm10cGdsaUdYdzd0THhsSGhhTWVZVHI0djU1VE05Yk1hYlllMGJmanJuNlFCVWhiZHl4UGJsWnVkdE1QbmdlUzZoOTk0QXVTeS1pZG1lMURkMjJmdDhCZTI5WnNfZ3dIZ05QYURQSldLSU0tUlZUZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 19:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quadrantid Meteor Shower: First 'shooting stars' of 2025 – when and where to watch - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Quadrantid Meteor Shower: First 'shooting stars' of 2025 – when and where to watch</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 3, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> indiastodayglobal</p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/quadrantid-meteor-shower-020138427-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=7wP8UBb.tmJyXWgQyU0U6QWSloDrTKKv&size=690:388" alt="Quadrantid meteor shower" title="Brace for Quadrantid meteor shower. Picture: NASA"><figcaption>Brace for Quadrantid meteor shower. Picture: NASA</figcaption><p>The Quadrantid meteor shower will peak on January 3, 2025, offering the first major celestial event of the year with a potential display of up to 200 meteors per hour in optimal conditions.</p><ul><li>The meteor shower is active from December 26, 2024, to January 16, 2025.</li><li>Best viewing time is in the early morning hours before dawn on January 3.</li><li>Ideal viewing conditions include dark, clear skies away from city lights, particularly in the Northern Hemisphere.</li><li>NASA emphasizes the importance of allowing your eyes to adjust to darkness for the best experience.</li></ul><blockquote>“The sight of these large, colourful explosions of light will be a stunning way to start your year.”</blockquote><p>Don't miss the chance to observe this beautiful astronomical event, ensuring you have the best conditions to enjoy the stunning display of meteors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/quadrantid-meteor-shower-first-shooting-stars-of-2025-when-and-where-to-watch-2658979-2025-01-03</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/quadrantid-meteor-shower-first-shooting-stars-of-2025-when-and-where-to-watch-2658979-2025-01-03</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 19:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Realme 14 Pro+ camera details confirmed - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxPaVRDS0p3TzRpNDVMaUhMOTVldVBLdUNiOFlBVnVzamFXYkVaSUh6b3pDM0VHdzRZWFV0UE1aVUhsb2Q0U012ZDBUeDA1aThZOF9mZXJ3Wk9wWml2eTVOXzhWRTRvNm1kdFd5VkxkVUp5QmUzLWZPb1pvWFlLOW9IYU1xaEHSAYABQVVfeXFMTzFsTmlOcmtrajgycHRYMFRpdDBOaWEyOTAzZ3FKTDBZNDRPeElVbUZXb2N6Z0dhYTdJUXV3LTNFYnkwVjE0R0xiZFRkUW0zUy1xTEo2NUZQVVpEanVkNmI5N0pGa2xkM09zLW5YY1RLZC1Ielk0R3VwMkZTU181cE8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxPaVRDS0p3TzRpNDVMaUhMOTVldVBLdUNiOFlBVnVzamFXYkVaSUh6b3pDM0VHdzRZWFV0UE1aVUhsb2Q0U012ZDBUeDA1aThZOF9mZXJ3Wk9wWml2eTVOXzhWRTRvNm1kdFd5VkxkVUp5QmUzLWZPb1pvWFlLOW9IYU1xaEHSAYABQVVfeXFMTzFsTmlOcmtrajgycHRYMFRpdDBOaWEyOTAzZ3FKTDBZNDRPeElVbUZXb2N6Z0dhYTdJUXV3LTNFYnkwVjE0R0xiZFRkUW0zUy1xTEo2NUZQVVpEanVkNmI5N0pGa2xkM09zLW5YY1RLZC1Ielk0R3VwMkZTU181cE8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 19:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 28 (Early Trends): Allu Arjun Only 3.75 Crore Away From The Biggest Milestone Of Hindi Cinema! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 28 (Early Trends): Allu Arjun Only 3.75 Crore Away From The Biggest Milestone</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p>
<img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2025/01/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-early-trends.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 28 (Early Trends): Inching Towards 800 Crore Club!" width="1200" height="630">
<figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 28: Inching Towards The Biggest Milestone! (Photo Credit – Instagram)</figcaption>
<p>Pushpa 2 Hindi has witnessed another strong day at the box office, reaching an estimated total of 796.25 crore in 28 days. The film is only 3.75 crore away from hitting the 800 crore mark, a significant milestone in Hindi Cinema.</p>
<ul>
<li>On Day 28, the film earned between 3.5 to 4 crore.</li>
<li>Despite a drop from the New Year’s collection of 10 crore, it stays on track for more records.</li>
<li>Week-wise earnings show a robust performance, with a total of 796.25 crore estimated.</li>
<li>The film is witnessing the biggest fourth-week box office collection at an estimated 56 crore, 48% higher than the previous record.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The fourth week of Pushpa 2 has finally ended at an estimated 56 crore at the box office.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, Pushpa 2 continues to perform exceptionally well, maintaining strong attendance rates and inching ever closer to record-breaking achievements in Hindi cinema.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-28-early-trends-allu-arjun-only-3-75-crore-away-from-the-biggest-milestone-of-hindi-cinema/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-28-early-trends-allu-arjun-only-3-75-crore-away-from-the-biggest-milestone-of-hindi-cinema/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 18:51:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV: The mysterious virus gripping China — What You Need to Know - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV: The Mysterious Virus Gripping China</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> March 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p>
<img alt="HMPV: The mysterious virus gripping China — What You Need to Know" title="HMPV: The mysterious virus gripping China — What You Need to Know" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" decoding="async" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360">
<figcaption>HMPV: The mysterious virus gripping China — What You Need to Know</figcaption>
<p>China is currently facing an outbreak of the human metapneumovirus (HMPV), which causes flu-like symptoms and primarily affects vulnerable populations such as children and the elderly.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The HMPV outbreak is raising concerns in several regions of China, five years after COVID-19 surfaced.</li>
  <li>The virus is an RNA virus first identified in 2001 and has been observed globally as a respiratory pathogen.</li>
  <li>Transmission occurs through droplets and close contact, with symptoms resembling the common cold.</li>
  <li>The virus can lead to severe respiratory issues like bronchitis and pneumonia, particularly in at-risk individuals.</li>
  <li>China's CDC has issued recommendations including mask-wearing and good hygiene practices.</li>
  <li>Laboratory protocols for case reporting and verification are being established to monitor the situation.</li>
  <li>Recent data shows a rise in respiratory infections linked to HMPV, especially among children under 14 in northern provinces.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Data from Dec 16-22 indicates a rise in acute respiratory infections, including HMPV, particularly in northern provinces.”</blockquote>
<p>The situation with HMPV underscores the importance of readiness and response to respiratory outbreaks, with lessons learned from the COVID-19 pandemic informing current measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/healthcare/hmpv-the-mysterious-virus-gripping-china-what-you-need-to-know-19533758.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/healthcare/hmpv-the-mysterious-virus-gripping-china-what-you-need-to-know-19533758.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 18:36:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk is standing in the way as Jeff Bezos reaches for orbit - Financial Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTFBTb2g4RFU2d0hSMm92ZE5ZQTUzclRVak16S1l6R3k2M0U5cjMyaGFHRFlfMld4R0FjRW1LY1lEMUZlaFFENXdncWJJUG40cTA4QzhRSldDOHhUSU9tdUd0bGs0R0pUYU1mR0drR2I5T04?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTFBTb2g4RFU2d0hSMm92ZE5ZQTUzclRVak16S1l6R3k2M0U5cjMyaGFHRFlfMld4R0FjRW1LY1lEMUZlaFFENXdncWJJUG40cTA4QzhRSldDOHhUSU9tdUd0bGs0R0pUYU1mR0drR2I5T04?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 18:09:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Musk is standing in the way as Bezos reaches for orbit - Financial Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Musk is Standing in the Way as Bezos Reaches for Orbit</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified <strong>Source: </strong>Financial Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fd1e00ek4ebabms.cloudfront.net%2Fproduction%2Fec1d9477-922d-4802-8092-24d5d5029430.jpg?source=next-article&amp;fit=scale-down&amp;quality=highest&amp;width=700&amp;dpr=1" alt="Blue Origin’s reusable New Glenn rocket" width="700" height="466" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Blue Origin’s reusable New Glenn rocket © Blue Origin</figcaption></figure><p>This article discusses Jeff Bezos’s Blue Origin as it attempts to launch a rocket into orbit, a pivotal moment in the private space race against Elon Musk’s SpaceX, which has seen considerable success.</p><ul><li>Blue Origin has faced delays and is attempting to launch its orbital rocket, New Glenn.</li><li>The private space race sees competition intensifying between Bezos and Musk.</li><li>Musk’s political influence and the growing costs in space exploration pose challenges for Bezos.</li><li>Expectation that the demand for launches will exceed supply through the rest of the decade.</li><li>Governments face a new challenge in controlling a space business that is dominated by wealthy individuals.</li></ul><blockquote>“The demand for space launches is expected to far exceed supply for the rest of this decade.”</blockquote><p>This event marks a significant turning point in private space exploration, with implications for both business and politics as rival billionaires push the boundaries of space travel.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ft.com/content/70286a82-b46a-4164-9d3a-9fba98501240</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ft.com/content/70286a82-b46a-4164-9d3a-9fba98501240</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 18:09:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dinesh Vijan reveals release dates of 'Bhediya 2', 'Stree 3', and 'Munjya 2' from the horror comedy unive - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dinesh Vijan reveals release dates of 'Bhediya 2', 'Stree 3', and 'Munjya 2'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116893557,imgsize-46438,width-400,resizemode-4/116893557.jpg' alt='Dinesh Vijan reveals release dates of 'Bhediya 2', 'Stree 3', and 'Munjya 2' from the horror comedy universe: Fans ask 'Marvel who?''><figcaption>Dinesh Vijan presents the genre-defining lineup of #MaddockHorrorComedyUniverse.</figcaption><p>The horror comedy universe expands with new sequels and spin-offs, generating excitement among fans.</p><ul><li>Upcoming films from 2025 to 2028 include 'Thama', 'Shakti Shalini', 'Bhediya 2', 'Stree 3', and 'Munjya 2'.</li><li>'Thama' will kick off the series in 2025, with notable stars Ayushmann Khurrana and Rashmika Mandanna.</li><li>'Bhediya 2' is set for an August 14, 2026 release, followed by 'Chamunda' on December 4, 2026.</li><li>'Stree 3', starring Shraddha Kapoor, is scheduled for August 13, 2027.</li><li>The series will conclude with two films on August 11 and October 18, 2028.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ab aaya hamara MARVEL-lous schedule!” - Fan Comment</blockquote><p>This lineup is being likened to Marvel's cinematic offerings, with fans eager for the upcoming releases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/dinesh-vijan-reveals-release-dates-of-bhediya-2-stree-3-and-munjya-2-from-the-horror-comedy-universe-fans-ask-marvel-who/articleshow/116893395.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/dinesh-vijan-reveals-release-dates-of-bhediya-2-stree-3-and-munjya-2-from-the-horror-comedy-universe-fans-ask-marvel-who/articleshow/116893395.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 18:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dinesh Vijan reveals release dates of 'Bhediya 2', 'Stree 3', and 'Munjya 2' from the horror comedy unive - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dinesh Vijan reveals release dates of 'Bhediya 2', 'Stree 3', and 'Munjya 2'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116893557,imgsize-46438,width-400,resizemode-4/116893557.jpg' alt='Dinesh Vijan reveals release dates of 'Bhediya 2', 'Stree 3', and 'Munjya 2' from the horror comedy universe: Fans ask 'Marvel who?''><figcaption>Dinesh Vijan presents the genre-defining lineup of #MaddockHorrorComedyUniverse.</figcaption><p>The horror comedy universe expands with new sequels and spin-offs, generating excitement among fans.</p><ul><li>Upcoming films from 2025 to 2028 include 'Thama', 'Shakti Shalini', 'Bhediya 2', 'Stree 3', and 'Munjya 2'.</li><li>'Thama' will kick off the series in 2025, with notable stars Ayushmann Khurrana and Rashmika Mandanna.</li><li>'Bhediya 2' is set for an August 14, 2026 release, followed by 'Chamunda' on December 4, 2026.</li><li>'Stree 3', starring Shraddha Kapoor, is scheduled for August 13, 2027.</li><li>The series will conclude with two films on August 11 and October 18, 2028.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ab aaya hamara MARVEL-lous schedule!” - Fan Comment</blockquote><p>This lineup is being likened to Marvel's cinematic offerings, with fans eager for the upcoming releases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/dinesh-vijan-reveals-release-dates-of-bhediya-2-stree-3-and-munjya-2-from-the-horror-comedy-universe-fans-ask-marvel-who/articleshow/116893395.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/dinesh-vijan-reveals-release-dates-of-bhediya-2-stree-3-and-munjya-2-from-the-horror-comedy-universe-fans-ask-marvel-who/articleshow/116893395.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 18:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poco X7 runs Geekbench, outs its chipset - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxOUE1uVi1vdEJPZnBKQUtWRC1ya3VINkpRNlY5cDdxVUpsLTdBRERncHNQU2VJVUlzdWlEdEFWMF83WHBDV0tsalhid2RSTHBDVVIwcUx3TDhXT2h5WWFab1hyNU9hbDdyTURiNWVZMzVPcE10NkhiU1BTSDFNZ2txaVlYa1pQd9IBggFBVV95cUxPYVVCbnI0WW5zdDBwcWFwLVBrRFlmM2hXR1FVMHNpR2tZcE5KZkVWMlY0RzNaMUswZF9hOFhjbTRYODIySV9HbFI2LTVraHgzNkpwY3F2czg0cmxMam5DcXhydTJoaVd1bGEwMnNJRGM4TmdUM2k4MExPbFRqMm5TUlR3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxOUE1uVi1vdEJPZnBKQUtWRC1ya3VINkpRNlY5cDdxVUpsLTdBRERncHNQU2VJVUlzdWlEdEFWMF83WHBDV0tsalhid2RSTHBDVVIwcUx3TDhXT2h5WWFab1hyNU9hbDdyTURiNWVZMzVPcE10NkhiU1BTSDFNZ2txaVlYa1pQd9IBggFBVV95cUxPYVVCbnI0WW5zdDBwcWFwLVBrRFlmM2hXR1FVMHNpR2tZcE5KZkVWMlY0RzNaMUswZF9hOFhjbTRYODIySV9HbFI2LTVraHgzNkpwY3F2czg0cmxMam5DcXhydTJoaVd1bGEwMnNJRGM4TmdUM2k4MExPbFRqMm5TUlR3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:31:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jennifer Lopez relates to her Unstoppable character's ‘challenging relationships’ amid divorce from Ben Affleck - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jennifer Lopez relates to her Unstoppable character Judy Robles, sharing similarities in their challenging relationships amid split with Ben Affleck.</h1><p><strong>Date: Jan 02, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/TOPSHOT-US-ENTERTAINMENT-WOMEN-0_1704042859973_1735838621770.jpg" alt="Jennifer Lopez connects deeply with her Unstoppable character, Judy Robles, citing shared experiences of challenging relationships and motherhood. (AFP)" title="Jennifer Lopez connects deeply with her Unstoppable character, Judy Robles, citing shared experiences of challenging relationships and motherhood. (AFP)"><figcaption>Jennifer Lopez connects deeply with her Unstoppable character, Judy Robles, citing shared experiences of challenging relationships and motherhood. (AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>In a new interview, Jennifer Lopez revealed that she strongly found her character from Unstoppable, Judy Robles’s “challenging relationships” relatable. She mentioned a connection with her character amidst her divorce from Ben Affleck.</p><ul><li>Lopez described shared experiences with Judy Robles, emphasizing their Latina backgrounds and motherhood.</li><li>Amid her divorce, she appreciates the strength that relationships require.</li><li>Despite the split, Lopez and Affleck maintain a cooperative relationship for their families.</li></ul><blockquote>“We both grew up Latina in this country. We both had children and had hopes and dreams for them. We both had challenging relationships.”</blockquote><p>Lopez continues to navigate her personal challenges while finding solace in her character's strength, illustrating the complexities of love and motherhood.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jennifer-lopez-relates-to-her-unstoppable-characters-challenging-relationships-amid-divorce-from-ben-affleck-101735832381420.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jennifer-lopez-relates-to-her-unstoppable-characters-challenging-relationships-amid-divorce-from-ben-affleck-101735832381420.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:28:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka: Woman kills husband, smashes his face with stone, chops body - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Woman Arrested for Murdering Husband, Disposing Body in Karnataka</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Jan 02, 2025</strong> <br> <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/Sandeep-Kumar--public-relations-officer-of-Gurugra_1735234196111_1735837862719.jpg" alt="A woman was arrested in Belagavi, Karnataka for allegedly murdering her drunkard husband (Representational image)" title="A woman was arrested in Belagavi, Karnataka for allegedly murdering her drunkard husband (Representational image)"><figcaption>A woman was arrested in Belagavi, Karnataka for allegedly murdering her drunkard husband (Representational image)</figcaption>
<p>A woman in Karnataka's Belagavi was arrested for allegedly murdering her husband and chopping his body, police said on Thursday.</p>
<ul>
<li>The woman allegedly strangled her 40-year-old husband, identified as Srimantha Itnali, and then smashed his face with a stone.</li>
<li>She cut his body into two pieces to dispose of it away from her house.</li>
<li>The incident took place on December 8, and the body was found on December 10 in Umarani village in Chikkodi taluk of Belagavi.</li>
<li>The police initially did not suspect the woman, but later brought her in for questioning, and she confessed to the crime.</li>
<li>The husband was reportedly a drunkard who abused his wife for money and wanted her to sell a piece of land to buy him a new motorbike.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"She first strangled him and when he was unconscious, used a boulder lying nearby to smash his face. She then disposed of the boulder in a well."</blockquote>
<p>The woman has been taken into custody.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/karnataka-belagavi-woman-kills-husband-smashes-his-face-with-stone-chops-body-101735837045103.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/karnataka-belagavi-woman-kills-husband-smashes-his-face-with-stone-chops-body-101735837045103.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:17:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Raza, Nyamhuri share spoils as Afghanistan all out for 157 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Raza, Nyamhuri share spoils as Afghanistan all out for 157</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/09/30/550x309/Cricket_3_1727677442716_1727677564058.jpg" alt="Raza, Nyamhuri share spoils as Afghanistan all out for 157" title="Raza, Nyamhuri share spoils as Afghanistan all out for 157"><figcaption>Raza, Nyamhuri share spoils as Afghanistan all out for 157</figcaption><p>Veteran Sikandar Raza and teenager Newman Nyamhuri took three wickets each as Zimbabwe bowled out Afghanistan for 157 on Thursday on the first day of the second Test in Bulawayo.</p><ul><li>Zimbabwe started their innings with 6 runs at stumps.</li><li>Captain Craig Ervine won the toss and chose to bowl, capitalizing on favorable conditions.</li><li>Afghanistan's captain Hashmatullah Shahidi and Rahmat Shah had notable performances in the past, but couldn't replicate their success this time.</li><li>A 27-run last-wicket stand helped Afghanistan reach a total of 157.</li></ul><blockquote>“Given the conditions, I was convinced bowling first was the way to go. The wicket had been under covers for some time.” - Craig Ervine</blockquote><p>This match showcases the promising talent of Zimbabwe's young players and highlights the challenges faced by the Afghan team in this Test series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/raza-nyamhuri-share-spoils-as-afghanistan-all-out-for-157-101735837892497.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/raza-nyamhuri-share-spoils-as-afghanistan-all-out-for-157-101735837892497.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:11:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Orleans truck attacker acted alone in an ‘act of terrorism’: FBI - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/new-orleans-truck-attacker-acted-alone-in-an-act-of-terrorism-fbi/article69055069.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/new-orleans-truck-attacker-acted-alone-in-an-act-of-terrorism-fbi/article69055069.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New York Mass Shooting LIVE: 10 people injured as group opens fire outside club in Queens | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxQcndfeXYzSmQtLTZrVnhpWm1fOFlDX3QzSmNkbXo2bzhKeF9IVTVNVFJQbl9WcGc0VWx6dVlnang3NjFEemt2MG5FTFB4M3BFQ21XUEc1bF81M3BFOGlSQk1DT2FJSHl5Ry14R0hrY3pGQThwMktaV2hOQW80SFlrc2Q3X2JObjJqNm1KQ3d1QnNSMGR3UjZYT2pkQWppQnhnTmdDYkNSUElyWDhlV2pQZnNEX3pHVW5CS1NKZEg0NTVRbXNWaFBfOU03dUlnWlNQV1VmQjJCTTgwQUhUd0wtSVB4MFhOVXcwOVR5UHpDcWdfa3l0S0F4SG42Q053Y0pjM1HSAYcCQVVfeXFMTXdOeW0ya2QwckpTZFlOTVkyZFZJYlJkQTZ0WFhtUFg2NU5HRndBZ3hZQmJ4NFpfeXlMNFNLTFgwV1ZhSEY2QTdOSXFmSXhKdHFOMFp3WmhBQlV6S0hvcDVrMTFMQ1BCS21xM3ItdmVsYzhsdXhFZ0UwMkZwRmJwMVRrSmV3RmJzbE5oQ2FuSmxuRnp3WTczQkZaS19MTy1qeUF5a0Z3eFZmS2pBX0lCeHgyNGNFcWVwVEhpT2VzR0pDMHc1WVozVDdnWDlXdk1kUzFrbUtKdXlwbVRBN09GajlyMkk4WTF4NU5EQlRxWGtwNGU0R3NGUmg0Y2RDVUVuUjN2XzM5cjQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxQcndfeXYzSmQtLTZrVnhpWm1fOFlDX3QzSmNkbXo2bzhKeF9IVTVNVFJQbl9WcGc0VWx6dVlnang3NjFEemt2MG5FTFB4M3BFQ21XUEc1bF81M3BFOGlSQk1DT2FJSHl5Ry14R0hrY3pGQThwMktaV2hOQW80SFlrc2Q3X2JObjJqNm1KQ3d1QnNSMGR3UjZYT2pkQWppQnhnTmdDYkNSUElyWDhlV2pQZnNEX3pHVW5CS1NKZEg0NTVRbXNWaFBfOU03dUlnWlNQV1VmQjJCTTgwQUhUd0wtSVB4MFhOVXcwOVR5UHpDcWdfa3l0S0F4SG42Q053Y0pjM1HSAYcCQVVfeXFMTXdOeW0ya2QwckpTZFlOTVkyZFZJYlJkQTZ0WFhtUFg2NU5HRndBZ3hZQmJ4NFpfeXlMNFNLTFgwV1ZhSEY2QTdOSXFmSXhKdHFOMFp3WmhBQlV6S0hvcDVrMTFMQ1BCS21xM3ItdmVsYzhsdXhFZ0UwMkZwRmJwMVRrSmV3RmJzbE5oQ2FuSmxuRnp3WTczQkZaS19MTy1qeUF5a0Z3eFZmS2pBX0lCeHgyNGNFcWVwVEhpT2VzR0pDMHc1WVozVDdnWDlXdk1kUzFrbUtKdXlwbVRBN09GajlyMkk4WTF4NU5EQlRxWGtwNGU0R3NGUmg0Y2RDVUVuUjN2XzM5cjQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:56:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Extremely tortured by in-laws, wife: Delhi cafe owners last video before suicide - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxPSUVMTWdReGtkczgzaTF3Zl91ZGd3dTZXbmNIcGNMY01BdVphS09CQk5hMVFZcV83R0RyMWxUMlQ4TWNuM1M0QkhiV0lFTlJxSU1XM3d0MllBNHRaRkVJejFqUnI4aDJiTGNaMkEweFhIN242SnkzdDJSUVljdDl0X3IySS02N1JGci1adVZUaGR1bkI4QW1Jc3ZNeGpOdUhmejBxNzV3YXB0RU1jejI4LUU2OXhPaklPLWlN0gG_AUFVX3lxTE8zTy1wY3JJRDRVY2VjcllXbDExNXBJOHNNd21iT0JWUjZEZVNmV1FiM0x0QUp0dkJ2Z2JGN2lseHhuUWVwNF9ZU0NKU2FLak5mU0ZTQzR2Y2FnRDQtelMxYzRpV2Q1YWtXcV9XNVVFb3RoS2VLZHRKaFVHUEFDaTBOTHF5OVBMcmtGckZVTmttQ2IzQWhyTHVxSFBtdWo0R0hzUEsyOWwxUklQUmRsQklXeFlJZTBvb0p1OENQeU4w?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxPSUVMTWdReGtkczgzaTF3Zl91ZGd3dTZXbmNIcGNMY01BdVphS09CQk5hMVFZcV83R0RyMWxUMlQ4TWNuM1M0QkhiV0lFTlJxSU1XM3d0MllBNHRaRkVJejFqUnI4aDJiTGNaMkEweFhIN242SnkzdDJSUVljdDl0X3IySS02N1JGci1adVZUaGR1bkI4QW1Jc3ZNeGpOdUhmejBxNzV3YXB0RU1jejI4LUU2OXhPaklPLWlN0gG_AUFVX3lxTE8zTy1wY3JJRDRVY2VjcllXbDExNXBJOHNNd21iT0JWUjZEZVNmV1FiM0x0QUp0dkJ2Z2JGN2lseHhuUWVwNF9ZU0NKU2FLak5mU0ZTQzR2Y2FnRDQtelMxYzRpV2Q1YWtXcV9XNVVFb3RoS2VLZHRKaFVHUEFDaTBOTHF5OVBMcmtGckZVTmttQ2IzQWhyTHVxSFBtdWo0R0hzUEsyOWwxUklQUmRsQklXeFlJZTBvb0p1OENQeU4w?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:34:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker, D Gukesh Among Four Champion Athletes Selected For Khel Ratna Award - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manu Bhaker, D Gukesh Among Four Champion Athletes Selected For Khel Ratna Award</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 02, 2025, 21:01 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Khel Ratna for Manu Bhaker and D Gukesh (PTI)" title="Khel Ratna for Manu Bhaker and D Gukesh (PTI)"><figcaption>Khel Ratna for Manu Bhaker and D Gukesh (PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>The Ministry of Youth Affairs & Sports has announced the National Sports Awards 2024, honoring Manu Bhaker, D Gukesh, Harmanpreet Singh, and Praveen Kumar with the Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna Award.</p><ul><li>Ministry announced the awards on January 02, 2025.</li><li>Manu Bhaker is the first athlete from independent India to win two medals in a single Olympics.</li><li>D Gukesh became the youngest World champion and helped the Indian team win gold at the Chess Olympiad.</li><li>Harmanpreet Singh led the Indian hockey team to a bronze medal and Praveen Kumar was crowned T64 champion in para athletics.</li><li>The awards ceremony will be held on January 17, 2025, at Rashtrapati Bhavan.</li></ul><blockquote>"The awardees will receive their awards from the President of India."</blockquote><p>The recognition of these athletes highlights their contributions and achievements in Indian sports, inspiring future generations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/sports/manu-bhakar-d-gukesh-harmanpreet-singh-and-praveen-kumar-to-be-conferred-major-dhyan-chand-khel-ratna-award-9175230.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/sports/manu-bhakar-d-gukesh-harmanpreet-singh-and-praveen-kumar-to-be-conferred-major-dhyan-chand-khel-ratna-award-9175230.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:34:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 after-dinner rituals that can help in digestion, prevent bloating - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 After-Dinner Rituals to Enhance Digestion and Prevent Bloating</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116886690.jpg?imgsize=39420&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="10 after-dinner rituals that can help in digestion, prevent bloating">
<figcaption>Adopting simple after-dinner rituals can promote better digestion and avoid bloating.</figcaption>
<p>Implementing certain after-dinner rituals can significantly improve digestion and prevent bloating, ensuring a healthier gut.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Consume probiotics like yogurt or kefir.</li>
  <li>Chew fennel seeds for their natural digestive qualities.</li>
  <li>Take a light 10-15 minute walk after dinner for better digestion.</li>
  <li>Drink warm water or herbal teas such as ginger or peppermint.</li>
  <li>Stay hydrated throughout the day, but avoid large quantities of water immediately post-meal.</li>
  <li>Engage in gentle stretches like yoga to relieve tension.</li>
  <li>Avoid lying down for at least 2-3 hours after eating.</li>
  <li>Massage your abdomen to stimulate digestion.</li>
  <li>Choose light desserts with fruit or dark chocolate to satisfy cravings without overloading the digestive system.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Every little effort put in can be rewarded with a healthy gut and overall fitness.”</blockquote>
<p>Carefully incorporating these rituals into daily life can lead to improved digestive health and overall well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxONVRhMzRtR2RXcDVFejR3ajhLT3k2ZG1tV0YxZk9qbzVySGZLMjZKTUZXclQ2WVJKa0NIS3U2eGJXVWlXWEJzTlB1bF94RXBIMzdDbGRmdnBCbGJkYVZ2ZVlxUGt2WmxqRG5KX3RUZnhGRzhwYURmcmtUbUI2MDlXRlh0WVR2aU84ZXc3eW5YQ294ajdGSnhnZ012V0cySjdJWnpaWWRTREpJM2RpZ01NdWJ0bUk1anhjNGxONjFGM0tBbTZ5YVQtWlNzWlpfYUlYNVY4aWhLbGd3cl81QnZYSFhkVWhMUk9PdklmNGdtbW5pcmtfWmNwM1VR0gH6AUFVX3lxTE41VGEzNG1HZFdwNUV6NHdqOEtPeTZkbW1XRjFmT2pvNXJIZksyNkpNRldyVDZZUkprQ0hLdTZ4YldVaVdYQnNOUHVsX3hFcEgzN0NsZGZ2cEJsYmRhVnZlWXFQa3ZabGpEbkpfdFRmeEZHOHBhRGZya1RtQjYwOVdGWHRZVHZpTzhldzd5blhDb3hqN0ZKeGdnTXZXRzJKN0laelpZZFNESkkzZGlnTU11YnRtSTVqeGM0bE42MUYzS0FtNnlhVC1aU3NaWl9hSVg1VjhpaEtsZ3dyXzVCdlhIWGRVaExST092SWY0Z21tbmlya19aY3AzVVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxONVRhMzRtR2RXcDVFejR3ajhLT3k2ZG1tV0YxZk9qbzVySGZLMjZKTUZXclQ2WVJKa0NIS3U2eGJXVWlXWEJzTlB1bF94RXBIMzdDbGRmdnBCbGJkYVZ2ZVlxUGt2WmxqRG5KX3RUZnhGRzhwYURmcmtUbUI2MDlXRlh0WVR2aU84ZXc3eW5YQ294ajdGSnhnZ012V0cySjdJWnpaWWRTREpJM2RpZ01NdWJ0bUk1anhjNGxONjFGM0tBbTZ5YVQtWlNzWlpfYUlYNVY4aWhLbGd3cl81QnZYSFhkVWhMUk9PdklmNGdtbW5pcmtfWmNwM1VR0gH6AUFVX3lxTE41VGEzNG1HZFdwNUV6NHdqOEtPeTZkbW1XRjFmT2pvNXJIZksyNkpNRldyVDZZUkprQ0hLdTZ4YldVaVdYQnNOUHVsX3hFcEgzN0NsZGZ2cEJsYmRhVnZlWXFQa3ZabGpEbkpfdFRmeEZHOHBhRGZya1RtQjYwOVdGWHRZVHZpTzhldzd5blhDb3hqN0ZKeGdnTXZXRzJKN0laelpZZFNESkkzZGlnTU11YnRtSTVqeGM0bE42MUYzS0FtNnlhVC1aU3NaWl9hSVg1VjhpaEtsZ3dyXzVCdlhIWGRVaExST092SWY0Z21tbmlya19aY3AzVVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>