<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 21:14:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 21:14:40 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 amazing cosmology pictures by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Amazing Cosmology Pictures by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ring-of-relativity-Headlines.jpg" alt="Ring of Relativity" />
<figcaption>Ring of Relativity captured by Hubble.</figcaption>
<p>This article features stunning images captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, showcasing the wonders of the universe through cosmology.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Lensing cluster Abell 383:</strong> A giant galaxy cluster showing the effect of dark matter bending light.</li>
  <li><strong>Hubble’s colourful view of the Universe:</strong> A detailed and colorful portrait of the evolving Universe.</li>
  <li><strong>Dark matter ring discovery:</strong> An international team found a ghostly ring formed by colliding galaxy clusters.</li>
  <li><strong>Cosmic Snake:</strong> A galaxy with regions of intense star formation affected by gravitational lensing.</li>
  <li><strong>Rings of Relativity:</strong> A unique cosmic phenomenon featuring a galaxy elegantly curving around another.</li>
  <li><strong>Astronomy in Action:</strong> A rare celestial phenomenon showcased in a striking Hubble image.</li>
  <li><strong>Ghost light from dead galaxies:</strong> Pandoras Cluster captured in a ghostly Hubble view.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Astronomers have utilized Hubble’s capability to capture detailed and colorful images of phenomena that would otherwise remain unseen.</blockquote>
<p>This collection of images serves as a reminder of the incredible capabilities of the Hubble Space Telescope and its contributions to our understanding of the cosmos.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-amazing-cosmology-pictures-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7499920/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-amazing-cosmology-pictures-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7499920/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 20:11:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists talk about dangers of debris in Earth's orbit - AzerNews.Az]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVEFVX3lxTFB3RjRwdlp1N0FJUzFqMnByVEY2amhzV29DZ0lkYTUzX19LYzAzaUdHYXE5WVZvS1piVmFIcWNLMmluUW5ray1RUC1wTnFuYXhJUHdSZQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVEFVX3lxTFB3RjRwdlp1N0FJUzFqMnByVEY2amhzV29DZ0lkYTUzX19LYzAzaUdHYXE5WVZvS1piVmFIcWNLMmluUW5ray1RUC1wTnFuYXhJUHdSZQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 mentally stimulating jobs that can prevent Alzheimer's, dementia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Mentally Stimulating Jobs That Can Prevent Alzheimer's and Dementia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116751041,imgsize-35544,width-400,resizemode-4/116751041.jpg" alt="5 mentally stimulating jobs that can prevent Alzheimer's, dementia" title="Mentally stimulating jobs decrease the risk of cognitive decline and dementia." decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Mentally stimulating jobs decrease the risk of cognitive decline and dementia.</figcaption><p>A recent study highlights the importance of mentally stimulating jobs in reducing the risk of cognitive decline and dementia as we age.</p><ul><li>Individuals in least mentally demanding jobs face a higher risk of cognitive decline.</li><li>Professions such as teaching, medicine, scientific research, management, and law are crucial in maintaining mental sharpness.</li><li>Those in less demanding roles have a 66% greater risk of mild cognitive impairment and a 31% greater risk of dementia post-70.</li></ul><blockquote>“Mentally stimulating jobs through life are linked to a decreased incidence of dementia and Alzheimer's disease.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, choosing a mentally stimulating job can significantly contribute to maintaining cognitive health and preventing serious conditions like Alzheimer's and dementia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/5-mentally-stimulating-jobs-that-can-prevent-alzheimers-dementia/articleshow/116751041.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/5-mentally-stimulating-jobs-that-can-prevent-alzheimers-dementia/articleshow/116751041.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 19:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump breaks silence on H-1B row, supports Elon-Vivek: 'It's a great program' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump breaks silence on H-1B row, supports Elon-Vivek: 'It's a great program'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>2023-10-20 <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><p>In a recent statement, Donald Trump expressed his support for the H-1B visa program, siding with notable figures such as Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy amidst ongoing debates regarding the program's impact on the job market.</p><ul><li>Trump declares H-1B as a 'great program' beneficial for innovation and technology sectors.</li><li>The statement aims to quell concerns over the program's influence on American jobs.</li><li>Musk and Ramaswamy have also been vocal supporters of revising the program to attract global talent.</li></ul><blockquote>"It's a great program that helps bring in the best and brightest minds to America." - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>This support could shift the narrative around H-1B visas, potentially influencing future immigration policies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-breaks-silence-on-h-1b-row-supports-elon-vivek-its-a-great-program/articleshow/116750940.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-breaks-silence-on-h-1b-row-supports-elon-vivek-its-a-great-program/articleshow/116750940.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 19:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GMC Srinagar urges precautions for people with cardiac issues - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPT2FOaVpqOFNuT2Rwdy1hdHRsRks4ZWFac1hoMGhwZUVMd1poWWptMmYyaV9Tdjd2ZmhFa3l2VjRMX1VFdTNydFViYmNrNzJqWE0wb0ItRnViQlNWVGxtUjk1Z0tQT2x0eHUwVVcyN005NFBvVWQyTWhQXzUtYUp6Z2tLMHRDbVBnQ1VmSGViaGUzQ0FBMDRlRnZtdDZWSzR4SHfSAa4BQVVfeXFMTXFEU3N6czBlU3A1YmNIRDlxZFNnNkFQcHVOWlM0S0RYdWVWbjN2OWR3QjZlMUM4Nmc5b1Ffemp6ZWV5Z3o2THVBYkx3UzJsMG84eHd0QjBkeGh5QkJSN0tlYU9FRFVvdGlEYXY3VEkxZVhQak52UU9RZnRZa2k1SVh3N3dvbmVDSkFtTEhYa0JndFBQODBKSkxMX1FISUVBRUF4U20zY2xwQnU2Zkpn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPT2FOaVpqOFNuT2Rwdy1hdHRsRks4ZWFac1hoMGhwZUVMd1poWWptMmYyaV9Tdjd2ZmhFa3l2VjRMX1VFdTNydFViYmNrNzJqWE0wb0ItRnViQlNWVGxtUjk1Z0tQT2x0eHUwVVcyN005NFBvVWQyTWhQXzUtYUp6Z2tLMHRDbVBnQ1VmSGViaGUzQ0FBMDRlRnZtdDZWSzR4SHfSAa4BQVVfeXFMTXFEU3N6czBlU3A1YmNIRDlxZFNnNkFQcHVOWlM0S0RYdWVWbjN2OWR3QjZlMUM4Nmc5b1Ffemp6ZWV5Z3o2THVBYkx3UzJsMG84eHd0QjBkeGh5QkJSN0tlYU9FRFVvdGlEYXY3VEkxZVhQak52UU9RZnRZa2k1SVh3N3dvbmVDSkFtTEhYa0JndFBQODBKSkxMX1FISUVBRUF4U20zY2xwQnU2Zkpn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 18:53:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jameela Jamil rips Hollywood amid ‘era of Ozempic heroin chic’ after eating disorder battle - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jameela Jamil rips Hollywood amid ‘era of Ozempic heroin chic’ after eating disorder battle</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/Britain-Glamour-Women-of-the-Year-Awards-4_1735408502843_1735408518879.jpg" alt="Jameela Jamil poses for photographers upon arrival at the Glamour Women of the Year awards on Tuesday, Oct. 1, 2024, in London. (Photo by Scott A Garfitt/Invision/AP)" title="Jameela Jamil poses for photographers upon arrival at the Glamour Women of the Year awards on Tuesday, Oct. 1, 2024, in London. (Photo by Scott A Garfitt/Invision/AP)"><figcaption>Jameela Jamil poses for photographers upon arrival at the Glamour Women of the Year awards on Tuesday, Oct. 1, 2024, in London. (Photo by Scott A Garfitt/Invision/AP)</figcaption></figure><p>Jameela Jamil, the actress known for her past struggles with anorexia, has openly criticized Hollywood for promoting an unhealthy 'Ozempic heroin chic' culture through her social media. She shared a video asserting her commitment to maintain her mental health despite industry pressures.</p><ul><li>Jamil's Instagram video features her celebrating body positivity while dancing in a swimsuit.</li><li>She expresses concern about the body-shaming culture fueled by weight loss drugs like Ozempic.</li><li>In a reflective throwback, she reveals the struggles faced during her anorexia battle.</li><li>Jamil suggests that the trend of extreme thinness is harmful and questions its impact on youth.</li><li>She vows not to conform to damaging beauty standards.</li></ul><blockquote>“What are we teaching the kids?” – Jameela Jamil questioning Hollywood's impact on young audiences.</blockquote><p>Jameela Jamil's candid remarks highlight ongoing issues regarding body image and the pressures faced by individuals in the entertainment industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jameela-jamil-rips-hollywood-amid-era-of-ozempic-heroin-chic-after-eating-disorder-battle-101735401750315.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jameela-jamil-rips-hollywood-amid-era-of-ozempic-heroin-chic-after-eating-disorder-battle-101735401750315.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 18:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nitish Kumar Reddy blossoms to give India hope as century stalls Australia - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitish Kumar Reddy Shines as India Gains Hope in Test Against Australia</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> News Source Not Specified</p>
<img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/f79a07010e986b1f64434b81c0ca0fec875435ce/0_265_4157_2496/master/4157.jpg?width=445&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none" alt="India’s Nitish Kumar Reddy smashes a six straight down the ground on his way to a century on day three of the third Test against Australia.">
<figcaption>India’s Nitish Kumar Reddy smashes Nathan Lyon for six on day three of the fourth Test against Australia. Photograph: Santanu Banik/Speed Media/REX/Shutterstock</figcaption>
<p>Nitish Kumar Reddy's remarkable century in the ongoing Test series against Australia has shifted focus from veteran players to young talent, showcasing his potential at just 21 years of age and bringing India back into contention during a challenging match.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Reddy scored his first Test century at a critical time for India, recovering from 358 for nine while chasing Australia’s 474.</li>
  <li>His innings was characterized by intelligent play, aggressive running, and adept shot selection against top Australian bowlers.</li>
  <li>Prior to his century, Reddy demonstrated potential with strong performances in previous innings, scoring 41 and 38 not out earlier in the series.</li>
  <li>Despite the pressure, particularly nearing his century, Reddy maintained focus and composure, ultimately guiding India towards a potentially competitive position in the match.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The skill, the composure, and the degree of difficulty means it’s an innings that should sit in the top tier of MCG centuries.”</blockquote>
<p>Reddy's outstanding performance not only highlights his potential as a future star for India but also renews hope in the team's chances in the current Test match against Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2024/dec/28/cricket-australia-india-fourth-test-day-three-report-nitish-kumar-reddy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2024/dec/28/cricket-australia-india-fourth-test-day-three-report-nitish-kumar-reddy</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal Targets BJP, Congress As LG Orders Probe Into AAP's Delhi Welfare Schemes - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/politics/delhi-elections-arvind-kejriwal-accuses-bjp-of-asking-sandeep-dikshit-to-file-complaint-against-aap-9170930.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/politics/delhi-elections-arvind-kejriwal-accuses-bjp-of-asking-sandeep-dikshit-to-file-complaint-against-aap-9170930.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:56:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk backs AfD party in German newspaper opinion piece - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk backs AfD party in German newspaper opinion piece</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Saturday</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Welt am Sonntag</p><p>US billionaire Elon Musk has expressed his support for the Alternative for Germany (AfD) party through a guest opinion piece, leading to the resignation of the opinion editor at the publication.</p><ul><li>Musk claims that “only the AfD can save Germany” in his commentary.</li><li>He argues that portraying the AfD as right-wing extremist is misleading, citing the party leader's personal life.</li><li>The piece has stirred significant controversy, prompting discussions about freedom of expression in journalism.</li><li>The AfD is positioned second in opinion polls ahead of upcoming elections in Germany.</li><li>Germany’s domestic intelligence agency has classified the AfD as a suspected extremism case since 2021.</li></ul><blockquote>“Democracy and journalism thrive on freedom of expression. This includes dealing with polarising positions and classifying them journalistically.” - Jan Philipp Burgard</blockquote><p>The discussion surrounding Musk's opinion raises important questions about the intersection of celebrity influence and political discourse in Germany.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1881649/elon-musk-backs-afd-party-in-german-newspaper-opinion-piece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1881649/elon-musk-backs-afd-party-in-german-newspaper-opinion-piece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:35:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On Congress Attacks Over Manmohan Singh Funeral, JP Nadda's 'Super PM' Swipe - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>On Congress Attacks Over Manmohan Singh Funeral, JP Nadda's 'Super PM' Swipe</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>New Delhi<br><strong>Source: </strong>News Article</p><p>Following the cremation of former Prime Minister Dr. Manmohan Singh, Congress leaders Rahul and Priyanka Gandhi criticized the BJP for 'insulting' his memory. BJP President JP Nadda accused Congress of playing 'cheap politics' regarding the former PM's funeral arrangements.</p><ul><li>Dr. Singh was cremated with full state honours at Nigambodh Ghat in Delhi.</li><li>Congress demanded a memorial site befitting Dr. Singh's stature, which they believe was not honored by the BJP.</li><li>Rahul Gandhi stated the BJP 'totally insulted' Dr. Singh by choosing the cremation site.</li><li>JP Nadda defended the government's decisions, arguing that space for a memorial would be allocated.</li><li>The controversy highlights ongoing political tensions surrounding the legacy of Manmohan Singh.</li></ul><blockquote>Rahul Gandhi: "Dr Manmohan Singh deserves our highest respect and a memorial. The government should have shown respect..."</blockquote><p>The incident reflects the deep political divide in India regarding the reverence shown to former leaders, particularly in the context of the late Dr. Singh's legacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/manmohan-singh-manmohan-singh-last-rites-on-congress-attacks-over-manmohan-singh-funeral-jp-naddas-super-pm-swipe-7352519</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/manmohan-singh-manmohan-singh-last-rites-on-congress-attacks-over-manmohan-singh-funeral-jp-naddas-super-pm-swipe-7352519</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:56:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: In A First, Israel Uses US Anti-Missile THAAD system To Counter Houthi Attack - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Deploys THAAD System for First Time Against Houthi Missile Attack</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Israel uses THAAD system to intercept missile fired by Houthi rebels (Screengrab)" title="Israel uses THAAD system to intercept missile fired by Houthi rebels (Screengrab)" loading="eager"><figcaption>Israel uses THAAD system to intercept missile fired by Houthi rebels (Screengrab)</figcaption></figure><p>In a significant military development, Israel successfully engaged a ballistic missile launched from Yemen by Houthi rebels using the U.S. Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) system. This marks the first recorded use of THAAD by Israel.</p><ul><li>THAAD was deployed in Israel in October 2024.</li><li>American soldier footage shows the THAAD interceptor launch, highlighting the anticipation of success after many years.</li><li>The Israeli Defense Forces confirmed the interception, although not the specifics of THAAD's involvement.</li><li>THAAD is designed to intercept various missile ranges and relies on kinetic energy for neutralization.</li><li>The deployment follows multiple Houthi missile attacks targeting Israel, notably Ben Gurion Airport.</li></ul><blockquote>“Eighteen years I’ve been waiting for this.” - American soldier during THAAD test</blockquote><p>This event underlines the escalating military tensions in the region, especially with continued Houthi aggression against Israel.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/video-in-a-first-israel-uses-us-anti-missile-thaad-system-to-counter-houthi-attack-9170958.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/video-in-a-first-israel-uses-us-anti-missile-thaad-system-to-counter-houthi-attack-9170958.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:41:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 morning habits that can help improve concentration and performance at work - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwJBVV95cUxONjZ4RTJ5RU01YVhDbU04dERwemZoUjF1d2h6NVUzdkZPTzhjMkpFdGthWmVBM2VDUlA4RjFHdk5IU1FQR0NCMHQwbEFmeWNNem5sOFVKNkZpeXk0QTdNM19tZ01kS3lTX0pxdkJqcWl0SjVna1pKNy02MlgzWV9lXzVJNGdrQWRleG5xVVRFVlVrS0xiXzJxYWxUNWZxLXZZbktxRTZvR1lVMDg5OGRjWWE3SGxYUFB4VFlrLVZ3YkVJLTlLVXhvbElRTmpFWi1uNGlib2pueDh2bDlxYlNZSUMwYnhaUVhHSUVGb1RscUwyM2RUWlZIRjJQaUZVeW9xcXI40gGDAkFVX3lxTE42NnhFMnlFTTVhWENtTTh0RHB6ZmhSMXV3aHo1VTN2Rk9POGMySkV0a2FaZUEzZUNSUDhGMUd2TkhTUVBHQ0IwdDBsQWZ5Y016bmw4VUo2Rml5eTRBN00zX21nTWRLeVNfSnF2QmpxaXRKNWdrWko3LTYyWDNZX2VfNUk0Z2tBZGV4bnFVVEVWVWtLTGJfMnFhbFQ1ZnEtdlluS3FFNm9HWVUwODk4ZGNZYTdIbFhQUHhUWWstVndiRUktOUtVeG9sSVFOakVaLW40aWJvam54OHZsOXFiU1lJQzBieFpRWEdJRUZvVGxxTDIzZFRaVkhGMlBpRlV5b3Fxcjg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwJBVV95cUxONjZ4RTJ5RU01YVhDbU04dERwemZoUjF1d2h6NVUzdkZPTzhjMkpFdGthWmVBM2VDUlA4RjFHdk5IU1FQR0NCMHQwbEFmeWNNem5sOFVKNkZpeXk0QTdNM19tZ01kS3lTX0pxdkJqcWl0SjVna1pKNy02MlgzWV9lXzVJNGdrQWRleG5xVVRFVlVrS0xiXzJxYWxUNWZxLXZZbktxRTZvR1lVMDg5OGRjWWE3SGxYUFB4VFlrLVZ3YkVJLTlLVXhvbElRTmpFWi1uNGlib2pueDh2bDlxYlNZSUMwYnhaUVhHSUVGb1RscUwyM2RUWlZIRjJQaUZVeW9xcXI40gGDAkFVX3lxTE42NnhFMnlFTTVhWENtTTh0RHB6ZmhSMXV3aHo1VTN2Rk9POGMySkV0a2FaZUEzZUNSUDhGMUd2TkhTUVBHQ0IwdDBsQWZ5Y016bmw4VUo2Rml5eTRBN00zX21nTWRLeVNfSnF2QmpxaXRKNWdrWko3LTYyWDNZX2VfNUk0Z2tBZGV4bnFVVEVWVWtLTGJfMnFhbFQ1ZnEtdlluS3FFNm9HWVUwODk4ZGNZYTdIbFhQUHhUWWstVndiRUktOUtVeG9sSVFOakVaLW40aWJvam54OHZsOXFiU1lJQzBieFpRWEdJRUZvVGxxTDIzZFRaVkhGMlBpRlV5b3Fxcjg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13R vs iQOO Neo 10 Pro: Which will be the ultimate flagship killer of 2025? - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/lifestyle/shopping/oneplus-13r-vs-iqoo-neo-10-pro-which-will-be-the-ultimate-flagship-killer-of-2025/ar-AA1wBZZP</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/lifestyle/shopping/oneplus-13r-vs-iqoo-neo-10-pro-which-will-be-the-ultimate-flagship-killer-of-2025/ar-AA1wBZZP</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:29:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vijay Sales' Apple Days Sale: Big discounts on iPhone 16 Pro Max, MacBook Pro Series and more | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vijay Sales’ Apple Days Sale: Big discounts on iPhone 16 Pro Max, MacBook Pro Series and more</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 29 December 2024 - 5 January 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>The year-end shopping season brings significant discounts on a variety of Apple products during Vijay Sales’ Apple Days Sale, including iPhones, MacBooks, iPads, and more.</p>
<ul>
    <li>iPhone 16 Pro available for <span>₹</span>106,900, discounted from <span>₹</span>119,900.</li>
    <li>iPhone 16 Pro Max 256GB priced at <span>₹</span>130,650, with an effective offer price of <span>₹</span>127,650.</li>
    <li>iPhone 15 128GB available for <span>₹</span>60,490, further reduced to <span>₹</span>57,490.</li>
    <li>MacBook Air with M3 chip starting at <span>₹</span>103,390, discounted to <span>₹</span>93,390.</li>
    <li>iPad 10th Gen priced at <span>₹</span>32,499, further reduced to <span>₹</span>29,499.</li>
    <li>Clearance discounts on open-box units starting at <span>₹</span>32,900 for iPhone 13.</li>
    <li>Partnerships with major banks offer instant discounts of up to <span>₹</span>10,000.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Shoppers who participate in the MyVS loyalty programme can earn points equivalent to 0.75 per cent of their total purchase value.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the Apple Days Sale provides an excellent opportunity for Apple fans to purchase their favorite products at reduced prices, along with additional bank and loyalty discounts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/vijay-sales-apple-days-sale-big-discounts-on-iphone-16-pro-max-macbook-pro-series-and-more-11735402721634.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/vijay-sales-apple-days-sale-big-discounts-on-iphone-16-pro-max-macbook-pro-series-and-more-11735402721634.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:23:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus Open 2 Leaks: Exciting Upgrades in Design, Features, and Performance - The Hans India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxPaWNTM2ptcWRXQk9COGZ2ZDZqMVBEYXlhUGtTVXVHLXhFQ2F5WWEyRHpUdl9zbmljazdub3pfdmxqN2psbkZlVHltSmlsa0k5OG81QWU3QjgzWUpRb3FpWGZkWE9rZ1hxejNra25vVW9qVERsbVhGaVl0eE5nejk1bjNCWDVfcV9MMnp0cGE5eDR4RnNNNHBfcDNxYmRhX3V1cUxTakJIaElGUk9kM0NTejJzaElDcEhJWFdJcjFOcW01c2ZEYlA3MHRZa0_SAdIBQVVfeXFMTlZDSlMzMU5VNldXWjhmaFFxRVNBdzBCZjJEN1JQSUsyOWdoTURhUEZ2N1JOVmxyNllSOEpsYWlnTmc5MzBSY3NIWVlQWExEZTFhMUZGOC1QVEZKLWtEWmpmVllmMmd4bFZuaUxTQWRDSUowWEhXeXhGS2ZvQkFpUk15ZFY2RVBFemJCc2V2WFp0QTBESTItMUdTWnI4VE92eDRMLUxoRHF6VmlfNW5raDJMWWVHSng1SkpkMzBwNGUtSnR2Z3NpS0NuTGQ3LXUwMWJn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxPaWNTM2ptcWRXQk9COGZ2ZDZqMVBEYXlhUGtTVXVHLXhFQ2F5WWEyRHpUdl9zbmljazdub3pfdmxqN2psbkZlVHltSmlsa0k5OG81QWU3QjgzWUpRb3FpWGZkWE9rZ1hxejNra25vVW9qVERsbVhGaVl0eE5nejk1bjNCWDVfcV9MMnp0cGE5eDR4RnNNNHBfcDNxYmRhX3V1cUxTakJIaElGUk9kM0NTejJzaElDcEhJWFdJcjFOcW01c2ZEYlA3MHRZa0_SAdIBQVVfeXFMTlZDSlMzMU5VNldXWjhmaFFxRVNBdzBCZjJEN1JQSUsyOWdoTURhUEZ2N1JOVmxyNllSOEpsYWlnTmc5MzBSY3NIWVlQWExEZTFhMUZGOC1QVEZKLWtEWmpmVllmMmd4bFZuaUxTQWRDSUowWEhXeXhGS2ZvQkFpUk15ZFY2RVBFemJCc2V2WFp0QTBESTItMUdTWnI4VE92eDRMLUxoRHF6VmlfNW5raDJMWWVHSng1SkpkMzBwNGUtSnR2Z3NpS0NuTGQ3LXUwMWJn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:19:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Heartening to see Kashmiris open homes to stranded’: As temperature plummets in Valley, tales of warmth - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kashmiris Open Homes to Stranded Tourists Amid Heavy Snowfall</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/jammu-srinagar.jpg?w=640" alt="Several hundred tourists, who were returning from the Sonamarg tourist destination, were stranded between Gagangir and Gund villages in Kagan." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Several hundred tourists, who were returning from the Sonamarg tourist destination, were stranded between Gagangir and Gund villages in Kagan. (Express Photos)</figcaption><p>The early snowfall in Kashmir has resulted in unexpected warmth from locals, who are opening their homes and mosques to assist stranded tourists and residents as heavy snow made roads impassable.</p><ul><li>Hundreds of tourists stranded due to heavy snowfall on the Srinagar-Jammu highway.</li><li>Locals opened homes and mosques to provide shelter and warmth to those affected.</li><li>About 1,000 tourists accommodated in Gund, with women and children sheltered in homes and men in the Jamia Masjid.</li><li>The snowfall was significant, with eight inches recorded in Srinagar and up to two feet in some southern areas.</li><li>The heavy snow led to power outages and road closures, with authorities working to restore services.</li></ul><blockquote>“Heartening to see Kashmiris opening their masjids and homes to stranded tourists amidst heavy snowfall.” - Mirwaiz Umar Farooq</blockquote><p>This event highlights the spirit of hospitality in Kashmir as the community rallies to support those in need during severe weather conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/kashmiris-open-homes-stranded-temperature-plummets-valley-tales-warmth-9749183/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/kashmiris-open-homes-stranded-temperature-plummets-valley-tales-warmth-9749183/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vodafone Group clears Rs 11,650 cr dues, releases pledged shares in Vodafone Idea - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxOWF81dFJyOERjMnV4cy1MOTNwWHA3eS1rOHFEbzg3Ym1oR1A3dklNUUNfZzJjbjNqbUlwUlJlRmVqWTgtSWhKdzhzcGp0NWZwZHl2QnVJSDFOeEFTN0lpcVd1ekppbzJ5UWJyNzZEYllMNXFGNklBSkdTUGYxRFFLaF9fNE1WUVJFTUFZZWtfRHFpUkZkeWhTOGROT1FpaUZ6OXFOZ293N0x2eVExQndFMC03OXdFdmxTSnFTNUh6U2Z0VVUybkQ1MVpxSDk0cXVpTEVqOWRvdDJJTzA3ZTd2YS0tcXVlOUVMV3o1bkFZOGRjTUd0aEHSAfsBQVVfeXFMTlJqSEMzYVZBU2ZiQ3djRzFFOFlKaERlUVVsZ0hVeEJ2TDR0dl9YQ052a1lxeER0WDdGcG1uMllNTE1LLTRSNjVrWmxIam5lQ3dFbmRKcUxxVW03RUwxck5JQm1RVGRpUEt5ZkRGeVhFd2NsVGRiMGZDSVlDajh3NkNWZmN0MXR2dm1rQllBNTlxMGNMZVN0cFppSUlpaWZLOHFGR3FaV1ZRVXZYZS1VLWRTTUhPaktlZEhNUHR0eFV4UzUwYzBORFFxNC03YTNnZWVXMzdXUGE5UmlOR2hKMWZHakExR1dBd0tQVHpJbmpJSmg4WU1FQ0hxMFk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxOWF81dFJyOERjMnV4cy1MOTNwWHA3eS1rOHFEbzg3Ym1oR1A3dklNUUNfZzJjbjNqbUlwUlJlRmVqWTgtSWhKdzhzcGp0NWZwZHl2QnVJSDFOeEFTN0lpcVd1ekppbzJ5UWJyNzZEYllMNXFGNklBSkdTUGYxRFFLaF9fNE1WUVJFTUFZZWtfRHFpUkZkeWhTOGROT1FpaUZ6OXFOZ293N0x2eVExQndFMC03OXdFdmxTSnFTNUh6U2Z0VVUybkQ1MVpxSDk0cXVpTEVqOWRvdDJJTzA3ZTd2YS0tcXVlOUVMV3o1bkFZOGRjTUd0aEHSAfsBQVVfeXFMTlJqSEMzYVZBU2ZiQ3djRzFFOFlKaERlUVVsZ0hVeEJ2TDR0dl9YQ052a1lxeER0WDdGcG1uMllNTE1LLTRSNjVrWmxIam5lQ3dFbmRKcUxxVW03RUwxck5JQm1RVGRpUEt5ZkRGeVhFd2NsVGRiMGZDSVlDajh3NkNWZmN0MXR2dm1rQllBNTlxMGNMZVN0cFppSUlpaWZLOHFGR3FaV1ZRVXZYZS1VLWRTTUhPaktlZEhNUHR0eFV4UzUwYzBORFFxNC03YTNnZWVXMzdXUGE5UmlOR2hKMWZHakExR1dBd0tQVHpJbmpJSmg4WU1FQ0hxMFk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:54:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Varun Dhawan's Baby John shows being replaced by Hindi version of Unni Mukundan's Marco: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Varun Dhawan's Baby John Faces Replacement by Marco's Hindi Version</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/Marco_2_1735397889353_1735397918196.jpg" alt="Unni Mukundan in a still from the Malayalam film Marco." title="Unni Mukundan in a still from the Malayalam film Marco."><figcaption>Unni Mukundan in a still from the Malayalam film Marco.</figcaption></figure><p>Varun Dhawan's film Baby John, which premiered on Christmas, is struggling at the box office, while the Malayalam film Marco is garnering positive attention and replacing Baby John's shows.</p><ul><li>Baby John has not performed well since its release.</li><li>Marco, starring Unni Mukundan, has been well-received and is set to replace shows of Baby John in North India.</li><li>Marco has collected ₹29.9 crore net in India and ₹57 crore worldwide.</li><li>Baby John has earned ₹19.65 crore net in India and ₹27.60 crore worldwide.</li><li>The violent nature of Marco has drawn significant curiosity among audiences.</li></ul><blockquote>“There’s a curiosity to see it (Marco)... it is touted to be one of India’s most violent films.”</blockquote><p>The replacement of shows indicates a shift in audience preference and highlights the competitive nature of current Bollywood releases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/varun-dhawans-baby-john-shows-being-replaced-by-hindi-version-of-unni-mukundans-marco-report-101735397924183.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/varun-dhawans-baby-john-shows-being-replaced-by-hindi-version-of-unni-mukundans-marco-report-101735397924183.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:53:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathi actress Urmila Kothare's car accidentally hits metro workers in Mumbai; one killed - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Marathi actress Urmila Kothare's car accidentally hits metro workers in Mumbai; one killed</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116747115,imgsize-51882,width-400,resizemode-4/116747115.jpg" alt="Marathi actress Urmila Kothare's car accidentally hits metro workers in Mumbai; one killed" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Urmila Kothare's vehicle was involved in a fatal accident in Mumbai.</figcaption><p>A car owned by Marathi actress Urmila Kothare accidentally hit two metro workers near Kandivali in Mumbai, resulting in one death and severe injuries to another worker. Kothare and her driver were also injured in the incident.</p><ul><li>The accident took place near Poisar Metro station while Urmila was returning from a film shoot.</li><li>One worker died at the scene, the other is hospitalized.</li><li>The police stated that the car was speeding and lost control.</li><li>A case has been filed against the driver, and an investigation is underway.</li></ul><blockquote>“Urmila avoided serious injuries thanks to the timely deployment of the car’s airbags.”</blockquote><p>This tragic event follows another incident in Mumbai where a six-year-old boy was fatally injured by an airbag during a car crash.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/marathi/movies/news/marathi-actress-urmila-kothares-car-accidentally-hits-metro-workers-in-mumbai-one-killed/articleshow/116747115.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/marathi/movies/news/marathi-actress-urmila-kothares-car-accidentally-hits-metro-workers-in-mumbai-one-killed/articleshow/116747115.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Sam Konstas Teases India Fans At MCG, Mimics Shoulder-Barge Incident With Virat Kohli - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/sam-konstas-teases-india-fans-at-mcg-mimics-shoulder-barge-incident-with-virat-kohli-watch-7350795</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/sam-konstas-teases-india-fans-at-mcg-mimics-shoulder-barge-incident-with-virat-kohli-watch-7350795</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:39:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Supporters Are No Longer Fans Of Elon Musk. Reason? Immigration - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Supporters Are No Longer Fans Of Elon Musk. Reason? Immigration</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Donald Trump and Elon Musk (AP Image)"><figcaption>Donald Trump and Elon Musk (AP Image)</figcaption><p>Supporters of US President-elect Donald Trump are expressing discontent over comments made by Elon Musk on immigration policies, particularly merit-based reforms, which contradict the anti-immigration stance of many Trump supporters.</p><ul><li>Elon Musk advocates for attracting global talent to maintain US technological dominance.</li><li>Criticism arose following the appointment of Sriram Krishnan to lead AI policy in Trump’s administration.</li><li>Comments made by conservative figures have sparked controversy within Trump’s supporter circles.</li></ul><blockquote>“If you want your TEAM to win the championship, you need to recruit top talent wherever they may be.” - Elon Musk</blockquote><p>The conversation surrounding immigration highlights a significant rift between Elon Musk's viewpoints and those of Trump's base.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-supporters-are-no-longer-fans-of-elon-musk-reason-immigration-9170742.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-supporters-are-no-longer-fans-of-elon-musk-reason-immigration-9170742.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:34:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 23: Record-Breaking Spree Continues As It Beats Uri & Baahubali 2 To Achieve A New Milestone! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 23: Record-Breaking Spree Continues</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided]<strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-vs-uri-vs-baahubali-box-office-01.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 23"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi Box Office Day 23 Update! ( Photo Credit – Facebook )</figcaption><p>Allu Arjun led Pushpa 2 continues its rock-solid hold at the Hindi box office. It has entered its fourth week, and the daily collections have gone below the 10 crore mark. The action thriller has achieved yet another milestone in India.</p><ul><li>Day 23 earnings: <strong>7.50 crores</strong></li><li>Overall box office collection now stands at <strong>747.75 crores</strong></li><li>Pushpa 2 is only <strong>2.25 crores</strong> away from the 750 crore mark, the first ever for a Hindi film.</li><li>Achieved the highest day 23 earnings in Hindi cinema history, surpassing Baahubali 2, Uri, and Jawan.</li><li>Return on investment reported at <strong>273.62%</strong></li></ul><blockquote>“The record-breaking spree seems never-ending for Pushpa 2: The Rule.”</blockquote><p>This successful run showcases the film's significant impact on the box office, making history with its earnings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-23-record-breaking-spree-continues-as-it-beats-uri-baahubali-2-to-achieve-a-new-milestone/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-box-office-day-23-record-breaking-spree-continues-as-it-beats-uri-baahubali-2-to-achieve-a-new-milestone/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:25:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modi government ‘insulted’ Manmohan Singh by cremating him at Nigambodh Ghat, charges Congress - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Accuses Modi Government of Insulting Manmohan Singh at His Funeral</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/btrm0l/article69037704.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241228183L.jpg" alt="Last rites of former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh being performed with full state honours, at Nigambodh Ghat in New Delhi on December 28, 2024." title="Last rites of former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh being performed with full state honours, at Nigambodh Ghat in New Delhi on December 28, 2024." /><figcaption>Last rites of former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh being performed with full state honours, at Nigambodh Ghat in New Delhi on December 28, 2024. | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The opposition Congress party has accused the Modi government of insulting former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh by not allocating a separate place for his funeral.</p><ul><li>Rahul Gandhi stated the government insulted Dr. Singh, a significant leader.</li><li>Congress president Mallikarjun Kharge requested the government to designate a memorial site for Singh.</li><li>The government claims a decision to set up a memorial has been made.</li><li>Criticism arose regarding the treatment of Dr. Singh’s family during the cremation.</li></ul><blockquote>“The great son of Mother India and the first Prime Minister of the Sikh community, Dr. Manmohan Singh ji has been totally insulted by the present government...” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote><p>The article highlights the political tension surrounding Dr. Singh's last rites and the implications for his legacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/modi-government-insulted-manmohan-singh-by-cremating-him-at-nigambodh-ghat-charges-congress/article69037420.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/modi-government-insulted-manmohan-singh-by-cremating-him-at-nigambodh-ghat-charges-congress/article69037420.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['This is the last time he will bat at 7': Ravi Shastri pushes for Nitish Reddy’s batting order promotion - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravi Shastri Advocates for Nitish Reddy’s Promotion in Batting Order</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>This article discusses Ravi Shastri's recommendation for Nitish Reddy to be promoted in the batting order, emphasizing the strategic importance of this change.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shastri believes Reddy's talent is underutilized at the current batting position.</li>
  <li>Promotion could enhance team performance based on statistical analysis.</li>
  <li>The move aligns with the team's goals for upcoming matches.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is the last time he will bat at 7” - Ravi Shastri</blockquote>
<p>Shastri's insights reflect a crucial strategic shift that could influence future games positively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/this-is-the-last-time-he-will-bat-at-7-ravi-shastri-pushes-for-nitish-reddys-batting-order-promotion/articleshow/116746211.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/this-is-the-last-time-he-will-bat-at-7-ravi-shastri-pushes-for-nitish-reddys-batting-order-promotion/articleshow/116746211.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This essential vitamin can reduce dementia and diabetes risk - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vitamin D Linked to Reduced Risk of Dementia and Diabetes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116746542,imgsize-1116785,width-400,resizemode-4/116746542.jpg" alt="This essential vitamin can reduce dementia and diabetes risk" title="(Image: Canva)"><figcaption>This essential vitamin can reduce dementia and diabetes risk</figcaption><p>Recent studies highlight the significant health benefits of Vitamin D, including its role in maintaining cognitive function and reducing risks related to dementia and diabetes.</p><ul><li>A study linked Vitamin D deficiency to a higher risk of Alzheimer's disease, finding that nearly 50% of the population may be at risk for dementia.</li><li>Research involving 270,000 participants revealed that regular intake of Vitamin D can lower the risk of developing Alzheimer's by 17%.</li><li>Vitamin D is crucial for brain health and may mitigate dementia risks through various biological mechanisms.</li><li>Another study found a connection between Vitamin D deficiency and an increased risk of diabetes, even in those managing blood sugar levels.</li></ul><blockquote>“Vitamin D regulates insulin levels and plays a protective role against brain inflammation.”</blockquote><p>To enhance Vitamin D intake, individuals are advised to seek sunlight exposure, take supplements, and consume Vitamin D-rich foods.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/this-essential-vitamin-can-reduce-dementia-and-diabetes-risk/articleshow/116746114.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/this-essential-vitamin-can-reduce-dementia-and-diabetes-risk/articleshow/116746114.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Squid Games meets Bigg Boss': Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser drop has an SRK connect and fans can't keep calm - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Salman Khan's Sikandar Teaser Drops</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/Sikandar_teaser_first_reactions_1735397902191_1735397902535.jpg" alt="Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser carries a Squid Game x Bigg Boss vibe, internet concludes(Photos: X)"><figcaption>Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser carries a Squid Game x Bigg Boss vibe, internet concludes(Photos: X)</figcaption><p>The official teaser for Salman Khan's upcoming film <i>Sikandar</i> has finally been released, generating excitement among fans. The teaser showcases Khan in an action-packed montage, reminiscent of popular shows like 'Squid Game' and 'Bigg Boss'.</p><ul><li>Teaser release followed an unexpected delay due to the demise of former PM Manmohan Singh.</li><li>Fans celebrated the teaser as a comeback for Salman Khan after his recent underwhelming performances.</li><li>The teaser hints at stunning visuals, with VFX handled by Shah Rukh Khan's Red Chillies Entertainment.</li><li>Film directed by AR Murugadoss, produced by Sajid Nadiadwala, featuring Rashmika Mandanna and Kajal Aggarwal.</li><li><i>Sikandar</i> is set to release around Eid 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“This looks really good, finally something worth Salman's stardom.”</blockquote><p>With the buzz generated by the teaser, there is great anticipation for <i>Sikandar</i>, and fans are eager to see Salman Khan back in his element.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/salman-khans-sikandar-teaser-has-a-shah-rukh-khan-connect-internet-detects-squid-game-x-bigg-boss-vibe-101735397614019.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/salman-khans-sikandar-teaser-has-a-shah-rukh-khan-connect-internet-detects-squid-game-x-bigg-boss-vibe-101735397614019.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:10:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Picks for 2025: HDFC Bank to Senco Gold— Religare Broking suggests THESE six stocks to ‘accumulate’ for long-term | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgJBVV95cUxQME9DVTh3YmtEQlR4YTFmaVhHZ1RXdFJscWlNbGRHZHR5VUdxRXZwdVFWZDI1M200UG1tWVdmQXFOZHM1YTdOQk9wWWRVSGZubFl6Smp1QlhZR0c2dUpzSFhTWkd0dUlQSFJTNFBCREZfTFpjbXoxTVpvd1NuV01RcE82X0I2VzBzbHFWeEFmNFdndmFTNlhvSVVZVnNwREplMk9GNzZvTVNlRU9rVTQwRjh5RGtwVlAtbmNKQ2p4VFlGWENxa3VibmVuT1UxamZSQW56ZDNoeGlGMXJJRDRuckZ5aGROZngyN1dVczg1WDhjeWZkM1lmemdxcWsxb2RNYUtOamNNcm85Ym9aT3paUl9R0gGXAkFVX3lxTE82Sk8yZXZKY2c0QjZSNzYxQjN2azNoTTlUcnVPMmJLc1BuYi14WERIQThVN0VXMmRJQjZybFBqMXBISWNXMEZxZ002Qkh6dG1PT2pGV1RfWFkxX1JFdFJsNmlHRmxxcnVJMnlLMk04SUFsc284NnhjVG5SMnlTMDBPLXF2Vmd3UG9YUHNocmJ6TGJIaFo0WlFZVjBUYmozVDdFRWV0eTU3RERJMVpzVmJtN1UzNVlubVFMR2szVzZ6enBjREtYTjlKeDRRdzNFMVhxaGpzM050YUFSSU5MNHZuOW5DSkVmdFRvaGJiVFoycXZfR3pkTFpSejkwcXluUjlweVljOEtPOTdtWWdGWlRlQ1JhbnJyTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgJBVV95cUxQME9DVTh3YmtEQlR4YTFmaVhHZ1RXdFJscWlNbGRHZHR5VUdxRXZwdVFWZDI1M200UG1tWVdmQXFOZHM1YTdOQk9wWWRVSGZubFl6Smp1QlhZR0c2dUpzSFhTWkd0dUlQSFJTNFBCREZfTFpjbXoxTVpvd1NuV01RcE82X0I2VzBzbHFWeEFmNFdndmFTNlhvSVVZVnNwREplMk9GNzZvTVNlRU9rVTQwRjh5RGtwVlAtbmNKQ2p4VFlGWENxa3VibmVuT1UxamZSQW56ZDNoeGlGMXJJRDRuckZ5aGROZngyN1dVczg1WDhjeWZkM1lmemdxcWsxb2RNYUtOamNNcm85Ym9aT3paUl9R0gGXAkFVX3lxTE82Sk8yZXZKY2c0QjZSNzYxQjN2azNoTTlUcnVPMmJLc1BuYi14WERIQThVN0VXMmRJQjZybFBqMXBISWNXMEZxZ002Qkh6dG1PT2pGV1RfWFkxX1JFdFJsNmlHRmxxcnVJMnlLMk04SUFsc284NnhjVG5SMnlTMDBPLXF2Vmd3UG9YUHNocmJ6TGJIaFo0WlFZVjBUYmozVDdFRWV0eTU3RERJMVpzVmJtN1UzNVlubVFMR2szVzZ6enBjREtYTjlKeDRRdzNFMVhxaGpzM050YUFSSU5MNHZuOW5DSkVmdFRvaGJiVFoycXZfR3pkTFpSejkwcXluUjlweVljOEtPOTdtWWdGWlRlQ1JhbnJyTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:06:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra man sets wife on fire for giving birth to third daughter - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maharashtra-man-sets-wife-on-fire-for-giving-birth-to-third-daughter-101735397917403.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maharashtra-man-sets-wife-on-fire-for-giving-birth-to-third-daughter-101735397917403.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:05:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vijay Sales’ Apple Day Sale is back: Massive discount on iPhone 16 Pro, MacBooks, iPads, and more - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vijay Sales’ Apple Day Sale is back: Massive discount on iPhone 16 Pro, MacBooks, iPads, and more</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 29, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/apple-ios-18-1735394214.webp" alt="Apple" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Apple</figcaption><p>Vijay Sales has launched its much-awaited Apple Days Sale, which runs from 29th December 2024 to 5th January 2025. The sale features attractive discounts, exchange offers, and cashback on Apple products, including iPhones, iPads, MacBooks, and more.</p><ul><li>iPhone 16 series starting at Rs 66,900</li><li>iPhone 16 Pro available at Rs 1,03,900</li><li>Previous models discounted: iPhone 15 at Rs 57,490, iPhone 14 at Rs 48,990, iPhone 13 at Rs 42,900</li><li>MacBook Air M1 starts at Rs 63,890</li><li>iPad 10th Gen available for Rs 29,499</li><li>Apple Watch Series 10 starting at Rs 41,099</li><li>AirPods 4 priced at Rs 11,249</li><li>Loyalty program offers redeemable points on purchases</li></ul><blockquote>“Vijay Sales’ MyVS loyalty program offers 0.75 per cent points on purchases, redeemable later for discounts.”</blockquote><p>This sale is a significant opportunity for customers to upgrade their Apple devices at discounted rates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/vijay-sales-apple-day-sale-is-back-massive-discount-on-iphone-16-pro-macbooks-ipads-and-more-2024-12-28-968388</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/vijay-sales-apple-day-sale-is-back-massive-discount-on-iphone-16-pro-macbooks-ipads-and-more-2024-12-28-968388</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revisiting the biggest moments in the space industry in 2024 - TechCrunch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Revisiting the biggest moments in the space industry in 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024<br/><strong>Source:</strong> TechCrunch</p>
<figure><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1536" height="1044" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/boeing-starliner-docked-to-iss-e1718849214277.webp?w=680" alt="Boeing Starliner docked to ISS" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/boeing-starliner-docked-to-iss-e1718849214277.webp 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/boeing-starliner-docked-to-iss-e1718849214277.webp?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/boeing-starliner-docked-to-iss-e1718849214277.webp?resize=300,204 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/boeing-starliner-docked-to-iss-e1718849214277.webp?resize=768,522 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/boeing-starliner-docked-to-iss-e1718849214277.webp?resize=680,462 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/boeing-starliner-docked-to-iss-e1718849214277.webp?resize=1200,816 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/boeing-starliner-docked-to-iss-e1718849214277.webp?resize=1280,870 1280w"><figcaption><span><strong>Image Credits:</strong><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nasa.gov/" target="_blank">NASA <span>(opens in a new window)</span></a></span></figcaption></figure>
<p>We are at the dawn of a new space age. This article highlights the five most significant moments in the space industry during 2024, detailing both achievements and setbacks.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Boeing’s Starliner Mission:</strong> Faced technical problems, leading to astronauts staying longer on the ISS.</li>
<li><strong>SpaceX Catches Super Heavy Booster:</strong> A historic catch marking a significant engineering achievement.</li>
<li><strong>Polaris Dawn Crew's Private Spacewalk:</strong> A commercial mission led to the first private spacewalk.</li>
<li><strong>Multiple Moon Landing Attempts:</strong> Various companies and nations aimed for moon landings, with mixed results.</li>
<li><strong>Space Force Contracts:</strong> Significant contracts awarded to commercial space providers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“During the fifth flight in October, the Super Heavy booster flew back to the launch site and was caught by two large arms jutting out from the launch tower.”</blockquote>
<p>This year has shown both remarkable advancements and challenges faced by the space industry, emphasizing the ongoing competition and innovation within this sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/28/revisiting-the-biggest-moments-in-the-space-industry-in-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/28/revisiting-the-biggest-moments-in-the-space-industry-in-2024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>