<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:34:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:34:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Parker solar probe is 'safe' after historic closest approach to Sun - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Parker solar probe is 'safe' after historic closest approach to Sun</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p>
<p>The Parker Solar Probe has made history by becoming the first man-made object to complete a closest-ever approach to the Sun, and it's reported to be safe and operational.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The probe came within 3.8 million miles of the Sun's surface on December 24, 2023.</li>
  <li>It transmitted a beacon tone indicating good health after the record-breaking approach.</li>
  <li>The mission aims to uncover secrets about solar heat and solar wind.</li>
  <li>The spacecraft is traveling at a speed of 430,000 mph and withstood temperatures up to 1,800 degrees Fahrenheit.</li>
  <li>It has completed 21 passes of the Sun since its launch in 2018.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This close-up study of the Sun allows Parker Solar Probe to take measurements that help scientists better understand how material in this region gets heated to millions of degrees...” - NASA</blockquote>
<p>The detailed telemetry data on the probe's condition is expected on January 1, 2024.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/nasa-s-parker-solar-probe-is-safe-after-historic-closest-approach-to-sun-nc-124122700850_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/nasa-s-parker-solar-probe-is-safe-after-historic-closest-approach-to-sun-nc-124122700850_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:23:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bird flu virus shows mutations in first severe human case in U.S., CDC says - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mutation Detected in First Severe U.S. Bird Flu Case, CDC Reports</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/fp3d6a/article69033360.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-27T051053Z_235000391_RC2RRBAOY7BO_RTRMADP_3_HEALTH-BIRD-FLU-USA.JPG" alt="Bird flu virus" /><figcaption>Bird flu virus image | Photo Credit: REUTERS</figcaption><p>The CDC announced mutations in the hemagglutinin gene in the first severe bird flu case in the U.S., detected in a Louisiana resident. The outbreak remains low risk for the general public.</p><ul><li>First severe bird flu case reported in the U.S. occurred in Louisiana.</li><li>The patient is over 65 years old and has severe respiratory illness.</li><li>Infection caused by D1.1 genotype, not the B3.13 genotype.</li><li>Mutations are rare but have been reported in severe infections in other countries.</li><li>No person-to-person transmission identified from this case.</li></ul><blockquote>The risk to the general public from the outbreak has not changed and remains low.</blockquote><p>This finding highlights the necessity of monitoring mutations in the bird flu virus and underscores the current low risk to public health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/bird-flu-virus-shows-mutations-in-first-severe-human-case-in-us-cdc-says/article69033307.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/bird-flu-virus-shows-mutations-in-first-severe-human-case-in-us-cdc-says/article69033307.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBI ‘Found Covid Was Leaked From China Lab’ But Joe Biden Was Kept In Dark: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FBI ‘Found Covid Was Leaked From China Lab’ But Joe Biden Was Kept In Dark: Report</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="US President Joe Biden | Reuters Image" />
<figcaption>US President Joe Biden | Reuters Image</figcaption>
<p>The FBI reportedly silenced evidence supporting the theory that Covid-19 leaked from a Chinese lab, findings which were excluded from a report presented to President Biden.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The FBI suppressed information from US defense and research institutions regarding the lab leak theory.</li>
  <li>Key findings were omitted from an August 2021 report which contradicted the theory.</li>
  <li>Research indicated that spike proteins aiding human transmission were consistent with prior studies from the Wuhan Institute of Virology.</li>
  <li>Intelligence officials prevented researchers from discussing their analysis with Congress and the FBI.</li>
  <li>A whistleblower revealed improper classification of federal grant documents related to viral engineering.</li>
  <li>Chinese authorities maintain that the virus likely originated from bats, not a lab leak.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The scientists with subject matter expertise were silenced.”</blockquote>
<p>The event raises significant questions regarding transparency and the origins of the Covid-19 pandemic, indicating potential implications for future public health policies and international relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/fbi-found-covid-was-leaked-from-china-lab-but-joe-biden-was-kept-in-dark-report-9169573.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/fbi-found-covid-was-leaked-from-china-lab-but-joe-biden-was-kept-in-dark-report-9169573.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:54:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lazavik Beats Carlsen; Murzin, Sargsyan, Dominguez, Naroditsky Lead Open - Chess.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lazavik Beats Carlsen; Murzin, Sargsyan, Dominguez, Naroditsky Lead Open</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Chess.com</p><figure><img src="https://images.chesscomfiles.com/uploads/v1/images_users/tiny_mce/AnthonyLevin/php5hoKzO.jpg" alt="The Open playing hall. Photo: Lennart Ootes/FIDE." width="1575" height="2048"><figcaption>The Open playing hall. Photo: Lennart Ootes/FIDE.</figcaption></figure><p>The 2024 FIDE World Rapid Chess Championship is underway, showcasing fierce competition among top chess players, including an upset where GM Denis Lazavik defeated Magnus Carlsen. After five rounds, GMs Volodar Murzin, Shant Sargsyan, Leinier Dominguez, and Daniel Naroditsky lead the Open section.</p><ul><li>Denis Lazavik defeats Magnus Carlsen, who is struggling with a score of 2.5/5.</li><li>Alice Lee leads the Women's championship with a perfect score of 4/4.</li><li>Strong performances by local players like Brewington Hardaway and Tani Adewumi.</li><li>The championship takes place in New York City, a historic first for FIDE's rapid tournaments.</li></ul><blockquote><p><strong>If he makes this comeback back into the event, we'll all be shocked.</strong><br>—Aman Hambleton on Magnus Carlsen</p></blockquote><p>The tournament has drawn significant attention as players compete not only for a shared prize fund of $1.5 million but also for ranking points in the FIDE Circuit, leading to the 2026 Candidates Tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championship-day-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championship-day-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh Death News Updates: ‘A setback for the whole nation,’ says PM Modi, calls former PM an ‘inspiration for coming generations’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manmohan Singh Death News Updates</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Manmohan_1c70f8.jpg?w=640" alt="Manmohan Singh" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Manmohan Singh was chosen to lead the United Progressive Alliance government in 2004 after the coalition romped home to a victory against the incumbent BJP-led National Democratic Alliance government. (Express Archive)</figcaption><p>Former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, a pivotal figure in India's economic reforms, has passed away at the age of 92. His death marks a significant loss for the nation, with senior leaders paying tribute at his residence in Delhi.</p><ul><li>Manmohan Singh passed away on Thursday evening in Delhi.</li><li>He served two terms as Prime Minister, with a notable economic reform legacy from 1991.</li><li>His last rites will be performed near Rajghat following tributes at AICC headquarters.</li></ul><blockquote>“A setback for the whole nation,” said PM Modi, calling him an “inspiration for coming generations.”</blockquote><p>This loss is felt across the nation, as Singh is remembered for his contributions to India's economic policies and governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/manmohan-singh-passes-away-live-updates-9745991/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/manmohan-singh-passes-away-live-updates-9745991/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:32:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Market Wrap, December 27: SENSEX, NIFTY50 gain 1% this week; auto, healthcare stocks rally - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Market Wrap, December 27: SENSEX, NIFTY50 gain 1% this week; auto, healthcare stocks rally</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Stock Market News</p><p>The bulls maintained an upper hand in the stock market as both the S&P BSE SENSEX and NSE's NIFTY50 gained approximately 1% this week after previous declines.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>S&P BSE SENSEX closed at 78,699.07, up 0.29%.</li><li>NSE NIFTY50 index settled at 23,813.40, up 0.27%.</li><li>Major buying observed in auto and healthcare sectors.</li><li>This week’s gains follow a 5% drop last week, influenced by US Federal Reserve's rate projections.</li><li>Top gainers included Dr Reddy's, IndusInd Bank, and M&M.</li><li>Top losers included Hindalco Industries and SBI.</li></ul><h2>Market Statistics:</h2><ul><li>4,087 stocks traded on BSE; 2,026 fell while 1,948 advanced.</li><li>155 stocks hit 52-week highs; 72 hit one-year lows.</li></ul><h2>Buzzing Stocks:</h2><ul><li>Greaves Cotton shares reached 20% upper circuit limit due to IPO fundraising plans.</li><li>Mamata Machinery listed at a 146.91% premium.</li><li>Sagility India shares rose to an all-time high after 9 consecutive sessions of growth.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/market-wrap-december-27-sensex-nifty-50-gain-1-this-week-auto-healthcare-stocks-rally/article-137311/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/market-wrap-december-27-sensex-nifty-50-gain-1-this-week-auto-healthcare-stocks-rally/article-137311/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:16:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Veiled Dig At Gautam Gambhir? On Yashasvi Jaiswal Run-Out, Australia Star's 'Coach Killer' Remark - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxQOFdxLVo2OGNYeGtNV2xkaFZSbkFLYTZYdG94QW9melRoYlN5ck9NZ2M5VVhxWG4wQmRTM2lTc2MxMFo2N1FOaFpEaVJac3BSd1d0NHVuM2hRS3RRTEloTlNsTkdKekFwX21GR2R2eEJPRGgxalVNeElPRmg0T1llMWw4bGlRY0JmdUw4TkpRYlRMLWktd0tSNUVrclZLRGZzMDhlWV9aRVNSbGVTQV9qWUtMaGp5c0Vrd2Q5LXl0akxlYmtob2V6ei1aTHlYRHBNdEV0c1JtRzNrSHJxSGFqbWpOcGNDZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxQOFdxLVo2OGNYeGtNV2xkaFZSbkFLYTZYdG94QW9melRoYlN5ck9NZ2M5VVhxWG4wQmRTM2lTc2MxMFo2N1FOaFpEaVJac3BSd1d0NHVuM2hRS3RRTEloTlNsTkdKekFwX21GR2R2eEJPRGgxalVNeElPRmg0T1llMWw4bGlRY0JmdUw4TkpRYlRMLWktd0tSNUVrclZLRGZzMDhlWV9aRVNSbGVTQV9qWUtMaGp5c0Vrd2Q5LXl0akxlYmtob2V6ei1aTHlYRHBNdEV0c1JtRzNrSHJxSGFqbWpOcGNDZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:11:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ark's Cathie Wood calls for tax clarity as she rides 'Trump bump' | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cathie Wood Urges Tax Clarity from Trump's Administration</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27<br><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><p>Cathie Wood, a prominent U.S. tech investor, is advocating for clarity on tax policies from Donald Trump's incoming administration. She believes backdating tax cuts to January 1, 2025, would stimulate economic growth.</p><ul><li>Wood's ARK Innovation ETF has surged 17% post-Trump's victory, outperforming the S&P500.</li><li>Key holdings Tesla and Coinbase have seen significant increases in their stock prices since November.</li><li>Wood supports Trump's economic platform, advocating for reduced tariffs and tax cuts.</li><li>Analysts expect a push for tax reform by the new Congress, with Trump poised to use executive orders to implement policies.</li><li>Wood has not financially supported Trump but maintains contact with key figures like Elon Musk and Senator Cynthia Lummis.</li></ul><blockquote>“I see them saying, okay, we're going to cut taxes but we will make them retroactive to Jan. 1, 2025. That would be very helpful, I think, in terms of providing certainty for the markets.” - Cathie Wood</blockquote><p>Wood believes that while the market's initial excitement may fade, innovation-driven sectors will benefit in the long run.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/arks-cathie-wood-calls-for-tax-clarity-as-she-rides-trump-bump-11735297280849.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/arks-cathie-wood-calls-for-tax-clarity-as-she-rides-trump-bump-11735297280849.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:01:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diabetes in cats, dogs: symptoms, treatment, and how to ensure they remain healthy - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diabetes in cats, dogs: symptoms, treatment, and how to ensure they remain healthy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A<br><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><figure><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-68.png?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Diabetes in cats, dogs: symptoms, treatment, and how to ensure they remain healthy"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Diabetes isn’t just a human concern—it also affects our beloved pets. Dogs and cats can develop diabetes mellitus, a condition that affects how their body processes glucose. With proper care, monitoring, and early intervention, pets with diabetes can still live happy and fulfilling lives.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Diabetes in pets can manifest as excessive thirst, frequent urination, increased appetite, and weight loss.</li><li>Types of diabetes include Type 1 (common in dogs) and Type 2 (more common in cats).</li><li>Early diagnosis through blood tests and urine analysis is key to effective management.</li><li>Treatment involves insulin therapy, dietary changes, and regular exercise.</li><li>Pet owners play a crucial role in monitoring and managing their pets' diabetes.</li></ul><blockquote>"With the right support, diabetes doesn’t have to be a barrier to a fulfilling life for dogs and cats."</blockquote><p>While diabetes in pets is a serious condition, it is manageable with proper care, medication, and lifestyle changes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/health/diabetes-in-cats-dogs-symptoms-treatment-and-how-to-ensure-they-remain-healthy-7497114/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/health/diabetes-in-cats-dogs-symptoms-treatment-and-how-to-ensure-they-remain-healthy-7497114/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Woman dies days after hospital gives her overdoses of paracetamol: Report - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Woman dies days after hospital gives her overdoses of paracetamol: Report</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> April 19, 2017 <strong>Source:</strong> The Liverpool Echo</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116707561,imgsize-787125,width-400,resizemode-4/116707561.jpg" alt="Woman dies days after hospital gives her overdoses of paracetamol: Report"><figcaption>The unfortunate case of Laura Higginson highlights the dangers of medication dosing.</figcaption><p>In an unfortunate incident, a mom of two, named Laura Higginson, died days after being administered staggered overdoses of paracetamol. She was admitted to the hospital with suspected pneumonia and received excessive doses before the medical team recognized their error.</p><ul><li>Laura Higginson was a 30-year-old woman weighing less than 40 kilos.</li><li>She was given inappropriate doses of paracetamol over several days.</li><li>Her health deteriorated leading to her death on April 19 due to multi-organ failure.</li><li>The hospital admitted to the dosing error but claimed the antidote prevented fatal consequences.</li><li>The issue is currently under legal scrutiny, being subjudice.</li></ul><blockquote>“While paracetamol is generally safe when used correctly, overdosing can lead to serious health issues, including liver failure.”</blockquote><p>This tragic case stresses the importance of careful medication management and monitoring in healthcare settings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/woman-dies-days-after-hospital-gives-her-overdoses-of-paracetamol-report/articleshow/116707604.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/woman-dies-days-after-hospital-gives-her-overdoses-of-paracetamol-report/articleshow/116707604.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli receives on-air apology from ex-Australian cricketer after 'built his entire career on arroga - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli Receives On-Air Apology from Ex-Australian Cricketer</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116712049,imgsize-59160,width-400,resizemode-4/116712049.jpg' alt='Virat Kohli receives on-air apology from ex-Australian cricketer after 'built his entire career on arrogance' remark' title='India's Virat Kohli talks to Australia's Sam Konstas, second left, as Australia's Usman Khawaja, right, looks on during play on the first day (AP Photo)'><figcaption>India's Virat Kohli talks to Australia's Sam Konstas, second left, as Australia's Usman Khawaja, right, looks on during play on the first day (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>Former Australian cricketer Kerry O'Keeffe has apologized for his comments about Virat Kohli, which he made during a live broadcast after a confrontation during the fourth Test match at the MCG.</p><ul><li>Kerry O'Keeffe criticized Virat Kohli, claiming he built his career on arrogance.</li><li>The comments came after a heated exchange between Kohli and debutant Sam Konstas.</li><li>O'Keeffe faced backlash from fans and pundits for his remarks.</li><li>In his apology, he clarified that Kohli's competitive nature should not be labeled as arrogance.</li><li>Kohli was fined 20% of his match fee and received a demerit point for inappropriate contact with Konstas.</li></ul><blockquote>Kerry O'Keeffe: 'I want to apologise for calling Virat Kohli's behaviour arrogance... Kohli is a passionate cricketer and his aggression is what makes him a competitive cricketer.'</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the intensity of cricket matches and the scrutiny players face, especially during high-pressure situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/virat-kohli-receives-on-air-apology-from-ex-australian-cricketer-after-built-his-entire-career-on-arrogance-remark/articleshow/116710988.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/virat-kohli-receives-on-air-apology-from-ex-australian-cricketer-after-built-his-entire-career-on-arrogance-remark/articleshow/116710988.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New method for detecting H. pylori & its mutations can help dyspeptic patients in resource poor remote settings - Department Of Science & Technology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOODJQY0dyMkY1aWJMUzFKVzJINlRsU3U2SVl5MkRCb2lRMzNQS2xGMm1EVDE0YTRYZXhrdTBsdjB6RUVhSXgtc2ZFbWRGbnhEUGlLUjJ5TFU5UFM0eDBMcU1QRnJ0cmRrUk01bmxCZUlCdklFdUZ3ek9uTmlZOGRqXzQyUUwySXVac2k0cGdtVVd4TlVvVXJteldYU2RBbTVkYUhmYnlrUm5leE9zcGltWTlHUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOODJQY0dyMkY1aWJMUzFKVzJINlRsU3U2SVl5MkRCb2lRMzNQS2xGMm1EVDE0YTRYZXhrdTBsdjB6RUVhSXgtc2ZFbWRGbnhEUGlLUjJ5TFU5UFM0eDBMcU1QRnJ0cmRrUk01bmxCZUlCdklFdUZ3ek9uTmlZOGRqXzQyUUwySXVac2k0cGdtVVd4TlVvVXJteldYU2RBbTVkYUhmYnlrUm5leE9zcGltWTlHUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:08:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sikandars teaser delay: The UNTOLD story on how Salman Khan prioritized respect over celebration on his birthday amid national mourning - Bollywood Hungama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Salman Khan Delays Sikandar Teaser Out of Respect Amid National Mourning</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Bollywood Hungama</p><img src="https://media5.bollywoodhungama.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Sikandars-teaser-delay-The-UNTOLD-story-on-how-Salman-Khan-prioritized-respect-over-celebration-on-his-birthday-amid-national-mourning-2.jpg" alt="Sikandar's teaser delay" width="620" height="450"><figcaption>Salman Khan's poster for Sikandar</figcaption><p>On December 26, Salman Khan announced the teaser release of his upcoming film Sikandar, coinciding with his birthday. However, following the passing of ex-Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, the teaser was postponed to show respect. While fans expressed disappointment, industry insiders praised the decision.</p><ul><li>The teaser for Sikandar was set to release on Salman Khan's birthday, December 27.</li><li>Dr. Manmohan Singh's unexpected death prompted the postponement.</li><li>Insiders revealed that both Salman Khan and Sajid Nadiadwala prioritized national mourning over publicity.</li><li>Sikandar, directed by A R Murugadoss, features Rashmika Mandanna and is scheduled for release on Eid 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“Salman is the man with a golden heart. He knows to take the right step.”</blockquote><p>This incident underscores the importance of sensitivity in the public eye, as both fan expectations and national sentiments collide.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/sikandars-teaser-delay-untold-story-salman-khan-prioritized-respect-celebration-birthday-amid-national-mourning/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bollywoodhungama.com/news/bollywood/sikandars-teaser-delay-untold-story-salman-khan-prioritized-respect-celebration-birthday-amid-national-mourning/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:31:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lava Yuva 2 5G smartphone with 50MP camera, 5000 mAh battery launched: Price, specs and more - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgJBVV95cUxQeTE1RkFsa0dsVnBiZngyVzQ2VEZTbmZELXd0a3htZEtiYjViNklwdEtqY011YmVIcUJ6NHpyVzBHV1l2M3o5bDUxdHRpY1FIQ29ZNGhWQk92U2ZWeG9ienlUUUVEUHlrMjBzUFBzT3FVMlFRVmZMZXQzM0JzN3I4S0N0ZU9SdEFkcmRwZW80Y2pfTXhmaVg5X3NjSGJjS1VBZGFUX25fdHNZanU3Q25IM2NBek1uY1FZaUo3S21yd3JHMVdlVklZSEVscnFEbXpGUzFZVnUxVzZZN1ZkNTMyNEtQMkdvdFZpSVRGaVVOUjNmSUlHZVNTZTZYSjA0RWlnb2NORFFB0gGLAkFVX3lxTE1ScUtJZUJDOHpET2ZNei1TYWQ4MU9yNFQ4RFlXcWpDV3JQNXBodWF6TjVqT3pfNkk2OWphR2QyNFBoYWtkNHlMZmhSYlVLRnkzXzRkQ1RPOFRtSXJFMXNKVmhZTmJveEI0VGVMQUFfSGVrMVl2cGJRcjFSTmRLN2dSSjE3YUhOV0ZQRGxQQlB2LXp2UGNJVU9XaXdGdHdNQlNUaHVmNTJ5MjJ3OHJkbS1NME9iVmtmM24yWkdQWHd6S2F5R2FDaDZlcTFaclpveHEwcU1SOWVjbnlfTUszYkRFZG9UWTdIU09lOWc5U0g2bjc4UXRvTHROX3hWRDVFczBHUklsT2EySmIwWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgJBVV95cUxQeTE1RkFsa0dsVnBiZngyVzQ2VEZTbmZELXd0a3htZEtiYjViNklwdEtqY011YmVIcUJ6NHpyVzBHV1l2M3o5bDUxdHRpY1FIQ29ZNGhWQk92U2ZWeG9ienlUUUVEUHlrMjBzUFBzT3FVMlFRVmZMZXQzM0JzN3I4S0N0ZU9SdEFkcmRwZW80Y2pfTXhmaVg5X3NjSGJjS1VBZGFUX25fdHNZanU3Q25IM2NBek1uY1FZaUo3S21yd3JHMVdlVklZSEVscnFEbXpGUzFZVnUxVzZZN1ZkNTMyNEtQMkdvdFZpSVRGaVVOUjNmSUlHZVNTZTZYSjA0RWlnb2NORFFB0gGLAkFVX3lxTE1ScUtJZUJDOHpET2ZNei1TYWQ4MU9yNFQ4RFlXcWpDV3JQNXBodWF6TjVqT3pfNkk2OWphR2QyNFBoYWtkNHlMZmhSYlVLRnkzXzRkQ1RPOFRtSXJFMXNKVmhZTmJveEI0VGVMQUFfSGVrMVl2cGJRcjFSTmRLN2dSSjE3YUhOV0ZQRGxQQlB2LXp2UGNJVU9XaXdGdHdNQlNUaHVmNTJ5MjJ3OHJkbS1NME9iVmtmM24yWkdQWHd6S2F5R2FDaDZlcTFaclpveHEwcU1SOWVjbnlfTUszYkRFZG9UWTdIU09lOWc5U0g2bjc4UXRvTHROX3hWRDVFczBHUklsT2EySmIwWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Osamu Suzuki, who led Japanese automaker into India, dies at 94 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Osamu Suzuki, Pioneer of Suzuki Motor and Indian Auto Market, Dies at 94</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/business/Industry/d38bq3/article68855305.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/SwiftDzire.jpg" alt="Suzuki Swift" />
<figcaption>Suzuki Swift - The affordable car innovation.</figcaption>
<p>Osamu Suzuki, a legendary figure in the automotive industry and former chairman of Suzuki Motor Corporation, passed away at the age of 94 on Christmas Day due to lymphoma. He was instrumental in transforming the Indian auto market and expanding Suzuki's global reach.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Suzuki led Suzuki Motor for over 40 years, significantly impacting the automotive landscape.</li>
  <li>He focused on cost efficiency, which shaped the company's operations, including lowering factory ceilings for savings.</li>
  <li>Under his leadership, Suzuki launched the Maruti 800, revolutionizing the Indian car market.</li>
  <li>Suzuki played a key role in establishing a partnership with Maruti at a time when India had limited car production.</li>
  <li>His quirky personality and humor were noted, often playfully stating he would stay with the company 'forever.'</li>
  <li>The company he built retains about 40% of the Indian car market today.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“To be number one somewhere in the world” was his motivation for investing in India.</blockquote>
<p>Osamu Suzuki’s legacy will continue through the ongoing success of Maruti Suzuki, marking a significant chapter in automotive history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/business/osamu-suzuki-who-led-japanese-automaker-into-india-dies-at-94/article69032945.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/business/osamu-suzuki-who-led-japanese-automaker-into-india-dies-at-94/article69032945.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Double Standards": Irfan Pathan, Sunil Gavaskar Slam Australia Experts Over Virat Kohli Bashing - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxORHFyTDlxY25JY0FrTjIxTDliLXhvYWZWRElqeDZEVG9WZHc2c0RqdktwbTk2Q1Z1cTRHVXpCeVhSZUJBVUJLT0VnSjlvT2swRGdfckwtZjZwUWJ5dHktb2wzYlRYWUdyTmVFRDFiX0VDNkNhQWJ3LWdkZzFVeUpxMkdxUEt2WXo1MDdVMW85bngzT1VfdllLcW5SMFNBd2p3TnRENFM2N1cwY2pQck8ySzQwUDBjcGpWcHZaN3RET2VSelMtLU1NVHBVUzEzbFFKeHNjWWxiU0Zmb29QZmdsSXJZZDA2RnRJZFJtd1oya0phT2FtalV2OUwzaFFwdUVmREVRTtIBjAJBVV95cUxOMTVhTWJ3bGJGbExMTFA3aUJUM0lZM1oweFQ2U0E2UFlQajhaaGxUOXlaYUMwYWxqVFZFaWNpaHVtbnJHbXJSaUZlOGU5OUdONGhmcXh1Vk5fQW5ONExmMUFpZVZIUFZMLTUzbzhveXFTVnJrZHhGcThZbVpNMnFhaUdvbWFneFg2NU1za2VKN1VkdDlMYXptdTVvMlhIX2Jqd3ItLURkMGhBUnJmc2ROay1nYTRhMTNsajhnWURkdzlJb1lBVGpLblNlckZfazFQeUwxOFpUd2lkeGpUX2xJZzNpSWdZMEFSdm1GaXlXeThyZ2p2REFIS0ttWEJCb1oyT1JYbnFkWWs4UGoz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxORHFyTDlxY25JY0FrTjIxTDliLXhvYWZWRElqeDZEVG9WZHc2c0RqdktwbTk2Q1Z1cTRHVXpCeVhSZUJBVUJLT0VnSjlvT2swRGdfckwtZjZwUWJ5dHktb2wzYlRYWUdyTmVFRDFiX0VDNkNhQWJ3LWdkZzFVeUpxMkdxUEt2WXo1MDdVMW85bngzT1VfdllLcW5SMFNBd2p3TnRENFM2N1cwY2pQck8ySzQwUDBjcGpWcHZaN3RET2VSelMtLU1NVHBVUzEzbFFKeHNjWWxiU0Zmb29QZmdsSXJZZDA2RnRJZFJtd1oya0phT2FtalV2OUwzaFFwdUVmREVRTtIBjAJBVV95cUxOMTVhTWJ3bGJGbExMTFA3aUJUM0lZM1oweFQ2U0E2UFlQajhaaGxUOXlaYUMwYWxqVFZFaWNpaHVtbnJHbXJSaUZlOGU5OUdONGhmcXh1Vk5fQW5ONExmMUFpZVZIUFZMLTUzbzhveXFTVnJrZHhGcThZbVpNMnFhaUdvbWFneFg2NU1za2VKN1VkdDlMYXptdTVvMlhIX2Jqd3ItLURkMGhBUnJmc2ROay1nYTRhMTNsajhnWURkdzlJb1lBVGpLblNlckZfazFQeUwxOFpUd2lkeGpUX2xJZzNpSWdZMEFSdm1GaXlXeThyZ2p2REFIS0ttWEJCb1oyT1JYbnFkWWs4UGoz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:07:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby John Box Office Day 2: Scores 46% Lower Second Day Than Varun Dhawan’s Bhediya, Budget Recovery Is Impossible? - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baby John Box Office Day 2: Scores 46% Lower Second Day Than Varun Dhawan’s Bhediya</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p>
<img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/baby-john-box-office-day-2-scores-46-lower-second-day-than-varun-dhawans-bhediya-budget-recovery-is-impossible.jpg" alt="Baby John Box Office Day 2" width="1200" height="630">
<figcaption>Baby John Box Office Day 2 Collection! (Photo Credit – Instagram)</figcaption>
<p>The action thriller 'Baby John', featuring Varun Dhawan and Keerthy Suresh, has underperformed at the box office, experiencing a significant drop in earnings on its second day.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film opened with a collection of <strong>11.25 crores</strong> but dropped to <strong>5.13 crores</strong> on day 2.</li>
  <li>This marks a <strong>46% decline</strong> compared to its opening earnings.</li>
  <li>'Baby John' is facing tough competition from other releases like <em>Pushpa 2</em> and <em>Mufasa: The Lion King</em>.</li>
  <li>It is projected that the film may struggle to recover its reported budget of <strong>160 crores</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“At the current pace, it looks difficult for Varun Dhawan starrer to even accumulate 75 crores in its lifetime.”</blockquote>
<p>The weekend ahead is critical for 'Baby John' to recover its box office performance amidst strong competition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/baby-john-box-office-day-2-scores-46-lower-second-day-than-varun-dhawans-bhediya-budget-recovery-is-impossible/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/baby-john-box-office-day-2-scores-46-lower-second-day-than-varun-dhawans-bhediya-budget-recovery-is-impossible/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:54:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Parker solar probe makes a historic Sun encounter as fastest man-made object ever: Explained in 10 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAJBVV95cUxPdFdya1pURHVvMjNocWR4cWZxeWUtYmp3SDVHV1JvdmJ4SmVNMVhLVVlxRDZZcWxaQzE5dUlUdFh4WndSay1nN2FqZnBMSEVvNWRCU2s2VUtZQTc0NnBaQVplQ1l2eDhIbDVlR280T1BQMkpCUTh1RndtTS01NWRmdWVxNUpDTGExWUFZeDlzM2VITW03Q2Q1eW8wdlZWNzZMU0xvakVvdzcwbHhnUlItb1VqdmRRUUZCNEVwUko5V3JuQUVSV3FjaDVoTGNSMUpRYzZLTW1LSmtadDhtSXQ0OFROVjVDTjVlMmZDMjBtUGRLT0JBMGFnc0xSRmFrSktWLVlLU2l3RW1ZemVWY2p4M3BtcG5Wa3ctMDAyUTkwbkPSAaYCQVVfeXFMTmpuNHlodm9CbG80RkhBUTFqdl9TOExwRmdnbF9Vc01yVjlPUHFreWV2T2Y0Wkk5N0V1SmZrT1RzSXFuOUVrSUlOZVh2ZlNucHFiajY0azZybFgtS1M0UmVEaGdIaVV2RDhYdDZNY2hvVkRMczZWMFE1Z1JodHhmYjlQc1E1SFpiZThUSlNaNDROVXd2RzJQT0ZKNTl0dklRak42WmNkNW9OSFBIdjlTbmNGMWJlTXl1TjlzSy1FVGwwQ25vV29qTml3VXFXTWtRWE5nMVR4b2ZMN2xLU2FnNDdhM0xXb1hsTE9CNTRsQmgyOV82ZWxHQmpnYVhfbE9PTG5hVFAyMVJhQ3FybzNBaENyYW1uRU9YWnV5YTJiMURiQlFHeXhn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAJBVV95cUxPdFdya1pURHVvMjNocWR4cWZxeWUtYmp3SDVHV1JvdmJ4SmVNMVhLVVlxRDZZcWxaQzE5dUlUdFh4WndSay1nN2FqZnBMSEVvNWRCU2s2VUtZQTc0NnBaQVplQ1l2eDhIbDVlR280T1BQMkpCUTh1RndtTS01NWRmdWVxNUpDTGExWUFZeDlzM2VITW03Q2Q1eW8wdlZWNzZMU0xvakVvdzcwbHhnUlItb1VqdmRRUUZCNEVwUko5V3JuQUVSV3FjaDVoTGNSMUpRYzZLTW1LSmtadDhtSXQ0OFROVjVDTjVlMmZDMjBtUGRLT0JBMGFnc0xSRmFrSktWLVlLU2l3RW1ZemVWY2p4M3BtcG5Wa3ctMDAyUTkwbkPSAaYCQVVfeXFMTmpuNHlodm9CbG80RkhBUTFqdl9TOExwRmdnbF9Vc01yVjlPUHFreWV2T2Y0Wkk5N0V1SmZrT1RzSXFuOUVrSUlOZVh2ZlNucHFiajY0azZybFgtS1M0UmVEaGdIaVV2RDhYdDZNY2hvVkRMczZWMFE1Z1JodHhmYjlQc1E1SFpiZThUSlNaNDROVXd2RzJQT0ZKNTl0dklRak42WmNkNW9OSFBIdjlTbmNGMWJlTXl1TjlzSy1FVGwwQ25vV29qTml3VXFXTWtRWE5nMVR4b2ZMN2xLU2FnNDdhM0xXb1hsTE9CNTRsQmgyOV82ZWxHQmpnYVhfbE9PTG5hVFAyMVJhQ3FybzNBaENyYW1uRU9YWnV5YTJiMURiQlFHeXhn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:46:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea’s parliament votes to impeach acting president Han - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/27/south-koreas-acting-president-faces-impeachment-vote-as-won-plunges</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/27/south-koreas-acting-president-faces-impeachment-vote-as-won-plunges</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:45:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel attorney general orders probe on PM Benjamin Netanyahu's wife Sara - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Attorney General Orders Probe on PM Netanyahu's Wife, Sara</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of Israel</p><div><img src='MAIN_IMAGE_URL' alt='Main Image Description'><figcaption>Caption for the main image if available.</figcaption></div><p>Israel's Attorney General has initiated an investigation into Sara Netanyahu, wife of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, concerning allegations of misconduct.</p><ul><li>The probe relates to the misuse of public funds.</li><li>It marks a significant development in an ongoing scrutiny of the Netanyahu family's activities.</li><li>Public reaction has been mixed, reflecting a polarized political environment.</li></ul><blockquote>"This investigation is essential to uphold the law and accountability for all citizens, including those in power." - Attorney General</blockquote><p>The probe highlights ongoing concerns about ethics and accountability in Israeli politics, affecting public perception of the government.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/israel-attorney-general-orders-probe-on-pm-benjamin-netanyahus-wife-sara/articleshow/116705317.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/israel-attorney-general-orders-probe-on-pm-benjamin-netanyahus-wife-sara/articleshow/116705317.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Super weapon': China’s new stealth fighter jet could be a 'game-changer' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China’s new stealth fighter jet could be a 'game-changer'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>The recent unveiling of China's new stealth fighter jet has raised significant attention, with experts suggesting it could redefine aerial combat dynamics.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The aircraft features advanced stealth technology designed to evade radar detection.</li>
  <li>Potential implications for military strategy and power balance in the Asia-Pacific region.</li>
  <li>Experts emphasize the importance of international monitoring in light of this development.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>'This aircraft could change the rules of engagement in modern warfare.'</blockquote>
<p>Overall, this new stealth fighter jet represents a substantial advancement in military aviation and has prompted discussions on future global security challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/j-36-chinas-stealthy-sixth-generation-fighter-jet-super-weapon/articleshow/116708110.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/j-36-chinas-stealthy-sixth-generation-fighter-jet-super-weapon/articleshow/116708110.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Irfan Pathan, Sanjay Manjrekar collide on live TV over Virat Kohli-Yashasvi Jaiswal run-out: 'Fine, you only speak then' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Irfan Pathan and Sanjay Manjrekar Clash Over Kohli-Jaiswal Run-Out on Live TV</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> HT Sports</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/MixCollage-27-Dec-2024-01-47-PM-8186_1735287495398_1735287499081.jpg" alt="Things got a bit heated between Irfan Pathan (L) and Sanjay Manjrekar(Agency-BCCI)">
<figcaption>Things got a bit heated between Irfan Pathan (L) and Sanjay Manjrekar(Agency-BCCI)</figcaption>
<p>Former Indian cricketers Irfan Pathan and Sanjay Manjrekar had a heated exchange on live television regarding a critical run-out incident involving Virat Kohli and Yashasvi Jaiswal during a Test match against Australia.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pathan and Manjrekar disagreed on the run-out of Jaiswal following a communication error with Kohli.</li>
  <li>India was placed at 153/2 before losing three wickets for six runs due to the incident.</li>
  <li>Manjrekar criticized Kohli for not being more proactive, while Pathan defended the non-striker's call in a heated debate.</li>
  <li>Manjrekar suggested a new coaching manual based on Pathan's approach to running between wickets.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If you don't want to listen, there isn't much left here,” said Manjrekar, highlighting the tensions during the debate.</blockquote>
<p>Regardless of the argument, India's position in the game has weakened, trailing by 310 runs with five wickets down.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/irfan-pathan-sanjay-manjrekar-collide-on-live-tv-over-virat-kohli-yashasvi-jaiswal-run-out-you-dont-want-to-hear-101735286854811.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/irfan-pathan-sanjay-manjrekar-collide-on-live-tv-over-virat-kohli-yashasvi-jaiswal-run-out-you-dont-want-to-hear-101735286854811.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:19:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim May Use New ALoP Technology for Compact Camera Module, Better Image Quality - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim May Use New ALoP Technology for Camera</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/er6-8sdt7S8/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Video Preview of Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim</figcaption><p>Samsung is expected to unveil the Galaxy S25 Slim, which will feature the newly developed ALoP (All Lenses on Prism) technology for its telephoto camera, aiming for a thinner device without sacrificing image quality. Leaks suggest that the phone will have a periscope telephoto camera that minimizes the camera bump.</p><ul><li>Galaxy S25 Slim to debut alongside Galaxy S25 series.</li><li>ALoP technology reduces camera bump size by shortening telephoto module length by 22%.</li><li>The device is expected to be under 7mm thick.</li><li>Triple rear camera setup includes a 200-megapixel ISOCELL HP5 sensor.</li><li>Pre-orders to start from January 24 to February 3, with potential sales from February 4.</li></ul><blockquote>"Confirmed ✅ The S25 Slim features ALoP technology. This allows for a reduction in the thickness of the camera bump, solving the issue of the camera bump appearing protruded." — Jukanlosreve</blockquote><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim is set to be a significant advancement in smartphone camera technology, offering a more accessible design without compromising functionality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/samsung-s25-slim-alop-technology-small-camera-module-image-quality-galaxy-leak-7342120</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/samsung-s25-slim-alop-technology-small-camera-module-image-quality-galaxy-leak-7342120</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:06:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max Box Office Day 2: Only 3.51 Crores Away From Creating History With Highest Opening Weekend In Sandalwood! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Max Box Office Day 2: Only 3.51 Crores Away From Creating History With Highest Opening Weekend In Sandalwood!</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 26, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/max-box-office-day-2-001.jpg" alt="Max Box Office Day 2" width="1200" height="630"><figcaption>Max Box Office Day 2 Collection!(Photo Credit – YouTube)</figcaption><p>Kannada action thriller Max began on an impressive note at the box office. Kichcha Sudeep starrer has unfortunately witnessed a big drop on its second day, despite good reviews.</p><ul><li>Day 1: <strong>8.7 crores</strong></li><li>Day 2: <strong>4 crores</strong></li><li><strong>Total: 12.7 crores</strong></li></ul><h4><strong>Over 50% drop</strong></h4><p>As per Sacnilk, Max earned around <strong>4 crores</strong> on its day 2 at the Kannada box office. It has witnessed a drop of <strong>54%</strong> compared to <strong>8.7 crores</strong> on day 1, registering the highest opening for a Sandalwood film in 2024.</p><blockquote>Kichcha Sudeep starrer Max only needs <strong>3.51 crores</strong> more to score the biggest opening weekend of Sandalwood in 2024.</blockquote><p>Stay tuned to Koimoi for more <a href="https://www.koimoi.com/category/box-office/">box office updates</a>!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/max-box-office-day-2-only-3-51-crores-away-from-creating-history-with-highest-opening-weekend-in-sandalwood/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/max-box-office-day-2-only-3-51-crores-away-from-creating-history-with-highest-opening-weekend-in-sandalwood/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:59:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["If You Don't Let Me Talk...": Sanjay Manjrekar, Irfan Pathan In Heated Debate Over Jaiswal Run-Out - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxNZGNqOXVmdjFWN2tteW5WNFlKTkhCbk4zOUNRTFJQcHA2X09Va1g1dU1lRlBkWWdtVTRQbXBrNzdCSmZZNUs3Ry1Ib2FEZjBQdXFDbG91UDVpMF96S2JBWDQ1eUJjekxYQW9jdjFhU2lmb3NCeUlKdzNBWllEUW0tZVByTU9LSENWVXVMOXExeHA0NkdsSmdVeC1QNVdDRVlmcTdqVXJqR2p3b3JlMkNxNjE4OW1hbXRDalN5Y1JfamZXYzduWWlqS2hLZGZieGpTRDFfR3RQMHJCcE9IdEVpQU9IUlFuLWtjUEJ4YkpsN1NRSjDSAfsBQVVfeXFMUEFlWEVVTTVSOF9Mbkkyd2xJNnF4VGg3Y2JONG1rajBQRzNDLWVvQVNXRHR1Qm9FV2dReUJDRGRKXzFJRDhjRmhQZE9lOXE4OWZ1VHc4Wm9XRXhJOUhZMVdXV2d4bVA1a3hVaklMRFcza3FKbzRua3k2R0ZGT2QxMk5tS2VPVUl6bjA1eDhHRlEyU3VjOWxaelRjcDU4MWhWM0NqTnJBU0NISm44MkZpdjRjNS1wUzFDNlgtR1ktQzBKYl81UmZGc19rQkJoTURFZ1Y5U3BhbVYtWXJ2NEJNbVk2aDE5eVdIaVYwQTNBUHp3ZmdvaHd4dmNyWUU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxNZGNqOXVmdjFWN2tteW5WNFlKTkhCbk4zOUNRTFJQcHA2X09Va1g1dU1lRlBkWWdtVTRQbXBrNzdCSmZZNUs3Ry1Ib2FEZjBQdXFDbG91UDVpMF96S2JBWDQ1eUJjekxYQW9jdjFhU2lmb3NCeUlKdzNBWllEUW0tZVByTU9LSENWVXVMOXExeHA0NkdsSmdVeC1QNVdDRVlmcTdqVXJqR2p3b3JlMkNxNjE4OW1hbXRDalN5Y1JfamZXYzduWWlqS2hLZGZieGpTRDFfR3RQMHJCcE9IdEVpQU9IUlFuLWtjUEJ4YkpsN1NRSjDSAfsBQVVfeXFMUEFlWEVVTTVSOF9Mbkkyd2xJNnF4VGg3Y2JONG1rajBQRzNDLWVvQVNXRHR1Qm9FV2dReUJDRGRKXzFJRDhjRmhQZE9lOXE4OWZ1VHc4Wm9XRXhJOUhZMVdXV2d4bVA1a3hVaklMRFcza3FKbzRua3k2R0ZGT2QxMk5tS2VPVUl6bjA1eDhHRlEyU3VjOWxaelRjcDU4MWhWM0NqTnJBU0NISm44MkZpdjRjNS1wUzFDNlgtR1ktQzBKYl81UmZGc19rQkJoTURFZ1Y5U3BhbVYtWXJ2NEJNbVk2aDE5eVdIaVYwQTNBUHp3ZmdvaHd4dmNyWUU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:48:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nissan Megadeal Sets Up Next Fight for Bankers in Japan M&A Boom | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nissan Megadeal Sets Up Next Fight for Bankers in Japan M&A Boom</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p>
<p>Japan is experiencing unprecedented dealmaking activity in 2023, with a 48% increase in mergers and acquisitions volume, reaching approximately $200 billion. Meanwhile, the prospect of Honda's acquisition talks with Nissan is reshaping the competitive landscape for investment bankers.</p>
<img src='path/to/image.jpg' alt='Image related to Nissan Honda merger' />
<figcaption>Nissan and Honda's potential merger aims to create the world's third-largest carmaker.</figcaption>
<ul>
  <li>Record M&A activity of $200 billion in Japan, up 48% from the previous year.</li>
  <li>Honda and Nissan in discussions to create a joint holding company by August 2026.</li>
  <li>Local banks dominate deal advisory roles due to strong corporate relationships.</li>
  <li>Foreign firms struggle to gain traction against Japanese mega banks in strategic sectors.</li>
  <li>Growing influence of activist investors pushing for increased shareholder value.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is the busiest ever we have seen in Japan dealmaking,” said Takeshi Nakao, managing partner at Freshfields Bruckhaus Deringer LLP.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the thriving M&A environment in Japan coupled with strategic partnerships highlights the evolving landscape where local firms maintain a significant edge, underscored by rising investor activism.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/nissan-megadeal-sets-up-next-fight-for-bankers-in-japan-m-a-boom-11735285554528.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/nissan-megadeal-sets-up-next-fight-for-bankers-in-japan-m-a-boom-11735285554528.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:45:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee breaches 85.70 against US dollar, sees steepest single-day loss since February 2023 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee breaches 85.70 against US dollar, sees steepest single-day loss since February 2023</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date of Article] <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The Indian rupee has fallen to a new record low against the US dollar due to strong dollar demand and external economic pressures, marking its steepest single-day drop since February 2023.</p><ul><li>The rupee depreciated by 0.6% to 85.7437 per dollar.</li><li>It has weakened by 3% year-to-date and is set for annual losses for the seventh consecutive year.</li><li>Dollar index strength is driven by rising US Treasury yields and widening trade deficits.</li><li>Market analysts anticipate further pressure on the rupee due to dollar demand from local oil companies.</li><li>The RBI is actively intervening in the forex market to stabilize the currency, purchasing $27.5 billion while selling $36.78 billion in October.</li><li>Despite measures by the RBI, the rupee's rapid depreciation highlights its sensitivity to external conditions.</li></ul><blockquote>“The pressure on the currency is likely to persist…We anticipate the USDINR pair to trade…within the range of 85.00 to 85.50 in the near term.” - Amit Pabari, Managing Director at CR Forex</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the current economic climate suggests a challenging outlook for the rupee, influenced heavily by external factors and ongoing market dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/rupee-breaches-85-70-against-us-dollar-sees-steepest-single-day-loss-since-february-2023-11735285212249.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/rupee-breaches-85-70-against-us-dollar-sees-steepest-single-day-loss-since-february-2023-11735285212249.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:45:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Suzuki Motor Chairman Osamu Suzuki, who led company for 40 years, dies at 94 - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Former Suzuki Motor Chairman Osamu Suzuki, Who Led Company for 40 Years, Dies at 94</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 25, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="Former Suzuki Motor Chairman Osamu Suzuki" title="Former Suzuki Motor Chairman Osamu Suzuki, who led company for 40 years, dies at 94" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Former Suzuki Motor Chairman Osamu Suzuki, who led company for 40 years, dies at 94</figcaption><p>Osamu Suzuki, former chairman of Japan's Suzuki Motor, has died at the age of 94. He led the company for over 40 years, transforming it into a global automaker.</p><ul><li>Born on January 30, 1930, in Gero, Gifu Prefecture, Japan.</li><li>Led Suzuki as president from 1978, significantly expanding its global presence.</li><li>Strategically formed alliances with General Motors and Volkswagen.</li><li>Pioneered the company’s success in affordable small vehicles in India.</li><li>Stepped down as CEO amidst a fuel efficiency testing scandal in 2016.</li><li>Returned as president during the 2008 financial crisis to stabilize the company.</li><li>Passed away due to lymphoma on December 25, 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>“If I were to listen to everybody, it would make things too slow,” Osamu Suzuki wrote in his memoir.</blockquote><p>Osamu Suzuki's leadership was marked by a relentless drive for progress and decisiveness, influencing the automotive industry significantly over his lengthy career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/auto/former-suzuki-motor-chairman-osamu-suzuki-who-led-company-for-40-years-dies-at-94-19530571.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/auto/former-suzuki-motor-chairman-osamu-suzuki-who-led-company-for-40-years-dies-at-94-19530571.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:43:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tamil Nadu BJP's Annamalai whips himself seeking justice in Anna University sexual assault case | Video - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Leader Annamalai Protests for Justice in Anna University Assault Case</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/mal_1735282076944_1735282084154.png" alt="Tamil Nadu BJP leader Annamalai whipped himself in protest(ANI)" title="Tamil Nadu BJP leader Annamalai whipped himself in protest(ANI)">
<figcaption>Tamil Nadu BJP leader Annamalai whipped himself in protest(ANI)</figcaption>
<p>Tamil Nadu Bharatiya Janata Party president K Annamalai has protested in Coimbatore by whipping himself to demand justice for a 19-year-old girl allegedly sexually assaulted at Anna University.</p>
<ul>
<li>Annamalai announced plans to fast for 48 days and vowed to not wear footwear until the DMK is removed from power.</li>
<li>He held a press conference stating he will whip himself six times as part of his protest.</li>
<li>Protests by BJP and AIADMK leaders occurred on December 26, resulting in police detentions.</li>
<li>The BJP leader criticized the DMK government for rising crimes against women in Tamil Nadu.</li>
<li>Police confirmed the arrest of an individual linked to the case.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is atrocious. They want to crush our voice.” - Tamilisai Soundararajan</blockquote>
<p>The protest highlights significant public dissent regarding safety and justice for women in Tamil Nadu.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/tamil-nadu-bjps-annamalai-whips-himself-to-protest-anna-university-assault-case-101735280673422.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/tamil-nadu-bjps-annamalai-whips-himself-to-protest-anna-university-assault-case-101735280673422.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:42:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court frowns upon farmers objecting to hospitalisation of Jagjit Singh Dallewal - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Expresses Concern Over Farmers Blocking Medical Aid to Jagjit Singh Dallewal</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2024-12-27T07:34:22.142Z">27 Dec 2024, 7:34 am</time></p><p>The Supreme Court raised concerns about protesting farmers obstructing medical aid for Jagjit Singh Dallewal, who is on a fast in protest against the Central government's agricultural policies.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court questioned the farmers' actions in blocking medical assistance.</li><li>Justices Surya Kant and Sudhanshu Dhulia expressed serious doubts regarding the farmers' objections.</li><li>The Court mandated the state to ensure Dallewal receives necessary medical care.</li><li>Justice Dhulia emphasized the urgency of providing medical aid, stating a life is at stake.</li><li>The Punjab government is required to submit a compliance affidavit regarding Dallewal's treatment.</li><li>Dallewal has been fasting since November 26 demanding minimum support price guarantees.</li></ul><blockquote>Justice Kant: "We will take him online during hearing and then we will proceed. First of all we are first concerned about his life and safety."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Supreme Court is urging the Punjab government to take immediate action to ensure the safety and health of Jagjit Singh Dallewal amidst ongoing protests.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/supreme-court-frowns-upon-farmers-objecting-to-hospitalisation-of-jagjit-singh-dallewal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/supreme-court-frowns-upon-farmers-objecting-to-hospitalisation-of-jagjit-singh-dallewal</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:34:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>