<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 03:35:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 03:35:43 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Terrorists Killed In Encounter With Security Forces In J&K's Kulgam - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxOS3NNcmlHanpQMU9zRXdrbV84OFUwcm9yOTZ3bWhHWkI2QlRmUGtjZ243cFYzYTE0emF5RERXYU0zSldqeFZhTW1sd0V5S0IzcDlpVjQ4aFpNUENuVGdJS1o4MnVrRWhFTVhObUtkcXlZc1U5UmRxRXdYVDlNUk5uQzZsMFAteFZlRkNIX0dIVFRpdzRJY1ktOFF6MjZoODhQMFlYWmRHMHJrWGxw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxOS3NNcmlHanpQMU9zRXdrbV84OFUwcm9yOTZ3bWhHWkI2QlRmUGtjZ243cFYzYTE0emF5RERXYU0zSldqeFZhTW1sd0V5S0IzcDlpVjQ4aFpNUENuVGdJS1o4MnVrRWhFTVhObUtkcXlZc1U5UmRxRXdYVDlNUk5uQzZsMFAteFZlRkNIX0dIVFRpdzRJY1ktOFF6MjZoODhQMFlYWmRHMHJrWGxw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 02:44:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ambedkar row: Congress's countrywide protest today seeking Amit Shah's resignation - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Protests Nationwide for Amit Shah's Resignation Over Ambedkar Remarks</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> December 19, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/amit_shah_ambedkar_remarks_1734571985214_1734571985413.jpg" alt="Protest against Amit Shah's remarks" title="Protest against Amit Shah's remarks"> <figcaption>LoP in the Rajya Sabha Mallikarjun Kharge and LoP in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi take part in a protest of opposition MPs demanding Union Home Minister Amit Shah's apology for his remarks which they claimed were an insult to BR. Ambedkar, during the Winter session of Parliament, in New Delhi, Wednesday, Dec. 18, 2024. (PTI)</figcaption> <p>The Congress has initiated a countrywide protest demanding the resignation of Union Home Minister Amit Shah following his controversial remarks about BR Ambedkar made during a session of Parliament.</p> <ul> <li>The protests are organized across state and district headquarters nationwide.</li> <li>Amit Shah’s comments about Congress leaders and Ambedkar provoked a significant political backlash.</li> <li>The opposition, including Congress, has collectively called for his resignation, claiming it insults Ambedkar's legacy.</li> <li>PM Narendra Modi defended Shah, stating the Congress has a history of seeking to tarnish Ambedkar's legacy.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“If they had taken God's name so many times, they would have got a place in heaven.” - Amit Shah</blockquote> <p>The protests reflect deep-rooted tensions between the opposition and ruling party, centering on the respect for Ambedkar's contributions to Indian democracy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ambedkar-row-congresss-countrywide-protest-today-seeking-amit-shahs-resignation-101734570714441.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ambedkar-row-congresss-countrywide-protest-today-seeking-amit-shahs-resignation-101734570714441.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:51:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli, Rohit Sharma Contradict On Ashwin's Retirement Plan, Confusion Erupts - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kohli and Rohit Dispute Details of Ashwin's Sudden Retirement Announcement</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 18 December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ekl6e10g_r-ashwin-afp_625x300_18_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Virat Kohli, Rohit Sharma Contradict On Ashwin's Retirement Plan, Confusion Erupts" /><figcaption>Virat Kohli, Rohit Sharma Contradict On Ashwin's Retirement Plan, Confusion Erupts</figcaption><p>Ravichandran Ashwin announced his retirement from international cricket during the ongoing India vs Australia series, leading to confusion over when he made the decision. Kohli and Rohit gave differing accounts, leaving supporters wondering about Ashwin's true intentions.</p><ul><li>Ashwin announced his retirement with two Tests remaining in the series.</li><li>Kohli claimed he learned about the retirement on the same day Ashwin announced it.</li><li>Rohit stated he was aware of Ashwin’s retirement thoughts beforehand.</li><li>Different reports suggest Ashwin had been contemplating retirement since earlier in the series.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’ve played with you for 14 years and when you told me today you're retiring, it made me a bit emotional,” - Virat Kohli.</blockquote><p>It remains unclear when exactly Ashwin decided to retire, with various reports complicating the narrative.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/when-did-ravichandran-ashwin-decide-to-retire-contradictory-reports-statements-lead-to-confusion-7279791</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/when-did-ravichandran-ashwin-decide-to-retire-contradictory-reports-statements-lead-to-confusion-7279791</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:48:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's alleged drug abuse will barr him from entering certain SpaceX buildings: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk's Alleged Drug Use Affects Security Clearance at SpaceX</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/-RAMASWAMY-VISIT-CAPITOL-HIL_1733939387392_1734571577906.jpg" alt="Reports indicate Musk's executives caution against higher security clearances due to risks of revocation linked to his lifestyle.(Getty Images via AFP)" title="Reports indicate Musk's executives caution against higher security clearances due to risks of revocation linked to his lifestyle.(Getty Images via AFP)"><figcaption>Reports indicate Musk's executives caution against higher security clearances due to risks of revocation linked to his lifestyle.(Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption><p>Elon Musk's executives have advised him against applying for higher security clearances due to concerns related to drug use allegations and foreign connections, which could lead to his current clearance being revoked.</p><ul><li>Musk’s security clearance status is currently “top secret,” allowing partial access to government-related projects.</li><li>Concerns have been raised regarding Musk’s lifestyle and substance use, particularly connections with foreign figures like Vladimir Putin.</li><li>SpaceX has denied allegations regarding Musk’s connections to Putin and any substance use.</li><li>Musk’s clearance allows access to certain Department of Defense facilities, but restricts him from viewing sensitive information.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Most of the stuff that I’m aware of...the reason to keep it top secret is it’s so boring.” - Elon Musk</p></blockquote><p>The implications of these allegations could impact Musk’s access to crucial security information and potential government projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/elon-musks-alleged-drug-abuse-will-barr-him-from-entering-certain-spacex-buildings-report-101734570235065.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/elon-musks-alleged-drug-abuse-will-barr-him-from-entering-certain-spacex-buildings-report-101734570235065.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:47:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uncertain Future, Knee Struggle, Family's Advice: Behind R Ashwin's Last-Minute Retirement Call - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxPeUYwdXJkUGN6X19wOGJoWHppZGF1R21ockdnQm95SFFLdERneVpvaXU1UTZ3cHJZaHlrZUtZMGNTd2ZfMi15QV8xZnRFYld1N0EwLVljLVBKTFdGdEgtTThEWTM4WE1EV1BBMGJqMk5sSEp6RkNIVWk1cFgxU2hBUGJCQnhuM3FfWnhlRld6U3RxLU5ZYWtaUmhSOExOdnl2a2taZGlJWllXZ2tua2hWMHZZMnVyYjhXYzF6MkxFWlkybXgtQy1OOXJB0gHSAUFVX3lxTE5PNnhhVlBVZXJ1RmFMclJPcEFWRzdtaHJDWlgwb0h2eHpzU3hURWZ3aVZEZWZYaWFxaUR0ckpwdFp3MmtuYTE1QWR0cnR0eGhLZm85clYwcThqdVFrdEJSVXVLZU5GaXNjWHVWUHg4VHNuQXJWZGRLWUJFOHZIN08waEF6alBIUHV4RTlsRVFYMTBEUXpCM2hGY1dGT3U1eFVLVHhGOFJzazVDQi1EN3VjWjZlNmR1Ykg0Znk4dFIwM0dfTEJYajh1a2RncHVtRzNIdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxPeUYwdXJkUGN6X19wOGJoWHppZGF1R21ockdnQm95SFFLdERneVpvaXU1UTZ3cHJZaHlrZUtZMGNTd2ZfMi15QV8xZnRFYld1N0EwLVljLVBKTFdGdEgtTThEWTM4WE1EV1BBMGJqMk5sSEp6RkNIVWk1cFgxU2hBUGJCQnhuM3FfWnhlRld6U3RxLU5ZYWtaUmhSOExOdnl2a2taZGlJWllXZ2tua2hWMHZZMnVyYjhXYzF6MkxFWlkybXgtQy1OOXJB0gHSAUFVX3lxTE5PNnhhVlBVZXJ1RmFMclJPcEFWRzdtaHJDWlgwb0h2eHpzU3hURWZ3aVZEZWZYaWFxaUR0ckpwdFp3MmtuYTE1QWR0cnR0eGhLZm85clYwcThqdVFrdEJSVXVLZU5GaXNjWHVWUHg4VHNuQXJWZGRLWUJFOHZIN08waEF6alBIUHV4RTlsRVFYMTBEUXpCM2hGY1dGT3U1eFVLVHhGOFJzazVDQi1EN3VjWjZlNmR1Ykg0Znk4dFIwM0dfTEJYajh1a2RncHVtRzNIdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:45:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J&K: 'Mystery' illness grips Rajouri village, toll at 8 as Govt calls in experts - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mystery Illness Claims 8 Lives in Rajouri Village, J&K Government Calls in Experts</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/ga68d647a6c6f1152d9d92f49943fd5ab_1734570970806_1734570971029.jpg" alt="Efforts are being made to understand the exact kind of illness that has been spreading. (Representative Image)"><figcaption>Efforts are being made to understand the exact kind of illness that has been spreading. (Representative Image)</figcaption><p>A mysterious illness has struck Badhaal village in Rajouri district, Jammu and Kashmir, resulting in eight fatalities, mostly children. Authorities have deployed a central team of experts and a mobile laboratory to investigate the cause of the illness.</p><ul><li>The death toll has risen to eight, with victims primarily from two families in Badhaal village.</li><li>A mobile laboratory (BSL-3) has been sent to expedite testing of the illness.</li><li>The latest victim was a 12-year-old boy who succumbed after being hospitalized for six days.</li><li>Past cases include the deaths of two of his younger siblings.</li></ul><blockquote>"In response to the incident, a Biosafety Level 3 (BSL-3) mobile laboratory has been sent to Rajouri," said a government spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the urgency of identifying the illness to prevent further cases, ensuring community safety and health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jk-mystery-illness-grips-rajouri-village-toll-at-8-as-govt-calls-in-experts-101734570436170.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jk-mystery-illness-grips-rajouri-village-toll-at-8-as-govt-calls-in-experts-101734570436170.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:33:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market today: Trade setup for Nifty 50 to US Fed meeting outcome; 5 stocks to buy or sell on Thursday — Dec 19 | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stock-market-today-trade-setup-for-nifty-50-to-us-fed-meeting-outcome-5-stocks-to-buy-or-sell-on-thursday-dec-19-11734541708138.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stock-market-today-trade-setup-for-nifty-50-to-us-fed-meeting-outcome-5-stocks-to-buy-or-sell-on-thursday-dec-19-11734541708138.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:08:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi wakes up to fog, nearly severe-plus AQI; cold wave in parts of Karnataka | Weather updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi wakes up to fog, nearly severe-plus AQI; cold wave in parts of Karnataka</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/delhi_weather_aqi_fog__1734569459395_1734569459657.jpg" alt="Noida, India- December 18, 2024: Commuters step out in foggy winter cold morning amid rising air pollution." title="Noida, India- December 18, 2024: Commuters step out in foggy winter cold morning amid rising air pollution."><figcaption>Noida, India- December 18, 2024: Commuters step out in foggy winter cold morning amid rising air pollution. Air pollution level in Delhi-NCR remain in the 'poor' category, in Noida, India, on Wednesday, December 18, 2024. (Photo by Sunil Ghosh / Hindustan Times)</figcaption></figure><p>On December 19, 2024, Delhi reported a dangerously high Air Quality Index (AQI) of 448, nearing the severe-plus category, as cold weather and dense fog enveloped the region.</p><ul><li><strong>AQI Levels:</strong> The overall AQI in various parts of Delhi is classified as 'very poor' to 'severe-plus' with 21 monitoring stations recording alarming levels.</li><li><strong>Cold Wave Conditions:</strong> Cold wave effects are being felt across large parts of northern India, including Himachal Pradesh and Jammu & Kashmir, where temperatures dropped below freezing.</li></ul><blockquote>"Delhi's AQI remains critically high, with many localities suffering from extreme pollution levels."</blockquote><p>The effects of both severe air pollution and cold weather are impacting daily life in the region, requiring urgent attention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-fog-air-quality-aqi-today-karnataka-bengaluru-weather-in-kashmir-imd-101734566195194.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-fog-air-quality-aqi-today-karnataka-bengaluru-weather-in-kashmir-imd-101734566195194.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:03:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravichandran Ashwin contradicts Rohit Sharma shortly after retirement; 'unusual' behaviour irks India legend - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravichandran Ashwin Contradicts Rohit Sharma Post Retirement Amid Controversy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 19, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/ANI-20241218424-0_1734548275303_1734548283683.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma (L) and Ravichandran Ashwin shared some unforgettable moments addressing the press conference(ANI)" title="Rohit Sharma (L) and Ravichandran Ashwin shared some unforgettable moments addressing the press conference(ANI)"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma (L) and Ravichandran Ashwin shared some unforgettable moments addressing the press conference(ANI)</figcaption></figure><p>In a surprising turn of events, Ravichandran Ashwin left for India after announcing his retirement, contradicting statements made by captain Rohit Sharma regarding his departure.</p><ul><li>Ashwin announced his retirement after the third Test against Australia in Brisbane, becoming India's second-highest wicket-taker in Tests.</li><li>Rohit Sharma initially stated Ashwin would depart following a day of the announcement, but Ashwin chose to leave immediately.</li><li>Sunil Gavaskar expressed concern over Ashwin's mid-tour exit, citing potential issues with team dynamics and planning for upcoming matches.</li></ul><blockquote>“At the end of the day, the person himself knows whether he's got it in him. You could possibly have the ability; it may still be there. But mentally, you may not want to be in the battle.” - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote><p>Ashwin's abrupt decision to leave has raised questions about player commitments during international tours and the impact on team strategy moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ravichandran-ashwin-contradicts-rohit-sharma-after-retirement-unusual-behaviour-irks-india-legend-sunil-gavaskar-101734548033373.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ravichandran-ashwin-contradicts-rohit-sharma-after-retirement-unusual-behaviour-irks-india-legend-sunil-gavaskar-101734548033373.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:39:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BR Ambedkar's grandson takes aim at Amit Shah on remarks: ‘Same old mentality’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BR Ambedkar's grandson takes aim at Amit Shah on remarks: ‘Same old mentality’</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> HT News</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/ANI-20241120404-0_1734567636171_1734567703333.jpg" alt="Vanchit Bahujan Aghadi President Prakash Ambedkar and his wife after voting" title="Vanchit Bahujan Aghadi President Prakash Ambedkar and his wife after voting">
<figcaption>FILE: Vanchit Bahujan Aghadi (VBA) President Prakash Ambedkar and his wife Anjali Maydeo show their ink-marked fingers after casting their votes for Maharashtra Assembly Elections, in Akola.(ANI)</figcaption>
<p>Prakash Ambedkar, the grandson of Dr. BR Ambedkar, criticized Home Minister Amit Shah's remarks regarding Dr. Ambedkar, suggesting they highlight the BJP's outdated mentality.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Prakash Ambedkar claimed that the BJP’s inability to achieve its goals is due to Dr. Ambedkar's influence.</li>
  <li>He stated Shah’s comments reflect a deep-rooted mentality within the BJP and accused them of not being able to implement their agenda due to opposition from Dr. Ambedkar's ideals.</li>
  <li>Several opposition MPs protested in Parliament against Shah’s remarks, calling them an insult to Dr. Ambedkar.</li>
  <li>Amit Shah suggested that the frequent mention of Ambedkar has become fashionable among opponents, implying a diminished respect for him.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"There is nothing new in the statement. They are not able to execute their old plans. Not because of Congress, but because of Babasaheb Ambedkar."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Prakash Ambedkar's comments not only criticize Shah's remarks but also express concern over political trends and their implications on democracy and governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/br-ambedkar-grandson-prakash-ambedkar-amit-shah-remarks-same-old-mentality-101734566806370.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/br-ambedkar-grandson-prakash-ambedkar-amit-shah-remarks-same-old-mentality-101734566806370.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:36:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 box office collection day 14 [updated live]: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna’s film hits Rs 973 - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 box office collection day 14 [updated live]</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Updated on day 14<br><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna’s film 'Pushpa 2' is performing exceptionally well, currently standing at Rs 973.2 crore as it heads towards the coveted Rs 1000 crore club.</p><ol><li>The film has crossed Rs 973.2 crore by its second Wednesday.</li><li>Viewers are eagerly anticipating the film's push to reach the Rs 1000 crore mark.</li><li>The film's popularity continues to grow as it reflects strong audience engagement.</li></ol><blockquote>"Pushpa 2 is on the verge of making box office history with its current collections."</blockquote><p>The film's performance suggests a strong cultural impact, resonating well with audiences and setting records in the film industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-14-updated-live-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandannas-film-hits-rs-973-2-cr-on-its-2nd-wednesday-heads-strongly-toward-the-rs1000-crore-club/articleshow/116453792.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-14-updated-live-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandannas-film-hits-rs-973-2-cr-on-its-2nd-wednesday-heads-strongly-toward-the-rs1000-crore-club/articleshow/116453792.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Morgan Stanley no longer sees Jan rate cut after hawkish Fed meeting - Investing.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Morgan Stanley no longer sees Jan rate cut after hawkish Fed meeting</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Investing.com</p><p>Morgan Stanley has revised its expectations regarding the Federal Reserve's interest rate cuts, indicating a more cautious approach due to ongoing inflation concerns.</p><ul><li>Morgan Stanley analysts now predict no 25 basis point cut in January 2025.</li><li>Expected future cuts are now projected for March and June 2025.</li><li>The Fed's hawkish tone reflects worries about inflation and economic policy changes.</li><li>Goldman Sachs has similarly adjusted its forecasts regarding interest rate cuts.</li><li>Traders are increasingly betting on a hold in January with a 91.1% probability.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Fed's hawkish turn appeared to reflect the incorporation of potential changes to trade, immigration, and fiscal policy by some members that led to a firmer inflation path and, in turn, a firmer policy rate path,” - Morgan Stanley analysts.</blockquote><p>The recent revisions from Morgan Stanley indicate a shift in how analysts view the Fed's monetary policy in light of economic growth and labor market conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.investing.com/news/economy/morgan-stanley-no-longer-sees-jan-rate-cut-after-hawkish-fed-meeting-3780810</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.investing.com/news/economy/morgan-stanley-no-longer-sees-jan-rate-cut-after-hawkish-fed-meeting-3780810</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:25:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun's Father Meets Stampede Victim's Husband, Visits Injured Son In Hospital - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun's Father Visits Injured Son in Hospital After Stampede Incident</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Allu Arjun's father visited the hospital to take stock of the child injured in the stampede." /><figcaption>Allu Arjun's father visited the hospital to take stock of the child injured in the stampede.</figcaption><p>Allu Arjun’s father, Allu Aravind, visited a Hyderabad hospital to check on a child injured during a stampede at the screening of Pushpa 2: The Rule. He also met with the family of a woman who tragically lost her life during the incident.</p><ul><li>Allu Arjun's father visited the injured child's hospital.</li><li>Health Secretary and Police Commissioner provided updates on the child's condition.</li><li>The child suffered brain damage; currently on ventilator support.</li><li>The stampede occurred on December 4, resulting in tragedy.</li><li>Allu Arjun was arrested related to the case but was granted bail.</li></ul><blockquote>“I remain deeply concerned about young Sri Tej, who is under constant medical care after the unfortunate incident.” - Allu Arjun</blockquote><p>This incident raises concerns about crowd control at events and the safety of attendees.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjun-father-meets-stampede-victims-husband-visits-injured-son-in-hospital-9160522.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjun-father-meets-stampede-victims-husband-visits-injured-son-in-hospital-9160522.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chalet’s next 1,000: acquisitions, new builds to fuel hotel chain’s aggressive expansion | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chalet’s next 1,000: acquisitions, new builds to fuel hotel chain’s aggressive expansion</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Chalet Hotels Ltd aims to add 1,000 rooms in major Indian cities by expanding its hotel capacity by approximately one-third, utilizing acquisitions alongside new builds.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The hotel chain is backed by K Raheja Corp. and owns notable properties like JW Marriott in Mumbai.</li>
  <li>Managing Director Sanjay Sethi announced plans to finance the expansion through internal funds.</li>
  <li>The focus will be on metro cities, catering to the growing demand in the hospitality sector.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We are looking to expand our portfolio aggressively in the coming years.” – Sanjay Sethi</blockquote>
<p>This expansion reflects the company's strategy to enhance its market position amidst a competitive hospitality landscape in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/chalets-next-1-000-acquisitions-new-builds-to-fuel-hotel-chain-s-aggressive-expansion-11734509283866.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/chalets-next-1-000-acquisitions-new-builds-to-fuel-hotel-chain-s-aggressive-expansion-11734509283866.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microplastics in the air may be leading to lung and colon cancers - Science Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>chrome-error://chromewebdata/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">chrome-error://chromewebdata/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 23:32:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT ‘Strands’ Hints, Spangram And Answers For Thursday, December 19 - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NYT Strands Hints and Answers for December 19</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 19, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Forbes</p>
<img src="https://specials-images.forbesimg.com/imageserve/662d382eeb3d71d37bfd28a8/strands-lead/960x0.png?fit=scale" alt="strands lead">
<figcaption>Strands Hint from NYT</figcaption>
<p><em>Looking for Thursday’s Strands hints, spangram, and answers? You can find them here:</em></p>
<h2><strong>How To Play Strands</strong></h2>
<p>The New York Times’ <em>Strands</em> puzzle is a play on the classic word search, presented in a 6x8 grid of letters with a themed clue that you must uncover.</p>
<h2><strong>What Is Today’s Strands Hint?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Roll with It</strong><br><strong>My hint is:</strong> <strong>Playing the classics</strong></p>
<h2><strong>What Are Today’s Strands Answers?</strong></h2>
<p>Today's spangram is:</p>
<p><strong>ROCKING</strong></p>
<p>And the answer list is:</p>
<ul>
  <li>METAL</li>
  <li>PROGRESSIVE</li>
  <li>GLAM</li>
  <li>ALTERNATIVE</li>
  <li>GRUNGE</li>
  <li>PUNK</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The NYT Strands puzzle continues to engage players with its thematic word search, testing their knowledge of music genres.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/12/18/nyt-strands-hints-spangram-and-answers-for-thursday-december-19-roll-with-it/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/12/18/nyt-strands-hints-spangram-and-answers-for-thursday-december-19-roll-with-it/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 23:30:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fed lowers rates but sees fewer cuts next year due to stubbornly high inflation By Reuters - Investing.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fed lowers rates but sees fewer cuts next year due to stubbornly high inflation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> WASHINGTON <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><p>The U.S. central bank has cut interest rates as expected, but future cuts depend on progress in addressing persistent inflation issues. Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell emphasized a cautious approach moving forward, impacting market expectations.</p><ul><li>The Fed cut the benchmark interest rate by a quarter percentage point.</li><li>Future rate cuts will be limited due to ongoing inflation concerns, particularly in housing.</li><li>Officials project that core inflation will remain above the Fed's target of 2% through 2025.</li><li>Only one 25-basis-point cut is currently reflected in market estimates for next year.</li><li>The economic outlook is clouded by potential changes from the incoming Trump administration.</li></ul><blockquote>"I think we're in a good place, but I think from here it's a new phase and we're going to be cautious about further cuts," said Jerome Powell.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while the Fed remains optimistic about economic growth, the interplay between monetary policy and potential new government policies will influence future rate decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.investing.com/news/economy-news/fed-expected-to-combine-interest-rate-cut-with-hawkish-2025-outlook-3778566</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.investing.com/news/economy-news/fed-expected-to-combine-interest-rate-cut-with-hawkish-2025-outlook-3778566</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 22:54:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India, China agree on peace roadmap, six-point consensus to boost ties - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India, China agree on peace roadmap, six-point consensus to boost ties</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>This article discusses the agreement between India and China to establish a roadmap for peace and a six-point consensus aimed at strengthening their bilateral relations.</p><ul><li>The six-point consensus includes commitments to peace, stability, and cooperation.</li><li>Both countries aim to enhance trade and investments while addressing border issues.</li><li>Leadership from both nations emphasizes mutual respect and understanding.</li><li>The agreement aims to defuse tensions that have existed between the two countries.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is a significant step towards improving diplomatic relations between India and China."</blockquote><p>The conclusion highlights that this consensus could pave the way for further dialogues and cooperation between the nations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-china-agree-on-peace-roadmap-six-point-consensus-to-boost-ties/articleshow/116449755.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-china-agree-on-peace-roadmap-six-point-consensus-to-boost-ties/articleshow/116449755.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US stocks tumble as Federal Reserve eyes fewer 2025 rate cuts, Dow falls 2.6% - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/us-stocks-tumble-as-federal-reserve-eyes-fewer-2025-rate-cuts-dow-26-101734556062116.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/us-stocks-tumble-as-federal-reserve-eyes-fewer-2025-rate-cuts-dow-26-101734556062116.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:13:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp users can now interact with ChatGPT AI chatbot. Here's how - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp Now Allows User Interaction with ChatGPT AI Chatbot</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/Screenshot_2024-12-19_022136_1734555130307_1734555142582.png" alt="The new WhatsApp account will help more users try ChatGPT through a familiar platform. (Pic used for representation)(PA_Media)" title="The new WhatsApp account will help more users try ChatGPT through a familiar platform. (Pic used for representation)(PA_Media)"><figcaption>The new WhatsApp account will help more users try ChatGPT through a familiar platform. (Pic used for representation)(PA_Media)</figcaption><p>WhatsApp users can now directly message ChatGPT for answers or creative help with projects, following an update that gives the chatbot its own contact number on the platform.</p><ul><li>OpenAI announced that anyone globally can message ChatGPT using the new phone number, 1-800-242-8478.</li><li>Meta recently introduced several new features for WhatsApp, including a new Typing Indicator for enhanced messaging experience.</li><li>WhatsApp will discontinue support for iOS versions earlier than 15.1 after May 2025.</li><li>Users can ask ChatGPT questions and receive assistance in creative writing, project planning, recommendations, and general conversations.</li><li>This feature aims to expand ChatGPT's user base as OpenAI addresses growing operational costs.</li></ul><blockquote>OpenAI stated that while the WhatsApp version of ChatGPT can be helpful, it is still an experimental feature.</blockquote><p>This new integration offers a familiar platform for users to interact with AI, enhancing accessibility and engagement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/whatsapp-users-can-now-interact-with-chatgpt-ai-chatbot-heres-how-101734551003770.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/whatsapp-users-can-now-interact-with-chatgpt-ai-chatbot-heres-how-101734551003770.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:05:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[​Airborne microplastic can lead to lung and colon cancers, says study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Study Finds Airborne Microplastic May Contribute to Lung and Colon Cancers</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This article discusses recent research linking airborne microplastics to an increased risk of lung and colon cancers, highlighting significant health implications.</p><ul><li>The study finds a correlation between airborne microplastics and cancer rates.</li><li>Research indicates that inhaling or ingesting microplastics may cause cellular damage leading to cancer.</li><li>Microplastics are ubiquitous in the environment, raising public health concerns.</li></ul><blockquote>“The persistent presence of microplastics in our air and food supply can have dire consequences for public health.”</blockquote><p>This study raises awareness about the hidden dangers of microplastics and underscores the need for stricter regulations and further research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/airborne-microplastic-can-lead-to-lung-and-colon-cancers-says-study/articleshow/116449675.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/airborne-microplastic-can-lead-to-lung-and-colon-cancers-says-study/articleshow/116449675.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Will continue to act against proliferation': US slaps sanctions on Pakistan over Ballistic Missile Progr - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Imposes Sanctions on Pakistan for Ballistic Missile Program</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br /><strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>This article discusses the recent sanctions imposed by the United States on Pakistan due to its ballistic missile program, reflecting the US's commitment to combat proliferation.</p><ul><li>The US Department of State announced sanctions against Pakistan.</li><li>This decision is based on concerns regarding Pakistan's ballistic missile development activities.</li><li>The sanctions are a part of broader efforts to prevent proliferation of missile technology.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will continue to act against proliferation, ensuring that no nation develops capability that threatens global security.”</blockquote><p>The sanctions showcase the US government's ongoing strategy to deter missile proliferation globally and hold responsible nations accountable.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/united-states-will-continue-to-act-against-proliferation-us-slaps-sanctions-on-pakistan-over-ballistic-missile-programme/articleshow/116449626.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/united-states-will-continue-to-act-against-proliferation-us-slaps-sanctions-on-pakistan-over-ballistic-missile-programme/articleshow/116449626.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 20:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mallya takes jibe at Finance Minister over claim of ₹14,000 crore debt recovery - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mallya Challenges Finance Minister on Debt Recovery Claims</h1><p><strong>Published: December 19, 2024 02:10 am IST | Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/b0ijrb/article69001803.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-07-26T140113Z_899243339_RC2139AVCK57_RTRMADP_3_INDIA-REGULATOR-VIJAY-MALLYA.JPG" alt="Vijay Mallya puts up post on social media saying this amount was more than twice the debt adjudicated by courts." title="Vijay Mallya puts up post on social media saying this amount was more than twice the debt adjudicated by courts."><figcaption>Vijay Mallya puts up post on social media saying this amount was more than twice the debt adjudicated by courts. | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>Vijay Mallya has publicly confronted Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman regarding her claims of asset recovery, highlighting a significant discrepancy between announced recovery amounts and the adjudicated debts.</p><ul><li>Mallya disputes the Finance Minister's statement that ₹14,131.6 crore has been recovered from him.</li><li>He asserts that this recovery amount exceeds the debt adjudicated by courts, which was ₹6203 crore.</li><li>The controversy arises from the government's ongoing efforts to combat financial crime as Mallya remains a fugitive from justice.</li><li>The Finance Minister noted significant recoveries from other figures involved in financial misconduct, including Nirav Modi and Mehul Choksi.</li></ul><blockquote>“The FM announced in Parliament that through the ED, Banks have recovered ₹14,131.60 crore from me against the judgement debt of ₹6203 crore and I am still an economic offender.” - Vijay Mallya</blockquote><p>This confrontation raises questions about the legal justification of asset recovery and its implications for Mallya's status as an economic offender.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/mallya-takes-jibe-at-finance-minister-over-claim-of-14000-crore-debt-recovery/article69001725.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/mallya-takes-jibe-at-finance-minister-over-claim-of-14000-crore-debt-recovery/article69001725.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 20:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mamta Kulkarni: 'Yes, it is true that I was with Vicky Goswami and will always love him' - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mamta Kulkarni: 'Yes, it is true that I was with Vicky Goswami and will always love him'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown<br><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p>
<p>Mamta Kulkarni has publicly confirmed her feelings for Vicky Goswami, expressing her enduring love for him.</p>
<ul>
<li>Mamta Kulkarni acknowledges her long-term relationship with Vicky Goswami.</li>
<li>She emphasizes that her love for him is genuine and persistent.</li>
<li>The article delves into the couple's past and public perceptions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Yes, it is true that I was with Vicky Goswami and will always love him."</blockquote>
<p>This revelation highlights the complexities of their relationship and public interest in the couple.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mamta-kulkarni-yes-it-is-true-that-i-was-with-vicky-goswami-and-will-always-love-him/articleshow/116449570.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/mamta-kulkarni-yes-it-is-true-that-i-was-with-vicky-goswami-and-will-always-love-him/articleshow/116449570.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 20:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus officially confirms big battery for the OnePlus 13R, new color for the Buds Pro 3 - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus Announces Big Battery for OnePlus 13R and New Color for Buds Pro 3</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> GSM Arena</p>
<img src="https://fdn.gsmarena.com/imgroot/news/24/12/oneplus-13r-details/-1200/gsmarena_000.jpg" alt="OnePlus 13 (left), OnePlus 13R (center), OnePlus Buds Pro 3 in Sapphire Blue (right)"><figcaption>OnePlus 13 (left), OnePlus 13R (center), OnePlus Buds Pro 3 in Sapphire Blue (right)</figcaption>
<p>OnePlus is set to reveal the new OnePlus 13 and 13R on January 7, with the latter featuring a significant battery capacity.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The OnePlus 13R will have a 6,000 mAh battery, matching the flagship OnePlus 13.</li>
  <li>It will feature a flat screen with Gorilla Glass 7i and an aluminum frame.</li>
  <li>The phone will be available in two colors: Nebula Noir and Astral Trail.</li>
  <li>Additionally, the OnePlus Buds Pro 3 will receive a new Sapphire Blue color variant.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The 13R will have a 6,000 mAh battery, matching the capacity of the flagship OnePlus 13.”</blockquote>
<p>This launch promises to enhance OnePlus's presence in the competitive smartphone market, showcasing advanced features and design.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gsmarena.com/oneplus_officially_confirms_big_battery_for_the_oneplus_13r_new_color_for_buds_pro_3-news-65788.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gsmarena.com/oneplus_officially_confirms_big_battery_for_the_oneplus_13r_new_color_for_buds_pro_3-news-65788.php</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 20:27:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real Madrid 3-0 Pachuca (18 Dec, 2024) Game Analysis - ESPN India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Real Madrid 3-0 Pachuca (18 Dec, 2024) Game Analysis</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 18 Dec, 2024 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN (IN)</p><p>Real Madrid won the Intercontinental Cup after defeating Pachuca 3-0 in a dominant performance at the Lusail Stadium in Qatar, securing their ninth global title.</p><ul><li>Real Madrid scored three goals, with Kylian Mbappé, Rodrygo, and Vinícius Júnior finding the net.</li><li>The match showcased Madrid's control despite Pachuca's attempts at counter-attacks.</li><li>Vinícius assisted Mbappé's opening goal before Rodrygo's stunning second.</li><li>Vinícius completed the scoring with a penalty in the 83rd minute.</li><li>Carlo Ancelotti set a record as Madrid's most decorated coach following the win.</li></ul><blockquote>"I'm happy with today's game, and with [winning The Best] yesterday, which was very special," Vinicius said.</blockquote><p>This victory adds another trophy to Real Madrid's storied history and emphasizes their dominance in international competitions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espn.in/football/report/_/gameId/721442</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espn.in/football/report/_/gameId/721442</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 19:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foreigners’ entry restricted in Manipur, Mizoram, Nagaland - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Foreigners’ Entry Restricted in Manipur, Mizoram, Nagaland</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> December 19, 2024 - <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/latest-news/akbvmo/article68997620.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/Manipur.jpg" alt="Security forces personnel during search operations in Manipur" title="Security forces personnel during search operations and area domination in the fringe and vulnerable areas of hill and valley districts of Manipur. File"><figcaption>Security forces personnel during search operations and area domination in the fringe and vulnerable areas of hill and valley districts of Manipur. File | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>The Union Home Ministry has reimposed the Protected Area Regime (PAR) in Manipur, Nagaland, and Mizoram due to security concerns regarding the influx of foreigners from neighboring countries.</p><ul><li>Foreigners now require prior permission and special permits to visit these states.</li><li>The relaxation of the PAR, previously in effect for 14 years, has been revoked.</li><li>The Ministry emphasized that visits to protected areas should only occur for extraordinary reasons.</li><li>The new directive was issued to the Chief Secretaries of the respective states.</li><li>Over 250 people have died, and more than 60,000 have been displaced due to recent ethnic violence in Manipur.</li></ul><blockquote>“The people of Manipur are urged to exercise caution and not to pay heed to statements or claims from organisations of dubious origins.”</blockquote><p>The reimposition of the Protected Area Regime underlines the focus on closely monitoring foreign movements in these northeastern states amidst ongoing tensions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/foreigners-entry-restricted-in-manipur-mizoram-nagaland/article69001937.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/foreigners-entry-restricted-in-manipur-mizoram-nagaland/article69001937.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 19:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Matt Gaetz says he used to be a womanizer, sent money to many women but... - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Matt Gaetz Reflects on Past as a Womanizer and Financial Support to Women</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This article discusses Matt Gaetz's admission of his past behavior as a womanizer and his financial contributions to several women in his life. It reflects on his personal changes and current stance on relationships.</p><ul><li>Gaetz acknowledges his previous actions and the money he sent to women.</li><li>He expresses a desire to distance himself from his past behavior.</li><li>The article raises questions about accountability and personal growth.</li></ul><blockquote>“I used to be a womanizer,” Gaetz said.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Gaetz's candid reflections invite a discussion on the complexities of personal growth and public accountability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/matt-gaetz-says-he-used-to-be-a-womanizer-sent-money-to-many-women-but-/articleshow/116449084.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/matt-gaetz-says-he-used-to-be-a-womanizer-sent-money-to-many-women-but-/articleshow/116449084.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 19:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Severe Malaria Identified as Cause of Outbreak in DRC's Kwango Province - Contagionlive.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Severe Malaria Identified as Cause of Outbreak in DRC's Kwango Province</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 18, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p>
<img src="https://cdn.sanity.io/images/0vv8moc6/contagion/691dbad8ac02f83d5707ff1db9c2e5e5a28dd3c8-852x850.png?fit=crop&amp;auto=format" alt="Southwestern Kwango Province" />
<figcaption>The Southwestern Kwango Province is outlined in red. Image credits: Google Maps</figcaption>
<p>A severe malaria outbreak in Kwango Province, DRC has resulted in 143 deaths and 592 confirmed cases. Issues surrounding treatment access, drug resistance, and malnutrition complicate the situation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The outbreak started in late October in the Panzi health zone.</li>
  <li>Case-fatality rate stands at 6.2% with symptoms like fever, headache, and cough.</li>
  <li>Malnutrition and low vaccination rates exacerbate the health crisis.</li>
  <li>Injectable artesunate is the recommended treatment, but access in rural areas is problematic.</li>
  <li>Concerns about artemisinin resistance have been raised in affected children.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"If untreated, severe malaria can progress rapidly and lead to death within hours or days."</blockquote>
<p>This outbreak underscores the dire need for improved healthcare infrastructure and access to treatments in rural areas facing malaria.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.contagionlive.com/view/severe-malaria-identified-as-cause-of-outbreak-in-drc-s-kwango-province</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.contagionlive.com/view/severe-malaria-identified-as-cause-of-outbreak-in-drc-s-kwango-province</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 19:20:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uzbek man confessed to killing Gen on orders of Ukraine's SBU: Russia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Uzbek Man Confesses to Killing General on Orders from Ukraine's SBU</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Russia Today</p><p>In a shocking revelation, an Uzbek man has confessed to committing a murder on the orders of Ukraine's Security Service (SBU). This event has sparked discussions on the complexities surrounding the ongoing geopolitical tensions.</p><ul><li>The suspect claims to have received direct orders from the SBU.</li><li>The murder involved a high-ranking military official.</li><li>This confession raises questions about Ukraine's involvement in covert operations.</li></ul><blockquote>"This incident highlights the intricate web of espionage and political maneuvering in the region."</blockquote><p>The situation presents significant implications for diplomatic relations and military strategies in Eastern Europe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/uzbek-man-confessed-to-killing-gen-on-orders-of-ukraines-sbu-russia/articleshow/116448946.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/uzbek-man-confessed-to-killing-gen-on-orders-of-ukraines-sbu-russia/articleshow/116448946.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 19:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>