<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 03:21:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 03:21:11 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Always poses a challenge': Pat Cummins praises Jasprit Bumrah ahead of Sydney Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pat Cummins Praises Jasprit Bumrah Ahead of Sydney Test</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 3, 2023<br>Source: Times of India</strong></p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116868443,imgsize-164786,width-400,resizemode-4/116868443.jpg" alt="Pat Cummins and Jasprit Bumrah" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Pat Cummins of Australia and Jasprit Bumrah of India. (Photo by Paul Kane/Getty Images)</figcaption>
<p>Australia captain Pat Cummins has heaped praise on India’s pace spearhead Jasprit Bumrah, acknowledging his exceptional form and consistent ability to trouble batters across all formats. Speaking ahead of the fifth and final Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy at the Sydney Cricket Ground, Cummins admitted that facing Bumrah is always a daunting task.</p>
<ol>
<li>Cummins praised Bumrah’s exceptional form and consistent ability to trouble batters.</li>
<li>Cummins admitted that facing Bumrah is always a daunting task.</li>
<li>Australia has the chance to secure the Border-Gavaskar Trophy and secure their place in the World Test Championship final with a win or draw in Sydney.</li>
<li>Australia has confirmed changes in their lineup, with Mitch Marsh dropped and Beau Webster set to make his debut.</li>
<li>Mitchell Starc has been retained despite carrying a rib niggle.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>"Bumrah is bowling well at the moment. He is always tough. Hopefully, by the time I come in, late in the day, he has bowled quite a bit, which might make it a bit easier for me. But he is bowling well. I’ve faced him quite a bit across the world in different formats, and he always poses a challenge."</blockquote>
<p>Cummins confirmed a few changes in Australia’s lineup, with all-rounder Mitch Marsh dropped following a string of underwhelming performances, and Beau Webster set to make his debut. Mitchell Starc has been retained despite carrying a rib niggle and will feature in the bowling attack alongside Cummins, Scott Boland, and Nathan Lyon.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/always-poses-a-challenge-pat-cummins-praises-jasprit-bumrah-ahead-of-sydney-test/articleshow/116868440.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/always-poses-a-challenge-pat-cummins-praises-jasprit-bumrah-ahead-of-sydney-test/articleshow/116868440.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Orleans truck attack: Joe Biden says FBI found ISIS-inspired Shamsud-Din Jabbar posted videos hours before rampage - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ISIS-Inspired Attack in New Orleans: President Biden Condemns Rampage, FBI Investigates</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source: </strong>January 1, 2025, Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/US-CRIME-ATTACK-39_1735782014412_1735782033303.jpg" alt="US President Joe Biden makes a statement about the terrorist attack in New Orleans from Camp David, Maryland, on January 1, 2025. (AFP)" title="US President Joe Biden makes a statement about the terrorist attack in New Orleans from Camp David, Maryland, on January 1, 2025. (AFP)"><figcaption>US President Joe Biden makes a statement about the terrorist attack in New Orleans from Camp David, Maryland, on January 1, 2025. (AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Introduction: A truck attack in New Orleans on New Year's Eve left at least 15 people dead and dozens injured, with the FBI linking the suspect to ISIS-inspiration.</p>
<ol>
<li>US Army veteran Shamsud-Din Jabbar, inspired by ISIS, drove a pickup truck into a crowd on Bourbon Street.</li>
<li>Jabbar posted videos hours before the attack, expressing his desire to kill.</li>
<li>President Joe Biden condemned the attack, offered condolences, and assured the public that the FBI is investigating.</li>
<li>The truck attack turned festive Bourbon Street into a macabre mayhem of maimed victims and fleeing pedestrians.</li>
<li>The FBI believes Jabbar was not solely responsible and is investigating potential associates and explosives found at the scene.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote><p>“This is not just an act of terrorism. This is evil.” - New Orleans Police superintendent Anne Kirkpatrick</p></blockquote>
<p>Conclusion: The FBI is actively investigating the New Orleans truck attack, treating it as an act of terrorism, with President Biden offering condolences to the victims and their families.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/new-orleans-truck-attack-joe-biden-says-fbi-found-isis-inspired-shamsud-din-jabbar-posted-videos-hours-before-rampage-101735779935489.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/new-orleans-truck-attack-joe-biden-says-fbi-found-isis-inspired-shamsud-din-jabbar-posted-videos-hours-before-rampage-101735779935489.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:42:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Tick: Here are the top global cues for today’s trade - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Tick: Here are the top global cues for today’s trade</h1><p><strong>Date: January 02, 2025</strong> / <strong>Source: Moneycontrol</strong></p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250101075910_bse_nse_stockmarket_nifty_sensex.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Market Today" title="Market Today" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Market Today</figcaption><p>The GIFT Nifty indicates a negative start for the day, with oil steady and gold having a significant annual gain since 2010.</p><ul><li>The Indian markets started the new year positively but are expected to open lower today.</li><li>Sensex ended January 1 up 368.40 points, while Nifty closed 98.10 points higher.</li><li>GIFT Nifty trading around 23,838 this morning.</li></ul><blockquote>“Hope you're all set for today's trade, we wish you a profitable day ahead.”</blockquote><p>Expectations are mixed as traders assess future monetary policies and global market conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/here-are-the-top-global-cues-for-today-s-trade-first-tick-6-12901584.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/here-are-the-top-global-cues-for-today-s-trade-first-tick-6-12901584.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:31:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jennifer Garner’s family 'wants' her back with ex Ben Affleck especially after… - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jennifer Garner's Family Hopes for Reunion with Ex-Husband Ben Affleck</h1><p><strong>Published on: Jan 02, 2025 06:57 AM IST</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/jennifer-garner-ben-affleck-c232a2398ae842d7a50801_1694922857283_1735781178768.jpg" alt="Ex-Couple Ben Affleck and Jennifer Garner(ASON MERRITT/GETTY)"><figcaption>Ex-Couple Ben Affleck and Jennifer Garner(ASON MERRITT/GETTY)</figcaption><p>Jennifer Garner's family is rooting for a reunion between the actress and her ex-husband Ben Affleck, as the former couple has been spending quality time together with their children, including during holidays. While Garner maintains a relationship with her current beau, John Miller, her family believes there's still chemistry between her and Affleck.</p><p>Garner and Affleck, who share three children, have been spotted together recently, fueling speculation about a possible reconciliation. The 'Gone Girl' star is currently going through a high-profile divorce from Jennifer Lopez.</p><ol><li>Garner's family is hoping for a reunion.</li<li>The former couple has been spending more time together.</li<li>Affleck's friends and family are supportive of a reunion.</li<li>Garner's current partner, John Miller, may feel like a 'third wheel.'</li></ol><blockquote>"Ben is laying it on thick, he’s giving Jen so much of himself and his attention and being so charming," a source told In Touch. "It’s very hard not to love him when he’s acting this way, and a lot of people are predicting that they could end up back together."</blockquote><p>While there's no confirmation of a reunion, Garner's family and friends are optimistic about the possibility of the former couple getting back together.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jennifer-garner-s-family-wants-her-back-with-ex-ben-affleck-especially-after-101735780882930.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/jennifer-garner-s-family-wants-her-back-with-ex-ben-affleck-especially-after-101735780882930.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:27:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Stock Picks For 2025: Axis Securities highlights 16 names with up to 40% upside - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Stock Picks for 2025: Axis Securities Highlights 16 Names with Up to 40% Upside</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> March 3, 2024, CNBC-TV18</p>
<img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&width=640&height=360" width="640" height="360" alt="Top Stock Picks" title="Top Stock Picks" loading="lazy" decoding="async" data-nimg="1"><figcaption></figcaption>
<p>Axis Securities has released its list of top stock picks for 2025, featuring 16 names with potential upsides ranging from 10% to 40%. The list includes a mix of largecap, midcap, and smallcap stocks.</p>
<ol>
  <li>ICICI Bank: <span style="color:green">+17%</span> (Buy, ₹1,500 price target)</li>
  <li>SBI: <span style="color:green">+31%</span> (Buy, ₹1,040 price target)</li>
  <li>Varun Beverages: <span style="color:green">+10%</span> (Buy, ₹700 price target)</li>
  <li>HDFC Bank: <span style="color:green">+14%</span> (Buy, ₹2,025 price target)</li>
  <li>Bharti Airtel: <span style="color:green">+18%</span> (Buy, ₹1,880 price target)</li>
  <li>Cholamandalam Investment: <span style="color:green">+41%</span> (Buy, ₹1,675 price target)</li>
  <li>HCLTech: <span style="color:green">+10%</span> (Buy, ₹2,110 price target)</li>
  <li>Aurobindo Pharma: <span style="color:green">+15%</span> (Buy, ₹1,500 price target)</li>
  <li>Lupin: <span style="color:green">+10%</span> (Buy, ₹2,600 price target)</li>
  <li>Dalmia Bharat: <span style="color:green">+15%</span> (Buy, ₹2,040 price target)</li>
  <li>Prestige Estates: <span style="color:green">+30%</span> (Buy, ₹2,195 price target)</li>
  <li>Chalet Hotels: <span style="color:green">+10%</span> (Buy, ₹1,075 price target)</li>
  <li>Sansera Engineering: <span style="color:green">+19%</span> (Buy, ₹1,780 price target)</li>
  <li>Healthcare Global: <span style="color:green">+18%</span> (Buy, ₹575 price target)</li>
  <li>Gravita India: <span style="color:green">+38%</span> (Buy, ₹3,000 price target)</li>
  <li>J Kumar Infra: <span style="color:green">+25%</span> (Buy, ₹950 price target)</li>
</ol>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.cnbctv18.com/markets/top-stock-picks-for-2025-axis-securities-icici-bank-sbi-hdfc-dalmia-gravita-share-price-upside-returns-19533106.htm">CNBC-TV18</a></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/top-stock-picks-for-2025-axis-securities-icici-bank-sbi-hdfc-dalmia-gravita-share-price-upside-returns-19533106.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/market/top-stock-picks-for-2025-axis-securities-icici-bank-sbi-hdfc-dalmia-gravita-share-price-upside-returns-19533106.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:26:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi matches beats with Diljit Dosanjh, beats table like dholak as Punjabi singer croons. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/pm-narendra-modi-matches-beats-with-diljit-dosanjh-beats-table-like-dholak-as-punjabi-singer-croons-watch-101735780059927.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/pm-narendra-modi-matches-beats-with-diljit-dosanjh-beats-table-like-dholak-as-punjabi-singer-croons-watch-101735780059927.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:24:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Gautam Gambhir a compromise, was never BCCI's first choice as India head coach. It was…' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/gautam-gambhir-compromise-was-never-bcci-first-choice-head-coach-it-was-vvs-laxman-101735746146120.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/gautam-gambhir-compromise-was-never-bcci-first-choice-head-coach-it-was-vvs-laxman-101735746146120.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 01:04:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 box office collection Day 28: Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna starrer shatters records; earns o - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2: The Rule Collector's Day 28 Box Office Success</h1><p><strong>Published on: January 1, 2023</strong> <br> <strong>Source: Times of India</strong></p><img src="https://example.com/pushpa2.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 movie poster" /><figcaption>Pushpa 2 movie poster</figcaption><p>The Allu Arjun and Rashmika Mandanna starrer Pushpa 2 has shattered records on its 28th day at the box office, earning over Rs 10 crore on New Year's day.</p><ol><li>The film's success has led to increased demand for its sequel.</li><li>The movie has been a major hit in both Telugu states and Hindi markets.</li></ol><blockquote>"This is a phenomenal achievement for a Telugu film," said trade analyst Taran Adarsh.</blockquote><p>With its impressive run at the box office, Pushpa 2 is expected to cross the Rs 100 crore mark in the coming days.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-28-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-shatters-records-earns-over-rs-10-crore-on-new-years-day/articleshow/116867699.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-28-allu-arjun-and-rashmika-mandanna-starrer-shatters-records-earns-over-rs-10-crore-on-new-years-day/articleshow/116867699.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After 40 years, convoy carrying gas tragedy waste heads out of Bhopal - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After 40 years, convoy carrying gas tragedy waste heads out of Bhopal</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Not specified - Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Gas tragedy waste convoy"/><figcaption>Convoy leaving Bhopal carrying chemical waste.</figcaption><p>The long-awaited convoy transporting waste from the 1984 Bhopal gas tragedy finally sets out after 40 years of delays, marking a significant step towards environmental cleanup and justice for victims.</p><ul><li>The waste, a byproduct of the Bhopal gas disaster, is being moved to a special facility for treatment.</li><li>This operation comes after years of protests and demands from survivors and activists.</li><li>The government claims that the project prioritizes safety and environmental standards.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is a huge victory for all those affected by the disaster; we have waited far too long for this moment." - Activist statement</blockquote><p>The movement of this waste is a crucial step for many victims and their families looking for accountability and restitution from the disaster's aftermath.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/after-40-years-convoy-carrying-gas-tragedy-waste-heads-out-of-bhopal/articleshow/116867788.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/after-40-years-convoy-carrying-gas-tragedy-waste-heads-out-of-bhopal/articleshow/116867788.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NZ bowl in cloudy Nelson; Wickramasinghe, Rakapaksa in for Sri Lanka - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Zealand Opts to Bowl First Against Sri Lanka in Final T20I</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>New Zealand won the toss and decided to bowl first in the final T20I match against Sri Lanka. With the series already secured at 2-0, New Zealand aims for a clean sweep.</p><ul><li>New Zealand has chosen to chase, reflecting their successful strategy in the previous matches.</li><li>The team lineup remains unchanged, emphasizing a youthful and effective squad.</li><li>Sri Lanka made two changes, bringing in Bhanuka Rajapaksa and Chamidu Wickramasinghe, while Kamindu Mendis and Matheesha Pathirana are dropped.</li><li>The conditions forecast overcast skies that may favor seamers, but the pitch appears conducive to batting.</li></ul><blockquote>Charith Asalanka highlighted the need for the middle order to contribute more runs.</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2024-25-1443537/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-3rd-t20i-1443545/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2024-25-1443537/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-3rd-t20i-1443545/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:39:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pre-market action: Here's the trade setup for today's session - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxOYlh1S0htWGVId2VaQVNIWVJNNFVUZ3ZoQVd2TTNLQjNaRU83X01KZUloaVhQeTZZWDQ1SmtPOGNpQWpNVkV5SlR2Rkx0RWh2ZTdCTEFLc2k2TldiUTBwelVNMjJ5YlRLZk1JSGpySFdNWkxEOC1WSW1OdWg2YzVFR21YSEdLWEJNZGJKUFVBTVpHYWpvcU1QQ0ppQVZ1UWdZWVg4d1JraldsbjNNTXpDSVBMSjdHNTEyaWxQRW8zZkUyUkMxMFpJWkRIaDLSAdIBQVVfeXFMUFhnTG9kbHA3ckN2Vl94RGl2bHkwNVNaYUJvUkY4a3B4ejQyckIyLVE2SkM1WEFrb1BEMU1tZ1FrQzFwTnlvMVVydXJWbmdfbFVSWU1BempUa0Q2ajZvX2xoUnV6S09CV21ya3JCdk9wWFhEbEVYMnI2WUp6WEpEV21HXzExOGxGRHBCcE1jQ0R6bjV6Z0VCUnhSYzNhd1E3SldhUFVobV8wLThMTXJ5dC1kLW43a0pRT3hORzc3THdGSUJadjBOTlIwUE5GWFJpSFFn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxOYlh1S0htWGVId2VaQVNIWVJNNFVUZ3ZoQVd2TTNLQjNaRU83X01KZUloaVhQeTZZWDQ1SmtPOGNpQWpNVkV5SlR2Rkx0RWh2ZTdCTEFLc2k2TldiUTBwelVNMjJ5YlRLZk1JSGpySFdNWkxEOC1WSW1OdWg2YzVFR21YSEdLWEJNZGJKUFVBTVpHYWpvcU1QQ0ppQVZ1UWdZWVg4d1JraldsbjNNTXpDSVBMSjdHNTEyaWxQRW8zZkUyUkMxMFpJWkRIaDLSAdIBQVVfeXFMUFhnTG9kbHA3ckN2Vl94RGl2bHkwNVNaYUJvUkY4a3B4ejQyckIyLVE2SkM1WEFrb1BEMU1tZ1FrQzFwTnlvMVVydXJWbmdfbFVSWU1BempUa0Q2ajZvX2xoUnV6S09CV21ya3JCdk9wWFhEbEVYMnI2WUp6WEpEV21HXzExOGxGRHBCcE1jQ0R6bjV6Z0VCUnhSYzNhd1E3SldhUFVobV8wLThMTXJ5dC1kLW43a0pRT3hORzc3THdGSUJadjBOTlIwUE5GWFJpSFFn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drug firms amp up hiring for top roles as growth beckons | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxPa3Q5eGgyYmJ0MG01N3QycnlCYlV2Wkg5RnljV2tzNUdvQ2QtRzJBektjaXBaTkVuWWFGVmxPdUFwQW1SclQxV285d1oxeF9LRXp6cHllSE96aEpwaWd3blRhWUFabXVtcnBsVjhjRXpUQ1ZwbW1pbUhMdktaYmRoOEVmTEZiWjVpbDdCZmdJRU04eXBYYUt4eV9nMDl2LUxnUUNzcDczX2xnWUsza3NjV1NCSElUNTdhTlVyM2t6Y09MTE9LUHp6WUFYVnVrU1RXVmdSZmJya2Y3VHJBVzUyakRjV20tQjRaNUwta3NrVF9WVG1mVERCY3ZR0gH_AUFVX3lxTE93Wk9NS0kzSW5CVEtHQUFjdGxVNTJONnhoa2NQUEtpeHRJX0thMnhQMXBCeHJkREFtSWNHbVhkY3N6YVhEWC1Ra09sdVJjZzk4YTJzdzAzbHBmUDY4Y3hCUzNyMUJ2TDhybW55ZnFzMU9ISTVBMXI3Y05wenBiemNaNktVNm1LbDlKWFZtZTRINmNyM0ozcGo1eDVkd05aOWx3V2c5aHpOM0JMRUs0cXRiOXk4ajdISDFsQzR1SXJzcXg1T1ZlTFc3ODNmMjlQTEJRbkhEMERFcVJEdHlGRlFzVUw4ejBla3cwUnFoRWdlVFlxNnRuaUpzZUVqVmdvTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxPa3Q5eGgyYmJ0MG01N3QycnlCYlV2Wkg5RnljV2tzNUdvQ2QtRzJBektjaXBaTkVuWWFGVmxPdUFwQW1SclQxV285d1oxeF9LRXp6cHllSE96aEpwaWd3blRhWUFabXVtcnBsVjhjRXpUQ1ZwbW1pbUhMdktaYmRoOEVmTEZiWjVpbDdCZmdJRU04eXBYYUt4eV9nMDl2LUxnUUNzcDczX2xnWUsza3NjV1NCSElUNTdhTlVyM2t6Y09MTE9LUHp6WUFYVnVrU1RXVmdSZmJya2Y3VHJBVzUyakRjV20tQjRaNUwta3NrVF9WVG1mVERCY3ZR0gH_AUFVX3lxTE93Wk9NS0kzSW5CVEtHQUFjdGxVNTJONnhoa2NQUEtpeHRJX0thMnhQMXBCeHJkREFtSWNHbVhkY3N6YVhEWC1Ra09sdVJjZzk4YTJzdzAzbHBmUDY4Y3hCUzNyMUJ2TDhybW55ZnFzMU9ISTVBMXI3Y05wenBiemNaNktVNm1LbDlKWFZtZTRINmNyM0ozcGo1eDVkd05aOWx3V2c5aHpOM0JMRUs0cXRiOXk4ajdISDFsQzR1SXJzcXg1T1ZlTFc3ODNmMjlQTEJRbkhEMERFcVJEdHlGRlFzVUw4ejBla3cwUnFoRWdlVFlxNnRuaUpzZUVqVmdvTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS: Australia make big change in playing XI for Sydney Test against India - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australia Revamps Squad for Sydney Test Against India</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116867540,imgsize-220342,width-400,resizemode-4/116867540.jpg" alt="IND vs AUS: Australia make big change in playing XI for Sydney Test against India" title="Australia's Captain Pat Cummins and teammates celebrate the team's win in Melbourne. (ANI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Australia's Captain Pat Cummins and teammates celebrate the team's win in Melbourne. (ANI Photo)</figcaption><p>Australia's captain Pat Cummins has announced a significant change in the playing XI for the fifth and final Test against India, with Beau Webster making his Test debut.</p><ul><li>Beau Webster will replace Mitch Marsh in the squad due to Marsh's poor form.</li><li>Webster is set to become Australia's 469th men’s Test player.</li><li>Australia leads the Border-Gavaskar Trophy series 2-1 heading into the final match.</li><li>Mitchell Starc has been cleared to play despite a rib niggle.</li></ul><blockquote>“He was never going to miss this one,” said Cummins about Starc's commitment.</blockquote><p>This change aims to enhance Australia's batting strength while facing a competitive Indian side at the SCG.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-australia-make-big-change-in-playing-xi-for-sydney-test-against-india/articleshow/116867525.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-australia-make-big-change-in-playing-xi-for-sydney-test-against-india/articleshow/116867525.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 23:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi meets Diljit Dosanjh; calls singer 'multifaceted, blend of talent and tradition' - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Meets Diljit Dosanjh</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 2, 2025, Source: Times of India</strong></p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116866875,imgsize-45592,width-400,resizemode-4/116866875.jpg" alt="PM Modi meets Diljit Dosanjh" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi with singer-actor Diljit Dosanjh.</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi met singer-actor Diljit Dosanjh and praised him as 'a combination of talent and tradition'. The two discussed music, culture, and India's vibrancy, including yoga, during their 'memorable' meeting.</p>
<ol>
<li>Modi lauded Dosanjh's achievements and praised his global success.</li>
<li>Dosanjh admired PM Modi's personal journey and his connection with India.</li>
<li>The meeting concluded with both parties expressing gratitude.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>"A fantastic start to 2025. A very memorable meeting with PM @narendramodi Ji." - Diljit Dosanjh</blockquote>
<p>Earlier, Diljit's concert in Ludhiana faced controversy due to songs promoting alcohol, despite previous warnings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/pm-modi-meets-diljit-dosanjh-calls-singer-multifaceted-blend-of-talent-and-tradition/articleshow/116866843.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/pm-modi-meets-diljit-dosanjh-calls-singer-multifaceted-blend-of-talent-and-tradition/articleshow/116866843.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 23:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Bakery Owner Dies By Suicide Amid Divorce Dispute, Family Says 'Wife Mentally Tortured Him' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Bakery Owner Dies By Suicide Amid Divorce Dispute, Family Blames Mental Torture by Wife</h1>
<p><strong>Published on January 02, 2025</strong> 
<p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2025/01/untitled-design-54-2025-01-980150cca61d9911de91275fa9381fd4.png" alt="Puneet Khurana" title="Puneet Khurana">
<figcaption>Puneet Khurana (Image: Twitter)</figcaption></p>
<p>A bakery owner in Delhi, Puneet Khurana, died by suicide amidst an ongoing marital dispute with his wife. Found hanging in his Model Town residence, the family alleges that his wife mentally tortured him. The couple married in 2016 and co-owned 'For God’s Cake' bakery and 'Woodbox Cafe'.</p>
<p>The wife was the last person he spoke to, with their conversation reportedly revolving around their bakery business. His family claims that the wife recorded the conversation and shared it with her relatives. Police have seized Khurana's phone and are investigating the case.</p>
<blockquote>"You disrespected me and my family. Tell me what you want now." - Puneet Khurana's wife</blockquote>
<p>The deceased's sister told ANI that Puneet's sister-in-law and parents had mentally tortured him. There's a 59-minute video recording where Puneet details the harassment he faced, including his wife hacking his social media account.</p>
<p>This case follows a similar incident involving Bengaluru-based techie Atul Subhash, who died by suicide last month, also citing harassment by his wife and her relatives.</p>
<p><em>If you or someone you know needs help, contact any of the listed helplines.</em></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/delhi-bakery-owner-dies-by-suicide-amid-divorce-dispute-was-upset-in-last-call-to-wife-9174436.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/delhi-bakery-owner-dies-by-suicide-amid-divorce-dispute-was-upset-in-last-call-to-wife-9174436.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 21:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Norovirus cases surge in USA: 5 key things you need to know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Norovirus Cases Surge in the USA: 5 Key Things to Know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 5, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116864854,imgsize-31606,width-400,resizemode-4/116864854.jpg" alt="Norovirus Surge" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Norovirus cases are on the rise in the USA according to CDC data.</figcaption><p>Cases of norovirus, a highly contagious stomach bug, are surging in the USA, prompting health officials to underline the importance of preventive measures.</p><ul><li>During the week of December 5, 91 norovirus outbreaks were reported, up from 69 the previous week.</li><li>This increase marks a significant rise as the previous years had a maximum of 65 cases at this time.</li><li>Norovirus is the leading cause of foodborne illness, responsible for 58% of such infections annually in the USA.</li><li>It spreads through contaminated food, water, surfaces, or close contact with infected individuals.</li><li>Young children, older adults, and those with weakened immune systems are at higher risk of infection.</li></ul><blockquote>“Norovirus is highly contagious, so prevention is key.”</blockquote><p>Health officials stress the importance of hygiene and preventive measures to reduce infection rates, especially during peak seasons.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/norovirus-cases-surge-in-usa-5-key-things-you-need-to-know/articleshow/116864854.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/norovirus-cases-surge-in-usa-5-key-things-you-need-to-know/articleshow/116864854.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 21:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Quordle’ Hints And Answers For Thursday, January 2 - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNSHBSYWduZ1MxTG1sOV92T3FjZFpqVzJHSGtMYXd6Q0xDMzRia3FaUk45RkhqYVB4TVJjYlB5SjBGNFRBZTc4eXJKankwZl9BVVB1WmJaRVZLU1g1c0xyNm1qWU1tQWZYMHk2ZmVNa3RUdHlTSi0tcmRjYUNTWUppM0xNZ1Bib05odUhOcU0yaW53SG1NdXFySFBBMUplY0k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNSHBSYWduZ1MxTG1sOV92T3FjZFpqVzJHSGtMYXd6Q0xDMzRia3FaUk45RkhqYVB4TVJjYlB5SjBGNFRBZTc4eXJKankwZl9BVVB1WmJaRVZLU1g1c0xyNm1qWU1tQWZYMHk2ZmVNa3RUdHlTSi0tcmRjYUNTWUppM0xNZ1Bib05odUhOcU0yaW53SG1NdXFySFBBMUplY0k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 21:00:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lucknow Horror: Man Shoots Murder Video, Shows Lifeless Bodies & Explains How He Killed Family - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/lucknow-murder-accused-arshad-blames-community-video-of-lifeless-bodies-of-mothers-sisters-9174419.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/lucknow-murder-accused-arshad-blames-community-video-of-lifeless-bodies-of-mothers-sisters-9174419.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:41:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ajit's mother calls for end to 'differences in Pawar family' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ajit's mother calls for end to 'differences in Pawar family'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>Ajit's mother appeals for unity within the Pawar family, urging an end to internal conflicts.</p><ul><li>Ajit's mother expresses deep concern over ongoing family differences.</li><li>Calls for harmony and collaboration among family members.</li><li>Emphasizes the importance of unity for family cohesion.</li></ul><blockquote>"Unity is our strength; we must overcome our differences for the sake of the family."</blockquote><p>This appeal highlights the need for reconciliation within the Pawar family during challenging times.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ajits-mother-calls-for-end-to-differences-in-pawar-family/articleshow/116864317.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ajits-mother-calls-for-end-to-differences-in-pawar-family/articleshow/116864317.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manhunt underway after gunman kills ten, injures several in Montenegro restaurant: 'All police teams are - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manhunt underway after gunman kills ten, injures several in Montenegro restaurant: 'All police teams are out'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 15, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Authorities in Montenegro are currently conducting a manhunt following a tragic shooting at a local restaurant that left ten people dead and several others injured. Police forces are deployed across the area in a concerted effort to catch the perpetrator.</p><ul><li>A gunman opened fire in a crowded restaurant.</li><li>The incident resulted in ten fatalities and numerous injuries.</li><li>Police are mobilized and actively searching for the shooter.</li></ul><blockquote>'All police teams are out,' stated a police spokesperson regarding the ongoing search efforts.</blockquote><p>This violent act has shocked the local community and triggered a rapid response from law enforcement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/manhunt-underway-after-gunman-kills-four-injures-several-in-montenegro-restaurant-all-police-teams-are-out/articleshow/116864252.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/manhunt-underway-after-gunman-kills-four-injures-several-in-montenegro-restaurant-all-police-teams-are-out/articleshow/116864252.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 20:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir's Position Unsafe: India Head Coach's Wings To Be Clipped If Downward Spiral Continues - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/gautam-gambhirs-position-unsafe-india-head-coachs-wings-to-be-clipped-if-downward-spiral-continues-9174521.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/gautam-gambhirs-position-unsafe-india-head-coachs-wings-to-be-clipped-if-downward-spiral-continues-9174521.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:43:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Political statement against Elon & Trump': Social media reacts to Cybertruck 'explosion' near Trump towe - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Social Media Reacts to Mysterious Explosion Near Trump Tower in Las Vegas</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Today<br>Source: Times of India</strong></p>
<img src="https://example.com/image.jpg" alt="Explosion near Trump Tower" width="300" height="200"><figcaption> Smoke rises from an explosion near Trump Tower in Las Vegas.</figcaption>
<p>Social media users are speculating about a mysterious explosion that occurred near Trump Tower in Las Vegas. The incident, caught on video, shows a vehicle exploding and catching fire.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The explosion occurred near Trump Tower on the Las Vegas Strip.</li>
  <li>Videos of the incident have gone viral on social media.</li>
  <li>No injuries have been reported, and the cause of the explosion is currently unknown.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Is this a terrorist attack? Or just a coincidence that it happened near Trump Tower?" - John D., Twitter user</blockquote><p>A spokesperson for Trump International Hotel Las Vegas declined to comment on the incident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/political-statement-against-elon-trump-social-media-reacts-to-cybertruck-explosion-near-trump-tower-in-las-vegas/articleshow/116863731.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/political-statement-against-elon-trump-social-media-reacts-to-cybertruck-explosion-near-trump-tower-in-las-vegas/articleshow/116863731.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five amazing images of Nebula captured by NASA Hubble Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Five Amazing Images of Nebula Captured by NASA Hubble Telescope</h1><p><strong>Date & Source: January 01, 2025, India.com</strong></p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/hazy-nebula-headlines.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&w=400&h=800" alt="hazy nebula headlines" width="400" height="800"><figcaption>A collection of stunning nebula images captured by the Hubble Space Telescope.</figcaption><p>The NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope has provided us with a stunning collection of nebula images. These nebulae, located in distant galaxies, offer a glimpse into the cosmos.</p><ol><li>Veil Nebula: A small section of the Veil Nebula observed by Hubble.</li><li>Eagle Nebula: A billowing tower of cold gas and dust rising from a stellar nursery in the Eagle Nebula.</li><li>NGC 1501: A complex planetary nebula located in the constellation of Camelopardalis, showcased in a new image from Hubble's Wide Field Planetary Camera 2.</li><li>Iris Nebula: A close-up of an area in the northwest region of the large Iris Nebula, clogged with cosmic dust.</li><li>Lagoon Nebula: A colorful image of the Lagoon Nebula, captured to celebrate Hubble's 28th anniversary in space.</li></ol>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/five-amazing-images-of-nebula-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-7508043/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/five-amazing-images-of-nebula-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-7508043/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:29:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Struggling to lose weight? It's time to rethink what you drink - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<html><head><style>body {font-family: Arial, sans-serif;}</style></head><body><h1>Title: Struggling to lose weight? It's time to rethink what you drink</h1><p><strong>Date & Source: January 3, 2023, The Times of India</strong></p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116863718,imgsize-43228,width-400,resizemode-4/116863718.jpg" alt="Struggling to lose weight? It's time to rethink what you drink" width="400"><figcaption>Image: A woman drinking soda</figcaption><p>As the holiday season winds down, many of us are looking to shed the extra pounds gained from festive feasts and drinks. However, before you start counting calories, consider what you're drinking. One glass of sugary soda or beverage could be hindering your weight loss goals.</p><ol><li>Sugar drinks, or sugar-sweetened beverages (SSBs), are leading sources of added sugars in the American diet.</li><li>Calories in sugary drinks are often overlooked but can be significant. For example, a 12-ounce can of soda contains 151 calories and 39 grams of sugar.</li><li>Consuming sugary drinks is linked to weight gain, obesity, type 2 diabetes, and other health issues. The body doesn't register liquid calories as it does solid ones, leading to overeating.</li><li>To avoid sugary drinks, replace them with unsweetened sparkling water, eat fruits instead of fruit juice, and make homemade drinks with natural sweeteners.</li></ol><blockquote>"Drinking sugary beverages is linked with weight gain, obesity, type 2 diabetes, heart disease, and other health issues." - Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)</blockquote><p>Conclusion: Paying attention to the sugary drinks we consume can help us better manage our weight and overall health.</p></body></html>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/weight-loss/struggling-to-lose-weight-its-time-to-rethink-what-you-drink/articleshow/116863718.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/weight-loss/struggling-to-lose-weight-its-time-to-rethink-what-you-drink/articleshow/116863718.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sugar Bowl CFP quarterfinal between Georgia and Notre Dame postponed after deadly truck attack - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/sugar-bowl-cfp-quarterfinal-between-georgia-and-notre-dame-postponed-after-deadly-truck-attack-101735759642901.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/sugar-bowl-cfp-quarterfinal-between-georgia-and-notre-dame-postponed-after-deadly-truck-attack-101735759642901.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:27:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inside Alia Bhatt, Ranbir Kapoor, and Raha’s Glamorous New Year Celebration - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Alia Bhatt, Ranbir Kapoor, and Raha's Glamorous New Year Celebration</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> <time>January 01, 2025, 17:03 IST</time></p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2025/01/picture-2025-01-0ac605079b44771b41352ce51a33f3d2.png" alt="Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor celebrated New Year with family" title="Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor celebrated New Year with family"><figcaption>Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor celebrated New Year with family</figcaption><p>Alia Bhatt, Ranbir Kapoor, and their daughter Raha rang in 2025 surrounded by their closest family members. The intimate celebration was filled with love, laughter, and stylish looks that set the perfect tone for the new year.</p><ul><li>The family members who joined the celebration included Neetu Kapoor, Soni Razdan, Riddhima Kapoor, Bharat Sahni, and Samara Sahni.</li><li>Neetu Kapoor and Riddhima shared glimpses of the celebration on Instagram.</li><li>Alia, Ranbir, and Neetu twinned in black outfits, while Soni Razdan chose a radiant red satin gown.</li><li>The family celebrated the start of 2025 in true style, blending fashion with heartfelt family moments.</li></ul><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The Kapoor-Bhatt family welcomed 2025 with a glamorous yet heartfelt celebration, showcasing their love and togetherness as they rang in the new year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/inside-alia-bhatt-ranbir-kapoor-and-rahas-glamorous-new-year-celebration-9174358.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/inside-alia-bhatt-ranbir-kapoor-and-rahas-glamorous-new-year-celebration-9174358.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:13:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big rockets, a big telescope and big changes in space await in 2025 - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/big-rockets-a-big-telescope-and-big-changes-in-space-await-in-2025-125010200001_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/big-rockets-a-big-telescope-and-big-changes-in-space-await-in-2025-125010200001_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 18:35:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who was Shamsud Din Jabbar? New Orleans New Year attack suspect named after 10 left dead, dozens injured - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/who-was-shamsud-din-jabbar-new-orleans-new-year-attack-suspect-named-after-10-left-dead-dozens-injured-101735753492096.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/who-was-shamsud-din-jabbar-new-orleans-new-year-attack-suspect-named-after-10-left-dead-dozens-injured-101735753492096.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 18:15:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjabi actor-singer Diljit Dosanjh meets PM Modi: ‘A fantastic start to 2025’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diljit Dosanjh Meets PM Modi: A Memorable Start to 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Wednesday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Modi-Dosanjh.jpg?w=640" alt="Modi Dosanjh" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Diljit Dosanjh met Prime Minister Narendra Modi. (X/diljitdosanjh)</figcaption><p>Punjabi actor-singer Diljit Dosanjh met Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Wednesday, marking a significant interaction filled with discussions about music and culture.</p><ul><li>Dosanjh described the meeting as “A fantastic start to 2025.”</li><li>The meeting included discussions on various topics, especially music.</li><li>PM Modi praised Dosanjh’s blend of talent and tradition and highlighted his journey from modest beginnings to international success.</li><li>Dosanjh expressed admiration for Modi’s sentiments toward his mother and the Ganga river.</li></ul><blockquote>“He has been winning over people,” Modi joked, referring to Diljit Dosanjh.</blockquote><p>Overall, the meeting signifies a blend of culture and recognition for Dosanjh's contributions to music and society.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/punjabi-actor-singer-diljit-dosanjh-meets-pm-modi-2025-9755327/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/punjabi-actor-singer-diljit-dosanjh-meets-pm-modi-2025-9755327/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 18:09:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tesla Cybertruck Explodes At Entrance Of Trump International Hotel In Las Vegas; VIDEO Surfaces - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tesla Cybertruck Explodes Outside Trump International Hotel in Las Vegas</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Wednesday, January 01, 2025, <a href="https://www.example.com">Example News</a></p>
<img src="https://example.com/cybertruck_explosion.jpg" alt="Tesla Cybertruck Explosion"><figcaption>Video footage shows the Tesla Cybertruck explosion outside Trump International Hotel in Las Vegas.</figcaption>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> A Tesla Cybertruck exploded at the entrance of Trump International Hotel in Las Vegas on Wednesday, raising security concerns ahead of Donald Trump's inauguration.</p>
<ul>
<li>The explosion occurred days before Trump's inauguration.</li>
<li>No injuries or casualties were reported.</li>
<li>The cause of the explosion is under investigation.</li>
<li>Tesla has not yet commented on the incident.</li>
<li>The explosion has heightened security concerns around the inauguration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote> "There are reports that the explosion might be due to foul play, given the timing of the blast before the major event." - Unknown source</blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The investigation is ongoing to determine the cause of the explosion and its potential impact on the upcoming inauguration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/world/tesla-cybertruck-explodes-at-entrance-of-trump-international-hotel-in-las-vegas-video-surfaces</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/world/tesla-cybertruck-explodes-at-entrance-of-trump-international-hotel-in-las-vegas-video-surfaces</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:56:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>