<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 13:21:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 13:21:44 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fibre in diet can reduce risk of gut infections: 6 ways to add more fibre in meals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fibre in Diet Can Reduce Risk of Gut Infections: 6 Ways to Add More Fibre in Meals</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 8, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> IANS</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117234544,imgsize-166512,width-400,resizemode-4/117234544.jpg" alt="Fibre in diet can reduce risk of gut infections: 6 ways to add more fibre in meals"><figcaption>Fibre in diet can reduce risk of gut infections: 6 ways to add more fibre in meals</figcaption><p>The article discusses the importance of dietary fibre in reducing the risk of gut infections and suggests six practical ways to incorporate more fibre into meals.</p><ul><li><strong>Start the Day Right:</strong> Choose high-fibre breakfast options like whole-grain cereals or muesli topped with fruits and nuts.</li><li><strong>Whole Grains Over Refined:</strong> Swap refined grains for whole grains like brown rice, quinoa, and whole-wheat bread.</li><li><strong>Load Up on Fruits and Vegetables:</strong> Incorporate a variety of fresh fruits and vegetables into your diet for added fibre and nutrients.</li><li><strong>Add Lentils and Beans:</strong> Use lentils, chickpeas, and beans in soups, salads, and stews for a fibre boost.</li><li><strong>Choose Nuts and Seeds:</strong> Snack on nuts and seeds instead of less healthy options to increase your fibre intake.</li><li><strong>Opt for Fibre-Enriched Foods:</strong> Look for packaged snacks and drinks labelled as high in fibre, but check ingredient lists for sugar and unhealthy fats.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dietary fiber reduces the chance of heart disease, type 2 diabetes, and some types of cancer.”</blockquote><p>By incorporating these strategies, individuals can significantly boost their fibre intake, supporting overall gut health and reducing the risk of infections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/fibre-in-diet-can-reduce-risk-of-gut-infections-6-ways-to-add-more-fibre-in-meals/articleshow/117234538.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/fibre-in-diet-can-reduce-risk-of-gut-infections-6-ways-to-add-more-fibre-in-meals/articleshow/117234538.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First full Moon of 2025: Will Wolf Moon be visible from India; know details - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Full Moon of 2025: Wolf Moon and Lunar Occultation Details</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Today</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Unspecified</p><p>The first full moon of 2025, known as the Wolf Moon, features a rare occurrence where it will pass in front of Mars, leading to a lunar occultation.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The lunar occultation occurs as the moon obscures Mars, which is approximately 40,000 times brighter.</li><li>The full moon peaks at 3:57 AM IST.</li><li>The Wolf Moon is named for the active howling of wolves in January.</li><li>This celestial event can be viewed using telescopes or binoculars, as Mars will not be visible from India.</li></ul><blockquote>No, the first full moon of January 2025 wouldn't be visible from India.</blockquote><p>Only locations in the contiguous United States and parts of Canada will witness this spectacular event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/lifestyle/first-full-moon-of-2025-will-wolf-moon-be-visible-from-india-know-details-nc-125011400774_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/lifestyle/first-full-moon-of-2025-will-wolf-moon-be-visible-from-india-know-details-nc-125011400774_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 11:50:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shah Rukh Khan calling comparison with Hrithik Roshan ‘shameless’, Rakesh Roshan getting shot: Kaho Naa Pyaar Hai at 25 - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shah Rukh Khan calling comparison with Hrithik Roshan ‘shameless’, Rakesh Roshan getting shot: Kaho Naa Pyaar Hai at 25</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/hrithik-roshan_ae02d0.jpg?w=640" alt="Hrithik Roshan in Kaho Naa Pyaar Hai's 'Ek Pal Ka Jeena'" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Hrithik Roshan in Kaho Naa Pyaar Hai's 'Ek Pal Ka Jeena'.</figcaption><p>The article reflects on the 25th anniversary of Kaho Naa Pyaar Hai, discussing the film's impact, the early rivalry between Hrithik Roshan and Shah Rukh Khan, and a personal tragedy faced by Rakesh Roshan.</p><ul><li>Shah Rukh Khan's statement on being the last star in Bollywood is juxtaposed with the rise of Hrithik Roshan.</li><li>Hrithik's debut in Kaho Naa Pyaar Hai surprised audiences and established him as a major star.</li><li>The article discusses the social media influences diluting star power.</li><li>Rakesh Roshan's challenges in launching his son's career are highlighted.</li><li>A tragic event shortly after the film’s release when Rakesh Roshan was shot is described.</li></ul><blockquote>“I entered as a nobody and when I came out, there was hysteria all around me.” - Hrithik Roshan</blockquote><p>Kaho Naa Pyaar Hai remains a significant moment in Bollywood history, marking both a star launch and personal challenges for the Roshan family.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/hrithik-roshan-war-with-shah-rukh-khan-rakesh-roshan-shot-kaho-naa-pyaar-hai-9776102/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/hrithik-roshan-war-with-shah-rukh-khan-rakesh-roshan-shot-kaho-naa-pyaar-hai-9776102/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 11:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hamas has accepted draft agreement for Gaza ceasefire, release of hostages: Officials - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hamas has accepted draft agreement for Gaza ceasefire, release of hostages: Officials</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2023/11/Truce-7.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Hamas has accepted draft agreement for Gaza ceasefire, release of hostages: Officials" title="Hamas has accepted draft agreement for Gaza ceasefire, release of hostages: Officials">
<figcaption>Hamas has accepted a draft agreement for a ceasefire in the Gaza Strip.</figcaption>
<p>Hamas has accepted a draft agreement for a ceasefire in the Gaza Strip and the release of dozens of hostages, according to officials involved in the discussions. Mediators from Qatar have indicated that negotiations are at their closest point yet to achieving a deal.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Hamas has accepted a ceasefire draft and hostages' release.</li>
  <li>Negotiations described as being at the “closest point” to sealing a deal.</li>
  <li>The proposed agreement was confirmed by several officials.</li>
  <li>Final details are being worked out, needing approval from the Israeli Cabinet.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Negotiations were at the closest point yet to sealing a deal.”</blockquote>
<p>This potential ceasefire agreement could represent a significant step towards resolving ongoing tensions and violence in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/hamas-has-accepted-draft-agreement-for-gaza-ceasefire-release-of-hostages-officials-12910456.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/hamas-has-accepted-draft-agreement-for-gaza-ceasefire-release-of-hostages-officials-12910456.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 11:28:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Learn From...": Virat Kohli Sent Brutal Message Amid Uncertainty Over Ranji Trophy - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Learn From...: Virat Kohli Sent Brutal Message Amid Uncertainty Over Ranji Trophy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 29, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/s5krgq28_virat-kohli-mcg-afp_625x300_29_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="&quot;Learn From...&quot;: Virat Kohli Sent Brutal Message Amid Uncertainty Over Ranji Trophy"><figcaption>Virat Kohli has been named on Delhi's probable squad for the final two rounds of fixtures.</figcaption><p>Virat Kohli's participation in the ongoing Ranji Trophy is in doubt as the DDCA has not received confirmation of his availability. This situation arises as the BCCI stresses the importance of domestic match participation for players.</p><ul><li>The DDCA awaits official communication from Kohli regarding his participation.</li><li>The BCCI has mandated players to justify their absence from domestic matches.</li><li>Rohit Sharma was seen attending Mumbai's Ranji practice, signaling his commitment to domestic cricket.</li><li>DDCA chief Ashok Sharma suggests Kohli should take inspiration from Mumbai players.</li><li>Shubman Gill confirmed for Punjab's upcoming fixture against Karnataka.</li></ul><blockquote>“Virat should take inspiration from the Mumbai cricketers and play for Delhi in domestic cricket, whenever he is available.” - Ashok Sharma</blockquote><p>Kohli's choice to participate will be significant for maintaining India's competitiveness in red-ball cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/yet-to-confirm-ranji-trophy-participation-virat-kohli-and-rishabh-pant-told-to-learn-from-mumbai-7470930</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/yet-to-confirm-ranji-trophy-participation-virat-kohli-and-rishabh-pant-told-to-learn-from-mumbai-7470930</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 11:25:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yet To Confirm Ranji Trophy Participation, Virat Kohli And Rishabh Pant Told To Learn From "Mumbai's..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxOcXI4ZmVKOHpsRzgwSGZNTzAtTkZ4LVpLbUlOcVY4MUFybFA5TnZGZmE0U2toeHJFMWdQT3djTlQ0TFFnclFSaW1BY1QtaWVkTC1fZ20tbUZDZzQwWlJ1SXF3X2hwQWhfdDJCdVJDNWx1VGJYS1NreFNMMlhCOUF0Y3E0Q0ZLRGVJY21RTUZ5SlFRbUJtYWo5ZzRqR2lpVy03WjQ2cHZobktwbkQ5NzYxSHBwU2dWVmtGRG9oMkFiaHp4MkVtUlNiNDU1WmFaQTByNnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxOcXI4ZmVKOHpsRzgwSGZNTzAtTkZ4LVpLbUlOcVY4MUFybFA5TnZGZmE0U2toeHJFMWdQT3djTlQ0TFFnclFSaW1BY1QtaWVkTC1fZ20tbUZDZzQwWlJ1SXF3X2hwQWhfdDJCdVJDNWx1VGJYS1NreFNMMlhCOUF0Y3E0Q0ZLRGVJY21RTUZ5SlFRbUJtYWo5ZzRqR2lpVy03WjQ2cHZobktwbkQ5NzYxSHBwU2dWVmtGRG9oMkFiaHp4MkVtUlNiNDU1WmFaQTByNnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 11:25:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI Set New Guideline For Indian Cricketers, Wives Won't Be Allowed To Stay For Entire Tour: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/bcci-set-new-guideline-for-indian-cricketers-wives-wont-be-allowed-to-stay-for-entire-tour-report-9187944.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/bcci-set-new-guideline-for-indian-cricketers-wives-wont-be-allowed-to-stay-for-entire-tour-report-9187944.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 11:23:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India’s disinflation progress could derail amid sharp rupee depreciation - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India’s Disinflation Progress Could Derail Amid Sharp Rupee Depreciation</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250114093512_rupee-inflation.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Rupee Inflation" title="Rupee Inflation" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>Rupee Inflation Trends</figcaption>
<p>The Indian rupee has depreciated by 3.2% against the US dollar, which may hinder the country’s disinflationary progress, leading to higher import costs and inflation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Indian rupee has faced a notable depreciation, becoming the second least volatile currency after the Hong Kong dollar.</li>
  <li>Experts warn that increased import costs may translate into imported inflation.</li>
  <li>Economists indicate that sectors reliant on imported raw materials will face escalating costs, impacting consumer prices and spending.</li>
  <li>Retail inflation in India saw a decline to 5.22% in December, thanks to easing food prices.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>Aditi Gupta, Economist at Bank of Baroda: “Sectors heavily dependent on imported raw materials are likely to witness escalation in costs due to higher input prices, impacting margins.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The sharp depreciation of the rupee poses significant challenges to India's economic stability, making it essential for policymakers to address the potential inflationary pressures while supporting growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/india-s-disinflation-progress-could-derail-amid-sharp-rupee-depreciation-12910311.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/india-s-disinflation-progress-could-derail-amid-sharp-rupee-depreciation-12910311.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 11:18:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maha Kumbh Mela 2025: Inside the management of the world’s largest pilgrimage - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maha Kumbh Mela 2025: Inside the management of the world’s largest pilgrimage</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2025-01-12 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Maha Kumbh Mela 2025: Inside the management of the world’s largest pilgrimage" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Maha Kumbh Mela 2025: Inside the management of the world’s largest pilgrimage</figcaption><p>The Maha Kumbh Mela, held in Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, is recognized as the world’s largest gathering of humanity, with an expected 400 million visitors over six weeks.</p><ul><li>A temporary city built for 150,000 pilgrims with sanitation facilities.</li><li>Massive security arrangements including over 50,000 personnel deployed.</li><li>Advanced technology used for surveillance and safety measures.</li><li>Significant investment in fire safety with ₹1.3 billion allocated.</li><li>Dedicated lost-and-found centers to assist separated families.</li></ul><blockquote>“Security is a cornerstone of the festival's management, with authorities implementing an extensive and multi-layered safety plan.”</blockquote><p>The Maha Kumbh Mela serves as a testament to India's logistical capabilities in managing large-scale events, ensuring the safety and comfort of millions of participants.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-inside-the-management-of-the-worlds-largest-pilgrimage-19539892.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-inside-the-management-of-the-worlds-largest-pilgrimage-19539892.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 11:08:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hospital Photos, Account Locked Amid Divorce: How 'Brad Pitt' Scammed Woman - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>French Woman Scammed by Fake Brad Pitt for 800,000 Euros</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> TF1</p><p>A French woman was deceived into believing she was in a relationship with actor Brad Pitt and lost 800,000 euros to a scammer using AI-generated images and messages.</p><ul><li>The scammer contacted her on Instagram posing as Brad Pitt and his mother.</li><li>The victim, Anne, who was going through a divorce, was drawn in by romantic messages and declarations of love.</li><li>The scammer avoided voice calls while sending manipulated videos and images.</li><li>After Anne's divorce, the scammer claimed to need money for medical treatment, further escalating the scam.</li><li>The fraud was uncovered when Anne realized the deception upon seeing news about Pitt's actual relationships.</li></ul><blockquote>“There are so few men who write such things. I liked the man I was talking to and he knew how to talk to women,” said Anne.</blockquote><p>This case highlights the dangers of online scams and the emotional vulnerability that can be exploited.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/account-locked-amid-divorce-how-brad-pitt-scammed-woman-of-8364-800-000-7471453</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/account-locked-amid-divorce-how-brad-pitt-scammed-woman-of-8364-800-000-7471453</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:53:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Share Market Highlights 14 January 2025: Sensex, Nifty see modest gains as financials recover - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQUFNyeUwyc00tckpldjVtaVhLRWRpajQ4MFNJVzAxR0tPdnlYb1dKdmFLSEV6cFFIRmlfa0NEeW1KMjNfSm1odmJrcjhCTW8zTjJtaS1JYUJST2lFc19RU1F4UjN3WE5MZU1DblB1QzYwdnBwTGttWWItTHozamRrUXdSekRTZS1qVWZiQTNnNDRMWExsbHBvdWRKSWxHUHpMQ0MtRTBINA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQUFNyeUwyc00tckpldjVtaVhLRWRpajQ4MFNJVzAxR0tPdnlYb1dKdmFLSEV6cFFIRmlfa0NEeW1KMjNfSm1odmJrcjhCTW8zTjJtaS1JYUJST2lFc19RU1F4UjN3WE5MZU1DblB1QzYwdnBwTGttWWItTHozamRrUXdSekRTZS1qVWZiQTNnNDRMWExsbHBvdWRKSWxHUHpMQ0MtRTBINA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:41:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bomb hoax: 'Parents of accused linked to NGO that opposed Afzal's hanging'; BJP targets AAP - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bomb Hoax Involves Parents of Accused Linked to NGO Opposing Afzal's Hanging; BJP Targets AAP</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a troubling incident, a bomb hoax has been reported which has drawn political attention as the parents of the accused are linked to a non-governmental organization that opposed the hanging of Afzal Guru. The BJP has criticized the AAP party over this matter.</p><ul><li>Bomb hoax reported involving parents of the accused.</li><li>Parents linked to an NGO that stood against Afzal Guru's hanging.</li><li>BJP uses the incident to target the AAP party politically.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/juvenile-hoax-callers-parent-linked-to-ngo-that-opposed-afzals-hanging-delhi-police/articleshow/117233307.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/juvenile-hoax-callers-parent-linked-to-ngo-that-opposed-afzals-hanging-delhi-police/articleshow/117233307.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bristol Astrophysicist Receives Prestigious Award with Special Historical Connection - India Education Diary]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indiaeducationdiary.in/bristol-astrophysicist-receives-prestigious-award-with-special-historical-connection/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiaeducationdiary.in/bristol-astrophysicist-receives-prestigious-award-with-special-historical-connection/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:36:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sankranthiki Vasthunam Box Office Collection Day 1 - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxOSnNrNC1OSGhrX1FaaFhpN3FjNVQxMEc2RDNXTHBTWmsyS3EzX01iT09RYk10cndiZVRQWnc3NHJnc3VxbW1mOXVnNHMzeDFFVURkOTlCUkdZNVpFcHFuVjlSek1ZQUtiMGdBUEVxSUtQX1B3TkRfNFp2akRPRkpLVkw0Tm42VHI1Z0VMRnBvVVYwVlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxOSnNrNC1OSGhrX1FaaFhpN3FjNVQxMEc2RDNXTHBTWmsyS3EzX01iT09RYk10cndiZVRQWnc3NHJnc3VxbW1mOXVnNHMzeDFFVURkOTlCUkdZNVpFcHFuVjlSek1ZQUtiMGdBUEVxSUtQX1B3TkRfNFp2akRPRkpLVkw0Tm42VHI1Z0VMRnBvVVYwVlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:36:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sierra Leone declares emergency after confirming second Mpox case in four days - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sierra Leone Declares Emergency After Second Mpox Case in Four Days</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p>
<img alt="Sierra Leone declares emergency after confirming second Mpox case in four days" title="Sierra Leone declares emergency after confirming second Mpox case in four days" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360">
<figcaption>Image illustrating the Mpox outbreak in Sierra Leone.</figcaption>
<p>Sierra Leone has declared a state of emergency after confirming its second case of Mpox within four days, as health authorities express concern over the rapid spread of the disease.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The first case involved recent travel to the northern Port Loko District.</li>
  <li>Both patients are currently receiving treatment in Freetown.</li>
  <li>Mpox was first identified in 1958, historically affecting mostly people in central and West Africa.</li>
  <li>In 2022, Mpox was confirmed to spread through sexual intercourse, leading to outbreaks in over 70 countries.</li>
  <li>Sierra Leone was previously the epicentre of the 2014 Ebola outbreak, resulting in significant loss of life and healthcare workforce.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Congo has borne the brunt of the epidemic, with a vast majority of the roughly 43,000 suspected cases and 1,000 deaths in Africa this year."</blockquote>
<p>This situation poses a significant public health challenge, especially in the context of Sierra Leone's past experiences with epidemics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/sierra-leone-declares-emergency-after-confirming-second-mpox-case-in-four-days-19539791.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/sierra-leone-declares-emergency-after-confirming-second-mpox-case-in-four-days-19539791.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:34:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sores in genital areas? This could be a sign of Herpes virus - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sores in genital areas? This could be a sign of Herpes virus</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>N/A | <strong>Source: </strong>N/A</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117233017,imgsize-1002702,width-400,resizemode-4/117233017.jpg" alt="Sores in genital areas? This could be a sign of Herpes virus"><figcaption>Sores in genital areas? This could be a sign of Herpes virus</figcaption><p>This article discusses the indications and implications of herpes simplex virus (HSV), highlighting symptoms, causes, and prevention strategies.</p><ul><li>Herpes simplex virus causes sores in oral and genital areas.</li><li>Genital herpes is an STI; 1 in 5 women aged 14-49 are affected.</li><li>67% of the global population under age 50 is at risk of HSV.</li><li>Risk factors include unprotected sex and multiple partners.</li><li>Early detection through various testing methods improves treatment outcomes.</li><li>Prevention includes abstinence, condom use, and maintaining hygiene during outbreaks.</li></ul><blockquote>“The common risk factors include sexual contact with someone infected with hsv-1 or hsv-2...” - Dr. Archana Dhawan Bajaj</blockquote><p>Understanding and preventing herpes involves knowledge about its symptoms, responsible sexual practices, and timely medical intervention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/sores-in-genital-areas-this-could-be-a-sign-of-herpes-virus/articleshow/117232994.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/sores-in-genital-areas-this-could-be-a-sign-of-herpes-virus/articleshow/117232994.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliamentary panel to summon Meta over Mark Zuckerberg's remark on India polls: BJP MP - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQV3lKZXFGNU1jTDhaN01KcjM0S3c1ZHlWTklBLWM2eDV5Q09YNDJxZnZ0UDR0SXVSOXQyQXJNZGVHQ2tlaTlIMnd2RXVSNTJCV2x2X0FGdzZuSDFfZjdTVmtDZmxrNlN3UEdCd2RBU1lVSzg1NTdLRU1nQzAtQnlMZ3hUcXVPU1ZaWmg4YjE0VnpfcDVzbmhxODlsbEdtbGRtQk0zYmQyWlkxemVsamZhUHRUbTBYeVVzakJPaXVGNzhDbFMzQ2RSS1RTRlhxeXpMbWFBcnJmZGxWd2ZoZ2xjMXdR0gHnAUFVX3lxTE5Od1VhSmlnTmoyXzE4SDJwMnB3ekhLcnNxMVlpXzlqS05ybWVSd3lKZnNyVmp6OHlBQ3A4WlE5TkFXSWFHaWtwSy1IaFRyblR5Y1ZtLUlqQXJ3ZURfMURPN3I4YnY3aTNpS0VGcTF2eXFrRnBNdVZuQkNnTFFERlhwQmhNTlR2dlU1UGNHRy11b0FkTi1LbllVUV9UNHVnanQxYU0wTXZlNWpWcGpuQnZ1RjMxaXdUQzVIX2lUNTNwaE1JaFFKalFzTHhxNDVSTVkycVM1eGN0dnlBTTJnRzg0Z0Q1NnFYVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQV3lKZXFGNU1jTDhaN01KcjM0S3c1ZHlWTklBLWM2eDV5Q09YNDJxZnZ0UDR0SXVSOXQyQXJNZGVHQ2tlaTlIMnd2RXVSNTJCV2x2X0FGdzZuSDFfZjdTVmtDZmxrNlN3UEdCd2RBU1lVSzg1NTdLRU1nQzAtQnlMZ3hUcXVPU1ZaWmg4YjE0VnpfcDVzbmhxODlsbEdtbGRtQk0zYmQyWlkxemVsamZhUHRUbTBYeVVzakJPaXVGNzhDbFMzQ2RSS1RTRlhxeXpMbWFBcnJmZGxWd2ZoZ2xjMXdR0gHnAUFVX3lxTE5Od1VhSmlnTmoyXzE4SDJwMnB3ekhLcnNxMVlpXzlqS05ybWVSd3lKZnNyVmp6OHlBQ3A4WlE5TkFXSWFHaWtwSy1IaFRyblR5Y1ZtLUlqQXJ3ZURfMURPN3I4YnY3aTNpS0VGcTF2eXFrRnBNdVZuQkNnTFFERlhwQmhNTlR2dlU1UGNHRy11b0FkTi1LbllVUV9UNHVnanQxYU0wTXZlNWpWcGpuQnZ1RjMxaXdUQzVIX2lUNTNwaE1JaFFKalFzTHhxNDVSTVkycVM1eGN0dnlBTTJnRzg0Z0Q1NnFYVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:13:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Would rather like people to be…’: ITC chairman Sanjiv Puri on 90-hour work week debate - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ITC Chairman Sanjiv Puri Responds to 90-Hour Work Week Debate</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/Confederation-of-Indian-Industry--CII--president-S_1736845248416_1736845264609.jpg" alt="ITC Limited chairman Sanjiv Puri (File Photo/ANI)"><figcaption>ITC Limited chairman Sanjiv Puri (File Photo/ANI)</figcaption><p>Sanjiv Puri, chairman and MD of ITC Limited, expressed that the company prefers not to quantify work hours, focusing instead on employee engagement.</p><ul><li>During a recent event, Sanjiv Puri highlighted that ITC emphasizes being part of the company's journey rather than logging hours.</li><li>Puri declined to specify work hour numbers, stressing a flexible work environment including remote work options.</li><li>This discussion comes in light of comments from L&T chairman SN Subrahmanyan advocating for a 90-hour work week, which drew significant criticism.</li></ul><blockquote>“We would rather like people to be part of the company's journey and feel passionately involved.” - Sanjiv Puri</blockquote><p>The remarks from both Sanjiv Puri and SN Subrahmanyan have sparked discussions on work-life balance in corporate settings, highlighting contrasting management philosophies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/would-rather-like-people-to-be-itc-chairman-sanjiv-puri-on-90-hour-work-week-debate-101736845037541.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/would-rather-like-people-to-be-itc-chairman-sanjiv-puri-on-90-hour-work-week-debate-101736845037541.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:50:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta To Get Parliamentary Panel Summons Over Zuckerberg's India Poll Remark - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"Would Have To Apologise...": House Panel To Summon Mark Zuckerberg's Meta</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> New Delhi</p><p>Social media giant Meta is set to be summoned by a Parliamentary Standing Committee due to remarks made by its CEO, Mark Zuckerberg, regarding the 2024 Indian general election.</p><ul><li>Meta is being accused of spreading misinformation about the electoral results in India.</li><li>Zuckerberg's comments suggested a global trend where incumbent governments lost elections due to the COVID pandemic, incorrectly citing India as an example.</li><li>Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw countered Zuckerberg's claims, stating that the NDA led by PM Modi retained trust among voters in the recent elections.</li><li>The BJP faced some setbacks in elections but maintained a majority with support from allies.</li></ul><blockquote>"Misinformation on a democratic country maligns its image. The organization would have to apologize to the Parliament and the people here for this mistake." - Nishikant Dubey</blockquote><p>The ruling BJP's response highlights the importance of factual accuracy in public statements, especially from influential leaders like Zuckerberg.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/meta-to-get-parliamentary-panel-summons-over-mark-zuckerbergs-india-election-remark-7470510</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/meta-to-get-parliamentary-panel-summons-over-mark-zuckerbergs-india-election-remark-7470510</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:49:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Jammu and Kashmir incomplete without PoK’: Defence minister Rajnath Singh - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Jammu and Kashmir incomplete without PoK’: Defence minister Rajnath Singh</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 14, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/Rajnath_Singh_1736847736362_1736847736656.jpg" alt="Jammu: Defence Minister Rajnath Singh during an event" title="Jammu: Defence Minister Rajnath Singh speaks during the Armed Forces Veterans' Day function, at Akhnoor, in Jammu district,(PTI)">
<figcaption>Jammu: Defence Minister Rajnath Singh speaks during the Armed Forces Veterans' Day function, at Akhnoor, in Jammu district,(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Defence minister Rajnath Singh emphasized that Jammu and Kashmir is 'incomplete' without Pakistan-Occupied Kashmir (PoK) and cautioned Pakistan against the existence of terrorist training camps in the region.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Singh stated that PoK is essentially a foreign territory for Pakistan.</li>
  <li>He warned that the land is being exploited for fostering terrorism.</li>
  <li>At the 9th Armed Forces Veterans' Day event, he highlighted historical conflicts, referencing a potential end to cross-border terrorism in 1965.</li>
  <li>Singh acknowledged the sacrifices made by the Muslim community in fighting against terrorism.</li>
  <li>He pointed out the government's priority to bridge the gap between Kashmir and the rest of India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Our Muslim brothers have sacrificed their lives fighting against terrorism. More than 80 per cent of terrorists entering India are from Pakistan."</blockquote>
<p>The Defence Minister's remarks come in the context of ongoing tensions and the importance of unity between regions in India, as articulated during the Armed Forces Veterans' Day celebrations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jammu-and-kashmir-incomplete-without-pok-defence-minister-rajnath-singh-101736846344504.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jammu-and-kashmir-incomplete-without-pok-defence-minister-rajnath-singh-101736846344504.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:47:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Kapil Dev bhi janta hai woh crack hai': Former Indian cricketer reacts to Yograj Singh's 'bullet' statem - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Kapil Dev bhi janta hai woh crack hai’: Former Indian cricketer reacts to Yograj Singh's 'bullet' statement</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>October 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Kapil Dev image"><figcaption>Kapil Dev, former Indian cricketer.</figcaption><p>This article explores the reaction of former Indian cricketer Kapil Dev to a controversial statement made by Yograj Singh, expressing his disapproval and highlighting the need for responsible comments in sports.</p><ul><li>Kapil Dev reacts to Yograj Singh's statement about cricketers.</li><li>The discussion is rooted in the importance of maintaining decorum in sports.</li><li>Yograj Singh's comments have sparked debate among cricket fans and experts.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kapil Dev also acknowledges the concern over irresponsible statements in sports.”</blockquote><p>The article concludes that player comments can greatly impact public perception and sport's integrity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/kapil-dev-bhi-janta-hai-woh-crack-hai-former-indian-cricketer-reacts-to-yograj-singhs-bullet-statement/articleshow/117232263.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/kapil-dev-bhi-janta-hai-woh-crack-hai-former-indian-cricketer-reacts-to-yograj-singhs-bullet-statement/articleshow/117232263.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to stay safe from HMPV? WION asks experts as virus spreads across globe - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxQdlhfTzJIVlN2S0ozemNtQkp0UUFlNFBOclpmY293R3FUSXQ3UDVqQVVBRHlCTF9IczdQWk4tVTVVa2kxajI3dGVxRV9LSFdGWW5aaGJyTHdzVFpBcnNKZnFmS2JOS2MyejhrT0dCUmF5aEVYNGltTWVJWlFpWkVfWHVSQ21VRVZWWWQ1OTk2U181ZURyVTlIYlIxdE9lLW9DZjBwS1lVci1Db3dHdGlFUzFPQTJDRklvZkl5U0FmLVlBZWJB0gHKAUFVX3lxTFB5bTlmaVhtQ0VnSngtU3lZak1zUzYtSGFFZ2xJR1pQTFJnSmoyOUhwMTdmdG1NNlVMVjBGSFA4bVdjY1BmN3Fsd0NkbUR5SFNrU2ZaN3pLcXpqUkJEel9icDhHRWlLYzVDV2xtY1JMMnlDX0hwYVc3TmFCNndMSWF3aFNMS3d4eVh6dWsyNlVOblQ5ZmRiYXJaM2xqcjY2ZHh6cVNXTElncTJVbVRLSy1EMW9uT2RUYmJzV0E0RFpoQVh6WFRlVDg0bnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxQdlhfTzJIVlN2S0ozemNtQkp0UUFlNFBOclpmY293R3FUSXQ3UDVqQVVBRHlCTF9IczdQWk4tVTVVa2kxajI3dGVxRV9LSFdGWW5aaGJyTHdzVFpBcnNKZnFmS2JOS2MyejhrT0dCUmF5aEVYNGltTWVJWlFpWkVfWHVSQ21VRVZWWWQ1OTk2U181ZURyVTlIYlIxdE9lLW9DZjBwS1lVci1Db3dHdGlFUzFPQTJDRklvZkl5U0FmLVlBZWJB0gHKAUFVX3lxTFB5bTlmaVhtQ0VnSngtU3lZak1zUzYtSGFFZ2xJR1pQTFJnSmoyOUhwMTdmdG1NNlVMVjBGSFA4bVdjY1BmN3Fsd0NkbUR5SFNrU2ZaN3pLcXpqUkJEel9icDhHRWlLYzVDV2xtY1JMMnlDX0hwYVc3TmFCNndMSWF3aFNMS3d4eVh6dWsyNlVOblQ5ZmRiYXJaM2xqcjY2ZHh6cVNXTElncTJVbVRLSy1EMW9uT2RUYmJzV0E0RFpoQVh6WFRlVDg0bnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:28:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Republic Day Sale: Big discounts on OnePlus Buds 3, GoPro Hero, and more | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxPZkVMRVl5YkNjRlZPeVJYNkh0VHNfRFB0UVRXRHcyS3VyQ0JYdGszdGpjbmpvQlFPSDloWE44UVBvcXlSZ3VxalBjcU5CV1B5eDNyTG1RWU9LYWlHM0tmVDlaZDhjaTVuNzZuT0gzcVoza1ZteU1rM19fVUlUc3BtX2dzTUJMbW9oYU5xZmZrTllUVF9mTTZrbE5SaEpNMlFEUGZfRi0zYmFsLXExN2Y0dXFEU1J4Q0NmMUYxN3BtdDBCUmZsalBIR01mektueFVqUWVyMFZOMWdlZ9IB3wFBVV95cUxOMGlhWEQ0RVI0OG5KUFl6MlFuTjc3enVlMmM5Ml9xZS1sQVE2M1NQdVRqQjNDYURDTnU0S2FuOWpvcWN0NXgwaDg1SEQxRDgxaDl5Ti0xbGM0dFdreHVPTGIxSTYwZTBJQUU3LTczdW55RF9RRXdNaE9tNUUtYm1UdTFqUGVvaUxIWXlHUTc2N3JUNEpFZ2xFdW1WNTZXRi1vS0ZLempGNm05UXZRc081U2pqUXI2d19tSGFrYklDcExlYmRtX1V3akZqSlczYWhqXzZ4YTlod2l1a3VYU3Rr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxPZkVMRVl5YkNjRlZPeVJYNkh0VHNfRFB0UVRXRHcyS3VyQ0JYdGszdGpjbmpvQlFPSDloWE44UVBvcXlSZ3VxalBjcU5CV1B5eDNyTG1RWU9LYWlHM0tmVDlaZDhjaTVuNzZuT0gzcVoza1ZteU1rM19fVUlUc3BtX2dzTUJMbW9oYU5xZmZrTllUVF9mTTZrbE5SaEpNMlFEUGZfRi0zYmFsLXExN2Y0dXFEU1J4Q0NmMUYxN3BtdDBCUmZsalBIR01mektueFVqUWVyMFZOMWdlZ9IB3wFBVV95cUxOMGlhWEQ0RVI0OG5KUFl6MlFuTjc3enVlMmM5Ml9xZS1sQVE2M1NQdVRqQjNDYURDTnU0S2FuOWpvcWN0NXgwaDg1SEQxRDgxaDl5Ti0xbGM0dFdreHVPTGIxSTYwZTBJQUU3LTczdW55RF9RRXdNaE9tNUUtYm1UdTFqUGVvaUxIWXlHUTc2N3JUNEpFZ2xFdW1WNTZXRi1vS0ZLempGNm05UXZRc081U2pqUXI2d19tSGFrYklDcExlYmRtX1V3akZqSlczYWhqXzZ4YTlod2l1a3VYU3Rr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:28:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flipkart Monumental Sale 2025: Up To 50% Off On iPhone 16, Other Premium Smartphones - HerZindagi English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Flipkart Monumental Sale 2025: Up To 50% Off On iPhone 16, Other Premium Smartphones</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> HerZindagi</p><img src="https://images.herzindagi.info/her-zindagi-english/images/2025/01/14/template/image/flipkart-1736846702148.avif" alt="flipkart" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Flipkart offers up to 50% off on various smartphones.</figcaption><p>Flipkart, the E-commerce giant, has launched its Monumental sale from January 14 to 19, 2025, featuring substantial discounts on premium gadgets, including the iPhone 16 series.</p><ul><li>iPhone 16 available at Rs 63,999, down from Rs 79,900 with additional discounts.</li><li>iPhone 16 Plus priced at Rs 73,999 instead of Rs 89,900.</li><li>Pro models pricing: iPhone 16 Pro at Rs 1,02,000 and Pro Max at Rs 1,27,900.</li><li>Previous models like iPhone 15 starting at Rs 55,999, iPhone 14 at Rs 46,999, and iPhone 13 at Rs 39,999.</li><li>Other smartphones on sale include Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra at Rs 1,21,999 and Xiaomi 14 CIVI at Rs 43,999.</li></ul><blockquote>“These amazing offers are not limited to just the iPhone 16 lineup.”</blockquote><p>The sale presents a significant opportunity for tech enthusiasts to purchase high-end smartphones at reduced prices, making it a notable event for Apple fans and other smartphone consumers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxNU19ZblRRbUkyU2hub0pHNzBUakFFeTZvTWkwNE8teEVOZWY0Z2Q4bmpydzUtS2ptZnhhUXpPc19rd09pWF93QzVDbE92UTEwQl9YNHBDOHlxTFRNV3JvY1c1cnh0UWxMVHpKbGZqQ19veGQ5Nk93MU5YT3d0aWRIVkpDeUREN2NhRlRtbktXa3Vub3ZDUjRYbm1SNjRaZ1p4UWlnZTFCODRzR20xRHJ3M2FybWltckRTZEJSMk5BQlp2cDV0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxNU19ZblRRbUkyU2hub0pHNzBUakFFeTZvTWkwNE8teEVOZWY0Z2Q4bmpydzUtS2ptZnhhUXpPc19rd09pWF93QzVDbE92UTEwQl9YNHBDOHlxTFRNV3JvY1c1cnh0UWxMVHpKbGZqQ19veGQ5Nk93MU5YT3d0aWRIVkpDeUREN2NhRlRtbktXa3Vub3ZDUjRYbm1SNjRaZ1p4UWlnZTFCODRzR20xRHJ3M2FybWltckRTZEJSMk5BQlp2cDV0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:27:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[At least six Army personnel injured in landmine explosion in J&K’s Rajouri - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Landmine Explosion Injures Six Army Personnel in Jammu and Kashmir</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ti5pi4/article69098514.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI08_12_2024_000257A.jpg" alt="Representational file image." title="Representational file image."><figcaption>Representational file image. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>At least six Army personnel were injured in a landmine explosion while on patrol duty in Rajouri district of Jammu and Kashmir.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred near Khamba Fort in the Nowshera sector around 10:45 AM.</li><li>Initial reports indicate that one soldier accidentally triggered the explosion by stepping on the landmine.</li><li>The injured personnel were quickly transported to the hospital, and their condition is stable.</li><li>Landmines are commonly placed in forward areas as part of an anti-infiltration obstacle system, but weather can cause these to become displaced.</li></ul><blockquote>“The troops were on patrol duty when one of the soldiers accidentally stepped over the landmine.”</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the dangers faced by military personnel in conflict zones, particularly with the prevalence of landmines in sensitive areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/landmine-explosion-in-jks-rajouri-six-army-personnel-injured/article69098505.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/landmine-explosion-in-jks-rajouri-six-army-personnel-injured/article69098505.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP govt treats Delhi, Kashmir equally: Rajnath - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Govt Treats Delhi and Kashmir Equally: Rajnath Singh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/x9h5w7/article69098509.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI01_14_2025_000229A.jpg" alt="Defence Minister Rajnath Singh speaks during the Armed Forces Veterans’ Day function, at Akhnoor, in Jammu district on Jan. 14, 2025." title="Defence Minister Rajnath Singh speaks during the Armed Forces Veterans’ Day function, at Akhnoor, in Jammu district on Jan. 14, 2025."><figcaption>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh at the Armed Forces Veterans’ Day function.</figcaption><p>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh asserted that the BJP government treats Delhi and Jammu & Kashmir equally, praising Chief Minister Omar Abdullah for reducing the distance between the hearts of the people.</p><ul><li>Rajnath Singh made the remarks during the Armed Forces Veterans’ Day rally in Akhnoor.</li><li>He emphasized efforts to bridge the gap (dil ki duri) between Kashmir and Delhi.</li><li>Singh criticized Pakistan-occupied Kashmir's Prime Minister for his statements against India.</li><li>The Defence Minister extended greetings to veterans and highlighted their importance in uniting the regions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kashmir was treated differently (by previous governments)... we have been working to bridge ‘dil ki duri’...”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Singh's statements reflect a commitment to equal treatment and connection between Kashmir and the capital, aiming to strengthen national unity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/bjp-govt-treats-delhi-kashmir-equally-rajnath/article69098495.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/bjp-govt-treats-delhi-kashmir-equally-rajnath/article69098495.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RBI Governor Sanjay Malhotra signals he’s open to more flexible rupee - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RBI Governor Sanjay Malhotra signals he’s open to more flexible rupee</h1>
<p><strong>Publication date: </strong> January 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source: </strong> Economic Times</p>
<p>The new central bank governor of India shows willingness to let the rupee move freely while managing excessive volatility in the foreign-exchange market.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Governor Sanjay Malhotra, in office since December, has shown interest in the RBI’s currency intervention.</li>
    <li>He indicated a departure from previous policies that aimed to tightly control the rupee's value.</li>
    <li>Since the departure of former Governor Shaktikanta Das, the rupee has seen increased volatility.</li>
    <li>The RBI’s strategy may involve allowing a wider range in the currency's closing value.</li>
    <li>Exporters have expressed concerns about the impact of a stable rupee on competitiveness.</li>
    <li>Recent trends show significant investor pullouts amid currency fluctuations, indicating a reevaluation of currency policies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The depreciation in the rupee corrects some of the overvaluation.”</blockquote>
<p>The RBI is balancing currency flexibility with the implications of India’s energy import costs, keeping a close watch on market conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/policy/rbi-governor-sanjay-malhotra-signals-hes-open-to-more-flexible-rupee/articleshow/117231742.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/policy/rbi-governor-sanjay-malhotra-signals-hes-open-to-more-flexible-rupee/articleshow/117231742.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:15:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['As if Trump came to sell kheer': US President-elect's look-alike pitches pudding on streets of Pakistan - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>As if Trump came to sell kheer: US President-elect's look-alike pitches pudding on streets of Pakistan</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 21, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p><img src="https://images.deccanherald.com/deccanherald%2F2025-01-14%2Fj9k10qat%2FDonald-Trump-look-alike-in-Pakistan-3.JPG?rect=1413%2C0%2C1477%2C1969" alt="Trump Look-Alike in Pakistan"><figcaption>Trump Look-Alike in Pakistan</figcaption><p>A food vendor in Pakistan, Saleem Bagga, who resembles US President-elect Donald Trump, is drawing global attention as he sells kheer (a type of pudding) on the streets.</p><ul><li>Bagga's resemblance to Trump has sparked humor and curiosity among both locals and tourists.</li><li>He engages customers by singing Punjabi songs near his cart.</li><li>Local residents express their amusement, with one saying, &quot;We feel as if Trump has come here to sell kheer.&quot;</li><li>His kheer is popular, and people share selfies with him, joking they met Trump.</li></ul><blockquote>&quot;His kheer is really delicious ...we take selfies with him and we tell our friends that we have taken these pictures with Trump,&quot; said a local.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Bagga's unique situation not only entertains but also promotes local cuisine, drawing smiles and laughter from the community.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/ampstories/world/as-if-trump-came-to-sell-kheer-us-president-elects-look-alike-pitches-pudding-on-streets-of-pakistan-3354507</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/ampstories/world/as-if-trump-came-to-sell-kheer-us-president-elects-look-alike-pitches-pudding-on-streets-of-pakistan-3354507</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:10:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 army personnel injured in landmine explosion in J&K's Rajouri - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Army Personnel Injured in Landmine Explosion in J&K's Rajouri</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><p>In a tragic incident in Rajouri district of Jammu and Kashmir, six army personnel were injured due to a landmine explosion. This event highlights the ongoing dangers faced by military personnel in conflict zones.</p><ul><li>The explosion occurred during routine patrol operations.</li><li>Injured personnel were immediately evacuated and are receiving medical treatment.</li><li>The incident has raised concerns about security measures along the Line of Control.</li></ul><blockquote>“The safety of our soldiers remains a top priority during such operations,” said a military spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This incident underscores the ongoing risks that armed forces face while maintaining peace and security in sensitive regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/6-army-personnel-injured-in-landmine-explosion-in-jks-rajouri/articleshow/117231527.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/6-army-personnel-injured-in-landmine-explosion-in-jks-rajouri/articleshow/117231527.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 09:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Would Have To Apologise...": House Panel To Summon Mark Zuckerberg's Meta - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxNVm5YV1Bmc3NhM3BDaEhRZzRtc3RJY29OOHM0Y3VKc0dEQXBvZnBBd1o3bXE0cUxIcWd4MnhENFdZV0VHbnhhWDI5THhzR2RJcTF2R0szWHVzd3JRZlZnXy0wVkV6VmFMQWxPZ1RoUXdrYVNweWk3dU56UHVBN1ZqQXhPTlpPeUFlRUk1Nm9yT1JweFVoMExOVlY2OEdYVXI3X3BNSWJTZm1GSFJVdXNUZjZJaHhPTzdNSGRZbWp2Tms?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxNVm5YV1Bmc3NhM3BDaEhRZzRtc3RJY29OOHM0Y3VKc0dEQXBvZnBBd1o3bXE0cUxIcWd4MnhENFdZV0VHbnhhWDI5THhzR2RJcTF2R0szWHVzd3JRZlZnXy0wVkV6VmFMQWxPZ1RoUXdrYVNweWk3dU56UHVBN1ZqQXhPTlpPeUFlRUk1Nm9yT1JweFVoMExOVlY2OEdYVXI3X3BNSWJTZm1GSFJVdXNUZjZJaHhPTzdNSGRZbWp2Tms?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 08:46:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>