<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 21:14:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 21:14:10 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What youth hit by Arvind Kejriwal's car claim, and AAP's response - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQOUtDRmtpNjVMZTJqYl9KQUVPTHBTM3dTeDR0VDQ0Z1FXdXdkcUpHenZwQjIwc0NscVMxaUpDNE9GUTBFYjFEM3JPbExNREFFWDVPakxiRWJ5d1dyQjBEcXZuSUV4YkZDWmRael9wazhGSjJqN0x4UE1LVDRfOVRKd1o3SkFMYl9tVm9DVWZKVF9BXzdmbU9SRHNnbUFTYkQtZFB4bjQyVEdfUFJlZWFIcFloZjY4VGZQZjh6WnN4T1c3YXZBSEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQOUtDRmtpNjVMZTJqYl9KQUVPTHBTM3dTeDR0VDQ0Z1FXdXdkcUpHenZwQjIwc0NscVMxaUpDNE9GUTBFYjFEM3JPbExNREFFWDVPakxiRWJ5d1dyQjBEcXZuSUV4YkZDWmRael9wazhGSjJqN0x4UE1LVDRfOVRKd1o3SkFMYl9tVm9DVWZKVF9BXzdmbU9SRHNnbUFTYkQtZFB4bjQyVEdfUFJlZWFIcFloZjY4VGZQZjh6WnN4T1c3YXZBSEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 18:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[H5N1 In US: Department Of Health Speeds Up Development Of New Bird Flu Vaccine Amid Pandemic Scare - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>H5N1 In US: Department Of Health Speeds Up Development Of New Bird Flu Vaccine Amid Pandemic Scare</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p><figure><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bird-flu-animal.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="H5N1 In US: Department Of Health Speeds Up Development Of New Bird Flu Vaccine Amid Pandemic Scare" width="900" height="375"><figcaption>US Speeds Up Development Of New Bird Flu Vaccine Amid Pandemic Fears</figcaption></figure><p>The U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) has announced a significant investment to accelerate the development of a new bird flu vaccine in response to rising concerns about avian influenza affecting humans.</p><ul><li>The federal government is addressing the surge in avian influenza cases.</li><li>A $590 million investment in Moderna has been revealed.</li><li>This funding builds on a previous $176 million grant from July.</li><li>The vaccine aims to target H5N1 and other strains affecting various animals.</li><li>mRNA technology is highlighted for its rapid development capabilities.</li></ul><blockquote>“Because it can be manufactured quickly, if we began to see something sweep across the country quickly, it would allow us to move fast, to give the first line of protection to the American people.” - Dawn O'Connell, HHS</blockquote><p>In the wake of recent bird flu cases, including one death in the U.S., the urgency to create effective vaccines is rising, particularly with the emergence of the H5N1 strain.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/us-speeds-up-development-of-new-bird-flu-vaccine-amid-pandemic-scare-1175882/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/us-speeds-up-development-of-new-bird-flu-vaccine-amid-pandemic-scare-1175882/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Michelle Obama 'checked out' of Washington DC life as she is 'fed up with the political circus': Reports - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Michelle Obama 'checked out' of Washington DC life as she is 'fed up with the political circus': Reports</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Michelle Obama has reportedly become disenchanted with life in Washington D.C., expressing her frustrations with the ongoing political atmosphere.</p><ul><li>She feels overwhelmed by the political circus.</li><li>Reports indicate she has distanced herself from her previous role.</li><li>There are indications of her exploring ventures outside of the political spotlight.</li></ul><blockquote>"Fed up with the political circus"</blockquote><p>This sentiment reflects a growing dissatisfaction among high-profile figures with the current political climate.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/michelle-obama-checked-out-of-washington-dc-life-as-she-is-fed-up-with-the-political-circus-reports/articleshow/117358150.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/michelle-obama-checked-out-of-washington-dc-life-as-she-is-fed-up-with-the-political-circus-reports/articleshow/117358150.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump admin plans mass arrests of undocumented immigrants from next week: Official - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump admin plans mass arrests of undocumented immigrants from next week: Official</h1><p><strong>Date: January 18, 2025</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Moneycontrol</strong></p><p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250118171111_usflagborderrtr.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="The move would be among the first by Republican Trump, who returns to the White House on Monday" title="The move would be among the first by Republican Trump, who returns to the White House on Monday" width="770" height="431"></p><figcaption>The move would be among the first by Republican Trump, who returns to the White House on Monday</figcaption><p>US immigration authorities are set to conduct mass arrests of undocumented immigrants next week, following President-elect Donald Trump's inauguration. This action is portrayed as an early step to fulfill Trump's campaign promise to deport millions of undocumented individuals.</p><ul><li>Trump's administration plans to prioritize deportations of individuals posing public safety or national security threats.</li><li>Potential broader deportation efforts may include undocumented farmworkers.</li><li>The first operation is reportedly slated to take place in Chicago.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will crack down on migration and boost U.S. energy production,” stated Trump's border czar, Tom Homan.</blockquote><p>The anticipated mass arrests indicate a significant policy shift under the new Trump administration, reflecting a commitment to stringent immigration enforcement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/donald-trump-administration-plans-mass-immigration-raid-next-week-official-12913833.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/donald-trump-administration-plans-mass-immigration-raid-next-week-official-12913833.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:12:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump administration plans mass arrests of undocumented immigrants from next week: Official - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Administration Set to Begin Mass Arrests of Undocumented Immigrants</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250118171111_usflagborderrtr.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="The move would be among the first by Republican Trump, who returns to the White House on Monday" title="The move would be among the first by Republican Trump, who returns to the White House on Monday" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>The move would be among the first by Republican Trump, who returns to the White House on Monday</figcaption><p>US immigration authorities are set to carry out mass arrests of undocumented immigrants starting Tuesday after President-elect Donald Trump's swearing-in ceremony.</p><ul><li>The move is a reflection of Trump's campaign pledge to deport millions of immigrants.</li><li>Prioritization of deportations will focus on individuals posing a public safety or national security threat.</li><li>There are indications that deportations may extend to undocumented farmworkers.</li><li>The operations will reportedly start in Chicago.</li></ul><blockquote>“Trump is expected to begin signing executive orders to crack down on migration once he returns to office.”</blockquote><p>This action represents a significant shift in U.S. immigration policy under the Trump administration, marking the beginning of a stringent approach to undocumented migration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/donald-trump-administration-plans-mass-immigration-raid-next-week-official-12913833.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/donald-trump-administration-plans-mass-immigration-raid-next-week-official-12913833.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:12:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan stabbing news: How railway police zeroed in on suspect in train - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saif Ali Khan Stabbing: Suspect Detained by Railway Police</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Jan 18, 2025, Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/ANI-20250118239-0_1737219873669_1737219901739.jpg" alt="The suspect, Akash Kanojia." title="The suspect, Akash Kanojia."><figcaption>The suspect, Akash Kanojia.</figcaption>
<p>The Railway Protection Force (RPF) detained a suspect in the Saif Ali Khan stabbing case while he was travelling by the Jnaneswari Express train in Durg district, Chhattisgarh.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The suspect, Aakash Kanojia, was located using information from the Mumbai police.</li>
  <li>Kanojia was apprehended in the train's general coach based on a photo and tower location provided by the Mumbai police.</li>
  <li>Saif Ali Khan was attacked in his home, resulting in multiple stab wounds.</li>
  <li>He was treated at Lilavati Hospital and is reported to be out of danger.</li>
  <li>The Mumbai police have assembled over 20 teams to find the intruder who attacked Khan.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The suspect's identity was confirmed through a video call with Mumbai Police. He has been detained. Further interrogation will be done by Mumbai Police." - Sanjay Sinha, RPF in-charge at Durg</blockquote>
<p>The swift action by the RPF showcases the effective collaboration between state police forces in the wake of a serious incident involving a public figure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-news-how-railway-police-zeroed-in-on-suspect-in-train-101737219571970.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-news-how-railway-police-zeroed-in-on-suspect-in-train-101737219571970.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's Squad For ODI Series Against England: Yashasvi Jaiswal Earns Maiden Call-Up, Siraj Dropped - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's ODI Squad Against England Features Yashasvi Jaiswal, Mohammed Siraj Dropped</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Yashasvi Jaiswal earns maiden India ODI call-up for England series and Champions Trophy 2025. (Picture Credit: Sportzpics)"><figcaption>Yashasvi Jaiswal earns maiden India ODI call-up for England series and Champions Trophy 2025. (Picture Credit: Sportzpics)</figcaption><p>Indian cricket selectors announced the ODI squad for the upcoming series against England, which will consist of three matches starting from February 6, 2025. Yashasvi Jaiswal has earned his first call-up to the ODI team, while Mohammed Siraj has been dropped.</p><ul><li>Yashasvi Jaiswal makes his debut selection for the India ODI team.</li><li>Mohammed Siraj is omitted from the squad for this series.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah is included for the Champions Trophy despite injury concerns.</li><li>Rohit Sharma will captain the team, with Shubman Gill as vice-captain.</li><li>Key players like Virat Kohli, Shreyas Iyer, and KL Rahul retain their places in the squad.</li></ul><blockquote>“Yashasvi Jaiswal has deservingly earned his maiden India ODI call-up for the home series.”</blockquote><p>The ODI series will be crucial for India's preparations ahead of the Champions Trophy scheduled later this year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/indias-squad-for-odi-series-against-england-yashasvi-jaiswal-earns-maiden-call-up-siraj-dropped-9193092.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/indias-squad-for-odi-series-against-england-yashasvi-jaiswal-earns-maiden-call-up-siraj-dropped-9193092.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coldplay Concert: Chris Martin Speaks In Hindi, Leaves Fans Berserk As He Says ‘Mumbai Mein Aake…’ | VIDEO - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Coldplay Concert: Chris Martin Speaks In Hindi, Leaves Fans Berserk As He Says ‘Mumbai Mein Aake…’ | VIDEO</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 19, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Chris Martin speaks in Hindi at Coldplay Mumbai concert"><figcaption>Chris Martin speaks in Hindi at Coldplay Mumbai concert (Pic Credit: Instagram/coldplayindia._in)</figcaption><p>The highly-anticipated Coldplay concert has finally begun, and videos from the event are going viral. Fans were left awestruck as the band’s lead singer Chris Martin spoke in Hindi!</p><ul><li>Chris Martin warmly greeted thousands of fans at the DY Patil Stadium.</li><li>He expressed joy at performing in Mumbai, stating it was their first real show in India.</li><li>His Hindi greeting elicited a positive reaction from the audience.</li><li>The concert marks the beginning of their Music of the Spheres World Tour.</li></ul><blockquote>“Good evening everybody. Aap sabka bohot swagat hai. Mumbai mein aakar humein bohot Khushi ho rahi hai.”</blockquote><p>This concert is part of Coldplay's return to India after their last performance in 2016.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/coldplay-concert-chris-martin-speaks-in-hindi-leaves-fans-berserk-as-he-says-mumbai-mein-aake-video-9193826.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/coldplay-concert-chris-martin-speaks-in-hindi-leaves-fans-berserk-as-he-says-mumbai-mein-aake-video-9193826.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 16:49:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka vs Vidarbha LIVE Cricket Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy 2024/25 Final: KAR beat VID by 36 runs in Vadodara - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka vs Vidarbha LIVE Cricket Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy 2024/25 Final</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Saturday, January 2025<br><strong>Source: </strong>Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Karnataka-vs-Vidarbha-KAR-vs-VID-KAR-vs-VID-live-score-KAR-vs-VID-final-match-KAR-vs-VID-match-live-score-Karnataka-vs-Vidarbha-live-score-live-cricket-online-score-Karnataka-vs-Vidarbha-live-cricket-score-KAR-vs-VI.jpg?w=750" alt="Karnataka vs Vidarbha LIVE Cricket Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy 2024/25 Final: Catch all the live updates" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Karnataka vs Vidarbha LIVE Cricket Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy 2024/25 Final: Catch all the live updates</figcaption>
<p>Karnataka win their fifth Vijay Hazare Trophy as they beat Vidarbha by 36 runs in an exciting final in Vadodara.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Karnataka set a target of 349 runs with Ravichandran Smaran scoring a crucial 101.</li>
  <li>Dhruv Shorey led Vidarbha's chase with a commendable 110 runs but lacked support.</li>
  <li>Karnataka's bowlers Vasuki Koushik, Prasidh Krishna, and Abhilash Shetty each took three wickets at important moments.</li>
  <li>Other key contributions came from Krishnan Shrijith (78) and Abhinav Manohar (79).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Sachin Tendulkar praised Karun Nair's outstanding form, urging him to keep going after an extraordinary season averaging 752 runs."</blockquote>
<p>The match showcased Karnataka's dominance in the tournament, further solidifying their status in Indian domestic cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/kar-vs-vid-vijay-hazare-trophy-2025-final-live-score-karnataka-vs-vidarbha-card-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-vht-2025-final-9785290/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/kar-vs-vid-vijay-hazare-trophy-2025-final-live-score-karnataka-vs-vidarbha-card-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-vht-2025-final-9785290/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 16:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Speeds Up Development Of New Bird Flu Vaccine Amid Pandemic Fears - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQaXRfTm5VOFk4emJTWTBuZTBYamVhYm5WM252eTFYMDI4YlZ0alR1TGZWWDlOR3dOVlRoMlE5UE9ROVFNM0Z1YnRkMVc3UkVnZGtMY0FZelM4ZkFQUy1wQ1RDZzJUSXJJS2hxMFJ1LXVCWmtKYjhBT2wyQzU1X0c0b3h6MWRUWGNNNkZKVHB3VlhyY0w5bnpQcEZ6bGoyTG5pY09zZTF5a1JzWlprRlA2NndR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQaXRfTm5VOFk4emJTWTBuZTBYamVhYm5WM252eTFYMDI4YlZ0alR1TGZWWDlOR3dOVlRoMlE5UE9ROVFNM0Z1YnRkMVc3UkVnZGtMY0FZelM4ZkFQUy1wQ1RDZzJUSXJJS2hxMFJ1LXVCWmtKYjhBT2wyQzU1X0c0b3h6MWRUWGNNNkZKVHB3VlhyY0w5bnpQcEZ6bGoyTG5pY09zZTF5a1JzWlprRlA2NndR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 16:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Speeds Up Development Of New Bird Flu Vaccine Amid Pandemic Scare - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Speeds Up Development Of New Bird Flu Vaccine Amid Pandemic Scare</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p>
<img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bird-flu-animal.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="US Speeds Up Development Of New Bird Flu Vaccine Amid Pandemic Scare">
<figcaption>US Speeds Up Development Of New Bird Flu Vaccine Amid Pandemic Fears</figcaption>
<p>The federal government is intensifying efforts to address the rising threat of bird flu in humans with a major investment in vaccine development to prevent a potential pandemic.</p>
<ul>
<li>The HHS has invested $590 million in Moderna for bird flu vaccine development.</li>
<li>This funding is in addition to a previous $176 million grant awarded in July.</li>
<li>The vaccine targets strains currently affecting wild birds, poultry, and dairy cows.</li>
<li>Using mRNA technology allows for rapid development and flexibility in response to emerging threats.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Because it can be manufactured quickly, if we began to see something sweep across the country quickly, it would allow us to move fast, to give the first line of protection to the American people." - Dawn O'Connell, HHS</blockquote>
<p>This initiative reflects the urgency of addressing public health concerns regarding avian influenza as cases rise.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/us-speeds-up-development-of-new-bird-flu-vaccine-amid-pandemic-scare-1175882/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/us-speeds-up-development-of-new-bird-flu-vaccine-amid-pandemic-scare-1175882/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 16:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 dinner mistakes that compromise weight loss goals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Dinner Mistakes That Compromise Weight Loss Goals</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/117348829.jpg?imgsize=1156525&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="10 dinner mistakes that compromise weight loss goals">
<figcaption>10 Dinner Mistakes That Compromise Weight Loss Goals</figcaption>
<p>Many people unknowingly make common dinner mistakes that can impede their weight loss efforts. From meal timing to ingredients, these habits can disrupt the balance necessary for effective weight management.</p>
<ul>
<li>Skipping meals, poor sleep, and emotional eating lead to overeating.</li>
<li>Having dinner too late can disrupt digestion.</li>
<li>Large portion sizes contribute to excessive calorie intake.</li>
<li>Missing adequate protein can leave you feeling hungry later.</li>
<li>A carb-heavy meal can spike blood sugar and increase fat storage.</li>
<li>Fried foods are calorie-dense and harder to digest.</li>
<li>Not having enough vegetables means missing essential nutrients.</li>
<li>Skipping dinner can lead to extreme hunger the next day.</li>
<li>Sugary beverages add unnecessary calories.</li>
<li>Eating while distracted leads to mindless overeating.</li>
<li>High-calorie condiments can undermine weight loss efforts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It's essential to recognize and adjust common dinner habits to support effective weight loss.”</blockquote>
<p>By making these changes, individuals can enhance their chances of achieving their weight loss goals while still enjoying their meals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/10-dinner-mistakes-that-compromise-weight-loss-goals/photostory/117348787.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/10-dinner-mistakes-that-compromise-weight-loss-goals/photostory/117348787.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smaran, Shrijith, Manohar power Karnataka to Vijay Hazare title - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka Clinches Vijay Hazare Trophy in Thrilling Final</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>In a high-stakes final, Karnataka defeated Vidarbha by 36 runs to win the Vijay Hazare Trophy, showcasing remarkable performances with the bat.</p><ul><li>Karnataka scored 348 for 6, led by Smaran's 101 and Manohar's 79.</li><li>Vidarbha managed 312, with Shorey hitting a century (110).</li><li>Dramatic finish as Vidarbha fell short chasing a target down to the last over.</li><li>The match featured over 650 runs in total, highlighting aggressive batting from both sides.</li><li>Karnataka's five-year trophy drought ends with this victory.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was a thriller, and the team showed great resilience,” said the Karnataka captain.</blockquote><p>This win marks a significant achievement for Karnataka, reinforcing their status in domestic cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-1445828/karnataka-vs-vidarbha-final-1446242/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-1445828/karnataka-vs-vidarbha-final-1446242/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 16:22:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru To Witness Rare Six-Planet Alignment In Night Sky Until February 13 | Details - Jagran English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxNajlyenI1Y011MUhVSVhna19mSFZBU1dpc28zUUhQTE5CUHptaUFHYlV2c1ZyT1BUQUpFc3UwSmVieU9uR2pucjlkc1Jwb1kwUTZqVGhrRlNiaVJtYldPWGI1LXhSY1ZsdW1TUHJ6VjlFWTFMS1g0dEplbHh1YTNSNjRrMDRueHRsb3FGdGtVRFQtLV9DMW91aXpqQk1DZ0QwN2M1M0Y4ZVY1MFcya1dCWlU3QnljYlJyVWZaaWdsZ1VKWC00?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxNajlyenI1Y011MUhVSVhna19mSFZBU1dpc28zUUhQTE5CUHptaUFHYlV2c1ZyT1BUQUpFc3UwSmVieU9uR2pucjlkc1Jwb1kwUTZqVGhrRlNiaVJtYldPWGI1LXhSY1ZsdW1TUHJ6VjlFWTFMS1g0dEplbHh1YTNSNjRrMDRueHRsb3FGdGtVRFQtLV9DMW91aXpqQk1DZ0QwN2M1M0Y4ZVY1MFcya1dCWlU3QnljYlJyVWZaaWdsZ1VKWC00?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chris Martin and Dakota Johnson visit Mumbai's Siddhivinayak Temple with Sonali Bendre and Gayatri Joshi: - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chris Martin and Dakota Johnson visit Mumbai's Siddhivinayak Temple</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117358731,imgsize-87110,width-400,resizemode-4/117358731.jpg" alt="Chris Martin and Dakota Johnson visit Mumbai's Siddhivinayak Temple with Sonali Bendre and Gayatri Joshi: Watch video"><figcaption>Chris Martin and Dakota Johnson at Siddhivinayak Temple</figcaption><p>Hollywood actress Dakota Johnson visited Mumbai's Siddhivinayak Temple with Bollywood stars Sonali Bendre and Gayatri Joshi while in India with her partner Chris Martin.</p><ul><li>Dakota Johnson, known for her role in Fifty Shades of Grey, was dressed in traditional attire alongside Bendre and Joshi.</li><li>The trio participated in the aarti ceremony at the temple.</li><li>Chris Martin, the lead singer of Coldplay, is in India for the band's Music of the Spheres World Tour.</li><li>Their visit follows another at Shri Babulnath Temple where they participated in similar traditional customs.</li><li>The Coldplay tour includes concerts at DY Patil Stadium in Mumbai in January 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>Johnson expressed her enjoyment of touring with Martin while he is working.</blockquote><p>The couple's visit highlights their connection to Indian culture and their engagements in the country during the tour.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/english/hollywood/news/chris-martin-and-dakota-johnson-visit-mumbais-siddhivinayak-temple-with-sonali-bendre-and-gayatri-joshi-watch-video/articleshow/117358690.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/english/hollywood/news/chris-martin-and-dakota-johnson-visit-mumbais-siddhivinayak-temple-with-sonali-bendre-and-gayatri-joshi-watch-video/articleshow/117358690.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[$TRUMP meme coin rakes in billions ahead of Donald Trump’s inauguration, spikes over 300% within hours after launch - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxNaGlDcDdBMnhJOVBQVExZV2FQWURNWDRCbkc3VTlrck4xaDZGUHViN0NOdnBPZ29tbS1oTk9PUWVPUEs1WkpnRFg0RUV5RlVVS3lzdWN4T3ZULXhaZXoyUmluR1RHLUVWZFhNWnBKSmF2RzY1TDExWjREa1RNdWVnc1ZmUlg1dGxGbXZ2R250T1lCa2pBa1prYlhzd0xLLVMyVE5tUjRRZXREa2NlWWRKbVQtaXpJbEJFMFBsQWtSZTlhUTZxQ3VrQnJlVUhITHlfSU5mRllkYW5xclRZWVpsODZMZG5xOGRhdE9JMnEyanluUmRGamJmY3l30gH_AUFVX3lxTE90a3ZqbDdLcWUyMURPR3NuT3pwWE56X3VlYmtvbkNsdWQwZEVVZmVqaGFCTzlpVnF4bkVJa29idG1iTTdFT2dTaFpBMVpLVXVad2tMT0tEM25DOHRwVUhFcVVQc1d3eWpYdVZIbFFld213a1ZvR1hVVW55WHVXZlVXTEVldEVqbU5KSW5NbDkxODJWVUpFcHYxWERSRDVQRHNXeXh0eWhGbDRKZ2YxYlFqSzhocUN5eGhBaHhWcXpMU2pweDdtZE54dGhoX0VNMmZhR0R6bk9RSHRmLVZJM2toM0hEMDd4SmVibWs3M09uUlZjTEc1dC1KX1kzRlNkZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxNaGlDcDdBMnhJOVBQVExZV2FQWURNWDRCbkc3VTlrck4xaDZGUHViN0NOdnBPZ29tbS1oTk9PUWVPUEs1WkpnRFg0RUV5RlVVS3lzdWN4T3ZULXhaZXoyUmluR1RHLUVWZFhNWnBKSmF2RzY1TDExWjREa1RNdWVnc1ZmUlg1dGxGbXZ2R250T1lCa2pBa1prYlhzd0xLLVMyVE5tUjRRZXREa2NlWWRKbVQtaXpJbEJFMFBsQWtSZTlhUTZxQ3VrQnJlVUhITHlfSU5mRllkYW5xclRZWVpsODZMZG5xOGRhdE9JMnEyanluUmRGamJmY3l30gH_AUFVX3lxTE90a3ZqbDdLcWUyMURPR3NuT3pwWE56X3VlYmtvbkNsdWQwZEVVZmVqaGFCTzlpVnF4bkVJa29idG1iTTdFT2dTaFpBMVpLVXVad2tMT0tEM25DOHRwVUhFcVVQc1d3eWpYdVZIbFFld213a1ZvR1hVVW55WHVXZlVXTEVldEVqbU5KSW5NbDkxODJWVUpFcHYxWERSRDVQRHNXeXh0eWhGbDRKZ2YxYlFqSzhocUN5eGhBaHhWcXpMU2pweDdtZE54dGhoX0VNMmZhR0R6bk9RSHRmLVZJM2toM0hEMDd4SmVibWs3M09uUlZjTEc1dC1KX1kzRlNkZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:26:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[$TRUMP meme coin skyrockets 300% in under three hours on explosive debut ahead of Donald Trump’s inauguration - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>$TRUMP meme coin rakes in billions ahead of Donald Trump’s inauguration; spikes massive 300% within hours after launch</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Donald Trump launched the $TRUMP meme coin days before his inauguration, achieving an $8 billion market cap and a 300% increase in value shortly after launch.</p><ul><li>The $TRUMP coin surged to a price of $7.1 from an initial $0.18.</li><li>Trading volumes approached $1 billion in under three hours.</li><li>Trump marketed the coin as his “official Trump meme” through posts on X and Truth Social.</li><li>The coin experienced a rapid rise, hitting a peak market cap of $7.7 billion shortly after launch.</li><li>200 million tokens were created for the launch, with plans for a total supply of 1 billion over three years.</li></ul><blockquote>“My NEW Official Trump Meme is HERE! It's time to celebrate everything we stand for: WINNING!”</blockquote><p>The rapid success of the $TRUMP token reflects significant interest in cryptocurrency and meme coins, particularly tied to pop culture figures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/trump-meme-coin-skyrockets-300-on-debut-in-under-three-hours-ahead-of-donald-trumps-inauguration-11737213620863.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/trump-meme-coin-skyrockets-300-on-debut-in-under-three-hours-ahead-of-donald-trumps-inauguration-11737213620863.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:26:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dakota Johnson visits Siddhivinayak Temple with Sonali Bendre, Gayatri Joshi. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dakota Johnson Visits Siddhivinayak Temple with Sonali Bendre, Gayatri Joshi</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Dakota_1737213577433_1737213577715.jpeg" alt="Dakota Johnson came to India with her boyfriend Chris Martin recently." title="Dakota Johnson came to India with her boyfriend Chris Martin recently."><figcaption>Dakota Johnson came to India with her boyfriend Chris Martin recently.</figcaption></figure><p>Hollywood actor Dakota Johnson is enjoying her visit to India with boyfriend Chris Martin. The couple, alongside Bollywood stars Sonali Bendre and Gayatri Joshi, visited the Siddhivinayak Temple to seek blessings on Sunday.</p><ul><li>Dakota was dressed in a navy-blue outfit with an orange dupatta.</li><li>The group was spotted happily engaging in conversation during their temple visit.</li><li>The singer Chris Martin has been exploring various spots in India as well.</li><li>They were accompanied by security during their visit.</li><li>Coldplay will perform in Mumbai and Ahmedabad shortly.</li></ul><blockquote>"Dakota was seen wearing a navy-blue ethnic outfit, with an orange dupatta draped around her."</blockquote><p>This visit highlights the couple's ongoing engagement with Indian culture as they prepare for their upcoming performances in the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/dakota-johnson-visits-siddhivinayak-temple-with-sonali-bendre-gayatri-joshi-watch-101737212103097.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/dakota-johnson-visits-siddhivinayak-temple-with-sonali-bendre-gayatri-joshi-watch-101737212103097.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Centre forms inter-ministerial team to probe mysterious deaths in J-Ks Rajouri - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxOTU9kTk1qbXo2MTg4R1Jpa09MQXpFN2syVVJveGxWLXdyMWVlNlBtT29EZURwUUhzQ2ExbWVtZEVlM29iRW9ZX18wcWt6VWcxdkdQbkhsaHBSSmRPU3VWNkduQ3FZaEVBeFIwejRxVm5WNjA4QzBuNGJHeGFTRDZPWEFzY0NicXhiaVhZMzVfaHNYV0I2M0NTUTdHWTRCVE1tUGhDeGpIdzhMdTFTWmZJTWtYQnJmbFN3a2sw0gG_AUFVX3lxTE1XS1pVZEthblR2bDJ5WmdXbnhhU1UtMlAzcjNTdnNERUtncEN5OXVJM2dIV25ZdjNLM01kZzR6TEdYLU9mQ1BaRkh2djVLaGI3NTZpd3N3Q1YyUWVNZFBpUXdLVFJ6cXpGU28ySlBDNk43M1MxVDJKYTVJa2NYZmxqSDE4VXJBcHI1N19aQ254QW13WVZkYlA3NHpOcjBjVlpZLTdMMkxPNk9FRi1YRkoybmxuUmNndmpIWUQ1WU80?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxOTU9kTk1qbXo2MTg4R1Jpa09MQXpFN2syVVJveGxWLXdyMWVlNlBtT29EZURwUUhzQ2ExbWVtZEVlM29iRW9ZX18wcWt6VWcxdkdQbkhsaHBSSmRPU3VWNkduQ3FZaEVBeFIwejRxVm5WNjA4QzBuNGJHeGFTRDZPWEFzY0NicXhiaVhZMzVfaHNYV0I2M0NTUTdHWTRCVE1tUGhDeGpIdzhMdTFTWmZJTWtYQnJmbFN3a2sw0gG_AUFVX3lxTE1XS1pVZEthblR2bDJ5WmdXbnhhU1UtMlAzcjNTdnNERUtncEN5OXVJM2dIV25ZdjNLM01kZzR6TEdYLU9mQ1BaRkh2djVLaGI3NTZpd3N3Q1YyUWVNZFBpUXdLVFJ6cXpGU28ySlBDNk43M1MxVDJKYTVJa2NYZmxqSDE4VXJBcHI1N19aQ254QW13WVZkYlA3NHpOcjBjVlpZLTdMMkxPNk9FRi1YRkoybmxuUmNndmpIWUQ1WU80?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:17:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Singer Darshan Raval Gets Married To 'Best Friend' Dharal Surelia. FIRST Wedding Pics Out - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/bollywood/singer-darshan-raval-gets-married-to-best-friend-dharal-surelia-first-wedding-pics-out-article-117358206</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/entertainment-news/bollywood/singer-darshan-raval-gets-married-to-best-friend-dharal-surelia-first-wedding-pics-out-article-117358206</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:00:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RG Kar rape case verdict: BJP alleges evidence was 'tampered' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rg-kar-rape-case-verdict-live-updates-kolkata-court-rape-murder-judgment-cbi-sanjay-roy-101737170770711.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rg-kar-rape-case-verdict-live-updates-kolkata-court-rape-murder-judgment-cbi-sanjay-roy-101737170770711.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:55:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RG Kar rape case verdict live: Judgment today by Kolkata court, victim's kin say ‘more involved’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RG Kar rape case verdict: BJP alleges evidence was 'tampered'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/sealdah_1737208588219_1737208588543.jpg" alt="RG Kar rape case highlights: View from the outside of the civil and criminal court in Sealdah on Saturday, January 18, 2025." title="RG Kar rape case highlights: View from the outside of the civil and criminal court in Sealdah on Saturday, January 18, 2025."><figcaption>RG Kar rape case highlights: View from the outside of the civil and criminal court in Sealdah on Saturday, January 18, 2025.</figcaption><p>On January 18, 2025, a court in Kolkata found Sanjay Roy guilty of the rape-murder of a 31-year-old trainee doctor, whose body was discovered in the RG Kar Medical College &amp; Hospital seminar hall on August 9, 2024. The ruling has raised concerns over the investigation, with allegations of evidence tampering from various political representatives.</p><ul><li>The body of a trainee doctor was found dead in RG Kar Medical College on August 9, 2024.</li><li>Sanjay Roy, a civic volunteer, was arrested shortly after the incident, following CCTV footage linking him to the crime.</li><li>The case led to widespread protests by junior doctors demanding justice and better safety measures.</li><li>The trial began on November 12, 2024, with a total of 50 witnesses presented.</li></ul><blockquote>“The court has convicted him (Sanjay Roy), but the people of West Bengal believe that more than one person may have been involved in the incident.” - Sukanta Majumdar, Union Minister</blockquote><p>The court is set to determine Sanjay Roy's sentence on January 20, 2025, amidst calls from the public for the maximum possible punishment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rg-kar-rape-case-verdict-live-updates-kolkata-court-rape-murder-judgment-cbi-sanjay-roy-101737170770711.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rg-kar-rape-case-verdict-live-updates-kolkata-court-rape-murder-judgment-cbi-sanjay-roy-101737170770711.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:55:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump administration prepares for nationwide arrests of undocumented immigrants from next week: Border of - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxQUW1Zd0Q1QzZiRUowU1hCVTZfZXdnME9TM2tjcDNYVHlkMjNHamYwTFdJSlRWbVVXR2MyQlBwLWZfakVvRV8xYnA5S25tRkZtLS1aYW10ZXByLXpLY0dkQzA5SS04eG1CRzB5OGswcGJkYVVrOVZYZ2tmTGZSX3FGakRDa2NVYzdhZU9WRGF4SnJoQzZiSWxid3F2akRpWUR6U003VmxYYU5TLWRBZWRfSzM4RTNKNkl4VFJhMGpoX05kVmtkX25BVWRjbUFLckVVcnBtVDJzNkZxSzdGVE5hUU13Q2JQRjdiUnJvV1BrRkI3cEZtQW4wU2ZFTHc4a1p1OXZnV2dTaVVKTGFaV2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxQUW1Zd0Q1QzZiRUowU1hCVTZfZXdnME9TM2tjcDNYVHlkMjNHamYwTFdJSlRWbVVXR2MyQlBwLWZfakVvRV8xYnA5S25tRkZtLS1aYW10ZXByLXpLY0dkQzA5SS04eG1CRzB5OGswcGJkYVVrOVZYZ2tmTGZSX3FGakRDa2NVYzdhZU9WRGF4SnJoQzZiSWxid3F2akRpWUR6U003VmxYYU5TLWRBZWRfSzM4RTNKNkl4VFJhMGpoX05kVmtkX25BVWRjbUFLckVVcnBtVDJzNkZxSzdGVE5hUU13Q2JQRjdiUnJvV1BrRkI3cEZtQW4wU2ZFTHc4a1p1OXZnV2dTaVVKTGFaV2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka vs Vidarbha LIVE Cricket Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy 2024/25 Final: VID 180/3 (Target 349) vs KAR in Vadodara - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/kar-vs-vid-vijay-hazare-trophy-2025-final-live-score-karnataka-vs-vidarbha-card-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-vht-2025-final-9785290/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/kar-vs-vid-vijay-hazare-trophy-2025-final-live-score-karnataka-vs-vidarbha-card-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-vht-2025-final-9785290/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RG Kar rape case verdict live: BJP alleges evidence was 'tampered' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rg-kar-rape-case-verdict-live-updates-kolkata-court-rape-murder-judgment-cbi-sanjay-roy-101737170770711.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rg-kar-rape-case-verdict-live-updates-kolkata-court-rape-murder-judgment-cbi-sanjay-roy-101737170770711.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:58:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Boring tha': Rohit Sharma's offbeat humour at Champions Trophy presser goes viral. Watch - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Boring tha': Rohit Sharma's Offbeat Humour at Champions Trophy Presser Goes Viral</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> NEW DELHI<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117357301,imgsize-69958,width-400,resizemode-4/117357301.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma and Ajit Agarkar (Photo: @BCCI on X)" title="Rohit Sharma and Ajit Agarkar (Photo: @BCCI on X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma and Ajit Agarkar (Photo: @BCCI on X)</figcaption><p>During the squad selection press conference, Indian captain Rohit Sharma lightened the mood with his humorous comment, which quickly gained traction online.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma quipped about the press conference being boring.</li><li>Ajit Agarkar, the chief selector, smiled in response, adding to the light-hearted atmosphere.</li><li>The event announced India's squad for the ODI series against England and the Champions Trophy 2025.</li><li>Key players like Yashasvi Jaiswal and Harshit Rana received their maiden call-ups.</li><li>Mohammed Shami and Kuldeep Yadav returned from injuries, while Jasprit Bumrah's fitness remains a concern.</li></ul><blockquote>“Boring tha PC,” says Rohit Sharma, highlighting his humorous side during the announcement.</blockquote><p>This light moment is a reminder of the importance of humor in high-pressure situations, exemplified by Rohit Sharma's wit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/boring-tha-rohit-sharmas-offbeat-humour-at-champions-trophy-presser-goes-viral-watch/articleshow/117357154.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/boring-tha-rohit-sharmas-offbeat-humour-at-champions-trophy-presser-goes-viral-watch/articleshow/117357154.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka vs Vidarbha LIVE Cricket Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy 2024/25 Final: VID 134/3 (Target 349) vs KAR in Vadodara - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka vs Vidarbha LIVE Cricket Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy 2024/25 Final</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Not Available</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Karnataka-vs-Vidarbha-KAR-vs-VID-KAR-vs-VID-live-score-KAR-vs-VID-final-match-KAR-vs-VID-match-live-score-Karnataka-vs-Vidarbha-live-score-live-cricket-online-score-Karnataka-vs-Vidarbha-live-cricket-score-KAR-vs-VI.jpg?w=750" alt="Karnataka vs Vidarbha LIVE Cricket Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy 2024/25 Final: Catch all the live updates" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Karnataka vs Vidarbha LIVE Cricket Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy 2024/25 Final: Catch all the live updates</figcaption><p>Karnataka has set a target of 349 runs in the Vijay Hazare Trophy final against Vidarbha, led by a crucial century from Ravichandran Smaran.</p><ul><li>Ravichandran Smaran scored 101 runs</li><li>Karnataka finished at 348/6</li><li>Vidarbha's key bowlers: Darshan Nalkande (2/67), Nachiket Bhute (2/70)</li><li>Karun Nair is in outstanding form, averaging 752 runs this season</li></ul><blockquote>Karun Nair's recent batting performance includes scores of 112, 44, 163, 111, 112, 122, and 88 in his last 7 innings.</blockquote><p>The match is ongoing; Karnataka is currently battling Vidarbha for the Vijay Hazare trophy at Kotambi Stadium, Vadodara.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/kar-vs-vid-vijay-hazare-trophy-2025-final-live-score-karnataka-vs-vidarbha-card-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-vht-2025-final-9785290/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/kar-vs-vid-vijay-hazare-trophy-2025-final-live-score-karnataka-vs-vidarbha-card-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-vht-2025-final-9785290/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit confirms availability for Mumbai's Ranji game - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Confirms Participation in Upcoming Ranji Match</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Sat, Jan 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p><img height="396" width="595" alt="Rohit Sharma's last Ranji game also came at the same venue." title="Rohit Sharma's last Ranji game also came at the same venue." src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c600970/rohit-sharmas-last-ranji-game.jpg"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma's last Ranji game also came at the same venue. © Getty</figcaption><p>Rohit Sharma has announced his availability for the Ranji Trophy match scheduled from January 23-26 against Jammu & Kashmir, marking his return to domestic cricket after nearly ten years.</p><ul><li>Rohit's last Ranji match was in November 2015, at the same Wankhede venue.</li><li>His confirmation came during the Champions Trophy squad announcement.</li><li>Rohit expressed confidence in managing the transition between formats.</li><li>He joined the Mumbai team for practice ahead of the match.</li><li>Other international players are also participating in domestic matches as per BCCI directives.</li></ul><blockquote>“Yes, I will play,” Rohit confirmed about his Ranji match involvement.</blockquote><p>The announcement is significant as it reflects a trend where top players are engaging in domestic cricket to support their state teams, in line with BCCI expectations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/133143/rohit-confirms-availability-for-mumbais-ranji-game</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/133143/rohit-confirms-availability-for-mumbais-ranji-game</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:51:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New bird flu vaccine development gathers pace amid fears of pandemic - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Bird Flu Vaccine Development Gathers Pace Amid Fears of Pandemic</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117357043,imgsize-45064,width-400,resizemode-4/117357043.jpg" alt="New bird flu vaccine development gathers pace amid fears of pandemic">
<figcaption>New bird flu vaccine development amidst rising cases</figcaption>
<p>Amid fears of a bird flu pandemic in humans due to the rise in bird flu cases, the federal government is accelerating efforts in developing new vaccines, including mRNA shots, with a $590 million commitment to Moderna.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The US Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) has intensified bird flu vaccine development.</li>
  <li>An mRNA vaccine is being prioritized for its ability to be developed quickly.</li>
  <li>$590 million has been committed to Moderna for fast-tracking vaccine production, in addition to a previous $176 million investment.</li>
  <li>67 confirmed human cases of bird flu have been reported in the US, with one death.</li>
  <li>Research funding is also being allocated for antivirals and monoclonal antibodies to combat bird flu.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Accelerating the development of new vaccines will allow us to stay ahead and ensure that Americans have the tools they need to stay safe.” - HHS Secretary Xavier Becerra</blockquote>
<p>The development of new vaccines for bird flu is critical in ensuring public safety and preventing a potential pandemic, as current vaccines may not be sufficient during a health crisis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/new-bird-flu-vaccine-development-gathers-pace-amid-fears-of-pandemic/articleshow/117357062.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/new-bird-flu-vaccine-development-gathers-pace-amid-fears-of-pandemic/articleshow/117357062.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Hindu Lit for Life 2025 Day 1 LIVE: ‘Sinauli excavations must answer Dalits’ role in Dravidian culture’, says Vasugi Bhaskar - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Hindu Lit for Life 2025 Day 1 LIVE: ‘Pre-marital sex is frowned upon but marital rape is legal’, says Leeza Mangaldas</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 18, 2025</strong><br><strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/v1n8lm/article69113018.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Leeza.jpg" alt="Leeza Mangaldas at The Hindu Lit for Life 2025">
<figcaption>Leeza Mangaldas talking about societal norms regarding sex.</figcaption>
<p>The first day of The Hindu Lit for Life 2025 began with vibrant discussions featuring various authors and speakers addressing key societal issues. Notably, Leeza Mangaldas made headlines with her statements about marital rape and societal attitudes towards sex.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Leeza Mangaldas emphasized how pre-marital sex is frowned upon while marital rape remains legal in India.</li>
  <li>Historian Peter Frankopan discussed the significance of the moon’s gravitational pull in human and animal reproduction.</li>
  <li>Dr. Abraham Verghese highlighted the power of novels to transcend time.</li>
  <li>Conversations included the influence of Tamil poetry in modernity, featuring insights from prominent literary figures.</li>
  <li>Upcoming sessions are expected to cover diverse topics including literature, LGBTQ rights, and climate change.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We live in a country where pre-marital sex is frowned upon, but marital rape is legal,” – Leeza Mangaldas.</blockquote>
<p>The event presents an opportunity for deep engagement with contemporary issues, inviting audiences to rethink societal norms and values.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/lit-for-life/the-hindu-lit-for-life-2025-day-1-live-updates-january-18-2024/article69108090.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/lit-for-life/the-hindu-lit-for-life-2025-day-1-live-updates-january-18-2024/article69108090.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>