<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:18:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:18:53 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 series full specs leaked ahead of January 22 Unpacked event: Details - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-samsung-galaxy-s25-series-full-specs-leaked-ahead-of-january-22-unpacked-event-details-3712250/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-samsung-galaxy-s25-series-full-specs-leaked-ahead-of-january-22-unpacked-event-details-3712250/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:29:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 series full specs leaked ahead of January 22 Unpacked event: Details - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-samsung-galaxy-s25-series-full-specs-leaked-ahead-of-january-22-unpacked-event-details-3712250/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-samsung-galaxy-s25-series-full-specs-leaked-ahead-of-january-22-unpacked-event-details-3712250/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:29:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Third HMPV case reported from Ahmedabad, state tally reaches four - Gujarat Samachar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Third HMPV Case Reported in Ahmedabad, Tally Reaches Four in Gujarat</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Friday | <strong>Source:</strong> Gujarat Samachar</p>
<img src="https://static.gujaratsamachar.com/content_image/content_image_bcac07ee-d433-40e9-969c-6158b4ccaefb.jpeg" alt="Third HMPV case reported from Ahmedabad, state tally reaches four">
<figcaption>Third HMPV case reported from Ahmedabad, state tally reaches four</figcaption>
<p>A new HMPV case has been reported from Ahmedabad, bringing the state's total to four cases. This incident marks the third reported case from Ahmedabad.</p>
<ul>
<li>The latest patient is a nine-month-old infant transferred from Viha Children’s Hospital to Childhood Hospital.</li>
<li>The previous case involved an 80-year-old man who tested positive and was admitted to Sterling Hospital.</li>
<li>Three cases of HMPV have been confirmed in Ahmedabad and one in Prantij.</li>
<li>HMPV is a respiratory virus that tends to peak in winter, particularly affecting young children and the elderly.</li>
<li>Advisory issued by the state urges citizens to follow health guidelines to combat respiratory infections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Metapneumovirus (HMPV) is similar to other respiratory viruses, and it's crucial to maintain hygiene and avoid crowded places to prevent infection.”</blockquote>
<p>Citizens are advised to cover their mouths when sneezing, wash hands regularly, and seek medical attention if they exhibit respiratory symptoms.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://english.gujaratsamachar.com/news/gujarat/third-hmpv-case-reported-from-ahmedabad-state-tally-reaches-four</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://english.gujaratsamachar.com/news/gujarat/third-hmpv-case-reported-from-ahmedabad-state-tally-reaches-four</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:18:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Very Beautiful Images Of Moon Taken By NASA - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Very Beautiful Images Of Moon Taken By NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/117123012/117123012.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=746481" alt="6 Very Beautiful Images Of Moon Taken By NASA">
<figcaption>Credit: Times Now</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases six breathtaking images of the Moon captured by NASA, highlighting the beauty and intrigue of Earth's natural satellite.</p>
<ul>
<li>2017 Total Solar Eclipse image showing the Sun's corona.</li>
<li>Full Moon photo taken from the International Space Station.</li>
<li>Unique perspective of the Moon by NASA's MESSENGER spacecraft.</li>
<li>Tycho Crater captured by the Hubble Space Telescope.</li>
<li>Oblique view of the Copernicus crater taken by Lunar Orbiter 2.</li>
<li>Image of the Moon captured by NASA’s Galileo spacecraft in 1992.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These images aid in understanding the physics and structure of the Moon, showcasing its beauty and our capabilities of capturing it from various spaces.”</blockquote>
<p>This collection of images not only emphasizes the aesthetic appeal of the Moon but also engages audiences in lunar exploration and science.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-very-beautiful-images-of-moon-taken-by-nasa/photostory/117122999.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-very-beautiful-images-of-moon-taken-by-nasa/photostory/117122999.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:22:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When Salim Khan revealed why marital bliss has always evaded Salman Khan - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/why-is-salman-khan-single-after-aishwarya-rai-katrina-kaif-salim-khan-reveals-reason-behind-no-marriage-in-throwback-101736506920769.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/why-is-salman-khan-single-after-aishwarya-rai-katrina-kaif-salim-khan-reveals-reason-behind-no-marriage-in-throwback-101736506920769.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:16:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When Salim Khan revealed why marital bliss has always evaded Salman Khan - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/why-is-salman-khan-single-after-aishwarya-rai-katrina-kaif-salim-khan-reveals-reason-behind-no-marriage-in-throwback-101736506920769.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/why-is-salman-khan-single-after-aishwarya-rai-katrina-kaif-salim-khan-reveals-reason-behind-no-marriage-in-throwback-101736506920769.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:16:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Gautam Gambhir Lagging Behind...": Coach's Every Error In Australia Tour Brutally Singled Out - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Lagging Behind...: Coach's Every Error In Australia Tour Brutally Singled Out</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/652mmrt_gautam-gambhir-ind-vs-aus_625x300_05_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Gautam Gambhir Lagging Behind..." />
<figcaption>File image of Gautam Gambhir. © BCCI</figcaption>
<p>Indian cricket team head coach Gautam Gambhir faces criticism after his team's losses against New Zealand and Australia. Former teammate Mohammad Kaif has pointed out several tactical errors made by Gambhir during the Australia tour.</p>
<ul>
<li>Gambhir has received backlash for back-to-back Test series losses.</li>
<li>Mohammad Kaif expressed concerns over Gambhir's tactics in a viral video.</li>
<li>Kaif questioned Gambhir's decisions regarding player selections in key matches.</li>
<li>The BCCI plans to review Gambhir's performance along with captain Rohit Sharma.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The best coach is always the one who is tactically No. 1,” Kaif stated, emphasizing the need for Gambhir to justify his decisions.</blockquote>
<p>Criticism of Gambhir's coaching abilities raises questions about the future of the Indian cricket team and its strategy moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-lagging-behind-coachs-every-error-in-australia-tour-brutally-singled-out-7432850</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-lagging-behind-coachs-every-error-in-australia-tour-brutally-singled-out-7432850</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:11:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Avoid panic’: Amid HMPV scare, Pune district collector calls for taking precautionary measures - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pune District Collector Addresses HMPV Concerns, Urges Calm and Precautions</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/hmpv_846863.jpg?w=640" alt="A ward of the Indira Gandhi Hospital being prepared for patients infected with Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) after two cases were detected, in Nagpur, Friday, Jan. 10, 2025. (PTI Photo)" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>A ward of the Indira Gandhi Hospital being prepared for patients infected with Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) after two cases were detected, in Nagpur, Friday, Jan. 10, 2025. (PTI Photo)</figcaption>
<p>Pune District Collector Jitendra Dudi has reassured citizens regarding the Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), stating that it is not a new threat and advising against panic. He emphasized the importance of basic health precautions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The district saw around 20 HMPV cases in the pediatric group and 4-5 cases in adults.</li>
  <li>No unusual surge in respiratory illnesses associated with HMPV has been reported in the country.</li>
  <li>Dr. Aarti Kinikar noted that the last HMPV case in Pune was detected on November 28 of last year.</li>
  <li>The state has increased surveillance due to an outbreak in China.</li>
  <li>A total of 48,019 individuals with suspected symptoms were screened in Maharashtra recently.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is not a new virus and we have urged people not to panic.” - Jitendra Dudi</blockquote>
<p>Health officials stress the need for calm as the situation develops; monitoring will continue to ensure public safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/pune/avoid-panic-hmpv-pune-district-collector-measures-9771890/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/pune/avoid-panic-hmpv-pune-district-collector-measures-9771890/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:06:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who would be Narendra Modi's first call after his happiest moment? PM answers - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who would be Narendra Modi's first call after his happiest moment? PM answers</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/pm_modi_1736433371032_1736506368577.png" alt="In the podcast, released by Zerodha co-founder Nikhil Kamath, PM Narendra Modi recalled a conversation with his mother.(X/nikhilkamathco)"> <figcaption>In the podcast, released by Zerodha co-founder Nikhil Kamath, PM Narendra Modi recalled a conversation with his mother.(X/nikhilkamathco)</figcaption><p>In his first podcast appearance, Prime Minister Narendra Modi shared that his mother would have been the first person he would call during his happiest moment. He reflected on significant events in his life and emphasized the importance of family.</p><ul><li>PM Modi discussed personal moments, including a pivotal call to his mother after hoisting the Indian flag at Lal Chowk in Srinagar.</li><li>He recalled his experience during an attack on his convoy in Punjab and the emotional significance of the call.</li><li>Modi talked about his childhood, political challenges, and lessons learned along the way.</li><li>The Prime Minister acknowledged his humanity and the inevitability of making mistakes.</li></ul><blockquote>“For me, it was a moment of joy and I also thought that my mother would have been worried.” - PM Narendra Modi</blockquote><p>This podcast marks an intimate look at Modi's thoughts on family, politics, and his life experiences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/who-would-be-narendra-modis-first-call-after-his-happiest-moment-pm-answers-101736505969452.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/who-would-be-narendra-modis-first-call-after-his-happiest-moment-pm-answers-101736505969452.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:50:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sambhal mosque well row: SC orders status quo, issues notice to Centre, ASI - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Orders Status Quo on Sambhal Mosque Well Dispute</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><p>In a significant ruling, the Supreme Court has ordered a status quo on the controversy surrounding a private well near the Mughal-era Jama Masjid mosque in Sambhal, Uttar Pradesh, while issuing notices to relevant authorities.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court intervened to order a status quo regarding a private well claimed by the mosque's management committee.</li><li>Notices were issued to the Centre, ASI, and private individuals involved in the case.</li><li>The dispute arose from the district administration's initiative to revive old temples and wells, which included the contested well.</li><li>Concerns of historical significance and potential violence surrounding the site prompted the Supreme Court's urgent intervention.</li><li>Previous violence related to the well had resulted in fatalities, leading to the need for judicial action.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have been drawing water from the well since time immemorial.” - Huzefa Ahmadi, Senior Advocate</blockquote><p>The Supreme Court's decision highlights its role in maintaining peace and harmony amid contentious religious disputes and emphasizes the importance of ensuring due process in legal proceedings regarding historically significant sites.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/sambhal-mosque-well-row-sc-orders-status-quo-issues-notice-to-centre-asi/article69084777.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/sambhal-mosque-well-row-sc-orders-status-quo-issues-notice-to-centre-asi/article69084777.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress takes dig at PM Modi over ‘I'm not a God' remark in podcast with Nikhil Kamath - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/congress-takes-dig-at-pm-modi-over-im-not-a-god-remark-in-podcast-with-nikhil-kamath-101736505505210.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/congress-takes-dig-at-pm-modi-over-im-not-a-god-remark-in-podcast-with-nikhil-kamath-101736505505210.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:09:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress takes dig at PM Modi over ‘I'm not a God' remark in podcast with Nikhil Kamath - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/congress-takes-dig-at-pm-modi-over-im-not-a-god-remark-in-podcast-with-nikhil-kamath-101736505505210.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/congress-takes-dig-at-pm-modi-over-im-not-a-god-remark-in-podcast-with-nikhil-kamath-101736505505210.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:09:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IIP growth rises to a six-month high of 5.2% in November - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IIP Growth Reaches 5.2% in November, the Highest in Six Months</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/07/20240716103554_petrochemical4.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Industrial production for November" title="Industrial production for November" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Industrial production for November</figcaption><p>The Index of Industrial Production (IIP) in India has grown by 5.2% in November, marking the highest growth rate in the last six months.</p><ul><li>The core sector output expanded to a four-month high of 4.3% in November.</li><li>This growth is compared to the previous month's growth rate of 3.7%.</li><li>Continued growth indicates positive trends in industrial activity across various sectors.</li></ul><blockquote>“This growth signifies a recovery in industrial production post-pandemic.”</blockquote><p>This increase in IIP reflects the resilience of the industrial sector and its importance for the overall economy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/europe/?url=https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/iip-growth-rises-to-a-six-month-high-of-5-2-in-november-12907472.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/europe/?url=https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/iip-growth-rises-to-a-six-month-high-of-5-2-in-november-12907472.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:05:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND-W vs IRE-W Highlights, 1st ODI: India take 1-0 lead in series with six-wicket victory over hosts - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Women Secure Six-Wicket Victory Over Ireland in 1st ODI</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 10 Jan 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p>
<img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/IND-W-vs-IRE-W-1st-ODI-Match-Live-1.png?w=300" alt="IND-W vs IRE-W 1st ODI Match Live" title="IND-W vs IRE-W Live Streaming: When and where to watch India Women vs Ireland Women 1st ODI live on TV, Online">
<figcaption>IND-W vs IRE-W Live Streaming: When and where to watch India Women vs Ireland Women 1st ODI live on TV, Online</figcaption>
<p>India Women started their tour of Ireland successfully by winning the first ODI with a six-wicket margin, chasing down Ireland’s total comfortably.</p>
<ul>
  <li>India Women chased down Ireland's target of 239 runs, ending at 240/4 in 34.3 overs.</li>
  <li>Ireland posted 238/7 in their 50 overs, with notable contributions from Gaby Lewis (92) and Leah Paul (59).</li>
  <li>Pratika Rawal top-scored for India with 89 runs, supported by Smriti Mandhana’s quick 41 and Tejal Hasabnis with an unbeaten 53.</li>
  <li>Indian bowlers performed well, with Priya Mishra taking 2 wickets for 56 runs and Aimee Maguire claiming 3 for 57 for Ireland.</li>
  <li>The win gave India a 1-0 lead in the series, setting up excitement for the next matches.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"India's efficient batting performance and disciplined bowling efforts were key to their victory."</blockquote>
<p>Looking ahead, India aims to maintain their winning momentum in the upcoming ODI matches against Ireland.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/sports/ind-w-vs-ire-w-live-score-1st-odi-catch-all-the-live-action-here-between-india-women-vs-ireland-women/3711684/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/sports/ind-w-vs-ire-w-live-score-1st-odi-catch-all-the-live-action-here-between-india-women-vs-ireland-women/3711684/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:52:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[THIS bowler use to bowl 150kmph but retired ahead of ICC Champions Trophy 2025, his name is... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/this-bowler-use-to-bowl-150kmph-but-retired-ahead-of-icc-champions-trophy-2025-his-name-is-419212/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/this-bowler-use-to-bowl-150kmph-but-retired-ahead-of-icc-champions-trophy-2025-his-name-is-419212/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:51:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[THIS bowler use to bowl 150kmph but retired ahead of ICC Champions Trophy 2025, his name is... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/this-bowler-use-to-bowl-150kmph-but-retired-ahead-of-icc-champions-trophy-2025-his-name-is-419212/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/this-bowler-use-to-bowl-150kmph-but-retired-ahead-of-icc-champions-trophy-2025-his-name-is-419212/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:51:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND-W vs IRE-W Live Score, 1st ODI: Stay tuned for latest updates between India Women vs Ireland Women - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPV1pEeDJBR3J5aHp5MFhpSk9sSWNlM0tyNDktZ2hRNzJlOE9yd1dYRGlsdXNsN1ZxeExQekFkWXdKSnotRjN0Tjh1OWVqbl8yWm5VZ2Vhb2NwY3BXbkRmc3VHRVFnUFhGV0VIVWNTS3g3Y0dWd2VVMmdaMHNTVnZJSWV3M1F3LVcxcHF4VG9CYzI4X01vYWlaRDdkbXJPTXVEMVViOXBwWmY4eDJxQmRLbDZpTVNKM1RGd0VrUjIxSkpNUzhpOEVlWUxpeHIxeTFsdG9Zek41bE9IVUxueDNmMnBuYWrSAesBQVVfeXFMUEh6aHJqSFBZbnFFdURsZmpZZWFXUTdvQzVNZWhEOWY5bWZUbzlUbFZfR3RwRlhKNWk1b29sMThlR3E4ZnVnN0VTRkt5WlhRekF1dTNMNm1IcWF2aGZuMlQwQkllWU9scjNFWWQ3a1h3Qjl4Z0QzT3BRdWg5TGNEeGk4dEZuMU9Md0NXMHM1OHR6dTYxOGwzc0EwTzR6Y3VtWFE3OVV3QXBYZjZxTlVOWHFKcEFwNElZVjhESjZoYXFvalVTRkl3eXFKekVFNGx4S2dFVXJUaTZsR3I0aF9xblIzcWpPWjZFazhtaw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPV1pEeDJBR3J5aHp5MFhpSk9sSWNlM0tyNDktZ2hRNzJlOE9yd1dYRGlsdXNsN1ZxeExQekFkWXdKSnotRjN0Tjh1OWVqbl8yWm5VZ2Vhb2NwY3BXbkRmc3VHRVFnUFhGV0VIVWNTS3g3Y0dWd2VVMmdaMHNTVnZJSWV3M1F3LVcxcHF4VG9CYzI4X01vYWlaRDdkbXJPTXVEMVViOXBwWmY4eDJxQmRLbDZpTVNKM1RGd0VrUjIxSkpNUzhpOEVlWUxpeHIxeTFsdG9Zek41bE9IVUxueDNmMnBuYWrSAesBQVVfeXFMUEh6aHJqSFBZbnFFdURsZmpZZWFXUTdvQzVNZWhEOWY5bWZUbzlUbFZfR3RwRlhKNWk1b29sMThlR3E4ZnVnN0VTRkt5WlhRekF1dTNMNm1IcWF2aGZuMlQwQkllWU9scjNFWWQ3a1h3Qjl4Z0QzT3BRdWg5TGNEeGk4dEZuMU9Md0NXMHM1OHR6dTYxOGwzc0EwTzR6Y3VtWFE3OVV3QXBYZjZxTlVOWHFKcEFwNElZVjhESjZoYXFvalVTRkl3eXFKekVFNGx4S2dFVXJUaTZsR3I0aF9xblIzcWpPWjZFazhtaw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:46:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The hidden dangers of air pollution and fog on human health - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/the-hidden-dangers-of-air-pollution-and-fog-on-human-health/articleshow/117120360.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/the-hidden-dangers-of-air-pollution-and-fog-on-human-health/articleshow/117120360.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The hidden dangers of air pollution and fog on human health - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/the-hidden-dangers-of-air-pollution-and-fog-on-human-health/articleshow/117120360.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/the-hidden-dangers-of-air-pollution-and-fog-on-human-health/articleshow/117120360.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer Box Office Day 1: Ram Charan Delivers 33% Higher Morning Hindi Occupancy Than Last Sankranti Hit HanuMan! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Box Office Day 1: Ram Charan Delivers 33% Higher Morning Hindi Occupancy Than Last Sankranti Hit</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2025/01/game-changer-box-office-day-1-ram-charan-delivers-33-higher-morning-hindi-occupancy-than-last-sankranti-hit-hanuman-01.jpg" alt="Game Changer Box Office Day 1: Ram Charan Delivers 33% Higher Morning Hindi Occupancy HanuMan!"><figcaption>Game Changer Box Office Day 1: Ram Charan Starts Big! ( Photo Credit – YouTube )</figcaption><p>Ram Charan’s Game Changer has started on a very strong note at the box office, securing an occupancy of 47.58% in theaters from the morning and afternoon shows.</p><ul><li>The film stars Kiara Advani along with Ram Charan.</li><li>Game Changer aims to break previous Sankranti records.</li><li>The Hindi version recorded a 33% increase in occupancy compared to last year's Sankranti hit HanuMan.</li></ul><blockquote>“An honest IAS officer’s fight against a corrupt political system through fair and transparent elections.”</blockquote><p>Overall, Game Changer shows promise at the box office and could become Ram Charan’s biggest Sankranti opening.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/game-changer-box-office-day-1-ram-charan-delivers-33-higher-morning-hindi-occupancy-than-last-sankranti-hit-hanuman/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/game-changer-box-office-day-1-ram-charan-delivers-33-higher-morning-hindi-occupancy-than-last-sankranti-hit-hanuman/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:34:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iron lines in the X-ray detected from a binary black hole system that can help infer their properties - Department Of Science & Technology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://dst.gov.in/iron-lines-x-ray-detected-binary-black-hole-system-can-help-infer-their-properties</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dst.gov.in/iron-lines-x-ray-detected-binary-black-hole-system-can-help-infer-their-properties</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:30:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iron lines in the X-ray detected from a binary black hole system that can help infer their properties - Department Of Science & Technology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://dst.gov.in/iron-lines-x-ray-detected-binary-black-hole-system-can-help-infer-their-properties</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dst.gov.in/iron-lines-x-ray-detected-binary-black-hole-system-can-help-infer-their-properties</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:30:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BepiColombo mission to Mercury provides new insights into planet formation - Innovation News Network]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQb3NjVWVHZWI5RDlnT0U1S2NHSHJjdnJuUmRpYXhkNEZHRzVWVnlCTG9uakNRQ2RaYU9fRjRYWkloNGlPemk4aFNDLXNlTk8xdUZZVjlSS0VsTUlsY3VsYVE3Q0plSFhhMjNJN0UweUlGaDNjSTFFSV95MGY5MjExc1poMXMxek5HcC1zalVUUzJYVW50WEtCOEJKcFlLbnFNYTVMcjdCTWhTaGZnOXpzeDNGWlJIWkVaNENV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQb3NjVWVHZWI5RDlnT0U1S2NHSHJjdnJuUmRpYXhkNEZHRzVWVnlCTG9uakNRQ2RaYU9fRjRYWkloNGlPemk4aFNDLXNlTk8xdUZZVjlSS0VsTUlsY3VsYVE3Q0plSFhhMjNJN0UweUlGaDNjSTFFSV95MGY5MjExc1poMXMxek5HcC1zalVUUzJYVW50WEtCOEJKcFlLbnFNYTVMcjdCTWhTaGZnOXpzeDNGWlJIWkVaNENV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:26:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rajiv Bajaj counters L&T Chairman's controversial ‘90-hour work week’ remark, says ‘let it start from the top’ | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rajiv Bajaj counters L&T Chairman’s controversial ‘90-hour work week’ remark, says ‘let it start from the top’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Amid ongoing controversy over L&T chairman S N Subrahmanyan's 90-hour work week remark, Rajiv Bajaj, Managing Director of Bajaj Auto, emphasized the importance of quality of work over quantity, suggesting that if a 90-hour week is to be enforced, it should start from the top management.</p><ul><li>Rajiv Bajaj stated, 'Let 90 hours start from the top' during an interview with CNBC-TV18.</li><li>S N Subrahmanyan's comments about working on weekends sparked backlash, with many industrialists and politicians voicing their concerns.</li><li>Bajaj criticized the notion of long hours, advocating for improved outcomes through better leadership and empowerment of employees.</li><li>RPG Group’s Harsh Goenka also spoke against the excessive work hours, calling for a balanced work-life approach.</li><li>L&T clarified that Subrahmanyan's comments were intended to inspire extraordinary efforts for the nation's progress.</li></ul><blockquote>“Number of hours of work doesn’t matter, quality of work does. We need a kinder, gentler world more than ever before.” - Rajiv Bajaj</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the discourse surrounding work hours continues to evolve, balancing productivity demands with the necessity for employee well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/rajiv-bajaj-counters-l-t-chairman-s-n-subrahmanyans-90-hour-work-week-remark-says-let-it-start-from-top-11736508040967.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/rajiv-bajaj-counters-l-t-chairman-s-n-subrahmanyans-90-hour-work-week-remark-says-let-it-start-from-top-11736508040967.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:24:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SENSEX, NIFTY extend losses into 3rd session on surging crude prices, FII outflows - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SENSEX, NIFTY extend losses into 3rd session on surging crude prices, FII outflows</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Friday, Publication Source: Not specified</p>
<p>Equity benchmark indices SENSEX and NIFTY faced losses for the third consecutive session due to concerns over economic growth and rising crude oil prices.</p>
<img src='image_link.jpg' alt='Market image' />
<figcaption>Equity market trends affected by crude oil prices.</figcaption>
<ul>
<li>SENSEX dropped 241.30 points to close at 77,378.91.</li>
<li>NIFTY fell by 95 points to settle at 23,431.50.</li>
<li>Major laggards included IndusInd Bank, NTPC, and Tata Steel.</li>
<li>Tata Consultancy Services reported nearly a 6% increase in net profit.</li>
<li>FIIs sold off equities worth ₹7,170.87 crore on Thursday.</li>
<li>Global markets, including Asian and European stocks, closed lower.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Surging crude oil prices and a strengthening dollar index contributed to the weak trend in equities.”</blockquote>
<p>The persistent losses in SENSEX and NIFTY reflect broader concerns regarding economic conditions and market performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/sensex-nifty-extend-losses-into-3rd-session-on-surging-crude-prices-fii-outflows/article-139860/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/sensex-nifty-extend-losses-into-3rd-session-on-surging-crude-prices-fii-outflows/article-139860/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:23:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['...Not American': Justin Trudeau Fires Back At Donald Trump Over 'Canada 51st State' Jibe - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Trudeau Responds to Donald Trump's 'Canada 51st State' Remarks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-117119155,thumbsize-1890327,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/117119155.jpg" alt="Justin Trudeau Responds To Donald Trump's Jibes" title="Justin Trudeau Responds To Donald Trump's Jibes"><figcaption>Justin Trudeau Responds To Donald Trump's Jibes</figcaption><p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau dismissed remarks from President-elect Donald Trump suggesting Canada could become the '51st State' of the United States, labeling them as a distraction tactic.</p><ul><li>Trump's suggestion followed his comments regarding imposing tariffs on Canadian imports unless Ottawa enhances border security.</li><li>Trudeau emphasized Canadian pride and identity as distinct from being American.</li><li>Trump reiterated the '51st State' notion on his social media platform and criticized Canada's trade practices.</li><li>Amidst these remarks, Trudeau announced his resignation as Prime Minister.</li></ul><blockquote>“Canadians are incredibly proud of being Canadian. One of the ways we define ourselves most easily is - we are not American.” - Justin Trudeau</blockquote><p>Despite announcing his resignation, Trudeau will remain in office until a new leader is chosen for his party.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/world/canada/justin-trudeau-fires-back-at-donald-trump-over-canada-51st-state-jibe-not-american-article-117118670</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/world/canada/justin-trudeau-fires-back-at-donald-trump-over-canada-51st-state-jibe-not-american-article-117118670</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:10:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee hits lifetime low of 85.97 vs USD amid persistent FII outflows, rising crude oil prices - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee hits lifetime low of 85.97 vs USD amid persistent FII outflows, rising crude oil prices</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/12/20241210070529_Rupee-shutterstock.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Rupee" title="Rupee" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Image illustrating the Indian Rupee's decline.</figcaption><p>The Indian rupee has fallen to an all-time low of 85.97 against the US dollar, affected by Foreign Institutional Investors' outflows, high oil prices, and rising US treasury yields.</p><ul><li>The rupee closed at 85.9728, down from 85.8788 at open.</li><li>The trading range today was between 85.8638 and 85.9750 against the dollar.</li><li>Risk aversion has led to increased demand for the dollar amidst selling in equities.</li><li>Brent crude oil prices are above $78.60 per barrel, adding pressure on the rupee.</li><li>Expert Anil Kumar Bhansali highlights the impact of upcoming US job data on currency markets.</li></ul><blockquote>“Rupee closed at its weakest as risk aversion was the name of the game...” - Anil Kumar Bhansali</blockquote><p>The decline of the rupee illustrates the challenges facing the Indian economy amidst global financial pressures, highlighting the need for strategic measures to stabilize the currency.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/rupee-hits-lifetime-low-of-85-97-amid-persistent-fii-outflows-rising-crude-oil-prices-12907611.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/rupee-hits-lifetime-low-of-85-97-amid-persistent-fii-outflows-rising-crude-oil-prices-12907611.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:47:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Underworld Don Chhota Rajan Admitted To AIIMS-Delhi For Sinus Treatment, Might Need Surgery - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chhota Rajan Hospitalized for Sinus Treatment at AIIMS-Delhi</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Underworld don Chhota Rajan, who is incarcerated in Tihar Jail, has been admitted to AIIMS Delhi for medical treatment." title="Underworld don Chhota Rajan, who is incarcerated in Tihar Jail, has been admitted to AIIMS Delhi for medical treatment.">
<figcaption>Underworld don Chhota Rajan hospitalized for medical treatment.</figcaption>
<p>Underworld don Chhota Rajan has been admitted to AIIMS Delhi for sinus treatment, with doctors suggesting that he might need surgery.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Chhota Rajan, also known as Rajendra Sadashiv Nikalje, is in Tihar Jail.</li>
  <li>He was arrested by Indonesian police in October 2015 and extradited to India.</li>
  <li>In May 2024, he was sentenced to life imprisonment for the murder of hotelier Jaya Shetty.</li>
  <li>Rajan has been found guilty in seven cases, including six in Mumbai.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Doctors hinted that Chhota Rajan might need an operation owing to which he has been admitted.”</blockquote>
<p>This hospitalization could indicate serious health issues for Chhota Rajan, raising questions about his medical care while incarcerated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/underworld-don-chhota-rajan-admitted-to-aiims-delhi-9184166.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/underworld-don-chhota-rajan-admitted-to-aiims-delhi-9184166.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:34:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Damage control': Congress mock PM Modi 'not a God' remark in his first podcast appearance - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Damage control': Congress mock PM Modi 'not a God' remark in his first podcast appearance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117118010,imgsize-1400100,width-400,resizemode-4/117118010.jpg" alt="'Damage control': Congress mock PM Modi 'not a God' remark in his first podcast appearance"><figcaption>Prime Minister Modi during his first podcast</figcaption><p>NEW DELHI: The Congress on Friday mocked Prime Minister Narendra Modi for his comments during his first podcast with Zerodha co-founder Nikhil Kamath.</p><ul><li>Congress leader Jairam Ramesh stated that Modi's remarks were an attempt at damage control after he had claimed he was sent by God.</li><li>During the podcast, Modi mentioned his previous role as Gujarat's chief minister and acknowledged that he is human and can make mistakes.</li><li>This podcast marks Modi's debut in the podcasting platform, despite his regular presence in other media.</li></ul><blockquote>“I said something in an insensitive way. Mistakes happen. I am human, not a God,” said PM Modi.</blockquote><p>The discussion emphasizes the need for public service-driven individuals in politics, focusing on mission rather than personal ambition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/damage-control-congress-mock-pm-modi-not-a-god-remark-in-his-first-podcast-appearance/articleshow/117117857.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/damage-control-congress-mock-pm-modi-not-a-god-remark-in-his-first-podcast-appearance/articleshow/117117857.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's industrial production grows 5.2% in Nov as against 3.5% in Oct - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/indicators/indias-industrial-production-grows-5-2-in-nov-from-3-5-in-oct/articleshow/117117022.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/indicators/indias-industrial-production-grows-5-2-in-nov-from-3-5-in-oct/articleshow/117117022.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:31:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>