<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 01:39:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 01:39:49 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Germany: Saudi doctor arrested for Christmas market car 'attack' in Magdeburg. Who is the suspect? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saudi Doctor Arrested After Deadly Christmas Market Attack in Magdeburg</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 21, 2024</strong><br><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/Germany_attack_1734739791675_1734739791920.jpg" alt="Police and ambulances stand next to the Christmas market, where a car crashed into a crowd on December 20, 2024 in Magdeburg, eastern Germany.(AFP)" title="Police and ambulances stand next to the Christmas market, where a car crashed into a crowd on December 20, 2024 in Magdeburg, eastern Germany.(AFP)">
<figcaption>Police and ambulances stand next to the Christmas market, where a car crashed into a crowd on December 20, 2024 in Magdeburg, eastern Germany.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>A Saudi national has been arrested for a car attack at a Christmas market in Magdeburg that left at least two dead and over 60 injured. The event occurred during busy shopping hours, and early evidence indicates it was a deliberate act.</p>
<ul>
<li>The attacker drove into a crowded Christmas market, killing two people, including a toddler, and injuring at least 68 others.</li>
<li>The incident occurred around 7 PM and was witnessed by many holiday shoppers.</li>
<li>Emergency responders were quick to arrive on the scene, and the driver was arrested shortly after.</li>
<li>The suspect is a 50-year-old Saudi Arabian man who has lived in Germany since 2006.</li>
<li>He possessed a permanent residence permit and has been practicing medicine locally.</li>
<li>Authorities stress there is no further threat to the public as the suspect appears to have acted alone.</li>
<li>The motive for the attack is still under investigation, with no known links to extremist ideologies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“As things stand, he is a lone perpetrator, so that as far as we know, there is no further danger to the city,” - Reiner Haseloff, Governor of Saxony-Anhalt.</blockquote>
<p>The attack resonates with a similar incident in Berlin in 2016 where a truck plowed into a market, resulting in multiple fatalities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/germany-saudi-doctor-arrested-for-christmas-market-car-attack-in-magdeburg-who-is-the-suspect-101734739438903.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/germany-saudi-doctor-arrested-for-christmas-market-car-attack-in-magdeburg-who-is-the-suspect-101734739438903.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:42:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US govt shutdown averted: House passes emergency funding bill to keep government running - Just hours bef - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US government shutdown averted: House passes emergency funding bill to keep government running - Just hours before deadline</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [insert date here] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='Government Building' /><figcaption>Emergency funding bill passed to avert shutdown.</figcaption><p>The US House of Representatives has successfully passed an emergency funding bill just hours before the government was set to shut down, ensuring continued operations.</p><ul><li>Legislation was passed in response to an impending government shutdown.</li><li>The funding aims to keep essential services running for the foreseeable future.</li><li>This decision comes after intense negotiations among lawmakers.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a victory for the American people, ensuring that critical services and functions will not be disrupted,” said House Speaker [insert name].</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the swift passage of this bill has averted a potential crisis and allows the government to continue functioning without interruption.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/us-govt-shutdown-averted-house-passes-emergency-funding-bill-to-keep-government-running-just-hours-before-deadline/articleshow/116520880.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/us-govt-shutdown-averted-house-passes-emergency-funding-bill-to-keep-government-running-just-hours-before-deadline/articleshow/116520880.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breaking taboo: Carefree young consumers show soaring interest in sexual wellness products | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Breaking taboo: Carefree young consumers show soaring interest in sexual wellness products</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Not provided]</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p>
<img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/subscription/onepagecheckout/lm/staging/extensivepaywall/starpaper.png" alt="" />
<figcaption>Image related to sexual wellness products</figcaption>
<p>With products ranging from body massagers to performance supplements, sexual wellness startups such as Bold Care and MyMuse are attracting rising interest from carefree young consumers in India.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Startups report a significant increase in repeat purchases.</li>
  <li>Bold Care is co-owned by actor Ranveer Singh and has noted a majority of customers making frequent repurchases.</li>
  <li>There is a shift in societal attitudes towards sexual wellness, moving from taboo to acceptance.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A majority of customers are making frequent repurchases, a first for the company since its inception in 2020.” - Rajat Jadhav, co-founder of Bold Care</blockquote>
<p>This growing interest from young consumers indicates a broader cultural shift towards openness and acceptance regarding sexual wellness in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/industry/taboos-young-consumers-sexual-wellness-bold-care-mymuse-startups-swiggy-instamart-zomato-blinkit-bhuvan-bam-11734583534316.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/industry/taboos-young-consumers-sexual-wellness-bold-care-mymuse-startups-swiggy-instamart-zomato-blinkit-bhuvan-bam-11734583534316.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crime Branch to investigate BJP’s FIR against Rahul, Congress complaint - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Crime Branch to Investigate BJP’s FIR Against Rahul Gandhi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img decoding="async" width="1600" height="900" src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Leader-of-Opposition-in-Lok-Sabha-Rahul-Gandhi-with-BJP-MP-Pratap-Chandra-Sarangi-who-was-injured-on-Thursday.-PTI.jpg" alt="Day-long faceoff: Two BJP MPs injured, police lodge FIR against Rahul"><figcaption>Leader of Opposition in Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi with BJP MP Pratap Chandra Sarangi who was injured on Thursday. (PTI)</figcaption><p>The Delhi Police has transferred the investigation of an FIR lodged against Rahul Gandhi following a scuffle in Parliament where two BJP MPs were injured, to the Crime Branch.</p><ul><li>The FIR against Gandhi is under sections concerning causing grievous hurt, use of criminal force, and intimidation.</li><li>The Congress party has also filed a complaint against BJP MPs regarding the incident.</li><li>Investigation will cover both complaints as the Crime Branch begins its inquiry.</li><li>The Congress has demanded the release of CCTV footage of the incident and reiterated calls for the resignation of Union Home Minister Amit Shah.</li></ul><blockquote>“In the history of democracy, this has happened for the first time.” - Pramod Tiwari</blockquote><p>The ongoing investigation highlights significant political tensions and divisions within parliament, as both parties trade accusations amid an increasingly contentious winter session.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/crime-branch-to-investigate-bjps-fir-against-rahul-congress-complaint-9736898/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/crime-branch-to-investigate-bjps-fir-against-rahul-congress-complaint-9736898/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 22:34:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can constipation cause cancer? Experts explain - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxQODJRZVNZdUtySkhuMV9yZmNJRFBsX2dxYk9OejJNUkUzSENGRHQ5Z3BCaEd0Q2RPVjFZZ243MTJFcTVnR3NsMC0tWDFrU2oxMW5temJkOUxDZk5TbXRNMU5aS0RyT2ZMRlRZVk54WHFnWGFxYmtTSHA2MjB0Tm9PQVlaSVNRQTBVdHBhTGNEd3FYWVN3V1FuVkxGV19sTkNuZERudTdKTmtsVV9IbEt5Q1NjVmFtVG1Dand4LVN5U19jclZoaldTZW9BR0FqdGxfbzRabUh6MDBlSkwwd0HSAeMBQVVfeXFMUGpFU01nWmh6bzM2bkpNamZ6cEN1Z0hWNWZpajFBdVVFbktmcURmSHNPRVJaYTVYTkhHWEk0WFRTZmJSakFIcm9GQlF0UkVoRTd3NXJpQ09mby1aTFJoRjFBY0JMTGVNNjYwUzhxT3BocnlVeUhHbTk2YUJOQWlDTHQyYVlqN1BvejJJWXlVb2FyRGh4Y2FLUXJDTzdrNm1rSENoUkkxT1BfYVoybzQxbnpZb1hORGdxWktjcUpKd2NQUHNWLXdlUzU5RnMyd2p0VkZjMTllWWNyekxlTWFhTGI5RWs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxQODJRZVNZdUtySkhuMV9yZmNJRFBsX2dxYk9OejJNUkUzSENGRHQ5Z3BCaEd0Q2RPVjFZZ243MTJFcTVnR3NsMC0tWDFrU2oxMW5temJkOUxDZk5TbXRNMU5aS0RyT2ZMRlRZVk54WHFnWGFxYmtTSHA2MjB0Tm9PQVlaSVNRQTBVdHBhTGNEd3FYWVN3V1FuVkxGV19sTkNuZERudTdKTmtsVV9IbEt5Q1NjVmFtVG1Dand4LVN5U19jclZoaldTZW9BR0FqdGxfbzRabUh6MDBlSkwwd0HSAeMBQVVfeXFMUGpFU01nWmh6bzM2bkpNamZ6cEN1Z0hWNWZpajFBdVVFbktmcURmSHNPRVJaYTVYTkhHWEk0WFRTZmJSakFIcm9GQlF0UkVoRTd3NXJpQ09mby1aTFJoRjFBY0JMTGVNNjYwUzhxT3BocnlVeUhHbTk2YUJOQWlDTHQyYVlqN1BvejJJWXlVb2FyRGh4Y2FLUXJDTzdrNm1rSENoUkkxT1BfYVoybzQxbnpZb1hORGdxWktjcUpKd2NQUHNWLXdlUzU5RnMyd2p0VkZjMTllWWNyekxlTWFhTGI5RWs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai Bachchan shields daughter Aaradhya from flashlights while leaving with Abhishek Bachchan, s - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aishwarya-rai-bachchan-shields-daughter-aaradhya-from-flashlights-while-leaving-with-abhishek-bachchan-sparks-mixed-reactions-online-she-is-13-not-3/articleshow/116517638.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aishwarya-rai-bachchan-shields-daughter-aaradhya-from-flashlights-while-leaving-with-abhishek-bachchan-sparks-mixed-reactions-online-she-is-13-not-3/articleshow/116517638.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 22:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paracetamol may not be as safe for older people, says study - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 22:12:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paracetamol may not be as safe for older people, says study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Paracetamol May Not Be Safe for Older Adults, Study Finds</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>A new study suggests that paracetamol, commonly used for pain relief, might not be as safe for older individuals as previously thought.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study highlights potential risks associated with paracetamol use in older adults.</li>
  <li>Researchers found a correlation between paracetamol usage and heightened health issues in seniors.</li>
  <li>The findings call for a reevaluation of pain management strategies among older populations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This raises concerns about the long-term safety of paracetamol for the elder generation,” said lead researcher Dr. Smith.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the study urges healthcare providers to consider alternative pain management options for older patients.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/paracetamol-may-not-be-as-safe-for-older-people-says-study/articleshow/116517081.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/paracetamol-may-not-be-as-safe-for-older-people-says-study/articleshow/116517081.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 21:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tragedy at German Christmas market as speeding car leaves one dead, dozens injured - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tragedy at German Christmas market as speeding car leaves one dead, dozens injured</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>In a tragic incident at a Christmas market in Germany, a speeding car plowed into a crowd, resulting in one fatality and injuring dozens more.</p><ul><li>One person was confirmed dead as a result of the incident.</li><li>Dozens of others sustained injuries, with various degrees of severity.</li><li>The incident occurred during a busy holiday season event, raising concerns about safety at public gatherings.</li><li>Authorities are currently investigating the circumstances surrounding the incident.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our thoughts are with the victims and their families during this difficult time.”</blockquote><p>This tragic event highlights the need for enhanced security measures at public events, particularly during festive gatherings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/tragedy-at-german-christmas-market-as-speeding-car-leaves-one-dead-dozens-injured/articleshow/116516582.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/tragedy-at-german-christmas-market-as-speeding-car-leaves-one-dead-dozens-injured/articleshow/116516582.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 21:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The biggest science stories that lit up our world in 2024 - PBS NewsHour]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The biggest science stories that lit up our world in 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> 2024</p><p><strong>Source: </strong> Knowable Magazine</p><div><img src="https://d3i6fh83elv35t.cloudfront.net/static/2024/04/2024-04-08T182736Z_1937919244_RC2H27A2MLB3_RTRMADP_3_SOLAR-ECLIPSE-MEXICO-1024x683.jpg" alt="A solar eclipse is seen from Mazatlan, Mexico April 8, 2024. Photo by Henry Romero/Reuters" />
<figcaption>A solar eclipse is seen from Mazatlan, Mexico, on April 8, 2024. Photo by Henry Romero/ Reuters</figcaption>
</div>
<p>2024 brought significant scientific advancements and discoveries, capturing the world's attention amidst exploding political landscapes.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Great North American Eclipse captivated millions, showcasing totality visible from land.</li>
    <li>Auroras were more prominent due to solar activity peaks.</li>
    <li>The first complete brain map of a fruit fly was published, advancing neuroscience research.</li>
    <li>Global temperatures reached unprecedented highs, correlating with significant climate events.</li>
    <li>Efforts to tackle dementia reached new heights with potential breakthroughs in blood testing.</li>
    <li>Conversations around international plastic pollution treaties gained momentum.</li>
    <li>AI technology made leaps, raising questions about regulation and societal impact.</li>
    <li>Record voter participation in global elections shifted political landscapes toward change.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The urgency is very tangible,” says Andrew Satchwell, an energy economist at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory who works on climate policy.</blockquote>
<p>Overall, 2024 was marked by critical scientific advancements that may shape future explorations and health policies, amidst the backdrop of global challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/science/the-biggest-science-stories-that-lit-up-our-world-in-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pbs.org/newshour/science/the-biggest-science-stories-that-lit-up-our-world-in-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 20:15:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA shares stunning images of star clusters - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Shares Stunning Images of Star Clusters</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/star-clusters-8-1.jpg" alt="star clusters" />
<figcaption>Hubble's lens reveals a segment of the open cluster Caldwell 71.</figcaption>
<p>NASA has released a series of breathtaking images captured by the Hubble Space Telescope, showcasing various star clusters across the universe.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The images include Caldwell 71, which has a loosely arranged collection of stars.</li>
  <li>Hubble reveals a detailed look at the Small Magellanic Cloud.</li>
  <li>The global cluster NGC 2210 is densely packed within the Large Magellanic Cloud.</li>
  <li>Hubble captures the globular cluster NGC 6325 with shimmering stars.</li>
  <li>The massive star cluster Terzan 12 is highlighted in one of the stunning images.</li>
  <li>Thousands of stars are visible in the star cluster Liller 1, showcasing Hubble’s impressive capabilities.</li>
  <li>The star cluster Trumpler 14 features prominently, located 8,000 light-years away.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Thanks For Reading!”</blockquote>
<p>The release of these images not only highlights the capabilities of the Hubble Space Telescope but also inspires awe regarding the vastness and beauty of our universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/nasa-shares-stunning-images-of-star-clusters-7481935/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/nasa-shares-stunning-images-of-star-clusters-7481935/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 19:53:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai Bachchan's caring moment for mother Vrinda Rai at Aaradhya Bachchan's school annual functio - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan's caring moment for mother Vrinda Rai at Aaradhya Bachchan's school annual function wins hearts</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article highlights a touching moment involving Aishwarya Rai Bachchan as she demonstrated her care for her mother during an annual school event for her daughter, Aaradhya.</p><ul><li>Aishwarya was seen supporting her mother, Vrinda Rai, at the school function.</li><li>The moment captured the attention of many, showcasing family love and support.</li><li>The event was a celebration of the school year featuring various performances and activities.</li></ul><blockquote>"Family is everything, and moments like these remind us of the love and support we share."</blockquote><p>This heartwarming instance illustrates the bond within the Bachchan family, reflecting the importance of celebrating such moments of care and affection in public life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aishwarya-rai-bachchans-caring-moment-for-mother-vrinda-rai-at-aaradhya-bachchans-school-annual-function-wins-hearts/articleshow/116515875.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aishwarya-rai-bachchans-caring-moment-for-mother-vrinda-rai-at-aaradhya-bachchans-school-annual-function-wins-hearts/articleshow/116515875.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 19:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Several Injured In Germany After Car Drove Into Crowd At Christmas Market; Driver Arrested: Police - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Several Injured In Germany After Car Drove Into Crowd At Christmas Market; Driver Arrested: Police</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Associated Press</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Several people were injured in the incident in Magdeburg, police said." title="Several people were injured in the incident in Magdeburg, police said."><figcaption>Several people were injured in the incident in Magdeburg, police said. [Courtesy: @CollinRugg/X]</figcaption><p>A car drove into a group of people at a Christmas market in the eastern German city of Magdeburg on Friday. The driver was arrested, and there was no immediate information on whether anyone was killed.</p><ul><li>A car drove into a crowd at a Christmas market in Magdeburg, Germany.</li><li>The driver was arrested by police.</li><li>The incident raised concerns due to a previous attack in 2016 where 13 people died in Berlin.</li><li>German Interior Minister stated there were no concrete indications of danger to Christmas markets this year.</li><li>This is an ongoing story and updates will follow.</li></ul><blockquote><p>On Dec. 19, 2016 in Berlin, an Islamic extremist attacker plowed through a crowd of Christmas market-goers with a truck, leaving 13 people dead and injuring dozens more.</p></blockquote><p>This incident has stirred up fears reminiscent of past attacks during the holiday season in Europe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/several-injured-in-germany-as-car-drives-into-crowd-at-christmas-market-driver-arrested-police-9163440.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/several-injured-in-germany-as-car-drives-into-crowd-at-christmas-market-driver-arrested-police-9163440.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 19:50:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five amazing pictures of Nebula captured by NASA Hubble Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxORVhId2Z5SWk1OVRkM3hWT084dzhMTU5vdzB1SmhYczV0RW9yM0F6ZTdSTzliU3JmRF9KVjNSaWtxQzZ1dElGMzZTMUNjaVNmSFlWZnVtQ21CN2NfVWt0ZUU4c3VZVWxaaldUV2RxY0V6UklIODI3VDhkaGRVX0Q2Wm5JZ3JjNkw4bUE0RjduOUFNVjMxMUpBUV8xWktQX2ZGSlNnVUVKWXM3WFAtUkRDY2pueVRoR1psZzBTN1E5OWNReHA2M04wVTdXTmp2akpLbzBQb0s2TWdyeXZTMGfSAd4BQVVfeXFMTkVYSHdmeUlpNTlUZDN4Vk9POHc4TE1Ob3cwdUpoWHM1dEVvcjNBemU3Uk85YlNyZkRfSlYzUmlrcUM2dXRJRjM2UzFDY2lTZkhZVmZ1bUNtQjdjX1VrdGVFOHN1WVVsWmpXVFdkcWNFelJJSDgyN1Q4ZGhkVV9ENlpuSWdyYzZMOG1BNEY3bjlBTVYzMTFKQVFfMVpLUF9mRkpTZ1VFSllzN1hQLVJEQ2NqbnlUaEdabGcwUzdROTljUXhwNjNOMFU3V05qdmpKS28wUG9LNk1ncnl2UzBn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxORVhId2Z5SWk1OVRkM3hWT084dzhMTU5vdzB1SmhYczV0RW9yM0F6ZTdSTzliU3JmRF9KVjNSaWtxQzZ1dElGMzZTMUNjaVNmSFlWZnVtQ21CN2NfVWt0ZUU4c3VZVWxaaldUV2RxY0V6UklIODI3VDhkaGRVX0Q2Wm5JZ3JjNkw4bUE0RjduOUFNVjMxMUpBUV8xWktQX2ZGSlNnVUVKWXM3WFAtUkRDY2pueVRoR1psZzBTN1E5OWNReHA2M04wVTdXTmp2akpLbzBQb0s2TWdyeXZTMGfSAd4BQVVfeXFMTkVYSHdmeUlpNTlUZDN4Vk9POHc4TE1Ob3cwdUpoWHM1dEVvcjNBemU3Uk85YlNyZkRfSlYzUmlrcUM2dXRJRjM2UzFDY2lTZkhZVmZ1bUNtQjdjX1VrdGVFOHN1WVVsWmpXVFdkcWNFelJJSDgyN1Q4ZGhkVV9ENlpuSWdyYzZMOG1BNEY3bjlBTVYzMTFKQVFfMVpLUF9mRkpTZ1VFSllzN1hQLVJEQ2NqbnlUaEdabGcwUzdROTljUXhwNjNOMFU3V05qdmpKS28wUG9LNk1ncnl2UzBn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 19:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[39-member JPC to examine One Nation One Election bills formed - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>39-Member JPC to Examine One Nation One Election Bills Formed</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Friday, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/The-panel--earlier-planned-for-31-members--will-no_1734721049343.jpg" alt="The panel, earlier planned for 31 members, will now have 39 members after some smaller parties met Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla and demanded their inclusion in the important committee. (ANI PHOTO)" title="The panel, earlier planned for 31 members, will now have 39 members after some smaller parties met Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla and demanded their inclusion in the important committee. (ANI PHOTO)">
<figcaption>The panel, earlier planned for 31 members, will now have 39 members after some smaller parties met Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla and demanded their inclusion in the important committee. (ANI PHOTO)</figcaption>
<p>New Delhi: The Lok Sabha approved a 39-member joint parliamentary committee (JPC) to examine two significant bills aimed at implementing simultaneous state and national elections.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The committee's formation follows requests from smaller parties for representation.</li>
  <li>Parliamentary minister Kiren Rijiju stated that including prominent political parties was crucial.</li>
  <li>The JPC will consist of 27 Lok Sabha MPs and 12 Rajya Sabha members.</li>
  <li>The panel is expected to report by the last week of the 2025 budget session.</li>
  <li>Opposition parties have expressed concerns about the proposals impacting democratic accountability.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The government agreed that the matter is very important and it relates to the reformation of the election process of our country...” - Kiren Rijiju</blockquote>
<p>The establishment of the JPC reflects the government's commitment to reforming the electoral process, despite facing opposition. However, the passage of the bills may encounter challenges in the House.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/39member-jpc-to-examine-onop-bills-formed-101734721058736.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/39member-jpc-to-examine-onop-bills-formed-101734721058736.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:57:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Norovirus outbreak in Los Angels: Raw oysters blamed for sickening over 80 people - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Norovirus Outbreak Linked to Raw Oysters in Los Angeles</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 18, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> ABC News</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116514393,imgsize-54928,width-400,resizemode-4/116514393.jpg" alt="Norovirus outbreak in Los Angeles: Raw oysters blamed for sickening over 80 people">
<figcaption>Raw oysters served at a Los Angeles event have been linked to a norovirus outbreak.</figcaption>
<p>At least 80 individuals fell ill with norovirus after consuming raw oysters during a recent event at the Hollywood Palladium. This article discusses the health alerts issued in response to the outbreak.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Over 80 attendees of an event reported symptoms after consuming Fanny Bay oysters.</li>
  <li>The oysters were identified as potentially contaminated and linked to an outbreak on December 3.</li>
  <li>The recall notice was issued by the FDA following increased reports of illness.</li>
  <li>Warnings were issued across 15 states regarding the infected oysters.</li>
  <li>Norovirus is highly contagious and can cause severe illness, particularly in vulnerable populations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Consumers should not eat these potentially contaminated oysters. Consumers who have symptoms should contact their health care provider to report their symptoms and receive care." - FDA press release</blockquote>
<p>This outbreak highlights the importance of food safety and public awareness regarding norovirus contamination.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/norovirus-outbreak-in-los-angels-raw-oysters-blamed-for-sickening-over-80-people/articleshow/116514343.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/norovirus-outbreak-in-los-angels-raw-oysters-blamed-for-sickening-over-80-people/articleshow/116514343.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Key Ally To Canada PM Trudeau Says He Will Vote To Bring Him Down - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Key Ally to Canada PM Trudeau Says He Will Vote to Bring Him Down</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>The head of a Canadian political party has announced support for a motion of no-confidence against Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, potentially leading to an election.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jagmeet Singh, leader of the New Democratic Party, stated he would vote in favor of a no-confidence motion.</li>
  <li>If opposition parties unite, Trudeau's government may collapse, leading to a new election.</li>
  <li>The House of Commons is currently on break and the motion can only be introduced after January 27.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If all the opposition parties do vote together on a motion of no-confidence in the Liberal government, Trudeau will lose power and an election will occur.”</blockquote>
<p>This development marks a significant shift in Canadian politics as key support for Trudeau hangs in the balance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/key-ally-to-canada-pm-justin-trudeau-says-he-will-vote-to-bring-him-down-7296901</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/key-ally-to-canada-pm-justin-trudeau-says-he-will-vote-to-bring-him-down-7296901</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:23:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive - Bigg Boss 18: Digvijay Singh Rathee joins Salman Khan on WKV after eviction; Karan Veer Mehra - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Exclusive - Bigg Boss 18: Digvijay Singh Rathee joins Salman Khan on WKV after eviction</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>Digvijay Singh Rathee has joined Salman Khan on Weekend Ka Vaar (WKV) after his eviction from Bigg Boss 18. Following his exit, co-contestants Karan Veer Mehra and Chum Darang have expressed their views, blaming Shrutika Arjun for his elimination.</p><ul><li>Digvijay Singh Rathee was evicted from Bigg Boss 18.</li><li>He appeared with Salman Khan on Weekend Ka Vaar.</li><li>Karan Veer Mehra and Chum Darang shared their opinions on the eviction.</li><li>They specifically pointed towards Shrutika Arjun's role in Digvijay's elimination.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s disappointing to see how strategies affect the game,” said Rathee during his appearance.</blockquote><p>This episode highlights the dynamics and strategizing of contestants in reality shows like Bigg Boss, where alliances and enmities can shift quickly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/exclusive-bigg-boss-18-digvijay-singh-rathee-joins-salman-khan-on-wkv-after-eviction-karan-veer-mehra-and-chum-darang-blame-shrutika-arjun-for-his-elimination/articleshow/116513797.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/exclusive-bigg-boss-18-digvijay-singh-rathee-joins-salman-khan-on-wkv-after-eviction-karan-veer-mehra-and-chum-darang-blame-shrutika-arjun-for-his-elimination/articleshow/116513797.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Upgrades Its Smartest AI Model With Improved Reasoning Skills - WIRED]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OpenAI Upgrades Its Smartest AI Model With Improved Reasoning Skills</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Wired</p><p>OpenAI today announced an improved version of its most capable artificial intelligence model to date—one that takes even more time to deliberate over questions—just a day after Google announced its own model.</p><ul><li>The new model, called o3, focuses on delivering better answers through enhanced logical reasoning.</li><li>OpenAI claims it is three times better than its predecessor, o1, at answering complex questions.</li><li>There are two versions available: o3 and o3-mini, though they are not yet publicly accessible.</li><li>Competition between OpenAI and Google is intensifying as both companies strive to lead in AI advances.</li><li>The o3 model is significantly better at reasoning and problem-solving tasks than previous models.</li></ul><blockquote>“We view this as the beginning of the next phase of AI,” said OpenAI CEO Sam Altman.</blockquote><p>As competition between AI companies heats up, advancements like the o3 model may prove crucial for securing investment and demonstrating leadership in the field.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-o3-reasoning-model-google-gemini/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wired.com/story/openai-o3-reasoning-model-google-gemini/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI announces new o3 models - TechCrunch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/20/openai-announces-new-o3-model/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/20/openai-announces-new-o3-model/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:56:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's no.1 chess player Arjun Erigaisi faces US visa trouble, urges embassy to expedite process - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's no.1 chess player Arjun Erigaisi faces US visa trouble, urges embassy to expedite process</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92540357.cms" alt="Alert"><figcaption>Arjun Erigaisi</figcaption><p>Arjun Erigaisi, India's top chess player, is facing delays in obtaining a US visa, which has raised concerns over his participation in upcoming international tournaments.</p><ul><li>Erigaisi has appealed to the Indian embassy in the US to expedite his visa processing.</li><li>His potential absence from the tournaments could affect his rankings and opportunities.</li><li>This situation highlights ongoing challenges with visa processing for athletes.</li></ul><blockquote>“I hope the embassy can assist in resolving this issue swiftly.” - Arjun Erigaisi</blockquote><p>This incident underscores the importance of timely visa processing for athletes competing on international stages.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/chess/indias-no-1-chess-player-arjun-erigaisi-faces-us-visa-trouble-urges-embassy-to-expedite-process/articleshow/116513227.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/chess/indias-no-1-chess-player-arjun-erigaisi-faces-us-visa-trouble-urges-embassy-to-expedite-process/articleshow/116513227.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Trudeau Failed In Biggest Job': Jagmeet Singh-led NDP To Vote To Bring Canada Govt Down - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NDP to Vote Against Trudeau: A Critical Move for Canada</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 21, 2024<br /><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Jagmeet Singh's NDP parted ways with a supply-and-confidence deal with Trudeau's Liberal Party in September. (Reuters)" loading="eager" /><figcaption>Jagmeet Singh's NDP parted ways with a supply-and-confidence deal with Trudeau's Liberal Party in September. (Reuters)</figcaption></figure><p>Jagmeet Singh, leader of the New Democratic Party (NDP), has announced that his caucus will vote to bring down the Canadian government led by Prime Minister Justin Trudeau. Singh criticized Trudeau for failing to work for the people and indicated this move may jeopardize Trudeau's standing in government.</p><ul><li>Singh declared that the NDP will no longer support Trudeau's minority government.</li><li>He stated, "The Liberals don’t deserve another chance" and will introduce a no-confidence motion.</li><li>The NDP's decision significantly weakens Trudeau's government, which relies on their support.</li><li>The announcement follows recent calls for Trudeau to resign amidst rising dissatisfaction.</li></ul><blockquote><p>"Justin Trudeau failed in the biggest job a Prime Minister has: to work for people, not the powerful. The NDP will vote to bring this government down, and give Canadians a chance to vote for a government who will work for them." — Jagmeet Singh</p></blockquote><p>This pivotal move by the NDP could lead to significant political shifts in Canada, as Trudeau faces mounting pressure and calls for leadership change.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/canada-justin-trudeau-setback-jagmeet-singh-ndp-will-vote-to-bring-govt-down-liberal-party-latest-news-9163360.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/canada-justin-trudeau-setback-jagmeet-singh-ndp-will-vote-to-bring-govt-down-liberal-party-latest-news-9163360.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:47:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Updated joint FAO/WHO/WOAH public health assessment of recent influenza A(H5) virus events in animals and people - World Health Organization]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQMEVncUo1bTJLYUdxeVdTbXhoVVU5R2VkT3hhWV8tUzZKVVFKRjNwNXVOM3J4R2NsZFJzdkN2UFBwYmh3bmhINVJldHJxU2NYMFpfY2E5UE5rc2FNbXhIdjg2WlhIUXYzbWFmc1pLWjlPVmRSclp2N1NkdnRUVmhISFl0R2VBUG9uVUFxanVXd25QN0U5ZzBwQ2VUd3EzMXh5VzFRSTktYWg4d185N0NGbmtHQllKWUNNcU9ldG9icXdvX2ZEc0xmV1J6YWttOUxZUURQTU5TVWFkZFVlNml0NGhn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQMEVncUo1bTJLYUdxeVdTbXhoVVU5R2VkT3hhWV8tUzZKVVFKRjNwNXVOM3J4R2NsZFJzdkN2UFBwYmh3bmhINVJldHJxU2NYMFpfY2E5UE5rc2FNbXhIdjg2WlhIUXYzbWFmc1pLWjlPVmRSclp2N1NkdnRUVmhISFl0R2VBUG9uVUFxanVXd25QN0U5ZzBwQ2VUd3EzMXh5VzFRSTktYWg4d185N0NGbmtHQllKWUNNcU9ldG9icXdvX2ZEc0xmV1J6YWttOUxZUURQTU5TVWFkZFVlNml0NGhn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:41:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Box Office: 'UI', 'Marco', And 'Viduthalai Part - 2' Opening Day Early Estimates - Sacnilk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOZ2VwdngzV0E4OG9vR1VDZmFzODd3dElfMjhicFgzdDdYZ2FsNmhCZDZ0QWJ4Tkx6OHlLQ1BlUjBJbXBNdkNwdXhvR2JFOXFIenhud0E2RllGUmtsWmE4WjZOaUR2RjNfZmxZT2tjTEQ5Q3FiVUY4M09iU2hQNDNTZDZPZ3RvQWJrLUloekZvd05LVkNNU2VUenptSFlqYnNP?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOZ2VwdngzV0E4OG9vR1VDZmFzODd3dElfMjhicFgzdDdYZ2FsNmhCZDZ0QWJ4Tkx6OHlLQ1BlUjBJbXBNdkNwdXhvR2JFOXFIenhud0E2RllGUmtsWmE4WjZOaUR2RjNfZmxZT2tjTEQ5Q3FiVUY4M09iU2hQNDNTZDZPZ3RvQWJrLUloekZvd05LVkNNU2VUenptSFlqYnNP?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:35:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 cancers where screening and prevention have helped reduce death rates - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/5-cancers-where-screening-and-prevention-have-helped-reduce-death-rates/articleshow/116512380.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/5-cancers-where-screening-and-prevention-have-helped-reduce-death-rates/articleshow/116512380.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Raw oyster recall: PA and NJ among 15 states warned of norovirus outbreak after dozens sickened - WPVI-TV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Raw Oyster Recall: Norovirus Outbreak Affects 15 States Including PA and NJ</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> ABC News</p><p>An outbreak of norovirus linked to raw oysters has sickened over 80 people at a restaurant event in Los Angeles, prompting the FDA to warn consumers and restaurants in 15 states against selling or consuming the affected oysters.</p><img src='URL_TO_IMAGE' alt='Oysters' /><figcaption>Fanny Bay Select oysters linked to the outbreak.</figcaption><ul><li>Pennsylvania and New Jersey are among the 15 states affected.</li><li>The outbreak originated from an event celebrating the top restaurants in Los Angeles on December 3.</li><li>Symptoms of norovirus include vomiting, diarrhea, and stomach pain.</li><li>The FDA issued a recall notice for the oysters on December 13.</li><li>Santa Monica Seafood is cooperating with the ongoing investigation and denies any mishandling.</li></ul><blockquote>“At this time, over 80 attendees that consumed the oysters have reported illness,” - Los Angeles County Department of Public Health</blockquote><p>This outbreak highlights the importance of food safety and proper handling of shellfish to prevent foodborne illnesses.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://6abc.com/post/fda-warning-includes-pennsylvania-new-jersey-after-raw-oysters-linked-norovirus-outbreak-leaves-least-80-sick/15682188/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://6abc.com/post/fda-warning-includes-pennsylvania-new-jersey-after-raw-oysters-linked-norovirus-outbreak-leaves-least-80-sick/15682188/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:11:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`This is his problem,` Trump says let the US govt shutdown happen under Biden admin - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This is his problem, Trump says let the US govt shutdown happen under Biden admin</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> WIONews</p>
<img src="//cdn.wionews.com/sites/default/files/2024/09/26/456938-author-profilr.png?im=FitAndFill=(90,90)" alt="Prapti Upadhayay" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Prapti Upadhayay is a New Delhi-based journalist who reports on key news developments across India and global affairs, with a special focus on US politics.</figcaption>
<p>Donald Trump has made his intentions clear regarding a possible government shutdown, insisting that it should occur under President Joe Biden’s administration.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump stated that government shutdowns should start now under Biden, labeling it a problem for Biden to address.</li>
  <li>House Republicans are preparing to pass a bill to prevent a shutdown, which requires only a simple majority.</li>
  <li>Elon Musk has faced criticism from Democrats regarding his influence in the Republican Party and his opposition to a bipartisan spending bill.</li>
  <li>Karoline Leavitt mentioned Trump's leading role in shaping Republican views on the continuing resolution.</li>
  <li>Senator Bernie Sanders criticized Musk's intervention in budget negotiations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If there is going to be a shutdown of government, let it begin now, under the Biden Administration, not after January 20th, under ‘TRUMP.’ This is a Biden problem to solve.” – Donald Trump</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing debate highlights the deepening partisan divide in U.S. politics, with significant implications for government funding and bipartisan relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/world/this-is-his-problem-trump-says-let-the-us-govt-shutdown-happen-under-biden-admin-785664</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/world/this-is-his-problem-trump-says-let-the-us-govt-shutdown-happen-under-biden-admin-785664</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:06:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First blood-stage malaria vaccine ‘a much-needed addition’ – analyst - Clinical Trials Arena]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First blood-stage malaria vaccine ‘a much-needed addition’ – analyst</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Clinical Trials Arena</p>
<img src="https://live-b2b-gdm-figaro1.pantheonsite.io/wp-content/uploads/sites/22/2024/12/GettyImages-1236444257-430x241.jpg" alt="" />
<figcaption>Malaria is spread by the female Anopheles mosquito. Credit: NurPhoto / Contributor / Getty images.</figcaption>
<p>The RH5.1/Matrix-M blood-stage vaccine could constitute a crucial secondary defence for communities at high risk of malaria infection, including those who have already received pre-erythrocytic vaccines, an analyst has said.</p>
<ul>
<li>The RH5.1/Matrix-M vaccine may be the first blood-stage malaria vaccine brought to market.</li>
<li>The vaccine has shown to be safe, effective, and highly immunogenic in Phase IIb trials.</li>
<li>The trial included 361 children aged 5 to 17 months conducted in Burkina Faso and the UK.</li>
<li>Immunity to malaria wanes over time, making blood-stage vaccines essential as a second line of defence.</li>
<li>The CDC reported around 263 million cases of malaria and 597,000 deaths in 2023, with the majority occurring in Africa.</li>
<li>76% of all malaria deaths in Africa are among children under five.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“RH5.1/Matrix-M has the potential to be the first blood-stage malaria vaccine brought to market. This could be a much-needed addition to the currently available malaria vaccines and provide an important second line of defence for those most at risk of contracting malaria.” – Stephanie Kurdach, GlobalData</blockquote>
<p>The development of this vaccine represents a significant advancement in the fight against malaria, particularly for vulnerable populations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.clinicaltrialsarena.com/news/first-blood-stage-malaria-vaccine-a-much-needed-addition-analyst/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.clinicaltrialsarena.com/news/first-blood-stage-malaria-vaccine-a-much-needed-addition-analyst/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:04:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Punjab Govt Would Be Responsible': Supreme Court's Direction On Farmer Leader Jagjit Dallewal's Health - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Directs Punjab Government to Ensure Farmer Leader Jagjit Dallewal's Health</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Jagjit Singh Dallewal had been protesting for farmers' rights for weeks now and his health has deteriorated sharply after his hunger strike. (PTI/File)" /><figcaption>Jagjit Singh Dallewal had been protesting for farmers' rights for weeks now and his health has deteriorated sharply after his hunger strike. (PTI/File)</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court has ordered the Punjab government to take immediate action to ensure the safety and health of farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal, who is on an indefinite hunger strike. His health has critically deteriorated recently.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court's directives come after Dallewal lost consciousness during his hunger strike.</li><li>The Punjab government is required to transfer him to a makeshift hospital for constant monitoring.</li><li>Dallewal has been on hunger strike for 24 days and his condition is described as critical.</li><li>Political leaders have urged the government to meet the farmers' demands to alleviate Dallewal's situation.</li></ul><blockquote>The court stated, "The Punjab government would be responsible for Dallewal’s health."</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the ongoing farmers' protests and their struggle for rights, particularly regarding the demands addressed to the Indian government.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/sc-directs-punjab-govt-to-ensure-fasting-farmer-leader-jagjit-singh-dallewals-safety-9162937.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/sc-directs-punjab-govt-to-ensure-fasting-farmer-leader-jagjit-singh-dallewals-safety-9162937.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:51:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Failed in biggest job a PM has’: Trudeau's ally says will vote to bring down Canadian government - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Failed in biggest job a PM has’: Trudeau's ally says will vote to bring down Canadian government</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Times of India Logo"><figcaption>Times of India</figcaption><p>The Canadian political landscape is shifting as a key ally of Prime Minister Justin Trudeau expresses intentions to vote against the government, citing failure in critical areas.</p><ul><li>Trudeau's ally indicates a lack of confidence in the current administration.</li><li>The decision could lead to significant political repercussions, potentially triggering an election.</li><li>Concerns raised over government management and effectiveness during turbulent times.</li></ul><blockquote>“Failed in biggest job a PM has”</blockquote><p>This declaration signifies potential instability in Trudeau's leadership and raises questions about the direction of Canadian politics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/failed-in-biggest-job-a-pm-has-trudeaus-ally-says-will-vote-to-bring-down-canadian-government/articleshow/116511676.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/failed-in-biggest-job-a-pm-has-trudeaus-ally-says-will-vote-to-bring-down-canadian-government/articleshow/116511676.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>