<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:16:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:16:07 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California man dies from an unusual lung cancer spread from another person - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Man Dies from Rare Lung Cancer Transmitted Through Organ Donation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117176600,imgsize-28188,width-400,resizemode-4/117176600.jpg" alt="California man dies from an unusual lung cancer spread from another person" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>California man dies from an unusual lung cancer spread from another person</figcaption><p>A 41-year-old man from California tragically died after developing metastatic pulmonary adenocarcinoma, a type of lung cancer, due to organ donation from a deceased donor who had undetected cancer.</p><ul><li>The patient had a history of chronic liver disease and underwent a liver transplant in 2001.</li><li>The original organ donor had a metastatic pulmonary adenocarcinoma that was not detected during pre-transplant screening.</li><li>Following the transplant, the patient was found to have developed the same type of lung cancer seven years later.</li><li>Despite a successful second transplant and initial recovery, the cancer progressed rapidly, leading to the patient’s death within 24 hours after hospitalization.</li></ul><blockquote>“Clearly, tumor cells had escaped the confines of the transplanted liver within one week after transplantation,” the doctors noted.</blockquote><p>This case highlights the rare occurrence of donor-to-recipient cancer transmission and underscores the need for thorough screening of organ donors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/california-man-dies-from-an-unusual-lung-cancer-spread-from-another-person/articleshow/117176600.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/california-man-dies-from-an-unusual-lung-cancer-spread-from-another-person/articleshow/117176600.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The OnePlus Open 2 tipped to be the thinnest foldable yet – with a new titanium build - TechRadar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techradar.com/phones/oneplus-phones/the-oneplus-open-2-tipped-to-be-the-thinnest-foldable-yet-with-a-new-titanium-build</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techradar.com/phones/oneplus-phones/the-oneplus-open-2-tipped-to-be-the-thinnest-foldable-yet-with-a-new-titanium-build</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The OnePlus Open 2 tipped to be the thinnest foldable yet – with a new titanium build - TechRadar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techradar.com/phones/oneplus-phones/the-oneplus-open-2-tipped-to-be-the-thinnest-foldable-yet-with-a-new-titanium-build</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techradar.com/phones/oneplus-phones/the-oneplus-open-2-tipped-to-be-the-thinnest-foldable-yet-with-a-new-titanium-build</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On L&T Chief's 90-Hour Workweek Call, Adar Poonawalla Says 'Even My Wife...' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Adar Poonawalla Responds to L&T Chief's 90-Hour Workweek Suggestion</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Adar Poonawalla agreed with Anand Mahindra, and said that his wife (Natasha Poonawalla) loves staring at him on Sundays." /><figcaption>Adar Poonawalla agreed with Anand Mahindra, and said that his wife (Natasha Poonawalla) loves staring at him on Sundays.</figcaption><p>Adar Poonawalla, CEO of Serum Institute of India, supports work-life balance in response to calls for a 90-hour workweek made by L&T Chairman SN Subrahmanyan.</p><ul><li>Poonawalla emphasizes the importance of work-life balance.</li><li>His comments followed Subrahmanyan's controversial statement suggesting employees work longer hours.</li><li>Industry reactions included support for non-traditional working hours and critiques of the work culture.</li><li>Poonawalla sarcastically remarked about how his wife enjoys spending time with him on Sundays.</li></ul><blockquote>“Even my wife loves staring at me on Sundays.” - Adar Poonawalla</blockquote><p>The growing discourse around work-life balance highlights differing perspectives in corporate culture, especially among influential leaders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/on-lt-chiefs-90-hour-workweek-call-adar-poonawalla-says-even-my-wife-9186136.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/on-lt-chiefs-90-hour-workweek-call-adar-poonawalla-says-even-my-wife-9186136.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:07:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh summons Indian High Commissioner over rising border tensions - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh Summons Indian Envoy Over Border Tensions</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Pranay-Verma.jpg?w=640" alt="Pranay Verma" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>While no official statement was issued by the interim government regarding the discussions, officials confirmed that Pranay Verma (left) has been summoned. (Photo: X/ MoFA Bangladesh)</figcaption><p>Bangladesh faced off with India Sunday over tensions at the border as the neighbouring country’s foreign ministry summoned High Commissioner Pranay Verma to express “deep concern” over “recent activities of the Border Security Force (BSF)”.</p><p>This came hours after Dhaka alleged that India was attempting to construct fences at five locations along the Indo-Bangla border, violating a bilateral agreement.</p><p>After meeting Bangladesh Foreign Secretary Jashim Uddin, the Indian High Commissioner said: “I just met Foreign Secretary to discuss India’s commitment to ensuring a crime-free border, effectively addressing challenges of smuggling, movement of criminals and trafficking.” “We have an understanding with regard to fencing the border for security. BSF and BGB (Border Guard Bangladesh) have been in communication in this regard. We expect that understandings will be implemented and there will be a cooperative approach to combating crime,” Verma said in Dhaka.</p><p>Earlier in the day, Bangladesh Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd.) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said that India had halted the construction of barbed wire fencing along the border after strong opposition from the BGB and local residents.</p><p>According to the Bangladesh Foreign Ministry, Jashim Uddin told the Indian envoy that the “unauthorized attempt” to construct fences and related operational actions by BSF have caused tensions along the border.</p><p>“He emphasised that the construction of barbed wire fences without proper authorization undermines the spirit of cooperation and friendly relations between the two neighboring countries. He hoped that the upcoming BGB-BSF DG Level Talks would be able to discuss the matter at length,” it said in a statement.</p><p>“Referring to the recent killing of a Bangladesh citizen at Sunamganj by BSF, Foreign Secretary… strongly resented these acts of killing and called for urgent action by the Indian authorities to stop recurrence of such incidents and conduct enquiries into all these border killings and take actions against those responsible,” it said.</p><p>He said Bangladesh believes such issues should be resolved through dialogue.</p><p>This article went live on January 12, 2025, at 6:06 PM.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-indian-high-commissioner-border-tensions-9774904/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-indian-high-commissioner-border-tensions-9774904/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More children test positive for mumps in Alappuzha - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>More children test positive for mumps in Alappuzha</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Local Health Report</p><p>The Alappuzha district is currently experiencing a rise in mumps infections among school students, prompting health officials to take action.</p><ul><li>At least five students at Eramalloor and four at Punnapra have tested positive.</li><li>The total infections at Eramalloor school have risen to 28, including a previous outbreak affecting 23 students.</li><li>Schools in the area have been closed for 21 days due to the outbreak.</li><li>Surveillance and preventive measures have been intensified by health department officials.</li><li>Mumps is primarily a disease in children but can also affect adolescents and adults, causing swelling of the salivary glands.</li></ul><blockquote>Mumps is a contagious disease caused by a virus that primarily affects children but could also infect adolescents and adults.</blockquote><p>This outbreak of mumps highlights the importance of vaccination and public health measures to control infectious diseases among school-aged children.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/more-children-test-positive-for-mumps-in-alappuzha/article69091922.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/more-children-test-positive-for-mumps-in-alappuzha/article69091922.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals: OnePlus 13 launches, Poco X7 and X7 Pro arrive in Europe as well - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 Launches Globally Alongside Poco X7 and X7 Pro in Europe</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> GSM Arena</p><div><img src="https://fdn2.gsmarena.com/vv/bigpic/oneplus-13.jpg" alt="OnePlus 13" width="75" height="100"><figcaption>OnePlus 13</figcaption></div><p>The OnePlus 13 has officially launched with a pricing strategy aimed to attract previous OnePlus 12 buyers, while the Poco X7 series has also been introduced in the UK, featuring two models distinguished by performance and battery specifications.</p><ul><li>The OnePlus 13 comes with a €100 discount for the 16/512GB model, aligning its price with last year's OnePlus 12.</li><li>The Poco X7 and X7 Pro both feature 6.67” 120Hz OLED displays, with significant differences in battery capacity and performance chipsets.</li><li>The Poco X7 Pro is equipped with the Dimensity 8400 Ultra, while the standard X7 offers the Dimensity 7300 Ultra.</li><li>Batteries range from 5,110mAh in the standard model to 6,000mAh in the Pro, with HyperCharge support for fast charging.</li><li>Both models feature similar camera setups, though the recording capabilities differ due to chipset variations.</li></ul><blockquote>“We may get a commission from qualifying sales.”</blockquote><p>This new launch strategy by OnePlus and Xiaomi reflects their approach to enhancing market penetration in Europe by offering competitive pricing and technologically advanced features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gsmarena.com/deals_oneplus_13_launches_poco_x7_and_x7_pro_arrive_in_europe_as_well-news-66051.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gsmarena.com/deals_oneplus_13_launches_poco_x7_and_x7_pro_arrive_in_europe_as_well-news-66051.php</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:41:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ajith Kumar kisses wife Shalini; thanks her for ‘letting him race’ at 24H Dubai 2025. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/tamil-cinema/ajith-kumar-kisses-wife-shalini-thanks-her-for-letting-him-race-at-24h-dubai-2025-watch-101736687096895.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/tamil-cinema/ajith-kumar-kisses-wife-shalini-thanks-her-for-letting-him-race-at-24h-dubai-2025-watch-101736687096895.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:33:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ajith Kumar kisses wife Shalini; thanks her for ‘letting him race’ at 24H Dubai 2025. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/tamil-cinema/ajith-kumar-kisses-wife-shalini-thanks-her-for-letting-him-race-at-24h-dubai-2025-watch-101736687096895.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/tamil-cinema/ajith-kumar-kisses-wife-shalini-thanks-her-for-letting-him-race-at-24h-dubai-2025-watch-101736687096895.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:33:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Find New Galaxy Forming At Tip Of Tidal Tail Stretching 1.27 Million Light-Years - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/scientists-find-new-galaxy-forming-at-tip-of-tidal-tail-str-hing-1-27-million-light-years-aa-9185533.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/scientists-find-new-galaxy-forming-at-tip-of-tidal-tail-str-hing-1-27-million-light-years-aa-9185533.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:02:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Air India plans more premium seats, eyes higher connecting traffic to tap 'huge growth opportunities' - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQOWx1X1NmOG1MWjdxTlV0ZHVOa0xPNktDNVZ1ZEJwMm4zVURYR0x4ZlhNMG15TEp3RVJqckZOVWgxd3FVM1hFemFEYm5XZzFDaHRwUjh4cjktSmVnZFl1ZVN0RHlnbTNINi1wRV9nUV9OX2w2VjBydGdBUDF0ZTZXLU42TWdfU09SU3BpUWdMMmZnOFVwZVM5Uzh5dkg1VXg4UnpNeU1aNmN4TnZNeUt6dzByaTJhV2NtMXRPZHI3cm5fMTIzbnFienlQb1VHVEhNaENnbWRKLU9nd1VQbHp3TE94aFNZT2RoQk5mbjZJajdhVUN2cDRQRNIB_gFBVV95cUxOWHNCZi1DcXhSTE1GUnlhb3dTQU9Lel9ZaHcwMlBSWW5wU3NVLWFRdTZNSlhYYXUyUmpib2VQREc3dTIzVFRMZHdZd1NoUGV3NktpTlFYb091dEF0V0YwX0ZScUctSHRBc0dIbFo3UWx0NGhJamdEVWZPSngwZEpFb1lZV2FEZEdDWndVdGowUFNxQ3FDNFV6RUpINGYtM3o3bjd3X09nek5BVElJbC1qdHdJS3loZUx0OG5Oa25McDdJM3YwZk5sb2JxWnVHSmtfX1d4RGhXQjBQZFZ1Y1NPQnhMbk9rejZuQldEaGtmeWZlTWktcFd5TXBIYnhIdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQOWx1X1NmOG1MWjdxTlV0ZHVOa0xPNktDNVZ1ZEJwMm4zVURYR0x4ZlhNMG15TEp3RVJqckZOVWgxd3FVM1hFemFEYm5XZzFDaHRwUjh4cjktSmVnZFl1ZVN0RHlnbTNINi1wRV9nUV9OX2w2VjBydGdBUDF0ZTZXLU42TWdfU09SU3BpUWdMMmZnOFVwZVM5Uzh5dkg1VXg4UnpNeU1aNmN4TnZNeUt6dzByaTJhV2NtMXRPZHI3cm5fMTIzbnFienlQb1VHVEhNaENnbWRKLU9nd1VQbHp3TE94aFNZT2RoQk5mbjZJajdhVUN2cDRQRNIB_gFBVV95cUxOWHNCZi1DcXhSTE1GUnlhb3dTQU9Lel9ZaHcwMlBSWW5wU3NVLWFRdTZNSlhYYXUyUmpib2VQREc3dTIzVFRMZHdZd1NoUGV3NktpTlFYb091dEF0V0YwX0ZScUctSHRBc0dIbFo3UWx0NGhJamdEVWZPSngwZEpFb1lZV2FEZEdDWndVdGowUFNxQ3FDNFV6RUpINGYtM3o3bjd3X09nek5BVElJbC1qdHdJS3loZUx0OG5Oa25McDdJM3YwZk5sb2JxWnVHSmtfX1d4RGhXQjBQZFZ1Y1NPQnhMbk9rejZuQldEaGtmeWZlTWktcFd5TXBIYnhIdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:50:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ice Baths for Stress: New research says cold water could sharpen your mind and improve sleep - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ice Baths for Stress: New research says cold water could sharpen your mind and improve sleep</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117174624,imgsize-1894125,width-400,resizemode-4/117174624.jpg" alt="Ice Baths for Stress" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Ice Baths for Stress: New research says cold water could sharpen your mind and improve sleep</figcaption><p>Recent research from the University of Central Lancashire reveals that regular cold-water immersion can enhance cognitive performance and improve sleep quality.</p><ul><li>Study involved 13 healthy participants aged 21, immersing in 10°C water for 10 minutes, three times a week.</li><li>Participants showed improved processing speed and better sleep by the third week.</li><li>Cold exposure may improve blood flow and promote relaxation.</li><li>Lead researcher Robert Allan emphasized that cold-water immersion can aid sleep, particularly during periods of sleep disturbances.</li></ul><blockquote>“Cold-water immersion helps with sleep, particularly during periods of pronounced sleep disturbances.” – Robert Allan</blockquote><p>Cold water therapy can enhance focus and productivity, and reduce symptoms of stress and anxiety by lowering inflammation and regulating hormones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/ice-baths-for-stress-new-research-says-cold-water-could-sharpen-your-mind-and-improve-sleep/articleshow/117174565.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/ice-baths-for-stress-new-research-says-cold-water-could-sharpen-your-mind-and-improve-sleep/articleshow/117174565.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fibre may help protect your gut from overgrowth of harmful bugs: Study - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fibre May Protect Gut Health Against Harmful Bacteria: New Study</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> (Date not provided), <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/fibre-2.jpg" alt="Future research will integrate additional tools, such as metabolomics (studying chemicals microbes produce) and transcriptomics (studying how genes are activated), to create a clearer picture of how the gut ecosystem works for our health benefit." />
<figcaption>Image Credit: Freepik</figcaption>
<p>This new study reveals how a healthy gut environment, influenced by diet, can inhibit harmful bacteria such as Enterobacteriaceae, offering insights into gut health management.</p>
<ul>
<li>The study analyzed over 12,000 stool samples globally, indicating a strong link between gut microbiome composition and the presence of harmful bacteria.</li>
<li>Fatty acids produced by bacteria like Faecalibacterium are crucial in preventing the overgrowth of harmful microbes.</li>
<li>Co-colonisers of harmful bacteria demonstrate adaptability, suggesting that gut conditions play a significant role in bacterial survival.</li>
<li>Findings may lead to alternative methods for preventing infections without antibiotics by promoting beneficial bacteria instead.</li>
<li>The research highlights the need for further studies on global microbiome diversity and its implications for health.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Instead of killing harmful bacteria directly, we could boost the co-excluders or create diets that support their growth.”</blockquote>
<p>This research underscores the importance of dietary fibres in maintaining gut health and could pave the way for new treatments targeting harmful bacteria.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/fibre-may-help-protect-your-gut-from-overgrowth-of-harmful-bugs-study-9774693/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/fibre-may-help-protect-your-gut-from-overgrowth-of-harmful-bugs-study-9774693/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:30:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘People in Maharashtra showed Sharad Pawar, Uddhav Thackeray their place’: Amit Shah’s dig over poll results - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amit Shah Criticizes Sharad Pawar and Uddhav Thackeray After Maharashtra Poll Results</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Amit_Shah_1736682210598_1736682210926.jpg" alt="Union Home Minister Amit Shah.(PTI)" title="Union Home Minister Amit Shah.(PTI)"><figcaption>Union Home Minister Amit Shah.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Union Home Minister Amit Shah took a dig at Sharad Pawar and Uddhav Thackeray, stating that the recent Maharashtra assembly election results clearly showed them their place in the political landscape.</p><ul><li>Shah emphasized that the results rejected the politics of dynasty and betrayal.</li><li>The BJP-led Mahayuti alliance secured a historic 233 seats in the assembly elections.</li><li>The Congress-led MVA won only 16 seats, while Thackeray's Shiv Sena secured 20 and Pawar’s NCP just 10.</li></ul><blockquote>“People in Maharashtra showed that Eknath Shinde's Shiv Sena is Balasaheb's Shiv Sena.”</blockquote><p>Shah expressed confidence in winning upcoming elections and remarked that the opposition's confidence has been shaken by the defeat in Maharashtra.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/people-in-maharashtra-showed-sharad-pawar-uddhav-thackeray-their-place-amit-shah-s-dig-over-poll-results-101736681036917.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/people-in-maharashtra-showed-sharad-pawar-uddhav-thackeray-their-place-amit-shah-s-dig-over-poll-results-101736681036917.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:29:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases in northern China declining, says country's health official - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV cases in northern China declining, says country's health official</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p> <figure> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/HMPV_1736679171766_1736679172042.jpg" alt="Wang Liping, second left, a researcher for the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention speaks during a press briefing in Beijing, Sunday, Jan. 12, 2025.(AP)" title="Wang Liping, second left, a researcher for the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention speaks during a press briefing in Beijing, Sunday, Jan. 12, 2025.(AP)"> <figcaption>Wang Liping, second left, a researcher for the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention speaks during a press briefing in Beijing, Sunday, Jan. 12, 2025.(AP)</figcaption> </figure> <p>The Chinese health authorities have reported a decline in human metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases, alleviating concerns amid a global focus on respiratory illnesses.</p> <ul> <li>HMPV is a frequent respiratory virus causing mild symptoms similar to a cold.</li> <li>China stated recent increases in case detection were due to improved detection methods, not a new surge of the virus.</li> <li>Research indicates that many adults have immunity, but the virus is more severe in infants or immunocompromised individuals.</li> <li>Reports of hospitals being overwhelmed have not been verified; WHO noted no unusual outbreaks.</li> <li>No vaccines or specific treatments are available for HMPV.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“At present, the rate of positive cases in human metapneumovirus detection is fluctuating, and the rate of positive cases in northern provinces is declining,” - Wang Liping.</blockquote> <p>Overall, the situation appears to be under control, with no significant shortages of medical resources reported.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/hmpv-cases-in-northern-china-declining-says-countrys-health-official-101736677964239.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/hmpv-cases-in-northern-china-declining-says-countrys-health-official-101736677964239.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:28:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi pollution: GRAP 3 revoked after air quality improves due to rainfall - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Pollution: Stage-I and Stage-II Measures, However, Will Remain in Effect</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 07:20 PM IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Delhi_rain_1736684414274_1736684414603.jpg" alt="New Delhi, Jan 11 (ANI): A man passes on a bicycle at the Kartavya Path as drizzle lashes, in New Delhi on Saturday. (ANI Photo/Ishant)(Ishant )" title="New Delhi, Jan 11 (ANI): A man passes on a bicycle at the Kartavya Path as drizzle lashes, in New Delhi on Saturday. (ANI Photo/Ishant)(Ishant )"><figcaption>New Delhi, Jan 11 (ANI): A man passes on a bicycle at the Kartavya Path as drizzle lashes, in New Delhi on Saturday. (ANI Photo/Ishant)(Ishant )</figcaption></figure><p>The Commission of Air Quality Management (CAQM) revoked the Stage III restrictions under the anti-pollution Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) in Delhi-NCR after the AQI improved due to rainfall.</p><ul><li>The revocation was due to significant improvement in AQI, which dropped from 'very poor' to 'poor' following rain.</li><li>Stage-I and Stage-II measures will remain in effect, including restrictions on private construction.</li><li>The average AQI in Delhi was recorded at 284 post-rain on Sunday.</li></ul><blockquote>“The rain was caused by a western disturbance affecting northwest India,” said Mahesh Palawat, vice president at Skymet.</blockquote><p>The rain has led to a temporary improvement in air quality, providing relief to residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-pollution-grap-3-revoked-after-air-quality-improves-due-to-rainfall-101736684324277.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-pollution-grap-3-revoked-after-air-quality-improves-due-to-rainfall-101736684324277.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:22:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 vitamins and minerals that are lost in cooking (and how to retain them) - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxNSnFyUVQyeWFPRmxaSjNzWGNEeEo0LXZPZkxiTFFVRVVsUkQwTTYyYXBINGlxNlkzQVUxTkNfY2xQX2NyWEdZQ1RqMHgtT3BvT01ERzNiY0Y0OFBvNG13M0Nwa1JOV1I4VGNXa0JyanRheTlxNGZlaFFSQUVWZ3JISWpZaTVXSHNQcjdMQmhfVk9Ecmk2VkZBMWsxbHJQRF85UjFybkNka29uWlAwS2VRdTRWbk41NG9lQWNLMlZEckJjaU9TSTdONW81NXdfU3NPMm1kVnJkZ1Rhd3dBYmdYWDlRRTBGc0RMT19uZUVjN1NIckI3SEhxc2RqbUdCaTTSAf8BQVVfeXFMTUpxclFUMnlhT0ZsWkozc1hjRHhKNC12T2ZMYkxRVUVVbFJEME02MmFwSDRpcTZZM0FVMU5DX2NsUF9jclhHWUNUajB4LU9wb09NREczYmNGNDhQbzRtdzNDcGtSTldSOFRjV2tCcmp0YXk5cTRmZWhRUkFFVmdySElqWWk1V0hzUHI3TEJoX1ZPRHJpNlZGQTFrMWxyUERfOVIxcm5DZGtvblpQMEtlUXU0Vm5ONTRvZUFjSzJWRHJCY2lPU0k3TjVvNTV3X1NzTzJtZFZyZGdUYXd3QWJnWFg5UUUwRnNETE9fbmVFYzdTSHJCN0hIcXNkam1HQmk0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxNSnFyUVQyeWFPRmxaSjNzWGNEeEo0LXZPZkxiTFFVRVVsUkQwTTYyYXBINGlxNlkzQVUxTkNfY2xQX2NyWEdZQ1RqMHgtT3BvT01ERzNiY0Y0OFBvNG13M0Nwa1JOV1I4VGNXa0JyanRheTlxNGZlaFFSQUVWZ3JISWpZaTVXSHNQcjdMQmhfVk9Ecmk2VkZBMWsxbHJQRF85UjFybkNka29uWlAwS2VRdTRWbk41NG9lQWNLMlZEckJjaU9TSTdONW81NXdfU3NPMm1kVnJkZ1Rhd3dBYmdYWDlRRTBGc0RMT19uZUVjN1NIckI3SEhxc2RqbUdCaTTSAf8BQVVfeXFMTUpxclFUMnlhT0ZsWkozc1hjRHhKNC12T2ZMYkxRVUVVbFJEME02MmFwSDRpcTZZM0FVMU5DX2NsUF9jclhHWUNUajB4LU9wb09NREczYmNGNDhQbzRtdzNDcGtSTldSOFRjV2tCcmp0YXk5cTRmZWhRUkFFVmdySElqWWk1V0hzUHI3TEJoX1ZPRHJpNlZGQTFrMWxyUERfOVIxcm5DZGtvblpQMEtlUXU0Vm5ONTRvZUFjSzJWRHJCY2lPU0k3TjVvNTV3X1NzTzJtZFZyZGdUYXd3QWJnWFg5UUUwRnNETE9fbmVFYzdTSHJCN0hIcXNkam1HQmk0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:22:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Wants To Buy Greenland: Here's What It Could Cost The US - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-wants-to-buy-greenland-heres-what-it-could-cost-the-us-9186373.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-wants-to-buy-greenland-heres-what-it-could-cost-the-us-9186373.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:17:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Wants To Buy Greenland: Here's What It Could Cost The US - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-wants-to-buy-greenland-heres-what-it-could-cost-the-us-9186373.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-wants-to-buy-greenland-heres-what-it-could-cost-the-us-9186373.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:17:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer box office collection day 3 (updated live): Ram Charan-Shankar film crosses Indian 2 lifetime - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer box office collection day 3 (updated live): Shankar's Telugu debut crossed lifetime collections of his much-hyped Kamal Haasan-starrer.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Game_Changer_bo_day_3_1736682089407_1736682097896.jpg" alt="Game Changer box office collection day 3 (updated live): Ram Charan and Kiara Advani in a still from the film." title="Game Changer box office collection day 3 (updated live): Ram Charan and Kiara Advani in a still from the film."><figcaption>Game Changer box office collection day 3 (updated live): Ram Charan and Kiara Advani in a still from the film.</figcaption><p>Shankar’s maiden Telugu film <em>Game Changer</em> has crossed the lifetime collection of his previous film, <em>Indian 2</em>. As of 7 PM, the film has grossed ₹85.09 crore net in India.</p><ul><li>On its opening day, <em>Game Changer</em> collected ₹51 crore net in India.</li><li>Day 2 showed a significant drop with a 57.65% decrease, earning only ₹21.6 crore net.</li><li>The film registered an 18.01% occupancy for its morning shows.</li><li>The competition includes Balakrishna’s <em>Daaku Maharaaj</em> and Venkatesh-starrer <em>Sankranthiki Vasthunam</em>.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“The film explores corruption in electoral politics with Suryah playing a corrupt politician.”</p></blockquote><p>The film's performance has been underwhelming for a Sankranthi release, and its future collection remains uncertain as it faces competition from other films released during the festival season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/game-changer-box-office-collection-day-3-updated-live-ram-charan-shankar-film-crosses-indian-2-lifetime-101736681756048.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/game-changer-box-office-collection-day-3-updated-live-ram-charan-shankar-film-crosses-indian-2-lifetime-101736681756048.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:12:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV is not new; stay calm and follow basic precautions, say experts - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Experts Advise Calm Amid HMPV Detection in India</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Health News</p><p>Amid concerns over human metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases in India, health experts affirm that the virus is not new, emphasizing calmness and basic precautions.</p><ul><li>HMPV typically spreads through the air, particularly in winter and early spring.</li><li>Common symptoms include cough, fever, fatigue, respiratory illness, sore throat, and body aches.</li><li>Good hygiene practices and vaccination are recommended to reduce transmission risk.</li><li>India's testing capacity has improved significantly due to the COVID-19 pandemic experience.</li><li>Experts discourage panic, noting that public awareness is key to minimizing HMPV spread.</li></ul><blockquote>“HMPV is not a new virus; it was first identified in 2001. There’s no reason to panic. Understanding its symptoms, taking necessary precautions, and following testing protocols are critical.” - Dr. Aabid Amin Bhat</blockquote><p>In conclusion, staying informed and practicing preventive health measures can contribute significantly to community resilience against health crises.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/health/hmpv-is-not-new-stay-calm-and-follow-basic-precautions-say-experts-125011200447_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/health/hmpv-is-not-new-stay-calm-and-follow-basic-precautions-say-experts-125011200447_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:09:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gut microbiome's role in fighting infections: Study reveals how diet can impact risk - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gut Microbiome's Role in Fighting Infections: Study Reveals Dietary Impact</h1>
<p><strong>Posted on:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/anna-pelzer-IGfIGP5ONV0-unsplash_1677140161308_1736682873973.jpg" alt="Diet changes linked to gut microbiome can reduce risk of life-threatening infections.(Unsplash)">
<figcaption>Diet changes linked to gut microbiome can reduce risk of life-threatening infections.(Unsplash)</figcaption>
<p>A new study highlights how the composition of the gut microbiome can predict susceptibility to infections like Klebsiella pneumoniae and E.coli, suggesting that increasing fiber intake can enhance protection against these harmful bacteria.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The gut microbiome may influence the risk of potentially life-threatening infections.</li>
  <li>Research analyzed stool samples from over 12,000 people worldwide to study gut microbiome signatures.</li>
  <li>Fibers in diet promote beneficial gut bacteria that can fend off harmful bacteria.</li>
  <li>Probiotics are less effective than dietary changes in altering gut health.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our results suggest that what we eat is potentially very important in controlling the likelihood of infection with a range of bacteria, including E.coli and Klebsiella pneumoniae because this changes our gut environment to make it more hostile to invaders.” - Dr Alexandre Almeida</blockquote>
<p>The findings point to the significance of dietary choices in promoting gut health and reducing the risk of serious infections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/gut-microbiomes-role-in-fighting-infections-study-reveals-how-diet-can-impact-risk-101736679538951.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/gut-microbiomes-role-in-fighting-infections-study-reveals-how-diet-can-impact-risk-101736679538951.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:56:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trade setup for January 13: Top 15 things to know before the opening bell - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxNRHMwMzdyLXNOYzI0dFpYbEtDZ01nMkJnYXlRMm9KNzB5RnFZV29zaWpfbHhxbGRycGJaQTVCcVdoaGJTdVE3X2ozRFlDelVhU0djN01CUGRIVlNmZDlvUEN2MVF0c2RUQThPTGx2SWZUaWo5MW55eVBiblZJTDFua0RWbzBYMVNxWFZTWU95RHpKOURzV0NkZnBvYzlYSU5zU3NYLXJUVmlzTWlYQno2czU1eDNPQUhGS3RTY1VmejF3elgtYzJpMEVLSERFRFkxaEZv0gHYAUFVX3lxTE8wcnVlb0dKTWpiYjl2S3otUmhfRlBGR1BoN204dFkzNGFuQTBNaXQwUnBfcHpxRG9pM21TVHhBYWN5VUZaQU4wLW5NaDZMOXNjNWNLbktQM1QtSURMOGMxRnVuNEtVMmpLMkFvekdIR1Fzem1zeXhDRjY3bVNmWFItU2owRWc1Y01fODNjSDJlZHFOS3o0NFpwbUtlcy01RGFMQXZ0bUJnQ2RtbjhsNVd5eURaeHd5VzJrSXNQd21Qc3kwTE5hZ2ZrUmRQNnpYRlR5TmtsSFFpQw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxNRHMwMzdyLXNOYzI0dFpYbEtDZ01nMkJnYXlRMm9KNzB5RnFZV29zaWpfbHhxbGRycGJaQTVCcVdoaGJTdVE3X2ozRFlDelVhU0djN01CUGRIVlNmZDlvUEN2MVF0c2RUQThPTGx2SWZUaWo5MW55eVBiblZJTDFua0RWbzBYMVNxWFZTWU95RHpKOURzV0NkZnBvYzlYSU5zU3NYLXJUVmlzTWlYQno2czU1eDNPQUhGS3RTY1VmejF3elgtYzJpMEVLSERFRFkxaEZv0gHYAUFVX3lxTE8wcnVlb0dKTWpiYjl2S3otUmhfRlBGR1BoN204dFkzNGFuQTBNaXQwUnBfcHpxRG9pM21TVHhBYWN5VUZaQU4wLW5NaDZMOXNjNWNLbktQM1QtSURMOGMxRnVuNEtVMmpLMkFvekdIR1Fzem1zeXhDRjY3bVNmWFItU2owRWc1Y01fODNjSDJlZHFOS3o0NFpwbUtlcy01RGFMQXZ0bUJnQ2RtbjhsNVd5eURaeHd5VzJrSXNQd21Qc3kwTE5hZ2ZrUmRQNnpYRlR5TmtsSFFpQw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:28:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anand Mahindra on 90-hour work week debate: My wife is wonderful, I love staring at her - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anand Mahindra Advocates for Quality Over Quantity in Work Hours</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 - <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/h5v1c4/article69089583.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/S%20N%20Subrahmanyan.jpg" alt="Anand Mahindra at the National Youth Festival"><figcaption>Anand Mahindra at the National Youth Festival</figcaption><p>During the National Youth Festival, Mahindra Group Chairman Anand Mahindra responded to the ongoing debate on a proposed 90-hour work week, emphasizing the importance of work quality rather than the number of hours worked.</p><ul><li>Mahindra highlighted that impactful work can be completed in as little as 10 hours.</li><li>He mentioned the significance of spending time with family and the need for diverse thinking in decision-making.</li><li>Mahindra quipped about his social media presence, attributing it to his love for his wife.</li><li>His comments came in response to controversial statements made by other industry leaders advocating for longer work hours.</li></ul><blockquote>“My point is we have to focus on the quality of work, not on the quantity of work.” - Anand Mahindra</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Mahindra calls for a shift in focus from hours worked to the actual output, urging others in the industry to adopt a similar perspective.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/my-wife-is-wonderful-i-love-staring-at-her-anand-mahindra-on-90-hr-work-week-debate/article69091958.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/my-wife-is-wonderful-i-love-staring-at-her-anand-mahindra-on-90-hr-work-week-debate/article69091958.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND-W vs IRE-W: Jemimah Rodrigues’ maiden ODI hundred powers India women to reach 370-run mark for 1st time in 47 years - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxNYTBiSlNPS3hxNVQwdmZ3Y0xQLS10c1VYWFVoaGFwNk5FWFBsWTBRU0R5eko5dm9ld0xUWUVJbDh0dm95MC04aW1KUUN1dllxNk9yTDlLTUV0VHJXV0p2NUtfNDh4WkhUZ1pzNVoyRXZaNlFhV2Mtb3JHM181c05HR0syUWFwWUJSaDc5LUFURkNYa3dFd1U5aXBZNHRSVzdiRXpxZFdPTHJ2cFU1allPa0JSMjZpQ1FpMFFudGtmZ2g4a3RZQXotRldjTlV2Z2tjSkIzWXBzTnJLVnl5TFFZaWN6VVJOTDhmQ081eGN5NDhVU282SHk0WFhNQ2RzZy1TMnJSRkwyZE94Rkk0TlHSAZMCQVVfeXFMT0d5N0I0aWJFNXkzaHdNZXFOQTVGOThNck43VkR0bFdXODBnSTU2QnJJUWFmZE9qUl9TcTF3d0tPNXMxRGJEbFkzeWN0b09ZTmVwTjFwOW9qcFY0cFlDRXhDU1RsSndCZHpKM2t5UkpsdF91cXVvZUZyd0Z5US00QUFTa3gtZk5ac00tQnYyS1dscXBuY3hEZHVLd3FORXluQUV3U0pOc2ZpaE83MlVURG9rMTFmdWN3TzFpM1hLaDZpakRYUjM2eEhBaVJJX2xHdHNEejI5dmNfdFVOQ2tfdEpQYVZXbW1XUDllMkVJdlRjNEY2NDVHendIRW1kVWdQa1FYTU9QeHhLM0tYbmliek9WR1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxNYTBiSlNPS3hxNVQwdmZ3Y0xQLS10c1VYWFVoaGFwNk5FWFBsWTBRU0R5eko5dm9ld0xUWUVJbDh0dm95MC04aW1KUUN1dllxNk9yTDlLTUV0VHJXV0p2NUtfNDh4WkhUZ1pzNVoyRXZaNlFhV2Mtb3JHM181c05HR0syUWFwWUJSaDc5LUFURkNYa3dFd1U5aXBZNHRSVzdiRXpxZFdPTHJ2cFU1allPa0JSMjZpQ1FpMFFudGtmZ2g4a3RZQXotRldjTlV2Z2tjSkIzWXBzTnJLVnl5TFFZaWN6VVJOTDhmQ081eGN5NDhVU282SHk0WFhNQ2RzZy1TMnJSRkwyZE94Rkk0TlHSAZMCQVVfeXFMT0d5N0I0aWJFNXkzaHdNZXFOQTVGOThNck43VkR0bFdXODBnSTU2QnJJUWFmZE9qUl9TcTF3d0tPNXMxRGJEbFkzeWN0b09ZTmVwTjFwOW9qcFY0cFlDRXhDU1RsSndCZHpKM2t5UkpsdF91cXVvZUZyd0Z5US00QUFTa3gtZk5ac00tQnYyS1dscXBuY3hEZHVLd3FORXluQUV3U0pOc2ZpaE83MlVURG9rMTFmdWN3TzFpM1hLaDZpakRYUjM2eEhBaVJJX2xHdHNEejI5dmNfdFVOQ2tfdEpQYVZXbW1XUDllMkVJdlRjNEY2NDVHendIRW1kVWdQa1FYTU9QeHhLM0tYbmliek9WR1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:22:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ramesh Bidhuri refutes AAP's 'BJP CM face' claim: 'Arvind Kejriwal accepted...' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ramesh Bidhuri refutes AAP's 'BJP CM face' claim: 'Arvind Kejriwal accepted...'</h1><p><strong>Date: Jan 12, 2025</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/PTI01-11-2025-000279A-0_1736680715234_1736680760404.jpg" alt="Ramesh Bidhuri at a BJP event.(PTI file photo)" title="Ramesh Bidhuri at a BJP event.(PTI file photo)"><figcaption>Ramesh Bidhuri at a BJP event.(PTI file photo)</figcaption><p>Ramesh Bidhuri, the Bharatiya Janata Party's candidate for the Kalkaji assembly seat, refutes Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) chief Arvind Kejriwal's claim that he would be the BJP's chief ministerial face, stating that he is not a claimant for any post.</p><ul><li>Bidhuri clarifies his loyalty to the BJP and dismisses the claim as misleading propaganda.</li><li>Kejriwal's statement is interpreted as an acceptance that the BJP will form a government in Delhi after upcoming elections.</li><li>Bidhuri highlights public dissatisfaction with Kejriwal's governance, citing issues like the liquor scam and infrastructure problems.</li><li>He urges voters to support the BJP in the upcoming elections.</li></ul><blockquote>“By making an announcement in my context, Arvind Kejriwal has accepted that the BJP government is coming to power in Delhi...”</blockquote><p>The Delhi assembly elections are set for February 5, with results announced on February 8.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ramesh-bidhuri-reacts-to-arvind-kejriwals-bjp-cm-face-claim-not-a-claimant-for-101736680438254.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ramesh-bidhuri-reacts-to-arvind-kejriwals-bjp-cm-face-claim-not-a-claimant-for-101736680438254.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:21:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Baseless to refer me as BJP's CM face': Ramesh Bidhuri slams Arvind Kejriwal over 'misleading propaganda - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baseless to refer me as BJP's CM face': Ramesh Bidhuri slams Arvind Kejriwal over 'misleading propaganda'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>The political landscape has intensified as Ramesh Bidhuri publicly refutes Arvind Kejriwal's claim regarding his association with the BJP.</p><ul><li>Bidhuri claims that calls him BJP's Chief Ministerial candidate are groundless.</li><li>He criticizes Kejriwal for what he refers to as 'misleading propaganda'.</li><li>The political rivalry escalates amidst ongoing election campaigns.</li></ul><blockquote>“The allegations made against me are completely unfounded and part of a larger disinformation campaign.”</blockquote><p>The encounter reflects the fierce competition and tactics employed in Indian politics, showcasing how public statements can shape perceptions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/baseless-to-refer-me-as-bjps-cm-face-ramesh-bidhuri-slams-arvind-kejriwal-over-misleading-propaganda/articleshow/117172859.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/baseless-to-refer-me-as-bjps-cm-face-ramesh-bidhuri-slams-arvind-kejriwal-over-misleading-propaganda/articleshow/117172859.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ajith Kumar’s team clinches 3rd place in Dubai 24H race; Madhavan hails him as ‘the one and only’. Watch - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ajith Kumar’s team clinches 3rd place in Dubai 24H race; Madhavan hails him as ‘the one and only’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Ajith-Kumars-team-clinches-3rd-place-in-Dubai-24H-race-12012025.jpg?w=640" alt="Ajith Kumar's team in the race" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>The Tamil star's team Ajith Kumar Racing by Bas Koeten secured third place in the 991 category, while he also got the Spirit of the Race recognition in the GT4 category.</figcaption><p>Much to the delight of his fans, Tamil superstar Ajith Kumar has triumphed in the 24H Dubai 2025 endurance race, emerging with flying colours. This victory serves as a significant boost for both the actor and his fans, especially following his recent accident during training.</p><ul><li>Ajith Kumar Racing by Bas Koeten secured 3rd place in the 991 category.</li><li>Ajith received the Spirit of the Race recognition in the GT4 category.</li><li>Madhavan praised Ajith on social media, calling him “the one and only”.</li><li>Images and videos of Ajith celebrating with family and teammates flooded social media after the race.</li></ul><blockquote>“What a remarkable comeback after an accident due to a brake failure.” - Suresh Chandra, Ajith's manager</blockquote><p>This victory not only showcases Ajith's resilience but also brings joy to his fans and the wider Tamil film community.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/tamil/ajith-kumars-team-clinches-3rd-place-in-dubai-24h-race-watch-9774728/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/tamil/ajith-kumars-team-clinches-3rd-place-in-dubai-24h-race-watch-9774728/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Inauguration Guest List: Who’s Invited, Who’s Not And Are VIP Passes Running Out? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump's Inauguration Guest List: Who's Invited and VIP Passes Update</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Donald Trump Inauguration" title="US President-elect Donald Trump has invited several world leaders to his swearing-in ceremony in a bid to turn his inauguration into a political spectacle. (IMAGE: REUTERS)"><figcaption>US President-elect Donald Trump has invited several world leaders to his swearing-in ceremony in a bid to turn his inauguration into a political spectacle. (IMAGE: REUTERS)</figcaption><p>US President-elect Donald Trump has invited several world leaders to his inauguration, marking a departure from traditional US foreign policy where such invitations are uncommon.</p><ul><li>Trump invited Chinese President Xi Jinping, who may send an envoy.</li><li>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar will represent India.</li><li>Invited guests include leaders sharing Trump's political beliefs, such as Italy's Giorgia Meloni and El Salvador's Nayib Bukele.</li><li>VIP ticket sales have halted due to high demand; general admission is now required for attendees.</li><li>The inaugural committee has raised over $170 million, with expectations to exceed $200 million.</li></ul><blockquote>“Space is limited.”</blockquote><p>The inauguration is set for January 20, with several influential figures from the tech industry expected to attend, amid reports of limited VIP access.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/trump-inauguration-guest-list-whos-invited-whos-not-and-are-vip-passes-running-out-9186313.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/trump-inauguration-guest-list-whos-invited-whos-not-and-are-vip-passes-running-out-9186313.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:06:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Greenland PM Ready To Speak To Trump, Denmark Sends Private Messages To US President-Elect - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Greenland PM Ready To Speak To Trump, Denmark Sends Private Messages To US President-Elect</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Amid Greenland PM Mute Egede expressing willingness to speak to Donald Trump" loading="eager"><figcaption>Amid Greenland PM Mute Egede expressing willingness to speak to Donald Trump, it was also reported that the Danish government sent private messages to the US President-elect regarding the security of the island. (IMAGE: REUTERS/NASA)</figcaption><p>Denmark has sent private messages to the US President-elect Donald Trump's team indicating a willingness to discuss enhancing security in Greenland.</p><ul><li>Greenland Prime Minister Mute Egede is ready to converse with Trump following his prior comments about using military force to claim the resource-rich island.</li><li>Greenland, with a population of 57,000, is a self-governing territory of Denmark seeking more autonomy.</li><li>The Danish government intends to reassure Trump that his security concerns can be managed without claiming Greenland.</li><li>Egede emphasizes Greenland's desire for independence while maintaining cooperation with Denmark.</li><li>Denmark’s Prime Minister has requested a meeting with Trump, though it's not expected before his inauguration.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have a desire for independence, a desire to be the master of our own house … This is something everyone should respect.”</blockquote><p>The communication indicates heightened diplomatic engagement regarding Greenland's status and international security relating to the island.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/greenland-pm-ready-to-speak-to-trump-denmark-sends-private-messages-to-us-president-elect-9186082.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/greenland-pm-ready-to-speak-to-trump-denmark-sends-private-messages-to-us-president-elect-9186082.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>