<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:13:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:13:43 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manipur's Naga Groups Allege "Kuki Volunteers" Assaulted Students' Body Members - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxPT1BEbnVmbDhmS0M5Mm5URGtvT1JocmcxcUtPU1dtejUtc092OVZJeVNwSXZtYkZUeVJ1T2s5T3hyb1dET2Z2czhWVVBBUURWc1pDTmZrSktUaDBwWURYZThNekUxczdoWURwNzF5V3JPOTJvVm82ODRuZzdRQU9ha295ckNTdUUzT1dKRG4wSzZPODFxVlV5ZjgwRm45ZWc5RlFPVXdtZjZUNHlpSENRY1JPcWN0UdIBvgFBVV95cUxPeExMNkR4STJ6TjB4QVNpaGN1MXNnb2ljWDVzYmFpX2lBckZUV3ZldHFaLUJPd0hicmZyVXFwTzhFTV9jMHZfTVUwQWxFM0pnOFN1WDVRNTZSamFwQjY3OTVMQmdwRFY0YnJ4WVhwTlJkM3FCUnc2Y0N1UUx0SGp3Q0otQ2RBZEtjQlFEWXcyYkRKZFBuYk5Lc2J0MkYwVkNpVEJYRE5rQTVQNTA2VGp4TVlPVklkRFdiTngyRnl3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxPT1BEbnVmbDhmS0M5Mm5URGtvT1JocmcxcUtPU1dtejUtc092OVZJeVNwSXZtYkZUeVJ1T2s5T3hyb1dET2Z2czhWVVBBUURWc1pDTmZrSktUaDBwWURYZThNekUxczdoWURwNzF5V3JPOTJvVm82ODRuZzdRQU9ha295ckNTdUUzT1dKRG4wSzZPODFxVlV5ZjgwRm45ZWc5RlFPVXdtZjZUNHlpSENRY1JPcWN0UdIBvgFBVV95cUxPeExMNkR4STJ6TjB4QVNpaGN1MXNnb2ljWDVzYmFpX2lBckZUV3ZldHFaLUJPd0hicmZyVXFwTzhFTV9jMHZfTVUwQWxFM0pnOFN1WDVRNTZSamFwQjY3OTVMQmdwRFY0YnJ4WVhwTlJkM3FCUnc2Y0N1UUx0SGp3Q0otQ2RBZEtjQlFEWXcyYkRKZFBuYk5Lc2J0MkYwVkNpVEJYRE5rQTVQNTA2VGp4TVlPVklkRFdiTngyRnl3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:42:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vitamin D has no role to play in preventing fractures: New Research - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vitamin D has no role to play in preventing fractures: New Research</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116608544,imgsize-42160,width-400,resizemode-4/116608544.jpg" alt="Vitamin D has no role to play in preventing fractures: New Research">
<figcaption>Vitamin D has no role to play in preventing fractures: New Research</figcaption>
<p>New research from the US Preventive Services Task Force (USPSTF) indicates that Vitamin D supplements do not prevent falls or fractures in older adults.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The USPSTF recommends against taking Vitamin D with or without calcium for older adults aged 60 and over who live at home.</li>
  <li>Falling is a primary cause of injury in older adults, but increases in risk of kidney stones have been noted with unnecessary supplementation.</li>
  <li>Effective preventive services for falls include screening for osteoporosis and structured exercise programs.</li>
  <li>The recommendations do not apply to those taking Vitamin D for medical reasons or individuals diagnosed with conditions affecting Vitamin D absorption.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Unfortunately, when we reviewed the latest evidence, we found that taking vitamin D with or without calcium does not prevent falls or fractures in older adults.” - John M. Ruiz, Ph.D., USPSTF member.</blockquote>
<p>The findings emphasize the need for alternative preventive methods for maintaining bone health in older adults.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/vitamin-d-has-no-role-to-play-in-preventing-fractures-new-research/articleshow/116608544.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/vitamin-d-has-no-role-to-play-in-preventing-fractures-new-research/articleshow/116608544.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oppo Reno 13 Series 5G confirmed to launch in India: Expected price, features, and specs | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Oppo Reno 13 Series 5G Confirmed for India: Price, Features, and Specs</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> OPPO India</p>
<p>Oppo has officially confirmed the launch of its Reno 13 series 5G smartphones in India, following the success of the Reno 12 series. The release will feature two models: Reno 13 5G and Reno 13 Pro 5G, with significant design upgrades and innovative specifications.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Launch details were teased, although the exact date is not yet available.</li>
  <li>Design upgrades include a premium aluminium frame and a sculpted glass back.</li>
  <li>The devices will feature a triple-camera setup with a unique triangular design.</li>
  <li>Display specifications include a 6.59-inch AMOLED display, 2760x1256 resolution, 120Hz refresh rate.</li>
  <li>Powered by MediaTek Dimensity 8350 chipset with a 5,600mAh battery and 80W fast charging.</li>
  <li>The camera setup includes a 50MP primary sensor with OIS and a 50MP front camera for selfies.</li>
  <li>Running on ColorOS 15 based on Android 15.</li>
  <li>Expected pricing in China starts at CNY 2,699 (approx. ₹31,400), with Indian pricing yet to be announced.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>“Familiar, yet so refreshingly new. Can you guess what’s coming?” — OPPO India (@OPPOIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/OPPOIndia/status/1871081185528684578?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 23, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>The upcoming launch is aimed at appealing to both camera enthusiasts and gamers, promising high performance and cutting-edge technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/gadgets/oppo-reno-13-series-5g-confirmed-to-launch-in-india-expected-price-features-and-specs-11734975031051.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/gadgets/oppo-reno-13-series-5g-confirmed-to-launch-in-india-expected-price-features-and-specs-11734975031051.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:35:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Parker Solar Probe Achieves Closest Sun Flyby Ever on December 24 - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe Achieves Closest Sun Flyby Ever on December 24</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets360</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/MdC4Er14Tvw/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Parker Solar Probe Video">
<figcaption>Watch the Parker Solar Probe in action.</figcaption>
<p>The Parker Solar Probe is set to perform its closest flyby of the sun, travelling within 3.8 million miles of its surface, at an unprecedented speed of 430,000 mph.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The probe will collect data on the sun's corona during its 22nd solar approach.</li>
  <li>NASA confirms the spacecraft is functioning normally ahead of the record-setting flyby.</li>
  <li>Future flybys are scheduled for March 22 and June 19, 2025.</li>
  <li>The probe's advanced heat shield will protect its instruments from extreme temperatures of 1,800 degrees Fahrenheit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The probe will provide unprecedented data from regions no spacecraft has explored before.” - Nick Pinkine, mission operations manager at JHUAPL</blockquote>
<p>The results from the Parker Solar Probe's flyby will enhance our understanding of solar phenomena and the sun's behavior, with significant implications for solar science.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/parker-solar-probe-sets-record-breaking-sun-flyby-on-christmas-eve-2024-7313408</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/parker-solar-probe-sets-record-breaking-sun-flyby-on-christmas-eve-2024-7313408</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:01:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ruling, Opposition leaders join protesters outside CM Omar Abdullah’s residence over J&K reservation policy - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ruling, Opposition leaders join protesters outside CM Omar Abdullah’s residence over J&K reservation policy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/jammu-and-kashmir/l2rxoo/article69020331.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_23_2024_000310A.jpg" alt="Protest scene" title="Medical students stage a protest, led by Aga Syed Ruhullah Mehdi, demanding rationalisation of reservation in Jammu and Kashmir, outside J&amp;K Chief Minister Omar Abdullah’s residence in Srinagar, on December 23, 2024."><figcaption>Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>On December 23, 2024, a significant protest took place outside the residence of Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah in Srinagar, where various political leaders joined numerous students from the general category demanding a rationalisation of the existing reservation policy in the Union Territory.</p><ul><li>Mainstream leaders including Aga Syed Ruhullah from the NC and Iltija Mufti from the PDP protested together with aggrieved students.</li><li>Students criticized the new reservation policy that disproportionately benefits reserved categories, reducing open merit opportunities to less than 40%.</li><li>MP Ruhullah articulated the need for a fair reservation system based on population ratios or adhering to the Supreme Court's guidelines.</li><li>Solidarity was shown amongst different political factions, including both the ruling and opposition parties, highlighting the political and social implications of the policy.</li><li>The Chief Minister has promised a dialogue with student representatives regarding their concerns.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our future is in the dark if the current policy goes on.” - AIP legislator MLA Sheikh Khurshid</blockquote><p>This protest marks a crucial moment, reflecting the intense public sentiment towards the reservation framework in Jammu and Kashmir, and thus poses significant challenges for the regional government.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/ruling-opposition-leaders-join-protesters-outside-cm-omar-abdullahs-residence-over-jk-reservation-policy/article69019802.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/ruling-opposition-leaders-join-protesters-outside-cm-omar-abdullahs-residence-over-jk-reservation-policy/article69019802.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 health benefits of eating black pepper regularly - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Health Benefits of Eating Black Pepper Regularly</h1><p><strong>Published on: </strong>Published time: October 27, 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>TOI Lifestyle Desk</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116596943.cms?width=680&amp;height=512&amp;imgsize=1349499" alt="Health benefits of black pepper"><figcaption>Know why black pepper is called the king of spices.</figcaption><p>Black pepper is often referred to as the 'king of spices' and offers multiple health benefits, including boosting metabolism and enhancing digestion. Here are 10 reasons to include black pepper in your diet.</p><ul><li>Boosts metabolism and promotes fat burning.</li><li>Rich in antioxidants, fighting oxidative stress.</li><li>Helps relieve cough and cold symptoms.</li><li>Aids digestion and enhances nutrient absorption.</li><li>Stimulates blood circulation for better cardiovascular health.</li><li>Promotes skin health with antibacterial properties.</li><li>Enhances brain function and memory.</li><li>Supports immune function with antimicrobial properties.</li><li>Improves absorption of essential nutrients like curcumin.</li><li>Contains anti-inflammatory compounds.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/10-health-benefits-of-eating-black-pepper-regularly/photostory/116595708.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/10-health-benefits-of-eating-black-pepper-regularly/photostory/116595708.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement In India's Border Gavaskar Trophy Squad Named. Not Axar Patel Or Y.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement In India's Border Gavaskar Trophy Squad Named. Not Axar Patel Or Yuzvendra Chahal</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024<strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2d0t7bp_ashwin-afp_625x300_20_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement In India's Border Gavaskar Trophy Squad Named. Not Axar Patel Or Yuzvendra Chahal"><figcaption>File photo of Ravichandran Ashwin</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team has chosen a spinner-allrounder, Tanush Kotian, to replace Ravichandran Ashwin, who recently announced his retirement after a match. Kotian, who has no international experience, will be heading to Australia to join the squad.</p><ul><li>Kotian has a record of 101 wickets in 33 First Class matches.</li><li>He has also performed well in List A and T20 formats.</li><li>Ashwin retired after a prominent career, being India's second-highest wicket-taker.</li><li>Originally, Axar Patel was expected to replace Ashwin but opted for a break due to personal reasons.</li></ul><blockquote>“I made myself a promise in 2012, we lost a tricky series against England. I was very early in my career and I was just telling myself we are not gonna lose another one. Ever.” – Ravichandran Ashwin</blockquote><p>With Ashwin's exit, Kotian's inclusion represents a significant moment for the young spinner as he steps into a historic series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ravichandran-ashwins-replacement-in-indias-border-gavaskar-trophy-squad-named-not-kuldeep-yadav-or-yuzvendra-chahal-7314817</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ravichandran-ashwins-replacement-in-indias-border-gavaskar-trophy-squad-named-not-kuldeep-yadav-or-yuzvendra-chahal-7314817</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:20:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tanush Kotian added to India's squad for the last two Tests against Australia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tanush Kotian added to India's squad for the last two Tests against Australia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116606686,imgsize-19566,width-400,resizemode-4/116606686.jpg" alt="Tanush Kotian added to India's squad for the last two Tests against Australia" title="Tanush Kotian (Photo by Darrian Traynor/Getty Images)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Tanush Kotian (Photo by Darrian Traynor/Getty Images)</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has announced the addition of all-rounder Tanush Kotian to the Indian cricket squad for the fourth and fifth Tests of the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy against Australia.</p><ul><li>Kotian, an off-spinner from Mumbai, has been rewarded for his impressive performances in domestic cricket.</li><li>He has taken 101 wickets in 33 first-class matches at an average of 25.70, including three five-wicket hauls.</li><li>Kotian has scored two centuries and 13 half-centuries.</li><li>The 24-year-old's standout performances in the 2023-24 Ranji Trophy season helped Mumbai achieve victory.</li><li>He was named Player of the Tournament, scoring 502 runs at an average of 41.83 and taking 29 wickets at an average of 16.96.</li><li>Kotian replaces R Ashwin, who announced his retirement after the third Test.</li></ul><blockquote>Kotian's addition provides the Indian team with an additional spin-bowling option and batting depth as they aim to clinch the series against the formidable Australian side.</blockquote><p>The series is currently tied at 1-1 after three Tests, making these upcoming matches crucial for both teams.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/tanush-kotian-added-to-indias-squad-for-the-last-two-tests-against-australia/articleshow/116606378.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/tanush-kotian-added-to-indias-squad-for-the-last-two-tests-against-australia/articleshow/116606378.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione pleads not guilty; lawyer blasts mayor Eric Adams for perp walk - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Luigi Mangione pleads not guilty; lawyer blasts mayor Eric Adams for perp walk</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 23, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Luigi Mangione" /><figcaption>Luigi Mangione during the court appearance.</figcaption><p>Luigi Mangione entered a not guilty plea regarding the charges against him, while his lawyer expressed strong criticism of Mayor Eric Adams for the manner in which Mangione was publicly escorted to court.</p><ul><li>Mangione's lawyer stated that the perp walk was unnecessary and harmful.</li><li>The charges against Mangione include serious criminal offenses.</li><li>Public reaction has been mixed, with some supporting the mayor's actions while others criticize them as politically motivated.</li></ul><blockquote>“This kind of treatment is not what justice looks like,” said Mangione's lawyer.</blockquote><p>The case has garnered significant media attention, raising questions about the treatment of individuals accused of crimes before a trial.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/luigi-mangione-pleads-not-guilty-lawyer-blasts-mayor-eric-adams-for-perp-walk/articleshow/116606255.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/luigi-mangione-pleads-not-guilty-lawyer-blasts-mayor-eric-adams-for-perp-walk/articleshow/116606255.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi LG VK Saxena blames Arvind Kejriwal for Yamuna pollution: ‘I personally hold you responsible’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi LG VK Saxena Blames Arvind Kejriwal for Yamuna Pollution: ‘I Personally Hold You Responsible’</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/VK_Saxena_and_Kejriwal_1734968969171_1734968969723.jpg" alt="New Delhi: Delhi Lt. Governor VK Saxena with former chief minister Arvind Kejriwal and Delhi CM Atishi.(PTI file)" title="New Delhi: Delhi Lt. Governor VK Saxena with former chief minister Arvind Kejriwal and Delhi CM Atishi.(PTI file)">
<figcaption>New Delhi: Delhi Lt. Governor VK Saxena with former chief minister Arvind Kejriwal and Delhi CM Atishi.(PTI file)</figcaption>
<p>Delhi lieutenant governor Vinai Kumar Saxena has publicly criticized former chief minister Arvind Kejriwal, attributing the severe pollution in the Yamuna River to his actions, including interference with cleaning efforts.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Saxena accused Kejriwal of halting pollution clean-up operations mandated by the Supreme Court.</li>
  <li>The Yamuna has reportedly reached unprecedented pollution levels this year.</li>
  <li>Saxena reiterated his requests for Kejriwal to personally assess the pollution situation.</li>
  <li>This incident follows prior instances of Saxena holding Kejriwal accountable for the river's declining condition.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Yamuna has reached its highest level of pollution this year. I will personally hold you responsible for this.” - Vinai Kumar Saxena</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing conflict highlights the contentious relationship between Delhi's current and former leadership regarding environmental management and accountability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-lg-vk-saxena-blames-arvind-kejriwal-for-yamuna-pollution-i-personally-hold-you-responsible-101734967880926.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-lg-vk-saxena-blames-arvind-kejriwal-for-yamuna-pollution-i-personally-hold-you-responsible-101734967880926.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:53:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digvijay Rathee to Jasmine Bhasin; Unfair evictions of Bigg Boss - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Digvijay Rathee to Jasmine Bhasin; Unfair evictions of Bigg Boss</h1><p><strong>Updated: Dec 23, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Times of India</strong></p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/imgsize-39098,msid-116606020,width-600,height-335,resizemode-75/116606020.jpg" alt="Digvijay Rathee to Jasmine Bhasin; Unfair evictions of Bigg Boss"><figcaption>Digvijay Rathee to Jasmine Bhasin; Unfair evictions of Bigg Boss</figcaption><p>The article discusses the impact of evictions in the popular reality show Bigg Boss, highlighting various contestants including Digvijay Rathee and Jasmine Bhasin. It raises concerns over the fairness of these evictions and the reactions from fans.</p><ul><li>Digvijay Rathee faced eviction amid controversies regarding the fairness of the decision.</li><li>Fans believe Rathee was a strong contender who deserved to stay longer on the show.</li><li>Other contestants like Umar Riaz and Zeeshan Khan also faced similar calls for their evictions being politically motivated.</li><li>The discussion extends to Jasmine Bhasin and other notable contestants who have made significant impacts during their time on the show.</li></ul><blockquote>"Many believe he was a strong contender who deserved to stay longer, leading to widespread calls for his return to the show."</blockquote><p>The controversies surrounding evictions on Bigg Boss continue to generate significant discussion among fans, suggesting a deeper engagement with the show's politics and contestant dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/digvijay-rathee-to-jasmine-bhasin-unfair-evictions-of-bigg-boss/photostory/116606001.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tv/news/hindi/digvijay-rathee-to-jasmine-bhasin-unfair-evictions-of-bigg-boss/photostory/116606001.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:38:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Love coffee or tea? These beverages may lower risk of head and neck cancer, claims study - mid-day.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxNc1Ztd2JOTmhRai1KdnNsbUhGdGJGV2pKbll5UlNUd2FtZ20wVE9CdnhMT2NFb1VsZjZkRTFWdFJLV1hwNnNiVDU0d2dyRmpHZFNXNkIwb2tMV2xVa1Z3WUt3SDhyQl85YjIwVThVemtNbFR2UU42OXlzWG5lRGJGTXhuZlVTV3pEWXFaWi0yUzN5QWdka3czd3dTWTRCQWlpdTRLMG56d3VRS3k3cVVNaFRWeTVJT3hURlphTkZYSFpRM3d5VVptS0NTT05aZXVXRXZrUm9ma2V6Mk8zSzB0X0xYU3pCX3Z5QU9XaNIB8gFBVV95cUxQcTJLbkd3X0NjMTctbFJITjQ5SktMN1NOa1Zuak9fb2FBR3VobzgxaTBKQUJianlYN3RXVEl0QVA2NVotR2RuZmtHNTFqd2J3cXlyWDdteXpXczZZdXZ4V3M4Yy1Pb2NaQ0Q5ZC1PS2pNOTBLZ1d6SFZzaFd0VW9WWTdnbGN1R2dlQXVhdy1tMlozX19Fc1VxaTJZcDVLZ1UwZUQ5RWdQY29uTjhJajRQWms5OHB5d3NWRFY5SHp3aXc5WWotcWNoVTRlSXpRcFFVOWk5bnM1a253cWNHU1k1bDhuVm9CaWowd0NvakE0UzVqZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxNc1Ztd2JOTmhRai1KdnNsbUhGdGJGV2pKbll5UlNUd2FtZ20wVE9CdnhMT2NFb1VsZjZkRTFWdFJLV1hwNnNiVDU0d2dyRmpHZFNXNkIwb2tMV2xVa1Z3WUt3SDhyQl85YjIwVThVemtNbFR2UU42OXlzWG5lRGJGTXhuZlVTV3pEWXFaWi0yUzN5QWdka3czd3dTWTRCQWlpdTRLMG56d3VRS3k3cVVNaFRWeTVJT3hURlphTkZYSFpRM3d5VVptS0NTT05aZXVXRXZrUm9ma2V6Mk8zSzB0X0xYU3pCX3Z5QU9XaNIB8gFBVV95cUxQcTJLbkd3X0NjMTctbFJITjQ5SktMN1NOa1Zuak9fb2FBR3VobzgxaTBKQUJianlYN3RXVEl0QVA2NVotR2RuZmtHNTFqd2J3cXlyWDdteXpXczZZdXZ4V3M4Yy1Pb2NaQ0Q5ZC1PS2pNOTBLZ1d6SFZzaFd0VW9WWTdnbGN1R2dlQXVhdy1tMlozX19Fc1VxaTJZcDVLZ1UwZUQ5RWdQY29uTjhJajRQWms5OHB5d3NWRFY5SHp3aXc5WWotcWNoVTRlSXpRcFFVOWk5bnM1a253cWNHU1k1bDhuVm9CaWowd0NvakE0UzVqZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chile’s WOM Cleared to Exit Chapter 11 Bankruptcy Proceedings | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chile’s WOM Cleared to Exit Chapter 11 Bankruptcy Proceedings</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p>
<p>The Chilean telecommunications company WOM has been granted court approval to exit Chapter 11 bankruptcy proceedings, following a takeover and restructuring agreement with a group of creditors.</p>
<ul>
  <li>WOM filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy eight months ago.</li>
  <li>A takeover bid from a group of bondholders valued WOM at $1.6 billion.</li>
  <li>The agreement includes a $500 million investment and a net debt reduction of $650 million.</li>
  <li>The decision was made by a US bankruptcy judge, rejecting a rival creditor's objection.</li>
  <li>WOM has approximately 20% of the mobile market share in Chile, ranking third behind Telefonica's Movistar and Entel.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The decision is a landmark in the Chapter 11 process and the efforts we have made as a team to financially restructure the company.” - Martín Vaca Narvaja, WOM’s CEO</blockquote>
<p>This restructuring plan ensures the operational continuity of WOM Chile and sets the stage for its future growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/chiles-wom-cleared-to-exit-chapter-11-bankruptcy-proceedings-11734968053779.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/chiles-wom-cleared-to-exit-chapter-11-bankruptcy-proceedings-11734968053779.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:34:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani Group Acquires Air Works MRO for $47 Million - Aviation A2z]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxOUWduazRKVHJFNkR6SF9JSWxnaDNyNEZxb21mbW0zcExhZW10dVNXTEdYTzI5c2VmSzRZVTV5NWJnZjlfUWQ1ZmNwTnNaeUxGNVM5Ulk3dGl5TUVlR0JJeE5ULVNMbHltVzFuR1NXUWNWN3pRaEN4YU9iTGVBRnZhaWhXRUhiOGs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxOUWduazRKVHJFNkR6SF9JSWxnaDNyNEZxb21mbW0zcExhZW10dVNXTEdYTzI5c2VmSzRZVTV5NWJnZjlfUWQ1ZmNwTnNaeUxGNVM5Ulk3dGl5TUVlR0JJeE5ULVNMbHltVzFuR1NXUWNWN3pRaEN4YU9iTGVBRnZhaWhXRUhiOGs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:08:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More reasons to cheer for tea, coffee lovers as latest research shows they can prevent cancer - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tea and Coffee May Help Prevent Head and Neck Cancer, Research Shows</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116605215,imgsize-44556,width-400,resizemode-4/116605215.jpg" alt="More reasons to cheer for tea, coffee lovers as latest research shows they can prevent cancer" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Research shows tea and coffee drinkers may reduce cancer risks.</figcaption>
<p>The latest research indicates that both tea and coffee drinkers may have a lower risk of developing head and neck cancer, establishing both beverages as potentially protective against certain cancers.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Studies suggest reduced risk of head and neck cancers among consumers of tea and coffee.</li>
  <li>Data from 14 studies analyzed 9,548 cancer patients and 15,783 controls.</li>
  <li>Drinking more than 4 cups of caffeinated coffee daily can lower the risk of throat cancer by 22% and oral cancer by 30%.</li>
  <li>Decaffeinated coffee and tea also show potential protective effects.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This study highlighted their varying effects with different sub-sites of head and neck cancer.” - Yuan-Chin Amy Lee, PhD</blockquote>
<p>These findings stress the importance of further research into how our beverage choices may contribute to cancer prevention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/more-reasons-to-cheer-for-tea-coffee-lovers-as-latest-research-shows-they-can-prevent-cancer/articleshow/116605215.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/more-reasons-to-cheer-for-tea-coffee-lovers-as-latest-research-shows-they-can-prevent-cancer/articleshow/116605215.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Absolute necessity': Why Trump wants to buy Greenland - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/absolute-necessity-why-trump-wants-to-buy-greenland/articleshow/116605013.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/absolute-necessity-why-trump-wants-to-buy-greenland/articleshow/116605013.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shyam Benegal, a giant of Indian cinema, passes away at 90 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shyam Benegal, a Giant of Indian Cinema, Passes Away at 90</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 23, 2024 - The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/o95r2w/article69019856.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/6_Shyam_Benegal.jpg" alt="Shyam Benegal at his office in Mumbai." title="Shyam Benegal at his office in Mumbai."><figcaption>Shyam Benegal at his office in Mumbai. | Photo Credit: Vivek Bendre</figcaption><p>Filmmaker Shyam Benegal, a towering figure in Indian cinema and a leading force behind the Parallel Cinema movement, has passed away at the age of 90 due to kidney-related ailments in Mumbai.</p><ul><li>Benegal was renowned for his impactful films such as <i>Ankur, Nishant, Mandi, Manthan</i>, and <i>Zubeidaa</i>.</li><li>He addressed critical social issues, including feudalism and women’s rights, and experimented with cinematic form.</li><li>His daughter confirmed his death, citing chronic kidney disease as the cause.</li><li>Naseeruddin Shah expressed deep gratitude for Benegal’s mentorship and support throughout his career.</li><li>He directed notable biopics and received numerous accolades including the Padma Shri and Padma Bhushan.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is impossible to describe in a few words what Shyam meant to me.” - Naseeruddin Shah</blockquote><p>Shyam Benegal's legacy will continue to inspire future filmmakers and audiences around the world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/veteran-filmmaker-shyam-benegal-dies-at-90/article69019832.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/veteran-filmmaker-shyam-benegal-dies-at-90/article69019832.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 The Rule stampede: Producer of Allu Arjun film donates ₹50 lakh to victim's family - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxQRVN3aG56anQzVUozTEJocWNoT0hUbXViY1NTci1PQlJ3S0sxV2dFWVY5elBQdW53UFE4Y2VyM1F3ay0xWExOTk5ERkJua1EyYWVHS3g1dGJIbUczQ29pQ1U3RUhmUjF4N2p5UDRqM2ZvRm1YN0xtMG1xZ2lWd3hROFRHa2ZYb2lJRDdRRWpLUldsbUFCQTktZjBNZ3ZNY0Z1OU9IZ0NSQ0F4RF9Bc1ZvTEhZc0pkX1QxTDN0WU1mbkRMMGNqZVl0UkpGcXpKT18wYldvMnlOR0lSWTh0OUFLbThHanZVN2E3dkxPa1QzaTJYZXJWLVZwX3JzblBaQdIBgwJBVV95cUxPX3BSZUJOaUtITm52R3pLRFJDdlRYMXNKREZqTW9VaGRhMXQ1SGV3ZVZDOWUycXZ6bFlBeUI5amU1dDdfeHhuUVZFM3BXU2J5ZE92anBYZzdhMWg3b3RTZVZ3MF80ZExFaDhjZTVQVjVOOC1BeDA2N2tmQURYYXp5NWdqUlZQU2tkbFNkVktmZmJrOUZsMnU0NTRQdkRnalE1SFJreElNUmZsc2tzRUJ3bFBLTUxuRk9nbW13cW5Wd1pRMERldWJxZlRvN3lwdlA4MTF0M1hYR1JnS1UzXy1RRXhMMjhwRGRMZXFXeTFkcjFPMzVZOW82NjY5NHlFdG15MS1v?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxQRVN3aG56anQzVUozTEJocWNoT0hUbXViY1NTci1PQlJ3S0sxV2dFWVY5elBQdW53UFE4Y2VyM1F3ay0xWExOTk5ERkJua1EyYWVHS3g1dGJIbUczQ29pQ1U3RUhmUjF4N2p5UDRqM2ZvRm1YN0xtMG1xZ2lWd3hROFRHa2ZYb2lJRDdRRWpLUldsbUFCQTktZjBNZ3ZNY0Z1OU9IZ0NSQ0F4RF9Bc1ZvTEhZc0pkX1QxTDN0WU1mbkRMMGNqZVl0UkpGcXpKT18wYldvMnlOR0lSWTh0OUFLbThHanZVN2E3dkxPa1QzaTJYZXJWLVZwX3JzblBaQdIBgwJBVV95cUxPX3BSZUJOaUtITm52R3pLRFJDdlRYMXNKREZqTW9VaGRhMXQ1SGV3ZVZDOWUycXZ6bFlBeUI5amU1dDdfeHhuUVZFM3BXU2J5ZE92anBYZzdhMWg3b3RTZVZ3MF80ZExFaDhjZTVQVjVOOC1BeDA2N2tmQURYYXp5NWdqUlZQU2tkbFNkVktmZmJrOUZsMnU0NTRQdkRnalE1SFJreElNUmZsc2tzRUJ3bFBLTUxuRk9nbW13cW5Wd1pRMERldWJxZlRvN3lwdlA4MTF0M1hYR1JnS1UzXy1RRXhMMjhwRGRMZXFXeTFkcjFPMzVZOW82NjY5NHlFdG15MS1v?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:50:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shyam Benegal, India's Parallel Cinema Pioneer, Dies At 90 - NDTV Movies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shyam Benegal, India's Parallel Cinema Pioneer, Dies At 90</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><p>Shyam Benegal, a seminal figure in Indian parallel cinema, passed away at the age of 90 in Mumbai, leaving a significant legacy in filmmaking known for realism and social commentary.</p><ul><li>Shyam Benegal died on December 14, 2023, after suffering from chronic kidney disease.</li><li>He was hospitalized in the intensive care unit at Wockhardt Hospital just days after his 90th birthday.</li><li>His daughter confirmed that he had been ill for several years but was still working on multiple projects.</li><li>Benegal's last film was the biographical 'Mujib: The Making of a Nation' released in 2023.</li><li>Known for classic films like 'Bhumika', 'Manthan', and 'Junoon', he is a pivotal figure in Hindi cinema.</li></ul><blockquote>“I'm working on two to three projects; they are all different from one another.” - Shyam Benegal on his 90th birthday.</blockquote><p>Shyam Benegal's contributions to parallel cinema have left an indelible mark on Indian culture, promoting realism and important social issues through his work.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/veteran-filmmaker-shyam-benegal-dies-at-90-7316077</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/veteran-filmmaker-shyam-benegal-dies-at-90-7316077</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:36:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Filmmaker Shyam Benegal passes away at the age of 90 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNd0tRTmpOT0x3TENRU0czYXlGYk41WEdlNUkzcVBSbEZCVHhUMGx6UjExMW9od20zRnRuYkpnMXhObmhfRzdIeTQzV3lBZnBzV0NNdVdhamZzd1B3XzdrNHl0c3lmdUd5Z0tqQWFRS3lJc2tVMmkyTlMxUFhRYURaZ1NBNE05RmtsRG9wN2owOENLYzJqR1p0Uy05RUdHdF9xNmxrZDRVT2t4SlBJSGJFaEEwUjg3VHZLYkJCWlNlTmlOQlpPb1pHVWxBVm1oaTNEaHhfWW9WRzl2ZW4zNlllYnhaRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNd0tRTmpOT0x3TENRU0czYXlGYk41WEdlNUkzcVBSbEZCVHhUMGx6UjExMW9od20zRnRuYkpnMXhObmhfRzdIeTQzV3lBZnBzV0NNdVdhamZzd1B3XzdrNHl0c3lmdUd5Z0tqQWFRS3lJc2tVMmkyTlMxUFhRYURaZ1NBNE05RmtsRG9wN2owOENLYzJqR1p0Uy05RUdHdF9xNmxrZDRVT2t4SlBJSGJFaEEwUjg3VHZLYkJCWlNlTmlOQlpPb1pHVWxBVm1oaTNEaHhfWW9WRzl2ZW4zNlllYnhaRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["It Pains My Heart...": PM Cites Germany, Lanka Attacks At Christmas Event - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxNMFV4YkZwcDZwZlducEZkcF9YSTJ1NUYzSlFRcTdMTFN3YlMxR25FRlVXSnVlRjNjVWJYOVl1Zm51U28yZk1SYWxRRk1kejlXZmdqcEI4WEg1N3VEak80LURaNHhBQkpjNFJaSUctN0d6UDE3bHRiNmJ0Y3FpQjlQYVlpRUlYUThmeVV1YXk4eXZPWWFyX1pScEhhR1VmQ1Rqc2owQ0Y1eHFYRW5OblhOMjZn0gG6AUFVX3lxTE8xR1R6WFBwZjNhQnd0V1B6N1JubzRUc3FDVXktZ0VqNkU0NlVIZjBzVTFXbVNFek9IcF9tRVN3aDhzRGlqUzFFaUVCb1I5T2ZDYWVpQzBmTkQyeGRSQ3ZJdHlXMXo4WWxIYUdNQi1taUpNRTdqaHV4eTZ0Q1YydVNNQjU4d0JWVVFXTzlZYXFyeV8zVzFqX2xrZ1I5bENlZ09SbWNaaWd0TDE5SmZLOHYza2lrbTlzTEtQUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxNMFV4YkZwcDZwZlducEZkcF9YSTJ1NUYzSlFRcTdMTFN3YlMxR25FRlVXSnVlRjNjVWJYOVl1Zm51U28yZk1SYWxRRk1kejlXZmdqcEI4WEg1N3VEak80LURaNHhBQkpjNFJaSUctN0d6UDE3bHRiNmJ0Y3FpQjlQYVlpRUlYUThmeVV1YXk4eXZPWWFyX1pScEhhR1VmQ1Rqc2owQ0Y1eHFYRW5OblhOMjZn0gG6AUFVX3lxTE8xR1R6WFBwZjNhQnd0V1B6N1JubzRUc3FDVXktZ0VqNkU0NlVIZjBzVTFXbVNFek9IcF9tRVN3aDhzRGlqUzFFaUVCb1I5T2ZDYWVpQzBmTkQyeGRSQ3ZJdHlXMXo4WWxIYUdNQi1taUpNRTdqaHV4eTZ0Q1YydVNNQjU4d0JWVVFXTzlZYXFyeV8zVzFqX2xrZ1I5bENlZ09SbWNaaWd0TDE5SmZLOHYza2lrbTlzTEtQUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oyo buys US-based G6 Hospitality from Blackstone for $525 mn, adds 1,500 hotels - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Oyo buys US-based G6 Hospitality from Blackstone for $525 mn, adds 1,500 hotels</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent publication<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Oyo has completed the acquisition of G6 Hospitality, known for its Motel 6 and Studio 6 brands, from Blackstone for $525 million. This deal is expected to significantly expand Oyo's presence in North America.</p>
<img src='URL-to-image' alt='Oyo Acquisition' />
<figcaption>Image depicting Oyo's new acquisition of G6 Hospitality.</figcaption>
<p>The acquisition aims to enhance Oyo's profitability, projecting an Ebitda of over ₹2,000 crore by FY26. Motel 6 is expected to contribute significantly to this goal in the upcoming financial year. Oyo will be adding about 1,500 franchised hotels across the US and Canada, with a combined booking value reaching approximately $3 billion.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Oyo's acquisition is worth $525 million.</li>
  <li>The deal adds 1,500 hotels to Oyo's portfolio.</li>
  <li>Integration of Motel 6 is expected to deliver ₹630 crore in Ebitda.</li>
  <li>The acquisition aligns with Oyo’s strategy for robust growth in the US market.</li>
  <li>Sonal Sinha appointed as CEO of G6 Hospitality.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This acquisition represents a transformative moment for Oyo's global operations. We could see this will be a value-accretive acquisition due to their strong brand franchise in the US, potential for growth and synergies.” - Ankit Tandon, Oyo</blockquote>
<p>This strategic move not only enhances Oyo's market position but also marks a significant step in its expansion plans across North America.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/oyo-acquires-g6-hospitality-from-blackstone-for-525-mn-eyes-rs-2000-cr-ebitda-in-fy26-11734960828739.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/oyo-acquires-g6-hospitality-from-blackstone-for-525-mn-eyes-rs-2000-cr-ebitda-in-fy26-11734960828739.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:17:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coffee, tea may protect against head & neck cancer: Study - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxNTDVENmRHbS1yOU9fenJKX0FMdGJaX05FejE5RExpanIyRklEWWlQWWRzazBobUxic2IwZVNJSFgzUkIwNjZIT0ExS1o3TC16alZmM1ltbEM2N1ptcXlGM0xjMkh3RXZRUmo2dlRXXzlHUGRlOFV3VHViTmwzb1VwWm5OV3JWMDlIODcwVlF2LUszVnlXN2Mw0gGjAUFVX3lxTE9PVk9oRTlYQ1JIcFlacDJfTzAtcTBsQ3dYajVRWndwNHV4czkzRUNqeUUycm1sYzVVRjNLUmk5OHdhUlNBVmZ6QTREM0V2NGNOMmthQjJHV2g5ODlGeEZRdWtkOFFjNzR5eHk4ejRpb0I1OEYtMkN4aWxOZHNJeWZjUkdfOGMwWnVURWdSeml1cEI5THFvTFVFR0VIcFVvVGFFR3M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxNTDVENmRHbS1yOU9fenJKX0FMdGJaX05FejE5RExpanIyRklEWWlQWWRzazBobUxic2IwZVNJSFgzUkIwNjZIT0ExS1o3TC16alZmM1ltbEM2N1ptcXlGM0xjMkh3RXZRUmo2dlRXXzlHUGRlOFV3VHViTmwzb1VwWm5OV3JWMDlIODcwVlF2LUszVnlXN2Mw0gGjAUFVX3lxTE9PVk9oRTlYQ1JIcFlacDJfTzAtcTBsQ3dYajVRWndwNHV4czkzRUNqeUUycm1sYzVVRjNLUmk5OHdhUlNBVmZ6QTREM0V2NGNOMmthQjJHV2g5ODlGeEZRdWtkOFFjNzR5eHk4ejRpb0I1OEYtMkN4aWxOZHNJeWZjUkdfOGMwWnVURWdSeml1cEI5THFvTFVFR0VIcFVvVGFFR3M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:03:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Clots In Brain": On Vinod Kambli's Urgent Hospitalisation, Doctor Gives Worrying Update - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli Hospitalized Due to Brain Clots: Doctor Provides Update</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/0g2i692o_vinod-kambli_625x300_23_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Vinod Kambli Hospitalized" /><figcaption>Vinod Kambli was hospitalized on Saturday night.</figcaption><p>Vinod Kambli, the former India cricketer, has been hospitalized with brain clots following initial complaints of a urinary infection. Doctors have reported that his condition remains critical but stable.</p><ul><li>Kambli was admitted to Akruti Hospital in Thane after experiencing urinary issues and cramps.</li><li>Medical examinations revealed clots in his brain; ongoing monitoring and further tests are scheduled.</li><li>Dr. Vivek Trivedi stated that Kambli's health is being closely observed.</li><li>Life-long free treatment has been pledged by the hospital in-charge, S Singh.</li><li>Kambli's recent health struggles have gained public attention, particularly due to viral videos showing his condition.</li></ul><blockquote>Kambli said, "I am better now. My wife takes care of me a lot... My son picked me up and brought me back to my feet."</blockquote><p>The situation remains serious as doctors continue to monitor Kambli's health, and further updates are anticipated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/clots-in-brain-on-vinod-kamblis-urgent-hospitalisation-doctor-gives-worrying-details-7315795</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/clots-in-brain-on-vinod-kamblis-urgent-hospitalisation-doctor-gives-worrying-details-7315795</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Clots In Brain": On Vinod Kambli's Urgent Hospitalisation, Doctor Gives Worrying Details - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli Hospitalized Due to Brain Clots: Doctor Provides Update</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/0g2i692o_vinod-kambli_625x300_23_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Vinod Kambli Hospitalized" /><figcaption>Vinod Kambli was hospitalized on Saturday night.</figcaption><p>Vinod Kambli, the former India cricketer, has been hospitalized with brain clots following initial complaints of a urinary infection. Doctors have reported that his condition remains critical but stable.</p><ul><li>Kambli was admitted to Akruti Hospital in Thane after experiencing urinary issues and cramps.</li><li>Medical examinations revealed clots in his brain; ongoing monitoring and further tests are scheduled.</li><li>Dr. Vivek Trivedi stated that Kambli's health is being closely observed.</li><li>Life-long free treatment has been pledged by the hospital in-charge, S Singh.</li><li>Kambli's recent health struggles have gained public attention, particularly due to viral videos showing his condition.</li></ul><blockquote>Kambli said, "I am better now. My wife takes care of me a lot... My son picked me up and brought me back to my feet."</blockquote><p>The situation remains serious as doctors continue to monitor Kambli's health, and further updates are anticipated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/clots-in-brain-on-vinod-kamblis-urgent-hospitalisation-doctor-gives-worrying-details-7315795</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/clots-in-brain-on-vinod-kamblis-urgent-hospitalisation-doctor-gives-worrying-details-7315795</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Attends Christmas Programme Hosted By Catholic Bishops Conference Of India - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Condemns Violence and Promotes Harmony During Christmas Address</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="PM Modi at Christmas celebrations hosted by the Catholic Bishops' Conference of India (CBCI)." title="PM Modi at Christmas celebrations hosted by the Catholic Bishops' Conference of India (CBCI)."><figcaption>PM Modi at Christmas celebrations hosted by the Catholic Bishops' Conference of India (CBCI). (Image: X/@narendramodi)</figcaption></figure><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi addressed a Christmas event hosted by the Catholic Bishops’ Conference of India, condemning attempts to incite violence and emphasizing the teachings of love and brotherhood from Jesus Christ.</p><ul><li>Modi vowed to strengthen the spirit of love as emphasized in Christian teachings.</li><li>Condemned a recent terror attack in Germany that resulted in multiple casualties.</li><li>Highlighted India's humanitarian efforts during the COVID-19 pandemic.</li><li>Stressed the importance of bringing back Indian citizens trapped in crises, including war-torn regions.</li><li>Celebrated the elevation of George Koovakad as a Cardinal by Pope Francis.</li><li>Invited Pope Francis to visit India, marking a significant diplomatic gesture.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Bible says – bear each other’s burdens. Our institutions and organisations work with this motto.” - PM Modi</blockquote><p>PM Modi’s address reinforced India's dedication to humanitarian values and interfaith harmony, marking a significant moment in the country's cultural and diplomatic landscape during the Christmas season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-attends-christmas-programme-hosted-by-catholic-bishops-conference-of-india-9166067.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-attends-christmas-programme-hosted-by-catholic-bishops-conference-of-india-9166067.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:55:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Not Able To Do The Job": Cheteshwar Pujara's Unfiltered Dig At India Duo Ahead of Boxing Day Test - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxPaW4xSGZ1amJEN1dBSnhIOXRPcU9uUlVGZ3BhdUEwRmttcldaNmJMOGFfSGFiVkZUV01aXzB0bTdqTndzMW1fUDhXR0tnU1RLWURlbjBLb2dWV0xZcWVyTGpnbVd6NWpDZ0RtZ1RMX3R2R3NucTQ4UTFqVU5sbVdVV3Q1Z1JwX1RYeTlBN0pDemJ0dWZrclF1cVdHaEdoWWRPLTl0bWg3dkExSnl1SUZSOUEyYnBHNFRydVJjMDE0eW45ZFFkUFc00gHPAUFVX3lxTE1RM3ozaV9fU1Rxa0IzOUl6VmtHbVZBVW9uYkpycGhHaEtPOGhjMWdEMEMxdld4dkFjUFN0S3N6WU82SXdfenJBOTM3aXQ3SlRrc2hYWGJXVUxiZTRtRmVfVEFrVkdYVmxPS0pRR25FUnZoOENvY2Y1R2NpTEl2Z2FadU1fcnlqZ3dod2lNRU1vUDhyWG44N3JBYjVuMVdLVGs3eDd2RUFGbXFXMlZvNXhmUlYtTmZFcTYtcnRjMUlVRGkwOEtZZlo2c2dhRmtVOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxPaW4xSGZ1amJEN1dBSnhIOXRPcU9uUlVGZ3BhdUEwRmttcldaNmJMOGFfSGFiVkZUV01aXzB0bTdqTndzMW1fUDhXR0tnU1RLWURlbjBLb2dWV0xZcWVyTGpnbVd6NWpDZ0RtZ1RMX3R2R3NucTQ4UTFqVU5sbVdVV3Q1Z1JwX1RYeTlBN0pDemJ0dWZrclF1cVdHaEdoWWRPLTl0bWg3dkExSnl1SUZSOUEyYnBHNFRydVJjMDE0eW45ZFFkUFc00gHPAUFVX3lxTE1RM3ozaV9fU1Rxa0IzOUl6VmtHbVZBVW9uYkpycGhHaEtPOGhjMWdEMEMxdld4dkFjUFN0S3N6WU82SXdfenJBOTM3aXQ3SlRrc2hYWGJXVUxiZTRtRmVfVEFrVkdYVmxPS0pRR25FUnZoOENvY2Y1R2NpTEl2Z2FadU1fcnlqZ3dod2lNRU1vUDhyWG44N3JBYjVuMVdLVGs3eDd2RUFGbXFXMlZvNXhmUlYtTmZFcTYtcnRjMUlVRGkwOEtZZlo2c2dhRmtVOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:46:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deepika Padukone-Ranveer Singh introduce daughter Dua to paps at private event. See photos - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Deepika Padukone-Ranveer Singh Introduce Daughter Dua to Paps at Private Event</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Deepika-Padukone-3.jpg?w=640" alt="Deepika Padukone with Ranveer Singh" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Deepika Padukone and Ranveer Singh reveal daughter Dua's face to paps. (Photo: APH)</figcaption><p>Bollywood couple Ranveer Singh and Deepika Padukone hosted an event to introduce their daughter, Dua Padukone Singh, to the paparazzi, marking their first public appearance since her birth in September.</p><ul><li>The couple requested privacy regarding their child's photos, similar to other Bollywood parents.</li><li>Deepika wore a beige long dress, while Ranveer opted for a white co-ord set during the event.</li><li>This initiative follows a trend among celebrity parents to control the media exposure of their newborns.</li><li>Dua was born on September 8, 2024, after the couple announced their pregnancy earlier that year.</li></ul><blockquote>“We kindly request the paps to avoid clicking our baby’s photo.” - Deepika Padukone</blockquote><p>This event highlights the ongoing conversation about privacy and media scrutiny faced by celebrity families in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/deepika-padukone-ranveer-singh-introduce-daughter-dua-to-paps-at-private-event-see-photos-9740781/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/deepika-padukone-ranveer-singh-introduce-daughter-dua-to-paps-at-private-event-see-photos-9740781/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione Due in NY Court Over State Murder Charges | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Luigi Mangione Due in NY Court Over State Murder Charges</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p><p>Luigi Mangione is scheduled to appear in New York state court for his arraignment on murder and weapon charges related to the shooting of a UnitedHealth Group executive.</p><ul><li>Mangione, 26, will respond to charges from Manhattan DA Alvin Bragg.</li><li>The arraignment was delayed due to simultaneous federal charges.</li><li>He is accused of using a 3D-printed gun to shoot UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson on December 4.</li><li>Mangione's federal case is described as “death eligible” by his lawyer.</li></ul><blockquote>“The state case is expected to go to trial first,” said the Justice Department.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Mangione faces serious charges that could result in severe penalties as both state and federal cases develop.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/luigi-mangione-due-in-ny-court-over-state-murder-charges-11734960671227.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/luigi-mangione-due-in-ny-court-over-state-murder-charges-11734960671227.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:31:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Parker Solar Probe aims to fly closer to the sun like never before - CGTN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQSFprR1ZuXzN1ZWlRWEZfV2Y5ejZ5bG9PN1phYmRvMll5a2gyeHRsellsREpRYm9tOGh1X2pFV0JBQk9Kc3RBNmdQZ1NiLTFadGlsT0p6U0VUd05KcGJpZ3BfSTlEOF9oekMwZUhtTGRjd2hpNzJmaDRUSlRXcG5QX3JLSk9Ea0JaTGVBWGstZV9RTGV1VlBDMFF2bHljWGFOOE1yeXRSQUNTZldZU3ZiZWhVYVdhRFlrdjRhcndhX3jSAcsBQVVfeXFMTjJidGlIVmVzZWJNV1FfbF9YQ0U3U1g3VEZaSkZlWEdWTEdlQk1jcWQzaXpGUzI5S2RYcGt2V0Zhd01Ia1ZSZmdrSmpvcVVSVUgwOHZGMzV4clllX1RTTERBemdudjhUaUVaejgwZFNRckVRZlN2Q3Y2UWlWanB4Mm5wSnhQWE00empRMzRmOGtiYWl2a2NmRGR1MFhDaWpDelYyS1VhV0drMEtnOXFkdGZkUjdJLWF4YnFJVUVleTZUM0pQMlNaUVZFSms?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQSFprR1ZuXzN1ZWlRWEZfV2Y5ejZ5bG9PN1phYmRvMll5a2gyeHRsellsREpRYm9tOGh1X2pFV0JBQk9Kc3RBNmdQZ1NiLTFadGlsT0p6U0VUd05KcGJpZ3BfSTlEOF9oekMwZUhtTGRjd2hpNzJmaDRUSlRXcG5QX3JLSk9Ea0JaTGVBWGstZV9RTGV1VlBDMFF2bHljWGFOOE1yeXRSQUNTZldZU3ZiZWhVYVdhRFlrdjRhcndhX3jSAcsBQVVfeXFMTjJidGlIVmVzZWJNV1FfbF9YQ0U3U1g3VEZaSkZlWEdWTEdlQk1jcWQzaXpGUzI5S2RYcGt2V0Zhd01Ia1ZSZmdrSmpvcVVSVUgwOHZGMzV4clllX1RTTERBemdudjhUaUVaejgwZFNRckVRZlN2Q3Y2UWlWanB4Mm5wSnhQWE00empRMzRmOGtiYWl2a2NmRGR1MFhDaWpDelYyS1VhV0drMEtnOXFkdGZkUjdJLWF4YnFJVUVleTZUM0pQMlNaUVZFSms?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:28:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>