<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:23:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:23:41 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Thyrocare labs are now NABL accredited - Medical Buyer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTFBHc3B4LVE3VHk2ZnBSdVN3bE5YSExORC1pTzRyQ19sOWlXeUhyeC04OFBMd1MyN3R4TmNYZERlci1hMlRCWU5RaFlQTEUxa0NQczJfVElHNVdJUUJxc2IxTF9MUU1iYWNLeDdwbHdjbmZXNlJuYm05MFF3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTFBHc3B4LVE3VHk2ZnBSdVN3bE5YSExORC1pTzRyQ19sOWlXeUhyeC04OFBMd1MyN3R4TmNYZERlci1hMlRCWU5RaFlQTEUxa0NQczJfVElHNVdJUUJxc2IxTF9MUU1iYWNLeDdwbHdjbmZXNlJuYm05MFF3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:24:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-Supreme Court judge V Ramasubramanian appointed NHRC chief - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>V Ramasubramanian appointed as new NHRC chief</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 18, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116601815,imgsize-932393,width-400,resizemode-4/116601815.jpg" alt="V Ramasubramanian" title="V Ramasubramanian" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Ex-Supreme Court judge V Ramasubramanian has been appointed as the chairperson of the NHRC.</figcaption><p>The former Supreme Court judge, V Ramasubramanian, has been appointed as the ninth chairperson of the National Human Rights Commission (NHRC) of India. This position had been vacant since June 2023.</p><ul><li>V Ramasubramanian served as a Supreme Court judge from 2019 to 2023.</li><li>He was previously the Chief Justice of Himachal Pradesh high court.</li><li>He became the first judge to hold a hearing over Skype.</li><li>He advocated for the decriminalization of defamation and supported freedom of expression.</li><li>His appointment follows a high-powered committee meeting led by Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is untrue. Presently, I am enjoying my retired life." - DY Chandrachud, former Chief Justice of India.</blockquote><p>The appointment of V Ramasubramanian as NHRC chief highlights a significant transition in India's human rights protection landscape following a vacancy of several months.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ex-supreme-court-judge-v-ramasubramanian-appointed-nhrc-chief/articleshow/116601429.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ex-supreme-court-judge-v-ramasubramanian-appointed-nhrc-chief/articleshow/116601429.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp may stop working on these Android smartphones starting next week - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp may stop working on these Android smartphones starting next week</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116601800,imgsize-11968,width-400,resizemode-4/116601800.jpg" alt="WhatsApp may stop working on these Android smartphones starting next week" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>WhatsApp will no longer support older Android devices</figcaption><p>WhatsApp is set to discontinue support for Android devices running on KitKat or older versions starting January 1, 2025, as part of a move by Meta to ensure app security and functionality.</p><ul><li>The change affects several older smartphones from brands like Samsung, Motorola, HTC, LG, and Sony.</li><li>Key outdated models include Galaxy S3, Galaxy Note 2, Moto G (1st Gen), and iPhone models such as iPhone 5s.</li><li>Meta has a history of discontinuing support for older operating systems to maintain compatibility and security standards.</li><li>Users are advised to upgrade to newer Android versions to continue accessing WhatsApp.</li></ul><blockquote>“This update will mainly affect users of older iPhones, specifically the iPhone 5s, iPhone 6, and iPhone 6 Plus, which are limited to iOS 12.5.7.”</blockquote><p>In summary, this move emphasizes the necessity for users to stay updated with their devices to ensure continuous access to WhatsApp services.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/whatsapp-may-stop-working-on-these-android-smartphones-starting-next-week/articleshow/116601770.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/whatsapp-may-stop-working-on-these-android-smartphones-starting-next-week/articleshow/116601770.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shami ruled out of remaining two Border-Gavaskar Trophy Tests - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammed Shami Ruled Out of Remaining Two Tests in Border-Gavaskar Trophy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p>Indian cricketer <a href="https://www.espncricinfo.com/cricketers/mohammed-shami-481896">Mohammed Shami</a> has been ruled out of the fourth and fifth Tests in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy due to swelling in his left knee, as per a BCCI press release.</p><ul><li>Shami recently played for Bengal and had a busy schedule leading up to the Tests.</li><li>His knee swelling is attributed to increased workload from recent bowling activities.</li><li>The BCCI medical team recommends more time for recovery before he can return to play.</li></ul><blockquote>“The swelling is on the expected lines, owing to the increased bowling after a prolonged period.”</blockquote><p>Shami has been recovering from a heel injury and will continue strength and conditioning work. His participation in the ongoing Vijay Hazare Trophy will depend on his knee condition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/mohammed-shami-ruled-out-of-last-two-border-gavaskar-trophy-tests-1466329</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/mohammed-shami-ruled-out-of-last-two-border-gavaskar-trophy-tests-1466329</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:21:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jaishankar to begin 6-day visit to US from December 24 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jaishankar to Begin 6-Day Visit to US from December 24</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24-29, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116601601,imgsize-43498,width-400,resizemode-4/116601601.jpg" alt="Jaishankar to begin 6-day visit to US from December 24"><figcaption>Jaishankar to begin 6-day visit to US from December 24</figcaption><p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar is set to embark on a significant six-day official visit to the United States starting from December 24, marking a key diplomatic engagement post the US presidential elections.</p><ul><li>Jaishankar will focus on discussing crucial bilateral, regional, and global issues.</li><li>He will preside over a conference with India's Consul Generals in the US.</li><li>This visit follows Jaishankar's earlier trip to the US in September.</li></ul><blockquote>S Jaishankar is the first high-ranking Indian official to visit the US after Donald Trump's election victory.</blockquote><p>This upcoming visit is pivotal in strengthening Indo-US relations amid the ongoing political transitions in the United States.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/jaishankar-to-begin-6-day-visit-to-us-from-december-24/articleshow/116601322.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/jaishankar-to-begin-6-day-visit-to-us-from-december-24/articleshow/116601322.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden commutes death sentences of 37 including child killers, mass murderers: Full list - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Commutes Death Sentences for 37 Individuals, Including Murderers</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116601392,imgsize-831916,width-400,resizemode-4/116601392.jpg" alt="Joe Biden commutes death sentences of 37 people two days before Christmas." decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Joe Biden commutes death sentences of 37 people two days before Christmas.</figcaption>
<p>President Joe Biden has commuted the death sentences of 37 individuals, including five child killers and several mass murderers. Biden emphasized that his decision is based on a belief that the death penalty should be abolished at a federal level.</p>
<ul>
  <li>37 out of 40 men had their sentences commuted.</li>
  <li>Among those pardoned are numerous convicted for serious crimes, including child murder.</li>
  <li>Biden still condemns the crimes committed by the individuals but believes halting the death penalty is necessary.</li>
  <li>Three notable individuals—Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, Robert Bowers, and Dylann Roof—did not receive commutations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Make no mistake: I condemn these murderers, grieve for the victims of their despicable acts, and ache for all the families who have suffered unimaginable and irreparable loss,” Biden stated.</blockquote>
<p>The commutations come as part of a broader trend in Biden's administration towards criminal justice reform and are significant in the dialogue surrounding the death penalty in the United States.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/joe-biden-commutes-death-sentences-of-37-including-child-killers-mass-murderers-full-list/articleshow/116601396.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/joe-biden-commutes-death-sentences-of-37-including-child-killers-mass-murderers-full-list/articleshow/116601396.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement In India's Border Gavaskar Trophy Squad Named. Not Axar Patel Or Y.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement In India's Border Gavaskar Trophy Squad Named</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2d0t7bp_ashwin-afp_625x300_20_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin" width="639" height="479"><figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement in Squad</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team has selected young Mumbai off-spinner Tanush Kotian to replace Ravichandran Ashwin, who announced his retirement following the third Test in Brisbane.</p><ul><li>Tanush Kotian has played 33 First Class matches, taking 101 wickets.</li><li>Kotian has been included as a precautionary measure and will travel to Australia.</li><li>Originally, Axar Patel was considered for the replacement but opted out due to personal reasons.</li><li>Ashwin retired as India's second-highest wicket-taker in Test cricket.</li></ul><blockquote>"I made myself a promise in 2012, we lost a tricky series against England. I was very early in my career and I was just telling myself we are not gonna lose another one. Ever. And that is what I promised myself," said Ashwin.</blockquote><p>The addition of Kotian underscores the Indian team's strategy to maintain squad strength following Ashwin's retirement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ravichandran-ashwins-replacement-in-indias-border-gavaskar-trophy-squad-named-not-kuldeep-yadav-or-yuzvendra-chahal-7314817</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ravichandran-ashwins-replacement-in-indias-border-gavaskar-trophy-squad-named-not-kuldeep-yadav-or-yuzvendra-chahal-7314817</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:52:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Hindi Worldwide Box Office (18 Days): Beats Salman Khan’s No.1 Grosser & Ranbir Kapoor’s Animal, Needs 67.85 Crores To Create History! - Koimoi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Hindi Worldwide Box Office (18 Days): Beats Salman Khan’s No.1 Grosser & Ranbir Kapoor’s</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recently</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Koimoi</p><img src="https://www.koimoi.com/wp-content/new-galleries/2024/12/pushpa-2-hindi-worldwide-box-office-18-days-crosses-salman-khans-bajrangi-bhaijaan-ranbir-kapoors-animal-001.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Hindi Worldwide Box Office (18 Days): Crosses Salman Khan's Bajrangi Bhaijaan & Ranbir Kapoor's Animal"><figcaption>Pushpa 2 Hindi Worldwide Box Office (18 Days): Crosses Salman Khan’s Bajrangi Bhaijaan & Ranbir Kapoor’s Animal (Photo Credit – Facebook/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Pushpa 2 has taken the box office by storm, emerging as the fourth highest-grossing Hindi film ever, surpassing major hits like Bajrangi Bhaijaan and Animal in just 18 days.</p><ul><li>The film has grossed <strong>932.15 crore</strong> worldwide.</li><li>It earned <strong>692.50 crore</strong> net in India.</li><li>It is expected to join the 1000 crore club soon.</li></ul><blockquote>“Whenever it happens, the Allu Arjun starrer will become the first Hindi-dubbed film from the South to score 1000 crores globally.”</blockquote><p>This monumental success highlights the film's widespread appeal and strong performance in the Hindi market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-worldwide-box-office-18-days-beats-salman-khans-no-1-grosser-ranbir-kapoors-animal-needs-67-85-crores-to-create-history/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koimoi.com/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-worldwide-box-office-18-days-beats-salman-khans-no-1-grosser-ranbir-kapoors-animal-needs-67-85-crores-to-create-history/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:51:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BRS vs Congress intensifies after vandalisation at Allu Arjun's house; all 6 accused get bail - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BRS vs Congress intensifies after vandalisation at Allu Arjun's house; all 6 accused get bail</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Publication date not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116600716,imgsize-1267129,width-400,resizemode-4/116600716.jpg" alt="BRS vs Congress intensifies after vandalisation at Allu Arjun's house; all 6 accused get bail" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Violence erupts outside Allu Arjun's residence</figcaption><p>The article covers the intensifying political conflict between BRS and Congress following vandalism at Telugu actor Allu Arjun's house, where protesters demanded compensation after a stampede linked to the actor's film.</p><ul><li>Vandalism occurred at Allu Arjun’s residence by a group claiming ties to Osmania University Joint Action Committee.</li><li>Protesters seek Rs 1 crore for the family of a woman who died during a stampede at a film screening.</li><li>Six individuals were arrested for the vandalism and granted bail.</li><li>BJP and BRS criticize Congress over governance and law and order issues.</li><li>Chief minister condemns the incident and calls for strict law enforcement.</li></ul><blockquote>“Attacks on film personalities or anyone are unacceptable.” - Chief Minister Revanth Reddy</blockquote><p>This incident reflects growing tensions in the political landscape and the film industry in Telangana, with significant public and political discourse likely to follow.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/brs-vs-congress-intensifies-after-vandalisation-at-allu-arjuns-house-all-6-accused-get-bail/articleshow/116600115.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/brs-vs-congress-intensifies-after-vandalisation-at-allu-arjuns-house-all-6-accused-get-bail/articleshow/116600115.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Massive ocean found in deep space - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibEFVX3lxTE8zbkxSWEliamVHclp4NVpxTDdWcGdVaEdiX3JXeEk2Q3JWc19TYmdDQ2djWDNyVDBnTGo3bjlrWTlqQXFreWg3MldqWjJsbVBncHpEdjQ1TU5xTmdXTVZuUVBpcW03ZmlxZVVIYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibEFVX3lxTE8zbkxSWEliamVHclp4NVpxTDdWcGdVaEdiX3JXeEk2Q3JWc19TYmdDQ2djWDNyVDBnTGo3bjlrWTlqQXFreWg3MldqWjJsbVBncHpEdjQ1TU5xTmdXTVZuUVBpcW03ZmlxZVVIYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:31:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea says it detects signs of North Korea preparing more troops, drones for Russia - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Detects North Korea Preparing Troops and Drones for Russia</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p>
<img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/V2EWKAM4UBODFMDL65X7GPPPJI.jpg?auth=4d0ea33d91583cf466ce4a4f31ade6b8d9be3863ba898994c05f96e289e64c2e&amp;width=4252&amp;quality=80" alt="Military parade commemorating 70th anniversary of the Korean War armistice in Pyongyang" />
<figcaption>Soldiers participate in a military parade to commemorate the 70th anniversary of the Korean War armistice in Pyongyang, North Korea, July 27, 2023.</figcaption>
<p>South Korea's military reports detecting signs of North Korea sending more troops and weaponry to Russia to bolster its efforts in the Ukraine conflict.</p>
<ul>
    <li>North Korea has already delivered military equipment including multiple rocket launchers and self-propelled howitzers to Russia.</li>
    <li>Preparation for suicide drone production has been noted following a recent test ordered by Kim Jong Un.</li>
    <li>Estimates suggest around 12,000 North Korean troops are currently in Russia, with significant casualties reported.</li>
    <li>Increased military collaboration between North Korea and Russia poses a threat to South Korea, possibly enhancing North Korea's military capabilities.</li>
    <li>South Korea's leadership emphasizes the need for a strong joint security posture with the U.S. amid escalating tensions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"With the backing of Russia, they'll likely try to stage various strategic provocations next year, such as launching intercontinental ballistic missiles and conducting a nuclear test..." - JCS Official</blockquote>
<p>This development highlights the deteriorating security situation and the potential for further escalations in the region, prompting vigilance from South Korea and its allies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/south-korea-detects-signs-north-korea-preparing-more-troops-drones-russia-2024-12-23/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/south-korea-detects-signs-north-korea-preparing-more-troops-drones-russia-2024-12-23/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:09:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Centre scraps no-detention policy for classes 5 and 8 students who fail to clear year-end exams - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxQS29VT0ZHd21kRmZielFzQ3F0Vml4QlNMNVRnOGFfbUxwcFJwY0RXRWpfVmxFTVBWLU5rNTRQdUZEZEl6TmtYWGcyeTRjY3BsRTJDOGpjMkFCUHUwbDlsQThnbGdzTlNFYXotYldjVjd4OE1sdnkxZHFaTXlqVGs5cnB2WTJ3dzdobGdaR2QzZ2ZHckc2T3o0NlQzZHZLYm13aldfSUdaZEZBcGhSRUJaQ1AtYXlsdWhhUV9ZSjBxRV9OOE5tNFBmUjhGbE40WFB5U1A00gHbAUFVX3lxTFBXMlFiaHZZTEg1X2FMbHJDd3ZKMjFFWnFVX0EyanZwTkJTaERqbXRCRGp6SGVneThZV0lBNVJ0UlBIZWdYVVJjZXhuajJJLS1JTXJpdWNNSEJqQTlER09tenBOdlZrNGVlajBYR19tcnU0U19GT2FGc2t3VXhLQVV1Vmdka20ydWtuMzY2Y3pwck9xNzVaZHI0T1ZDbHp3LURVcGprQjV4YVRCRnJYbFg5NkRsc2ZnUWNLZUQwdlMtVHVqT29DblY2SzNoRjZFaTBsYjQ1U2tnVzU3RQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxQS29VT0ZHd21kRmZielFzQ3F0Vml4QlNMNVRnOGFfbUxwcFJwY0RXRWpfVmxFTVBWLU5rNTRQdUZEZEl6TmtYWGcyeTRjY3BsRTJDOGpjMkFCUHUwbDlsQThnbGdzTlNFYXotYldjVjd4OE1sdnkxZHFaTXlqVGs5cnB2WTJ3dzdobGdaR2QzZ2ZHckc2T3o0NlQzZHZLYm13aldfSUdaZEZBcGhSRUJaQ1AtYXlsdWhhUV9ZSjBxRV9OOE5tNFBmUjhGbE40WFB5U1A00gHbAUFVX3lxTFBXMlFiaHZZTEg1X2FMbHJDd3ZKMjFFWnFVX0EyanZwTkJTaERqbXRCRGp6SGVneThZV0lBNVJ0UlBIZWdYVVJjZXhuajJJLS1JTXJpdWNNSEJqQTlER09tenBOdlZrNGVlajBYR19tcnU0U19GT2FGc2t3VXhLQVV1Vmdka20ydWtuMzY2Y3pwck9xNzVaZHI0T1ZDbHp3LURVcGprQjV4YVRCRnJYbFg5NkRsc2ZnUWNLZUQwdlMtVHVqT29DblY2SzNoRjZFaTBsYjQ1U2tnVzU3RQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AIIMS, Delhi developing low cost adaptive cellular therapy for treatment of multiple myeloma - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AIIMS, Delhi developing low cost adaptive cellular therapy for treatment of multiple myeloma</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/vprin4/article69018678.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_3d_medical_backgroun_2_1_19CPL41E.jpg" alt="(CAR) T-cell therapy is a form of adaptive cellular therapy in which a patient’s T cells are isolated, genetically modified and infused back in the patients body to recognise and kill cancer cells." /><figcaption>(CAR) T-cell therapy is a form of adaptive cellular therapy in which a patient’s T cells are isolated, genetically modified and infused back in the patients body to recognise and kill cancer cells. Photo Credit: Freepik</figcaption><p>Doctors at AIIMS, Delhi are developing a low-cost antibody-based therapy for multiple myeloma, a type of blood cancer. This innovative approach aims to make advanced CAR-T cell therapies more accessible and affordable in India.</p><ul><li>The therapy targets B-cell maturation antigen (BCMA) to specifically eliminate multiple myeloma cells.</li><li>Animal trials have shown promising results, with plans for phase-1 human clinical trials on the horizon.</li><li>The goal is to significantly reduce the costs associated with existing CAR-T cell therapies.</li></ul><blockquote>“CAR-T cell therapies have changed the way we approach and treat cancer. Development of CAR-T cell therapy has been in a nascent state in India despite the rapid pace at which it is moving around the world.” - Dr. Mayank Singh</blockquote><p>This development is significant as it seeks to provide a more viable treatment option for many patients in India, addressing both cost and accessibility challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/aiims-delhi-developing-low-cost-adaptive-cellular-therapy-for-treatment-of-multiple-myeloma/article69018622.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/aiims-delhi-developing-low-cost-adaptive-cellular-therapy-for-treatment-of-multiple-myeloma/article69018622.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Parker Solar Probe to make history with unprecedented flyby of the Sun’s corona on Christmas eve D - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe to Make Historic Flyby of the Sun’s Corona on Christmas Eve</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116598972,imgsize-52538,width-400,resizemode-4/116598972.jpg" alt="NASA’s Parker Solar Probe to make history" title="Image source: Space.com" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Nasa's Parker Solar Probe during its mission.</figcaption><p>The Parker Solar Probe is set to achieve a historic milestone by flying through the Sun's corona on December 24, 2024, at a record distance of 3.8 million miles from the Sun’s surface. This flyby marks the 22nd close approach of the spacecraft, launched in 2018, aimed at studying the Sun's inner workings and the mysterious discrepancy in temperatures between its surface and corona.</p><ul><li>The Parker Solar Probe will measure magnetic fields and charged particles in the Sun's outer atmosphere.</li><li>It travels at speeds of 430,000 miles per hour, making it the fastest man-made object.</li><li>The probe is equipped with a specialized heat shield capable of withstanding temperatures as high as 2,500 degrees Fahrenheit.</li><li>The closest approach will occur at 6:53 a.m. EST on December 24.</li><li>Data collected will provide insights into solar flares, coronal mass ejections, and their impact on space weather.</li></ul><blockquote>“This historic flyby will help reveal the secrets of the Sun, allowing us to protect our technology from solar disruptions.”</blockquote><p>The Parker Solar Probe's upcoming flyby on December 24 is expected to yield groundbreaking data about solar phenomena that could protect Earth’s technologies from solar-induced disruptions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasas-parker-solar-probe-to-make-history-with-unprecedented-flyby-of-the-suns-corona-on-christmas-eve-december-24/articleshow/116598335.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasas-parker-solar-probe-to-make-history-with-unprecedented-flyby-of-the-suns-corona-on-christmas-eve-december-24/articleshow/116598335.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli's Health Deteriorates, Admitted To Hospital. Report Says Condition Stable But... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli's Health Deteriorates, Admitted To Hospital</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> IANS</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8620asm_vinod-kambli-hospital_625x300_23_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Vinod Kambli's Health Deteriorates"><figcaption>Vinod Kambli is being attended at a hospital in Thane. © IANS/Twitter</figcaption><p>Former Indian cricket star Vinod Kambli has been hospitalized due to a serious health issue. Though his condition is reported to be stable, it remains critical. Kambli's recent public appearances have sparked concerns over his health.</p><ul><li>Kambli was admitted to Akriti Hospital in Thane after his health deteriorated.</li><li>His condition is stable but remains critical according to reports.</li><li>He communicated with fans via social media, giving a thumbs-up to show he is improving.</li><li>Kambli revealed he has been battling a urine infection and has received support from his family and friends.</li><li>He expressed gratitude towards his wife and children for their support during his recovery.</li></ul><blockquote>"I am better now. My wife takes care of me a lot. She took me to 3 different hospitals and told me 'You have to get fit'." - Vinod Kambli</blockquote><p>Kambli's struggles highlight the importance of health and family support in recovery. Fans and former teammates are rallying behind him during this challenging time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/vinod-kamblis-health-deteriorates-admitted-to-hospital-report-says-condition-stable-but-7314280</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/vinod-kamblis-health-deteriorates-admitted-to-hospital-report-says-condition-stable-but-7314280</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:48:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina extradition: Bangladesh sends note verbale asking India to send back deposed PM - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh Requests Extradition of Deposed PM Sheikh Hasina from India</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/gs7h40/article69018653.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_Bangladesh_Timeline__2_1_SUDOJ97T.jpg" alt="Former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina." title="Former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina." />
<figcaption>Former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina. | Photo Credit: AP</figcaption>
<p>Bangladesh's interim government has requested the extradition of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina from India, where she has been living in exile since fleeing the country amid protests.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sheikh Hasina fled to India on August 5, 2024, amid student-led protests that deposed her.</li>
  <li>Bangladesh's International Crimes Tribunal has issued arrest warrants against Hasina for crimes against humanity.</li>
  <li>The interim government has sent a diplomatic note to India requesting her return for judicial proceedings.</li>
  <li>An existing extradition treaty between Bangladesh and India could facilitate the process.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Bangladesh wants her back here for the judicial process,” Foreign Affairs Adviser Touhid Hossain said.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Bangladesh is actively pursuing the legal return of Sheikh Hasina to face serious charges stemming from her time in office.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/bangladesh-sends-note-verbale-asking-india-to-send-back-deposed-pm-sheikh-hasina/article69018619.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/bangladesh-sends-note-verbale-asking-india-to-send-back-deposed-pm-sheikh-hasina/article69018619.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oppo Reno 13 And Reno 13 Pro India Launch In January 2025: All You Need To Know - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Oppo Reno 13 and Reno 13 Pro Set to Launch in India in January 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116599049,thumbsize-721157,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116599049.jpg" alt="Oppo Reno 13 Series" title="Oppo Reno 13 Series"><figcaption>Oppo Reno 13 Series</figcaption><p>The Oppo Reno 13 series is confirmed to launch in India by the end of January 2025, featuring significant upgrades in design and camera setup.</p><ul><li>The Reno 13 Pro will be available in Graphite Grey and Mist Lavender.</li><li>The Reno 13 will come in Ivory White and Luminous Blue.</li><li>Both models will feature a triple camera setup and an OLED display.</li><li>The Reno 13 Pro has a thickness of 7.55mm and weighs 195g, while the Reno 13 ranges between 7.24 to 7.29mm and weighs 181g.</li><li>Both phones are expected to be 5G capable and include premium features like IP66, IP68, and IP69 ratings.</li><li>The Reno 13 Pro will likely come with a MediaTek Dimensity 8350 chipset, according to leaks.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Reno 13 series will sport a triple camera setup and a flat display.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Oppo Reno 13 series promises to bring advanced features and elegant designs to the smartphone market in early 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/oppo-reno-13-and-reno-13-pro-india-launch-in-january-2025-all-you-need-to-know-article-116598976</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/oppo-reno-13-and-reno-13-pro-india-launch-in-january-2025-all-you-need-to-know-article-116598976</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:43:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh sends India formal note seeking extradition of Sheikh Hasina - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh Requests Extradition of Sheikh Hasina from India</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Bangladesh has formally approached India seeking the extradition of Sheikh Hasina, the current Prime Minister of Bangladesh, amidst ongoing political tensions.</p><ul><li>The extradition request is based on numerous allegations against Sheikh Hasina.</li><li>This move is expected to raise diplomatic tensions between the two countries.</li><li>Officials from both nations are likely to engage in discussions regarding the legitimacy of the request.</li></ul><blockquote>“This could have significant implications for regional security and diplomacy.”</blockquote><p>This development highlights the complex political relationship between Bangladesh and India and will require careful diplomatic handling.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/bangladesh-sends-india-formal-note-seeking-extradition-of-sheikh-hasina/articleshow/116598267.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/bangladesh-sends-india-formal-note-seeking-extradition-of-sheikh-hasina/articleshow/116598267.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Constipation Awareness Month 2024: 10 Dietary Changes You Can Make For Better Digestion - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Constipation Awareness Month 2024: 10 Dietary Changes You Can Make For Better Digestion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Zee News</p><img src="https://english.cdn.zeenews.com/sites/default/files/2024/12/23/1615190-hme.png?im=Resize=(400)" alt="Constipation Awareness Month"/><figcaption>Constipation Awareness Month encourages awareness about digestive health.</figcaption><p>December is Constipation Awareness Month, focusing on improving digestion and combatting constipation through dietary changes. Here are 10 recommendations for better digestive health:</p><ul><li>Increase fibre intake by consuming whole grains, fruits, and vegetables.</li><li>Stay hydrated with water and herbal teas.</li><li>Incorporate probiotics found in yogurt and kefir.</li><li>Avoid processed foods high in unhealthy fats and sugars.</li><li>Include healthy fats such as olive oil and avocados.</li><li>Add magnesium-rich foods like spinach and nuts.</li><li>Eat smaller, more frequent meals instead of large portions.</li><li>Avoid caffeine and alcohol to prevent dehydration.</li><li>Don’t skip meals to maintain regular eating patterns.</li><li>Experiment with natural laxatives like prunes and papaya.</li></ul><blockquote>“By making these simple dietary changes, you can improve your digestion, reduce constipation, and enhance your overall health.”</blockquote><p>Awareness campaigns during Constipation Awareness Month encourage healthier habits and prompt individuals to seek medical help when necessary.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/photos/lifestyle/constipation-awareness-month-2024-10-dietary-changes-you-can-make-for-better-digestion-2834970</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/photos/lifestyle/constipation-awareness-month-2024-10-dietary-changes-you-can-make-for-better-digestion-2834970</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli admitted to Thane hospital in critical condition - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli in Critical Condition, Hospitalized in Thane</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Saturday Night<br><strong>Source:</strong> IANS</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116598630,imgsize-51044,width-400,resizemode-4/116598630.jpg" alt="Vinod Kambli admitted to Thane hospital in critical condition" title="Former India cricketer Vinod Kambli has been hospitalised in Thane, Maharashtra. (IANS)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Former India cricketer Vinod Kambli has been hospitalised in Thane, Maharashtra. (IANS)</figcaption><p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli has been hospitalized in Thane, Maharashtra, due to health issues. His recent public appearances, including an event at Shivaji Park, contrasted with his current critical health condition.</p><ul><li>Kambli's condition is described as stable but critical.</li><li>He has faced health challenges recently, including a serious urine problem.</li><li>Support has poured in from his teammates, including Kapil Dev and Sunil Gavaskar.</li><li>Kambli had undergone two heart surgeries previously in 2013.</li><li>His international cricket career included noteworthy achievements, including being the first Indian with consecutive double centuries in Tests.</li></ul><blockquote>“I was suffering from a urine problem. It was just flowing. My son, Jesus Cristiano, picked me up and brought me back to my feet.”</blockquote><p>The cricket community is rallying around Kambli as he seeks recovery from his recent health setbacks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-admitted-to-thane-hospital-in-critical-condition/articleshow/116598447.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-admitted-to-thane-hospital-in-critical-condition/articleshow/116598447.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Galaxy Unpacked 2025: Samsung may introduce 'Slim' model in S25 series - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Galaxy Unpacked 2025: Samsung may introduce 'Slim' model in S25 series</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> 91mobiles</p><p>Samsung is set to unveil the Galaxy S25 series in January 2025, with potential plans for a new 'Slim' model coming later in the second quarter.</p><ul><li>The Galaxy S25 Slim is expected to be only 6mm thick, compared to 7.6mm for the Galaxy S24.</li><li>The smartphone may offer a 6.66-inch display and a 4,700mAh battery.</li><li>It is likely to include a triple-camera system: a 200MP main sensor, a 50MP telephoto lens, and a 50MP ultra-wide lens.</li><li>The device may feature a Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Elite processor.</li><li>It aims to compete directly with Apple's iPhone 17 Air.</li></ul><blockquote>“Samsung’s Galaxy S25 Slim could be a direct competitor to Apple’s thin-profile iPhone 17 Air.”</blockquote><p>In summary, the Galaxy S25 Slim emphasizes a sleek design and competitive specifications, setting the stage for an interesting market battle with Apple's upcoming offerings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/galaxy-unpacked-2025-samsung-may-introduce-slim-model-in-s25-series-124122300594_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/galaxy-unpacked-2025-samsung-may-introduce-slim-model-in-s25-series-124122300594_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:22:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp to stop working on older phones, including some samsung Galaxy models, after December 31 - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp to Stop Working on Older Phones After December 31</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/whatsapp-new-video-calling-features-1734948756.webp" alt="WhatsApp support for Android" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>WhatsApp support for Android</figcaption>
<p>WhatsApp, with over two billion users, will discontinue support for several older smartphone models from January 1, 2025, impacting users primarily on older versions of Android.</p>
<ul>
<li>More than 20 smartphones will lose access, primarily those running Android KitKat and earlier.</li>
<li>Brands affected include Samsung, LG, Motorola, HTC, and Sony.</li>
<li>Users will not receive updates, bug fixes, or security patches on these devices.</li>
<li>The change also affects other Meta platforms such as Facebook and Instagram.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Older operating systems lack the necessary capabilities for advanced features and can present security vulnerabilities.”</blockquote>
<p>Though WhatsApp will continue to function on these phones, the lack of support for updates raises security concerns for users with outdated devices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/apps/whatsapp-to-stop-working-on-older-phones-including-some-samsung-galaxy-models-after-december-31-2024-12-23-967577</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/apps/whatsapp-to-stop-working-on-older-phones-including-some-samsung-galaxy-models-after-december-31-2024-12-23-967577</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:17:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani Group expands aviation reach with ₹400 crore acquisition of Air Works group - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigJBVV95cUxOYWNobTZjcEJSOHdCbGFqNk9rMjZVRWtyOFZIaWRVUWl4a3BzR2tXUi1rNlRZbDN6bTA3eUs5MmtqN1pGSTd3RFdGbDhfVDdOajQ0cnpZU3huN2R6WmFsU1VFaGtCZEphOGlYSFRpb3BfN0M2Sll1cVJBSC1RSk1JclRrS0c3eVZlV2RvYzZPTXA0amZLcXNOcTlyTWloZEdNYlR1TGtVd1dLaE5NelQybGIxS051ci0yS291WnUxTGtZeXBsbmlST0VXWHp6SmJJemNLVTVGeEFwUTdrMnlsUnN0M0c2U25wNFdUcDBieTU2Wmxmdm90VjM5MlgxRGV1Ump3RjZCM0dxd9IBjwJBVV95cUxQOEpzd0tFLWI4ZzBobmlIRFJNWUtsT2hfRzlhM3RHSGhHN3IxQVduMHpEZmdfUlMzTWRKWENxam8zYVJqbjNyQjA4LUZseDhSeTdBZ0FvcUtkbFZaejc5Z3JkeVNaWVFybmpSVGQ1VC1QZWdnZHdYOVcwRTVmYWNXcnBMeW54Si16Q2c4TVRJdUV3NEJsRk9lNWJnRHVLOWZXVExYUGtNajQzTmpadms1RmEyc3pzQ2c3QTRldHRxWW1UeV9ORHRHOWhtNksybVVOSkZybWZQbXRTNzZRSHM0TF9IeXMwZTFScVdDdEd1ZU90TTdycFl4cGRSSnBaSzRqYldFN2pJMnNVX1h4d2Rr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigJBVV95cUxOYWNobTZjcEJSOHdCbGFqNk9rMjZVRWtyOFZIaWRVUWl4a3BzR2tXUi1rNlRZbDN6bTA3eUs5MmtqN1pGSTd3RFdGbDhfVDdOajQ0cnpZU3huN2R6WmFsU1VFaGtCZEphOGlYSFRpb3BfN0M2Sll1cVJBSC1RSk1JclRrS0c3eVZlV2RvYzZPTXA0amZLcXNOcTlyTWloZEdNYlR1TGtVd1dLaE5NelQybGIxS051ci0yS291WnUxTGtZeXBsbmlST0VXWHp6SmJJemNLVTVGeEFwUTdrMnlsUnN0M0c2U25wNFdUcDBieTU2Wmxmdm90VjM5MlgxRGV1Ump3RjZCM0dxd9IBjwJBVV95cUxQOEpzd0tFLWI4ZzBobmlIRFJNWUtsT2hfRzlhM3RHSGhHN3IxQVduMHpEZmdfUlMzTWRKWENxam8zYVJqbjNyQjA4LUZseDhSeTdBZ0FvcUtkbFZaejc5Z3JkeVNaWVFybmpSVGQ1VC1QZWdnZHdYOVcwRTVmYWNXcnBMeW54Si16Q2c4TVRJdUV3NEJsRk9lNWJnRHVLOWZXVExYUGtNajQzTmpadms1RmEyc3pzQ2c3QTRldHRxWW1UeV9ORHRHOWhtNksybVVOSkZybWZQbXRTNzZRSHM0TF9IeXMwZTFScVdDdEd1ZU90TTdycFl4cGRSSnBaSzRqYldFN2pJMnNVX1h4d2Rr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:17:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ousted Syrian President Assad’s Wife Unhappy With Life In Russia? What Led Her To File For Divorce - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Asma al-Assad Files for Divorce Amid Dissatisfaction in Moscow</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Bashar al-Assad with his wife Asma al-Assad | File Image"><figcaption>Bashar al-Assad with his wife Asma al-Assad | File Image</figcaption><p>The British wife of ousted Syrian president Bashar al-Assad, Asma, has filed for divorce, expressing her unhappiness with life in Moscow where her family has sought asylum.</p><ul><li>Asma al-Assad filed for divorce in a Russian court after dissatisfaction with her life in Moscow.</li><li>She reportedly wishes to return to her hometown in London.</li><li>Asma moved to Syria in 2000 after marrying Bashar al-Assad.</li><li>Reports indicate that her divorce application is currently being evaluated by Russian authorities.</li><li>Bashar al-Assad was granted asylum in Moscow after being ousted by rebels.</li><li>He is living under restrictions and cannot leave Moscow or engage in political activities.</li></ul><blockquote>Russian authorities have frozen Bashar al-Assad’s assets, including gold and real estate.</blockquote><p>The situation reflects the complexities faced by the Assad family after the fall of their regime, with Asma seeking a return to a more familiar life in the UK.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/ousted-syrian-president-assads-wife-unhappy-with-life-in-russia-what-led-her-to-file-divorce-9165294.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/ousted-syrian-president-assads-wife-unhappy-with-life-in-russia-what-led-her-to-file-divorce-9165294.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:02:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OPPO Reno 13 series will launch in India in January; design and colours confirmed - 91mobiles]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OPPO Reno 13 series India launch month, design, colours confirmed</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> 91mobiles</p><img src="https://www.91-cdn.com/hub/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/OPPO-Reno-13-series.png?tr=w-781"><figcaption>OPPO Reno 13 series design preview</figcaption><p>OPPO is preparing for the global launch of the Reno 13 series in January 2025, including in India. The Reno 13 and Reno 13 Pro will feature distinct design elements and a variety of color options.</p><ul><li>Launch scheduled for January 2025.</li><li>Reno 13 Pro will come in Graphite Grey and Mist Lavender, while Reno 13 will be available in Ivory White and Luminous Blue.</li><li>Graphite Grey and Luminous Blue have a matte finish; Ivory White and Mist Lavender have a glossy look.</li><li>Innovative design with grayscale exposure laser direct writing technique for the glossy finishes.</li><li>Luminous Blue variant features a glowing camera module.</li><li>Constructed with an aerospace-grade aluminium frame and a Gorilla Glass 7i front.</li><li>Reno 13 Pro has 93.8% screen-to-body ratio; Reno 13 has 93.4%.</li><li>Both models offer IP66, IP68, and IP69 water and dust resistance ratings.</li></ul><p><strong>Performance:</strong> The Reno 13 Pro recently scored 1301 in single-core and 3930 in multi-core on Geekbench, featuring Android 15 and MediaTek Dimensity 8350 processor.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/oppo-reno-13-series-india-launch-january-confirmed/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/oppo-reno-13-series-india-launch-january-confirmed/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:02:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia reacts to reports of ousted Syrian President Assad’s wife seeking divorce - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/russia-reacts-to-reports-of-ousted-syrian-president-assads-wife-seeking-divorce/articleshow/116596783.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/russia-reacts-to-reports-of-ousted-syrian-president-assads-wife-seeking-divorce/articleshow/116596783.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Protests in J&K over reservation policy, CM Omar Abdullah's son joins stir | What we know - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Protests in J&K Over Reservation Policy, CM Omar Abdullah's Son Joins Stir</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/kashmir_protests_1734947115305_1734947121934.jpeg" alt="Protests in J&K" title="Hundreds of students, along with NC MP Ruhulla Mehdi, and other political leaders gathered outside CM Omar Abdullah's residence for the protest. (Waseem Andrabi/HT)"><figcaption>Hundreds of students, along with NC MP Ruhulla Mehdi, and other political leaders gathered outside CM Omar Abdullah's residence for the protest. (Waseem Andrabi/HT)</figcaption></figure><p>Several political leaders and hundreds of students have gathered outside the residence of Jammu and Kashmir chief minister Omar Abdullah to seek a review of the reservation policy, introduced by the administration earlier this year.</p><ul><li>Chief Minister Omar Abdullah's son joined the protests alongside students and party members.</li><li>Opposition leaders have also expressed their dissent regarding the new reservation policy.</li><li>The Jammu and Kashmir government formed a panel to review the policy amid growing calls for its revision.</li></ul><blockquote>“We hope the govt that came to power with a huge mandate and with a promise that they will rationalise the reservation - we hope the NC govt fulfils their promises in a time-bound manner.” - Iltija Mufti</blockquote><p>The growing unrest over the reservation policy highlights significant political and social tensions within Jammu and Kashmir, particularly concerning youth representation and equitable access to opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/protests-in-j-k-over-reservation-policy-cm-omar-abdullahs-son-joins-stir-what-we-know-101734946650260.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/protests-in-j-k-over-reservation-policy-cm-omar-abdullahs-son-joins-stir-what-we-know-101734946650260.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:57:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A look at Team India's probable Schedule of ICC Champions Trophy 2025 - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Team India's Schedule for ICC Champions Trophy 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/hybrid-model-for-icc-champions-trophy-2025-202412-1734947359.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Hybrid model for ICC Champions Trophy 2025">
<figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption>
<p>The ICC Champions Trophy 2025 is approaching with a new hybrid model, ensuring India's matches are hosted in the UAE amidst security concerns over travel to Pakistan.</p>
<ul>
  <li>India will play group stage matches in Dubai against Bangladesh on February 20 and New Zealand on March 2.</li>
  <li>Pakistan will begin the tournament with their first match against New Zealand in Karachi on February 19.</li>
  <li>The semifinal matches are scheduled for March 4 and 5, with the final set for March 9.</li>
  <li>Neutral venues will be used for matches between India and Pakistan to maintain impartiality.</li>
  <li>Hosting all of India's matches in UAE aims to ensure a secure environment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Given the ongoing political tensions between India and Pakistan, any matches between these two nations will be played at impartial venues."</blockquote>
<p>This tournament promises to be an exciting event, with critical matches taking place in Dubai offering neutral grounds for competing teams.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/a-look-at-team-indias-probable-schedule-of-icc-champions-trophy-2025-415875/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/a-look-at-team-indias-probable-schedule-of-icc-champions-trophy-2025-415875/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:54:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jayant removes all RLD spokespersons after Dalit leader slams Amit Shah for Ambedkar remarks - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jayant removes all RLD spokespersons after Dalit leader slams Amit Shah for Ambedkar remarks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> ThePrint</p><p>In a swift decision, Jayant Chaudhary, leader of the Rashtriya Lok Dal (RLD), has removed all national and state spokespersons following remarks made by Dalit leader Kamal Gautam, who criticized Union Home Minister Amit Shah's comments about Ambedkar.</p><ul><li>All RLD national and state spokespersons were dismissed for being either inactive or overly active.</li><li>The decision followed Gautam's call for Shah to apologize for his 'inappropriate' remarks on Ambedkar.</li><li>Shah asserted his statements were misrepresented and defended his remarks in the Rajya Sabha.</li><li>Gautam highlighted the lack of action against rising criminal incidents affecting Dalits and women.</li><li>The removal may indicate internal party tensions regarding public comments and coalition dynamics.</li></ul><blockquote>“Amit Shah’s statement on Babasaheb is not correct... This will reach all those who follow Babasaheb across the world.” - Kamal Gautam</blockquote><p>This incident underscores the sensitivity surrounding Dalit issues within Indian politics and the reaction of political parties to internal dissent.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/politics/jayant-removes-all-rld-spokespersons-after-dalit-leader-slams-amit-shah-for-ambedkar-remarks/2416088/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/politics/jayant-removes-all-rld-spokespersons-after-dalit-leader-slams-amit-shah-for-ambedkar-remarks/2416088/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:41:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress denies link to vandalism at Pushpa 2 actor Allu Arjun's residence in Hyderabad: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Denies Any Link to Vandalism at Allu Arjun's Residence</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/MixCollage-23-Dec-2024-02-48-PM-9371_1734945551239_1734945563512.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 actor Allu Arjun (L) and Telangana CM Revanth Reddy in picture." title="Pushpa 2 actor Allu Arjun (L) and Telangana CM Revanth Reddy in picture."><figcaption>Pushpa 2 actor Allu Arjun (L) and Telangana CM Revanth Reddy in picture.</figcaption><p>The Congress party has denied allegations of involvement in the vandalism at actor Allu Arjun's residence in Hyderabad, following a stampede incident during the premiere of his film, Pushpa 2.</p><ul><li>The vandalism occurred amid protests outside Allu Arjun's house in response to the Sandhya Theatre stampede incident that resulted in a woman’s death.</li><li>Congress spokesperson Sama Ram Mohan Reddy clarified that none of the accused are affiliated with the party.</li><li>Telangana CM Revanth Reddy condemned the attack and called for strict action from law enforcement.</li><li>Protesters identified as students from Osmania University allegedly caused damage to Allu Arjun's property.</li></ul><blockquote>“I condemn the attack on the homes of film celebrities. I am directing the State DGP and City Police Commissioner to take strict action regarding law and order.” - Revanth Reddy</blockquote><p>The incident highlights ongoing tensions and the dissatisfaction among certain groups following the tragic events at the theatre.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/congress-denies-link-to-vandalism-at-pushpa-2-actor-allu-arjuns-residence-in-hyderabad-report-101734943729081.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/congress-denies-link-to-vandalism-at-pushpa-2-actor-allu-arjuns-residence-in-hyderabad-report-101734943729081.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:31:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>