<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 18:21:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 18:21:36 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experts question ‘bird strike’ as reason behind South Korea plane crash that killed 179 | Top updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Experts question ‘bird strike’ as reason behind South Korea plane crash that killed 179</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 29, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/TOPSHOT-SKOREA-AVIATION-ACCIDENT-5_1735492056838_1735492077341.jpg" alt="Firefighters and rescue personnel work near the wreckage of a Jeju Air Boeing 737-800 series aircraft after the plane crashed and burst into flames at Muan International Airport in South Jeolla Province, some 288 kilometres southwest of Seoul on December 29, 2024.(AFP)">
<figcaption>Firefighters and rescue personnel work near the wreckage of a Jeju Air Boeing 737-800 series aircraft after the plane crashed and burst into flames at Muan International Airport in South Jeolla Province, some 288 kilometres southwest of Seoul on December 29, 2024.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>The tragic Jeju Air flight 7C2216 crash has raised significant questions regarding the actual cause, with experts disputing the likelihood of a bird strike leading to the aircraft's malfunction.</p>
<ul>
<li>The plane was landing at Muan International Airport when it crashed, resulting in the death of 179 people.</li>
<li>Experts argue that a bird strike could not have solely caused the malfunctioning of the landing gear.</li>
<li>Survivors of the crash are stable and conscious but the majority of passengers have not been identified.</li>
<li>The South Korean government declared a period of national mourning following the incident.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“At this point there are a lot more questions than we have answers.” - Gregory Alegi, aviation expert</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing investigation into the crash continues as authorities examine the factors that contributed to this tragic event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/experts-question-bird-strike-as-reason-behind-south-korea-plane-crash-that-killed-179-top-updates-101735489167236.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/experts-question-bird-strike-as-reason-behind-south-korea-plane-crash-that-killed-179-top-updates-101735489167236.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 17:20:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Companies News Today Live Updates on December 29, 2024: Reliance pulls out an old video of a very young Mukesh Ambani from archives for Jamnagar refinery celebrations | Watch | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Companies News Today Live Updates on December 29, 2024: Reliance pulls out an old video of a very young Mukesh Ambani from archives for Jamnagar refinery celebrations | Watch</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 29, 2024</strong><br><strong>Source: LiveMint</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2024/12/29/600x338/3664e1a8-4556-11ed-b45c-96b88fd91a1d_1672219055584_1672219055584_1735491217891.jpg" alt="Companies News Today Live Updates: Reliance pulls out an old video of a very young Mukesh Ambani from archives for Jamnagar refinery celebrations" title="Companies News Today Live Updates: Reliance pulls out an old video of a very young Mukesh Ambani from archives for Jamnagar refinery celebrations" />
<figcaption>Companies News Today Live Updates: Reliance pulls out an old video of a very young Mukesh Ambani from archives for Jamnagar refinery celebrations | Watch</figcaption>
<p>Reliance Industries commemorated the 25th anniversary of its Jamnagar refinery by sharing an old video featuring a young Mukesh Ambani, highlighting the company's historical significance in the petroleum industry.</p>
<ul>
<li>Reliance posted an old video of a young Mukesh Ambani to celebrate the Jamnagar refinery's 25th anniversary.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Stay ahead of the curve with the latest insights from the corporate world,” states the article.</blockquote>
<p>This celebration highlights the continued impact of Reliance's Jamnagar refinery on India's petroleum sector over the past 25 years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/latest-company-news-today-on-december-29-2024-live-updates-11735447167296.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/latest-company-news-today-on-december-29-2024-live-updates-11735447167296.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 17:08:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From lathicharge to water cannons: Bihar police crackdown on protesting BPSC aspirants - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bihar Police Use Force Against BPSC Aspirants Protests</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Protests by Bihar Public Service Commission (BPSC) aspirants escalated as police employed water cannons and lathi charges to disperse crowds demanding exam reforms.</p><ul><li>Protests arose from grievances over the BPSC examination process and calls for transparency.</li><li>Police responded with water cannons and physical force to manage the large gatherings of students.</li><li>Students expressed frustration with the lack of significant actions taken by the BPSC.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are fighting for our future; the authorities need to listen to us,” one protester stated.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights ongoing tensions between government agencies and youth aspiring for government jobs in Bihar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/from-lathicharge-to-water-cannons-bihar-police-crackdown-on-protesting-bpsc-aspirants/articleshow/116772263.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/from-lathicharge-to-water-cannons-bihar-police-crackdown-on-protesting-bpsc-aspirants/articleshow/116772263.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 17:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Should I Say My Last Words’: Jeju Air Flyer's Final Message To Family Moments Before Plane Crash - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/south-korea-jeju-air-plane-crash-flyers-last-message-to-family-eyewitness-video-latest-updates-9171756.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/south-korea-jeju-air-plane-crash-flyers-last-message-to-family-eyewitness-video-latest-updates-9171756.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 16:41:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Afghanistan-Pakistan Border War: What Is The “Hypothetical” Durand Line That Taliban Claims Crossing & Seizing Pak Army Posts - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Afghanistan-Pakistan Border War: What Is The “Hypothetical” Durand Line That Taliban Claims Crossing & Seizing Pak Army Posts</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Eurasian Times</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Su-57-1290-x-650-px-5.png" alt="" width="1290" height="650">
<figcaption>Pakistan airstrikes inside Afghanistan. Image Credits Platform X.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Recent military confrontations along the Durand Line have resulted in significant casualties for both Afghan and Pakistani forces. Following airstrikes by Pakistan in Afghanistan, Afghan forces launched counterstrikes across the border, leading to escalating tensions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>19 Pakistani soldiers were reported killed as Afghan forces crossed the contested Durand Line.</li>
  <li>The Afghan attacks were in retaliation for previous Pakistani airstrikes that killed 46 Afghan civilians, predominantly women and children.</li>
  <li>Afghan Defense Minister claims that the operations targeted areas used to launch attacks on Afghanistan.</li>
  <li>Both nations have acknowledged ongoing clashes and casualties on their sides, indicating a significant rise in border tensions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We do not consider it to be the territory of Pakistan… but it was on the other side of the hypothetical line.” - Enayatullah Khowarazmi, Afghan Ministry of Defense</blockquote>
<p>The escalating situation illustrates the persistent instability and the historical complexities surrounding the Durand Line, which has never been officially recognized by Afghanistan. The conflict reflects broader geopolitical dynamics in South Asia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/afghan-surgical-strikes-in-pak-taliban-crosses/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/afghan-surgical-strikes-in-pak-taliban-crosses/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 16:25:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress MLA Uma Thomas suffers serious injuries after 15-feet fall at JLN Stadium, Kerala - The New Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress MLA Uma Thomas Injured in 15-Foot Fall at JLN Stadium</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 29 Dec 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> TNIE</p><img src='image_url' alt='The 15-foot-high pavilion at the Jawaharlal Nehru Stadium'><figcaption>The 15-foot-high pavilion at the Jawaharlal Nehru Stadium (Photo | A Sanesh, EPS)</figcaption><p>Uma Thomas, Congress MLA of Thrikkakara, fell from a 15-foot-high dais while attending a dance program at Jawaharlal Nehru Stadium, resulting in serious injuries.</p><ul><li>The accident occurred when Thomas was heading towards the dais for the inauguration of the event.</li><li>She lost balance and fell onto a concrete platform, sustaining multiple fractures and bleeding.</li><li>Her condition is stable but she is currently on a ventilator.</li><li>A tube will be inserted to drain accumulated blood in her lungs, and a CT scan is needed to assess further injuries.</li></ul><blockquote>“MLA was unconscious and profusely bleeding... I was shocked to see her fall from the height.” - Sudheesh, eyewitness</blockquote><p>The incident highlights concerns over safety measures at public events and the need for secure barriers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/states/kerala/2024/Dec/29/congress-mla-uma-thomas-suffers-serious-injuries-after-15-feet-fall-at-jln-stadium-kerala</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newindianexpress.com/states/kerala/2024/Dec/29/congress-mla-uma-thomas-suffers-serious-injuries-after-15-feet-fall-at-jln-stadium-kerala</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 16:22:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is highest successful run-chase at Melbourne Cricket Ground in Tests? - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Set to Chase Record at MCG in 4th Test Against Australia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date Not Specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><p>As India gears up to chase a challenging target of 334 runs against Australia in the ongoing 4th Test at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG), this match could see the highest successful run chase in Test history at this iconic venue.</p><ul><li>India requires 334 runs to win after Australia opted not to declare their second innings.</li><li>Mohammed Siraj took a crucial wicket of Marnus Labuschagne, balancing the game in India's favor briefly.</li><li>Australia’s tail-enders boosted their second-innings total, pushing their lead to 333 runs by Day 4's end.</li><li>India's Jasprit Bumrah had a missed opportunity to dismiss Nathan Lyon due to a no-ball call, which could affect the outcome.</li></ul><blockquote>“Will Australia press on further with their innings or declare overnight? Day 5 promises high drama and a thrilling finish.”</blockquote><p>Historically, England holds the record for the highest successful run chase at the MCG with 332 runs against Australia in 1928, a record that remains unbeaten.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/cricket/news/what-is-highest-successful-run-chase-at-melbourne-cricket-ground-in-tests-124122900144_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/cricket/news/what-is-highest-successful-run-chase-at-melbourne-cricket-ground-in-tests-124122900144_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 16:06:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan and AbRam arrive in Jamnagar to celebrate New Year 2025 with the Ambani family - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan and AbRam arrive in Jamnagar to celebrate New Year 2025 with the Ambani family</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Shah Rukh Khan, along with his wife Gauri Khan and son AbRam, arrived in Jamnagar to mark the New Year 2025 celebrations with the Ambani family.</p><ul><li>The family was seen arriving at the Ambani residence.</li><li>This gathering is part of the traditional New Year celebrations held by the Ambani family.</li><li>Shah Rukh Khan’s presence added star power to the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s a joy to celebrate with close friends and family.” - A source close to the family.</blockquote><p>The festive gathering of Bollywood stars and prominent business figures showcases the interconnectedness of Indian cinema and business.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/shah-rukh-khan-gauri-khan-and-abram-arrive-in-jamnagar-to-celebrate-new-year-2025-with-the-ambani-family/articleshow/116772526.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/shah-rukh-khan-gauri-khan-and-abram-arrive-in-jamnagar-to-celebrate-new-year-2025-with-the-ambani-family/articleshow/116772526.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 16:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 (Hindi) 4th Weekend Box Office: Allu Arjun starrer scores another All Time Record; Platform set to enter 700 crore club - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 (Hindi) 4th Weekend Box Office: Allu Arjun starrer scores another All Time Record; Platform set to enter 700 crore club</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p>
<img src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/1113535790_pushpa-3.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2 Box Office Record" title="Pushpa 2 (Hindi) 4th Weekend Box Office" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Pushpa 2 continues its impressive box office run.</figcaption>
<p>The Allu Arjun led Pushpa 2 is achieving new heights at the box office, reaching impressive ticket sales and revenue figures. It is on track to enter the prestigious 700 crore club.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sold over 4 crore tickets in Hindi.</li>
  <li>Fourth weekend collections estimated at Rs 26.00 to Rs 26.50 crore.</li>
  <li>Total collections after 25 days stand at Rs 688.75 crore.</li>
  <li>Pushpa 2 is competing strongly against other films and remains the #1 choice in North India.</li>
  <li>Historical comparisons made with Gadar and Bahubali with ticket sales above 4 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The film is set to debut in the Rs 700 crore club by Tuesday and is expected to have lasting records.”</blockquote>
<p>Pushpa 2's remarkable box office performance highlights its dominance in the industry and sets a high bar for future films.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-4th-weekend-box-office-allu-arjun-starrer-scores-another-all-time-record-platform-set-to-enter-700-crore-club-1364792</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-hindi-4th-weekend-box-office-allu-arjun-starrer-scores-another-all-time-record-platform-set-to-enter-700-crore-club-1364792</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:56:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Panamanian President gives major reality check to Trump over China operates Panama Canal claim: ‘Whole world is free…' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Panamanian President José Raúl Mulino gives major reality check to Trump over China operates Panama Canal claim: ‘Whole world is free…'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/Untitled_1734932675342_1735486349895.jpg" alt="Panama president José Raúl Mulino reacts after Donald Trump threatens to take control of Panama Canal (AP Photo/Pamela Smith, photo by JOSH EDELSON / AFP)" title="Panama president José Raúl Mulino reacts after Donald Trump threatens to take control of Panama Canal (AP Photo/Pamela Smith, photo by JOSH EDELSON / AFP)">
<figcaption>Panama president José Raúl Mulino reacts after Donald Trump threatens to take control of Panama Canal (AP Photo/Pamela Smith, photo by JOSH EDELSON / AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Panamanian President José Raúl Mulino dismissed US President-elect Donald Trump's accusation of Chinese troops operating the Panama Canal as unfounded.</p>
<ul>
<li>President Mulino called Trump's claims "nonsense" and stressed that there is currently no Chinese presence in the canal.</li>
<li>Mulino emphasized the canal's Panamanian ownership and independence, stating it is not up for negotiation.</li>
<li>He highlighted the respectful diplomatic relationship between Panama and China established after severing ties with Taiwan in 2017.</li>
<li>Trump's comments were made during a social media post and at a conference where he expressed grievances over Panama's fees.</li>
<li>Mulino asserted the sovereignty of Panama, countering Trump’s threats to seize control of the canal.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There is not a single Chinese soldier in the canal. For the love of God, you are free, the whole world is free, to visit the canal if you please.” - José Raúl Mulino</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights ongoing tensions in U.S.-Latin America relations, particularly concerning U.S. accusations regarding China's involvement in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/panamanian-president-gives-major-reality-check-to-trump-over-china-operates-panama-canal-claim-whole-world-is-free-101735484247030.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/panamanian-president-gives-major-reality-check-to-trump-over-china-operates-panama-canal-claim-whole-world-is-free-101735484247030.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:37:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China unveils prototype of world's fastest train, capable of reaching 450 km/h - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Unveils Prototype of World's Fastest Train, Capable of Reaching 450 km/h</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>China has showcased a prototype of what it claims to be the fastest train in the world, with capabilities to travel at speeds of up to 450 kilometers per hour.</p><ul><li>The train represents a significant advancement in high-speed rail technology.</li><li>It is designed for both passenger and cargo transport, aiming to improve efficiency and reduce travel time.</li><li>China’s aim is to enhance its railway network and boost economic development across regions.</li></ul><blockquote>“This train is a game-changer for the global transportation sector,” said a spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This development signifies China’s continuous commitment to leading in transportation technology and innovation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/china-unveils-protoype-of-worlds-fastest-train-capable-of-reaching-450-km/h/articleshow/116772040.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/china-unveils-protoype-of-worlds-fastest-train-capable-of-reaching-450-km/h/articleshow/116772040.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can permanent hair dyes and chemical hair straighteners increase breast cancer risk? Expert explains - mid-day.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxPN0YyLUhzeGNBQ1paOUN6R0JUQXJSVjNYVDJtT280Umx0LTZkdUpHYm5NQzZkZjlIN0cwX18xSzFfYzhvVHNHckJ3LXJ3UkREWDN2b05hMEJBenRnSWFjTXNLcXI4S3Y2clZ0Y1hKbUxkUnlidVdTREVHZkxDSXFyMTRBS21taF9FWm9MbjhYekxETlo4YkJiTHdvdTFJZ1YxZlh0dGVyQkZJS19wc2ZFa2xCVFJUWmJGWW1mQjg2M3Ria2syVmJRTmh3eFB2VVFCV190b2g2eWxVS1UweS1GN0VwZUpsODFvbm4wb1ZKdGd1OXBtVUhfeWh5NHZpQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxPN0YyLUhzeGNBQ1paOUN6R0JUQXJSVjNYVDJtT280Umx0LTZkdUpHYm5NQzZkZjlIN0cwX18xSzFfYzhvVHNHckJ3LXJ3UkREWDN2b05hMEJBenRnSWFjTXNLcXI4S3Y2clZ0Y1hKbUxkUnlidVdTREVHZkxDSXFyMTRBS21taF9FWm9MbjhYekxETlo4YkJiTHdvdTFJZ1YxZlh0dGVyQkZJS19wc2ZFa2xCVFJUWmJGWW1mQjg2M3Ria2syVmJRTmh3eFB2VVFCV190b2g2eWxVS1UweS1GN0VwZUpsODFvbm4wb1ZKdGd1OXBtVUhfeWh5NHZpQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea plane crash live: Only 65 victims of plane crash identified - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Plane Crash: 65 Victims Identified Amid National Mourning</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/SKOERA-AVIATION-ACCIDENT-0_1735472836685_1735472851854.jpg" alt="Firefighters and rescue personnel carry the body of a victim near the scene" title="Firefighters and rescue personnel carry the body of a victim near the scene"><figcaption>Firefighters and rescue personnel carry the body of a victim near the scene.</figcaption><p>The Jeju Air flight 7C2216 crashed during landing in Muan, resulting in the deaths of 179 out of 181 passengers. Only two flight attendants survived the horrific accident.</p><ul><li>The plane was returning from Bangkok with 175 passengers and six crew members.</li><li>The South Korean government has declared seven days of national mourning for the victims.</li><li>Widespread condolences have been offered from international leaders, including Pope Francis and the German Chancellor.</li><li>Five of the deceased were children under ten, with the youngest being just three years old.</li><li>The crash is the deadliest air disaster in South Korean history since 1997.</li></ul><blockquote>“I believe no words of consolation would suffice for the bereaved families who have suffered this tragedy,” - South Korea's acting President Choi Sang-mok.</blockquote><p>This tragic event is a somber reminder of the vulnerabilities involved in air travel, prompting a thorough investigation into the causes to prevent future incidents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-jeju-air-muan-boeing-death-toll-101735437972261.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-jeju-air-muan-boeing-death-toll-101735437972261.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 14:23:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valley fever cases spike in California by 20% compared to 2023: Here’s everything you need to know about - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Valley fever cases spike in California by 20% compared to 2023: Here’s everything you need to know about the infection</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 11, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> California Health Department</p><p>An alarming 20% rise in valley fever cases has been reported in California compared to the previous year, prompting health officials to alert the public about the infection.</p><ul><li>Valley fever, or coccidioidomycosis, is caused by a fungus found in soil.</li><li>Symptoms can include fever, cough, and fatigue, with severe cases requiring hospitalization.</li><li>The increase is attributed to climate changes affecting environmental conditions.</li></ul><blockquote>"This spike is concerning, particularly as many areas face ongoing drought and changes in climate patterns that make conditions ripe for the fungus to spread," said a state health official.</blockquote><p>Health experts emphasize the importance of awareness and preventive measures to combat this rising health threat.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/valley-fever-cases-spike-in-california-by-20-compared-to-2023-heres-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-infection/articleshow/116769292.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/valley-fever-cases-spike-in-california-by-20-compared-to-2023-heres-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-infection/articleshow/116769292.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How South Africa booked their place in the World Test Championship final - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-world-test-championship/how-south-africa-booked-their-place-in-the-world-test-championship-final/articleshow/116770456.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-world-test-championship/how-south-africa-booked-their-place-in-the-world-test-championship-final/articleshow/116770456.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oppo Find N5 Specifications Have Reportedly Been Leaked: From Design & Camera To Battery, Here's What We Know - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Oppo Find N5 Specifications Have Reportedly Been Leaked: From Design & Camera To Battery</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024-12-01<strong> Source:</strong> Tech News</p>
<p>As Oppo gears up for 2025, key specifications of the Find N5 have reportedly been leaked, hinting at significant improvements over its predecessor.</p>
<ul>
  <li>6.4-inch external display with 120Hz refresh rate and 8-inch main screen with 2K resolution.</li>
  <li>Powered by Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite processor and a 5700mAh battery with 80W wired charging.</li>
  <li>Rumored 50W wireless charging support.</li>
  <li>Triple-camera system with three 50MP sensors for versatile photography.</li>
  <li>Expected configurations up to 16GB RAM and 1TB storage.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These leaked specifications should be taken cautiously, as Oppo has yet to officially confirm any details.”</blockquote>
<p>Speculation suggests an official announcement will occur shortly after the Chinese New Year in 2025, possibly in February.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/oppo-find-n5-leaks-specifications-design-camera-battery-display-what-we-know-1740621</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/oppo-find-n5-leaks-specifications-design-camera-battery-display-what-we-know-1740621</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:52:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 mesmerising images of galaxies by NASA - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNVS1XRTVqaFE5clpqTGg5UzFwbUtJWHRmdHVzVlQ4X3E3bE5fVG1fcXBEVGFyb1U5TmtrY1BlTk5hUU0wQ0d4ak5heVEwSWhWczd1ZzQ4NEc2d05Za2t1cUw2cmxGZG1ROHdPNnRMaDJ0RGU3bFZEZHRXRjRyWWJUNUpnWHdsdEtKcnBpanVEejBRNmVlVng0UzZ0alh2amfSAZ8BQVVfeXFMTVUtV0U1amhROXJaakxoOVMxcG1LSVh0ZnR1c1ZUOF9xN2xOX1RtX3FwRFRhcm9VOU5ra2NQZU5OYVFNMENHeGpOYXlRMEloVnM3dWc0ODRHNndOWWtrdXFMNnJsRmRtUTh3TzZ0TGgydERlN2xWRGR0V0Y0clliVDVKZ1h3bHRLSnJwaWp1RHowUTZlZVZ4NFM2dGpYdmpn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNVS1XRTVqaFE5clpqTGg5UzFwbUtJWHRmdHVzVlQ4X3E3bE5fVG1fcXBEVGFyb1U5TmtrY1BlTk5hUU0wQ0d4ak5heVEwSWhWczd1ZzQ4NEc2d05Za2t1cUw2cmxGZG1ROHdPNnRMaDJ0RGU3bFZEZHRXRjRyWWJUNUpnWHdsdEtKcnBpanVEejBRNmVlVng0UzZ0alh2amfSAZ8BQVVfeXFMTVUtV0U1amhROXJaakxoOVMxcG1LSVh0ZnR1c1ZUOF9xN2xOX1RtX3FwRFRhcm9VOU5ra2NQZU5OYVFNMENHeGpOYXlRMEloVnM3dWc0ODRHNndOWWtrdXFMNnJsRmRtUTh3TzZ0TGgydERlN2xWRGR0V0Y0clliVDVKZ1h3bHRLSnJwaWp1RHowUTZlZVZ4NFM2dGpYdmpn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:38:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breaking: Dil Raju announces Game Changer trailer launch date - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dil Raju Announces Game Changer Trailer Launch Date</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 29, 2024 at 7:04 pm IST | Source: 123Telugu</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Game-Changer-7.jpg" alt="Game Changer Movie" width="450" height="338"><figcaption>Game Changer teaser features Ram Charan in a dual role.</figcaption><p>Ram Charan's forthcoming political drama, <em>Game Changer</em>, is set for theatrical release on January 10, with the trailer launching on January 1.</p><ul><li>Producer Dil Raju announced the trailer release date amid fan festivities.</li><li>The trailer will feature a 2'45 minute duration showcasing Ram Charan's “Nata Viswaroopam”.</li><li>The film's teaser highlighted Ram Charan in a dual role, promising a grand cinematic experience.</li><li>Collaborations include Kiara Advani and renowned director Shankar.</li></ul><blockquote>“Fans will witness Ram Charan’s ‘Nata Viswaroopam’ in the trailer.” - Dil Raju</blockquote><p>The upcoming trailer is highly anticipated, following the buzz generated by the teaser and the film's star-studded cast.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/breaking-dil-raju-announces-game-changer-trailer-launch-date.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/breaking-dil-raju-announces-game-changer-trailer-launch-date.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PKL 2024 Finals HIGHLIGHTS: Haryana Steelers beat Patna Pirates to win their maiden PKL title - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PKL 2024 Finals HIGHLIGHTS: Haryana Steelers beat Patna Pirates to win their maiden PKL title</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><div><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" alt="PKL 2024 Final highlights" width="803" height="452"><figcaption>PKL 2024 Final highlights</figcaption></div><p>The Pro Kabaddi League 2024 concluded with Haryana Steelers defeating Patna Pirates by 9 points, securing their first-ever championship title.</p><ul><li>Haryana Steelers overcame last season's disappointment as runners-up.</li><li>This marks the fourth instance in PKL history where a team won the title after being a runner-up the previous season.</li><li>Patna Pirates were unable to relive their past success of winning from the eliminators.</li><li>The match ended with a score of 32-23 in favor of Haryana Steelers.</li><li>Notable player performances included Devank Dalal leading in raid points, and Mohammadreza Shadloui as the top defender.</li></ul><blockquote>“Haryana Steelers are now the eighth team in PKL history to win the trophy.”</blockquote><p>This victory signifies a remarkable turnaround for the Haryana Steelers, illustrating their growth and resilience in the league.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/sports/pro-kabaddi-league/pkl-2024-finals-live-score-updates-haryana-steelers-to-take-on-patna-pirates-in-title-clash-at-8-pm-124122900237_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/sports/pro-kabaddi-league/pkl-2024-finals-live-score-updates-haryana-steelers-to-take-on-patna-pirates-in-title-clash-at-8-pm-124122900237_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:30:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is Nitish Kumar Reddy's IPL earnings? SRH owner Kavya Maran raised his salary 25 times in just one year - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitish Kumar Reddy's IPL Earnings Soar 25 Times in a Year</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/what-is-nitish-kumar-reddys-ipl-earnings-srh-owner-kavya-maran-raised-his-salary-25-times-in-just-one-year-202412-1735478824.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Nitish Kumar Reddy's IPL Earnings" />
<figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption>
<p>Nitish Kumar Reddy, after an impressive performance in the IPL, has seen a significant raise in his salary, which has increased 25 times within a year, from Rs 20 lakh to Rs 6 crore.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nitish Kumar Reddy debuted in IPL 2023 but gained recognition in 2024.</li>
  <li>Reddy scored 303 runs with a strike rate of 143 in the 2024 season, including 2 half-centuries.</li>
  <li>His salary was raised by Kavya Maran, the owner of Sunrisers Hyderabad.</li>
  <li>He played a critical role in leading his team to the IPL final.</li>
  <li>Nitish Reddy has been retained for IPL 2025 for Rs 6 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Nitish earned Rs 20 lakh in 2023, he is set to make Rs 6 crore in the 2025 IPL.”</blockquote>
<p>This remarkable raise underscores the impact of Reddy's performance on his team's success and the IPL's growing financial dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/what-is-nitish-kumar-reddys-ipl-earnings-srh-owner-kavya-maran-raised-his-salary-25-times-in-just-one-year-417048/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/what-is-nitish-kumar-reddys-ipl-earnings-srh-owner-kavya-maran-raised-his-salary-25-times-in-just-one-year-417048/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:29:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I Am Your Father": Australia Media Insults Virat Kohli Again, Hits All-New Low - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxNWmwyc0hmeWh6WWdfWEhUQUk3UXM4ckp5cmxXTHI1Y2phckgzVk9kNElxMml1T1lENE1UT3hoLVgxVFpRMG45X2hMNDJVLWN0ZEhsTGVYeWdsQkxGZkRhYjZnZEp5ZEs1XzB6dEZ1b3VWcXpQTXVlaS1Ib04wYnJGblVQTC1WZEw5WDVpZ0VzSGRidVctdjh0MVNaQUlsN3VfQU5OM2lGQnVnSWtpTU9wUUVHdEdDeVNDdGdCeXhXVjdmS3BhSFF4c1k1cU9FVTg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxNWmwyc0hmeWh6WWdfWEhUQUk3UXM4ckp5cmxXTHI1Y2phckgzVk9kNElxMml1T1lENE1UT3hoLVgxVFpRMG45X2hMNDJVLWN0ZEhsTGVYeWdsQkxGZkRhYjZnZEp5ZEs1XzB6dEZ1b3VWcXpQTXVlaS1Ib04wYnJGblVQTC1WZEw5WDVpZ0VzSGRidVctdjh0MVNaQUlsN3VfQU5OM2lGQnVnSWtpTU9wUUVHdEdDeVNDdGdCeXhXVjdmS3BhSFF4c1k1cU9FVTg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:20:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Physical relations’ cannot automatically mean sexual assault, rules Delhi High court - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Physical relations’ cannot automatically mean sexual assault, rules Delhi High court</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024 - <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/Delhi_high_court_1735476460055_1735476460262.jpg" alt="The Delhi high court. (Mint File Photo)"><figcaption>The Delhi high court. (Mint File Photo)</figcaption></figure><p>The Delhi High Court acquitted a man accused under the Protection of Children from Sexual Offences Act (POCSO), stating that the phrase 'physical relations' used by the minor cannot automatically be interpreted as sexual assault. The court highlighted the need for concrete evidence rather than assumptions in such cases.</p><ul><li>The ruling was made by Justices Pratibha M Singh and Amit Sharma.</li><li>The accused had initially been sentenced to life imprisonment.</li><li>The court emphasized the absence of clarity on the term 'physical relations' as used by the minor.</li></ul><blockquote>The court stated, "The mere fact that the survivor is below 18 years cannot lead to a conclusion that there was penetrative sexual assault."</blockquote><p>This ruling raises important questions about definitions and interpretations in sexual assault cases, especially regarding minors. The court's decision to acquit the accused based on the nuances of language highlights the complexities involved in such legal matters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/physical-relations-cannot-automatically-mean-sexual-assault-rules-delhi-high-court-101735476437856.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/physical-relations-cannot-automatically-mean-sexual-assault-rules-delhi-high-court-101735476437856.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:17:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[End of 21-day hunt, tigress Zeenat sedated and caged in Bengal - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>End of 21-day hunt, tigress Zeenat sedated and caged in Bengal</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024  <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<p>Tigress Zeenat was successfully sedated and caged after a 21-day hunt covering over 300 kilometres across Odisha, Jharkhand, and West Bengal.</p>
<blockquote><p>“My heartiest congratulations to the forest officials of West Bengal on the successful rescue of the tigress- Zeenat.” — Mamata Banerjee</p></blockquote>
<ul>
    <li>Zeenat was sedated in Bankura district, West Bengal.</li>
    <li>The operation was supported by forest officials from both West Bengal and Odisha.</li>
    <li>The tigress will be transported to Alipore Zoo for health checks.</li>
    <li>Zeenat had escaped from Simlipal Tiger Reserve and covered over 300 km during her journeys.</li>
    <li>Forest Minister Birbaha Hansda highlighted the efforts to avoid man-animal conflict during the rescue.</li>
</ul>
<p>This successful rescue demonstrates teamwork and dedication towards wildlife conservation while ensuring the safety of both the tigress and local residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/tigress-zeenat-sedated-caged-bengal-9750337/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/tigress-zeenat-sedated-caged-bengal-9750337/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Koneru Humpy: From mulling retirement to a second world rapid crown - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Koneru Humpy Triumphs Again: From Retirement Doubts to a Second World Rapid Championship</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/India-s-Koneru-Humpy--at-37--now-has-two-Women-s-W_1735477384862.jpg" alt="India’s Koneru Humpy, at 37, now has two Women’s World Rapid Championship titles (PTI)" title="India’s Koneru Humpy, at 37, now has two Women’s World Rapid Championship titles (PTI)"><figcaption>India’s Koneru Humpy, at 37, now has two Women’s World Rapid Championship titles (PTI)</figcaption><p>Koneru Humpy has made a remarkable comeback in chess, winning her second Women's World Rapid title against all odds at the age of 37. This victory marks her as one of the only players to win this title twice.</p><ul><li>She previously took a break from competitive chess following complications from pregnancy and motherhood.</li><li>In the 2019 championship, she claimed her first title through tie-breaks.</li><li>This time, she won outright without needing tiebreakers, finishing first with a score of 8.5/11 points.</li><li>Humpy faced doubts about her performance leading up to the tournament but turned her struggles into a title-winning performance.</li><li>She believes her success will inspire younger players in India to pursue chess professionally.</li></ul><blockquote>“This victory is very special. I was feeling low and this win gives me the boost to fight and to work on chess again.” - Koneru Humpy</blockquote><p>Humpy’s journey emphasizes overcoming personal and professional hurdles to achieve success, showcasing her dedication to chess and her family.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/koneru-humpy-from-mulling-retirement-to-a-second-world-rapid-crown-101735477388036.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/koneru-humpy-from-mulling-retirement-to-a-second-world-rapid-crown-101735477388036.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump backs Elon Musk and H-1B visas amid MAGA meltdown - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Backs Elon Musk and H-1B Visas Amid MAGA Meltdown</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>The article discusses Donald Trump's recent support for Elon Musk and the continuation of H-1B visas amidst controversy from his supporters.</p><ul><li>Trump shows renewed support for technology and immigration policies.</li><li>The impact of this stance on his political base is debated.</li><li>Elon Musk's influence in tech and politics highlighted.</li></ul><blockquote>"We must embrace innovation to stay competitive." - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>This development could signal a shift in Trump's approach to immigration and technology policy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-backs-elon-musk-and-h-1b-visas-amid-maga-meltdown/articleshow/116769297.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-backs-elon-musk-and-h-1b-visas-amid-maga-meltdown/articleshow/116769297.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan accuses Russia of trying to hide causes of plane crash; says the plane was shot from Russia - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Azerbaijan accuses Russia of trying to hide causes of plane crash; says the plane was shot from Russia</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/5ueo2b/article69040073.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-29T121219Z_1883412839_RC2L3BAXKGEP_RTRMADP_3_KAZAKHSTAN-CRASH-RUSSIA.JPG" alt="Azerbaijan’s President Ilham Aliyev said the Azerbaijan Airlines jet that crashed this week was shot at from Russia and called for Moscow to admit “guilt” in the disaster. File" /><figcaption>Azerbaijan’s President Ilham Aliyev speaking about the incident.</figcaption><p>Azerbaijan’s President Ilham Aliyev stated that the Azerbaijan Airlines jet that crashed was shot at from Russia, calling for Moscow to acknowledge its responsibility for the tragedy.</p><ul><li>The crash resulted in the death of 38 people out of 67 onboard.</li><li>Aliyev claimed the plane was struck “by accident” from Russian territory.</li><li>Russian President Vladimir Putin has apologized but did not confirm that the jet was hit by Russian fire.</li><li>Aliyev blamed Russian electronic warfare systems for compromising the plane's control.</li><li>He criticized Russia for suggesting theories that attempt to cover up the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“Of course, our plane was hit by accident. Of course, there can be no talk of a deliberate act of terror here.” - President Ilham Aliyev</blockquote><p>In light of the circumstances, Aliyev urged timely admission of guilt from Russia, highlighting the importance of transparent communication regarding the incident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/azerbaijan-accuses-russia-of-trying-to-hide-causes-of-plane-crash-says-the-plane-was-shot-from-russia/article69040088.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/azerbaijan-accuses-russia-of-trying-to-hide-causes-of-plane-crash-says-the-plane-was-shot-from-russia/article69040088.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EV financing no longer risky, says Shriram Finance's executive vice chairman Umesh Revankar | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>EV Financing Considered Low Risk, Says Shriram Finance Executive</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/subscription/onepagecheckout/lm/staging/extensivepaywall/headphone.png" alt="EV Financing Image"><figcaption>Image representing EV financing.</figcaption><p>Umesh Revankar, executive vice-chairman of Shriram Finance, discusses the current landscape of electric vehicle financing, highlighting its low risk status compared to five years ago.</p><ul><li>Revankar asserts that established manufacturers are enhancing the reliability of EV technology.</li><li>He believes that growing infrastructure alongside innovative large entities will drive change in the EV market.</li><li>The trend of reliable financing is being observed across two-wheeler and three-wheeler segments as well.</li></ul><blockquote>"Once large entities come and build technology, reliability and infrastructure, then automatically that industry goes for a big change."</blockquote><p>This analysis suggests a positive shift towards financing electric vehicles as market confidence grows.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/ev-financing-no-longer-risky-says-shriram-finances-executive-vice-chairman-umesh-revankar-11735465065111.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/ev-financing-no-longer-risky-says-shriram-finances-executive-vice-chairman-umesh-revankar-11735465065111.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:46:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shah Rukh Khan hides face in hoodie, holds pet dog as he returns to Mumbai. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shah Rukh Khan hides face in hoodie, holds pet dog as he returns to Mumbai</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/shah_rukh__1735473476234_1735473476646.jpg" alt="Shah Rukh Khan was spotted holding a dog in his hands." title="Shah Rukh Khan was spotted holding a dog in his hands."><figcaption>Shah Rukh Khan was spotted holding a dog in his hands.</figcaption><p>On Sunday, Shah Rukh Khan was spotted returning to Mumbai from Alibaug with his family. The actor was seen hiding his face with a black hoodie while carrying a pet dog in his arms.</p><ul><li>Shah Rukh Khan traveled with wife Gauri Khan and children Suhana and AbRam Khan.</li><li>The family had tight security during their return.</li><li>Shah Rukh avoided the cameras, using his hoodie to hide his face.</li><li>He was observed taking care of his pet dog during the outing.</li><li>Shah Rukh is currently preparing for his upcoming film 'King', which features Suhana Khan.</li></ul><blockquote>“The next film I am doing King, I have to start working on it, have to lose some weight a little, do some stretching.” - Shah Rukh Khan</blockquote><p>This sighting has generated buzz among fans, especially regarding the new pet and the upcoming film.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-hides-face-in-hoodie-holds-pet-dog-as-he-returns-to-mumbai-watch-101735473132750.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-hides-face-in-hoodie-holds-pet-dog-as-he-returns-to-mumbai-watch-101735473132750.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:25:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea Plane Crash Live Updates: Seven day national mourning declared till Jan 4 - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Plane Crash Live Updates</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 24, 2024, Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/expressintro-9.jpg?w=640" alt="South Korea plane crash" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>South Korea Plane Crash Live: The accident happened around 9 am (local time) when the Jeju Air flight was landing at Muan International Airport in South Jeolla Province, about 288 km away from capital Seoul. (X/Yonhanp news agency)</figcaption><p>In an emergency meeting on Sunday, South Korea’s acting President Choi Sang-mok declared a national mourning period until January 4 following the deadly plane crash at Muan International Airport that killed 179. All on board except two crew members are feared dead as a plane carrying 181 passengers and six crew on a flight from Bangkok crashed and burst into flames early Sunday.</p><p>The crash site has been declared a special disaster zone.</p><ul><li>A Jeju Air flight veered off the runway while landing and exploded into flames.</li><li>The airline is gathering information regarding the casualties and causes of the accident.</li><li>Two Thai nationals were among the 175 passengers, with the rest believed to be South Koreans.</li></ul><blockquote>“The government would like to offer its sincere condolences to the bereaved families and will do its best to recover from this accident and prevent a recurrence.” - Choi Sang-mok</blockquote><p>This tragic incident has raised significant concerns regarding aviation safety measures in South Korea.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:22:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WTC Points Table: South Africa book spot in the final; Here's what it means for India and Australia - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxPNTN0Q082aTdnZE1yVldrZXptYktXX0MwQmNkUjVuTVJsUTFxTmdwQnExVVQ3aDhma1FTV0p1b3U1RUVlQ29PbFBzam5nWndrRHczZGJDa1N0dFNBNnhRSUNCR3BPcE9oc1FBUUtmcWp4WTUwTGxHOEtKSU5zcERzWkt2SlNXUVg1eFQ2eTV4NXpqR2s0Q3pNYVNZRTZDLWRaTzdhUnVEdlRkb2g5NDVfS3FvRVFtMV82VlQ0N1lHcjY3dk9QNzMxaGVSazEtTjVsaHczU0gzbVV3eWNhT01GT3U2WmVaU0hjU0xKLTdLcThRSmlL0gH6AUFVX3lxTE1OYlZ5VllUaTJ5Z2lJOW5OeG15ZVEyS25pVHBWU2Q3SFRXUzhGSWcyVmsyQ05RV3p4amFSN2FRUXB4Qm56SFlhNEZaeDY3aEZ0SHIyeEZCTTN1T2dOa1d1SFJBb0VWN2F0NF81OVpJY1plR3VIV3RJdmgwU3FiaDVyamNhcjNOTS1obk1KNmpSbU5Gc0dkMjZqTll6OTROdk82V21GaTMzYy1IVlBqRC03UTJJaHByMzJqNHpxRFR3ODJERWtJOERybHAxUm50NzJ1TjQ5LWRkbTBNQmJ6NTB4RzFYY1lOb1lZdjVSRU5TV3BCWlQwNFdrUFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxPNTN0Q082aTdnZE1yVldrZXptYktXX0MwQmNkUjVuTVJsUTFxTmdwQnExVVQ3aDhma1FTV0p1b3U1RUVlQ29PbFBzam5nWndrRHczZGJDa1N0dFNBNnhRSUNCR3BPcE9oc1FBUUtmcWp4WTUwTGxHOEtKSU5zcERzWkt2SlNXUVg1eFQ2eTV4NXpqR2s0Q3pNYVNZRTZDLWRaTzdhUnVEdlRkb2g5NDVfS3FvRVFtMV82VlQ0N1lHcjY3dk9QNzMxaGVSazEtTjVsaHczU0gzbVV3eWNhT01GT3U2WmVaU0hjU0xKLTdLcThRSmlL0gH6AUFVX3lxTE1OYlZ5VllUaTJ5Z2lJOW5OeG15ZVEyS25pVHBWU2Q3SFRXUzhGSWcyVmsyQ05RV3p4amFSN2FRUXB4Qm56SFlhNEZaeDY3aEZ0SHIyeEZCTTN1T2dOa1d1SFJBb0VWN2F0NF81OVpJY1plR3VIV3RJdmgwU3FiaDVyamNhcjNOTS1obk1KNmpSbU5Gc0dkMjZqTll6OTROdk82V21GaTMzYy1IVlBqRC03UTJJaHByMzJqNHpxRFR3ODJERWtJOERybHAxUm50NzJ1TjQ5LWRkbTBNQmJ6NTB4RzFYY1lOb1lZdjVSRU5TV3BCWlQwNFdrUFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:19:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>