<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 06:23:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 06:23:17 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah makes a return to Sydney Cricket Ground after hospital visit - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Returns to Sydney Cricket Ground After Hospital Visit</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116930957,imgsize-25488,width-400,resizemode-4/116930957.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah returns to Sydney Cricket Ground after hospital visit" title="Jasprit Bumrah (Video grab)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah (Video grab)</figcaption><p>India's stand-in captain Jasprit Bumrah made a concerning exit from the SCG during the final Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy but has since returned after a visit to the hospital.</p><ul><li>Bumrah left the field with the team doctor after bowling just one over post-Lunch.</li><li>He previously took the important wicket of Marnus Labuschagne, bringing his series total to 32 wickets.</li><li>The record, set on Australian soil, surpasses the previous record of 31 wickets held by Bishan Singh Bedi.</li><li>Bumrah's timely return is crucial as he has been pivotal to the team's performance this series.</li></ul><blockquote>Throughout his spell, Bumrah maintained decent speeds and consistently clocked over 135 kmph with no visible discomfort.</blockquote><p>Team India hopes that Bumrah's minor issue is not serious, as his availability is essential for the remainder of the match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-leaves-the-sydney-cricket-ground-with-team-doctor/articleshow/116930962.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-leaves-the-sydney-cricket-ground-with-team-doctor/articleshow/116930962.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 06:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia LIVE Cricket Score, 5th Test Day 2: Jasprit Bumrah is back in the Indian dressing room, IND 97/4 vs AUS in Sydney - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia LIVE Cricket Score, 5th Test Day 2</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Saturday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/5thTest-IND-vs-AUS-day-02.jpg?w=750" alt="India vs Australia LIVE Cricket Score, 5th Test Day 2"><figcaption>India vs Australia LIVE Cricket Score, 5th Test Day 2: Follow the IND vs AUS updates from Sydney on Saturday.</figcaption><p>On Day 2 of the 5th Test in Sydney, India is in a challenging position with 124 runs for 5 wickets, while Australia had taken a slight lead of 181 runs at Tea. Notable performances include Mohammed Siraj and Prasidh Krishna taking three wickets each, and Jasprit Bumrah’s hospital visit after a bowling incident.</p><ul><li>India scored 185 in their first innings.</li><li>Mohammed Siraj and Prasidh Krishna took three wickets each to restrict Australia.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah sent to the hospital for scans after his bowling outing.</li><li>Rishabh Pant has departed during the ongoing match.</li><li>Match is live at the Sydney Cricket Ground.</li></ul><blockquote>“India could not put on a better top-order display despite replacing their out-of-form skipper Rohit Sharma.”</blockquote><p>As the match progresses, Australia's steadiness with a lead suggests a riveting contest ahead as India needs to regroup to stay competitive.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/ind-vs-aus-5th-test-day-2-live-score-india-vs-australia-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-sydney-cricket-ground-9758758/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/ind-vs-aus-5th-test-day-2-live-score-india-vs-australia-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-sydney-cricket-ground-9758758/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 05:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indians need not to worry about HMPV outbreak as of now, says ICMR ex-chief - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/healthcare/indians-need-not-to-worry-about-hmpv-outbreak-as-of-now-says-icmr-ex-chief-19534438.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/healthcare/indians-need-not-to-worry-about-hmpv-outbreak-as-of-now-says-icmr-ex-chief-19534438.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 05:39:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[500 On Bumble, 200 On Snapchat: Delhi Man Scams 700 Women As "US Model" - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Man Scams Over 700 Women by Posing as US Model on Dating Apps</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not Specified</p><p>An East Delhi man was arrested for defrauding over 700 women by posing as a US-based model on dating apps, using manipulation and blackmail for financial gain.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Tushar Singh Bisht, 23, worked as a recruiter in Noida while engaging in cybercrime at night.</li><li>Created fake profiles on dating apps using stolen photos of a Brazilian model.</li><li>Targeted primarily women aged 18-30, extorting money with manipulated intimate content.</li><li>Victims were threatened with the release of personal content if they refused to pay.</li><li>Police investigations revealed over 500 women contacted on Bumble and more than 200 on Snapchat.</li><li>Recovered mobile phone and incriminating evidence during the arrest.</li><li>At least four victims have been identified in addition to the initial complainant.</li></ul><blockquote>“If a victim refused his demands for money, he would threaten to upload their explicit content online or sell it on the dark web.”</blockquote><p>The investigation highlights the growing danger of online impersonation and the need for awareness regarding online interactions and privacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/500-on-bumble-200-on-snapchat-delhi-man-scams-700-women-as-us-model-7396611</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/500-on-bumble-200-on-snapchat-delhi-man-scams-700-women-as-us-model-7396611</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 05:19:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 16 Plus now available for only Rs 39,750, here's how to avail this offer - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Massive Discount on iPhone 16 Plus: Now Available for Rs 39,750</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/iphone-16-representational-image-1735967623.webp" alt="iPhone 16 discount" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>iPhone 16 discount</figcaption><p>The new year has brought excellent discounts on smartphones, particularly on the iPhone 16 series. The iPhone 16 Plus is now available for Rs 39,750 through various offers and discounts.</p><ul><li>The iPhone 16 Plus has a listed price of Rs 89,900 but has dropped to Rs 84,900 due to a 5% discount.</li><li>Add an instant discount of Rs 4,000 with specific credit card payments, reducing the price further to Rs 80,900.</li><li>By trading in an old smartphone, customers can receive an additional exchange value of Rs 41,150.</li><li>Overall, with all offers applied, the iPhone 16 Plus can be purchased for just Rs 39,750.</li><li>The smartphone features a 6.7-inch Super AMOLED display, IP68 certification, and runs on iOS 18.</li><li>It is powered by the Apple A18 Bionic chipset and offers up to 8GB RAM and 512GB storage.</li></ul><blockquote>“If you make the most of these offers, you could walk away with the iPhone 16 Plus for just Rs 39,750.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, this is a great opportunity for customers looking to invest in an iPhone this new year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/iphone-16-plus-now-available-for-only-rs-39-750-here-s-how-to-avail-this-offer-2025-01-04-969445</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/iphone-16-plus-now-available-for-only-rs-39-750-here-s-how-to-avail-this-offer-2025-01-04-969445</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 05:15:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia LIVE Cricket Score, 5th Test Day 2: AUS 181 all out vs IND at Sydney - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia LIVE Cricket Score, 5th Test Day 2: Updates from Sydney</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 2025, Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/5thTest-IND-vs-AUS-day-02.jpg?w=750" alt="India vs Australia LIVE Cricket Score, 5th Test Day 2: Follow the IND vs AUS updates from Sydney on Saturday." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>India vs Australia LIVE Cricket Score, 5th Test Day 2: Follow the IND vs AUS updates from Sydney on Saturday.</figcaption><p>On Day 2 of the 5th Test in Sydney, Mohammed Siraj and Prasidh Krishna excelled with the ball, taking three wickets each to restrict Australia to 181 runs at Tea, giving India a lead in the first innings.</p><ul><li>Australia scored 181 runs by Tea on Day 2.</li><li>India had a total score of 185 runs in their first innings.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah picked up two wickets, but was taken to the hospital for scans.</li><li>Beau Webster scored 50 runs for Australia.</li><li>The match faced off-field tensions due to Rohit Sharma's omission from the squad.</li></ul><blockquote>“Selectors told Rohit Sharma they were looking beyond him after BGT.”</blockquote><p>The match continues with India leading by 52 runs, showcasing an interesting contest as both teams aim to gain the upper hand in this critical Test.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/ind-vs-aus-5th-test-day-2-live-score-india-vs-australia-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-sydney-cricket-ground-9758758/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/ind-vs-aus-5th-test-day-2-live-score-india-vs-australia-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-sydney-cricket-ground-9758758/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 04:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US surgeon Vivek Murthy says alcohol increases risk of 7 types of cancers; urges warning on labels | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Surgeon General Urges Cancer Warnings on Alcohol Labels</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>U.S. Surgeon General Vivek Murthy has highlighted the link between alcohol consumption and the increased risk of at least seven types of cancer, calling for warning labels on alcoholic beverages.</p><ul><li>Alcohol consumption increases the risk of breast, colon, and liver cancer, among others.</li><li>Surgeon General emphasizes that most consumers are unaware of these risks.</li><li>Alcohol is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the U.S.</li><li>Currently, alcohol is responsible for 100,000 cancer cases and 20,000 cancer deaths annually.</li><li>Increased alcohol consumption leads to about five additional women and three more men developing cancer per 100.</li></ul><blockquote>"Alcohol consumption is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the United States, after tobacco and obesity." - Vivek Murthy</blockquote><p>The Surgeon General's advisory suggests that re-evaluating alcohol consumption guidelines could help individuals make informed decisions regarding drinking.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/health/us-surgeon-vivek-murthy-says-alcohol-increases-risk-of-7-types-of-cancers-urges-warning-on-labels-11735962782664.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/health/us-surgeon-vivek-murthy-says-alcohol-increases-risk-of-7-types-of-cancers-urges-warning-on-labels-11735962782664.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 04:05:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia LIVE Score, 5th Test Day 2: IND race ahead with Reddy double strike despite Bumrah injury - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia LIVE Score, 5th Test Day 2</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>January 4, 2025 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/Australia-India-Cricket-41_1735961860507_1735961907015.jpg" alt="Nitish Kumar Reddy's double strike brought Australia down to their last two wickets." title="Nitish Kumar Reddy's double strike brought Australia down to their last two wickets." loading="lazy" decoding="async" /><figcaption>Nitish Kumar Reddy's double strike brought Australia down to their last two wickets.</figcaption></div><p>India has taken a narrow 4-run lead after Australia were all out for 181, despite a critical injury setback for Indian captain Jasprit Bumrah.</p><ul><li>India leads by 4 runs after Australia all out for 181.</li><li>Nitish Kumar Reddy took Australia’s last two wickets in consecutive balls.</li><li>Prasidh Krishna and Mohammed Siraj both claimed three wickets each.</li><li>Beau Webster scored a half-century on his Test debut.</li><li>Bumrah left the field for medical scans after bowling just one over.</li></ul><blockquote>“Jasprit Bumrah was spotted leaving the SCG for scans; he left the field after bowling just one over.”</blockquote><p>This match holds significant implications, with Australia seeking their first Border-Gavaskar Trophy win in over a decade and India aiming for a place in the World Test Championship finals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-live-score-5th-test-day-2-ind-vs-aus-border-gavaskar-trophy-latest-scorecard-updates-sydney-101735920515163.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-live-score-5th-test-day-2-ind-vs-aus-border-gavaskar-trophy-latest-scorecard-updates-sydney-101735920515163.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 03:43:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indo Farm Equipment IPO Allotment Status: Is It Out Yet? Steps To Check Allotment Status Online, Check GMP - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indo Farm Equipment IPO Allotment Status: Is It Out Yet? Steps To Check Allotment Status Online, Check GMP</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 04, 2025, 14:39 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Indo Farm Equipment IPO." title="Indo Farm Equipment IPO."><figcaption>Indo Farm Equipment IPO.</figcaption></figure><p>The allotment of Indo Farm Equipment IPO is highly anticipated, with a heavy subscription rate causing a delay in the finalization. The shares are expected to show a strong listing while the grey market price indicates a significant premium.</p><ul><li>Indo Farm Equipment Ltd's IPO was heavily subscribed, receiving 227.67 times in total, with different subscription rates across categories.</li><li>The grey market premium (GMP) currently stands at 46.05%, suggesting a strong listing on January 7.</li><li>Investors can check their allotment status via the BSE and NSE websites or on Mas Services Ltd's portal.</li><li>The IPO consists of a fresh issue of 86 lakh equity shares and an Offer-for-Sale of 35 lakh equity shares.</li></ul><blockquote>“Status will be available on January 4, 2025” - Mas Services Ltd.</blockquote><p>The IPO of Indo Farm Equipment Ltd, a company involved in manufacturing agricultural equipment, indicates strong investor interest and could lead to a significant market capitalisation upon listing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-allotment-status-is-it-out-yet-steps-to-check-allotment-status-online-check-gmp-9176738.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/ipo/indo-farm-equipment-ipo-allotment-status-is-it-out-yet-steps-to-check-allotment-status-online-check-gmp-9176738.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 03:39:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India monitoring reports of HMPV spread in China, no cause for panic: Health ministry - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Monitoring HMPV Spread in China: Health Ministry Assures No Panic Required</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="India Health Ministry" width="600" height="400">
<figcaption>Health Ministry officials assure no immediate threat from HMPV.</figcaption>
<p>The Indian government is closely monitoring reports of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) detected in China but assures the public there is no cause for panic.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Health Ministry stated it is aware of the rise in HMPV cases in China.</li>
  <li>Health officials recommend vigilance and adherence to health protocols but see no immediate threat to India.</li>
  <li>The ministry is in contact with health authorities globally for updates and guidance.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“At this moment, we do not foresee a crisis; our healthcare system is prepared to handle any potential cases.” - Health Ministry Spokesperson</blockquote>
<p>The government will continue to monitor the situation and keep the public informed with timely updates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/kolkata/india-monitoring-reports-of-hmpv-spread-in-china-no-cause-for-panic-health-ministry/articleshow/116931284.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/kolkata/india-monitoring-reports-of-hmpv-spread-in-china-no-cause-for-panic-health-ministry/articleshow/116931284.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 03:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli Leads India, Worrying Visuals Show Jasprit Bumrah Leaving For Hospital Due To... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Leaves Match for Hospital After Injury Scare</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 4, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: NDTV</strong></p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/r29em0qo_jasprit-bumrah-ambulance_625x300_04_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Jasprit Bumrah Leaves for Hospital" />
<figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah leaving Sydney stadium for precautionary scans.</figcaption>
<p>India faced a significant setback as pace spearhead Jasprit Bumrah left the Sydney stadium for scans after experiencing discomfort during the fifth Test against Australia.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bumrah felt discomfort after bowling one over post-lunch.</li>
  <li>He has taken 32 wickets in the series so far, with figures of 2/33 in the current match.</li>
  <li>Virat Kohli is leading the team in Bumrah's absence.</li>
  <li>Bumrah left the field after consulting with Kohli and was seen leaving in a vehicle.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Humare ladke jab tak shaant hain tab tak shaant hain. Agar aap ungli kar rahe ho, tab thodi na koi shaant baithega.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote>
<p>This incident raises concerns about Bumrah's injury and its potential impact on the Indian team's performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/video-jasprit-bumrah-out-of-5th-test-worrying-visuals-from-sydney-go-viral-7396115</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/video-jasprit-bumrah-out-of-5th-test-worrying-visuals-from-sydney-go-viral-7396115</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 03:26:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma To Retire After India vs Australia Series? Star Says: "I Am Father Of 2..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQWXlVRThlNW5vRVlWMWp1ZksyZU9vYW5ESUZSVFFSWGY5bklLMWU5S3RZMHBrY1hmVlZDN3phY2dseklIcWR2Zl9HWDJraUlBRm8tOGZyUF85U2pMYV9FY0xmNEppLVNkNzRuZXVIS2NqTmdhXzlrZ1VoNVp4VllLaVdTN2RIX0VxY0lBZmVKOHlFWWgzU1g5ZXNSQV9mMWNHemNoREFNRVgyZnJldGVYMHNiOW54Z0ZaOUdyUTNsQndNRmlaclFodE5lcUd5d2lzSHl3SjZiQmZTLXZUVXVsa0tJeXVVbklCTlFjclpGMGxCdTAzNTdReg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQWXlVRThlNW5vRVlWMWp1ZksyZU9vYW5ESUZSVFFSWGY5bklLMWU5S3RZMHBrY1hmVlZDN3phY2dseklIcWR2Zl9HWDJraUlBRm8tOGZyUF85U2pMYV9FY0xmNEppLVNkNzRuZXVIS2NqTmdhXzlrZ1VoNVp4VllLaVdTN2RIX0VxY0lBZmVKOHlFWWgzU1g5ZXNSQV9mMWNHemNoREFNRVgyZnJldGVYMHNiOW54Z0ZaOUdyUTNsQndNRmlaclFodE5lcUd5d2lzSHl3SjZiQmZTLXZUVXVsa0tJeXVVbklCTlFjclpGMGxCdTAzNTdReg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 03:18:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah leaves the Sydney Cricket Ground with team doctor - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Leaves Sydney Cricket Ground with Team Doctor</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Saturday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116930957,imgsize-25488,width-400,resizemode-4/116930957.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah leaves the Sydney Cricket Ground with team doctor" title="Jasprit Bumrah (Video grab)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah (Video grab)</figcaption><p>Jasprit Bumrah left the Sydney Cricket Ground (SCG) during a match against Australia after a short bowling spell. Initial reports suggest that he is being taken for scans although there is no official confirmation from the Indian team yet.</p><ul><li>Bumrah took a total of 32 wickets in Australia, breaking the previous record held by Bishan Singh Bedi.</li><li>He bowled a four-over spell in the morning session and has been the key player for India in this series.</li><li>His quick departure after bowling just one over post-lunch raised concerns about his fitness.</li></ul><blockquote>“India would hope there is nothing serious because he has been their MVP this series.”</blockquote><p>This incident raises questions about Bumrah's fitness as he has been crucial for India's performance, and his absence would be felt significantly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-leaves-the-sydney-cricket-ground-with-team-doctor/articleshow/116930962.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-leaves-the-sydney-cricket-ground-with-team-doctor/articleshow/116930962.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 03:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 5th Test Day 2 LIVE Score: Injury scare for Bumrah, good start for AUS after Lunch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxPWlNwYXVhRnowTjl6ZDdnQlp2R2pGRzdDRFN1NHYxNEVqR2JwV0ItWXk2b0N0RzMxZi1GampGdXpwUm9ZM0VwVFZJMUlqdHQtLUpTM2ROR0ZfLXJpNVhzZVpIRlByXzU0YzJPMnM0c1VTYnQ3N1dNT2xsMlRobElKUUJXQkphYnRiZWFVV0t0dmNNMGs1RGZoazJKUHZLRVJfanJtQU1iNFFvcFI3M0dIUVVFdVl5NlZiQ2xtcldnMjBxTGpUM2tCNFNTbkthY2xkVXVxS3hvQWRUdnE3RlZZamlVQk4ySHhsUzJLLTVVXzU5c1ZhOGdhbi1BRjVEaVnSAYQCQVVfeXFMTlF3UHhGT3hBS0ZYczhaRDJKNHVEcnU4c2lCQ3RYdnVKYjVOdjljU3c3aWgzRTVSZ2VkaVNBWThjdXR0UXVSclY3YXhVSENYTmlrNkNyS09EbnJZOUVtMnMtV3JmeE9MSUZuR1dhcnpxNDc1XzVITXd4UVJpSGd2ZkpWdzVZYVkyNW5GYW1rX0hvVEVaMlRkdUcxSGdDY3dVTjNBbUtVZDhhcWhmMGpmNUdfU3RSdTg0RW5NQUk5TndoQkFPNEowVTNHUFNrZ0lPaW0zR0d6b0VwUFhfM01SZVpVbWEzRHh0c052QXZxNW00eHV0c1VRbjhnNUZfZFVpQ0RVMGM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxPWlNwYXVhRnowTjl6ZDdnQlp2R2pGRzdDRFN1NHYxNEVqR2JwV0ItWXk2b0N0RzMxZi1GampGdXpwUm9ZM0VwVFZJMUlqdHQtLUpTM2ROR0ZfLXJpNVhzZVpIRlByXzU0YzJPMnM0c1VTYnQ3N1dNT2xsMlRobElKUUJXQkphYnRiZWFVV0t0dmNNMGs1RGZoazJKUHZLRVJfanJtQU1iNFFvcFI3M0dIUVVFdVl5NlZiQ2xtcldnMjBxTGpUM2tCNFNTbkthY2xkVXVxS3hvQWRUdnE3RlZZamlVQk4ySHhsUzJLLTVVXzU5c1ZhOGdhbi1BRjVEaVnSAYQCQVVfeXFMTlF3UHhGT3hBS0ZYczhaRDJKNHVEcnU4c2lCQ3RYdnVKYjVOdjljU3c3aWgzRTVSZ2VkaVNBWThjdXR0UXVSclY3YXhVSENYTmlrNkNyS09EbnJZOUVtMnMtV3JmeE9MSUZuR1dhcnpxNDc1XzVITXd4UVJpSGd2ZkpWdzVZYVkyNW5GYW1rX0hvVEVaMlRkdUcxSGdDY3dVTjNBbUtVZDhhcWhmMGpmNUdfU3RSdTg0RW5NQUk5TndoQkFPNEowVTNHUFNrZ0lPaW0zR0d6b0VwUFhfM01SZVpVbWEzRHh0c052QXZxNW00eHV0c1VRbjhnNUZfZFVpQ0RVMGM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 02:47:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Closely monitoring influenza cases in India, no need to be alarmed: Govt on HMPV outbreak in China - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Monitoring Influenza Cases: No Alarm Needed Over HMPV in China</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/china-2025-virus.jpg?w=640" alt="hmpv, china virus, Human Metapneumovirus" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>There is reportedly no substantial increase in the December 2024 data on respiratory outbreaks in India. (File Photo)</figcaption><p>The National Centre for Disease Control (NCDC) is closely monitoring respiratory and seasonal influenza cases in India, amidst reports of an outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in China. Official sources have stated that there is no need for alarm.</p><ul><li>NCDC is in touch with international agencies regarding the HMPV outbreak.</li><li>There is no substantial increase in respiratory outbreak data for December 2024 in India.</li><li>DGHS Dr. Atul Goel likened HMPV to common cold viruses.</li><li>Precautions advised include respiratory etiquette and avoiding contact if symptomatic.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is nothing to be alarmed about the present situation,” - Dr. Atul Goel</blockquote><p>As winter increases the outbreak of respiratory infections, hospitals are prepared with necessary supplies and beds. General precautions for respiratory infections are recommended.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/influenza-cases-india-alarmed-govt-hmpv-outbreak-china-9759209/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/influenza-cases-india-alarmed-govt-hmpv-outbreak-china-9759209/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 02:47:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai Bachchan says 'chala chala' adorably in Marathi, wishes 'Happy New Year', Abhishek Bachchan - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan says 'chala chala' adorably in Marathi, wishes 'Happy New Year', Abhishek Bachchan wins the internet as a protective husband, father - WATCH VIDEO</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116930586,imgsize-44444,width-400,resizemode-4/116930586.jpg" alt="Aishwarya Rai Bachchan says 'chala chala' adorably in Marathi, wishes 'Happy New Year', Abhishek Bachchan wins the internet as a protective husband, father - WATCH VIDEO">
<figcaption>Aishwarya Rai Bachchan and Abhishek Bachchan on their way to the car after returning from holiday.</figcaption>
<p>Abhishek and Aishwarya Rai Bachchan have addressed rumors about their marriage while celebrating the New Year with their daughter. The couple has shared a recent public appearance, dispelling the divorce rumors circulating about them.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The couple was not seen at a recent wedding, sparking speculation about their relationship.</li>
  <li>They attended a wedding together and their daughter Aaradhya's school function to combat narratives of separation.</li>
  <li>Returning from a New Year holiday, they engaged with photographers, with Aishwarya adorably saying 'Chala Chala' in Marathi.</li>
  <li>Abhishek played a protective role, ensuring both Aishwarya and Aaradhya were safe as they entered their car.</li>
  <li>Abhishek's recent work includes acclaimed performance in 'I Want To Talk' and upcoming roles in 'Housefull 5' and 'King'.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Chala Chala” - Aishwarya Rai Bachchan, wishing the paparazzi a Happy New Year.</blockquote>
<p>The couple seems unaffected by rumors, presenting a united front for their daughter and public, further cementing their family image.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aishwarya-rai-bachchan-says-chala-chala-adorably-in-marathi-wishes-happy-new-year-abhishek-bachchan-wins-the-internet-as-a-protective-husband-father-watch-video/articleshow/116930578.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/aishwarya-rai-bachchan-says-chala-chala-adorably-in-marathi-wishes-happy-new-year-abhishek-bachchan-wins-the-internet-as-a-protective-husband-father-watch-video/articleshow/116930578.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 02:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parental Consent Needed For Children To Join Social Media, Gaming Platforms : Proposal In Draft Digital... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_AFBVV95cUxNWlI2X0xsNUFMYXMwUnNfTkxNWnRrY2NuSmZWVWh0N3JfUHNYNDBGTUY0RFFiNm9rX3Q3TDV3VGRvbkZkSk1Uem93TjR3M0R5dng3YlFjcXo0cFlxNXI3M3hTdW1PU2VldnZzcW5aZDVzYVRfN1ZYZDVLVkxCekd1VFItenlZX3lKYm5LZFdwQWJlLUh5MC02N3hZNGlodzJsQ0pBcEkxaExaT1Q4Y2NncUx5R0VXUTdjYnlWdEQtNlZ1SURjaDZiY2NvV0R6RV8zSzZocHI1cm0wN0t6b3N0ckZ6WnhWRFNEQm00RXpLRDNuS2U2N1ZUT0ZKRjjSAYICQVVfeXFMUHlvUVZfUElGTmlHS3RYNTBjSWN3cVVMNHVIaV92UjZ5WEU3SHJxUTVKX1E2VXRFSi1IOWpRcUlhTlJJRThwSThZVlo3cDZjMnZybFFiMEVBX3NiZmZfM05XNHJIczZ4WU1iR1BGOEttdlNxd1paSm9XcnZta0s4UFloa1ZYeHpYQ05PZ2dxcUNmZS1xa2RwYk5YeS1ya1ZIRGdjcFduVFNDREVkZnAyUWFmYXJVd2owQ2hLRzNfZlItYWRCcDdjM3hyTXAyR2VCNVE4ZmhsVE5td1BsTXZpeGJhV1lhUEhmT0dIQUFIT3hBSVFMMURZTHNpSjNyR1BSSHF3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_AFBVV95cUxNWlI2X0xsNUFMYXMwUnNfTkxNWnRrY2NuSmZWVWh0N3JfUHNYNDBGTUY0RFFiNm9rX3Q3TDV3VGRvbkZkSk1Uem93TjR3M0R5dng3YlFjcXo0cFlxNXI3M3hTdW1PU2VldnZzcW5aZDVzYVRfN1ZYZDVLVkxCekd1VFItenlZX3lKYm5LZFdwQWJlLUh5MC02N3hZNGlodzJsQ0pBcEkxaExaT1Q4Y2NncUx5R0VXUTdjYnlWdEQtNlZ1SURjaDZiY2NvV0R6RV8zSzZocHI1cm0wN0t6b3N0ckZ6WnhWRFNEQm00RXpLRDNuS2U2N1ZUT0ZKRjjSAYICQVVfeXFMUHlvUVZfUElGTmlHS3RYNTBjSWN3cVVMNHVIaV92UjZ5WEU3SHJxUTVKX1E2VXRFSi1IOWpRcUlhTlJJRThwSThZVlo3cDZjMnZybFFiMEVBX3NiZmZfM05XNHJIczZ4WU1iR1BGOEttdlNxd1paSm9XcnZta0s4UFloa1ZYeHpYQ05PZ2dxcUNmZS1xa2RwYk5YeS1ya1ZIRGdjcFduVFNDREVkZnAyUWFmYXJVd2owQ2hLRzNfZlItYWRCcDdjM3hyTXAyR2VCNVE4ZmhsVE5td1BsTXZpeGJhV1lhUEhmT0dIQUFIT3hBSVFMMURZTHNpSjNyR1BSSHF3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 02:10:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Surgeon-General Vivek Murthy wants cancer warning on alcohol: How does your drinking habit cause cancer? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Surgeon-General Vivek Murthy Wants Cancer Warning on Alcohol</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not mentioned in the article<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/drinking-vivek-murthy.jpg?w=640" alt="drinking, vivek murthy, alcohol, cancer" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>The risk for cancers of the breast, the mouth and the throat may rise with consumption of as little as one drink a day, or even less, said Dr Murthy. (File Photo/Representational)</figcaption>
<p>US Surgeon-General Vivek Murthy has called for alcoholic beverages to carry cancer warning labels, highlighting evidence that no level of alcohol consumption is safe when it comes to cancer risk.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Alcohol is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the US, following tobacco and obesity.</li>
  <li>Consumption of just one drink per day can increase the risk for several cancers including breast, mouth, and throat.</li>
  <li>Alcohol is classified as a group 1 carcinogen by the WHO, with no safe level of consumption.</li>
  <li>Dr Murthy's report states alcohol increases the risk of at least seven types of cancer.</li>
  <li>Dr Murthy draws parallels with India's anti-smoking campaigns as a model for addressing alcohol-related harm.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Alcohol has been confirmed as a group 1 carcinogen... there is no safe level of alcohol,” - Dr Pankaj Chaturvedi</blockquote>
<p>This initiative reflects a growing recognition of the health risks associated with alcohol consumption and aims to reduce the incidence of alcohol-related cancers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/vivek-murthy-cancer-warning-alcohol-drinking-cancer-9759172/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/vivek-murthy-cancer-warning-alcohol-drinking-cancer-9759172/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 02:09:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dense fog engulfs Delhi; flight operations hit at IGI airport - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dense Fog Disrupts Flight Operations in Delhi</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 04, 2025 07:34 am IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><p>Delhi has experienced the longest period of zero visibility due to intense fog, halting flight operations at Indira Gandhi International Airport (IGI) for several hours.</p><img src='image_url_here' alt='Dense fog at Delhi Airport'><figcaption>Dense fog covers Delhi Airport affecting flight schedules.</figcaption><p>The key points regarding the fog disruption include:</p><ul><li>Record zero visibility lasting 9 hours from January 3 to January 4.</li><li>Fifteen flights diverted between 12:15 am and 1:30 am on January 4.</li><li>IndiGo and Air India reported significant delays and held operations.</li><li>Over 400 flights were delayed on January 3 due to adverse weather conditions.</li><li>CTA III compliant airplanes are less affected.</li></ul><blockquote>“Passengers are requested to contact the airline concerned for updated flight information.” - Delhi International Airport Ltd (DIAL)</blockquote><p>This weather event illustrates the challenges posed by fog to air travel, affecting hundreds of passengers and airlines over the course of several days.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/dense-fog-engulfs-delhi-flight-operations-hit-at-igi-airport/article69060262.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/dense-fog-engulfs-delhi-flight-operations-hit-at-igi-airport/article69060262.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 02:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aishwarya Rai and Abhishek Bachchan return to Mumbai together after vacation, putting all divorce rumours to rest. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgJBVV95cUxPWUFNcjBSalFFR2oxcWNZVTlsVTVJQ1hBTlhIMVYtMEZLSmd0YzhfXzFjZ0tGQ2JGR2RmdlBCOW9POXFtRHVuczZRa3MzbG1MbHQwbHFZcTA0VUVCbW5nTTlaY2NPcmdLRmxqcFFaVWZiaDV2UTlBLUljY2J2eXdyS3FxRTI1TUs5clRoWTRlQXRzZW1CWjFDRTl4UUZPZDVaZmt5SkdCOWdPUHVURVlobjIzWVplSDNBc2JZQjNXc2t3Mmx2V1U0NkZLVDBpWFFZcDdPSW9nZFIxYUwxTno2RTRBTEhHM1RqLXlHZHNVOEwwWjF3OEVGNXozb2ItazZ2VHpVV2duemgwTHF4dGFpUTg2MjZUeG1lREHSAZ8CQVVfeXFMTWd1MzVZTzIyUVlQQVdXUThOWlBhQWVxOU1saWNwMW1PU0NWZFQ5LUZDZHZzNFo0S3czT01lR1V6VGpaVmhxdzM4Q3l6ZUQxTWw0eld0WC1Fd3Y1bDNXS0pfODJKWlhvRkE5bU9qbjdTTlVLR3IxRmZ4cmNEa2J2MmpGWkZ1TDZ4c2lhSHBkTzlXOTRLSkpLVWVJWFVpX0F3TGphV3VNM2UyYWZ6UXpRam5yQTFRQmJIa1A4SkdHX2Jta1YwdnhjeGxsbGI2MWpJOGVUeWNQbmIwNTFRRmhwbFBVQ1ZNQkFYVGxleW42WkdGalJNa1hxZ2MxUHQwLVk5dWJUNExzcUxTZ1QtS0JDRWJ2RUpRMENMX2ZGSjBZMTg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgJBVV95cUxPWUFNcjBSalFFR2oxcWNZVTlsVTVJQ1hBTlhIMVYtMEZLSmd0YzhfXzFjZ0tGQ2JGR2RmdlBCOW9POXFtRHVuczZRa3MzbG1MbHQwbHFZcTA0VUVCbW5nTTlaY2NPcmdLRmxqcFFaVWZiaDV2UTlBLUljY2J2eXdyS3FxRTI1TUs5clRoWTRlQXRzZW1CWjFDRTl4UUZPZDVaZmt5SkdCOWdPUHVURVlobjIzWVplSDNBc2JZQjNXc2t3Mmx2V1U0NkZLVDBpWFFZcDdPSW9nZFIxYUwxTno2RTRBTEhHM1RqLXlHZHNVOEwwWjF3OEVGNXozb2ItazZ2VHpVV2duemgwTHF4dGFpUTg2MjZUeG1lREHSAZ8CQVVfeXFMTWd1MzVZTzIyUVlQQVdXUThOWlBhQWVxOU1saWNwMW1PU0NWZFQ5LUZDZHZzNFo0S3czT01lR1V6VGpaVmhxdzM4Q3l6ZUQxTWw0eld0WC1Fd3Y1bDNXS0pfODJKWlhvRkE5bU9qbjdTTlVLR3IxRmZ4cmNEa2J2MmpGWkZ1TDZ4c2lhSHBkTzlXOTRLSkpLVWVJWFVpX0F3TGphV3VNM2UyYWZ6UXpRam5yQTFRQmJIa1A4SkdHX2Jta1YwdnhjeGxsbGI2MWpJOGVUeWNQbmIwNTFRRmhwbFBVQ1ZNQkFYVGxleW42WkdGalJNa1hxZ2MxUHQwLVk5dWJUNExzcUxTZ1QtS0JDRWJ2RUpRMENMX2ZGSjBZMTg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 02:01:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump To Be Sentenced In Hush Money Case 10 Days Before Taking Office. Will He Go To Jail? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQUjZMWkx1TUVJRlFRMVMzXzZVZTgxUEhEZS1pS1YyenZBczV4ci05aFptbV9SM180RzBNTWx3UENCRzFIQkliZGhxQ2M3TGRsemxqWE0yTVZrNUNMMjRuRV9Rd2pXZ0d2NEpIOHBYOWg4Q29kbldlc0x6NnNzVVB2blQycjRUZE9UUldDSW14MDFFUk9Bbms1TjhiOUNHWVptbUlKUFNvYTZtX2p3QkR4alVad0lBdDdnZDM1T0w5QdIBxAFBVV95cUxPTHFvQlI1dF9nbG54eUNDYVl5NzBQenpac095bXVZV2NZYzIxM3BoS2lnTndqOU9qWVRYR0NzZGVfRG1qc1ZZT19pTExiOTUyZVF2dERaLTBiWkViRVdGcUp2cjh3RnRJMm9CMDN1dGZtb094OUxtSy0xNkw3ai1FeFE0M29QSXBEWWRHQmJudzNOTGF5U0dWc3kyaHBvXzVib0FLQzR6ZHpCMXdhSnR5YVRMVmE5aVNkdThIUmh0aW5fY2E2?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQUjZMWkx1TUVJRlFRMVMzXzZVZTgxUEhEZS1pS1YyenZBczV4ci05aFptbV9SM180RzBNTWx3UENCRzFIQkliZGhxQ2M3TGRsemxqWE0yTVZrNUNMMjRuRV9Rd2pXZ0d2NEpIOHBYOWg4Q29kbldlc0x6NnNzVVB2blQycjRUZE9UUldDSW14MDFFUk9Bbms1TjhiOUNHWVptbUlKUFNvYTZtX2p3QkR4alVad0lBdDdnZDM1T0w5QdIBxAFBVV95cUxPTHFvQlI1dF9nbG54eUNDYVl5NzBQenpac095bXVZV2NZYzIxM3BoS2lnTndqOU9qWVRYR0NzZGVfRG1qc1ZZT19pTExiOTUyZVF2dERaLTBiWkViRVdGcUp2cjh3RnRJMm9CMDN1dGZtb094OUxtSy0xNkw3ai1FeFE0M29QSXBEWWRHQmJudzNOTGF5U0dWc3kyaHBvXzVib0FLQzR6ZHpCMXdhSnR5YVRMVmE5aVNkdThIUmh0aW5fY2E2?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 01:56:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India protests China’s ‘new counties’ in the Hotan Prefecture that incorporates territory of Ladakh - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Protests China's New Counties in Hotan Prefecture Affected Ladakh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 03, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/latest-news/jsbt2d/article69059142.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Jaiswal.jpg" alt="New counties in Hotan Prefecture will have no bearing on India’s sovereignty over the area, says Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal." title="New counties in Hotan Prefecture will have no bearing on India’s sovereignty over the area, says Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal."><figcaption>New counties in Hotan Prefecture will have no bearing on India’s sovereignty over the area, says Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal. Photo: YouTube/@MEAIndia</figcaption><p>India has lodged a solemn protest with China over the formation of two counties in the Hotan Prefecture that incorporates parts of Ladakh. The Ministry of External Affairs has asserted India's position on its sovereignty over these territories.</p><ul><li>India protested against China's formation of He’an County and Hekang County in Hotan Prefecture.</li><li>Ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal emphasized India's non-acceptance of China's territorial claims.</li><li>Concerns raised over a Chinese hydro project impacting the Brahmaputra river.</li><li>The protest comes after a significant meeting between Indian and Chinese representatives regarding border tensions.</li><li>The announcement of the world's largest dam by China further complicates the situation.</li></ul><blockquote>“Creation of new counties will neither have a bearing on India’s long-standing and consistent position regarding our sovereignty over the area nor lend legitimacy to China’s illegal and forcible occupation.” - Randhir Jaiswal</blockquote><p>India will continue to monitor developments and take measures to protect its interests in the region as tensions remain high.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/weekly-media-briefing-by-the-mea-official-spokesperson-randhir-jaiswal/article69057393.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/weekly-media-briefing-by-the-mea-official-spokesperson-randhir-jaiswal/article69057393.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 01:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heavy snowfall likely in Kashmir today, IMD's thunderstorms alert for Himachal Pradesh | Weather updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Heavy snowfall likely in Kashmir today, IMD's thunderstorms alert for Himachal Pradesh</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 4, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/ANI-20250103080-0_1735949000322_1735949024716.jpg" alt="Children make their way on snow-covered road in the Gurez valley as the upper reaches of Jammu and Kashmir receives fresh snowfall, in Baramulla on Friday. (ANI)"><figcaption>Children make their way on snow-covered road in the Gurez valley as the upper reaches of Jammu and Kashmir receives fresh snowfall, in Baramulla on Friday. (ANI)</figcaption><p>The India Meteorological Department (IMD) has issued a warning of heavy snowfall in Jammu and Kashmir this weekend and thunderstorms in Himachal Pradesh from January 4 to 6.</p><ul><li>Heavy snowfall is expected in Jammu and Kashmir on January 4 and 5.</li><li>Light to moderate rainfall is forecasted in the adjoining plains.</li><li>Thunderstorms, light rainfall, and squalls are predicted in Himachal Pradesh districts.</li><li>Flight operations at Srinagar airport faced disruptions due to dense fog reducing visibility.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is an active western disturbance which lies over the western Himalayan region,” IMD scientist Naresh Kumar stated.</blockquote><p>This weather pattern is expected to affect visibility and travel plans significantly across affected regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/heavy-snowfall-likely-in-kashmir-today-imds-yellow-alert-for-himachal-pradesh-weather-updates-101735948862915.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/heavy-snowfall-likely-in-kashmir-today-imds-yellow-alert-for-himachal-pradesh-weather-updates-101735948862915.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 01:40:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 stunning images of star cluster captured by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Stunning Images of Star Cluster Captured by NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Star-cluster-1.jpg" alt="Star cluster">
<figcaption>One of the stunning images captured by NASA's equipment.</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases seven mesmerizing images of star clusters taken by NASA, highlighting their beauty and scientific significance.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Westerlund 2, a massive cluster of 3,000 stars in the stellar nursery Gum 29.</li>
    <li>Caldwell 71, an open cluster with loosely bound stars.</li>
    <li>NGC 1850, a globular cluster located in the Large Magellanic Cloud.</li>
    <li>Liller 1, a star cluster over 11 billion years old.</li>
    <li>Terzan 4, featuring hot blue stars in the center and cooler red stars on the edges.</li>
    <li>Trumpler 14, hosting some of the galaxy's most massive and luminous stars.</li>
    <li>The Arches star cluster depicted from within the Milky Way.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>This NASA image shows Westerlund 2, a massive cluster in the turbulent stellar nursery Gum 29.</blockquote>
<p>These images not only display the breathtaking beauty of the universe but also contribute to our understanding of stellar evolution and the composition of galaxies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-stunning-images-of-star-cluster-captured-by-nasa-7513029/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-stunning-images-of-star-cluster-captured-by-nasa-7513029/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 01:32:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 5th Test Day 2 LIVE Score: IND's early momentum dies out as Smith, Webster calm things down for AUS - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia 5th Test Day 2 LIVE Score: Bumrah off the field, Kohli leading IND early in 2nd session</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-63_1735956109288_1735956127334.jpg" alt="India vs Australia 5th Test Day 2 LIVE Score: Jasprit Bumrah and Mohammed Siraj got India off to a flier in the first session." title="India vs Australia 5th Test Day 2 LIVE Score: Jasprit Bumrah and Mohammed Siraj got India off to a flier in the first session."><figcaption>India vs Australia 5th Test Day 2 LIVE Score: Jasprit Bumrah and Mohammed Siraj got India off to a flier in the first session.</figcaption></div><p>The live action continues as India faces Australia in the 5th Test, with significant stakes for both teams. After losing key wickets, India aims to maintain pressure on the Australian batting lineup.</p><ul><li>India started strong, with Bumrah dismissing Labuschagne and Siraj following up with key wickets.</li><li>At Lunch, Australia was 101/5, trailing by 84 runs.</li><li>The conditions at SCG favor pace bowlers, making it a challenging day for batters.</li><li>Ongoing controversies include Rohit Sharma's absence from the squad due to form issues.</li></ul><blockquote>Rohit Sharma stated, “I am not getting runs. No guarantee that it will be the same a few months later.”</blockquote><p>This Test is crucial, as it affects future championships for both teams.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-live-score-5th-test-day-2-ind-vs-aus-border-gavaskar-trophy-latest-scorecard-updates-sydney-101735920515163.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-live-score-5th-test-day-2-ind-vs-aus-border-gavaskar-trophy-latest-scorecard-updates-sydney-101735920515163.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 01:11:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma, Gautam Gambhir, Ajit Agarkar Meeting: What Happened Before India Captain's 'Big' Decis.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxPaE54UVZkbXBYU2NLYlJUckkyQzl4SzIxdy1IZEhkNy1ValBKclU3T2xQWUtjVWFoYzBjQXBHd3M1SkdqSXJPNl82Sk5WeEhILXZZY3ZBTkYwaFVDbmZfS2RZczZqTmZScGEzU2F1QXY0ei1XaWdoTGI2RHR0Ymd1OFFCZ0pXV19OZzRyckRmU0wyaHlFVjNqekhONUUwUm8wOWFUMGh4V2tINm9HZTAzd3BJSkREMzRWTl9GYkJPbTFKWVMwNk5UUEN2OTdRVjZPTWtRQ3FCd29hSGtHUkHSAeYBQVVfeXFMTS0xTGUxVTVVeGpvN2ljdmZuYnd3RWZtc1NFMjdyclVqRmplakZVZGw3ckFNbWpWbEpOa0F0ZV9ibHA2UjVSdVBURWtvV3hqY1NlZHBnV0xPakVmSVZaajJ0cGpIMThJbEhzalpsWU10YTc1NkdsWnMxS2FQdV9PRWdMQ1FXaURqUXN6ZDBnZ0liQlBpMWNXMHB4b3kxWktELUdBbzhIci1oaW5LMXhRY1Y4b3FiOUtzY0l0YkVQVmlvUnZybG5UZlRRc05xY3VTUHR0RzM0SHRaM184S01fV2d5MkthSXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxPaE54UVZkbXBYU2NLYlJUckkyQzl4SzIxdy1IZEhkNy1ValBKclU3T2xQWUtjVWFoYzBjQXBHd3M1SkdqSXJPNl82Sk5WeEhILXZZY3ZBTkYwaFVDbmZfS2RZczZqTmZScGEzU2F1QXY0ei1XaWdoTGI2RHR0Ymd1OFFCZ0pXV19OZzRyckRmU0wyaHlFVjNqekhONUUwUm8wOWFUMGh4V2tINm9HZTAzd3BJSkREMzRWTl9GYkJPbTFKWVMwNk5UUEN2OTdRVjZPTWtRQ3FCd29hSGtHUkHSAeYBQVVfeXFMTS0xTGUxVTVVeGpvN2ljdmZuYnd3RWZtc1NFMjdyclVqRmplakZVZGw3ckFNbWpWbEpOa0F0ZV9ibHA2UjVSdVBURWtvV3hqY1NlZHBnV0xPakVmSVZaajJ0cGpIMThJbEhzalpsWU10YTc1NkdsWnMxS2FQdV9PRWdMQ1FXaURqUXN6ZDBnZ0liQlBpMWNXMHB4b3kxWktELUdBbzhIci1oaW5LMXhRY1Y4b3FiOUtzY0l0YkVQVmlvUnZybG5UZlRRc05xY3VTUHR0RzM0SHRaM184S01fV2d5MkthSXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 01:11:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who is Mike Johnson, new US House Speaker re-elected amid Republican dissent? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who is Mike Johnson, new US House Speaker re-elected amid Republican dissent?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 04, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/US-119TH-CONGRESS-BEGINS-ITS-TERM-ON-CAPITOL-HILL-201_1735950882644_1735950904806.jpg" alt="US Speaker of the House Mike Johnson holds up the gavel after being re-elected Speaker on the first day of the 119th Congress in the House Chamber of the US Capitol Building on January 3, 2025, in Washington, DC. (Getty Images via AFP)"/><figcaption>US Speaker of the House Mike Johnson holds up the gavel after being re-elected Speaker on the first day of the 119th Congress in the House Chamber of the US Capitol Building on January 3, 2025, in Washington, DC. (Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>US House Speaker Mike Johnson was reelected amid Republican dissent, securing his position with 218 votes after intense negotiations. His reelection is bolstered by support from President-elect Donald Trump.</p><ul><li>Mike Johnson narrowly overcame hard-right GOP opposition.</li><li>He represents Louisiana's 4th Congressional District and is known for his conservative views.</li><li>His leadership aligns with a broader GOP agenda focused on reducing government size.</li><li>Trump endorsed Johnson during the vote.</li><li>Johnson's previous election came after a historic removal of former Speaker Kevin McCarthy.</li></ul><blockquote>“Mike will be a Great Speaker, and our Country will be the beneficiary,” Trump posted on social media.</blockquote><p>Johnson's reelection signals ongoing divisions within the GOP but also reflects strategic party support from influential figures like Trump.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/who-is-mike-johnson-new-us-house-speaker-re-elected-amid-republican-dissent-101735949698339.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/who-is-mike-johnson-new-us-house-speaker-re-elected-amid-republican-dissent-101735949698339.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:43:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Motive behind soldier's Cybertruck suicide bombing revealed: ‘Needed to cleanse my mind…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/motive-behind-soldiers-cybertruck-suicide-bombing-revealed-needed-to-cleanse-my-mind-101735949909503.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/motive-behind-soldiers-cybertruck-suicide-bombing-revealed-needed-to-cleanse-my-mind-101735949909503.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:42:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zepto plans IPO filing by March-April; Singapore nod in for moving domicile - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AFBVV95cUxNSWRWMVhRQmZkZ0dySDY4T1VFdWdyQ1VYQ2lXYjJVa3ZxZllCSGhkR2ZNdHJ5TGE3Y0VYSUIyYWdwekF5Rk9aZWNrT1A1NTJqU1ZtLTlhR2J5a0ktclRDajM3T1ZiSWVieHFYRG53VmVoQzAtSVdrb0tob2JvcVpqc29pY1R1OThtcUt6UzJXbW5QeklLZ0hpSWtBb19hY09kbmhhSjZWc0ZDZHNrMktDcDA1T0t6ZjJ3QWJ0STV6ZV96OFo0TU9hbmZvN3RKcmduemZwZVdBdXhDdjMzOXBSc9IB5gFBVV95cUxOWDNSVk5HNnVRNWhZejlwMGNNR1dPbkVCeTBGNkUzTW93Vm5GdDBxeU5MZThiZklTd3U5bnlpN3lVUnZscTBMT3EyUTdEX1hSUFZBdW50YUpXUlA5VkwwYzZPbFhucFRZejR0ZnZ0SDREYzBRQ0JZNmJaU3hrVk1FTElPb2NrcGNlQzFzTlhEWjlCdXNNNkZoVjY2N1FuMDNBUWlHc2FLY1NUbW5HVFBUZWRDaFhhNFRuTVZxNWZGZS1BLVlKWGRqOHRlcEpoNVp5RjUxOFhfckRlWE1jbFNTUDBzYjRzQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AFBVV95cUxNSWRWMVhRQmZkZ0dySDY4T1VFdWdyQ1VYQ2lXYjJVa3ZxZllCSGhkR2ZNdHJ5TGE3Y0VYSUIyYWdwekF5Rk9aZWNrT1A1NTJqU1ZtLTlhR2J5a0ktclRDajM3T1ZiSWVieHFYRG53VmVoQzAtSVdrb0tob2JvcVpqc29pY1R1OThtcUt6UzJXbW5QeklLZ0hpSWtBb19hY09kbmhhSjZWc0ZDZHNrMktDcDA1T0t6ZjJ3QWJ0STV6ZV96OFo0TU9hbmZvN3RKcmduemZwZVdBdXhDdjMzOXBSc9IB5gFBVV95cUxOWDNSVk5HNnVRNWhZejlwMGNNR1dPbkVCeTBGNkUzTW93Vm5GdDBxeU5MZThiZklTd3U5bnlpN3lVUnZscTBMT3EyUTdEX1hSUFZBdW50YUpXUlA5VkwwYzZPbFhucFRZejR0ZnZ0SDREYzBRQ0JZNmJaU3hrVk1FTElPb2NrcGNlQzFzTlhEWjlCdXNNNkZoVjY2N1FuMDNBUWlHc2FLY1NUbW5HVFBUZWRDaFhhNFRuTVZxNWZGZS1BLVlKWGRqOHRlcEpoNVp5RjUxOFhfckRlWE1jbFNTUDBzYjRzQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump's hush money case sentencing set for January 10 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump's Hush Money Case Sentencing Set for January 10</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2024</p> <p><strong>Source:</strong> Unspecified News Source</p> <p>This article discusses the upcoming sentencing date for Donald Trump's hush money case, shedding light on the implications and public reactions surrounding this significant legal proceeding.</p> <ul> <li>Donald Trump's sentencing for his hush money case is scheduled for January 10, 2024.</li> <li>The case relates to payments made during the 2016 presidential campaign to silence allegations of past conduct.</li> <li>This event continues to fuel discussions around Trump's legal battles and their influence on his political ambitions.</li> </ul> <blockquote>"This case raises important questions about campaign finance and the legal boundaries of political conduct."</blockquote> <p>This upcoming sentencing is expected to capture significant public and media attention, reflecting ongoing tensions in the political landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trumps-hush-money-case-sentencing-set-for-january-10/articleshow/116929294.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trumps-hush-money-case-sentencing-set-for-january-10/articleshow/116929294.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>