<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:23:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:23:11 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space-Comm Expo reveals 2025 space industry trends and challenges - BroadcastProME.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQbXpkcjVNTjNqeFY1Q19QV0QtcVhsYVFJcmxfQnFzWGNDeC1wNUFuS2M1T2JRUVktcGNTRjdPOTRIb3JwdzFXMF9KN2RSWnpmdmk0NndnOEp2YllPZGVrbmNFNWFwVUVLTUMzVGJSb0ZLM2pyMVMyYldTa21RUy1zYXExOEZWZHlIUzdZaEVHRjBZenE1REZ5SVd6R0VuMnRCTDlQV3A5UHpobncyUGZaSlhn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQbXpkcjVNTjNqeFY1Q19QV0QtcVhsYVFJcmxfQnFzWGNDeC1wNUFuS2M1T2JRUVktcGNTRjdPOTRIb3JwdzFXMF9KN2RSWnpmdmk0NndnOEp2YllPZGVrbmNFNWFwVUVLTUMzVGJSb0ZLM2pyMVMyYldTa21RUy1zYXExOEZWZHlIUzdZaEVHRjBZenE1REZ5SVd6R0VuMnRCTDlQV3A5UHpobncyUGZaSlhn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First meteor shower of 2025 is coming. How to catch the Quadrantids - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Meteor Shower of 2025: How to Catch the Quadrantids</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/quadrantid-meteor-shower-025954468-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=xLQw_C3PeEHcSzbP7va4U5cJuv8IDuA9&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Quadrantid meteor shower" title="These meteors usually don’t have long trains, but the heads may appear as bright fireballs. (Photo: Getty)" height="388"><figcaption>These meteors usually don’t have long trains, but the heads may appear as bright fireballs. (Photo: Getty)</figcaption><p>As the new year unfolds, stargazers are in for a treat with the Quadrantid meteor shower, which peaks on January 3-4, 2025. This celestial event marks the first significant meteor shower of the year, offering a dazzling display of fireballs streaking across the night sky.</p><ul><li>The Quadrantids are a unique meteor shower, originating from the asteroid 2003 EH1.</li><li>They peak at 60 to 120 meteors per hour under ideal conditions.</li><li>The meteor shower is visible particularly between 3:00 AM and 5:00 AM local time.</li><li>Quadrantids typically do not leave long trails but can be bright fireballs.</li><li>The meteor shower will remain active until January 16, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>Nasa's William Cooke notes that while Quadrantids typically do not leave long trails, their heads can appear as bright fireballs.</blockquote><p>Finding a dark location away from city lights is essential for optimal viewing. Minimal moonlight interference offers an excellent opportunity for celestial enthusiasts to enjoy this spectacular event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/quadrantid-meteor-shower-is-coming-when-and-where-to-watch-them-2658508-2025-01-02</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/quadrantid-meteor-shower-is-coming-when-and-where-to-watch-them-2658508-2025-01-02</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:01:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israeli airstrike kills at least 10 in southern Gaza, medics say - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israeli Airstrike Kills 10 in Southern Gaza, Medics Report</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><img src="https://www.reutersagency.com/en/licensereuterscontent/?utm_medium=rcom-article-media&utm_campaign=rcom-rcp-lead" alt="Palestinian child next to damage in tent camp"><figcaption>A Palestinian child looks on next to damage at a tent camp sheltering displaced people, following an Israeli strike, amid the Israel-Hamas conflict, in Al-Mawasi area, Khan Younis.</figcaption><p>The early morning airstrike killed at least 10 Palestinians, including women and children, in a tent encampment intended for displaced families in southern Gaza.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred in Al-Mawasi, a designated humanitarian area in Khan Younis.</li><li>Fifteen additional individuals suffered injuries in the strike.</li><li>Notable figures, including two police department officials, were among the casualties.</li><li>Israel's military has not provided an immediate comment regarding the attack.</li><li>Since the outbreak of war, over 45,500 Palestinians have been reported killed according to health officials in Gaza.</li></ul><blockquote>“Most of Gaza's 2.3 million people have been displaced, and much of the tiny coastal strip is in ruins.”</blockquote><p>This latest airstrike underscores the ongoing humanitarian crisis and violence in the Gaza Strip, where civilian casualties continue to rise significantly amid the conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-airstrike-kills-least-10-southern-gaza-medics-say-2025-01-02/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-airstrike-kills-least-10-southern-gaza-medics-say-2025-01-02/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bajaj Finance shares jump over 5% as Citi maintains 'Buy' on Q3 optimism, sees up to 17% upside for stock - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bajaj Finance shares jump over 5% as Citi maintains 'Buy' on Q3 optimism, sees up to 17% upside for stock</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/10/20241001115250_bf.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Bajaj Finance shares jump 5% as Citi maintains 'Buy' on Q3 optimism, sees up to 17% upside for stock" title="Bajaj Finance shares jump 5% as Citi maintains 'Buy' on Q3 optimism, sees up to 17% upside for stock" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>Bajaj Finance shares jump 5% as Citi maintains 'Buy' on Q3 optimism, sees up to 17% upside for stock</figcaption>
<p>Bajaj Finance share price surged over 5 percent in Thursday's trade after analysts at the brokerage Citi reiterated its 'Buy' rating on the stock. The stock climbed to an intraday high of Rs 7,306.05, marking a 5.34 percent gain from its previous close.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Citi has set a price target of Rs 8,150 for Bajaj Finance, indicating a potential upside of 17.51 percent from Wednesday's closing price.</li>
  <li>The brokerage highlighted expectations of loan growth stability and a positive bias in net interest margins.</li>
  <li>Key support is coming from segments like mortgage financing and sales financing.</li>
  <li>A marginal rise in credit costs is estimated between 2.2 to 2.5 percent.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Key support is coming from segments like mortgage financing, sales financing, and new business ventures," Citi noted in its report.</blockquote>
<p>This positive movement in Bajaj Finance shares aligns with the overall rise in the finance and NBFC sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/bajaj-finance-shares-jump-over-5pc-as-citi-maintains-buy-on-q3-optimism-sees-up-to-17pc-upside-for-stock-12901974.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/markets/bajaj-finance-shares-jump-over-5pc-as-citi-maintains-buy-on-q3-optimism-sees-up-to-17pc-upside-for-stock-12901974.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:30:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's dressing room confidentiality breach an unexpected storm, 'leak' reeks of Chappell-Ganguly, Kohli-Kumble feuds - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Dressing Room Confidentiality Breach: A Storm of Controversy</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-26_1735802469820_1735802490107.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah, Rohit Sharma, and Gautam Gambhir in controversy" title="Jasprit Bumrah, Rohit Sharma, and Gautam Gambhir in controversy">
<figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah (L), Rohit Sharma (C) and Gautam Gambhir (R) find themselves in the middle of a controversy at a time when India have a Test match to win(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>In an unexpected turn of events, leaks from within the Indian cricket team following a disappointing defeat against Australia have raised concerns about the sanctity of the dressing room. This breach of confidentiality has drawn parallels to past controversies involving high-profile figures in Indian cricket.</p>
<ul>
<li>The dressing room is traditionally a private space for players to express themselves freely.</li>
<li>Recent alleged leaks come just before a crucial Test match, highlighting the timing's unfortunate nature.</li>
<li>Historical precedents show detrimental effects of such leaks on team dynamics and morale.</li>
<li>The head coach has publicly addressed the situation, emphasizing the need for honesty and integrity among players.</li>
<li>Drawing from past resilience, the team aims to overcome adversity and focus on performance.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Those are just reports. That's not the truth... Honesty is extremely important if you want to go on and achieve some great things.” - Head Coach Gautam Gambhir</blockquote>
<p>This situation underscores the challenges faced by the team but also serves as a reminder of their capacity to rally together and perform against the odds.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/indias-dressing-room-confidentiality-breech-an-unexpected-storm-leak-reeks-of-chappell-ganguly-kohli-kumble-feuds-101735802356404.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/indias-dressing-room-confidentiality-breech-an-unexpected-storm-leak-reeks-of-chappell-ganguly-kohli-kumble-feuds-101735802356404.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:28:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[vivo T3x 5G is Now Available at an Attractive New Price - vivo Newsroom India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPNjI5eEdPcDl5TE1MZnJsUy05WjNQaE5pUGxrd196TzJwMlN5VjBadzJZYVpIeVN2WW9uTVFHWFhsWFRxMDgwb0ZSeEVFUWc5LWZ0SHI2QlNXYmM3ZFhtazdRM3RBRVE0SXBpdUlRY25hSTFWc2hsUTdYOXF2bHdqN1pZcVBxYUlBNURXN3k2N2V4VnBHbFlXWUZR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPNjI5eEdPcDl5TE1MZnJsUy05WjNQaE5pUGxrd196TzJwMlN5VjBadzJZYVpIeVN2WW9uTVFHWFhsWFRxMDgwb0ZSeEVFUWc5LWZ0SHI2QlNXYmM3ZFhtazdRM3RBRVE0SXBpdUlRY25hSTFWc2hsUTdYOXF2bHdqN1pZcVBxYUlBNURXN3k2N2V4VnBHbFlXWUZR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:54:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gambhir non-committal on Rohit Sharma's selection for SCG Test - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gambhir Non-Committal on Rohit Sharma's Selection for SCG Test</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Thu, Jan 2, 2025, 06:52 AM<br><strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p><img height="396" width="595" alt="Bumrah will lead India if regular skipper Rohit is dropped." title="Bumrah will lead India if regular skipper Rohit is dropped." src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c594943/bumrah-will-lead-india-if-regu.jpg" itemprop="contentUrl"><figcaption>Bumrah will lead India if regular skipper Rohit is dropped. © Getty</figcaption><p>Amidst speculation, India's head coach Gautam Gambhir did not confirm Rohit Sharma's inclusion in the final Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy series in Sydney. Rohit has struggled significantly in the longest format since October 2023, raising questions regarding his current form.</p><ul><li>Gautam Gambhir suggests that everything is fine with Rohit despite his absence from media duties.</li><li>Rohit has averaged just 11.69 over his last seven Tests, with only 31 runs across six innings on the current tour.</li><li>Gambhir emphasized the team's need for a balance between aggression and restraint in batting.</li><li>Confidence remains high in the dressing room to retain the Border-Gavaskar Trophy despite recent losses.</li></ul><blockquote>“Extremely, extremely confident [of winning]. You know, we've got the skill set. We've got the individuals.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>With ongoing debates about team composition and performance expectations, Gambhir remains committed to focusing on team needs rather than individual performances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132975/gambhir-non-committal-on-rohit-sharmas-selection-for-scg-test</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132975/gambhir-non-committal-on-rohit-sharmas-selection-for-scg-test</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:52:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fans call Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Diljit Dosanjh’s ‘memorable meeting’ the ‘first unexpected col - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fans call PM Modi and Diljit Dosanjh’s meeting the ‘first unexpected collaboration of 2025’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116876091,imgsize-57502,width-400,resizemode-4/116876091.jpg" alt="PM Modi and Diljit Dosanjh’s meeting"><figcaption>Prime Minister Modi and Diljit Dosanjh during their meeting.</figcaption><p>The New Year dawned with an unexpected yet memorable meeting between Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and global icon Diljit Dosanjh, sparking excitement on social media.</p><ul><li>Diljit Dosanjh celebrated the start of 2025 with a meeting with PM Modi.</li><li>The meeting was shared on social media, highlighting their warm interaction.</li><li>PM Modi praised Diljit, emphasizing the pride of seeing talent from small beginnings shine globally.</li><li>Diljit expressed his realization of India's greatness through his travels.</li><li>The joint post received an enthusiastic response, with fans dubbing it the 'first unexpected collaboration of 2025.'</li></ul><blockquote>“When a boy from a small village in 'Hindustan' shines on the global stage, it feels amazing.” - PM Modi</blockquote><blockquote>“A fantastic start to 2025. A very memorable meeting with PM @narendramodi Ji.” - Diljit Dosanjh</blockquote><p>This heartwarming interaction highlights the blend of music, culture, and the importance of recognizing the human connections behind public figures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/music/news/fans-call-prime-minister-narendra-modi-and-diljit-dosanjhs-memorable-meeting-the-first-unexpected-collaboration-of-2025/articleshow/116876001.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/music/news/fans-call-prime-minister-narendra-modi-and-diljit-dosanjhs-memorable-meeting-the-first-unexpected-collaboration-of-2025/articleshow/116876001.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Norovirus outbreak in the US: Know all about symptoms, causes and treatment of this winter vomiting disease - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxNaGlrVUtrcTFLdjJMOUFtTzc2cUxKS0lPT0Z0QURTWnB6WVlaaGMwZXhudnZaU05rX0xJM3ZLNHRMLUVfTng1Qk04S1BJQ1ppc2pBalFLWkZCWEduaE9jSEl1ejhDelYwdV9GLWlZM2xNbzh1T0hyTF9VVWZUREZqVlNtOWk1TUtkdVdiejR0QzN5anpnaFF0R3FrMHhZZWxCV1hSREEzN3ktb20yYjVSNWlPb0NYQjQ2aXJPTzFjaTNKM0VMbEhvTnFBYXg2ekJkNXVZa0ttX25ZUTBjay0zUzhCUjJPd1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxNaGlrVUtrcTFLdjJMOUFtTzc2cUxKS0lPT0Z0QURTWnB6WVlaaGMwZXhudnZaU05rX0xJM3ZLNHRMLUVfTng1Qk04S1BJQ1ppc2pBalFLWkZCWEduaE9jSEl1ejhDelYwdV9GLWlZM2xNbzh1T0hyTF9VVWZUREZqVlNtOWk1TUtkdVdiejR0QzN5anpnaFF0R3FrMHhZZWxCV1hSREEzN3ktb20yYjVSNWlPb0NYQjQ2aXJPTzFjaTNKM0VMbEhvTnFBYXg2ekJkNXVZa0ttX25ZUTBjay0zUzhCUjJPd1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:40:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poco X7 Pro Iron Man Edition's launch date and design revealed - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxObVozMnFMMkVicTlTV19EQ3FHNGJ4R2tGZE5hdVRrSEJFT09ma01GZ2xuNDhUNU8yZzczRXdhSXhoR2VMeHY5Y0t1clhPOGtXSWhRR3E3NHVVRFRlWEVHTmxDMDVISDZ2cGMzd28yWnFrdng3WjNKUzNCQUoxbjBuYnFyTzVydG5wVTlJWFRTaXHSAYwBQVVfeXFMTXlSOUJQOFVxcWlBbmNMUWdBdlp3Y2dWNm9TeGhBY0JWdEw3dGNuUnhXVUx3R1lBTnE0ZnpWMjlYUndFQWFVV2w3a0R3cWtuVnBZeUZYVU9zVFBsZGFIeTktQzE0WjRFMFNQYmc4Y2JUdlFSblJoWEUyT2liYlpkV3hHNmdlLUR0Zjd0YnE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxObVozMnFMMkVicTlTV19EQ3FHNGJ4R2tGZE5hdVRrSEJFT09ma01GZ2xuNDhUNU8yZzczRXdhSXhoR2VMeHY5Y0t1clhPOGtXSWhRR3E3NHVVRFRlWEVHTmxDMDVISDZ2cGMzd28yWnFrdng3WjNKUzNCQUoxbjBuYnFyTzVydG5wVTlJWFRTaXHSAYwBQVVfeXFMTXlSOUJQOFVxcWlBbmNMUWdBdlp3Y2dWNm9TeGhBY0JWdEw3dGNuUnhXVUx3R1lBTnE0ZnpWMjlYUndFQWFVV2w3a0R3cWtuVnBZeUZYVU9zVFBsZGFIeTktQzE0WjRFMFNQYmc4Y2JUdlFSblJoWEUyT2liYlpkV3hHNmdlLUR0Zjd0YnE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:31:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Setback for Hindu monk Chinmoy Krishna Das as Bangladesh court rejects bail plea - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh Court Denies Bail to Hindu Monk Chinmoy Krishna Das</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/chinmoy_krishna_das__1732641067980_1735798157287.jpg" alt="Chinmoy Krishna Das was arrested by Bangladeshi forces from the Dhaka airport. (File)"><figcaption>Chinmoy Krishna Das was arrested by Bangladeshi forces from the Dhaka airport. (File)</figcaption><p>A Chattogram court in Bangladesh has denied bail to Chinmoy Krishna Das, a former ISKCON monk, during a tightly secured hearing.</p><ul><li>The court hearing lasted about 30 minutes with arguments presented by both sides.</li><li>A team of 11 Supreme Court lawyers represented Chinmoy Krishna Das.</li><li>His bail plea was rejected by Metropolitan Sessions judge Md Saiful Islam.</li><li>Chinmoy faces sedition charges for allegedly raising a saffron flag above Bangladesh's national flag.</li><li>His arrest on November 25 led to protests and clashes resulting in a lawyer's death.</li><li>Additional arrests of fellow monks occurred amid the unrest.</li><li>The Indian government expressed concern over the situation in Bangladesh.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will move for Chinmoy in the court for his bail.” - Lawyer Apurba Kumar Bhattacharjee</blockquote><p>The decision by the Chattogram court highlights ongoing tensions in Bangladesh regarding minority rights and protests against extremism.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/bangladesh-court-rejects-hindu-monk-chinmoy-krishna-dass-bail-plea-101735797855767.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/bangladesh-court-rejects-hindu-monk-chinmoy-krishna-dass-bail-plea-101735797855767.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:06:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One year enough for GoI: CM Omar Abdullah on restoration of Statehood to Jammu and Kashmir - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxNRFhGLXdHZlN2SzFYN1d3RFREWFcwcmxZaUNvRmtSWjh6UzBhcUIyU19sNmhHbEs2bkZ6X2Z2bWtOS0VjaVBtX0E1ZjltRFgwdGtuQ2lfR2owLUQ4ZkZvdTNzSkhMV3FsSWVSSWxKUG91T1NlaXBUT1hXbUdjZmZoWFNOVlVKT0xPZVJVMFJ0U1cxOWl0OFJvbUk4Rnp0R2I2M20wM3dYRW5lUHIzM0RWeU4yS2dpY0ZsQzVMU2FmSVNXMDN5ak5WazMxdGVNZ9IB0wFBVV95cUxPMUdzdzBOZ2pLMy1HelhDRE5jc01GNVV4YW9jbzN1dFVFaG9JVG9rYVZXbTB0TDNSNUNKMDltSG9rTTgwMllNRnBlTlAyem5pbHQzSTdCa3hzMm1CbWduaktLQ05aMFdpbjFGbEtvaVo1YTQ0UlJyWld6ajBHaDRlVnV3LVNORFdsazJQR0IyR3FtWTJleGpvcWhSQ2xzTjlTUUJTbzdKRTN3LUtuV1g2ZVF4QzhZRm1pa1BnV0ttYUdkUWVhaFRqOTJJYjdha0lnWG4w?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxNRFhGLXdHZlN2SzFYN1d3RFREWFcwcmxZaUNvRmtSWjh6UzBhcUIyU19sNmhHbEs2bkZ6X2Z2bWtOS0VjaVBtX0E1ZjltRFgwdGtuQ2lfR2owLUQ4ZkZvdTNzSkhMV3FsSWVSSWxKUG91T1NlaXBUT1hXbUdjZmZoWFNOVlVKT0xPZVJVMFJ0U1cxOWl0OFJvbUk4Rnp0R2I2M20wM3dYRW5lUHIzM0RWeU4yS2dpY0ZsQzVMU2FmSVNXMDN5ak5WazMxdGVNZ9IB0wFBVV95cUxPMUdzdzBOZ2pLMy1HelhDRE5jc01GNVV4YW9jbzN1dFVFaG9JVG9rYVZXbTB0TDNSNUNKMDltSG9rTTgwMllNRnBlTlAyem5pbHQzSTdCa3hzMm1CbWduaktLQ05aMFdpbjFGbEtvaVo1YTQ0UlJyWld6ajBHaDRlVnV3LVNORFdsazJQR0IyR3FtWTJleGpvcWhSQ2xzTjlTUUJTbzdKRTN3LUtuV1g2ZVF4QzhZRm1pa1BnV0ttYUdkUWVhaFRqOTJJYjdha0lnWG4w?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:05:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[​8 Beautiful Unseen Deep Space Pictures Captured By NASA​ - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Beautiful Unseen Deep Space Pictures Captured By NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116873908/116873908.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=2127622" alt="8 Beautiful Unseen Deep Space Pictures Captured By NASA">
<figcaption>Credit: ESA/Hubble-NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases eight stunning images captured by NASA, revealing the breathtaking beauty and complexity of deep space. Each image highlights various celestial phenomena as observed by the Hubble Space Telescope.</p>
<ul>
<li>Arp-Madore 2339-661: Interacting galaxies that highlight complex gravitational interactions.</li>
<li>XZ Tauri: A multiple star system expelling hot gas bubbles, showcasing star formation.</li>
<li>From Dim To Dazzling: A vibrant star-forming region within the Milky Way.</li>
<li>A Spiral Star Factory: The spiral galaxy NGC 5668 known for its star formation.</li>
<li>Stellar Ensemble In NGC 6357: A star cluster that ionizes parts of the emission nebula.</li>
<li>Stellar Remnant SNR 0509-68.7: A supernova remnant closely studied by astronomers.</li>
<li>NGC 6302: A planetary nebula, known as the butterfly nebula, formed by a fading star.</li>
<li>AFGL 5180: A star-forming region providing insights into solar system formation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"These images not only mesmerize but also promote an understanding of the universe we inhabit." - TN Tech Desk</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, these breathtaking images taken by NASA serve as a reminder of the vast beauty and complexity of the universe, inspiring curiosity and further exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/8-beautiful-unseen-deep-space-pictures-captured-by-nasa/photostory/116873839.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/8-beautiful-unseen-deep-space-pictures-captured-by-nasa/photostory/116873839.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:45:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lavender to lemon: 10 oils to relieve stress, and boost energy - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxONzZRTmF0TlAzazlvTHZKZlRFM3VRSHZEU0FrZW1xZGcyaVpDMC1BMUYyYzBiaDk3SFFjb3JWaVdubnNKanJwZXkxSFVneWN4OHhqRUxYWUVrQkNvR2NDeFpBNjZsRE41RmJocTl4LTJmR3doc1ZvRTRnS3ZmTnFiZnhpVi3SAYQBQVVfeXFMTjc2UU5hdE5QM2s5b0x2SmZURTN1UUh2RFNBa2VtcWRnMmlaQzAtQTFGMmMwYmg5N0hRY29yVmlXbm5zSmpycGV5MUhVZ3ljeDh4akVMWFlFa0JDb0djQ3haQTY2bERONUZiaHE5eC0yZkd3aHNWb0U0Z0t2Zk5xYmZ4aVYt?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxONzZRTmF0TlAzazlvTHZKZlRFM3VRSHZEU0FrZW1xZGcyaVpDMC1BMUYyYzBiaDk3SFFjb3JWaVdubnNKanJwZXkxSFVneWN4OHhqRUxYWUVrQkNvR2NDeFpBNjZsRE41RmJocTl4LTJmR3doc1ZvRTRnS3ZmTnFiZnhpVi3SAYQBQVVfeXFMTjc2UU5hdE5QM2s5b0x2SmZURTN1UUh2RFNBa2VtcWRnMmlaQzAtQTFGMmMwYmg5N0hRY29yVmlXbm5zSmpycGV5MUhVZ3ljeDh4akVMWFlFa0JDb0djQ3haQTY2bERONUZiaHE5eC0yZkd3aHNWb0U0Z0t2Zk5xYmZ4aVYt?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:40:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New York: At least 11 shot at in night club in Queens - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>At Least 11 Shot in Queens Night Club Shooting</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="New York: At least 11 shot at in night club in Queens" loading="lazy"><figcaption>New York: At least 11 shot at in night club in Queens</figcaption><p>Reports indicate that gunfire erupted at the Amazura event hall in Jamaica, Queens, resulting in at least 11 injuries.</p><ul><li>The shooting occurred around 11:20 PM on January 1.</li><li>Details on the conditions of the injured individuals have not been released by the NYPD yet.</li><li>The incident is part of a growing concern over gun violence in the United States.</li></ul><blockquote>“At least 11 people have been shot in Queens, NY at Amazura Night Club. This is still an ACTIVE situation.” — Nick Sortor</blockquote><p>This shooting adds to the troubling pattern of violent incidents affecting public safety in the US.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/us-attack-new-york-at-least-11-shot-at-in-night-club-in-queens-new-orleans-19533235.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/us-attack-new-york-at-least-11-shot-at-in-night-club-in-queens-new-orleans-19533235.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:31:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New York mass shooting: At least 11 shot as gunman fires inside Amazura Night Club in Queens, say reports | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>At least 11 shot outside Amazura Night Club in Queens</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> New York Post</p><p>The incident occurred just before 11:20 pm near the Amazura nightclub in Jamaica, New York. At least 11 individuals were shot but are expected to survive, according to the NYPD.</p><ul><li>The shooting took place outside the Amazura nightclub.</li><li>Victims were transported to nearby hospitals, including Long Island Jewish Hospital.</li><li>None of the victims are in critical condition.</li><li>Footage of the scene shows a significant police and ambulance presence.</li></ul><blockquote>“All are expected to survive.” — NYPD</blockquote><p>This incident comes on the heels of a deadly attack in New Orleans that left 15 dead.</p><p>The Amazura nightclub is known for its vibrant atmosphere, featuring dancing, DJs, and live performances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/new-york-mass-shooting-at-least-11-dead-as-gunman-shoots-inside-amazura-night-club-in-queens-say-reports-11735795383312.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/new-york-mass-shooting-at-least-11-dead-as-gunman-shoots-inside-amazura-night-club-in-queens-say-reports-11735795383312.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:28:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold rate today nudges higher as investors await US data for US Fed rate cut cues. US inflation in focus | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-wFBVV95cUxPVlFySXMya2hvY3VtRW1mLVlDemlKWlg0WlloMHM1N3NCalBFS1dmUjlwaUR3Z2p0dDZLTldRaDlOOE02YjA1alFQYU9xRENPZGs3YXc1X2hONFpaclJacHpLanE0azY5N0U3MWN6dFB4RF96X1JqdzRFTW9pS0x4TzR2T18xRnh5TnpacDVYU1djblpBRjFBaWlQXzNCYU5DcUZhY1dmcUN0clJjTDV2NnNzbGpzUGhoeGFKb0Y5QTNJSlZDSlhLR3pHUVc3dW5ZV2pLczNOa0RvTWhVcVpTWnQ1dXVKTmYydUR2SGJoNVJPZlEzU0dISVNrVdIBgAJBVV95cUxPbGplbEh4LTlKclFMbHVOUHZzUWZ0cjJ4amRLaXJRYVhYblVuaWl5RUNRVDFueDBzLURGQkpySThEaHFmZEozZC1ldnMyYkJUY0gwRzRTeVlHWlBUTURhQ09VcjRSejhKTy1naGN1QWIwME1JWk4wRGdtY01mMERHWW41UndpdDlxOU8zb1dXV2NtdnM4LXFBREtJSllVV3VMeEtFc1dxb2h4OTBvdWpmb1R6SEtlZElQbllRLVI5d25uRDNKcVNCU0ZGQjVydERmbFhzMlBuXzN0LU85OGVJeXRfem5hS1V3VGNFdmptS3l0MnVCeGp2Z0tYSTVjaUdp?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-wFBVV95cUxPVlFySXMya2hvY3VtRW1mLVlDemlKWlg0WlloMHM1N3NCalBFS1dmUjlwaUR3Z2p0dDZLTldRaDlOOE02YjA1alFQYU9xRENPZGs3YXc1X2hONFpaclJacHpLanE0azY5N0U3MWN6dFB4RF96X1JqdzRFTW9pS0x4TzR2T18xRnh5TnpacDVYU1djblpBRjFBaWlQXzNCYU5DcUZhY1dmcUN0clJjTDV2NnNzbGpzUGhoeGFKb0Y5QTNJSlZDSlhLR3pHUVc3dW5ZV2pLczNOa0RvTWhVcVpTWnQ1dXVKTmYydUR2SGJoNVJPZlEzU0dISVNrVdIBgAJBVV95cUxPbGplbEh4LTlKclFMbHVOUHZzUWZ0cjJ4amRLaXJRYVhYblVuaWl5RUNRVDFueDBzLURGQkpySThEaHFmZEozZC1ldnMyYkJUY0gwRzRTeVlHWlBUTURhQ09VcjRSejhKTy1naGN1QWIwME1JWk4wRGdtY01mMERHWW41UndpdDlxOU8zb1dXV2NtdnM4LXFBREtJSllVV3VMeEtFc1dxb2h4OTBvdWpmb1R6SEtlZElQbllRLVI5d25uRDNKcVNCU0ZGQjVydERmbFhzMlBuXzN0LU85OGVJeXRfem5hS1V3VGNFdmptS3l0MnVCeGp2Z0tYSTVjaUdp?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:16:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manufacturing PMI slips to a 12-month low of 56.4 in Dec - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manufacturing PMI slips to a 12-month low of 56.4 in December</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 02, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2023/10/Foxconn.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Manufacturing activity declines in December" title="Manufacturing activity declines in December" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Manufacturing activity declines in December</figcaption><p>India’s manufacturing activity closed the year at a 12-month low of 56.4 in December compared with 56.5 a month back, according to a private sector survey released on January 2.</p><ul><li>The HSBC India Manufacturing Purchasing Managers’ Index declined from 57.5 to 56.5 in November.</li><li>This marks the second consecutive month of decline in manufacturing activity.</li><li>The index averaged over 57.5 in 2024, compared with 56.8 in the previous year.</li></ul><blockquote>“December marks the second consecutive month of decline in activity.”</blockquote><p>This decline in the manufacturing PMI suggests potential challenges in the industrial sector moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/manufacturing-pmi-slips-to-a-12-month-low-of-56-4-in-dec-12901901.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/economy/manufacturing-pmi-slips-to-a-12-month-low-of-56-4-in-dec-12901901.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:10:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Planet parade, meteor showers and more: Here's celestial calender of 2025 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxNMUhBS2ZTOW9hcVNqMk0yeXFOWlZyTm1vaHNUd1c3SF9KTlZ2VHJHM1BiTFlwQ0xWS3JSeUZpOVVqRHRhWEZyU1FKQmNJQ3p1MFpPWnVYMFFHQ0xWZE9TbU1vdlZvSWtTMVI0TUtfY19GNV9iU3p0bUZKdWFmaldETFBpeS0wMEZkZ1RuR25PY091VWNOMzRZM3pmb3NfTmhWS1d0ZDFkOE9WMzY1cmszZzVWRVZhbERfT2lLWVBWb3JFV2kyOFV1RFRvRTRxcTlvaEZN0gHYAUFVX3lxTE1EaXlDdUxQeHp2TUFOWTNPX3YzYkc3LTU3TVV3SDlPOWt5bmdxSVFBNUFsWDA4RGp5Wl9tcmFMZFVWTmFfTlFfTEJpSkhWYm9HNXFCcTZVY0NGYzNmaTF3MUs2bU52SWVsNFJyQjF4aGpYdWlTWmJHUjMwWnJycVczWDR5ZlZNNl9oTV9nbkt0MjVWdXg0WUY2d2dTNDlzdkRTdnhIQkM3TVI5NWpqeDlGQjhRTXNwU2FmbUJJRjJZNXVFQURZcjhiWVl0RG5pbXhWUHBFTDRSRg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxNMUhBS2ZTOW9hcVNqMk0yeXFOWlZyTm1vaHNUd1c3SF9KTlZ2VHJHM1BiTFlwQ0xWS3JSeUZpOVVqRHRhWEZyU1FKQmNJQ3p1MFpPWnVYMFFHQ0xWZE9TbU1vdlZvSWtTMVI0TUtfY19GNV9iU3p0bUZKdWFmaldETFBpeS0wMEZkZ1RuR25PY091VWNOMzRZM3pmb3NfTmhWS1d0ZDFkOE9WMzY1cmszZzVWRVZhbERfT2lLWVBWb3JFV2kyOFV1RFRvRTRxcTlvaEZN0gHYAUFVX3lxTE1EaXlDdUxQeHp2TUFOWTNPX3YzYkc3LTU3TVV3SDlPOWt5bmdxSVFBNUFsWDA4RGp5Wl9tcmFMZFVWTmFfTlFfTEJpSkhWYm9HNXFCcTZVY0NGYzNmaTF3MUs2bU52SWVsNFJyQjF4aGpYdWlTWmJHUjMwWnJycVczWDR5ZlZNNl9oTV9nbkt0MjVWdXg0WUY2d2dTNDlzdkRTdnhIQkM3TVI5NWpqeDlGQjhRTXNwU2FmbUJJRjJZNXVFQURZcjhiWVl0RG5pbXhWUHBFTDRSRg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:05:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magnus Carlsen defends Blitz title, shares it with Nepomniachtchi; Wenjun Champion in Women’s section - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Magnus Carlsen defends Blitz title, beats Nepomniachtchi in final; Wenjun Champion in Women’s section</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://ss-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ord7b0/article69048918.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/54237875187_f3f47e7a84_o.jpg" alt="Magnus Carlsen and Ian Nepomniachtchi during the final of the World Blitz Championship 2024 in New York." /><figcaption><p>Magnus Carlsen and Ian Nepomniachtchi during the final of the World Blitz Championship 2024 in New York. | Photo Credit: FIDE/Michał Walusza</p></figcaption><p>In a historic conclusion to the World Blitz Championship 2024 on Wall Street, New York, reigning champion Magnus Carlsen shared the title with Ian Nepomniachtchi after a series of draws in sudden-death play. Despite Carlsen's initial wins, Nepomniachtchi's resilience forced a tie, leading to an unprecedented decision of shared victory.</p><ul><li>Carlsen and Nepomniachtchi ended the game tied at 2-2, resulting in three drawn games in sudden-death.</li><li>This match mirrored the 2021 Classical World Championship, enhancing its historical significance.</li><li>Carlsen has now won eight Blitz titles and 18 major championships overall.</li><li>Ju Wenjun claimed the Women's World Blitz Championship by defeating Lei Tingjie.</li><li>India’s R. Vaishali advanced in the tournament but was defeated by Wenjun in the semifinals.</li></ul><blockquote>— International Chess Federation (@FIDE_chess) <a href="https://twitter.com/FIDE_chess/status/1874247415337017478?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 1, 2025</a></blockquote><p>This championship showcases the high-level competition in chess and the continuing evolution of the game.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/chess/magnus-carlsen-ian-nepomniachtchi-share-world-blitz-championship-title-ju-wenjun-wins-womens-section-result-news/article69048298.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/chess/magnus-carlsen-ian-nepomniachtchi-share-world-blitz-championship-title-ju-wenjun-wins-womens-section-result-news/article69048298.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Step inside Vinod Kambli's luxurious home worth Rs..., defaulted on home loan, it can be taken away due to non-payment of Rs... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Inside Vinod Kambli's Luxurious Home and Recent Financial Struggles</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Date not provided <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/step-inside-vinod-kamblis-luxurious-home-worth-rs-defaulted-on-home-loan-it-can-be-taken-away-due-to-non-payment-of-rs-202501-1735792925.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Inside Vinod Kambli’s Luxurious Home"><figcaption>Image credit: X (Formerly Twitter)</figcaption><p>The article provides an overview of former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli's luxurious home in Mumbai, valued at over Rs 8 crore, and discusses his current financial difficulties with loan defaults.</p><ul><li>Vinod Kambli's home is located in Mumbai and is valued at over Rs 8 crore.</li><li>He has defaulted on home and car loans from DNS Bank since 2014.</li><li>Kambli and his wife Andrea Hewitt have been declared defaulters publicly.</li><li>They owe maintenance fees of over Rs 18 lakh to their co-operative society.</li><li>Kambli has received financial assistance of Rs 5 lakh from the Shiv Sena party.</li></ul><blockquote>“The couple have been marked as defaulters by the co-operative society of the apartment and their flat can even be taken away if the dues are not cleared.”</blockquote><p>The financial situation of Kambli highlights the struggles faced by some retired athletes despite their previous successes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/step-inside-vinod-kambli-luxurious-home-worth-rs-defaulted-on-home-loan-it-can-be-taken-away-due-to-non-payment-of-rs-417633/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/step-inside-vinod-kambli-luxurious-home-worth-rs-defaulted-on-home-loan-it-can-be-taken-away-due-to-non-payment-of-rs-417633/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:54:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eclipse, Meteors, Auroras, Supermoon in 2025 - Deccan Chronicle]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Celestial Events to Look Forward to in 2025: Eclipses, Supermoons, and More</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> AP News</p>
<p>The year 2025 will feature a series of spectacular astronomical events including eclipses, supermoons, and a parade of planets. Stargazers can expect multiple opportunities to witness these cosmic occurrences, enhancing the viewing experience for enthusiasts.</p>
<ul>
  <li>January will kick off with a six-planet parade visible for an extended period.</li>
  <li>The first lunar eclipse will occur on March 14, followed by a partial solar eclipse two weeks later.</li>
  <li>Three supermoons are expected in October, November, and December, with the closest occurring in November.</li>
  <li>A line-up of six planets will be visible around mid-January.</li>
  <li>Geomagnetic storms may lead to enhanced displays of the northern and southern lights throughout the year.</li>
  <li>Popular meteor showers such as the Perseids and Geminids will peak in August and December.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“People should go out and see them sometime during the next many weeks. I certainly will,” said Bruce Betts, chief scientist at the Planetary Society.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, astronomy enthusiasts have much to look forward to in 2025, with various celestial events expected to delight and inspire star watchers around the globe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/world/2025-guide-to-night-sky-and-celestial-wow-moments-1851320</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanchronicle.com/world/2025-guide-to-night-sky-and-celestial-wow-moments-1851320</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:45:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why do women have high pain tolerance? Is it a healthy trait? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why do women have high pain tolerance? Is it a healthy trait?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116871142,imgsize-578129,width-400,resizemode-4/116871142.jpg" alt="Why do women have high pain tolerance? Is it a healthy trait?" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Why do women have high pain tolerance? Is it a healthy trait?</figcaption><p>Women possess a remarkable capacity to endure various forms of pain, with their pain tolerance being influenced by biological, hormonal, and psychological factors.</p><ul><li>Dr. Astha Dayal highlights that women's pain tolerance may be linked to evolutionary adaptations, particularly regarding childbirth.</li><li>Hormonal aspects, especially estrogen, play a significant role in pain perception and tolerance.</li><li>Women are encouraged to address pain, as ignoring it can lead to negative health outcomes.</li><li>Societal conditioning often leads women to view pain as an expected part of life, which can discourage open discussions about discomfort.</li><li>Dr. Sameer Malhotra notes the subjective nature of pain and how it can be influenced by various factors, including social expectations.</li><li>Acknowledging pain is viewed as an act of self-care rather than weakness, promoting better health outcomes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pain is often the body’s first alert to something amiss.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while women's high pain tolerance can be seen as resilience, it is essential to recognize and address pain appropriately to maintain overall health and well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-do-women-have-high-pain-tolerance-is-it-a-healthy-trait/articleshow/116871155.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-do-women-have-high-pain-tolerance-is-it-a-healthy-trait/articleshow/116871155.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13 India Launch Next Week: Expected Price, Full Specifications, How To Watch OnePlus Event Live - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 India Launch Next Week: Expected Price, Full Specifications, How To Watch OnePlus Event Live</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Tech News Network</p><img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116871627,thumbsize-16524,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116871627.jpg" alt="oneplus 13" title="oneplus 13"><figcaption>OnePlus 13 - Expected Launch</figcaption><p>OnePlus is all set to host its Winter Event on January 7, unveiling its flagship smartphones, the OnePlus 13 and OnePlus 13R, in India. These devices have already launched in China and have generated a lot of excitement among Indian fans.</p><ul><li>The OnePlus 13 is expected to be priced between Rs 67,000 and Rs 70,000 in India.</li><li>It features a 6.82-inch AMOLED display with a 120Hz refresh rate.</li><li>Powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset, promising high performance.</li><li>Camera system includes three 50MP sensors co-engineered with Hasselblad.</li><li>Expected to come with a 6,000mAh battery supporting 100W fast charging.</li><li>Live streaming of the event will be available on the official OnePlus website and YouTube channel.</li></ul><blockquote>"Tune in on January 7 to catch all the action as it happens."</blockquote><p>The launch of the OnePlus 13 and OnePlus 13R promises to be an exciting event packed with innovation and premium features, reflecting OnePlus's commitment to the Indian market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/gadgets/oneplus-13-india-launch-next-week-expected-price-full-specifications-how-to-watch-oneplus-event-live-article-116871671</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/gadgets/oneplus-13-india-launch-next-week-expected-price-full-specifications-how-to-watch-oneplus-event-live-article-116871671</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:29:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025’s first meteor shower 'Quadrantid' to light up the skies: When to watch in India - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/2025s-first-meteor-shower-quadrantid-to-light-up-the-skies-where-to-watch-in-india/articleshow/116869318.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/2025s-first-meteor-shower-quadrantid-to-light-up-the-skies-where-to-watch-in-india/articleshow/116869318.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025’s first meteor shower 'Quadrantid' to light up the skies: Where to watch in India - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2025’s first meteor shower 'Quadrantid' to light up the skies: When to watch in India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>The Quadrantid meteor shower will be visible this January, providing an opportunity for sky watchers in India to enjoy a spectacular celestial show.</p><ul><li>The peak of the shower is expected to occur on January 4th, 2025.</li><li>Observers should look towards the northeast sky for the best view.</li><li>Ideal viewing conditions require a dark, clear sky away from city lights.</li><li>Up to 120 meteors per hour can be seen at the peak.</li></ul><blockquote>"Enjoying a meteor shower is one of the most beautiful experiences for stargazers."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Quadrantid meteor shower promises to be a highlight for astronomy enthusiasts early in 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/2025s-first-meteor-shower-quadrantid-to-light-up-the-skies-where-to-watch-in-india/articleshow/116869318.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/2025s-first-meteor-shower-quadrantid-to-light-up-the-skies-where-to-watch-in-india/articleshow/116869318.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Places of worship law: SC agrees to hear AIMIM chief Asaduddin Owaisi’s plea on February 17 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxQUzVMRjRZTzN4XzduWU1EY2dXRWp1cDVtelB3dERGb1ZvX01DVHRDb1U2U0U5MFRva25CcHJtcWlvYUhqT3hibGNpVHkxNjZvWmhsLUJwLWVMUDNISFNqcWJodjl5NTlKcm1mNXJnVktnVHhpYkdfLVlMVkRUV2VWZDNrUGEzMG1DQ2RHZFFpRTd3WTJ6Wmoxa0dHNEZ6SHNuQnlCX2JNVjlYd3k5WGlKTUNhZ3o4NGxWWUU4emVLVGQ5alFWWG1GaFJn0gHQAUFVX3lxTFBjc3NxNklQQU9VNlNYSkhxVDhiMXA5U1c3X3h5bG1mcDVYWHRFZDl4YlY1T3FFM09MLWJFWlJ1MzY5TEdqWldMUzVxZ09tcmREQWszbVJseklrQzBrcnpXZFhfYkhyeGw2RzdwUk9Wc3RKd2p3dVJkTzUxOTFPTHdTOHlNbFowN0lXNHR1Q09TdXA4amU5SzYzeGduZWpZY21zSjBCaVhNY3BJVTNRbHFkSkNBZFNHR0d6YjdfRGpoZkJsemFUUFpsaExFWGNZbFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxQUzVMRjRZTzN4XzduWU1EY2dXRWp1cDVtelB3dERGb1ZvX01DVHRDb1U2U0U5MFRva25CcHJtcWlvYUhqT3hibGNpVHkxNjZvWmhsLUJwLWVMUDNISFNqcWJodjl5NTlKcm1mNXJnVktnVHhpYkdfLVlMVkRUV2VWZDNrUGEzMG1DQ2RHZFFpRTd3WTJ6Wmoxa0dHNEZ6SHNuQnlCX2JNVjlYd3k5WGlKTUNhZ3o4NGxWWUU4emVLVGQ5alFWWG1GaFJn0gHQAUFVX3lxTFBjc3NxNklQQU9VNlNYSkhxVDhiMXA5U1c3X3h5bG1mcDVYWHRFZDl4YlY1T3FFM09MLWJFWlJ1MzY5TEdqWldMUzVxZ09tcmREQWszbVJseklrQzBrcnpXZFhfYkhyeGw2RzdwUk9Wc3RKd2p3dVJkTzUxOTFPTHdTOHlNbFowN0lXNHR1Q09TdXA4amU5SzYzeGduZWpZY21zSjBCaVhNY3BJVTNRbHFkSkNBZFNHR0d6YjdfRGpoZkJsemFUUFpsaExFWGNZbFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Places of worship law: SC to hear AIMIM chief Asaduddin Owaisi’s plea - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court to Hear Owaisi's Plea on Places of Worship Law</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/61epnz/article69052499.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241214321L.jpg" alt="All India Majlis-e-Ittehadul Muslimeen (AIMIM) MP Asaduddin Owaisi." /><figcaption>All India Majlis-e-Ittehadul Muslimeen (AIMIM) MP Asaduddin Owaisi. | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court has agreed to consider the plea of AIMIM chief Asaduddin Owaisi regarding the implementation of the 1991 places of worship law aimed at maintaining the religious character of places as they existed on August 15, 1947.</p><ul><li>The Court will tag Owaisi's plea with pending cases on February 17, 2025.</li><li>AIMIM's plea follows a prior order restraining courts from hearing new suits on reclaiming religious places.</li><li>The 1991 law prohibits the conversion of places of worship.</li><li>Owaisi's plea seeks effective enforcement of the law amid concerns over court-ordered surveys of mosques.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will tag this,” the CJI said regarding the plea.</blockquote><p>Owaisi's call for action reflects ongoing tensions surrounding religious site claims in India, emphasizing the need for legal clarity and enforcement of existing regulations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/sc-hearing-aimim-chief-owaisis-plea-on-places-of-worship-law-jan-2-2025/article69052472.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/sc-hearing-aimim-chief-owaisis-plea-on-places-of-worship-law-jan-2-2025/article69052472.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court to hear AIMIM chief Asaduddin Owaisi's plea on places of worship law - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court to Hear Asaduddin Owaisi's Plea on Places of Worship Law</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/61epnz/article69052499.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241214321L.jpg" alt="All India Majlis-e-Ittehadul Muslimeen (AIMIM) MP Asaduddin Owaisi." title="All India Majlis-e-Ittehadul Muslimeen (AIMIM) MP Asaduddin Owaisi."><figcaption>Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court is set to hear AIMIM chief Asaduddin Owaisi's plea regarding the 1991 places of worship law, which mandates maintaining the religious character of places as they were on August 15, 1947. The hearing follows a recent Supreme Court ruling that halted fresh litigations against the law.</p><ul><li>Owaisi filed his plea on December 17, 2024, through advocate Fuzail Ahmad Ayyubi.</li><li>The 1991 law prohibits changing the religious character of places of worship as they existed in 1947.</li><li>A recent Supreme Court order restrained courts from taking on new suits regarding the religious character of several mosques.</li><li>Cases concerning various religious sites, including Gyanvapi, Shahi Idgah, and Shahi Jama Masjid, have been stalled pending the court's review.</li><li>The Muslim side has filed pleas for the law's strict enforcement to maintain communal peace.</li></ul><blockquote>“The petitions challenging the law were filed with 'mischievous intent' to facilitate lawsuits against these religious sites.”</blockquote><p>This upcoming hearing may tag Owaisi's plea with existing cases regarding the law's implementation and its implications for communal harmony.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/sc-hearing-aimim-chief-owaisis-plea-on-places-of-worship-law-jan-2-2025/article69052472.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/sc-hearing-aimim-chief-owaisis-plea-on-places-of-worship-law-jan-2-2025/article69052472.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quordle Answer for Today (January 2); Hints, Answers & How to Play? - Gizbot]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Quordle Answer for Today (January 2); Hints, Answers & How to Play?</h1>
<p><strong>Updated: Thursday, January 2, 2025, 9:32 [IST]</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.gizbot.com/img/2025/01/quordle4-1735790242.jpeg" alt="Quordle Answer for Today (January 2); Hints, Answers &amp; How to Play?" width="600" height="338">
<figcaption>Quordle Answer for January 2, 2025</figcaption>
<p>Quordle is a unique word game where players solve four puzzles at once. For those looking for today's (Quordle 1074) hints and answers, you can find them below.</p>
<h2>Quordle 1074 Hints For January 2, 2025</h2>
<p>Starting Letters: U, S, D, I<br>Ending Letters: Y, E, T, O</p>
<ul>
  <li>Word 1 - Make or become united</li>
  <li>Word 2 - Make a solemn statement or promise undertaking to do something</li>
  <li>Word 3 - A place for the storage of large quantities of equipment</li>
  <li>Word 4 - An introduction</li>
</ul>
<h2>Quordle 1074 Answers For January 2, 2025</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Word 1 - UNIFY</li>
  <li>Word 2 - SWORE</li>
  <li>Word 3 - DEPOT</li>
  <li>Word 4 - INTRO</li>
</ul>
<h2>How to Play Quordle?</h2>
<p>Start Quordle by selecting any five-letter word. Each grid will display guessed letters in different colours indicating their position or relevance to the target words.</p>
<p>Green indicates the correct letter and position, yellow means it is in the word but not in the right spot, and grey shows it isn't part of any of the words. Use these colour-coded hints to inform your guesses.</p>
<p>Quordle is both a challenge and enjoyable, so take your time and visit Merriam-Webster's website regularly for updates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gizbot.com/gaming/news/quordle-answer-for-today-january-2-hints-answers-how-to-play-107803.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gizbot.com/gaming/news/quordle-answer-for-today-january-2-hints-answers-how-to-play-107803.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 03:58:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>