<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:17:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:17:05 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Lionel Messi came, Kylian Mbappé was a little jealous': Neymar spills secrets of PSG days - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Neymar Reveals Secrets from PSG Days Involving Messi and Mbappé</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>Neymar shares anecdotes from his time at Paris Saint-Germain, discussing the dynamics between himself, Lionel Messi, and Kylian Mbappé.</p><ul><li>Neymar describes Messi's arrival at PSG and the impact it had on the team.</li><li>He mentions moments that hinted at jealousy from Mbappé regarding Messi's status.</li><li>The interview provides insights into the relationships formed between the star players.</li></ul><blockquote>Neymar stated, "Lionel Messi came, Kylian Mbappé was a little jealous."</blockquote><p>This retrospective on Neymar's time at PSG offers fans a glimpse into the locker room atmosphere and the interplay between three of football's biggest stars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/football/top-stories/lionel-messi-came-kylian-mbapp-was-a-little-jealous-neymar-spills-secrets-of-psg-days/articleshow/117318397.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/football/top-stories/lionel-messi-came-kylian-mbapp-was-a-little-jealous-neymar-spills-secrets-of-psg-days/articleshow/117318397.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi fog today: Several flights delayed at IGI airport; AQI improves after rain - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-air-quality-rain-delhi-ncr-noida-ghaziabad-fog-aqi-imd-weather-news-101737080617597.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-air-quality-rain-delhi-ncr-noida-ghaziabad-fog-aqi-imd-weather-news-101737080617597.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:10:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Industries shares in focus after Q3 results beats estimates. Should you buy, sell and hold? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxPN1NwQXZITDJLOFJMUFB1VlhtWnB4dUtEWm9MQl8yNnJXX2FwczE5aFMxcUVoenFIcTlpdHdjbHFxUlp4VjZyZUczcU9LYlduOHdUVndjZ3A4Tnl4eEV6eUc5RmtZZ18zUFFSVWd3WVdTdEx0bHNqVEZxdkhvMkM5MTU4a1ZmU0VNNUY0VlJMVGZncFBYYWVOVVY3ZlY3RlpHdmFFOFhzTnpRNXRTSFR6bFBvVjBnQk9lSHQ4bDBXaURnRF92U1ZjM28wMXZySHFHUkJSRzNqQ1ZwS1dxai1TSTFrdlpsYkMzbWZGXy1ScGxpZGJVaXFjUkVnYXpPS0550gGGAkFVX3lxTE1kOVFRb3hBRWZhc0gzbkhQVEczU3dHME9BbnNyd1BfaGRfR1BEWFFGYjdyYnNXdTBXR0VDQVJVM0VkU1Y0Z3FKT1JQWkVBQTB0cXNzdkRlWk9DcE5yTEdNVVFLRjZTSkJqN3FyRjkxS1R4MkRkbk5VZXM2R01rYXgtOWFuRmgwUUJGSUQ5dktWSnBFeXVXdmxiX1VfNzNTZktoaTUxcTVLVU5sRENDTEs5VVJIeDM5ZV9KRURGZy1feUVNakJlX3d6RFI3NlhBMlBBa0ZRWW5Wc1g5UFE4NHpqMUNMVW8xR1hycFdMcUQtd29mS0JJRnZYdkNqcXBfVHdkcHFYS0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxPN1NwQXZITDJLOFJMUFB1VlhtWnB4dUtEWm9MQl8yNnJXX2FwczE5aFMxcUVoenFIcTlpdHdjbHFxUlp4VjZyZUczcU9LYlduOHdUVndjZ3A4Tnl4eEV6eUc5RmtZZ18zUFFSVWd3WVdTdEx0bHNqVEZxdkhvMkM5MTU4a1ZmU0VNNUY0VlJMVGZncFBYYWVOVVY3ZlY3RlpHdmFFOFhzTnpRNXRTSFR6bFBvVjBnQk9lSHQ4bDBXaURnRF92U1ZjM28wMXZySHFHUkJSRzNqQ1ZwS1dxai1TSTFrdlpsYkMzbWZGXy1ScGxpZGJVaXFjUkVnYXpPS0550gGGAkFVX3lxTE1kOVFRb3hBRWZhc0gzbkhQVEczU3dHME9BbnNyd1BfaGRfR1BEWFFGYjdyYnNXdTBXR0VDQVJVM0VkU1Y0Z3FKT1JQWkVBQTB0cXNzdkRlWk9DcE5yTEdNVVFLRjZTSkJqN3FyRjkxS1R4MkRkbk5VZXM2R01rYXgtOWFuRmgwUUJGSUQ5dktWSnBFeXVXdmxiX1VfNzNTZktoaTUxcTVLVU5sRENDTEs5VVJIeDM5ZV9KRURGZy1feUVNakJlX3d6RFI3NlhBMlBBa0ZRWW5Wc1g5UFE4NHpqMUNMVW8xR1hycFdMcUQtd29mS0JJRnZYdkNqcXBfVHdkcHFYS0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:06:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu says deal to release Hamas-held hostages has been reached - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Netanyahu Announces Deal for Release of Hamas-held Hostages</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png" alt="Supporters and family members of hostages kidnapped during the deadly October 7, 2023, attack on Israel by Hamas, gather next to a slogan formed of candles on a road during a protest ahead of a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, in Tel Aviv, Israel, on January 16, 2025" title="Supporters and family members of hostages kidnapped during the deadly October 7, 2023, attack on Israel by Hamas, gather next to a slogan formed of candles on a road during a protest ahead of a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, in Tel Aviv, Israel, on January 16, 2025"><figcaption>Supporters and family members of hostages during a protest in Tel Aviv, January 16, 2025 | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>The office of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced a deal has been reached for the release of hostages held by Hamas, with a political-security cabinet convening to discuss the details.</p><ul><li>Netanyahu's office confirmed agreements on a deal to release the hostages.</li><li>The families of the hostages have been informed and preparations are being made for their return.</li><li>If approved, the truce would start on Sunday, enabling the exchange of Israeli hostages for Palestinian prisoners.</li><li>The deal was mediated by Qatar and the United States, announced on Wednesday.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Prime Minister ordered the political-security cabinet to convene tomorrow (Friday). The government will then convene to approve the deal,” Netanyahu’s office stated.</blockquote><p>Should this deal be approved, it could mark a significant step towards a ceasefire and a resolution to the ongoing conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/netanyahu-says-deal-to-release-hamas-held-hostages-has-been-reached/article69107335.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/netanyahu-says-deal-to-release-hamas-held-hostages-has-been-reached/article69107335.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning Regarding '10-Point Diktat' For Indian Cricket Team .. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning Regarding '10-Point Diktat' For Indian Cricket Team Stars</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/qcmgaih_sc_625x300_17_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605' alt='BCCI's New Policy' /><figcaption>File photo of Indian cricket team © AFP</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has enforced a new policy for senior players following recent disappointing performances to promote discipline and team unity.</p><ul><li>Restrictions introduced on personal shoots and endorsements during tours.</li><li>Players must attend BCCI functions and cannot leave practice sessions early.</li><li>Families allowed limited visits on long tours (only two weeks).</li><li>Mandatory participation in domestic matches for national team consideration.</li><li>Disciplinary actions outlined for non-compliance, including suspensions and fee deductions.</li></ul><blockquote>“All players are expected to adhere strictly to the above guidelines. Non-compliance may lead to disciplinary action as deemed appropriate by the BCCI.”</blockquote><p>This policy aims to ensure players remain committed to their training and the overall cricketing structure in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:57:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning Regarding '10-Point Diktat' For Indian Cricket Team Stars - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning For Indian Cricket Team Stars</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/qcmgaih_sc_625x300_17_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="'Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning For Indian Cricket Team Stars"><figcaption>File photo of Indian cricket team © AFP</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has introduced a strict new policy for senior cricketers, requiring adherence to a 10-point diktat in light of the team's recent performance issues. This policy includes restrictions on personal endorsements and mandates players to remain disciplined during tours.</p><ul><li>The BCCI restricts family and personal staff from tours to promote discipline and unity.</li><li>Players will be required to participate in domestic matches to be eligible for national selection.</li><li>Non-compliance may result in suspension and financial penalties.</li><li>Exceptions to the policy require approval from BCCI officials.</li></ul><blockquote>“This policy ensures that players remain connected to the domestic cricket ecosystem, fostering talent development, maintaining match fitness, and strengthening the overall domestic structure.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the BCCI's stringent new rules aim to reinforce discipline among players and enhance their commitment to the team, with clear consequences for non-adherence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:57:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China population shrinks for third year even with more babies born - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's Population Decline Continues Despite Increase in Births</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>China has reported a continued decrease in its population for the third consecutive year, even as the birth rate shows a slight increase.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The overall population has experienced a shrinkage, indicating a demographic crisis.</li>
  <li>Increased birth rates have not been sufficient to counterbalance the aging population.</li>
  <li>Government measures to encourage higher birth rates have yet to produce the desired results.</li>
  <li>Experts are concerned about the long-term economic implications of this trend.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This trend could lead to significant economic challenges in the future, including a shrinking workforce." - Demographic Expert</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing demographic shift highlights the complexity of population management and the urgent need for targeted policy interventions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/china-population-shrinks-for-third-year-even-with-more-babies-born/articleshow/117317118.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/china-population-shrinks-for-third-year-even-with-more-babies-born/articleshow/117317118.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Intent was to replace govt': Indian national gets 8 yrs of jail for White House attack plot - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian Man Sentenced to 8 Years for Plot to Attack the White House</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The article reports on the sentencing of an Indian national who attempted to carry out an attack on the White House. He has been sentenced to eight years in prison.</p><ul><li>The individual was found guilty of conspiracy to commit an attack.</li><li>The case highlights serious security concerns regarding threats to U.S. government buildings.</li><li>The defendant expressed intentions to replace the government.</li></ul><blockquote>“The intent was clear: to replace the government through violent means.”</blockquote><p>This case raises questions about national security and the effectiveness of preventive measures against potential threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/intent-was-to-replace-govt-indian-national-gets-8-yrs-for-white-house-attack-plot/articleshow/117316941.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/intent-was-to-replace-govt-indian-national-gets-8-yrs-for-white-house-attack-plot/articleshow/117316941.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian national sentenced for 8 years for Nazi-inspired attack on White House - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/intent-was-to-replace-govt-indian-national-gets-8-yrs-for-white-house-attack-plot/articleshow/117316941.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/intent-was-to-replace-govt-indian-national-gets-8-yrs-for-white-house-attack-plot/articleshow/117316941.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Says Israel Has Reached Deal To Return Hostages Held In Gaza - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Netanyahu's Office Says 'Deal To Release Hostages' Reached</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>January 25, 2025 <strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p>
<img title="Netanyahu's Office Says 'Deal To Release Hostages' Reached" alt="Netanyahu's Office Says 'Deal To Release Hostages' Reached" id="story_image_main" height="435" width="773" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/a6cgbh3_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_16_January_25.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=773,height=435">
<figcaption>Benjamin Netanyahu addressing the situation regarding hostages.</figcaption>
<p>The office of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced that a deal has been reached to release hostages held by Hamas, with plans for a political-security cabinet meeting to finalize the details.</p>
<ul>
  <li>A deal to release hostages has been negotiated, as confirmed by Netanyahu's office.</li>
  <li>The political-security cabinet is set to convene to approve the deal.</li>
  <li>Hamas has been accused of not complying with the agreement, which they deny.</li>
  <li>If the agreement is approved, it will include the exchange of Israeli hostages for Palestinian prisoners.</li>
  <li>The deal is expected to be finalized by the cabinet meeting on Friday.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Prime Minister ordered the political-security cabinet to convene tomorrow. The government will then convene to approve the deal." - Netanyahu's office</blockquote>
<p>This development signifies potential progress towards a resolution of the hostage situation and may lead to a broader truce in the ongoing conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-says-israel-has-reached-deal-to-return-hostages-held-in-gaza-7492349</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-says-israel-has-reached-deal-to-return-hostages-held-in-gaza-7492349</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:42:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Q3 results today: Wipro, Tech Mahindra, Jio Financial Services, SBI Life, others to announce earnings; check list - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wipro, Tech Mahindra, Jio Financial Services, SBI Life to Announce Q3 Earnings Today</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Upstox</p>
<p>Today, several key companies will reveal their financial results for the third quarter of the fiscal year, including major players in technology, finance, and insurance sectors.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Wipro Ltd</li>
  <li>Tech Mahindra Ltd</li>
  <li>Jio Financial Services Ltd</li>
  <li>SBI Life Insurance Company Ltd</li>
  <li>ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company Ltd</li>
  <li>Others including Tata Chemicals and Rajoo Engineers</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Reliance Industries posted a 7.4% increase in its December quarter net profit, supported by a rebound in retail business.</blockquote>
<p>This financial reporting day is significant as it reflects the performance of various sectors and can indicate economic trends based on the earnings reported.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/earnings/q3-results-wipro-tech-mahindra-jio-financial-services-others-to-announce-earnings-on-january-17-check-list/article-140837/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/earnings/q3-results-wipro-tech-mahindra-jio-financial-services-others-to-announce-earnings-on-january-17-check-list/article-140837/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:40:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infosys CEO asked about low salary hikes, toxic work culture. His response - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Infosys CEO Addresses Salary Hikes and Work Culture Concerns</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/Infosys_CEO_Salil_Parekh_1737081365033_1737081365294.png" alt="Infosys CEO and MD Salil Parekh addressed concerns about the company's work culture.(YouTube/Infosys)">
<figcaption>Infosys CEO and MD Salil Parekh addressed concerns about the company's work culture.(YouTube/Infosys)</figcaption>
<p>Infosys CEO Salil Parekh addressed employee concerns about the company's toxic work culture during the Q3 earnings call, emphasizing fair treatment amid allegations of low salaries.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Infosys reported a fiscal third quarter profit of ₹6,806 crore, up 11.46% YoY.</li>
  <li>Parekh responded to allegations of insufficient salary hikes and a poor work culture during the earnings call.</li>
  <li>Concerns escalated after comments from founder Narayana Murthy about young employees working excessive hours.</li>
  <li>Many former employees have accused Infosys of underpaying staff, particularly fresh graduates.</li>
  <li>Parekh insists that Infosys maintains a fair treatment policy for all employees.</li>
  <li>The company is on track to hire around 15,000 freshers in FY25.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In terms of the employee question, within Infosys we have a very clear approach to make sure that everyone is treated fairly.” - Salil Parekh</blockquote>
<p>The discussion highlights ongoing challenges at Infosys concerning employee satisfaction, attracting new talent, and maintaining a positive work environment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/infosys-ceo-salil-parekh-asked-about-low-salary-hikes-toxic-work-culture-his-response-101737081204834.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/infosys-ceo-salil-parekh-asked-about-low-salary-hikes-toxic-work-culture-his-response-101737081204834.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ahead of Champions Trophy selection, BCCI to probe Sanju Samson's Vijay Hazare Trophy no-show - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ahead of Champions Trophy selection, BCCI to probe Sanju Samson's Vijay Hazare Trophy no-show</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Several days before January 19, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117316696,imgsize-63274,width-400,resizemode-4/117316696.jpg" alt="Sanju Samson no-show" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Sanju Samson’s absence from the Vijay Hazare Trophy has raised concerns ahead of the Champions Trophy selection.</figcaption>
<p>As the national selectors prepare to choose the ODI team for the series against England and the ICC Champions Trophy, the BCCI is set to investigate Sanju Samson's decision to skip the Vijay Hazare Trophy. This absence could affect his selection chances.</p>
<ul>
  <li>BCCI displeased with Samson's non-participation in a critical domestic tournament.</li>
  <li>Kerala Cricket Association did not include him due to his unavailability for the preparatory camp.</li>
  <li>Selecting the Champions Trophy squad is crucial, and selectors seek a valid reason for his absence.</li>
  <li>In the past, players lost central contracts for similar reasons, raising the stakes for participation in domestic cricket.</li>
  <li>Samson is competing for one of the wicketkeeper spots against Rishabh Pant, KL Rahul, and Dhruv Jurel.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The selectors would want a valid reason. Otherwise, it will be difficult to consider him for the ODI season."</blockquote>
<p>The outcome of this investigation may shape the selectors' decisions, especially regarding the balance of the squad if Rahul is unfit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/ahead-of-champions-trophy-selection-bcci-to-probe-sanju-samsons-vijay-hazare-trophy-no-show/articleshow/117316723.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/ahead-of-champions-trophy-selection-bcci-to-probe-sanju-samsons-vijay-hazare-trophy-no-show/articleshow/117316723.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israeli PM Benjamin Netanyahu PM Netanyahu says Israel-Hamas deal to release hostages held in Gaza reached - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel and Hamas Reach Hostage Deal, Ceasefire Likely</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> HT News</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/FILES-POLAND-ISRAEL-DIPLOMACY-0_1737080669232_1737080683108.jpg" alt="(FILES) Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu delivers a speech during the opening of the Permanent Exhibition SHOAH at the former Nazi death camp Auschwitz-Birkenau State Museum,.(AFP)" title="(FILES) Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu delivers a speech during the opening of the Permanent Exhibition SHOAH at the former Nazi death camp Auschwitz-Birkenau State Museum,.(AFP)"><figcaption>(FILES) Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu delivers a speech during the opening of the Permanent Exhibition SHOAH at the former Nazi death camp Auschwitz-Birkenau State Museum,.(AFP)</figcaption></img><p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced that a deal to return hostages held in the Gaza Strip has been reached, marking a significant step towards a ceasefire after 15 months of conflict.</p><ul><li>Netanyahu plans to convene his security Cabinet to approve the agreement.</li><li>The deal aims to pause the ongoing war and facilitate the release of hostages in exchange for Palestinian prisoners.</li><li>Since the conflict began on October 7, 2023, significant casualties have occurred on both sides.</li><li>Hamas has denied claims that it reneged on parts of the agreement.</li><li>The ceasefire agreement faces opposition from Netanyahu's far-right coalition partners.</li></ul><blockquote>“The State of Israel is committed to achieving all the goals of the war, including the return of all our hostages – both living and dead,” - Prime Minister's Office</blockquote><p>This agreement could potentially alleviate further violence and allow displaced Palestinians to return to their homes, emphasizing the fragile state of ceasefire negotiations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israeli-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-says-truce-and-hostage-deal-with-hamas-reached-101737080670257.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israeli-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-says-truce-and-hostage-deal-with-hamas-reached-101737080670257.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:27:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan attack: 20 teams formed to nab attacker, say Mumbai police - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/saif-ali-khan-attack-20-teams-formed-to-nab-attacker-say-mumbai-police/article69107279.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/saif-ali-khan-attack-20-teams-formed-to-nab-attacker-say-mumbai-police/article69107279.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infosys shares remain the top IT stock pick after Q3 results; Check new price targets - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/infosys-share-price-top-it-stock-pick-post-q3-results-adr-buy-sell-target-guidance-19541668.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/infosys-share-price-top-it-stock-pick-post-q3-results-adr-buy-sell-target-guidance-19541668.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:03:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian stock market: 10 key things that changed for market overnight - Gift Nifty, Reliance Q3 results to Infosys ADR - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian stock market: 10 key things that changed for market overnight - Gift Nifty, Reliance Q3 results to Infosys ADR</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The Indian stock market is set to open lower, influenced by declines in global markets, particularly following weak performances in Asian and US stocks. Despite recent gains, key upcoming events are on traders' radar.</p><img src='https://www.livemint.com/stock-market-image.jpg' alt='Stock Market Image'><figcaption>Market Overview</figcaption><p>Key headlines from the market include:</p><ul><li>Sensex rose 318.74 points to close at 77,042.82, while Nifty closed at 23,311.80.</li><li>Asian markets experienced declines ahead of key economic data from China.</li><li>Gift Nifty indicates a negative start for Indian indices after trading around 23,322.</li><li>Reliance Industries reported a Q3 profit of ₹18,540 crore, a 7.4% increase YoY.</li><li>Infosys’ Q3 net profit rose by 4.6%, totaling ₹6,806 crore, with raised revenue guidance for FY25.</li></ul><blockquote>“While Nifty has seen a three-day recovery, it remains below its 200 DMA at 23,963, with key support at 23,000.” - Prashanth Tapse, Senior VP (Research), Mehta Equities Ltd.</blockquote><p>The market's outlook remains cautious as investors await more data and reactions to corporate earnings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/indian-stock-market-10-key-things-that-changed-for-market-overnight-gift-nifty-reliance-q3-results-to-infosys-adr-11737040092214.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/indian-stock-market-10-key-things-that-changed-for-market-overnight-gift-nifty-reliance-q3-results-to-infosys-adr-11737040092214.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:41:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lancet commission proposes new definition for obesity: All you need to know - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lancet Commission Proposes New Definition for Obesity: Key Insights</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Lancet</p><p>A new definition and method for diagnosing obesity has been proposed by the Lancet Diabetes &amp; Endocrinology Commission, moving beyond the BMI standard to better reflect health outcomes related to body fat.</p><ul><li>The traditional BMI measurement may lead to over- and under-diagnosis of obesity.</li><li>A new category called Preclinical Obesity has been introduced for individuals with excess body fat but no ongoing illness.</li><li>Clinical obesity is defined as a chronic illness impacting organ functions.</li><li>Evaluation requires multiple physical measurements and assessments by a doctor.</li><li>The Indian definition of obesity will maintain stage classifications instead of the new proposed categories.</li></ul><blockquote>Dr. Anoop Misra stated, “We saw that Indians would get diabetes... even at lower BMI due to higher body fat percentages.”</blockquote><p>The new definitions aim to improve diagnosis and management strategies for obesity, particularly in diverse populations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-health/lancet-new-definition-obesity-9782591/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-health/lancet-new-definition-obesity-9782591/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:32:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8th Pay Commission approved: What does it mean? Who will benefit after Cabinet nod? Key facts - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8th Pay Commission approved: What does it mean? Who will benefit after Cabinet nod? Key facts</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/INDIA-MARKETS-RUPEE-0_1737075431887_1737075444921.JPG" alt="Over one crore Central employees and pensioners are set to benefit from the setting of the 8th Pay Commission. (REUTERS)"><figcaption>Over one crore Central employees and pensioners are set to benefit from the setting of the 8th Pay Commission. (REUTERS)</figcaption><p>The Union Cabinet, led by PM Narendra Modi, has approved the establishment of the 8th Pay Commission to revise salaries of central government employees and pensioners, ahead of the 2025 Union Budget and Delhi assembly elections.</p><ul><li>Approximately 49 lakh central government employees and 65 lakh pensioners will benefit from the new commission.</li><li>The 7th Pay Commission was established in 2016, with a term ending in 2026.</li><li>The decision is expected to improve the quality of life and boost consumption, according to PM Modi.</li><li>Consultations with stakeholders will be held for appointing the commission members.</li></ul><blockquote>“Setting up the 8th Pay Commission well before the term of the 7th Pay Commission ends in 2026 will give us sufficient time to receive recommendations,” - Ashwini Vaishnaw.</blockquote><p>This timely decision aims to ensure timely salary revisions and enhance overall economic conditions for millions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/8th-pay-commission-approved-what-does-it-mean-who-will-benefit-after-cabinet-nod-key-facts-101737075146106.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/8th-pay-commission-approved-what-does-it-mean-who-will-benefit-after-cabinet-nod-key-facts-101737075146106.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:30:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Republic Day sale 2025: Get up to 35% off and more on top load washing machines with innovative technology | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/gadgets/amazon-republic-day-sale-2025-get-up-to-35-off-and-more-on-top-load-washing-machines-with-innovative-technology-11737028749441.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/gadgets/amazon-republic-day-sale-2025-get-up-to-35-off-and-more-on-top-load-washing-machines-with-innovative-technology-11737028749441.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:30:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US CDC recommends faster testing for bird flu in hospitalized patients - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQdW1zTm0xY1cxa3QtRzhXbWJzMVNEcjJTZGdWd3FuYTlRVEhWZXFqaG9MTVQ2a0prekcwN1k3OG5MeHFDWS05MUtoS2dFdUR0bEJjSVYya0t6elBPY0dWOHM3M2h6amN3ejV5WWF6dmM3ZTI5UUltZnNZZm9NanJCRWdVaEdpckdiMGZxSkM1a2NFb0ZlZDY1bXU2RVJ3NU1zZzM2UXVhNlVfc2xib3pXSHhSQjR0OGhoNF81Z3A2eDcwblViZVRSTWJiR1pLRHdKWEVxLdIB2gFBVV95cUxOaVZvRzU2dnZ5U0RybkRpaFNPTko4ZHotSjVTRlpsUFdjOUwxaktOaXhBMVFnYm0zeEIwNS1kUXlDRGprdVBaRGpKWVBKY084eWo5cENuWW1CdHlWVTRhUnlzOWQ4MWtObU9lVnpvakxkLTZuZDNkT0FIOENGSjU1SXh1TUlob3U0SWVEcEhaU1k0aTJfVDJEVkhvRmV5NW5FcEdWZ3FndHFuMHd6a1hGbkFSMS1hVzNWUU11UWI0U0xiVGRja2ZVdGZfeDQ0V3JvdnNBck1zVzQ2dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQdW1zTm0xY1cxa3QtRzhXbWJzMVNEcjJTZGdWd3FuYTlRVEhWZXFqaG9MTVQ2a0prekcwN1k3OG5MeHFDWS05MUtoS2dFdUR0bEJjSVYya0t6elBPY0dWOHM3M2h6amN3ejV5WWF6dmM3ZTI5UUltZnNZZm9NanJCRWdVaEdpckdiMGZxSkM1a2NFb0ZlZDY1bXU2RVJ3NU1zZzM2UXVhNlVfc2xib3pXSHhSQjR0OGhoNF81Z3A2eDcwblViZVRSTWJiR1pLRHdKWEVxLdIB2gFBVV95cUxOaVZvRzU2dnZ5U0RybkRpaFNPTko4ZHotSjVTRlpsUFdjOUwxaktOaXhBMVFnYm0zeEIwNS1kUXlDRGprdVBaRGpKWVBKY084eWo5cENuWW1CdHlWVTRhUnlzOWQ4MWtObU9lVnpvakxkLTZuZDNkT0FIOENGSjU1SXh1TUlob3U0SWVEcEhaU1k0aTJfVDJEVkhvRmV5NW5FcEdWZ3FndHFuMHd6a1hGbkFSMS1hVzNWUU11UWI0U0xiVGRja2ZVdGZfeDQ0V3JvdnNBck1zVzQ2dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:16:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Criminal': Journalist forced out of Antony Blinken's presser over question on Gaza | Video - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Journalist Disrupts Antony Blinken's Press Conference Over Gaza Conflict</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/blinken_presser_sam_husseini_1737074402274_1737074433471.jpg" alt="Sam Husseini, an independent journalist, was forcibly picked up and taken out by security personnel after he interrupted Blinken's press briefing.(X/@ryangrim and AFP)"><figcaption>Sam Husseini, an independent journalist, was forcibly picked up and taken out by security personnel after he interrupted Blinken's press briefing.(X/@ryangrim and AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>During a press briefing, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken was interrupted by independent journalist Sam Husseini, who criticized the US's stance on the Gaza conflict and demanded accountability for the death toll affecting Palestinians.</p><ul><li>Husseini shouted, “Criminal… Why aren't you in The Hague?”</li><li>Several journalists interrupted Blinken's final press conference as he defended his handling of the conflict.</li><li>Husseini was forcibly removed by security personnel, voicing distress during the removal.</li><li>The briefing was marred by calls for accountability regarding the slaughter of over 46,000 Palestinians due to ongoing military actions.</li><li>A truce between Israel and Hamas was recently negotiated, to exchange hostages.</li></ul><blockquote>“You're hurting me,” said Husseini as security personnel picked him up.</blockquote><blockquote>“Why did you keep the bombs flowing when we had a deal in May?” asked journalist Max Blumenthal.</blockquote><p>The confrontation illustrates rising tensions and accountability demands regarding US foreign policy in the Middle East and concerns over humanitarian crises in Gaza.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/criminal-journalist-forced-out-of-antony-blinkens-presser-over-question-on-gaza-video-101737071789925.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/criminal-journalist-forced-out-of-antony-blinkens-presser-over-question-on-gaza-video-101737071789925.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:12:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Actor Saif Ali Khan stabbed inside Bandra house: Here are 5 unanswered questions - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/actor-saif-ali-khan-stabbed-inside-bandra-house-here-5-unanswered-questions-101737072461555.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/actor-saif-ali-khan-stabbed-inside-bandra-house-here-5-unanswered-questions-101737072461555.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:42:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI cracks whip, makes domestic cricket participation mandatory in 10-point diktat; lists IPL ban as part of punishment - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Cracks Whip on Domestic Cricket Participation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/TOPSHOT-CRICKET-AUS-IND-7_1737050569633_1737050582768.jpg" alt="India's Jasprit Bumrah reacts during trophy ceremony" title="India's Jasprit Bumrah reacts during trophy ceremony"><figcaption>India's Jasprit Bumrah (L) reacts with teammates during the trophy ceremony after the fifth cricket Test match between Australia and India at The SCG in Sydney on January 5 (AFP)</figcaption><p>In response to recent poor performances, the BCCI has announced stricter protocols for the Indian cricket team, prioritizing domestic cricket participation and imposing several restrictions to enhance team discipline.</p><ul><li>Mandatory participation in domestic cricket for players to be eligible for national selection.</li><li>Restriction on family and personal staff presence during tours.</li><li>Bar on individual endorsements during series.</li><li>Only a two-week window allowed for family visits during overseas tours.</li><li>Disciplinary actions will be taken against non-compliance, including potential bans from the IPL.</li></ul><blockquote>“Any exceptions or deviations must be pre-approved by the Chairman of the Selection Committee and Head Coach. Non-compliance may lead to disciplinary action as deemed appropriate by the BCCI,”</blockquote><p>These measures aim to create a focused and disciplined environment for the players to enhance their performance on the pitch.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/bcci-cracks-whip-makes-domestic-cricket-participation-mandatory-in-10-point-diktat-lists-ipl-ban-as-part-of-punishment-101737050535209.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/bcci-cracks-whip-makes-domestic-cricket-participation-mandatory-in-10-point-diktat-lists-ipl-ban-as-part-of-punishment-101737050535209.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:41:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pre-market action: Here's the trade setup for today's session - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxOOWdPS2E1WjVCcTduelpYTkszVkZCbWo1ODVxeEN4aGdRU1AxN1g2VjBHNmJ2cWpfOHVSUlZTdWJEVHEwTlVrV0xvdkstMHI4OW82SDQzeXJqWTBpSnQ3Q0VVU285QnY2Y3FPS19zN0VKd0pqS1lpUGtfeWNhWVN1Z2t6NDhIcy1lbTZ1Zy1HdW9rRE1PRm8wYzZlSTlhN3dlZm1IdUhCY2FRUFV5U3h0UVlkZlI5ZWIwaDlHRzBTUG5pdlFHTDlDbS1QQWbSAdIBQVVfeXFMT19ld0JVVnVFOUd3dXpHeVhGNEZ6emtMNUtSVHRaNERKLTJoc3E5Z1k3bkhQSzllMnFQUzdJZGQ1V010ZnZZVWV0bGFkVnJLbjJveWVlX0stTklPYjdBSmN4cjJZRU16UVpnUHQyZ1RZLXRTS2VhVVZ6cWl3S1ZFbVppYTBsM2NxMTBMUkFFRmJERUtMajJ6cHc2VjdTWVgzZWdyRjV0NnV3MWlfUWlwZk9ic3h2T2s1WUstWXBVa3YyTE9kT1BIOEp6T1dVeHRackVR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxOOWdPS2E1WjVCcTduelpYTkszVkZCbWo1ODVxeEN4aGdRU1AxN1g2VjBHNmJ2cWpfOHVSUlZTdWJEVHEwTlVrV0xvdkstMHI4OW82SDQzeXJqWTBpSnQ3Q0VVU285QnY2Y3FPS19zN0VKd0pqS1lpUGtfeWNhWVN1Z2t6NDhIcy1lbTZ1Zy1HdW9rRE1PRm8wYzZlSTlhN3dlZm1IdUhCY2FRUFV5U3h0UVlkZlI5ZWIwaDlHRzBTUG5pdlFHTDlDbS1QQWbSAdIBQVVfeXFMT19ld0JVVnVFOUd3dXpHeVhGNEZ6emtMNUtSVHRaNERKLTJoc3E5Z1k3bkhQSzllMnFQUzdJZGQ1V010ZnZZVWV0bGFkVnJLbjJveWVlX0stTklPYjdBSmN4cjJZRU16UVpnUHQyZ1RZLXRTS2VhVVZ6cWl3S1ZFbVppYTBsM2NxMTBMUkFFRmJERUtMajJ6cHc2VjdTWVgzZWdyRjV0NnV3MWlfUWlwZk9ic3h2T2s1WUstWXBVa3YyTE9kT1BIOEp6T1dVeHRackVR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to view rare planetary parade, on until Feb, in Bengaluru - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How to view rare planetary parade, on until Feb, in Bengaluru</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 17 January 2025, 00:33 IST</p><p>In a rare celestial event, six planets can be seen in the night sky at the same time from Bengaluru, lasting until February 13. Experts inform that the best viewing times are from 7:30 PM, with specific apps recommended for locating the planets.</p><ul><li>The planetary parade is visible with the naked eye, including Venus, Mars, Jupiter, and Saturn.</li><li>Uranus and Neptune require a telescope to be viewed.</li><li>Stargazing tours are organized by local astronomy groups for better observation.</li></ul><blockquote>“The planets are aligned in the ecliptic plane but not in a straight line.” - Chrisphin Karthick, Indian Institute of Astrophysics</blockquote><p>This event encourages public engagement in astronomy and provides a unique opportunity for stargazing enthusiasts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/bengaluru/how-to-view-rare-planetary-parade-on-until-feb-in-b-luru-3359375</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/bengaluru/how-to-view-rare-planetary-parade-on-until-feb-in-b-luru-3359375</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:33:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infosys ADR falls 6% overnight post Q3 results, will Indian shares follow suit? - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Infosys ADR Falls 6% Overnight After Q3 Results</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 17, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="Infosys ADR falls 6% overnight post Q3 results, will Indian shares follow suit?" title="Infosys ADR falls 6% overnight post Q3 results, will Indian shares follow suit?" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Stock performance of Infosys following Q3 results.</figcaption><p>The American Depository Receipts (ADRs) of Infosys Ltd fell by 6% overnight after the company announced its December quarter results. Despite revising revenue growth guidance higher for the third consecutive quarter, the shares declined.</p><ul><li>Infosys revised its revenue growth forecast for FY2025 to 4.5%-5% from 3.75%-4.5%.</li><li>The EBIT margin guidance remains unchanged at 20%-22%.</li><li>Infosys shares in India dropped 1.5% just before the earnings announcement.</li><li>Organic Services revenue fell by 0.9% sequentially.</li><li>Revenue from the top five clients decreased by 6.4% in US Dollar terms.</li><li>Attrition rate increased to 13.7%, with expectations of worsening conditions.</li><li>The company secured $2.5 billion in new deals for the quarter, despite a 32% drop in Total Contract Value year-on-year.</li></ul><blockquote>“Infosys won deals worth $2.5 billion in the quarter... yet the nine-month Total Contract Value is down 32% year-on-year.”</blockquote><p>The significant fall in ADRs raises concerns about how Indian shares might respond in the coming days.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/infosys-share-price-us-listed-adr-drops-q3-results-impact-analyst-target-guidance-19541652.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/infosys-share-price-us-listed-adr-drops-q3-results-impact-analyst-target-guidance-19541652.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 23:59:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI issues curbs on personal staff, family travel, endorsement shoots during tours for centrally-contracted cricketers; violators may face IPL ban - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI issues curbs on personal staff, family travel, endorsement shoots during tours for centrally-contracted cricketers; violators may face IPL ban</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 - <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/INDIAN-CRICKET-TEAM-CROP-AP-A.jpg?w=640" alt="India's Rohit Sharma, Rishabh Pant, Shubman Gill and Virat Kohli wait for play to start on day three of the third Test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane, Australia. (AP Photo) BCCI" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>India's Rohit Sharma, Rishabh Pant, Shubman Gill and Virat Kohli wait for play to start on day three of the third Test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane, Australia. (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>The BCCI has introduced ten new guidelines for centrally-contracted players following a review meeting after their defeat in Australia. These guidelines impose strict rules on family travel, personal staff, endorsement work, and player discipline during tours.</p><ul><li>Mandatory participation in domestic tournaments for selection.</li><li>Restrictions on family travel and personal staff presence during tours.</li><li>Players prohibited from returning home prematurely or engaging in endorsement shoots during tours.</li><li>Enforcement of unity and discipline within the team dynamic.</li><li>Players required to travel only with the team.</li><li>Families allowed on tours for a maximum of 14 days if the tour exceeds 45 days.</li><li>Attendance at all practice sessions is now mandatory.</li></ul><blockquote>“Players must stay with the team until the scheduled end of the match series or tour, even if matches conclude earlier than planned. This ensures unity, fosters team bonding, and avoids disruption to team dynamics.”</blockquote><p>These measures aim to strengthen team cohesion and discipline among players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/bcci-policy-india-curbs-personal-staff-family-domestic-ipl-ban-9783112/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/bcci-policy-india-curbs-personal-staff-family-domestic-ipl-ban-9783112/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 23:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India: Wearable Tech Mimics Pain to Detect Stress - OpenGov Asia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wearable Tech Mimics Pain to Detect Stress</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> OpenGov Asia</p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://cdn.opengovasia.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Article-Sam_Ind-Jan-17-emb.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="258"><figcaption>Image credits: Press Information Bureau</figcaption><p>Scientists from JNCASR in Bengaluru have developed a wearable device that senses stress by mimicking the human body's response to pain, paving the way for efficient health monitoring systems.</p><ul><li>The device uses a silver wire network embedded in stretchable material.</li><li>It detects strain and learns from it, mimicking pain responses seen in the human body.</li><li>This adaptive ability allows it to adjust its electrical response over time.</li><li>The technology could transform healthcare and robotics by providing real-time stress detection.</li><li>It's inspired by nociceptors, which detect pain and trigger protective responses.</li><li>Published in Materials Horizons by the Royal Society of Chemistry.</li></ul><blockquote>“This novel wearable device represents a significant step forward in the development of more intelligent, adaptable technology.”</blockquote><p>This development signifies a major leap in creating technology that is more aligned with human physiological responses, enhancing the possibilities of healthcare and robotic applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://opengovasia.com/2025/01/17/india-wearable-tech-mimics-pain-to-detect-stress/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://opengovasia.com/2025/01/17/india-wearable-tech-mimics-pain-to-detect-stress/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 23:43:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real Madrid player ratings vs. Celta Vigo: That's why they signed Endrick! Brazilian teenager's heroics save Los Blancos in extra time to secure Copa del Rey win - GOAL English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Real Madrid player ratings vs. Celta Vigo: That's why they signed Endrick!</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] &nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><img src="https://assets.goal.com/images/v3/bltc23350b8df0d34d4/GOAL%20-%20Multiple%20Images%20-%203%20Stacked%20-%20Facebook(220).png?auto=webp&amp;format=pjpg&amp;width=3840&amp;quality=60" alt="Real Madrid Celta Vigo GFX "><figcaption>Getty</figcaption><p>The 18-year-old scored twice in extra time to save his side from cup embarrassment at home.</p><p>Endrick enjoyed his first signature Real Madrid moment Thursday evening, bashing home an extra time winner - and then completing a brace - to carry Los Blancos past Celta Vigo in an eventual 5-2 victory.</p><ul><li>Real Madrid dominated for 80 minutes but faced struggles late in regulation.</li><li>The team regained control in extra time, led by Endrick's critical goals.</li><li>Celta Vigo capitalized on a mistake to equalize but couldn't maintain momentum.</li><li>Endrick's performance solidified his potential and value in the team.</li></ul><blockquote>“This was far from a convincing showing.”</blockquote><p>Overall, the match showcased the resilience of Real Madrid and young talents like Endrick whom the club signed to make a significant impact.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.goal.com/en-in/lists/real-madrid-player-ratings-vs-celta-vigo-endrick-jude-bellingham/blt2e15cce422246784</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.goal.com/en-in/lists/real-madrid-player-ratings-vs-celta-vigo-endrick-jude-bellingham/blt2e15cce422246784</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 23:11:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>