<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 06:20:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 06:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Squad Announcement For Champions Trophy 2025, LIVE Updates: New Vice-Captain To Be Named? - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Squad Announcement For Champions Trophy 2025, LIVE Updates: Injury Concerns Provide Fresh Twist</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 17, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>This article discusses the latest updates on the India squad announcement for the upcoming Champions Trophy, highlighting injury concerns that add an unexpected twist to the preparations.</p><ul><li>Announcement of the India squad for the 2025 Champions Trophy.</li><li>Discussion of injury concerns affecting key players.</li><li>Live updates and insights on team composition.</li></ul><blockquote>"Injuries could impact the final squad and strategy for the tournament."</blockquote><p>The ongoing updates suggest that the team's final composition might be heavily influenced by player fitness and form as the event approaches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/india-squad-announcement-for-champions-trophy-2025-england-series-live-updates-7497382</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/india-squad-announcement-for-champions-trophy-2025-england-series-live-updates-7497382</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 05:48:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Republic Day Sale: Grab the best offers on ACs from brands like Lloyd, Daikin, Panasonic and LG, up to 60% off - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amazon Republic Day Sale: Grab the best offers on ACs from brands like Lloyd, Daikin, Panasonic and LG, up to 60% off</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/air_conditioners_1736940033956_1736940043504.png" alt="Shop the Amazon Sale 2025 for premium ACs at amazing prices from trusted brands like Daikin and Panasonic!" title="Shop the Amazon Sale 2025 for premium ACs at amazing prices from trusted brands like Daikin and Panasonic!" /><figcaption>Shop the Amazon Sale 2025 for premium ACs at amazing prices from trusted brands like Daikin and Panasonic!</figcaption><p>The ongoing Amazon Sale 2025 offers savvy shoppers a chance to purchase premium air conditioners from top brands at significant discounts, making it an ideal time to upgrade cooling options.</p><ul><li>Massive discounts on air conditioners from brands like Lloyd, Daikin, Panasonic, and more.</li><li>Energy-efficient models with advanced features available for various room sizes.</li><li>Convenient online shopping and doorstep delivery promote easy access to deals.</li></ul><blockquote>"This sale ensures unmatched value for money in premium air conditioning."</blockquote><p>Shop smart with exclusive deals during the Amazon Republic Day Sale and get the best options for your cooling needs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-republic-day-sale-grab-the-best-offers-on-acs-from-brands-like-lloyd-daikin-panasonic-and-lg-up-to-60-off-101736935439753.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-republic-day-sale-grab-the-best-offers-on-acs-from-brands-like-lloyd-daikin-panasonic-and-lg-up-to-60-off-101736935439753.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 05:30:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WATCH: Canadian man’s doorbell camera captures audio, video of meteorite crashing Earth - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WATCH: Canadian man’s doorbell camera captures audio, video of meteorite crashing Earth</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CBC News</p><p>An incredible event unfolded as Joe Velaidum recorded both video and audio of a meteorite crashing to Earth, marking what scientists believe to be the first documentation of such an event.</p><ul><li>A Canadian man's doorbell camera captured the rare event of a meteorite landing.</li><li>The meteorite is classified as an ordinary chondrite and is the first recorded from Prince Edward Island.</li><li>Velaidum had been standing at the impact spot just minutes before the meteorite struck.</li><li>Experts confirmed the authenticity of the meteorite after initial skepticism from Velaidum's family.</li><li>This documentation provides new insights into the natural history of Prince Edward Island.</li></ul><blockquote>“As far as we know, it’s the first time that a meteorite falling to Earth has been recorded on video, with sound.” - Chris Herd, Geologist</blockquote><p>The remarkable capture not only showcases a unique scientific milestone but also deepens our understanding of natural events in this region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/canadian-man-camera-capture-audio-video-of-meteorite-crashing-earth-viral-9785396/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/canadian-man-camera-capture-audio-video-of-meteorite-crashing-earth-viral-9785396/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 05:18:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to glimpse a parade of planets in the January night sky - Deccan Chronicle]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How to Glimpse a Parade of Planets in the January Night Sky</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> AP News</p><p>Six planets grace the sky this month in what’s known as a planetary parade, visible to the naked eye. The planets align on one side of the sun, offering a spectacular view for observers.</p><ol><li>Venus, Mars, Jupiter, and Saturn are visible without special equipment.</li><li>Uranus and Neptune require binoculars or telescopes to spot.</li><li>The best time for viewing is a few hours after sunset on clear nights.</li><li>Venus and Saturn will appear especially close, just two degrees apart.</li><li>Stargazing apps may enhance the viewing experience.</li></ol><blockquote>“It gives us a little bit better sense of our place in the solar system and the universe.” - Kevin Williams, planetarium director</blockquote><p>As planets gradually exit through the spring, this astrological event reminds us of our place in the cosmos.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/world/how-to-glimpse-a-parade-of-planets-in-the-january-night-sky-1854861</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanchronicle.com/world/how-to-glimpse-a-parade-of-planets-in-the-january-night-sky-1854861</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 05:00:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kolkata doctor rape and murder case hearing LIVE updates: Court likely to pronounce judgment in R.G. Kar case today - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/west-bengal/rg-kar-doctor-rape-and-murder-case-hearing-updates-january-18/article69111615.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/west-bengal/rg-kar-doctor-rape-and-murder-case-hearing-updates-january-18/article69111615.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 04:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[33 hostages, 737 prisoners, 42 days: Phase 1 of Israel-Hamas Gaza ceasefire deal | Key details - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>33 Hostages, 737 Prisoners, 42 Days: Phase 1 of Israel-Hamas Gaza Ceasefire Deal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Israel_Gaza_1735842380580_1737173592806.jpg" alt="The ceasefire deal will also witness Israel allowing displaced Palestinians to return home via electronic checkpoints. (AP)" title="The ceasefire deal will also witness Israel allowing displaced Palestinians to return home via electronic checkpoints. (AP)"><figcaption>The ceasefire deal will also witness Israel allowing displaced Palestinians to return home via electronic checkpoints. (AP)</figcaption></figure><p>This article details the ceasefire agreement between Israel and Hamas, marking a significant pause in the ongoing war in Gaza. The deal is set to initiate a 42-day truce beginning January 19, involving the release of hostages and prisoners.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The ceasefire will last for 42 days, during which 33 hostages will be released by Hamas.</li><li>In exchange, Israel will release 737 prisoners and detainees.</li><li>Hostages will be evaluated by medical professionals upon release.</li><li>Israeli forces will withdraw from densely populated areas of Gaza during this period.</li><li>Electronic checkpoints will be set up for returning displaced Palestinians.</li><li>Phase two negotiations are expected to start halfway through the first phase.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes:</h2><blockquote>“We hope that this will be the last page of the war and we hope that all parties will commit to implementing all the terms of this agreement,” - Qatari PM Sheikh Mohammed.</blockquote><p>This ceasefire represents a critical moment in mitigating tensions and hopes for a long-term resolution to the conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/33-hostages-95-prisoners-42-days-phase-1-of-israel-hamas-gaza-ceasefire-deal-key-details-101737173186357.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/33-hostages-95-prisoners-42-days-phase-1-of-israel-hamas-gaza-ceasefire-deal-key-details-101737173186357.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 04:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New SUV Brand Enters India! Should Tata & Mahindra Worry? - MotorOctane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinfast Launches New EV SUVs in India – Should Tata & Mahindra Be Concerned?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today <strong>Source:</strong> MotorOctane</p>
<img src="https://motoroctane.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Auto-Expo-2025-Website-44.png" alt="Vinfast Auto Expo – VF7">
<figcaption>Vinfast Auto Expo – VF7</figcaption>
<p>Today marks the entry of a new Vietnamese automotive brand, Vinfast, in India. The brand has introduced two new electric vehicles (EVs) showcasing their innovations at the Auto Expo.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Vinfast launched the VF7 and VF6 electric SUVs at the Auto Expo in India.</li>
  <li>The VF7 is locally assembled in Tamil Nadu and features a modern design and several high-tech features.</li>
  <li>Pricing for the VF7 has yet to be announced, while the vehicle is equipped with a 73 kWh battery.</li>
  <li>The VF6 aims to compete with established models like the Hyundai Creta EV and BYD Atto 3, and includes a 59.6 kWh battery with a range of up to 400 km.</li>
  <li>Both models feature advanced tech such as ADAS, large infotainment screens, and luxurious interiors.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The new Vinfast SUV gets a 59.6 kWh battery pack and offers a range of up to 400 km on a single charge internationally.</blockquote>
<p>This entry of Vinfast into the Indian market introduces significant competition for existing brands like Tata and Mahindra, especially in the rapidly evolving EV sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://motoroctane.com/news/282586-new-suv-brand-enters-india-should-tata-mahindra-worry</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motoroctane.com/news/282586-new-suv-brand-enters-india-should-tata-mahindra-worry</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 04:17:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Squad Announcement For Champions Trophy 2025, LIVE Updates: Three Uncapped Star To Make Cut? - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQMWViSHNRZGhKVjhJN282UVdWLXZNSGg3bGNIcWplWldhMTlkR2dRMFdRc3ZSQ1ZXSXVrSTUyRDJYMG15UG9CTDFteUM4SThJTEo4Z0R1R2NJZm9KR0dqTHRFbW1BLThMSzQyeW1rZnJJTWVTQVlPUlJvMUs1NjNOQXZnTTJ4TE1HSmJVME9jdkJBVXdqamZadldVVzQ2eVZ6Q1FZNGlWcV8zMTc4dURjUGJ5SVpXbHB3QzRQb1hjZFRWUjVuUEpUVy1MVm02TENNbFHSAdoBQVVfeXFMTm01R1JZMkRndjJCdGtMck9WRHQxekRWQnJRbTJxM0xoSE9BdnNOdlRscklBNWplV1BWcndUYk9FQWN2eWM5S0VPVDc4RWxZbktkV0xXc0t5alNsUjdiaWs4eTdpV3VwdGNKOFMwRHRrTG1udWhfM1pkbk1HX2VuRWJOMHFZTGp5VXk2eTdIUkNIdTV3Z3Z5QklCeThhTjFBbF9kanZLT0lvZGFEUmF2S3BVYnU3X1dyQ0VqQW5xU0NMVG9kbHF2bFY4amVja1NsMUZRVk9GaXkyeHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQMWViSHNRZGhKVjhJN282UVdWLXZNSGg3bGNIcWplWldhMTlkR2dRMFdRc3ZSQ1ZXSXVrSTUyRDJYMG15UG9CTDFteUM4SThJTEo4Z0R1R2NJZm9KR0dqTHRFbW1BLThMSzQyeW1rZnJJTWVTQVlPUlJvMUs1NjNOQXZnTTJ4TE1HSmJVME9jdkJBVXdqamZadldVVzQ2eVZ6Q1FZNGlWcV8zMTc4dURjUGJ5SVpXbHB3QzRQb1hjZFRWUjVuUEpUVy1MVm02TENNbFHSAdoBQVVfeXFMTm01R1JZMkRndjJCdGtMck9WRHQxekRWQnJRbTJxM0xoSE9BdnNOdlRscklBNWplV1BWcndUYk9FQWN2eWM5S0VPVDc4RWxZbktkV0xXc0t5alNsUjdiaWs4eTdpV3VwdGNKOFMwRHRrTG1udWhfM1pkbk1HX2VuRWJOMHFZTGp5VXk2eTdIUkNIdTV3Z3Z5QklCeThhTjFBbF9kanZLT0lvZGFEUmF2S3BVYnU3X1dyQ0VqQW5xU0NMVG9kbHF2bFY4amVja1NsMUZRVk9GaXkyeHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 03:56:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Republic Day Sale ends tomorrow: Hurry! Get up to 50% off on multivitamins, collagen supplements, and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/amazon-republic-day-sale-ends-tomorrow-hurry-get-up-to-50-off-on-multivitamins-collagen-supplements-and-more-101736859201074.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/amazon-republic-day-sale-ends-tomorrow-hurry-get-up-to-50-off-on-multivitamins-collagen-supplements-and-more-101736859201074.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 03:30:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Republic Day Sale ends tomorrow: Hurry! Get up to 50% off on multivitamins, collagen supplements, and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/amazon-republic-day-sale-ends-tomorrow-hurry-get-up-to-50-off-on-multivitamins-collagen-supplements-and-more-101736859201074.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/amazon-republic-day-sale-ends-tomorrow-hurry-get-up-to-50-off-on-multivitamins-collagen-supplements-and-more-101736859201074.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 03:30:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi fog: Several trains, flights delayed; Rain, thunderstorm likely next week, says IMD - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AFBVV95cUxOM1kyME9mRUhKZ3NOZGVOdUNRekE4d2ZDUWhoRkEzMzAxN2pBSlJSQ0dHQl9sSWt1NkFVXy1BQ2RKWDFmeE9lSjlBMlZITnJ1MG80bFBINmc5bHBoWDhhd3JGSGdTZjBoVTNBbDM4bHg5RUVTMGF5RHZHY1Q5WjlLazlpMm5DOFBqazFISTBqaVE0YkNrV1dQUHdrLVNpdE1qTWtzU0UtNF9nR3FwclhiS2pzenpsWGdGUUc2ZGdDMjVuYzRJRzRBNW9NU3BfNFNJREx0Mk5Bd1RLU29sekdMR9IB5gFBVV95cUxNRVpNY3dyOFhNNmNkOVc4Mm5pcGlSZUdxa0tYdlBtUlBWSHd4b2pXV0xmX2cxZTVqbGZXekMwV3FmZ2c3M1VqcWNxYVMyWWFhRmdnZVlCWHl6X3BuaUMwV0Ruc3FjSVYxQmp6c1dpWVJFNy1UOEdIN3Q5Snc3a2Y4c28wWlRGRmlpTDJTNE5LX2NDNzd2cEoyZ3F5dzI4T1g0bFVPVDl4N0VQeHE5ZU16OExhcWJIdHM3V3lTLTBCemlnT1RIRUotczRNQlhLRjQwQXhfV253ZkltMFlXcEhVVjRhdVE3UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AFBVV95cUxOM1kyME9mRUhKZ3NOZGVOdUNRekE4d2ZDUWhoRkEzMzAxN2pBSlJSQ0dHQl9sSWt1NkFVXy1BQ2RKWDFmeE9lSjlBMlZITnJ1MG80bFBINmc5bHBoWDhhd3JGSGdTZjBoVTNBbDM4bHg5RUVTMGF5RHZHY1Q5WjlLazlpMm5DOFBqazFISTBqaVE0YkNrV1dQUHdrLVNpdE1qTWtzU0UtNF9nR3FwclhiS2pzenpsWGdGUUc2ZGdDMjVuYzRJRzRBNW9NU3BfNFNJREx0Mk5Bd1RLU29sekdMR9IB5gFBVV95cUxNRVpNY3dyOFhNNmNkOVc4Mm5pcGlSZUdxa0tYdlBtUlBWSHd4b2pXV0xmX2cxZTVqbGZXekMwV3FmZ2c3M1VqcWNxYVMyWWFhRmdnZVlCWHl6X3BuaUMwV0Ruc3FjSVYxQmp6c1dpWVJFNy1UOEdIN3Q5Snc3a2Y4c28wWlRGRmlpTDJTNE5LX2NDNzd2cEoyZ3F5dzI4T1g0bFVPVDl4N0VQeHE5ZU16OExhcWJIdHM3V3lTLTBCemlnT1RIRUotczRNQlhLRjQwQXhfV253ZkltMFlXcEhVVjRhdVE3UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 03:24:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who is Priya Saroj? 26-Year-Old Samajwadi Party MP Linked With Rinku Singh – In Pics - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who is Priya Saroj? A Look at the Young Samajwadi Party MP Linked to Cricketer Rinku Singh</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> January 18, 2025</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Zeenews</p><img src="https://english.cdn.zeenews.com/sites/default/files/2025/01/18/1637606-priyasarojmp.jpg" alt="Priya Saroj" width="100%" height="300"><figcaption>Priya Saroj, MP from Uttar Pradesh</figcaption><p>Priya Saroj, a 26-year-old MP from Uttar Pradesh, is gaining attention not only for her political achievements but also for alleged engagement rumors with cricketer Rinku Singh.</p><ul><li>Youngest MP from Uttar Pradesh.</li><li>Legal expert turned politician with a law degree from Amity University.</li><li>Daughter of Tufani Saroj, a seasoned politician.</li><li>Overcame election challenges, winning against incumbents by a significant margin.</li><li>Rumors of engagement with cricket star Rinku Singh.</li><li>Active member of the Parliamentary Committee on Social Justice and Empowerment.</li><li>Educational achievements include graduating from Delhi University.</li><li>Balancing traditional political lineage with a modern, educated persona.</li><li>Future prospects look bright as a role model for young leaders.</li></ul><blockquote>“Priya embodies a modern, educated leader, resonating with the youth.”</blockquote><p>Priya Saroj represents a new generation of politicians who blend traditional values with modern ideas, and her journey continues to inspire many.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/photos/sports/who-is-priya-saroj-26-year-old-samajwadi-party-mp-linked-with-rinku-singh-in-pics-2845359</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/photos/sports/who-is-priya-saroj-26-year-old-samajwadi-party-mp-linked-with-rinku-singh-in-pics-2845359</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 03:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bharat Mobility Global Auto Expo 2025 Day 2 live updates: Automakers drive sustainability with electric launches dominating the event - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxQVlNOM2V0aE5jZGY2cHlUNjlqemJncFZxaG9wNGJXMmpVU1FGTjdMNmtONXFMRzItbmw1bWlNVklhcWtPNGYxdG1QRVdHU1pEbmxuZXpwV1F6V0lic2ZBa05SY1p1aG5tdm9ESFp4a2V5TDA3S0RPZWZDT1pieU5hNmh5U3UtWGtOYTdFNTJ3VDlnaXpnLTJZbzV6Slo2N1AtSzZBUE1vNjJJdjFqU2R3ams2bUVXNk8wY0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxQVlNOM2V0aE5jZGY2cHlUNjlqemJncFZxaG9wNGJXMmpVU1FGTjdMNmtONXFMRzItbmw1bWlNVklhcWtPNGYxdG1QRVdHU1pEbmxuZXpwV1F6V0lic2ZBa05SY1p1aG5tdm9ESFp4a2V5TDA3S0RPZWZDT1pieU5hNmh5U3UtWGtOYTdFNTJ3VDlnaXpnLTJZbzV6Slo2N1AtSzZBUE1vNjJJdjFqU2R3ams2bUVXNk8wY0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 03:11:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Emergency box office collection day 1: Kangana Ranaut scores her biggest opening in 5 years with maiden solo directorial - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Emergency Box Office Collection Day 1: Kangana Ranaut Scores Her Biggest Opening in 5 Years</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 18, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Kangana_Ranaut_1736147393754_1737168571344.png" alt="Emergency Box Office Collection Day 1" title="Emergency box office collection day 1: Kangana Ranaut's maiden solo directorial scores her biggest opening in five years.">
<figcaption>Emergency box office collection day 1: Kangana Ranaut's maiden solo directorial scores her biggest opening in five years.</figcaption>
<p>The film 'Emergency', Kangana Ranaut's first solo directorial, has hit cinemas and opened with impressive figures, marking her biggest box office opening in five years.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The film opened at ₹2.35 crore on its first day.</li>
  <li>This surpasses her previous openings, including 'Tejas' which earned ₹1.25 crore and 'Dhaakad' with ₹1.20 crore.</li>
  <li>Emergency's storyline centers around the 1975 Emergency in India, with Kangana portraying Indira Gandhi.</li>
  <li>Despite its opening success, the film faced controversy and protests related to its content, particularly from the SGPC.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Kangana mentioned that the SGPC's demand for a ban on 'Emergency' is a complete harassment of "art and the artist."</blockquote>
<p>The debut of 'Emergency' stands out as a significant moment in Kangana's career, illustrating both the challenges and triumphs of filmmaking in a politically sensitive landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/emergency-box-office-collection-day-1-kangana-ranaut-scores-her-biggest-opening-in-5-years-101737168380022.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/emergency-box-office-collection-day-1-kangana-ranaut-scores-her-biggest-opening-in-5-years-101737168380022.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 03:06:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICC Champions Trophy 2025 Squad Announcement LIVE: Rohit continues as captain, Agarkar to end suspense on Bumrah, Nair - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAJBVV95cUxQd3ZUc1NXX2dqT3FITnpCZzJ1ZldOMS1aU3BEa3hza0VPR3ZKMEhCbTJOYXB4TThxOS1wY2tLTkNsWjd4blpVTUU3NU9jS1RGUno1MmJzZEkxLXptT21FTTZnRFU2dkpjNXNBOXNkcGRMQnFMeGprMGt1eUpoTDRoS3ZjdGpqQVA0SkdmRkk4SXN6THJrUkdDT3B5anN2cG8tdjIxY1JwN1V6ellxZFR2eGRFcGttYW9nVldaYWIyUF9rREZXWW96TGVOdkJ5MDdMQWRNa2dwQXI2dFNiTGVNeWNxNUVZR1dodFhHRDk3ak1uN3I2cU9iSnZlQnBkZHNvZ3M2Mlk1VWlOeXJj0gGSAkFVX3lxTE9DS0Q3OTNzdnlLemIxTHFxM25na3FtcWtnM2JZdklDaVBKUjJNUHo5M1NjYmJzSjZ1d2tJelRqY0lhejQzcjBvQTJqb2czUFhpeG9MQ2xWRGR4VGxDd0ZZd0FVWkpvdERzSW0xX0ZTMzh0QmxnTlpXQkhqMUFPNFctSmxOMTRwVjN5TEJWeEdoQWVIcXJ6a1BlV0hLTnFqSVBvdjhoSVBtX1Fjdmh0N3VJcEVwdU10UDdpX01hZ0JrRlNEeVJwZW50NWlpYUVOQnNWakZ0eTNBLV9xNnpGLXk4WjZaOWo3WENGSHRpUjRXS1ptMnN2cGJHYlRnM0FsVFF4azlEcmxxWm5lcHZmcTRselE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAJBVV95cUxQd3ZUc1NXX2dqT3FITnpCZzJ1ZldOMS1aU3BEa3hza0VPR3ZKMEhCbTJOYXB4TThxOS1wY2tLTkNsWjd4blpVTUU3NU9jS1RGUno1MmJzZEkxLXptT21FTTZnRFU2dkpjNXNBOXNkcGRMQnFMeGprMGt1eUpoTDRoS3ZjdGpqQVA0SkdmRkk4SXN6THJrUkdDT3B5anN2cG8tdjIxY1JwN1V6ellxZFR2eGRFcGttYW9nVldaYWIyUF9rREZXWW96TGVOdkJ5MDdMQWRNa2dwQXI2dFNiTGVNeWNxNUVZR1dodFhHRDk3ak1uN3I2cU9iSnZlQnBkZHNvZ3M2Mlk1VWlOeXJj0gGSAkFVX3lxTE9DS0Q3OTNzdnlLemIxTHFxM25na3FtcWtnM2JZdklDaVBKUjJNUHo5M1NjYmJzSjZ1d2tJelRqY0lhejQzcjBvQTJqb2czUFhpeG9MQ2xWRGR4VGxDd0ZZd0FVWkpvdERzSW0xX0ZTMzh0QmxnTlpXQkhqMUFPNFctSmxOMTRwVjN5TEJWeEdoQWVIcXJ6a1BlV0hLTnFqSVBvdjhoSVBtX1Fjdmh0N3VJcEVwdU10UDdpX01hZ0JrRlNEeVJwZW50NWlpYUVOQnNWakZ0eTNBLV9xNnpGLXk4WjZaOWo3WENGSHRpUjRXS1ptMnN2cGJHYlRnM0FsVFF4azlEcmxxWm5lcHZmcTRselE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 03:05:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Hindu Lit for Life 2025 Day 1 LIVE: I owe my father a lot for my “word ethic” says Shashi Tharoor - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Hindu Lit for Life 2025 Day 1: I owe my father a lot for my “word ethic” says Shashi Tharoor</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/xm0cp/article69111860.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/WhatsApp%20Image%202025-01-18%20at%2010.59.07.jpeg" alt="Shashi Tharoor in conversation"/><figcaption>A Wonderland of Words: Shashi Tharoor in conversation with L.V. Navaneeth at The Hindu Lit For Life 2025. | Photo Credit: R. Ragu</figcaption><p>The first day of The Hindu Lit for Life features a host of renowned authors including Shashi Tharoor, who discussed his new book “A Wonderland of Words” and reflected on the influence of his father on his linguistic approach.</p><ul><li>Keynote address by Dr. Abraham Verghese on the power of literature.</li><li>Discussions on modern Tamil poetry by Bogan Shankar and Perundevi.</li><li>Engaging sessions and workshops for attendees to participate in.</li><li>Prominent themes included the relationship between words and identity, and the evolution of language.</li><li>Tharoor highlighted the need for the correct and inventive usage of words.</li></ul><blockquote>"Books and reading can change your life." - Dr. Abraham Verghese</blockquote><p>The Hindu Lit for Life 2025 is poised to explore literature, culture, and the arts, emphasizing their role in enriching lives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/lit-for-life/the-hindu-lit-for-life-2025-day-1-live-updates-january-18-2024/article69108090.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/lit-for-life/the-hindu-lit-for-life-2025-day-1-live-updates-january-18-2024/article69108090.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Emergency' box office Day 1: Kangana Ranaut's political drama makes a good start with more than Rs.2 cro - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kangana Ranaut's 'Emergency' Box Office Opens Strong with Over Rs. 2 Crore</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The political drama 'Emergency', starring Kangana Ranaut, has made a promising start at the box office, earning over Rs. 2 crore on its opening day.</p><ul><li>The film's opening day collection surpassed expectations, reflecting audience interest.</li><li>Kangana Ranaut leads the cast, portraying a pivotal historical figure.</li><li>The film is directed by Ranaut herself, marking her directorial debut with a politically charged narrative.</li></ul><blockquote>“The film's opening is a testament to the strong connection it has made with viewers,” said industry analysts.</blockquote><p>This successful debut indicates a positive reception ahead for 'Emergency' in its subsequent runs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/emergency-box-office-day-1-kangana-ranauts-political-drama-makes-a-good-start-with-more-than-rs-2-crore-opening-business/articleshow/117346065.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/emergency-box-office-day-1-kangana-ranauts-political-drama-makes-a-good-start-with-more-than-rs-2-crore-opening-business/articleshow/117346065.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 02:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kartik Aaryan feels ‘surreal’ as Murlikant Petkar receives Arjuna Award: Feeling so proud to be present in this moment - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kartik Aaryan Celebrates Murlikant Petkar's Arjuna Award Win</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Kartik_Aaryan_1737169026053_1737169036562.png" alt="Kartik Aaryan posed for a photo with President Droupadi Murmu and Murlikant Petkar." title="Kartik Aaryan posed for a photo with President Droupadi Murmu and Murlikant Petkar.">
<figcaption>Kartik Aaryan posed for a photo with President Droupadi Murmu and Murlikant Petkar.</figcaption>
<p>Kartik Aaryan congratulated Paralympic Gold medalist Murlikant Petkar for receiving the Arjuna Award, expressing his pride and joy for being present at the moment.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kartik shared a video on Instagram showcasing Petkar's award ceremony.</li>
  <li>Petkar expressed gratitude towards producer Sajid Nadiadwala for his recognition.</li>
  <li>Kartik referred to the moment as surreal and highlighted Petkar's inspiring journey.</li>
  <li>Kartik portrayed Petkar in the film <em>Chandu Champion</em>.</li>
  <li>Petkar made history as India's first Paralympic gold medalist in 1972.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This award is a testament to the support I received from the Government of India, Maharashtra State, Rotary Clubs and many others who believed in me…” - Murlikant Petkar</blockquote>
<p>The event marks a significant recognition for an athlete who has inspired many, with both Kartik and Murlikant feeling a strong emotional connection to the award.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/kartik-aaryan-feels-surreal-as-murlikant-petkar-receives-arjuna-award-feeling-so-proud-to-be-present-in-this-moment-101737168251932.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/kartik-aaryan-feels-surreal-as-murlikant-petkar-receives-arjuna-award-feeling-so-proud-to-be-present-in-this-moment-101737168251932.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 02:58:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tiktok's warning after US Supreme Court upholds ban law: ‘Will go dark on Sunday in US if…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tiktok's warning after US Supreme Court upholds ban law: ‘Will go dark on Sunday in US if…’</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/tiktok_ban_1737168428718_1737168428994.jpg" alt="In this photo illustration, the TikTok logo is displayed on a phone on January 17, 2025 in New York City. (Getty Images via AFP)" title="In this photo illustration, the TikTok logo is displayed on a phone on January 17, 2025 in New York City. (Getty Images via AFP)">
<figcaption>In this photo illustration, the TikTok logo is displayed on a phone on January 17, 2025 in New York City. (Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption>
<p>TikTok has warned that it will cease operations in the U.S. unless the Biden administration provides assurances to its service providers regarding enforcement actions related to a Supreme Court upheld ban over national security concerns.</p>
<ul>
  <li>TikTok will go dark if assurances are not given by January 19, 2025.</li>
  <li>The U.S. Supreme Court ruled 9-0 to uphold a law banning TikTok.</li>
  <li>Fate of TikTok now depends on the incoming Trump administration.</li>
  <li>The White House has declined to comment on TikTok's request for assurances.</li>
  <li>Major U.S. companies could face fines if they continue services to TikTok after the deadline.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Unless the Biden Administration immediately provides a definitive statement to satisfy the most critical service providers assuring non-enforcement, unfortunately TikTok will be forced to go dark on January 19,"</blockquote>
<p>The future of TikTok remains uncertain as key service providers await clarity from the administration, creating a looming dilemma in the tech industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/tiktoks-warning-after-us-supreme-court-upholds-ban-law-will-go-dark-on-sunday-in-us-if-101737167637184.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/tiktoks-warning-after-us-supreme-court-upholds-ban-law-will-go-dark-on-sunday-in-us-if-101737167637184.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 02:50:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Impeached South Korean president Yoon to appear in court hearing to plead against his arrest - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxPS0JGbmVveVM2dTdqYWNiM0RTSG5wWVdpZThudWxxMm91Y0Y0NGRlelMxaXoxVkpZYTZyTTl1VmJSRjlRbFAyRXJES0NQWkxzV1hXRVpuTzhBc192NkdEZFo2UElxVjUyNjFwYnJjNUNTUnFzSmREWV9sZHl4S3c5clQyRTk1VDdYLTUzT1FFZHhZNEJqc1NmOEIwRWt3MFRuVlg4Z09PQ2NRMEFOZDJ2bGZTSFJ5LU1WWHphZnB1YUM0dTBTNVZzcUJYMzdEb3czckg3WGxlYTl5LVJrRFRV0gHkAUFVX3lxTE9xbl9UZTFnMWNNR2FwdllHUkNqNTdBekhGc2xkaTh0Si12eElKUkt3OUJZOFM3czNHTzhDeTJTQkRGQ3ROcGpjbkozYUlTTW5sN2JnY1RHU1FINlcwZXRCakROOVBtaG9SRTViWTI4YnV6SDM4ODVwbktUQnloTXFyZjRDZzlXU3RWWjdoLUFJc2ozNUExdkNRSnNCMVo5cG9Hbm9XaXN3V1ppRmM2WHRYNWE1Qi1xUk5MSDQ5QU5Gci1MVFB5QWJWQXJTZUtqMXEwOVk1cHhUc3VLTkpBLUpCdzdZMg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxPS0JGbmVveVM2dTdqYWNiM0RTSG5wWVdpZThudWxxMm91Y0Y0NGRlelMxaXoxVkpZYTZyTTl1VmJSRjlRbFAyRXJES0NQWkxzV1hXRVpuTzhBc192NkdEZFo2UElxVjUyNjFwYnJjNUNTUnFzSmREWV9sZHl4S3c5clQyRTk1VDdYLTUzT1FFZHhZNEJqc1NmOEIwRWt3MFRuVlg4Z09PQ2NRMEFOZDJ2bGZTSFJ5LU1WWHphZnB1YUM0dTBTNVZzcUJYMzdEb3czckg3WGxlYTl5LVJrRFRV0gHkAUFVX3lxTE9xbl9UZTFnMWNNR2FwdllHUkNqNTdBekhGc2xkaTh0Si12eElKUkt3OUJZOFM3czNHTzhDeTJTQkRGQ3ROcGpjbkozYUlTTW5sN2JnY1RHU1FINlcwZXRCakROOVBtaG9SRTViWTI4YnV6SDM4ODVwbktUQnloTXFyZjRDZzlXU3RWWjdoLUFJc2ozNUExdkNRSnNCMVo5cG9Hbm9XaXN3V1ppRmM2WHRYNWE1Qi1xUk5MSDQ5QU5Gci1MVFB5QWJWQXJTZUtqMXEwOVk1cHhUc3VLTkpBLUpCdzdZMg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 02:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Canadian foreign minister warns of 'biggest trade war with US' as Trump's tariff threat looms - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Canadian Foreign Minister Warns of 'Biggest Trade War with US'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>As President Trump threatens new tariffs, Canada's foreign minister expresses concerns about an escalating trade conflict with the U.S., highlighting significant economic stakes for both nations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Introduction of tariffs could impact various industries.</li>
  <li>Canadian officials are preparing for potential repercussions.</li>
  <li>Trade relations at risk amid ongoing negotiations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We must be prepared for the toughest negotiations yet, which could lead to a significant trade war." - Canadian Foreign Minister</blockquote>
<p>This situation underscores the fragility of U.S.-Canada trade relations and the need for ongoing dialogue to prevent economic fallout.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/canadian-foreign-minister-warns-of-biggest-trade-war-with-us-as-trumps-tariff-threat-looms/articleshow/117345826.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/canadian-foreign-minister-warns-of-biggest-trade-war-with-us-as-trumps-tariff-threat-looms/articleshow/117345826.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 02:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump plans big immigration raid in Chicago: reports - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Plans Major Immigration Raid in Chicago</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 18, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/pctx15/article69111563.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Trump_Climate_10385.jpg" alt="Donald Trump’s incoming U.S. Presidential administration plans to launch a large immigration raid in Chicago. File " title="Donald Trump’s incoming U.S. Presidential administration plans to launch a large immigration raid in Chicago. File "/><figcaption>Donald Trump’s incoming U.S. Presidential administration plans to launch a large immigration raid in Chicago. File | Photo Credit: AP</figcaption><p>Donald Trump’s incoming U.S. Presidential administration is set to launch a large immigration raid in Chicago the day after his inauguration, according to reports.</p><ul><li>The operation is expected to start on January 21, 2025, and last all week.</li><li>Between 100 and 200 immigration officers will be deployed for the raid.</li><li>Trump's border czar stated that the operation will begin in Chicago.</li><li>Trump threatened to prosecute the Chicago mayor if he obstructs the raid.</li><li>The issue of immigration has been central to Trump’s campaign.</li></ul><blockquote>"Within moments of my inauguration, we will begin the largest domestic deportation operation in American history," Mr. Trump said in January 2024.</blockquote><p>The upcoming raid underscores Trump's commitment to his immigration policies as he mobilizes federal resources to deport a record number of immigrants.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-plans-big-immigration-raid-in-chicago-reports/article69111559.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-plans-big-immigration-raid-in-chicago-reports/article69111559.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 02:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Africa reports over 200 disease outbreaks in 2024 - Social News XYZ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Africa Reports Over 200 Disease Outbreaks in 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Social News XYZ</p>
<img title="Africa reports over 200 disease outbreaks in 2024" alt="Africa reports over 200 disease outbreaks in 2024" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.socialnews.xyz/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/18/202501183303771.jpg?w=777&amp;crop=0,10,777px,437px">
<figcaption>Africa CDC highlights alarming rise in disease outbreaks.</figcaption>
<p>The Africa CDC has reported a significant increase in disease outbreaks across the continent, with more than 200 events recorded in 2024 compared to 166 in 2023. The urgent need for improved public health strategies and investment has been emphasized by the CDC director-general.</p>
<ul>
<li>In 2024, there were 213 disease events compared to 166 in 2023.</li>
<li>Cholera, measles, dengue, mpox, and diphtheria are identified as the top five high-burden diseases.</li>
<li>Cholera resulted in approximately 204,115 cases and 3,747 deaths in 2023.</li>
<li>Measles caused 234,320 cases and 3,220 deaths this year.</li>
<li>Mpox reported 77,888 cases and 1,321 deaths across 21 countries.</li>
<li>Calls for better infrastructure and investment in vaccines and public health facilities.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We see that the number of disease outbreaks in 2024 was more than in 2023... This year will hopefully be different from the last year," said Africa CDC Director-General Jean Kaseya.</blockquote>
<p>Efforts to fortify Africa's healthcare response during emergent disease outbreaks are crucial for future public health resilience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.socialnews.xyz/2025/01/17/africa-reports-over-200-disease-outbreaks-in-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.socialnews.xyz/2025/01/17/africa-reports-over-200-disease-outbreaks-in-2024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 02:07:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICC Champions Trophy 2025 India Squad Announcement LIVE Updates: Ajit Agarkar likely to announce squad today | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICC Champions Trophy 2025 India Squad Announcement LIVE Updates</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 18 Jan 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Various Updates</p><p>As the ICC Champions Trophy approaches, India and Pakistan remain the last teams to announce their player squads. The BCCI is waiting on the conclusion of the Vijay Hazare Trophy to finalize their 15-man squad, and injury issues are causing further delays.</p><ul><li>The announcement of India’s squad is expected to happen on January 18, 2025.</li><li>Key player injuries, particularly to Jasprit Bumrah and Kuldeep Yadav, are influencing the squad selection process.</li><li>Notable comments from former cricketers highlight the impact of team dynamics and player evaluations.</li></ul><blockquote>“My recovery went quite well and I’ve been bowling for some time now. I’m feeling good about my progress.” - Kuldeep Yadav</blockquote><p>In summary, the Indian cricket team is undergoing key evaluations and discussions, making the squad announcement a subject of significant anticipation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgJBVV95cUxPMEtRTElmZ3UwbTVNSWxqOERUMnpHdjlJa1N0TkVyRTNvWVFmSFh1YmQyWjhSYXBpa0J6dGQ2cWllM0RrUjY2U2JkU19PUzJ2S0luSDhlTS1XQzBXbGhPUkNySmhSYXFrcnljb0dDMUdzVnVjcmJINmdrX3FaLVRKREUtMUdNS3ZldDkwYXFQUjZWV3JmM1Q3VW43dnF3b2NaNFZHb01qaEYzZDVYMDhFeWExdFJXSmhYUng1OHZnaFE2alNkNFdRSFRjQVcxakxzbnNGRzBLMHl6WW9NVElkcjR1LWF2aWJRSXdHVFIycnU3VHJqYjVQYlhmOEJ1Unl3M2paRzZibnBRWGU0aVBkY3Rn0gGXAkFVX3lxTE1IeUdEazVxOGtfcUhBLWo1alBxWDlJRDhZOFd0NFpQbmRMWUE3cGE3ZHJDOWdab29tUmkzVzRfLTRlVnVvSmZnUUZaLUx1QnBOanlvS0xBLWJhQk96UkhpNUREM1NlRzdnUFJyVTJ1Z1lxUkZ4SVZSNEEyNjAzZEJSZGpjM0xEVjhBQTlKVUZ1VXF4RnY4STluRGZYUXEzakpBLTdLVzVOZHBUSDliQm1NOTFMNzF3TEZnMEZHSmw3TmNnS1E2LVlRNFYzeElBdFJ2ZkhId1ZuME1QdHpBbEk5b0VlSlZLaUZLelJwOFhoeHcyS0ktNFltNU04RjFVT2pjZFpSWFN4V1J1STZaSDE4VS1IMFdSVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgJBVV95cUxPMEtRTElmZ3UwbTVNSWxqOERUMnpHdjlJa1N0TkVyRTNvWVFmSFh1YmQyWjhSYXBpa0J6dGQ2cWllM0RrUjY2U2JkU19PUzJ2S0luSDhlTS1XQzBXbGhPUkNySmhSYXFrcnljb0dDMUdzVnVjcmJINmdrX3FaLVRKREUtMUdNS3ZldDkwYXFQUjZWV3JmM1Q3VW43dnF3b2NaNFZHb01qaEYzZDVYMDhFeWExdFJXSmhYUng1OHZnaFE2alNkNFdRSFRjQVcxakxzbnNGRzBLMHl6WW9NVElkcjR1LWF2aWJRSXdHVFIycnU3VHJqYjVQYlhmOEJ1Unl3M2paRzZibnBRWGU0aVBkY3Rn0gGXAkFVX3lxTE1IeUdEazVxOGtfcUhBLWo1alBxWDlJRDhZOFd0NFpQbmRMWUE3cGE3ZHJDOWdab29tUmkzVzRfLTRlVnVvSmZnUUZaLUx1QnBOanlvS0xBLWJhQk96UkhpNUREM1NlRzdnUFJyVTJ1Z1lxUkZ4SVZSNEEyNjAzZEJSZGpjM0xEVjhBQTlKVUZ1VXF4RnY4STluRGZYUXEzakpBLTdLVzVOZHBUSDliQm1NOTFMNzF3TEZnMEZHSmw3TmNnS1E2LVlRNFYzeElBdFJ2ZkhId1ZuME1QdHpBbEk5b0VlSlZLaUZLelJwOFhoeHcyS0ktNFltNU04RjFVT2pjZFpSWFN4V1J1STZaSDE4VS1IMFdSVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 02:04:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold price today: MCX gold rate hits one-month high despite strong US dollar. US Fed rate cut in focus - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gold price today: MCX gold rate hits one-month high despite strong US dollar. US Fed rate cut in focus</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 17, 2025, Live Mint</p><p>Despite soaring US dollar rates, gold prices continue to rise in domestic and international markets. The MCX gold rate finished at ₹79,019 per 10 gm on Friday, marking a weekly gain of 0.80%.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>MCX gold rate logged a gain against the previous week's ₹78,400 per 10 gm.</li><li>COMEX gold finished at $2,748.70 per troy ounce.</li><li>Speculations about a US Fed rate cut following soft inflation data.</li><li>Experts link gold’s rise to decreased US Treasury yields and economic uncertainties ahead of Donald Trump’s inauguration.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite a stronger US dollar, gold sustained its upward trajectory as US core inflation softened to 3.2 per cent.” - Sugandha Sachdeva</blockquote><p>This event indicates ongoing volatility in the gold market alongside geopolitical factors influencing investor sentiment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/commodities/gold-price-today-mcx-gold-rate-hits-one-month-high-despite-soaring-us-dollar-rate-us-fed-rate-cut-inflation-in-focus-11737164438888.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/commodities/gold-price-today-mcx-gold-rate-hits-one-month-high-despite-soaring-us-dollar-rate-us-fed-rate-cut-inflation-in-focus-11737164438888.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 01:57:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple pulls error-prone AI-generated news feature in beta iPhone software - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Halts Faulty AI News Feature in iOS Beta After Complaints</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> Jan 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" alt="Apple and its vendors are aiming to assemble 32 per cent of iPhone’s global production volume and 26 per cent of its value in India by 2026-27 —a year after the final year of the five-year production-linked incentive (PLI) scheme for mobile devices." width="826" height="465"><figcaption>Apple aims to enhance its production capacity in India by 2026-27.</figcaption><p>Apple is suspending an AI-based news feature in its beta iOS software after receiving complaints regarding inaccurate alerts.</p><ul><li>Apple has disabled the error-prone AI-generated news summary feature included in the iOS 18.3 beta update.</li><li>The feature was creating false headlines, leading to confusion and dissatisfaction from media organizations such as the BBC.</li><li>This decision to suspend the feature comes amidst efforts to integrate AI technology into Apple's products, despite challenges faced.</li><li>High-profile incidents included false alerts regarding a news story involving a shooting linked to a UnitedHealthcare CEO.</li></ul><blockquote>“Apple sent alerts that transformed its reports into false headlines,” noted the BBC.</blockquote><p>The suspension of the feature highlights ongoing challenges in implementing AI technologies accurately, as Apple aims to advance its AI capabilities in future updates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/apple-pulls-error-prone-ai-generated-news-feature-in-beta-iphone-software-125011800001_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/apple-pulls-error-prone-ai-generated-news-feature-in-beta-iphone-software-125011800001_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 01:54:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intruder was very aggressive but didn’t steal anything: Kareena to police - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxPR2hCekF4X2JxQVZXSzNNb2FMUmUzT0ppdFREZHVLS2NqM1VoRjZDWVZDOHk0bUhNY0txdkl6WF9PQUVTb2lzdU9sM3EwSVk0bHJwYTZ4Sm96T1F2dkVVYzZvaVlsbWZCYlRreThVSDhwMHFjenpZMER6OC1VdzVSOGp1ZWx1Vm5SbW13dE9PY1NBWE9zOWp3NlBTUmI4U3V5aVdmSkdfbDh5U3hGb3V2dWI0c1UydnFpWDZWQllKajMwNEFneHpF0gHOAUFVX3lxTFBvdC1LTGNvak9TM3FRdzRQd2hQZW1INXctcGthTzhvV054YWJZSWVNX2FRbEg5aUZGSmNsLXhWSjBXejZNME1Jd2J1TmZib3ZsenlscVdhM1p0cWlnREJuc0RKbUhjT0JtMGQ3ZVlEeVN4Ql85SEVNZUV5eGcxR2d1WWhKX3F5NVAteEdhbFBVT2hEWFhQTWdBNkhnaktacUtPbnUzYTQyUEdTM0Q5RnY1V0x4TDVYSHBsSHkyUFZKT3lHOXNjQ1R6YzI2UmZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxPR2hCekF4X2JxQVZXSzNNb2FMUmUzT0ppdFREZHVLS2NqM1VoRjZDWVZDOHk0bUhNY0txdkl6WF9PQUVTb2lzdU9sM3EwSVk0bHJwYTZ4Sm96T1F2dkVVYzZvaVlsbWZCYlRreThVSDhwMHFjenpZMER6OC1VdzVSOGp1ZWx1Vm5SbW13dE9PY1NBWE9zOWp3NlBTUmI4U3V5aVdmSkdfbDh5U3hGb3V2dWI0c1UydnFpWDZWQllKajMwNEFneHpF0gHOAUFVX3lxTFBvdC1LTGNvak9TM3FRdzRQd2hQZW1INXctcGthTzhvV054YWJZSWVNX2FRbEg5aUZGSmNsLXhWSjBXejZNME1Jd2J1TmZib3ZsenlscVdhM1p0cWlnREJuc0RKbUhjT0JtMGQ3ZVlEeVN4Ql85SEVNZUV5eGcxR2d1WWhKX3F5NVAteEdhbFBVT2hEWFhQTWdBNkhnaktacUtPbnUzYTQyUEdTM0Q5RnY1V0x4TDVYSHBsSHkyUFZKT3lHOXNjQ1R6YzI2UmZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 01:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[False lead and new footage later, Saif Ali Khan stabbing accused remains elusive - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-intruder-changed-clothes-police-9784609/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-intruder-changed-clothes-police-9784609/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 01:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Open: Sindhu left disappointed by quarterfinal defeat against Tunjung, but shows promise on return to action - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu's Quarterfinal Loss at India Open: A Promising Return</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/PV-Sindhu.jpg?w=640" alt="PV Sindhu in action at Yonex Sunrise India Open 2025" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>PV Sindhu in action on Day 4 at Yonex Sunrise India Open 2025; (RIGHT) The two-time Olympic medallist poses with a hand-made poster presented to her. (PHOTOS: BAI, Express Photo)</figcaption><p>In her comeback tournament, PV Sindhu faced disappointment in the quarterfinals against Gregoria Mariska Tunjung at the India Open. Despite a strong crowd and a hopeful atmosphere, Sindhu lost in a closely contested match that showcased her determination.</p><ul><li>Sindhu recovered from a poor start, closing in at 17-17 in the third set after losing the first game 9-21.</li><li>A pivotal rally at 17-17 shifted the momentum in favor of Tunjung, who ultimately won the match 21-9, 19-21, 21-17.</li><li>Sindhu's performance was commendable, reflecting her preparation and eagerness to improve despite her recent training.</li><li>A young fan in the audience showed unwavering support, later receiving Sindhu's autograph on her hand-made poster.</li></ul><blockquote>“If that 1-2% I had played a bit more back, maybe that would have been the difference. It is sad for sure, when you play a long match and lose in the third set after fighting so hard. But that’s sport.” - PV Sindhu</blockquote><p>Although disappointing, Sindhu's journey at the India Open reflects her potential to bounce back stronger in future tournaments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/badminton/tunjung-nets-sindhu-front-court-trap-drops-half-smashes-9784935/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/badminton/tunjung-nets-sindhu-front-court-trap-drops-half-smashes-9784935/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 01:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 fascinating images of space shared by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Fascinating Images of Space Shared by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p> <img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/FotoJet-2025-01-18T063833.015.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=400&amp;h=800" alt="Fascinating Images of Space" /> <figcaption>NASA Hubble Space Telescope</figcaption> <p>This article showcases five stunning images of space taken by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting various celestial phenomena.</p> <ul> <li>Several hundred never before seen galaxies captured in the Hubble Deep Field.</li> <li>The glimmering stars of the globular cluster NGC 6544.</li> <li>NASA's view of the tiny moon Phobos around Mars.</li> <li>Spiral galaxy NGC 4248, located approximately 24 million light-years away.</li> <li>Stellar nursery known as N159, a vast HII region.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“This beautiful clump of glowing gas, dark dust and glittering stars is the spiral galaxy NGC 4248.”</blockquote> <p>The images presented not only display the beauty of the universe but also deepen our understanding of celestial structures and phenomena.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/5-fascinating-images-of-space-shared-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7547077/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/5-fascinating-images-of-space-shared-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7547077/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 01:30:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>