<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:24:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:24:36 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Realme to supercharge smartphone design with 300% boost to ID talent, 450% R&D investment in 2025 | Exclusive - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Realme to Boost Smartphone Design and R&D Investments by 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> financialexpress.com</p><figure><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="533" src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Sky-Li-2.jpg" alt="Sky Li - Founder and CEO of Realme"><figcaption>Sky Li – Founder and CEO of Realme</figcaption></figure><p>Realme's founder and CEO, Sky Li, discusses the company's ambitious plans for 2025, including a 450% increase in R&D investment and a 300% boost in Industrial Design talent. The Realme 14 Pro series, aimed at tech-savvy youth, focuses on innovation, design aesthetics, and advanced camera capabilities.</p><ul><li>The target market for the Realme 14 Pro series consists of young adults valuing innovation and performance.</li><li>Realme aims to enhance user experience with India-specific software and colour variants.</li><li>Notable growth in 2024 included an 117% rise in Western Europe and 281% in Latin America.</li><li>The 14 Pro series focuses on high-performance features like advanced camera technology and impressive battery life.</li><li>Significant investment in quad-curved display technology emphasizing user experience.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“India remains a key pillar of our success, where we [have] reinforced our position as the most popular smartphone brand among the youth.” - Sky Li</p></blockquote><p>The Realme 14 Pro series showcases the company’s focus on innovation, targeting an expansion in both local and global markets. Their commitment to R&D will significantly influence future smartphone design and user experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-realme-to-supercharge-smartphone-design-with-300-boost-to-id-talent-450-rampd-investment-in-2025-exclusive-3717823/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-realme-to-supercharge-smartphone-design-with-300-boost-to-id-talent-450-rampd-investment-in-2025-exclusive-3717823/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:58:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli had a neck sprain, participation in Ranji Trophy 'subject to availability' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli's Neck Sprain: Ranji Trophy Participation Uncertain</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p><p>Indian cricket star Virat Kohli has suffered a neck sprain, raising doubts about his availability for the upcoming Ranji Trophy matches.</p><ul><li>Kohli's injury could affect his participation in the Ranji Trophy.</li><li>The BCCI will assess his condition before the selection.</li><li>This injury comes at a crucial time for Kohli and the Indian team.</li></ul><blockquote>“His participation will depend on his recovery and fitness levels,” said a source.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Kohli's injury is a concern for both him and the cricketing community as they await updates on his fitness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/virat-kohli-had-a-neck-sprain-participation-in-ranji-trophy-subject-to-availability/articleshow/117321685.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/virat-kohli-had-a-neck-sprain-participation-in-ranji-trophy-subject-to-availability/articleshow/117321685.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shraddha Kapoor confirms relationship with Rahul Mody? Rumoured love birds twin in matching outfits in cute pic - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shraddha Kapoor Confirms Relationship with Rahul Mody</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/ssss_1737090857181_1737090880461.jpg" alt="Shraddha Kapoor shares cute picture with rumoured boyfriend Rahul Mody." title="Shraddha Kapoor shares cute picture with rumoured boyfriend Rahul Mody.">
<figcaption>Shraddha Kapoor shares cute picture with rumoured boyfriend Rahul Mody.</figcaption>
<p>Shraddha Kapoor is making headlines for sharing a cute matching outfits picture with her rumored boyfriend, Rahul Mody, on Instagram, further fueling their relationship rumors.</p>
<ul>
<li>Shraddha Kapoor shared a photo with Rahul Mody in matching night dresses on Instagram.</li>
<li>They were seen twinning, although only their lower bodies were visible.</li>
<li>Shraddha previously shared a picture enjoying a vada pav date with Rahul, putting split rumors to rest.</li>
<li>The couple was recently spotted together in Mumbai after a dinner date.</li>
<li>Shraddha has a successful film, Stree 2, and is set to star in Nagin.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“May I always bully you into taking me for vada pav,” said Shraddha Kapoor in her social media post.</blockquote>
<p>This adorable post has only added to the excitement surrounding Shraddha Kapoor's personal life and upcoming projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shraddha-kapoor-confirms-relationship-with-rahul-mody-rumoured-love-birds-twin-in-matching-outfits-in-cute-pic-101737087478545.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shraddha-kapoor-confirms-relationship-with-rahul-mody-rumoured-love-birds-twin-in-matching-outfits-in-cute-pic-101737087478545.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:39:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan fans angry over mean jokes and memes on actor's stabbing, ask trolls to ‘have some shame' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/saif-ali-khan-fans-angry-over-mean-jokes-on-actor-stabbing-ask-trolls-to-have-some-shame-101737087695284.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/saif-ali-khan-fans-angry-over-mean-jokes-on-actor-stabbing-ask-trolls-to-have-some-shame-101737087695284.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:00:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Lionel Messi came, Kylian Mbappé was a little jealous': Neymar spills secrets of PSG days - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Neymar Reveals Secrets from PSG Days Involving Messi and Mbappé</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>Neymar shares anecdotes from his time at Paris Saint-Germain, discussing the dynamics between himself, Lionel Messi, and Kylian Mbappé.</p><ul><li>Neymar describes Messi's arrival at PSG and the impact it had on the team.</li><li>He mentions moments that hinted at jealousy from Mbappé regarding Messi's status.</li><li>The interview provides insights into the relationships formed between the star players.</li></ul><blockquote>Neymar stated, "Lionel Messi came, Kylian Mbappé was a little jealous."</blockquote><p>This retrospective on Neymar's time at PSG offers fans a glimpse into the locker room atmosphere and the interplay between three of football's biggest stars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/football/top-stories/lionel-messi-came-kylian-mbapp-was-a-little-jealous-neymar-spills-secrets-of-psg-days/articleshow/117318397.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/football/top-stories/lionel-messi-came-kylian-mbapp-was-a-little-jealous-neymar-spills-secrets-of-psg-days/articleshow/117318397.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infosys shares tank 6% amid likely weak Q4, uncertainty over wage hike impact - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPQVNBb0paT1pmTnJpM1R4N2RLbjQ2QW95TnJxeXM2bWxMZkZmWnAweWhSNjE1SHFLb2Zoa3lRdV93NWRaNDU0UVUzMXRxNE53YjJjNzNVcU1TcjlyTGQ0b1BRRDdPSUYzNEdsYWZ1Y1JDQlk4a1ZnZklhRE1BN3FPRWd3QU9jcFlhZXFrZ05IRjUxckxlRWZ4SEVXd25VeWluZU1MTkVvZXBqNzBnVGJwc2xkVXVsNzFwVjc4b1RkdnU0N0ZOUVpxS0NKRDhEbFpWaUFkSll0UdIB3AFBVV95cUxQSWJpNUtacFczVmRsaHR6SFdGOFRzSTBINDJVWnJkdmU3Q2EtREp3NG4temRGRlNtSnV2ZUR2YXZsNTRfdm5jV1dDY2dRblRYUW1iLVBVQ2FnN3dBbjVPSGJpSnRTbWo5ZjZpbXJJN3h2ZHVta240czNZcTlqSVhXTHJpcDVEWDJsRmstaVZRVURkZkhIQ0h1ZWQxMzJjNFJaNlcwSW5QMThUWTZleUJqS2o2RmNqbndZZWtuYlpqRlB0MmdpenMxd1V3bHZjdl84bjZ3RDlYc3Iyc29O?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPQVNBb0paT1pmTnJpM1R4N2RLbjQ2QW95TnJxeXM2bWxMZkZmWnAweWhSNjE1SHFLb2Zoa3lRdV93NWRaNDU0UVUzMXRxNE53YjJjNzNVcU1TcjlyTGQ0b1BRRDdPSUYzNEdsYWZ1Y1JDQlk4a1ZnZklhRE1BN3FPRWd3QU9jcFlhZXFrZ05IRjUxckxlRWZ4SEVXd25VeWluZU1MTkVvZXBqNzBnVGJwc2xkVXVsNzFwVjc4b1RkdnU0N0ZOUVpxS0NKRDhEbFpWaUFkSll0UdIB3AFBVV95cUxQSWJpNUtacFczVmRsaHR6SFdGOFRzSTBINDJVWnJkdmU3Q2EtREp3NG4temRGRlNtSnV2ZUR2YXZsNTRfdm5jV1dDY2dRblRYUW1iLVBVQ2FnN3dBbjVPSGJpSnRTbWo5ZjZpbXJJN3h2ZHVta240czNZcTlqSVhXTHJpcDVEWDJsRmstaVZRVURkZkhIQ0h1ZWQxMzJjNFJaNlcwSW5QMThUWTZleUJqS2o2RmNqbndZZWtuYlpqRlB0MmdpenMxd1V3bHZjdl84bjZ3RDlYc3Iyc29O?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:57:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea investigators to file request to extend President Yoon's detention - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korean Investigators Seek to Extend President Yoon's Detention</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p>
<img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4RE54PYVJBLTJGXLAOMX6DVIXQ.jpg?auth=1c059ba69aff506a3e1f5bf6dbe4d0909042a42382ccb594b3c6e8ff5d3d6c09&amp;width=3120&amp;quality=80" alt="Police stand guard outside Seoul Detention Center where impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is held in custody in Uiwang"><figcaption>Police stand guard outside Seoul Detention Center where impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is held in custody in Uiwang, South Korea. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption>
<p>South Korea's anti-corruption agency is requesting to extend the detention of President Yoon Suk Yeol following his refusal to be questioned by investigators. He is embroiled in a legal challenge regarding accusations of insurrection related to his brief imposition of martial law in December.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Authorities face a deadline to release President Yoon or extend his detention.</li>
  <li>Investigators expect to file a request for a detention warrant for up to 20 days.</li>
  <li>The Seoul court has rejected Yoon's challenge against his arrest.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I think you can consider it almost finished," a CIO official stated regarding the investigation.</blockquote>
<p>The situation highlights ongoing political turmoil in South Korea and the implications of Yoon's actions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/south-koreas-yoon-recalled-questioning-detention-deadline-looms-2025-01-16/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/south-koreas-yoon-recalled-questioning-detention-deadline-looms-2025-01-16/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian national, Sai Varshith Kandula, sentenced to 8 years for attempted attack on White House - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian National Sentenced to 8 Years for Attempted Attack on White House</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/b5bsgs/article68173762.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/White_House_Truck_Crash_62079.jpg" alt="Attempted attack on the White House" /><figcaption>A U.S. Park Police officer inspects a security barrier for damage in Lafayette Square park near the White House.</figcaption><p>Indian national Sai Varshith Kandula was sentenced to eight years for an attempted attack on the White House with a rented truck, aiming to overthrow the U.S. government.</p><ul><li>Kandula pled guilty to willful injury to U.S. property.</li><li>He drove a truck onto a sidewalk and crashed into security barriers near the White House.</li><li>He brandished a Nazi flag after the crash, promoting a dictatorship.</li><li>Kandula caused an estimated $4,322 in damage.</li><li>He had planned the attack for weeks, trying to acquire armed guards and larger vehicles.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kandula's intent was to replace the democratically elected government with a dictatorship fueled by ideology of Nazi Germany,” stated the Department of Justice.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights significant security concerns and the urgency of addressing radical ideologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/indian-national-sai-varshith-kandula-sentenced-to-8-years-for-attempted-attack-on-white-house/article69107380.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/indian-national-sai-varshith-kandula-sentenced-to-8-years-for-attempted-attack-on-white-house/article69107380.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Emergency box office collection Day 1 early estimates: Kangana Ranaut starrer off to a slow start - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Emergency Box Office Collection Day 1 Early Estimates: Kangana Ranaut Starrer Off to a Slow Start</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117317125,imgsize-20950,width-400,resizemode-4/117317125.jpg" alt="Emergency box office collection Day 1 early estimates: Kangana Ranaut starrer off to a slow start" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Kangana Ranaut in Emergency</figcaption><p>The much-anticipated political drama 'Emergency' has had a sluggish start at the box office according to early estimates, with initial earnings around Rs 1 lakh.</p><ul><li>The film is expected to earn between Rs 2-3 crore net in India by the end of Day 1.</li><li>Kangana announced a special pricing of Rs 99 for tickets on Cinema Lovers Day to boost sales.</li><li>Advance ticket sales have outstripped its competitor 'Azaad', but overall numbers remain weak.</li><li>The film addresses a significant historical period in Indian politics from 1975 to 1977, featuring Kangana as Indira Gandhi.</li></ul><blockquote>“Watch Emergency at Rs 99,” said Kangana Ranaut, highlighting the promotional ticket pricing.</blockquote><p>Despite its slow start, 'Emergency' has the potential to pick up pace during the day, competing against other films.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/emergency-box-office-collection-day-1-early-estimates-kangana-ranaut-starrer-off-to-a-slow-start-earns-rs-1-lakh-from-morning-shows/articleshow/117317114.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/emergency-box-office-collection-day-1-early-estimates-kangana-ranaut-starrer-off-to-a-slow-start-earns-rs-1-lakh-from-morning-shows/articleshow/117317114.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australia flex batting depth to set England an improbable 308 - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gardner's Century and King's Five-for Give Australia ODI Series Sweep</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p><figure><img src="https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/placeholder-16-9.png" alt="Ashleigh Gardner celebrates her maiden ODI century, Australia vs England, 3rd ODI, Women's Ashes, Hobart, January 17, 2025"><figcaption>Ashleigh Gardner celebrates her maiden ODI century&nbsp;&nbsp;•&nbsp;&nbsp;Getty Images</figcaption></figure><p>Ashleigh Gardner scored her maiden international century, leading Australia to an 86-run victory over England in the third ODI, securing a 6-0 lead in the series.</p><ul><li>Ashleigh Gardner scored an impressive 102 runs off 102 balls.</li><li>McGrath contributed a solid 55 runs, while Mooney added 50 runs.</li><li>King took 5 wickets for 46 runs, while Schutt took 3 for 57.</li><li>Australia scored 308 for 8, while England could only manage 222 runs.</li><li>Both Beaumont and Sciver-Brunt scored half-centuries for England.</li><li>Australia now requires just two points to retain the Ashes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Gardner's run-a-ball century rescued Australia from 59 for 4.”</blockquote><p>This victory places Australia in a strong position to retain the Ashes, showcasing their dominant performance in the series thus far.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/women-s-ashes-2024-25-1426615/australia-women-vs-england-women-3rd-odi-1426625/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/women-s-ashes-2024-25-1426615/australia-women-vs-england-women-3rd-odi-1426625/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:11:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi fog today: Several flights delayed at IGI airport; AQI improves after rain - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-air-quality-rain-delhi-ncr-noida-ghaziabad-fog-aqi-imd-weather-news-101737080617597.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-air-quality-rain-delhi-ncr-noida-ghaziabad-fog-aqi-imd-weather-news-101737080617597.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:10:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Industries shares in focus after Q3 results beats estimates. Should you buy, sell and hold? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxPN1NwQXZITDJLOFJMUFB1VlhtWnB4dUtEWm9MQl8yNnJXX2FwczE5aFMxcUVoenFIcTlpdHdjbHFxUlp4VjZyZUczcU9LYlduOHdUVndjZ3A4Tnl4eEV6eUc5RmtZZ18zUFFSVWd3WVdTdEx0bHNqVEZxdkhvMkM5MTU4a1ZmU0VNNUY0VlJMVGZncFBYYWVOVVY3ZlY3RlpHdmFFOFhzTnpRNXRTSFR6bFBvVjBnQk9lSHQ4bDBXaURnRF92U1ZjM28wMXZySHFHUkJSRzNqQ1ZwS1dxai1TSTFrdlpsYkMzbWZGXy1ScGxpZGJVaXFjUkVnYXpPS0550gGGAkFVX3lxTE1kOVFRb3hBRWZhc0gzbkhQVEczU3dHME9BbnNyd1BfaGRfR1BEWFFGYjdyYnNXdTBXR0VDQVJVM0VkU1Y0Z3FKT1JQWkVBQTB0cXNzdkRlWk9DcE5yTEdNVVFLRjZTSkJqN3FyRjkxS1R4MkRkbk5VZXM2R01rYXgtOWFuRmgwUUJGSUQ5dktWSnBFeXVXdmxiX1VfNzNTZktoaTUxcTVLVU5sRENDTEs5VVJIeDM5ZV9KRURGZy1feUVNakJlX3d6RFI3NlhBMlBBa0ZRWW5Wc1g5UFE4NHpqMUNMVW8xR1hycFdMcUQtd29mS0JJRnZYdkNqcXBfVHdkcHFYS0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxPN1NwQXZITDJLOFJMUFB1VlhtWnB4dUtEWm9MQl8yNnJXX2FwczE5aFMxcUVoenFIcTlpdHdjbHFxUlp4VjZyZUczcU9LYlduOHdUVndjZ3A4Tnl4eEV6eUc5RmtZZ18zUFFSVWd3WVdTdEx0bHNqVEZxdkhvMkM5MTU4a1ZmU0VNNUY0VlJMVGZncFBYYWVOVVY3ZlY3RlpHdmFFOFhzTnpRNXRTSFR6bFBvVjBnQk9lSHQ4bDBXaURnRF92U1ZjM28wMXZySHFHUkJSRzNqQ1ZwS1dxai1TSTFrdlpsYkMzbWZGXy1ScGxpZGJVaXFjUkVnYXpPS0550gGGAkFVX3lxTE1kOVFRb3hBRWZhc0gzbkhQVEczU3dHME9BbnNyd1BfaGRfR1BEWFFGYjdyYnNXdTBXR0VDQVJVM0VkU1Y0Z3FKT1JQWkVBQTB0cXNzdkRlWk9DcE5yTEdNVVFLRjZTSkJqN3FyRjkxS1R4MkRkbk5VZXM2R01rYXgtOWFuRmgwUUJGSUQ5dktWSnBFeXVXdmxiX1VfNzNTZktoaTUxcTVLVU5sRENDTEs5VVJIeDM5ZV9KRURGZy1feUVNakJlX3d6RFI3NlhBMlBBa0ZRWW5Wc1g5UFE4NHpqMUNMVW8xR1hycFdMcUQtd29mS0JJRnZYdkNqcXBfVHdkcHFYS0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:06:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anushka Sharma can't stay with Virat Kohli for more than 14 days during India tours: What BCCI family travel policy says - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anushka Sharma can't stay with Virat Kohli for more than 14 days during India tours</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/anushka_dipika_1737082652507_1737082659827.jpg" alt="File photo of Anushka Sharma and Dipika Pallikal" title="File photo of Anushka Sharma and Dipika Pallikal"><figcaption>File photo of Anushka Sharma and Dipika Pallikal</figcaption><p>The BCCI has announced that players' wives and children cannot accompany them for more than 14 days during long overseas tours. This rule is part of a new family travel policy aimed at maintaining discipline and operational efficiency.</p><ul><li>The BCCI's family travel policy allows players to have their partners and children visit them for one visit per series lasting up to two weeks if they are outside India for over 45 days.</li><li>Shared accommodation for visitors will be covered by the BCCI, but all other expenses will be the player's responsibility.</li><li>Visits must be scheduled at a single time agreed upon by the coach, captain, and GM operations.</li><li>Any deviations from this policy need pre-approval from the coach and captain.</li></ul><blockquote>“Non-compliance may lead to disciplinary action as deemed appropriate by the BCCI.”</blockquote><p>This decision may impact personal well-being and relationships, especially for players like Virat Kohli, who have previously enjoyed the presence of their partners during tours.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/anushka-sharma-cant-stay-with-virat-kohli-for-more-than-14-days-during-india-tours-what-bcci-family-travel-policy-says-101737082179869.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/anushka-sharma-cant-stay-with-virat-kohli-for-more-than-14-days-during-india-tours-what-bcci-family-travel-policy-says-101737082179869.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu says deal to release Hamas-held hostages has been reached - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Netanyahu Announces Deal for Release of Hamas-held Hostages</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png" alt="Supporters and family members of hostages kidnapped during the deadly October 7, 2023, attack on Israel by Hamas, gather next to a slogan formed of candles on a road during a protest ahead of a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, in Tel Aviv, Israel, on January 16, 2025" title="Supporters and family members of hostages kidnapped during the deadly October 7, 2023, attack on Israel by Hamas, gather next to a slogan formed of candles on a road during a protest ahead of a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, in Tel Aviv, Israel, on January 16, 2025"><figcaption>Supporters and family members of hostages during a protest in Tel Aviv, January 16, 2025 | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>The office of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced a deal has been reached for the release of hostages held by Hamas, with a political-security cabinet convening to discuss the details.</p><ul><li>Netanyahu's office confirmed agreements on a deal to release the hostages.</li><li>The families of the hostages have been informed and preparations are being made for their return.</li><li>If approved, the truce would start on Sunday, enabling the exchange of Israeli hostages for Palestinian prisoners.</li><li>The deal was mediated by Qatar and the United States, announced on Wednesday.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Prime Minister ordered the political-security cabinet to convene tomorrow (Friday). The government will then convene to approve the deal,” Netanyahu’s office stated.</blockquote><p>Should this deal be approved, it could mark a significant step towards a ceasefire and a resolution to the ongoing conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/netanyahu-says-deal-to-release-hamas-held-hostages-has-been-reached/article69107335.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/netanyahu-says-deal-to-release-hamas-held-hostages-has-been-reached/article69107335.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning Regarding '10-Point Diktat' For Indian Cricket Team .. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning Regarding '10-Point Diktat' For Indian Cricket Team Stars</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/qcmgaih_sc_625x300_17_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605' alt='BCCI's New Policy' /><figcaption>File photo of Indian cricket team © AFP</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has enforced a new policy for senior players following recent disappointing performances to promote discipline and team unity.</p><ul><li>Restrictions introduced on personal shoots and endorsements during tours.</li><li>Players must attend BCCI functions and cannot leave practice sessions early.</li><li>Families allowed limited visits on long tours (only two weeks).</li><li>Mandatory participation in domestic matches for national team consideration.</li><li>Disciplinary actions outlined for non-compliance, including suspensions and fee deductions.</li></ul><blockquote>“All players are expected to adhere strictly to the above guidelines. Non-compliance may lead to disciplinary action as deemed appropriate by the BCCI.”</blockquote><p>This policy aims to ensure players remain committed to their training and the overall cricketing structure in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:57:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning Regarding '10-Point Diktat' For Indian Cricket Team Stars - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning For Indian Cricket Team Stars</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/qcmgaih_sc_625x300_17_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="'Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning For Indian Cricket Team Stars"><figcaption>File photo of Indian cricket team © AFP</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has introduced a strict new policy for senior cricketers, requiring adherence to a 10-point diktat in light of the team's recent performance issues. This policy includes restrictions on personal endorsements and mandates players to remain disciplined during tours.</p><ul><li>The BCCI restricts family and personal staff from tours to promote discipline and unity.</li><li>Players will be required to participate in domestic matches to be eligible for national selection.</li><li>Non-compliance may result in suspension and financial penalties.</li><li>Exceptions to the policy require approval from BCCI officials.</li></ul><blockquote>“This policy ensures that players remain connected to the domestic cricket ecosystem, fostering talent development, maintaining match fitness, and strengthening the overall domestic structure.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the BCCI's stringent new rules aim to reinforce discipline among players and enhance their commitment to the team, with clear consequences for non-adherence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:57:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China population shrinks for third year even with more babies born - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's Population Decline Continues Despite Increase in Births</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>China has reported a continued decrease in its population for the third consecutive year, even as the birth rate shows a slight increase.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The overall population has experienced a shrinkage, indicating a demographic crisis.</li>
  <li>Increased birth rates have not been sufficient to counterbalance the aging population.</li>
  <li>Government measures to encourage higher birth rates have yet to produce the desired results.</li>
  <li>Experts are concerned about the long-term economic implications of this trend.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This trend could lead to significant economic challenges in the future, including a shrinking workforce." - Demographic Expert</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing demographic shift highlights the complexity of population management and the urgent need for targeted policy interventions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/china-population-shrinks-for-third-year-even-with-more-babies-born/articleshow/117317118.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/china-population-shrinks-for-third-year-even-with-more-babies-born/articleshow/117317118.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Intent was to replace govt': Indian national gets 8 yrs of jail for White House attack plot - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian Man Sentenced to 8 Years for Plot to Attack the White House</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The article reports on the sentencing of an Indian national who attempted to carry out an attack on the White House. He has been sentenced to eight years in prison.</p><ul><li>The individual was found guilty of conspiracy to commit an attack.</li><li>The case highlights serious security concerns regarding threats to U.S. government buildings.</li><li>The defendant expressed intentions to replace the government.</li></ul><blockquote>“The intent was clear: to replace the government through violent means.”</blockquote><p>This case raises questions about national security and the effectiveness of preventive measures against potential threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/intent-was-to-replace-govt-indian-national-gets-8-yrs-for-white-house-attack-plot/articleshow/117316941.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/intent-was-to-replace-govt-indian-national-gets-8-yrs-for-white-house-attack-plot/articleshow/117316941.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian national sentenced for 8 years for Nazi-inspired attack on White House - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/intent-was-to-replace-govt-indian-national-gets-8-yrs-for-white-house-attack-plot/articleshow/117316941.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/intent-was-to-replace-govt-indian-national-gets-8-yrs-for-white-house-attack-plot/articleshow/117316941.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Says Israel Has Reached Deal To Return Hostages Held In Gaza - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Netanyahu's Office Says 'Deal To Release Hostages' Reached</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>January 25, 2025 <strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p>
<img title="Netanyahu's Office Says 'Deal To Release Hostages' Reached" alt="Netanyahu's Office Says 'Deal To Release Hostages' Reached" id="story_image_main" height="435" width="773" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/a6cgbh3_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_16_January_25.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=773,height=435">
<figcaption>Benjamin Netanyahu addressing the situation regarding hostages.</figcaption>
<p>The office of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced that a deal has been reached to release hostages held by Hamas, with plans for a political-security cabinet meeting to finalize the details.</p>
<ul>
  <li>A deal to release hostages has been negotiated, as confirmed by Netanyahu's office.</li>
  <li>The political-security cabinet is set to convene to approve the deal.</li>
  <li>Hamas has been accused of not complying with the agreement, which they deny.</li>
  <li>If the agreement is approved, it will include the exchange of Israeli hostages for Palestinian prisoners.</li>
  <li>The deal is expected to be finalized by the cabinet meeting on Friday.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Prime Minister ordered the political-security cabinet to convene tomorrow. The government will then convene to approve the deal." - Netanyahu's office</blockquote>
<p>This development signifies potential progress towards a resolution of the hostage situation and may lead to a broader truce in the ongoing conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-says-israel-has-reached-deal-to-return-hostages-held-in-gaza-7492349</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-says-israel-has-reached-deal-to-return-hostages-held-in-gaza-7492349</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:42:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to watch, January 17: Tech Mahindra, RIL, Infosys, Wipro, LTIMindtree, Jio Financial, Axis Bank, Havells, and more - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxQZnhPY3lMbVZVRDBabmtKQlQxeEpwN0IySl9jdS1YT3E2cU1SVUZ1UHdzZ3NNRTcyZG1YVjhqTnlhZ0x2ZnFlRmh2aUcxNmVFUG4wMkxxdHZQUnhpbnRLTS1TUWN5VGlPS0JRalRObElZOC0wZkN0QXNRY0kyTTdON3hXcGFPemRuT0xQNGRDd1g5UkhhZ0lKRlB0Y1pCZFZIc3c0N0xBa28zZDZidlBvTUhDaFFaUFBGbnBoNzVzWnpEaDBKS1ZxeFUxTE1sTzJzQTlGU1pYcDJ3TmFZTzBNWnhWNGtkakNjMVRCVWxHNmExRExCZlZYS1VYT1JORlBm?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxQZnhPY3lMbVZVRDBabmtKQlQxeEpwN0IySl9jdS1YT3E2cU1SVUZ1UHdzZ3NNRTcyZG1YVjhqTnlhZ0x2ZnFlRmh2aUcxNmVFUG4wMkxxdHZQUnhpbnRLTS1TUWN5VGlPS0JRalRObElZOC0wZkN0QXNRY0kyTTdON3hXcGFPemRuT0xQNGRDd1g5UkhhZ0lKRlB0Y1pCZFZIc3c0N0xBa28zZDZidlBvTUhDaFFaUFBGbnBoNzVzWnpEaDBKS1ZxeFUxTE1sTzJzQTlGU1pYcDJ3TmFZTzBNWnhWNGtkakNjMVRCVWxHNmExRExCZlZYS1VYT1JORlBm?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:40:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Q3 results today: Wipro, Tech Mahindra, Jio Financial Services, SBI Life, others to announce earnings; check list - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wipro, Tech Mahindra, Jio Financial Services, SBI Life to Announce Q3 Earnings Today</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Upstox</p>
<p>Today, several key companies will reveal their financial results for the third quarter of the fiscal year, including major players in technology, finance, and insurance sectors.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Wipro Ltd</li>
  <li>Tech Mahindra Ltd</li>
  <li>Jio Financial Services Ltd</li>
  <li>SBI Life Insurance Company Ltd</li>
  <li>ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company Ltd</li>
  <li>Others including Tata Chemicals and Rajoo Engineers</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Reliance Industries posted a 7.4% increase in its December quarter net profit, supported by a rebound in retail business.</blockquote>
<p>This financial reporting day is significant as it reflects the performance of various sectors and can indicate economic trends based on the earnings reported.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/earnings/q3-results-wipro-tech-mahindra-jio-financial-services-others-to-announce-earnings-on-january-17-check-list/article-140837/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/earnings/q3-results-wipro-tech-mahindra-jio-financial-services-others-to-announce-earnings-on-january-17-check-list/article-140837/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:40:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infosys CEO asked about low salary hikes, toxic work culture. His response - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Infosys CEO Addresses Salary Hikes and Work Culture Concerns</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/Infosys_CEO_Salil_Parekh_1737081365033_1737081365294.png" alt="Infosys CEO and MD Salil Parekh addressed concerns about the company's work culture.(YouTube/Infosys)">
<figcaption>Infosys CEO and MD Salil Parekh addressed concerns about the company's work culture.(YouTube/Infosys)</figcaption>
<p>Infosys CEO Salil Parekh addressed employee concerns about the company's toxic work culture during the Q3 earnings call, emphasizing fair treatment amid allegations of low salaries.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Infosys reported a fiscal third quarter profit of ₹6,806 crore, up 11.46% YoY.</li>
  <li>Parekh responded to allegations of insufficient salary hikes and a poor work culture during the earnings call.</li>
  <li>Concerns escalated after comments from founder Narayana Murthy about young employees working excessive hours.</li>
  <li>Many former employees have accused Infosys of underpaying staff, particularly fresh graduates.</li>
  <li>Parekh insists that Infosys maintains a fair treatment policy for all employees.</li>
  <li>The company is on track to hire around 15,000 freshers in FY25.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In terms of the employee question, within Infosys we have a very clear approach to make sure that everyone is treated fairly.” - Salil Parekh</blockquote>
<p>The discussion highlights ongoing challenges at Infosys concerning employee satisfaction, attracting new talent, and maintaining a positive work environment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/infosys-ceo-salil-parekh-asked-about-low-salary-hikes-toxic-work-culture-his-response-101737081204834.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/infosys-ceo-salil-parekh-asked-about-low-salary-hikes-toxic-work-culture-his-response-101737081204834.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ahead of Champions Trophy selection, BCCI to probe Sanju Samson's Vijay Hazare Trophy no-show - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ahead of Champions Trophy selection, BCCI to probe Sanju Samson's Vijay Hazare Trophy no-show</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Several days before January 19, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117316696,imgsize-63274,width-400,resizemode-4/117316696.jpg" alt="Sanju Samson no-show" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Sanju Samson’s absence from the Vijay Hazare Trophy has raised concerns ahead of the Champions Trophy selection.</figcaption>
<p>As the national selectors prepare to choose the ODI team for the series against England and the ICC Champions Trophy, the BCCI is set to investigate Sanju Samson's decision to skip the Vijay Hazare Trophy. This absence could affect his selection chances.</p>
<ul>
  <li>BCCI displeased with Samson's non-participation in a critical domestic tournament.</li>
  <li>Kerala Cricket Association did not include him due to his unavailability for the preparatory camp.</li>
  <li>Selecting the Champions Trophy squad is crucial, and selectors seek a valid reason for his absence.</li>
  <li>In the past, players lost central contracts for similar reasons, raising the stakes for participation in domestic cricket.</li>
  <li>Samson is competing for one of the wicketkeeper spots against Rishabh Pant, KL Rahul, and Dhruv Jurel.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The selectors would want a valid reason. Otherwise, it will be difficult to consider him for the ODI season."</blockquote>
<p>The outcome of this investigation may shape the selectors' decisions, especially regarding the balance of the squad if Rahul is unfit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/ahead-of-champions-trophy-selection-bcci-to-probe-sanju-samsons-vijay-hazare-trophy-no-show/articleshow/117316723.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/ahead-of-champions-trophy-selection-bcci-to-probe-sanju-samsons-vijay-hazare-trophy-no-show/articleshow/117316723.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israeli PM Benjamin Netanyahu PM Netanyahu says Israel-Hamas deal to release hostages held in Gaza reached - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel and Hamas Reach Hostage Deal, Ceasefire Likely</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> HT News</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/FILES-POLAND-ISRAEL-DIPLOMACY-0_1737080669232_1737080683108.jpg" alt="(FILES) Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu delivers a speech during the opening of the Permanent Exhibition SHOAH at the former Nazi death camp Auschwitz-Birkenau State Museum,.(AFP)" title="(FILES) Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu delivers a speech during the opening of the Permanent Exhibition SHOAH at the former Nazi death camp Auschwitz-Birkenau State Museum,.(AFP)"><figcaption>(FILES) Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu delivers a speech during the opening of the Permanent Exhibition SHOAH at the former Nazi death camp Auschwitz-Birkenau State Museum,.(AFP)</figcaption></img><p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced that a deal to return hostages held in the Gaza Strip has been reached, marking a significant step towards a ceasefire after 15 months of conflict.</p><ul><li>Netanyahu plans to convene his security Cabinet to approve the agreement.</li><li>The deal aims to pause the ongoing war and facilitate the release of hostages in exchange for Palestinian prisoners.</li><li>Since the conflict began on October 7, 2023, significant casualties have occurred on both sides.</li><li>Hamas has denied claims that it reneged on parts of the agreement.</li><li>The ceasefire agreement faces opposition from Netanyahu's far-right coalition partners.</li></ul><blockquote>“The State of Israel is committed to achieving all the goals of the war, including the return of all our hostages – both living and dead,” - Prime Minister's Office</blockquote><p>This agreement could potentially alleviate further violence and allow displaced Palestinians to return to their homes, emphasizing the fragile state of ceasefire negotiations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israeli-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-says-truce-and-hostage-deal-with-hamas-reached-101737080670257.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israeli-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-says-truce-and-hostage-deal-with-hamas-reached-101737080670257.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:27:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['People forced to sleep on footpaths in freezing cold': Rahul Gandhi visits Delhi AIIMS; see video - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>People forced to sleep on footpaths in freezing cold: Rahul Gandhi visits Delhi AIIMS; see video</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a recent visit to the All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS) in Delhi, Rahul Gandhi addressed the plight of individuals forced to sleep on footpaths due to harsh weather conditions.</p><ul><li>Rahul Gandhi highlighted the impact of freezing temperatures on the vulnerable population.</li><li>The video footage captured during his visit showcases the dire situation outside AIIMS.</li><li>Calls for immediate government intervention have been made to address this humanitarian issue.</li></ul><blockquote>“No one should have to endure such challenges during extreme weather,” said Rahul Gandhi during his visit.</blockquote><p>This visit sheds light on the ongoing struggles faced by many in urban areas during winter, emphasizing the need for improved social safety nets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/both-central-and-delhi-governments-failed-rahul-gandhi-visits-aiims-to-support-patients-amid-treatment-delays/articleshow/117316608.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/both-central-and-delhi-governments-failed-rahul-gandhi-visits-aiims-to-support-patients-amid-treatment-delays/articleshow/117316608.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan attack: 20 teams formed to nab attacker, say Mumbai police - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/saif-ali-khan-attack-20-teams-formed-to-nab-attacker-say-mumbai-police/article69107279.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/saif-ali-khan-attack-20-teams-formed-to-nab-attacker-say-mumbai-police/article69107279.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infosys shares remain the top IT stock pick after Q3 results; Check new price targets - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/infosys-share-price-top-it-stock-pick-post-q3-results-adr-buy-sell-target-guidance-19541668.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/infosys-share-price-top-it-stock-pick-post-q3-results-adr-buy-sell-target-guidance-19541668.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:03:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian stock market: 10 key things that changed for market overnight - Gift Nifty, Reliance Q3 results to Infosys ADR - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian stock market: 10 key things that changed for market overnight - Gift Nifty, Reliance Q3 results to Infosys ADR</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The Indian stock market is set to open lower, influenced by declines in global markets, particularly following weak performances in Asian and US stocks. Despite recent gains, key upcoming events are on traders' radar.</p><img src='https://www.livemint.com/stock-market-image.jpg' alt='Stock Market Image'><figcaption>Market Overview</figcaption><p>Key headlines from the market include:</p><ul><li>Sensex rose 318.74 points to close at 77,042.82, while Nifty closed at 23,311.80.</li><li>Asian markets experienced declines ahead of key economic data from China.</li><li>Gift Nifty indicates a negative start for Indian indices after trading around 23,322.</li><li>Reliance Industries reported a Q3 profit of ₹18,540 crore, a 7.4% increase YoY.</li><li>Infosys’ Q3 net profit rose by 4.6%, totaling ₹6,806 crore, with raised revenue guidance for FY25.</li></ul><blockquote>“While Nifty has seen a three-day recovery, it remains below its 200 DMA at 23,963, with key support at 23,000.” - Prashanth Tapse, Senior VP (Research), Mehta Equities Ltd.</blockquote><p>The market's outlook remains cautious as investors await more data and reactions to corporate earnings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/indian-stock-market-10-key-things-that-changed-for-market-overnight-gift-nifty-reliance-q3-results-to-infosys-adr-11737040092214.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/indian-stock-market-10-key-things-that-changed-for-market-overnight-gift-nifty-reliance-q3-results-to-infosys-adr-11737040092214.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:41:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lancet commission proposes new definition for obesity: All you need to know - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lancet Commission Proposes New Definition for Obesity: Key Insights</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Lancet</p><p>A new definition and method for diagnosing obesity has been proposed by the Lancet Diabetes &amp; Endocrinology Commission, moving beyond the BMI standard to better reflect health outcomes related to body fat.</p><ul><li>The traditional BMI measurement may lead to over- and under-diagnosis of obesity.</li><li>A new category called Preclinical Obesity has been introduced for individuals with excess body fat but no ongoing illness.</li><li>Clinical obesity is defined as a chronic illness impacting organ functions.</li><li>Evaluation requires multiple physical measurements and assessments by a doctor.</li><li>The Indian definition of obesity will maintain stage classifications instead of the new proposed categories.</li></ul><blockquote>Dr. Anoop Misra stated, “We saw that Indians would get diabetes... even at lower BMI due to higher body fat percentages.”</blockquote><p>The new definitions aim to improve diagnosis and management strategies for obesity, particularly in diverse populations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-health/lancet-new-definition-obesity-9782591/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-health/lancet-new-definition-obesity-9782591/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:32:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>