<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 10:13:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 10:13:05 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's critical warning: A 200-foot, airplane-sized asteroid is approaching Earth at high speed tomorrow - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-s-critical-warning-a-200-foot-airplane-sized-asteroid-is-approaching-earth-at-high-speed-tomorrow-article-12889891.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-s-critical-warning-a-200-foot-airplane-sized-asteroid-is-approaching-earth-at-high-speed-tomorrow-article-12889891.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:30:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session LIVE: ‘Rahul clueless on pages in Constitution', says Thakur - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament Winter Session LIVE: BJP invokes Emergency to counter Rahul Gandhi's attacks</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/image_1734165966421_1734165975726.png" alt="Parliament Session Live: Leader of opposition in the Lok Sabha speaks during a debate on 75 years of India's Constitution." title="Parliament Session Live: Leader of opposition in the Lok Sabha speaks during a debate on 75 years of India's Constitution." width="360" height="202" loading="lazy" decoding="async">
<figcaption>Parliament Session Live: Leader of opposition in the Lok Sabha speaks during a debate on 75 years of India's Constitution.</figcaption>
<p>During the second day of the Winter Session of Parliament, important discussions took place regarding the Constitution, with prominent debates between the ruling party and the opposition highlighting ongoing political tensions.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Lok Sabha holds a special debate on the Constitution, celebrating its 75th anniversary.</li>
    <li>Rahul Gandhi accused the BJP of using Emergency tactics to suppress dissent.</li>
    <li>Priyanka Gandhi Vadra delivered her maiden speech, criticizing the government for failing to support citizens.</li>
    <li>The BJP countered opposition claims, specifically targeting Rahul Gandhi's remarks on the Constitution and historical figures.</li>
    <li>Upcoming discussions on the 'One Nation, One Election' bill, sparking controversy among opposition parties.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Constitution is a document of modern India, but it could never have been written without ancient India, her ideas." - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote>
<p>This Parliament session has showcased the ongoing clash between the BJP and Congress, with leaders vying to define their narratives around the nation's constitutional identity and current political issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-constitution-debate-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-101734138429086.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-constitution-debate-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-101734138429086.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:29:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Nahi ho raha swing' - Jasprit Bumrah's frustration an early worry for India in Gabba Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nahi ho raha swing - Jasprit Bumrah's frustration an early worry for India in Gabba Test</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116314093,imgsize-29074,width-400,resizemode-4/116314093.jpg" alt="'Nahi ho raha swing' - Jasprit Bumrah's frustration an early worry for India in Gabba Test" title="Jasprit Bumrah (Photo Source: X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah (Photo Source: X)</figcaption>
<p>In the third Test against Australia at the Gabba, Indian captain Rohit Sharma opted to bowl first under cloudy conditions. However, Jasprit Bumrah expressed his frustration over the lack of swing during the early overs.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Rohit Sharma chose to bowl first despite expectations of a favorable pitch for fast bowlers.</li>
    <li>Bumrah was heard on the stump microphone saying, "Nahin ho raha swing aise bhi; kahin bhi kar lo", indicating the ball was not swinging.</li>
    <li>The first day was disrupted by rain, with only 13.2 overs bowled, leaving Australia at 28 for 0 by the end.</li>
    <li>Indian bowlers experimented with different lines but failed to get swing or seam movement.</li>
    <li>Former players and commentators expressed concerns about the decision to bowl first at the Gabba, citing historical context.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"You bat at the Gabba. If you face Australia, you want them to bat second and fourth." - Kerry O'Keeffe</blockquote>
<p>This situation highlights ongoing challenges for India in the Test series and raises questions about their bowling strategy in conditions that did not provide the expected advantages.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/nahi-ho-raha-swing-jasprit-bumrahs-frustration-an-early-worry-for-india-in-gabba-test/articleshow/116314004.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/nahi-ho-raha-swing-jasprit-bumrahs-frustration-an-early-worry-for-india-in-gabba-test/articleshow/116314004.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Imad, Amir announce retirement from international cricket - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Imad, Amir announce retirement from international cricket</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> PCB Statement</p>
<p>Imad Wasim and Mohammad Amir have announced their retirement from international cricket, expressing gratitude to fans and the Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) for their support throughout their careers.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Imad Wasim mentioned the fulfillment of a dream representing Pakistan.</li>
    <li>He expressed gratitude to fans and the PCB, wishing success for the national team.</li>
    <li>Mohammad Amir emphasized the honor of playing for Pakistan in all formats.</li>
    <li>Amir believes it is time for the next generation to take over in Pakistan cricket.</li>
    <li>Both players thanked fans for their support and the PCB for their assistance over the years.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It has been a great journey representing my country... I wish great success to the national team.” – Imad Wasim</blockquote>
<blockquote>“It has been a great honour to play for Pakistan... I feel this is the right time for the next generation to take the baton.” – Mohammad Amir</blockquote>
<p>Both Imad Wasim and Mohammad Amir leave behind a legacy of dedication to Pakistan cricket, prompting a hopeful outlook for its future with new players. </p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/pakistan-star-announces-retirement-from-international-cricket</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/pakistan-star-announces-retirement-from-international-cricket</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:37:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol Impeached Over Failed Martial Law Bid - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNaFBWYk10c2pvRVp5OFlVaUxvYVlreEVZWVJEV2JPX3lRTUhiT21oRlNhampXOGp3a05IVG5tZ3l3dmJDaVVaOFlyeEY2eEFRWEJKaW94ZzAxY2Z6SUF4NzdvQ0taemNBZVFoYkV4UW9Ia01tazMtbWs0MHdWbXNsRFl2d3U1Tms0UTZRM2VqbEtLd2VLTnJ5RDJNdVJZcnRiMjVMU0EyZUJOUWxFc2dqNlgtWVhhZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNaFBWYk10c2pvRVp5OFlVaUxvYVlreEVZWVJEV2JPX3lRTUhiT21oRlNhampXOGp3a05IVG5tZ3l3dmJDaVVaOFlyeEY2eEFRWEJKaW94ZzAxY2Z6SUF4NzdvQ0taemNBZVFoYkV4UW9Ia01tazMtbWs0MHdWbXNsRFl2d3U1Tms0UTZRM2VqbEtLd2VLTnJ5RDJNdVJZcnRiMjVMU0EyZUJOUWxFc2dqNlgtWVhhZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:08:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naga Chaitanya, Rana Daggubati, Vijay Deverakonda meet Pushpa 2 star Allu Arjun after his release from jail. Watch videos - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Naga Chaitanya, Rana Daggubati, Vijay Deverakonda meet Pushpa 2 star Allu Arjun after his release from jail. Watch videos.</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Arjun.jpg?w=640" alt="Allu Arjun was welcomed by his friends" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Allu Arjun was welcomed by his Vijay Deverakonda, Naga Chaitanya, Rana Daggubati and others (Photo: X)</figcaption>
<p>After his emotional release from jail, Allu Arjun received a warm welcome from his friends and family, including notable actors and the director of his film Pushpa 2.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Allu Arjun was released from jail after being arrested in connection with a tragic incident at a screening of his film.</li>
    <li>Vijay Deverakonda, Naga Chaitanya, Rana Daggubati, and director Sukumar were present to greet him.</li>
    <li>Many videos and photos of the reunion were shared on social media.</li>
    <li>The actor had spent a night in Chanchalguda jail before being released.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Vijay Deverakonda visiting #AlluArjun shows real brotherhood, fans love this bond!” — Madhu (@MadhuOmNamo)</blockquote>
<p>Allu Arjun's lawyer claimed that the prison authorities didn’t release him on time despite receiving the bail order. The incident leading to his arrest involved a stampede that resulted in the death of a woman and injuries to her son.</p>
<p>The outpouring of support from his friends and the public emphasizes the strong connections within the film community and the ongoing love for Allu Arjun among fans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/naga-chaitanya-rana-daggubati-vijay-deverakonda-meet-pushpa-2-star-allu-arjun-after-his-release-from-jail-watch-videos-9724472/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/telugu/naga-chaitanya-rana-daggubati-vijay-deverakonda-meet-pushpa-2-star-allu-arjun-after-his-release-from-jail-watch-videos-9724472/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 07:46:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atul Subhash Suicide | Accused-Wife Moves Allahabad High Court Seeking Anticipatory Bail In Abetment To... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Atul Subhash Suicide | Accused-Wife Moves Allahabad High Court Seeking Anticipatory Bail In Abetment To</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p>
<img src="https://www.livelaw.in/h-upload/2024/12/14/750x450_576388-atul-subhash.webp" alt="Atul Subhash Suicide | Accused-Wife Moves Allahabad High Court Seeking Anticipatory Bail In Abetment To Suicide Case" title="Atul Subhash Suicide | Accused-Wife Moves Allahabad High Court Seeking Anticipatory Bail In Abetment To Suicide Case">
<figcaption>Image related to Atul Subhash's case.</figcaption>
<p>The wife of Atul Subhash, a 34-year-old techie from Bangalore who allegedly died by suicide, has filed for anticipatory bail in connection with an FIR accusing her and her family of abetting his suicide.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Atul Subhash left a 'justice is due' placard and a 24-page suicide note before his death.</li>
    <li>He recorded an 81-minute video detailing the harassment he faced from his wife, Nikita Singhania, during their legal disputes.</li>
    <li>An FIR was lodged against Nikita and her family by Atul's brother, claiming abetment to suicide.</li>
    <li>Nikita and three family members have filed an anticipatory bail plea with the Allahabad High Court.</li>
    <li>A PIL has been filed in the Supreme Court seeking reforms in domestic violence and dowry laws to protect husbands and their families.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>#JustIn #AtulSubhashSuicideCase | An anticipatory bail petition has been filed by his wife, Nikita Singhania, and three of her family members before the #AllahabadHighCourt in connection with an FIR filed against them over abetment to suicide case.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This case highlights the complexities surrounding domestic disputes and mental health, raising important discussions on legal protections in familial conflicts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/allahabad-high-court/atul-subhash-suicide-accused-wife-moves-allahabad-high-court-seeking-anticipatory-bail-in-abetment-to-suicide-case-278344</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/allahabad-high-court/atul-subhash-suicide-accused-wife-moves-allahabad-high-court-seeking-anticipatory-bail-in-abetment-to-suicide-case-278344</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 07:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Happy we reached our country': Four Indians arrive in Delhi from Syria - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/happy-we-reached-our-country-four-indians-arrive-in-delhi-from-syria/articleshow/116310411.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/happy-we-reached-our-country-four-indians-arrive-in-delhi-from-syria/articleshow/116310411.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 07:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ranbir-Alia channel Raj Kapoor-core, Saif-Kareena bring Nawabi flair to greatest showman's centenary celebrations - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ranbir-Alia channel Raj Kapoor-core, Saif-Kareena bring Nawabi flair to greatest showman's centenary celebrations</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Best_dressed_at_Raj_Kapoors_centenary_celebrations_1734159503096_1734159503481.jpg" alt="Raj Kapoor's centenary celebrations see Ranbir-Alia channel the retro vibe with Saif-Kareena tapping into some old world charm(Photos: X, Instagram)" title="Raj Kapoor's centenary celebrations see Ranbir-Alia channel the retro vibe with Saif-Kareena tapping into some old world charm(Photos: X, Instagram)">
<figcaption>Raj Kapoor's centenary celebrations see Ranbir-Alia channel the retro vibe with Saif-Kareena tapping into some old world charm (Photos: X, Instagram)</figcaption>
<p>The celebrations marking the centenary of Raj Kapoor brought together prominent members of the Kapoor family, showcasing stunning fashion and honoring the legacy of Indian cinema's greatest showman.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Ranbir Kapoor and Alia Bhatt opened the event at the Prime Minister's residence, inviting guests to a celebration in Mumbai.</li>
    <li>Ranbir donned a midnight velveteen bandhgala, resembling Raj Kapoor, while Alia wore a vintage-inspired Sabyasachi saree.</li>
    <li>Kareena Kapoor and Saif Ali Khan showcased their Nawabi heritage with elegant traditional attire.</li>
    <li>Vicky Kaushal also captured attention with a sharp pinstriped suit, adding to the evening's fashion highlight.</li>
    <li>Fashion trends of the night leaned heavily on retro styles, celebrating the iconic era of the 60s.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Alia looked sophisticated-ly sultry while Saif and Kareena looked every bit the Nawab and Begum."</blockquote>
<p>The night was a grand salute to the legacy of Raj Kapoor, as stars paid tribute through their attire, embodying the essence and glamour of Indian cinema’s rich history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/raj-kapoor-100-years-celebration-ranbir-kapoor-alia-bhatt-kareena-kapoor-saif-ali-khan-vicky-kaushal-steal-the-show-101734158563254.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/raj-kapoor-100-years-celebration-ranbir-kapoor-alia-bhatt-kareena-kapoor-saif-ali-khan-vicky-kaushal-steal-the-show-101734158563254.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 07:01:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Juno mission uncovers heart of Jovian moon's volcanic rage - CGTN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Juno mission uncovers heart of Jovian moon's volcanic rage</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Xinhua News Agency</p>
<img src="https://news.cgtn.com/news/2024-12-14/NASA-s-Juno-mission-uncovers-heart-of-Jovian-moon-s-volcanic-rage-1zjXenFAFfG/img/68f41429f50245388a1c8bf686defb93/68f41429f50245388a1c8bf686defb93.jpeg" alt="Jupiter's volcanic moon Io was captured by NASA's Juno during the spacecraft's close pass of the gas giant, February 3, 2024. /CFP">
<figcaption>Jupiter's volcanic moon Io was captured by NASA's Juno during the spacecraft's close pass of the gas giant, February 3, 2024. /CFP</figcaption>
<p>Scientists with NASA's Juno mission have revealed new insights into the volcanic activity of Jupiter's moon Io, showing that each volcano is likely powered by individual chambers of magma rather than a single ocean of magma.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The finding addresses a 44-year-old mystery regarding Io's volcanic activity.</li>
    <li>Io, similar in size to Earth's moon, is the most volcanically active body in the solar system, with approximately 400 volcanoes.</li>
    <li>The Juno spacecraft conducted close flybys of Io in December 2023 and February 2024, achieving proximity of about 1,500 kilometers to its surface.</li>
    <li>Juno collected high-precision data to analyze Io's gravity and the effects of tidal flexing on the moon.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Juno's discovery that tidal forces do not always create global magma oceans does more than prompt us to rethink what we know about Io's interior," - Ryan Park, Juno co-investigator.</blockquote>
<p>The insights gained from Juno's mission may also reshape our understanding of other celestial bodies and have broader implications for the study of planetary formation and evolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.cgtn.com/news/2024-12-14/NASA-s-Juno-mission-uncovers-heart-of-Jovian-moon-s-volcanic-rage-1zjXenFAFfG/p.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.cgtn.com/news/2024-12-14/NASA-s-Juno-mission-uncovers-heart-of-Jovian-moon-s-volcanic-rage-1zjXenFAFfG/p.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:44:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['One Nation, One Election' : How Constitution Is Proposed To Be Amended For Simultaneous Elections To Lok ... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>One Nation, One Election: How Constitution Is Proposed To Be Amended For Simultaneous Elections To Lok</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p>
<p>The 'One Nation, One Election' Bill aims to amend the Constitution to facilitate simultaneous elections for the Lok Sabha and all Legislative Assemblies. The Bill is set to be tabled in Parliament and proposes significant changes to existing electoral laws.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Bill seeks to insert Article 82A for simultaneous elections to the House of the People and all Legislative Assemblies.</li>
    <li>It also amends Articles 83, 172, and 327 regarding the duration and conduct of elections.</li>
    <li>Simultaneous elections mean general elections held together for the Lok Sabha and all Legislative Assemblies.</li>
    <li>Provisions include how mid-term elections will be managed and their alignment for Union Territories.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"There was an imperative need for holding of simultaneous elections. The imposition of Model Code of Conduct in various parts of the country which are poll-bound puts on hold the entire development programs." - Government Statement</blockquote>
<p>The proposed amendments focus on streamlining the electoral process, addressing inefficiencies caused by staggered elections, and aligning legislative terms to enhance governance and development.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/one-nation-one-election-how-constitution-is-proposed-to-be-amended-for-simultaneous-elections-to-lok-sabha-state-assemblies-278339</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/one-nation-one-election-how-constitution-is-proposed-to-be-amended-for-simultaneous-elections-to-lok-sabha-state-assemblies-278339</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:37:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Box Office Collections: Allu Arjun starrer holds well on second Friday, rises to 850cr in India - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office Collections: Allu Arjun starrer holds well on second Friday, rises to 850cr in India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024&nbsp;|&nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p>
<img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/843557979_pushpa-3.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2" title="Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)</figcaption>
<p>Pushpa 2 has achieved impressive box office success, grossing a total of Rs. 853 crore in India, approaching the Rs. 1000 crore milestone.</p>
<ul>
    <li>On its second Friday, Pushpa 2 earned approximately Rs. 42.50 crore.</li>
    <li>The film experienced minimal collection drops and even some growth in Telugu states from Thursday.</li>
    <li>Pushpa 2’s second Friday gross is the second highest of all time, trailing only Baahubali 2.</li>
    <li>The film has already surpassed Rs. 1000 crore worldwide as of Wednesday.</li>
    <li>Territorial box office breakdown shows AP/TS leading with Rs. 234.50 crore, followed by the Hindi Belt at Rs. 485 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>“It was essential for it to hold well on the second Friday to hope for a strong second-week hold, and the film has done better than it probably needed to.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Pushpa 2 is on course to challenge the box office record held by Baahubali 2 as it continues its successful run in theaters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collections-allu-arjun-starrer-holds-well-on-second-friday-rises-to-850cr-in-india-1362730</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collections-allu-arjun-starrer-holds-well-on-second-friday-rises-to-850cr-in-india-1362730</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:36:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Priyanka Gandhi meant when she told BJP: ‘Learn from us on Emergency, you too apologise’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What Priyanka Gandhi meant when she told BJP: ‘Learn from us on Emergency, you too apologise’</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>

<p>In her inaugural speech in Parliament, Priyanka Gandhi Vadra addressed the BJP's criticisms regarding the Emergency, urging them to acknowledge their own mistakes and fight fair elections.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Priyanka Gandhi spoke during a special debate on the Constitution, challenging BJP leaders.</li>
    <li>She quoted Defence Minister Rajnath Singh, suggesting that the BJP should apologize for its mistakes.</li>
    <li>Congress leaders, including Rahil Gandhi and Sonia Gandhi, have previously acknowledged the Emergency as a “mistake.”</li>
    <li>Historian Pranab Mukherjee described the Emergency as a "misadventure" in his writings.</li>
    <li>Shashi Tharoor highlighted that the Emergency was "undemocratic" but not "unconstitutional."</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>“What happened in the Emergency is wrong. Let us not go back and forth on it.” — Jyotiraditya Scindia</blockquote>

<p>The Congress party has a history of reflecting on the Emergency, with leaders admitting its faults while navigating complex discussions around accountability and historical context.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/priyanka-gandhi-emergency-bjp-parliament-speech-constitution-9724385/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/priyanka-gandhi-emergency-bjp-parliament-speech-constitution-9724385/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:31:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia Highlights, 3rd Test Day 1: Rain Forces Stumps; India's WTC Final Hopes Hang In Balance - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-1-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7242619</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-1-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7242619</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:25:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[E.V.K.S. Elangovan, senior Congress leader and Erode (East) MLA, no more - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>E.V.K.S. Elangovan, senior Congress leader and Erode (East) MLA, no more</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/pohwxh/article68984563.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/9870_31_5_2024_12_35_21_2_ER01EVKS2.JPG" alt="Erode (East) MLA E.V.K.S. Elangovan. File photo." title="Erode (East) MLA E.V.K.S. Elangovan. File photo.">
<figcaption>Erode (East) MLA E.V.K.S. Elangovan. File photo. | Photo Credit: M. Govarthan</figcaption>
<p>Former chief of the Tamil Nadu Congress Committee (TNCC) and former Union Minister of State, E.V.K.S. Elangovan, passed away in Chennai on Saturday morning after a brief illness at the age of 73.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Mr. Elangovan was admitted to MIOT hospital on November 13.</li>
    <li>He is survived by his wife and a son.</li>
    <li>He represented Erode (East), a seat previously held by his deceased son, E. Thirumahan Everaa.</li>
    <li>He was a prominent figure in Tamil Nadu politics, serving as TNCC president twice.</li>
    <li>He was also a former Union Minister of State, with responsibilities in key sectors such as Petroleum and Commerce.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"He held the post of TNCC president twice - 2000 to 2002 and 2014 to 2016 when the party was increasingly getting marginalised in the State politics."</blockquote>
<p>With a notable political lineage, Mr. Elangovan's contributions to the Congress party and Tamil Nadu politics have left a lasting impact.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/tamil-nadu/evks-elangovan-senior-congress-leader-and-erode-east-mla-no-more/article68984569.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/tamil-nadu/evks-elangovan-senior-congress-leader-and-erode-east-mla-no-more/article68984569.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 signs on your face and body that say your hands are not clean - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 signs on your face and body that say your hands are not clean</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/imgsize-40146,msid-116309799,width-600,height-335,resizemode-75/116309799.jpg" alt="10 signs on your face and body that say your hands are not clean">
<figcaption>10 signs indicating that your hands are not clean.</figcaption>
<p>Hygiene is crucial for good health, and there are often overlooked signs on your face and body that indicate your hands may not be clean. These symptoms, such as outbreaks and inflammation, emphasize the importance of hand hygiene.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Eye infections may occur from rubbing eyes with unclean hands, leading to conditions like conjunctivitis.</li>
    <li>Skin infections can arise when germs transfer from dirty hands to cuts or scrapes.</li>
    <li>Touching the mouth or nose with unwashed hands can lead to frequent colds and flu.</li>
    <li>Chapped lips may result from bacteria and dirt transferring to sensitive skin from dirty hands.</li>
    <li>Nail infections can develop due to germs under the nails, caused by inadequate hand hygiene.</li>
    <li>Frequent acne may be linked to touching the face with unclean hands, which clogs pores.</li>
    <li>Rashes or allergic reactions can be triggered by transferring irritants from dirty hands to sensitive skin.</li>
    <li>Eczema symptoms may flare up due to contamination from unclean hands.</li>
    <li>Stomach troubles, including food poisoning, can result from bacteria on dirty hands entering the digestive system.</li>
    <li>Body odour can develop when bacteria from unclean hands transfer to clothing or skin.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Proper hand hygiene can efficiently prevent health risks associated with dirty hands." </blockquote>
<p>Practicing good hand hygiene is essential for maintaining overall health and preventing various infections and conditions that can arise from dirty hands.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/10-signs-on-your-face-and-body-that-say-your-hands-are-not-clean/photostory/116309768.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/10-signs-on-your-face-and-body-that-say-your-hands-are-not-clean/photostory/116309768.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:51:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's per capita availability of fruits and vegetables increases by 7 kg and 12 kg over last decade: Report | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/indias-per-capita-availability-of-fruits-and-vegetables-increases-by-7-kg-and-12-kg-over-last-decade-report-11734155494052.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/indias-per-capita-availability-of-fruits-and-vegetables-increases-by-7-kg-and-12-kg-over-last-decade-report-11734155494052.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:51:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Farmers resume ‘Delhi chalo’ protest march, internet suspended in Ambala - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Farmers resume ‘Delhi chalo’ protest march, internet suspended in Ambala</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/farmers_protest_1734161768674_1734161768959.jpg" alt="Farmers raise slogans as they gather at their protest site at Shambhu border for their 'Delhi Chalo' protest march. (PTI)">
<figcaption>Farmers raise slogans as they gather at their protest site at Shambhu border for their 'Delhi Chalo' protest march. (PTI)</figcaption>
<p>A group of farmers has resumed their protest march towards Delhi, asserting their right to agitate at the national capital, while internet services are suspended in Ambala to maintain public order.</p>
<ul>
    <li>101 farmers resumed their ‘Delhi Chalo’ protest from Haryana's Shambhu border, marking the 307th day of their agitation.</li>
    <li>Farmers demand legal guarantees for Minimum Support Price (MSP), debt waivers, pension, withdrawal of police cases, and justice for victims of the 2021 Lakhimpur Kheri violence.</li>
    <li>Police deployed tear gas and water cannons as farmers continued their march despite warnings.</li>
    <li>The Haryana government suspended mobile internet services in 12 villages in Ambala until December 17 to prevent unrest.</li>
    <li>Supreme Court intervened to ensure medical aid for a farmer on a hunger strike, emphasizing the importance of dialogue over agitation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Union Agriculture Minister has not been speaking about the protest either and the way BJP MPs are doing 'bayanbazi' is going to cause division in communities." - Sarwan Singh Pandher, KMM leader</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing protests highlight the farmers' determination to press for their rights amidst heightened tensions and police interventions.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/farmers-to-resume-delhi-chalo-protest-march-saturday-internet-suspended-in-ambala-101734153442630.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/farmers-to-resume-delhi-chalo-protest-march-saturday-internet-suspended-in-ambala-101734153442630.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:31:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Market Weekly Recap: SENSEX, NIFTY rebound to extend gains for 4th week; NIFTY IT hits lifetime high - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Weekly Recap: SENSEX, NIFTY rebound to extend gains for 4th week; NIFTY IT hits lifetime high</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p>
<p>It was a roller coaster ride for Indian stock markets this week, but benchmark indices closed higher, extending gains for the fourth consecutive week, driven by strong performances from key sectors.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Bharti Airtel, Bajaj Finance, Infosys, and Wipro were major gainers, while Tata Consumer Products, HUL, NTPC, and Reliance Industries saw losses.</li>
    <li>The NIFTY IT index reached a lifetime high of 46,088.90, increasing over 2.5% for the week.</li>
    <li>Religare Enterprises shares rose by 10% following RBI approval for the Burman family to acquire an additional stake.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“SENSEX advanced 623.07 points, or 0.76%, while NIFTY gained 90.5 points, or 0.36%, on a weekly basis.”</blockquote>
<p>Despite volatility and cautious investor sentiment linked to global political instability and upcoming US Federal Reserve decisions, the markets showed resilience, with domestic investors buying on dips. This week witnessed significant fluctuations in trading, ending on a positive note with a surge in buying activity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/stock-market-weekly-recap-sensex-nifty-rebound-to-extend-gains-for-4th-week-nifty-it-hits-lifetime-high/article-135168/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/trading/stock-market-weekly-recap-sensex-nifty-rebound-to-extend-gains-for-4th-week-nifty-it-hits-lifetime-high/article-135168/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:14:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session 2024: Lok Sabha erupts in protest as A. Raja alleges that a government functionary has said they want to ‘change the Constitution’ - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPYzlxeTFZeFlvYkUyWTRFWkV6WWdiN3RMZ2NFSWc4b0Y4NjhWQnJYdnN6ZEtuRW9OMlFhLWtqeTVpQ3otdjk0U2NSRVNCc2xKU0VpVGc1R2kxQ2N3S2hlNHBobFFSWnhyZ2pTYlBldnQtZFFSSF9odUs1MEtHZWtoWWJJSjhORlVQcDBCY2NFOWQtTlVYVWlodUs0ekNYUEo3U1VMNkg4aXhtd3dqWGhCQUVWWW43Z3lFZWU5NUpUM3dNYmZ2elhJVzZsTElFQVM5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPYzlxeTFZeFlvYkUyWTRFWkV6WWdiN3RMZ2NFSWc4b0Y4NjhWQnJYdnN6ZEtuRW9OMlFhLWtqeTVpQ3otdjk0U2NSRVNCc2xKU0VpVGc1R2kxQ2N3S2hlNHBobFFSWnhyZ2pTYlBldnQtZFFSSF9odUs1MEtHZWtoWWJJSjhORlVQcDBCY2NFOWQtTlVYVWlodUs0ekNYUEo3U1VMNkg4aXhtd3dqWGhCQUVWWW43Z3lFZWU5NUpUM3dNYmZ2elhJVzZsTElFQVM5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for December 14, 2024: Grab freebies in battle royale game daily - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-december-14-2024-grab-freebies-in-battle-royale-game-daily-article-12889852.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-december-14-2024-grab-freebies-in-battle-royale-game-daily-article-12889852.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:04:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gold Rate And Silver Price Today on December 14, 2024: Check latest Rates in India | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/commodities/gold-rate-and-silver-price-today-on-december-14-2024-check-latest-rates-in-india-11734152403004.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/commodities/gold-rate-and-silver-price-today-on-december-14-2024-check-latest-rates-in-india-11734152403004.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for December 14: Win diamonds, pets, cool skins, and more rewards today - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-december-14-win-diamonds-pets-cool-skins-and-more-rewards-today/articleshow/116308399.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-december-14-win-diamonds-pets-cool-skins-and-more-rewards-today/articleshow/116308399.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 04:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nearly 18K Indians in US on deportation list - The Siasat Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nearly 18K Indians in US on deportation list</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 22, 2020</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/2020_5img10_May_2020_PTI10-05-2020_000261B-780x470.jpg" alt="Mumbai: Indian nationals who were stranded in Singapore wait to board buses towards a quarantine centre at Mumbai International Airport after being evacuated by the government under 'Vande Bharat' mission, during the ongoing COVID-19 lockdown, in Mumbai, Sunday, May 10, 2020. (PTI Photo)(PTI10-05-2020_000261B)" width="1200" height="775">
    <figcaption>Representational Image</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Nearly 18,000 undocumented Indian nationals are on the deportation list prepared by the US government amidst a significant deportation initiative by the Trump administration.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Nearly 18,000 Indians are included in a wider ICE deportation list of approximately 1.5 million people.</li>
    <li>The US has around 725,000 illegal immigrants from India, which is the third-largest group of unauthorized immigrants.</li>
    <li>Over the last three years, an average of 90,000 Indians have been apprehended while attempting to cross US borders illegally.</li>
    <li>India is categorized by ICE as "uncooperative" regarding coordination for the return of its nationals.</li>
    <li>ICE considers 15 countries uncooperative, including India, in facilitating deportations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “The average of 90,000 Indians have been apprehended while attempting to cross US borders illegally over the last three financial years.”
</blockquote>
<p>This situation highlights the struggle of thousands of undocumented Indians in the US who seek to legalize their status while facing significant hurdles. The US government’s actions reflect broader immigration enforcement practices and international relations related to deportation. </p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.siasat.com/nearly-18k-indians-in-us-on-deportation-list-3147747/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.siasat.com/nearly-18k-indians-in-us-on-deportation-list-3147747/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 04:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 reasons why beauty sleep is important - Health shots]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxPaVpsOVREZGR2eVRZLVFEb2RkbDdkdGhwRGNFeDZ0cUQxR01wbUVrbURoTmpzYUxSWURGT3gyQ3BPVmJBV2s3NFp5MjYzbFpWMkkxazhRSF9RS09GLUYxdFJmSmx2Q2w2UXZ2STFWVTlsQ0g2Q09VaU91UGhaMzFlNm5WSEhldW1yWWdxQ3J2d2hVQnZFcUcyZ3NDSjRia0nSAZ8BQVVfeXFMT2labDlURGRkdnlUWS1RRG9kZGw3ZHRocERjRXg2dHFEMUdNcG1Fa21EaE5qc2FMUllERk94MkNwT1ZiQVdrNzRaeTI2M2xaVjJJMWs4UUhfUUtPRi1GMXRSZkpsdkNsNlF2dkkxVlU5bENINkNPVWlPdVBoWjMxZTZuVkhIZXVtcllncUNydndoVUJ2RXFHMmdzQ0o0YmtJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxPaVpsOVREZGR2eVRZLVFEb2RkbDdkdGhwRGNFeDZ0cUQxR01wbUVrbURoTmpzYUxSWURGT3gyQ3BPVmJBV2s3NFp5MjYzbFpWMkkxazhRSF9RS09GLUYxdFJmSmx2Q2w2UXZ2STFWVTlsQ0g2Q09VaU91UGhaMzFlNm5WSEhldW1yWWdxQ3J2d2hVQnZFcUcyZ3NDSjRia0nSAZ8BQVVfeXFMT2labDlURGRkdnlUWS1RRG9kZGw3ZHRocERjRXg2dHFEMUdNcG1Fa21EaE5qc2FMUllERk94MkNwT1ZiQVdrNzRaeTI2M2xaVjJJMWs4UUhfUUtPRi1GMXRSZkpsdkNsNlF2dkkxVlU5bENINkNPVWlPdVBoWjMxZTZuVkhIZXVtcllncUNydndoVUJ2RXFHMmdzQ0o0YmtJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 04:30:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp now offers you in-app dialer for calling unknown numbers - NewsBytes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxOcnpCbDNobndpY3M0M3VsVEFvWkF0Y2piSml0ZjRvR1VlV09FOWlBbWhDMF9wRktKdGhnTklZX0I2SEtrdTBfY0p3RWkyQS1aQ3NUYVJrVjVGNnVVelNiZUZ2ZkNvcVQ1S0xvOG9tWXJvNEwyZy1OMmVpNHp4VkJPdURGOUVGbHNVSV9RNERMLWZ3T2UzeUpIM3NkTHdqak0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxOcnpCbDNobndpY3M0M3VsVEFvWkF0Y2piSml0ZjRvR1VlV09FOWlBbWhDMF9wRktKdGhnTklZX0I2SEtrdTBfY0p3RWkyQS1aQ3NUYVJrVjVGNnVVelNiZUZ2ZkNvcVQ1S0xvOG9tWXJvNEwyZy1OMmVpNHp4VkJPdURGOUVGbHNVSV9RNERMLWZ3T2UzeUpIM3NkTHdqak0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 04:29:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explained: The Assad regime fallout in Syria and why India charts a cautious path - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/explained-the-assad-regime-fallout-in-syria-and-why-india-charts-a-cautious-path-12889837.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/explained-the-assad-regime-fallout-in-syria-and-why-india-charts-a-cautious-path-12889837.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 04:18:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FIDE reacts to ‘deliberately lost’ allegations on Gukesh vs Ding World Championship final, counters Carlsen, Kramnik - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FIDE reacts to ‘deliberately lost’ allegations on Gukesh vs Ding World Championship final, counters Carlsen, Kramnik</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/PTI12-13-2024-000509A-0_1734147732625_1734147841264.jpg" alt="India's D Gukesh poses for photographs with the FIDE World Chess Championship 2024 trophy, in Singapore(PTI)">
<figcaption>India's D Gukesh poses for photographs with the FIDE World Chess Championship 2024 trophy, in Singapore(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Amid heavy criticism from former World Champions regarding the quality of the Gukesh vs Ding World Championship final, FIDE President Arkady Dvorkovich stated that mistakes in sports are natural and should not be attributed to players of such high caliber.</p>
<ul>
    <li>FIDE President Arkady Dvorkovich commented on the criticism regarding the players' performance in the final, stating that mistakes are an inherent part of sports.</li>
    <li>Defending champion Ding made a critical error in the final match, leading to an unexpected victory for 18-year-old Gukesh.</li>
    <li>Former champion Vladimir Kramnik criticized Ding's mistake, labeling it "childish" and calling for an investigation.</li>
    <li>Kramnik expressed disappointment over the match quality, calling it "the end of chess as we know it."</li>
    <li>Magnus Carlsen also questioned the standard of play, stating it resembled early rounds of an open tournament.</li>
    <li>Viswanathan Anand advised Gukesh to ignore criticism, emphasizing that it accompanies success.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Sports is about mistakes, without mistakes, there would be no goals in football. Every sportsman makes mistakes but that's what we are excited about, whether the opponent can find the way to use a mistake." - Arkady Dvorkovich</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing debate highlights the intense scrutiny faced by young champions like Gukesh and the differing opinions within the chess community regarding the evolving standards of the game.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/fide-reacts-to-deliberately-lost-allegations-on-gukesh-vs-ding-world-championship-final-counters-carlsen-kramnik-101734147141365.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/fide-reacts-to-deliberately-lost-allegations-on-gukesh-vs-ding-world-championship-final-counters-carlsen-kramnik-101734147141365.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 03:52:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bonus Share: BUY 1 get 9 FREE; record date next week - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bonus Share: BUY 1 get 9 FREE; record date next week</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ET NOW News</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="91 Bonus Issue" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>9:1 Bonus Issue: The stock has delivered a jaw-dropping 4,828% return over the past three years. (Image: Canva/ET NOW News)</figcaption>
<p>A smallcap company, Sky Gold, has announced a bonus issue of shares at a 9:1 ratio. Shareholders are set to receive nine free shares for every one share held, with the record date being fixed for next week.</p>
<ul>
    <li>A smallcap company has announced a bonus issue of shares in the ratio 9:1.</li>
    <li>The stock has delivered a remarkable 4,828% return over the past three years.</li>
    <li>The company's board has set the record date for December 16, 2024.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This stock has been a true multibagger, delivering a jaw-dropping 4,828% return over the past three years.”</blockquote>
<p>The Sky Gold shares closed at Rs 4,435.30 per share, with a 52-week range from Rs 902.1 to Rs 4,680. This announcement is seen as a way to reward shareholders and enhance liquidity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/bonus-share-buy-1-get-9-free-record-date-next-week-sky-gold-article-116305755</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/bonus-share-buy-1-get-9-free-record-date-next-week-sky-gold-article-116305755</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 03:45:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump suggests government knows more about drone sightings than they are letting on, ‘Let the public know’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump suggests government knows more about drone sightings than they are letting on, ‘Let the public know’</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Media-Fearing-Trump-0_1734147645419_1734147688804.jpg" alt="Donald Trump claims government knows more about drone sightings than they are letting on (Timothy A. Clary/Pool Photo via AP, File)(AP)">
<figcaption>Donald Trump claims government knows more about drone sightings than they are letting on (Timothy A. Clary/Pool Photo via AP, File)(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Donald Trump publicly claimed that the government is withholding information regarding recent drone sightings in the Northeast. He suggested that if the government is unaware of these objects, they should be shot down.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump stated that there are mysterious drone sightings across the U.S. and demanded that the public be informed.</li>
  <li>The drone sightings have raised concerns among lawmakers, linking the incidents to potential threats from foreign adversaries like Iran.</li>
  <li>The Pentagon has denied any foreign involvement regarding the drones spotted near U.S. military installations.</li>
  <li>Republican lawmakers, including Marjorie Taylor Greene and Anna Paulina Luna, have expressed concerns and called for the drones to be shot down.</li>
  <li>Congresswoman Luna emphasized the need for immediate action on unknown objects in airspace, criticizing prior incidents like the Chinese spy balloon event.</li>
  <li>The House Committee on Homeland Security has requested a classified briefing from federal agencies about these drone sightings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Mystery Drone sightings all over the Country. Can this really be happening without our government’s knowledge? I don’t think so! Let the public know, and now. Otherwise, shoot them down!!! DJT,” Trump wrote on Truth Social.</blockquote>
<p>The situation around the drone sightings has sparked significant political discourse, highlighting the intersection of national security and public transparency concerns. As more information comes to light, the calls for action may escalate further.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trump-suggests-government-knows-more-about-drone-sightings-than-they-are-letting-on-let-the-public-know-101734147352733.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trump-suggests-government-knows-more-about-drone-sightings-than-they-are-letting-on-let-the-public-know-101734147352733.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 03:43:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>