<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:14:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus Open 2 to be a big upgrade over its predecessor, expected this spring - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxPWkc0Vld6Z0EzVlI5YWxkOEU1bDhNSXVnQ0dpWWhYRnRqc0JuRjhSTV91RWtGM3MzRUlfNGhyRndTc2gzbUNhNWRydGFKXzBOLV9oMGVGMDJZNm5PcFpqY2Q4VWdIZGJ5Yk9zZl9nQjV0VDlKYklBT0NPVUl1eDdHdXhaWHZpaU8tVG5NV1N0U3FmOXFIZTc3RjFvUy1qa3UyVUt6Y2JrYi1TN180UkJRaWttaWp6UVnSAbMBQVVfeXFMT2RxWDJFNVNnRm9UNlVBZWxub0FHWHFCN0U0WXFvWThsRTF6LXNzTHUyUFVwWUF1NmgydjI0SDBqdmMtb1V6c0NrbWVlOE5GR3pUQk1xTi1QOHhOeTlCbTBwSkIyTlIwVHhOSXo5NnZhZFpVOXZBMjJDUTVHNUQ0S1NSWUdkQ0R0UlhoeEpldlh1SEsyc2NBdmFlU0pFTDlyNDZBZzFtT0lrVGQ2LW1IUDZoTmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxPWkc0Vld6Z0EzVlI5YWxkOEU1bDhNSXVnQ0dpWWhYRnRqc0JuRjhSTV91RWtGM3MzRUlfNGhyRndTc2gzbUNhNWRydGFKXzBOLV9oMGVGMDJZNm5PcFpqY2Q4VWdIZGJ5Yk9zZl9nQjV0VDlKYklBT0NPVUl1eDdHdXhaWHZpaU8tVG5NV1N0U3FmOXFIZTc3RjFvUy1qa3UyVUt6Y2JrYi1TN180UkJRaWttaWp6UVnSAbMBQVVfeXFMT2RxWDJFNVNnRm9UNlVBZWxub0FHWHFCN0U0WXFvWThsRTF6LXNzTHUyUFVwWUF1NmgydjI0SDBqdmMtb1V6c0NrbWVlOE5GR3pUQk1xTi1QOHhOeTlCbTBwSkIyTlIwVHhOSXo5NnZhZFpVOXZBMjJDUTVHNUQ0S1NSWUdkQ0R0UlhoeEpldlh1SEsyc2NBdmFlU0pFTDlyNDZBZzFtT0lrVGQ2LW1IUDZoTmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:17:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India my favourite vs Pakistan, Jasprit Bumrah's absence will be huge loss: Mohammad Amir opens up on ICC - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywJBVV95cUxQU1Y5T2xrNlZ0bGlvVkVJZDBScHc5dG9CRUhJTThpQ05tb1l2bXUzX1BEM0hPY0tNVm1jQU1ZTS1uLWczdFpyLV9wa1MxWl9pWHBCYVBfZHNiREQtdVBaZW10dDdaNzFlVjQ1cFhtTEJYeGxPRWJTLUhma2JkTi1Td2d1SzNYT0hZOEpDV0xqOU1GLU1wX0REVjd5QURzbFZmSERNMXJobGNELVpjcG5LcmRpNENpNGhtVjNlRmxFUWdWUFhzMTBxUkNncjBUZUFVNmxNTFVLNjlaaWdTMW13MHhHMTdqMDZsYURsNHhBRlFwOHlGM3RoNURLOHdiSG1UbVJGVmNKQXVUVWtKT25IMllFcTVFVVE2ZElCZTd6VE1jT3Q4b2JDT2N0OTJHc1VsaURNTjRNWkJNLWwzcjFDNU5kVERJd1VyVWxV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywJBVV95cUxQU1Y5T2xrNlZ0bGlvVkVJZDBScHc5dG9CRUhJTThpQ05tb1l2bXUzX1BEM0hPY0tNVm1jQU1ZTS1uLWczdFpyLV9wa1MxWl9pWHBCYVBfZHNiREQtdVBaZW10dDdaNzFlVjQ1cFhtTEJYeGxPRWJTLUhma2JkTi1Td2d1SzNYT0hZOEpDV0xqOU1GLU1wX0REVjd5QURzbFZmSERNMXJobGNELVpjcG5LcmRpNENpNGhtVjNlRmxFUWdWUFhzMTBxUkNncjBUZUFVNmxNTFVLNjlaaWdTMW13MHhHMTdqMDZsYURsNHhBRlFwOHlGM3RoNURLOHdiSG1UbVJGVmNKQXVUVWtKT25IMllFcTVFVVE2ZElCZTd6VE1jT3Q4b2JDT2N0OTJHc1VsaURNTjRNWkJNLWwzcjFDNU5kVERJd1VyVWxV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires live: 16 dead as Palisades Fire spreads eastward, strong dry winds to worsen - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires: 16 Dead as Palisades Fire Intensifies Amid Dry Winds</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/CALIFORNIA_WILDFIRES_1736668888577_1736668889150.JPG' alt='California wildfire victims' /><figcaption>California wildfire live updates: Ivette Torres is embraced by a neighbour as she stands outside her home of 20 years that was devastated by the Eaton fire.</figcaption><p>The ongoing wildfires in California have led to at least 16 fatalities, the destruction of over 12,000 structures, and thousands of residents under evacuation orders.</p><ul><li>Six simultaneous wildfires affecting Los Angeles County.</li><li>National Weather Service warns of worsening weather conditions with potential gusts reaching up to 70 mph.</li><li>12,000 structures have been damaged or destroyed.</li><li>Over 150,000 residents are under evacuation orders, with many seeking refuge in shelters.</li><li>Continued firefighting efforts include both aerial and ground support.</li></ul><blockquote>“The fires are still raging in L.A. This is one of the worst catastrophes in the history of our Country.” - President Donald Trump</blockquote><p>California continues to confront the aftermath of the wildfires, with significant resources deployed to combat the ongoing crisis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:57:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh summons Indian envoy over border tensions - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh Summons Indian Envoy Over Border Tensions</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Pranay-Verma.jpg?w=640" alt="Pranay Verma" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Pranay Verma (left) has been summoned by Bangladesh amid border tensions. (Photo: X/ MoFA Bangladesh)</figcaption><p>Bangladesh expressed its concerns to India regarding border security and recent actions by the Border Security Force (BSF) that have escalated tensions along the Indo-Bangla border.</p><ul><li>Bangladesh summoned Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma to discuss border tensions.</li><li>Allegations were made that India attempted to construct fences at five locations along the border.</li><li>The Indian envoy emphasized cooperation between BSF and Bangladesh's Border Guard.</li><li>Recent incidents, including a citizen's killing by BSF, heightened concerns.</li><li>Bangladesh aims to resolve issues through dialogue rather than conflict.</li></ul><blockquote>“Unauthorized attempts to construct fences undermine the spirit of cooperation and friendly relations between the two neighboring countries.” - Bangladesh Foreign Secretary Jashim Uddin</blockquote><p>This meeting reflects the ongoing challenges in Indo-Bangladesh relations, emphasizing the need for continued dialogue over border security issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-indian-high-commissioner-border-tensions-9774904/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-indian-high-commissioner-border-tensions-9774904/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Historic planet parade on Jan 25: NASA's 2025 sky guide and how to watch - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Historic Planet Parade on January 25: NASA's 2025 Sky Guide and How to Watch</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> June 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>This January, the night sky offers a rare treat: a parade of four bright planets visible at the same time after sunset. Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars align along the ecliptic, creating a stunning celestial display.</p><img src='link_to_image.jpg' alt='Planet Parade' /><figcaption>The alignment of planets in January 2023.</figcaption><p>To catch the planet parade, head outside after dark and look southwest to spot Venus and Saturn nearby, with Jupiter high overhead and Mars rising in the east.</p><ul><li>Find a spot away from city lights to avoid light pollution.</li><li>Dress warmly, as January nights can be chilly.</li><li>Use binoculars or a telescope to enhance your view of Mars, Venus, and Saturn.</li><li>Be patient and allow your eyes to adjust to the dark.</li><li>Take a star map or use a skywatching app to help identify planets and constellations.</li></ul><p>The Quadrantid meteor shower peaks on January 3, offering up to 30 meteors per hour under ideal conditions. Venus and Saturn will come close on January 17-18, appearing only two degrees apart. Mars will shine bright as it’s at opposition this month, making it an excellent target for observation.</p><blockquote>“On January 13, the full Moon will pass in front of Mars, creating an unforgettable sight for skywatchers.”</blockquote><p>Don't miss out on this incredible opportunity to witness the beauty of our solar system!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-tech/historic-planet-parade-on-jan-25-nasas-2025-sky-guide-and-how-to-watch-8613354</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-tech/historic-planet-parade-on-jan-25-nasas-2025-sky-guide-and-how-to-watch-8613354</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:46:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi BJP MLA's ‘big mistake’ warning over poll ticket to Kapil Mishra in Karawal Nagar - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi BJP MLA's ‘big mistake’ warning over poll ticket to Kapil Mishra in Karawal Nagar</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Kapil-Mishra_1736692087069_1736692087521.jpg" alt="BJP leader Kapil Mishra.(Sanchit Khanna/ Hindustan Times)" title="BJP leader Kapil Mishra.(Sanchit Khanna/ Hindustan Times)"><figcaption>BJP leader Kapil Mishra.(Sanchit Khanna/ Hindustan Times)</figcaption><p>Delhi BJP MLA Mohan Singh Bisht has criticized the party's decision to field former AAP leader Kapil Mishra in the upcoming assembly elections, calling it a "big mistake". Bisht, who won the Karawal Nagar seat in 2020, stated that the party seems to believe they can win regardless of the candidate chosen.</p><ul><li>Bisht stated that the BJP's decision to field Kapil Mishra is a major error.</li><li>He emphasized that only time will reveal the consequences of this decision across various constituencies.</li><li>Bisht announced he would only file his nomination from the Karawal Nagar seat.</li><li>He expressed discontent over the party rewarding individuals who indulge in flattery.</li><li>Protests erupted among BJP members regarding ticket distribution for the assembly polls.</li></ul><blockquote>“The BJP thinks they will field anyone and he will win. This is a big mistake.” - Mohan Singh Bisht</blockquote><p>This event highlights the internal discontent within the BJP and raises questions about the strategic decisions leading up to the elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-bjp-mlas-big-mistake-warning-over-poll-ticket-to-kapil-mishra-in-karawal-nagar-101736688723145.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-bjp-mlas-big-mistake-warning-over-poll-ticket-to-kapil-mishra-in-karawal-nagar-101736688723145.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:13:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliamentary panel reviews price spike of medicines | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliamentary panel reviews price spike of medicines</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 7 January | <strong>Source:</strong> Today News</p>
<p>The Parliamentary Standing Committee on Chemicals and Fertilizers met to discuss the rising prices of essential medicines, with a goal to potentially lower the cost of life-saving drugs.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The meeting was attended by officials from the Department of Pharmaceuticals (DoP).</li>
  <li>The primary focus was on essential medicines and their pricing strategies.</li>
  <li>The committee aims to address issues concerning price spikes in the pharmaceutical sector.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This move may lead to a lowering of prices of life-saving medicines.”</blockquote>
<p>In summary, the review of medicine prices by the parliamentary panel highlights a proactive approach towards ensuring affordable access to essential healthcare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/india/parliamentary-panel-reviews-price-spike-of-medicines-11736676507675.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/india/parliamentary-panel-reviews-price-spike-of-medicines-11736676507675.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:46:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telugu actor Rana Daggubati, family members booked over Deccan Kitchen Hotel demolition: Report - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxPaVJyVTNicGk1bXRUY3h1XzdJWXZyei1PVHJSMm1rWTRxRjlBN0ZvV3dSUFpmUGFtZW1YNHFndEoxMVlFRjB1V2kybU5wUkJWQVZaV2t5OXJGNWNnZ3BmU1pDb0hNbmxFV3V0eTR5S2ZZQlppVkxhYmJoNTBvRTN2Zk1OMUk1bi1Qdy13VHVFT2tZQXQwMzZ0TE94bmNnN3hnZkRTczFOMUtBeGZVbVdtSkpIdjBTSFlWYmVwZ0NzRjBOdXM1ekpLTGhuTGxCdzh4WnAwbHBsZE16Sl9hcDY0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxPaVJyVTNicGk1bXRUY3h1XzdJWXZyei1PVHJSMm1rWTRxRjlBN0ZvV3dSUFpmUGFtZW1YNHFndEoxMVlFRjB1V2kybU5wUkJWQVZaV2t5OXJGNWNnZ3BmU1pDb0hNbmxFV3V0eTR5S2ZZQlppVkxhYmJoNTBvRTN2Zk1OMUk1bi1Qdy13VHVFT2tZQXQwMzZ0TE94bmNnN3hnZkRTczFOMUtBeGZVbVdtSkpIdjBTSFlWYmVwZ0NzRjBOdXM1ekpLTGhuTGxCdzh4WnAwbHBsZE16Sl9hcDY0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:45:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California man dies from an unusual lung cancer spread from another person - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Man Dies from Rare Lung Cancer Transmitted Through Organ Donation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117176600,imgsize-28188,width-400,resizemode-4/117176600.jpg" alt="California man dies from an unusual lung cancer spread from another person" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>California man dies from an unusual lung cancer spread from another person</figcaption><p>A 41-year-old man from California tragically died after developing metastatic pulmonary adenocarcinoma, a type of lung cancer, due to organ donation from a deceased donor who had undetected cancer.</p><ul><li>The patient had a history of chronic liver disease and underwent a liver transplant in 2001.</li><li>The original organ donor had a metastatic pulmonary adenocarcinoma that was not detected during pre-transplant screening.</li><li>Following the transplant, the patient was found to have developed the same type of lung cancer seven years later.</li><li>Despite a successful second transplant and initial recovery, the cancer progressed rapidly, leading to the patient’s death within 24 hours after hospitalization.</li></ul><blockquote>“Clearly, tumor cells had escaped the confines of the transplanted liver within one week after transplantation,” the doctors noted.</blockquote><p>This case highlights the rare occurrence of donor-to-recipient cancer transmission and underscores the need for thorough screening of organ donors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/california-man-dies-from-an-unusual-lung-cancer-spread-from-another-person/articleshow/117176600.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/california-man-dies-from-an-unusual-lung-cancer-spread-from-another-person/articleshow/117176600.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The OnePlus Open 2 tipped to be the thinnest foldable yet – with a new titanium build - TechRadar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The OnePlus Open 2 tipped to be the thinnest foldable yet – with a new titanium build</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> TechRadar</p><figure><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Awh6TceqdLmtNca2E89mem-320-80.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3"><figcaption>The Honor Magic V3 is currently the thinnest foldable (Image credit: Future)</figcaption></figure><p>The OnePlus Open 2 is anticipated to launch soon, promising to be the thinnest foldable phone to date with an enhanced titanium build.</p><ul><li>Expected release imminent.</li><li>Rumored to feature a tougher, lighter and thinner design.</li><li>Honor Magic V3 is currently the thinnest foldable at 9.2 mm thickness.</li><li>Predicted specifications include a triple-lens camera, Snapdragon 8 Extreme Edition, 6,000 mAh battery, and wireless charging.</li></ul><blockquote>The OnePlus Open 2 is touted as having a 'new industrial design, focusing on durability.'</blockquote><p>This new foldable is generating excitement, especially as it builds on the popularity of the first OnePlus Open launched in October 2023.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techradar.com/phones/oneplus-phones/the-oneplus-open-2-tipped-to-be-the-thinnest-foldable-yet-with-a-new-titanium-build</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techradar.com/phones/oneplus-phones/the-oneplus-open-2-tipped-to-be-the-thinnest-foldable-yet-with-a-new-titanium-build</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ajith Kumar’s team claims 3rd place at Dubai Autodrome 24-Hour Racing Event - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ajith Kumar’s Team Finishes 3rd at Dubai 24-Hour Racing Event</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Sunday, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Tamil superstar Ajith Kumar's racing team achieved an impressive third-place finish in the Dubai 24H 2025 race, an annual endurance challenge at the Dubai Autodrome.</p><ul><li>The event features high-performance GT and touring cars in a challenging 24-hour race format.</li><li>Ajith Kumar Racing, launched in September last year, saw participation from teammates Mathieu Detry, Fabian Duffieux, and Cameron McLeod.</li><li>The victory was celebrated with videos shared on social media showing Ajith with the Indian flag at the awards ceremony.</li><li>Actor R Madhavan praised Ajith on social media, expressing pride in his accomplishment.</li><li>Despite a recent crash during practice, Ajith escaped unharmed.</li></ul><blockquote>“Here We Go!! #AjithkumarRacing secured 3rd Place in #24HDUBAI #Dubai24HSeries Proud Moment for Ak & Team,” - Official fan club post.</blockquote><p>The achievement marks a significant milestone for Ajith Kumar as a racer and highlights his growing presence in the motorsport scene.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/ajith-kumars-team-claims-3rd-place-at-dubai-autodrome-24-hour-racing-event-11736690607015.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/ajith-kumars-team-claims-3rd-place-at-dubai-autodrome-24-hour-racing-event-11736690607015.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:15:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On L&T Chief's 90-Hour Workweek Call, Adar Poonawalla Says 'Even My Wife...' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Adar Poonawalla Responds to L&T Chief's 90-Hour Workweek Suggestion</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Adar Poonawalla agreed with Anand Mahindra, and said that his wife (Natasha Poonawalla) loves staring at him on Sundays." /><figcaption>Adar Poonawalla agreed with Anand Mahindra, and said that his wife (Natasha Poonawalla) loves staring at him on Sundays.</figcaption><p>Adar Poonawalla, CEO of Serum Institute of India, supports work-life balance in response to calls for a 90-hour workweek made by L&T Chairman SN Subrahmanyan.</p><ul><li>Poonawalla emphasizes the importance of work-life balance.</li><li>His comments followed Subrahmanyan's controversial statement suggesting employees work longer hours.</li><li>Industry reactions included support for non-traditional working hours and critiques of the work culture.</li><li>Poonawalla sarcastically remarked about how his wife enjoys spending time with him on Sundays.</li></ul><blockquote>“Even my wife loves staring at me on Sundays.” - Adar Poonawalla</blockquote><p>The growing discourse around work-life balance highlights differing perspectives in corporate culture, especially among influential leaders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/on-lt-chiefs-90-hour-workweek-call-adar-poonawalla-says-even-my-wife-9186136.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/on-lt-chiefs-90-hour-workweek-call-adar-poonawalla-says-even-my-wife-9186136.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:07:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCLT Hearing Hack: A Wake-Up Call to Bolster Courts' Cybersecurity | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NCLT Hearing Hack: A Wake-Up Call to Bolster Courts' Cybersecurity</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Today News</p><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/subscription/onepagecheckout/lm/staging/extensivepaywall/computer.png" alt="NCLT Hearing Hack"/><figcaption>Image depicting cybersecurity concerns in courts.</figcaption><p>The National Company Law Tribunal (NCLT) in Mumbai has temporarily suspended virtual hearings, requiring lawyers to appear physically after its virtual hearing system was hacked on 12 and 17 December.</p><ul><li>Unidentified hackers disrupted proceedings by broadcasting pornographic content.</li><li>Legal and cyber law experts warn about the vulnerability of Indian courts to such cyberattacks.</li><li>There is a growing consensus on the need to strengthen digital infrastructure to ensure accessible justice.</li></ul><blockquote>"This incident highlights the critical need for enhanced cybersecurity measures in our legal system." - Cyber Law Expert</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the recent hack of the NCLT's virtual hearing system serves as a significant reminder of the vulnerabilities present in digital court systems and the urgent need for improved cybersecurity measures to protect the integrity of judicial proceedings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/india/nclt-hearing-hack-a-wake-up-call-to-bolster-courts-cybersecurity-11736666586781.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/india/nclt-hearing-hack-a-wake-up-call-to-bolster-courts-cybersecurity-11736666586781.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:01:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh summons Indian High Commissioner over rising border tensions - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh Summons Indian Envoy Over Border Tensions</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Pranay-Verma.jpg?w=640" alt="Pranay Verma" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>While no official statement was issued by the interim government regarding the discussions, officials confirmed that Pranay Verma (left) has been summoned. (Photo: X/ MoFA Bangladesh)</figcaption><p>Bangladesh faced off with India Sunday over tensions at the border as the neighbouring country’s foreign ministry summoned High Commissioner Pranay Verma to express “deep concern” over “recent activities of the Border Security Force (BSF)”.</p><p>This came hours after Dhaka alleged that India was attempting to construct fences at five locations along the Indo-Bangla border, violating a bilateral agreement.</p><p>After meeting Bangladesh Foreign Secretary Jashim Uddin, the Indian High Commissioner said: “I just met Foreign Secretary to discuss India’s commitment to ensuring a crime-free border, effectively addressing challenges of smuggling, movement of criminals and trafficking.” “We have an understanding with regard to fencing the border for security. BSF and BGB (Border Guard Bangladesh) have been in communication in this regard. We expect that understandings will be implemented and there will be a cooperative approach to combating crime,” Verma said in Dhaka.</p><p>Earlier in the day, Bangladesh Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd.) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said that India had halted the construction of barbed wire fencing along the border after strong opposition from the BGB and local residents.</p><p>According to the Bangladesh Foreign Ministry, Jashim Uddin told the Indian envoy that the “unauthorized attempt” to construct fences and related operational actions by BSF have caused tensions along the border.</p><p>“He emphasised that the construction of barbed wire fences without proper authorization undermines the spirit of cooperation and friendly relations between the two neighboring countries. He hoped that the upcoming BGB-BSF DG Level Talks would be able to discuss the matter at length,” it said in a statement.</p><p>“Referring to the recent killing of a Bangladesh citizen at Sunamganj by BSF, Foreign Secretary… strongly resented these acts of killing and called for urgent action by the Indian authorities to stop recurrence of such incidents and conduct enquiries into all these border killings and take actions against those responsible,” it said.</p><p>He said Bangladesh believes such issues should be resolved through dialogue.</p><p>This article went live on January 12, 2025, at 6:06 PM.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-indian-high-commissioner-border-tensions-9774904/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-indian-high-commissioner-border-tensions-9774904/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More children test positive for mumps in Alappuzha - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>More children test positive for mumps in Alappuzha</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Local Health Report</p><p>The Alappuzha district is currently experiencing a rise in mumps infections among school students, prompting health officials to take action.</p><ul><li>At least five students at Eramalloor and four at Punnapra have tested positive.</li><li>The total infections at Eramalloor school have risen to 28, including a previous outbreak affecting 23 students.</li><li>Schools in the area have been closed for 21 days due to the outbreak.</li><li>Surveillance and preventive measures have been intensified by health department officials.</li><li>Mumps is primarily a disease in children but can also affect adolescents and adults, causing swelling of the salivary glands.</li></ul><blockquote>Mumps is a contagious disease caused by a virus that primarily affects children but could also infect adolescents and adults.</blockquote><p>This outbreak of mumps highlights the importance of vaccination and public health measures to control infectious diseases among school-aged children.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/more-children-test-positive-for-mumps-in-alappuzha/article69091922.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/more-children-test-positive-for-mumps-in-alappuzha/article69091922.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals: OnePlus 13 launches, Poco X7 and X7 Pro arrive in Europe as well - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 Launches Globally Alongside Poco X7 and X7 Pro in Europe</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> GSM Arena</p><div><img src="https://fdn2.gsmarena.com/vv/bigpic/oneplus-13.jpg" alt="OnePlus 13" width="75" height="100"><figcaption>OnePlus 13</figcaption></div><p>The OnePlus 13 has officially launched with a pricing strategy aimed to attract previous OnePlus 12 buyers, while the Poco X7 series has also been introduced in the UK, featuring two models distinguished by performance and battery specifications.</p><ul><li>The OnePlus 13 comes with a €100 discount for the 16/512GB model, aligning its price with last year's OnePlus 12.</li><li>The Poco X7 and X7 Pro both feature 6.67” 120Hz OLED displays, with significant differences in battery capacity and performance chipsets.</li><li>The Poco X7 Pro is equipped with the Dimensity 8400 Ultra, while the standard X7 offers the Dimensity 7300 Ultra.</li><li>Batteries range from 5,110mAh in the standard model to 6,000mAh in the Pro, with HyperCharge support for fast charging.</li><li>Both models feature similar camera setups, though the recording capabilities differ due to chipset variations.</li></ul><blockquote>“We may get a commission from qualifying sales.”</blockquote><p>This new launch strategy by OnePlus and Xiaomi reflects their approach to enhancing market penetration in Europe by offering competitive pricing and technologically advanced features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gsmarena.com/deals_oneplus_13_launches_poco_x7_and_x7_pro_arrive_in_europe_as_well-news-66051.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gsmarena.com/deals_oneplus_13_launches_poco_x7_and_x7_pro_arrive_in_europe_as_well-news-66051.php</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:41:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ajith Kumar kisses wife Shalini; thanks her for ‘letting him race’ at 24H Dubai 2025. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ajith Kumar Celebrates Racing Wins and Thanks Wife Shalini at 24H Dubai 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Ajith_Kumar_Shalini_kissing_1736687337843_1736687363590.jpg" alt="Ajith Kumar kissed wife Shalini after scoring 2 wins at the 24H Dubai 2025." title="Ajith Kumar kissed wife Shalini after scoring 2 wins at the 24H Dubai 2025."><figcaption>Ajith Kumar kissed wife Shalini after scoring 2 wins at the 24H Dubai 2025.</figcaption><p>Ajith Kumar returned to racing in the 24H Dubai 2025 endurance race, achieving significant wins and celebrating with his family, who supported him throughout the event.</p><ul><li>Ajith Kumar is the owner of his racing team, Ajith Kumar Racing.</li><li>He achieved two wins, placing 3rd in the 991 category and winning the Spirit of the Race in the GT4 category.</li><li>He thanked his wife, Shalini, during the celebration, which resonated well with the audience.</li><li>Social media has buzzed with congratulatory messages and videos highlighting his successful return to racing.</li></ul><blockquote>“And Shalu, thank you for letting me race.”</blockquote><p>The event showcased Ajith's determination and the support of his family, marking a successful comeback after a challenging past accident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/tamil-cinema/ajith-kumar-kisses-wife-shalini-thanks-her-for-letting-him-race-at-24h-dubai-2025-watch-101736687096895.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/tamil-cinema/ajith-kumar-kisses-wife-shalini-thanks-her-for-letting-him-race-at-24h-dubai-2025-watch-101736687096895.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:33:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates: In trial attempt at docking, SpaDeX satellites successfully come 3 meters to each other, says ISRO - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> April 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2023/04/SpaDex_d73f5d.jpg?w=640" alt="ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates: SpaDeX satellites hold position at 15m. (@isro/X)</figcaption>
<p>The Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) successfully brought its SpaDeX satellites, Chaser and Target, within 3 meters of each other as part of a trial for a future docking experiment.</p>
<ul>
<li>The docking mission aims to showcase in-space docking technologies.</li>
<li>If successful, India will join the US, Russia, and China as a nation capable of complex docking operations.</li>
<li>This mission is key for future Indian space missions, including lunar sample collection and establishing a space station by 2035.</li>
<li>ISRO emphasizes caution in the docking process due to its complexity and its status as a technology demonstration mission.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Getting it right is more important than getting it done on schedule.” - ISRO</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the successful close approach of the SpaDeX satellites marks a significant step in India's ambitious space exploration goals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/science/isro-spadex-docking-mission-live-updates-9773511/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/science/isro-spadex-docking-mission-live-updates-9773511/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:12:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GRAP 3 revoked in Delhi-NCR after dip in air pollution levels - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi-NCR Revokes GRAP Stage 3 After Air Quality Improvement</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/vcqd07/article69092260.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241230168L.jpg" alt="The restrictions under the anti-pollution Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) in Delhi-NCR ended as the CAQM revoked stage 3 of the GRAP with an improvement in air quality, on January 12, 2025" title="The restrictions under the anti-pollution Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) in Delhi-NCR ended as the CAQM revoked stage 3 of the GRAP with an improvement in air quality, on January 12, 2025"><figcaption>Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption></p><p>The restrictions under the anti-pollution Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) in Delhi-NCR ended as the CAQM revoked stage 3 of the GRAP with an improvement in air quality.</p><ul><li>CAQM lifted the ban on construction, demolition activities, and the use of certain vehicles.</li><li>The revocation followed rain in the area which resulted in a significant improvement in the Air Quality Index (AQI).</li><li>Stage-I and Stage-II restrictions will remain in place.</li></ul><blockquote>The Commission stated that the lifting of restrictions was due to a western disturbance that occurred on January 11-12, leading to improved air quality.</blockquote><p>The revocation of Stage 3 is a significant step towards restoring normalcy in Delhi-NCR as the air quality improves, although earlier restrictions will continue to be enforced.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/grap-3-revoked-in-delhi-ncr-after-dip-in-air-pollution-levels/article69092266.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/grap-3-revoked-in-delhi-ncr-after-dip-in-air-pollution-levels/article69092266.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Find New Galaxy Forming At Tip Of Tidal Tail Stretching 1.27 Million Light-Years - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/scientists-find-new-galaxy-forming-at-tip-of-tidal-tail-str-hing-1-27-million-light-years-aa-9185533.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/scientists-find-new-galaxy-forming-at-tip-of-tidal-tail-str-hing-1-27-million-light-years-aa-9185533.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:02:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Air India plans more premium seats, eyes higher connecting traffic to tap 'huge growth opportunities' - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQOWx1X1NmOG1MWjdxTlV0ZHVOa0xPNktDNVZ1ZEJwMm4zVURYR0x4ZlhNMG15TEp3RVJqckZOVWgxd3FVM1hFemFEYm5XZzFDaHRwUjh4cjktSmVnZFl1ZVN0RHlnbTNINi1wRV9nUV9OX2w2VjBydGdBUDF0ZTZXLU42TWdfU09SU3BpUWdMMmZnOFVwZVM5Uzh5dkg1VXg4UnpNeU1aNmN4TnZNeUt6dzByaTJhV2NtMXRPZHI3cm5fMTIzbnFienlQb1VHVEhNaENnbWRKLU9nd1VQbHp3TE94aFNZT2RoQk5mbjZJajdhVUN2cDRQRNIB_gFBVV95cUxOWHNCZi1DcXhSTE1GUnlhb3dTQU9Lel9ZaHcwMlBSWW5wU3NVLWFRdTZNSlhYYXUyUmpib2VQREc3dTIzVFRMZHdZd1NoUGV3NktpTlFYb091dEF0V0YwX0ZScUctSHRBc0dIbFo3UWx0NGhJamdEVWZPSngwZEpFb1lZV2FEZEdDWndVdGowUFNxQ3FDNFV6RUpINGYtM3o3bjd3X09nek5BVElJbC1qdHdJS3loZUx0OG5Oa25McDdJM3YwZk5sb2JxWnVHSmtfX1d4RGhXQjBQZFZ1Y1NPQnhMbk9rejZuQldEaGtmeWZlTWktcFd5TXBIYnhIdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQOWx1X1NmOG1MWjdxTlV0ZHVOa0xPNktDNVZ1ZEJwMm4zVURYR0x4ZlhNMG15TEp3RVJqckZOVWgxd3FVM1hFemFEYm5XZzFDaHRwUjh4cjktSmVnZFl1ZVN0RHlnbTNINi1wRV9nUV9OX2w2VjBydGdBUDF0ZTZXLU42TWdfU09SU3BpUWdMMmZnOFVwZVM5Uzh5dkg1VXg4UnpNeU1aNmN4TnZNeUt6dzByaTJhV2NtMXRPZHI3cm5fMTIzbnFienlQb1VHVEhNaENnbWRKLU9nd1VQbHp3TE94aFNZT2RoQk5mbjZJajdhVUN2cDRQRNIB_gFBVV95cUxOWHNCZi1DcXhSTE1GUnlhb3dTQU9Lel9ZaHcwMlBSWW5wU3NVLWFRdTZNSlhYYXUyUmpib2VQREc3dTIzVFRMZHdZd1NoUGV3NktpTlFYb091dEF0V0YwX0ZScUctSHRBc0dIbFo3UWx0NGhJamdEVWZPSngwZEpFb1lZV2FEZEdDWndVdGowUFNxQ3FDNFV6RUpINGYtM3o3bjd3X09nek5BVElJbC1qdHdJS3loZUx0OG5Oa25McDdJM3YwZk5sb2JxWnVHSmtfX1d4RGhXQjBQZFZ1Y1NPQnhMbk9rejZuQldEaGtmeWZlTWktcFd5TXBIYnhIdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:50:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Air India to offer first class seats in A350-1000 planes - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Air India Introduces First Class Seats on A350-1000 Aircraft</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><p>Air India is set to include first class seating in its A350-1000 aircraft, aiming to capture a larger share of the global aviation market amidst a competitive landscape.</p><ul><li>Air India's Chief Commercial Officer, Nipun Aggarwal, emphasized the ongoing relevance and demand for first class seating.</li><li>The fleet currently consists of 202 planes, including 67 wide body aircraft.</li><li>The introduction of first class seating is seen as essential for competing with top airlines.</li><li>These new A350-1000 planes will be integrated into Air India's fleet over the coming years.</li></ul><blockquote>“To compete with the best airlines you need to have first class, it is an aspirational product...” - Nipun Aggarwal</blockquote><p>In addition to enhancing customer experience, the airline is also focusing on improving its loyalty program and corporate travel services as part of its strategic overhaul.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/transportation/airlines-/-aviation/air-india-to-offer-first-class-seats-in-a350-1000-planes/articleshow/117174762.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/transportation/airlines-/-aviation/air-india-to-offer-first-class-seats-in-a350-1000-planes/articleshow/117174762.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:48:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ice Baths for Stress: New research says cold water could sharpen your mind and improve sleep - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ice Baths for Stress: New research says cold water could sharpen your mind and improve sleep</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117174624,imgsize-1894125,width-400,resizemode-4/117174624.jpg" alt="Ice Baths for Stress" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Ice Baths for Stress: New research says cold water could sharpen your mind and improve sleep</figcaption><p>Recent research from the University of Central Lancashire reveals that regular cold-water immersion can enhance cognitive performance and improve sleep quality.</p><ul><li>Study involved 13 healthy participants aged 21, immersing in 10°C water for 10 minutes, three times a week.</li><li>Participants showed improved processing speed and better sleep by the third week.</li><li>Cold exposure may improve blood flow and promote relaxation.</li><li>Lead researcher Robert Allan emphasized that cold-water immersion can aid sleep, particularly during periods of sleep disturbances.</li></ul><blockquote>“Cold-water immersion helps with sleep, particularly during periods of pronounced sleep disturbances.” – Robert Allan</blockquote><p>Cold water therapy can enhance focus and productivity, and reduce symptoms of stress and anxiety by lowering inflammation and regulating hormones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/ice-baths-for-stress-new-research-says-cold-water-could-sharpen-your-mind-and-improve-sleep/articleshow/117174565.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/ice-baths-for-stress-new-research-says-cold-water-could-sharpen-your-mind-and-improve-sleep/articleshow/117174565.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fibre may help protect your gut from overgrowth of harmful bugs: Study - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fibre May Protect Gut Health Against Harmful Bacteria: New Study</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> (Date not provided), <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/fibre-2.jpg" alt="Future research will integrate additional tools, such as metabolomics (studying chemicals microbes produce) and transcriptomics (studying how genes are activated), to create a clearer picture of how the gut ecosystem works for our health benefit." />
<figcaption>Image Credit: Freepik</figcaption>
<p>This new study reveals how a healthy gut environment, influenced by diet, can inhibit harmful bacteria such as Enterobacteriaceae, offering insights into gut health management.</p>
<ul>
<li>The study analyzed over 12,000 stool samples globally, indicating a strong link between gut microbiome composition and the presence of harmful bacteria.</li>
<li>Fatty acids produced by bacteria like Faecalibacterium are crucial in preventing the overgrowth of harmful microbes.</li>
<li>Co-colonisers of harmful bacteria demonstrate adaptability, suggesting that gut conditions play a significant role in bacterial survival.</li>
<li>Findings may lead to alternative methods for preventing infections without antibiotics by promoting beneficial bacteria instead.</li>
<li>The research highlights the need for further studies on global microbiome diversity and its implications for health.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Instead of killing harmful bacteria directly, we could boost the co-excluders or create diets that support their growth.”</blockquote>
<p>This research underscores the importance of dietary fibres in maintaining gut health and could pave the way for new treatments targeting harmful bacteria.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/fibre-may-help-protect-your-gut-from-overgrowth-of-harmful-bugs-study-9774693/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/fibre-may-help-protect-your-gut-from-overgrowth-of-harmful-bugs-study-9774693/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:30:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trade Setup For Jan. 13: Nifty 50 At 23,600 – Key Level To Watch - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trade Setup For Jan. 13: Nifty 50 At 23,600 – Key Level To Watch</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg Quint</p><img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2025-01-10%2F9wh1o2t8%2Fbank.jpg?w=1200" alt="Trade Setup For Jan. 13: Nifty 50 At 23,600 – Key Level To Watch"><figcaption>Market overview image</figcaption><p>The NSE Nifty 50 index is approaching a crucial support level of 23,600, according to experts. The market's stability will depend on whether it stays above this level or falls below 23,350.</p><ul><li>Nifty likely to continue a pullback to 23,800 if it holds above 23,600.</li><li>Falling below 23,350 could accelerate selling pressure, potentially slipping to 23,250-23,100.</li><li>Market is currently experiencing bearish signals, but some relief rallies may occur.</li><li>Bank Nifty's significant moving average is around 49,900, acting as a strong resistance level.</li><li>Foreign investors sold stocks worth approximately Rs 2,254.68 crore on Friday.</li></ul><blockquote>“The overall structure of the market is bearish but considering a sharp decline, some relief rally can be expected.” - Aditya Gaggar, director of Progressive Shares</blockquote><p>This market analysis suggests traders should be vigilant about the crucial levels and make informed decisions based on market fluctuations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/trade-setup-for-jan-13-nifty-50-at-23600-key-level-to-watch</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/markets/trade-setup-for-jan-13-nifty-50-at-23600-key-level-to-watch</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘People in Maharashtra showed Sharad Pawar, Uddhav Thackeray their place’: Amit Shah’s dig over poll results - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amit Shah Criticizes Sharad Pawar and Uddhav Thackeray After Maharashtra Poll Results</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Amit_Shah_1736682210598_1736682210926.jpg" alt="Union Home Minister Amit Shah.(PTI)" title="Union Home Minister Amit Shah.(PTI)"><figcaption>Union Home Minister Amit Shah.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Union Home Minister Amit Shah took a dig at Sharad Pawar and Uddhav Thackeray, stating that the recent Maharashtra assembly election results clearly showed them their place in the political landscape.</p><ul><li>Shah emphasized that the results rejected the politics of dynasty and betrayal.</li><li>The BJP-led Mahayuti alliance secured a historic 233 seats in the assembly elections.</li><li>The Congress-led MVA won only 16 seats, while Thackeray's Shiv Sena secured 20 and Pawar’s NCP just 10.</li></ul><blockquote>“People in Maharashtra showed that Eknath Shinde's Shiv Sena is Balasaheb's Shiv Sena.”</blockquote><p>Shah expressed confidence in winning upcoming elections and remarked that the opposition's confidence has been shaken by the defeat in Maharashtra.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/people-in-maharashtra-showed-sharad-pawar-uddhav-thackeray-their-place-amit-shah-s-dig-over-poll-results-101736681036917.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/people-in-maharashtra-showed-sharad-pawar-uddhav-thackeray-their-place-amit-shah-s-dig-over-poll-results-101736681036917.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:29:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases in northern China declining, says country's health official - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV cases in northern China declining, says country's health official</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p> <figure> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/HMPV_1736679171766_1736679172042.jpg" alt="Wang Liping, second left, a researcher for the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention speaks during a press briefing in Beijing, Sunday, Jan. 12, 2025.(AP)" title="Wang Liping, second left, a researcher for the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention speaks during a press briefing in Beijing, Sunday, Jan. 12, 2025.(AP)"> <figcaption>Wang Liping, second left, a researcher for the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention speaks during a press briefing in Beijing, Sunday, Jan. 12, 2025.(AP)</figcaption> </figure> <p>The Chinese health authorities have reported a decline in human metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases, alleviating concerns amid a global focus on respiratory illnesses.</p> <ul> <li>HMPV is a frequent respiratory virus causing mild symptoms similar to a cold.</li> <li>China stated recent increases in case detection were due to improved detection methods, not a new surge of the virus.</li> <li>Research indicates that many adults have immunity, but the virus is more severe in infants or immunocompromised individuals.</li> <li>Reports of hospitals being overwhelmed have not been verified; WHO noted no unusual outbreaks.</li> <li>No vaccines or specific treatments are available for HMPV.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“At present, the rate of positive cases in human metapneumovirus detection is fluctuating, and the rate of positive cases in northern provinces is declining,” - Wang Liping.</blockquote> <p>Overall, the situation appears to be under control, with no significant shortages of medical resources reported.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/hmpv-cases-in-northern-china-declining-says-countrys-health-official-101736677964239.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/hmpv-cases-in-northern-china-declining-says-countrys-health-official-101736677964239.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:28:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi pollution: GRAP 3 revoked after air quality improves due to rainfall - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Pollution: Stage-I and Stage-II Measures, However, Will Remain in Effect</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 07:20 PM IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Delhi_rain_1736684414274_1736684414603.jpg" alt="New Delhi, Jan 11 (ANI): A man passes on a bicycle at the Kartavya Path as drizzle lashes, in New Delhi on Saturday. (ANI Photo/Ishant)(Ishant )" title="New Delhi, Jan 11 (ANI): A man passes on a bicycle at the Kartavya Path as drizzle lashes, in New Delhi on Saturday. (ANI Photo/Ishant)(Ishant )"><figcaption>New Delhi, Jan 11 (ANI): A man passes on a bicycle at the Kartavya Path as drizzle lashes, in New Delhi on Saturday. (ANI Photo/Ishant)(Ishant )</figcaption></figure><p>The Commission of Air Quality Management (CAQM) revoked the Stage III restrictions under the anti-pollution Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) in Delhi-NCR after the AQI improved due to rainfall.</p><ul><li>The revocation was due to significant improvement in AQI, which dropped from 'very poor' to 'poor' following rain.</li><li>Stage-I and Stage-II measures will remain in effect, including restrictions on private construction.</li><li>The average AQI in Delhi was recorded at 284 post-rain on Sunday.</li></ul><blockquote>“The rain was caused by a western disturbance affecting northwest India,” said Mahesh Palawat, vice president at Skymet.</blockquote><p>The rain has led to a temporary improvement in air quality, providing relief to residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-pollution-grap-3-revoked-after-air-quality-improves-due-to-rainfall-101736684324277.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-pollution-grap-3-revoked-after-air-quality-improves-due-to-rainfall-101736684324277.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:22:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 vitamins and minerals that are lost in cooking (and how to retain them) - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxNSnFyUVQyeWFPRmxaSjNzWGNEeEo0LXZPZkxiTFFVRVVsUkQwTTYyYXBINGlxNlkzQVUxTkNfY2xQX2NyWEdZQ1RqMHgtT3BvT01ERzNiY0Y0OFBvNG13M0Nwa1JOV1I4VGNXa0JyanRheTlxNGZlaFFSQUVWZ3JISWpZaTVXSHNQcjdMQmhfVk9Ecmk2VkZBMWsxbHJQRF85UjFybkNka29uWlAwS2VRdTRWbk41NG9lQWNLMlZEckJjaU9TSTdONW81NXdfU3NPMm1kVnJkZ1Rhd3dBYmdYWDlRRTBGc0RMT19uZUVjN1NIckI3SEhxc2RqbUdCaTTSAf8BQVVfeXFMTUpxclFUMnlhT0ZsWkozc1hjRHhKNC12T2ZMYkxRVUVVbFJEME02MmFwSDRpcTZZM0FVMU5DX2NsUF9jclhHWUNUajB4LU9wb09NREczYmNGNDhQbzRtdzNDcGtSTldSOFRjV2tCcmp0YXk5cTRmZWhRUkFFVmdySElqWWk1V0hzUHI3TEJoX1ZPRHJpNlZGQTFrMWxyUERfOVIxcm5DZGtvblpQMEtlUXU0Vm5ONTRvZUFjSzJWRHJCY2lPU0k3TjVvNTV3X1NzTzJtZFZyZGdUYXd3QWJnWFg5UUUwRnNETE9fbmVFYzdTSHJCN0hIcXNkam1HQmk0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxNSnFyUVQyeWFPRmxaSjNzWGNEeEo0LXZPZkxiTFFVRVVsUkQwTTYyYXBINGlxNlkzQVUxTkNfY2xQX2NyWEdZQ1RqMHgtT3BvT01ERzNiY0Y0OFBvNG13M0Nwa1JOV1I4VGNXa0JyanRheTlxNGZlaFFSQUVWZ3JISWpZaTVXSHNQcjdMQmhfVk9Ecmk2VkZBMWsxbHJQRF85UjFybkNka29uWlAwS2VRdTRWbk41NG9lQWNLMlZEckJjaU9TSTdONW81NXdfU3NPMm1kVnJkZ1Rhd3dBYmdYWDlRRTBGc0RMT19uZUVjN1NIckI3SEhxc2RqbUdCaTTSAf8BQVVfeXFMTUpxclFUMnlhT0ZsWkozc1hjRHhKNC12T2ZMYkxRVUVVbFJEME02MmFwSDRpcTZZM0FVMU5DX2NsUF9jclhHWUNUajB4LU9wb09NREczYmNGNDhQbzRtdzNDcGtSTldSOFRjV2tCcmp0YXk5cTRmZWhRUkFFVmdySElqWWk1V0hzUHI3TEJoX1ZPRHJpNlZGQTFrMWxyUERfOVIxcm5DZGtvblpQMEtlUXU0Vm5ONTRvZUFjSzJWRHJCY2lPU0k3TjVvNTV3X1NzTzJtZFZyZGdUYXd3QWJnWFg5UUUwRnNETE9fbmVFYzdTSHJCN0hIcXNkam1HQmk0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:22:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Wants To Buy Greenland: Here's What It Could Cost The US - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Wants To Buy Greenland: Here's What It Could Cost The US</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Trump, who takes office on Jan. 20, has refused to rule out using military or economic action to pursue the acquisition of Greenland. (Reuters/NASA)"><figcaption>Trump, who takes office on Jan. 20, has refused to rule out using military or economic action to pursue the acquisition of Greenland. (Reuters/NASA)</figcaption><p>US President-elect Donald Trump has reiterated his ambitions to obtain Greenland, describing it as a crucial element for US national defense, which has sparked protests from leaders in Denmark and Greenland.</p><ul><li>Trump has indicated he may use military or economic measures to pursue the acquisition of Greenland.</li><li>Greenland Prime Minister Mute Egede expressed readiness to engage in discussion with Trump, emphasizing Greenland's aspirations for autonomy.</li><li>Danish officials have shown willingness to enhance cooperation regarding security in Greenland.</li><li>Greenland's value has been estimated between $12.5 billion to $77 billion based on historical purchases and economic assessments.</li><li>Trump's strategic interest centers around mining and defense, particularly due to global competition for rare earth minerals.</li></ul><blockquote>“Greenland is an absolute necessity” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>The event reflects ongoing geopolitical tensions and aspirations around resource acquisition in the Arctic region, showcasing the complex interplay between national interests and international relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-wants-to-buy-greenland-heres-what-it-could-cost-the-us-9186373.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-wants-to-buy-greenland-heres-what-it-could-cost-the-us-9186373.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:17:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>