<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:19:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:19:28 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All about Uganda 'Dinga Dinga' fever outbreak which makes patients 'shake like dancing' - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>All about Uganda 'Dinga Dinga' fever outbreak which makes patients 'shake like dancing'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> March 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="All about Uganda 'Dinga Dinga' fever outbreak which makes patients 'shake like dancing'" loading="lazy"><figcaption>The 'Dinga Dinga' fever outbreak in Uganda, affecting over 300 individuals.</figcaption><p>In Uganda's Bundibugyo district, health authorities are investigating a mysterious disease known locally as 'Dinga Dinga,' which manifests as severe body shaking and fever. This outbreak predominantly affects women and girls, with more than 300 reported cases.</p><ul><li>More than 300 cases of 'Dinga Dinga' fever have been reported, mainly among women and girls.</li><li>The disease is characterized by fever and uncontrollable body shaking that restricts movement.</li><li>Health officials are treating patients with antibiotics, although a confirmed diagnosis is still pending.</li><li>Symptoms include fever, headache, cough, runny nose, and body aches.</li><li>Health experts are investigating possible links to respiratory pathogens like influenza and COVID-19.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was very disturbing. I was taken to the Bundibugyo Hospital for treatment, and thank God, I am now fine.” - Affected Patient</blockquote><p>The situation is under close observation as local health authorities urge residents to avoid relying on unverified herbal treatments and instead seek proper medical care.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/all-about-uganda-dinga-dinga-fever-outbreak-which-makes-patients-shake-like-dancing-19527510.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/all-about-uganda-dinga-dinga-fever-outbreak-which-makes-patients-shake-like-dancing-19527510.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:05:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[European markets slide; Novo Nordisk down 20% after obesity drug results - CNBC]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>European Markets Decline Amid U.S. Political Turmoil; Novo Nordisk Shares Drop 20%</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC</p><div><p>The European markets faced a decline on Friday as investors reacted to recent political instability in the U.S. and monetary policy updates from major economies. Notably, Novo Nordisk experienced a significant stock drop after disappointing trial results for its obesity drug.</p></div><div><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>The Stoxx 600 index fell by 1.7% by early afternoon, with all major sectors in the red.</li><li>Political uncertainty in the U.S. arose from a failed spending bill that could lead to a government shutdown.</li><li>Novo Nordisk's stock dropped over 20% following disappointing trial results for CagriSema.</li><li>Volkswagen shares gained more than 2% amid positive negotiation news with striking workers.</li><li>China held interest rates steady, while the U.S. Fed cut its core interest rate by 25 basis points.</li></ul></div><blockquote>“The pan-European Stoxx 600 index was 1.7% lower by 1:46 p.m. London time, with every sector and all major bourses in negative territory.”</blockquote><p>Despite the difficulties in the markets, there are sectors like Volkswagen showing resilience. The overall sentiment remains cautious as investors navigate through the uncertainties.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/20/european-markets-live-updates-us-government-shutdown-data-and-stocks.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/20/european-markets-live-updates-us-government-shutdown-data-and-stocks.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RBI fines IndusInd Bank for ₹27 lakh over non-compliance | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RBI Fines IndusInd Bank ₹27 Lakh for Non-Compliance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 20, 2024<p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</strong></p><p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has imposed a monetary penalty of ₹27 lakh on IndusInd Bank Ltd. for failing to comply with regulatory norms by opening savings accounts for ineligible entities.</p><ul><li>The monetary penalty amounts to ₹27.30 lakh.</li><li>The RBI's inspection revealed non-compliance with the 'Reserve Bank of India (Interest Rate on Deposits) Directions, 2016.'</li><li>The inspection assessed the bank's financial position as of March 31, 2023.</li><li>The penalty does not affect the validity of any transactions made by the bank with its customers.</li><li>IndusInd Bank reported a 39.5% YoY decline in consolidated net profit for the July-September quarter.</li></ul><blockquote>“RBI found, inter alia, that the charge pertaining to opening of certain savings deposit accounts in the name of ineligible entities was sustained, warranting imposition of monetary penalty,” the statement said.</blockquote><p>This fine underscores the importance of regulatory compliance in the banking sector and aims to ensure that banks operate within prescribed guidelines to protect consumers and maintain a robust financial system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/rbi-fines-indusind-bank-for-rs-27-lakh-over-noncompliance-11734700622899.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/rbi-fines-indusind-bank-for-rs-27-lakh-over-noncompliance-11734700622899.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:21:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA alert! Massive 120-foot asteroid to fly past Earth on Christmas eve - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxNSDF4eWlOOF8wTU56UUFtQ1F6X3pxUnBwT3g5cHJJbjRiSnBwR19vTGlpdHRoRWk2TW5HU2tNcTdoOHI3UDNOZFpBLUg0eFlqMFlHLWtvZEVVMHM5NHdqZ0FDY1VaOGRDQk5RVDJnSm9NZXh0TFRoM3U0eWdMRmdzS0RwRzV2bzE5OTZ6QlVnQUZhS3NDTy1BaVYyYjBrYkpoZVVxZ2MyWTcwclBlXy1uTzhGSlNRS2tQT2dZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxNSDF4eWlOOF8wTU56UUFtQ1F6X3pxUnBwT3g5cHJJbjRiSnBwR19vTGlpdHRoRWk2TW5HU2tNcTdoOHI3UDNOZFpBLUg0eFlqMFlHLWtvZEVVMHM5NHdqZ0FDY1VaOGRDQk5RVDJnSm9NZXh0TFRoM3U0eWdMRmdzS0RwRzV2bzE5OTZ6QlVnQUZhS3NDTy1BaVYyYjBrYkpoZVVxZ2MyWTcwclBlXy1uTzhGSlNRS2tQT2dZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INLD patriarch O P Chautala’s long journey: Five-time CM to 10-year jail and party’s fall - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>O P Chautala: The Rise and Fall of a Political Patriarch</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Friday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<p>Om Prakash Chautala, former Chief Minister of Haryana and INLD patriarch, passed away at the age of 89. His political journey spanned over five decades, marked by significant ups and downs, including a conviction and imprisonment.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Chautala served as Haryana's CM five times.</li>
  <li>He was part of a prominent political family; his father was a Deputy Prime Minister.</li>
  <li>First took office as CM in December 1989 but resigned amidst controversy.</li>
  <li>Convicted in a recruitment scandal in 2013, serving 10 years in prison.</li>
  <li>Post-release, his party, INLD, struggled politically, leading to a split with the formation of JJP.</li>
  <li>INLD’s influence declined significantly, securing only 2 seats in the 2024 Assembly polls.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"He was a dominant figure in Haryana politics for over five decades."</blockquote>
<p>The life of O P Chautala reflects both the rise of a powerful political legacy and the challenges faced by his party in recent years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/inld-patriarch-o-p-chautalas-journey-five-time-cm-to-10-year-jail-9736398/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/inld-patriarch-o-p-chautalas-journey-five-time-cm-to-10-year-jail-9736398/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:21:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Be mindful': India raps Bangladesh government over now-deleted 'annex' post by key aide of Muhammed Yunu - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxOOTRiLUMySHBqMk1sREh1NXZ0djFFbThkZU9WTmEzYU83Qk5UMjlMRVlXY095WDV0UDRvOWVWUUtkU1NiV3U4cDZLSXZCSmJZamtHM2g3dEczSVVFdGxTV0ZNZnRuM3BIbjNNUFY2R2xQSG5CMmFDNVFxVmY4MzQ1dHVpZHFIVjBNaXl5bW5ERzA3TzluYXdEV3gyS2NDTEpreVA2bW1TakFDSU15aTAwdENTTTBBVHlhUWQ5VGpmSExZQm1VQWZLNzRJa0xZZWJVbFpsLTJXNktrdGtXcDZKZk5XeGRiWDNHOExXdWt0TGlxcVZGUTVLZlYzaWVUQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxOOTRiLUMySHBqMk1sREh1NXZ0djFFbThkZU9WTmEzYU83Qk5UMjlMRVlXY095WDV0UDRvOWVWUUtkU1NiV3U4cDZLSXZCSmJZamtHM2g3dEczSVVFdGxTV0ZNZnRuM3BIbjNNUFY2R2xQSG5CMmFDNVFxVmY4MzQ1dHVpZHFIVjBNaXl5bW5ERzA3TzluYXdEV3gyS2NDTEpreVA2bW1TakFDSU15aTAwdENTTTBBVHlhUWQ5VGpmSExZQm1VQWZLNzRJa0xZZWJVbFpsLTJXNktrdGtXcDZKZk5XeGRiWDNHOExXdWt0TGlxcVZGUTVLZlYzaWVUQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telangana HC provides relief to K.T. Rama Rao; no arrest till December 30 in Formula E race case - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telangana HC Provides Relief to K.T. Rama Rao; No Arrest Till December 30 in Formula E Race Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/k20l38/article69009253.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/20241124213L.jpg" alt="Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) working president K.T. Rama Rao" title="Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) working president K.T. Rama Rao"><figcaption>Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) working president K.T. Rama Rao | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The Telangana High Court has granted interim relief to former Minister K.T. Rama Rao, prohibiting his arrest until December 30 regarding a corruption case involving the release of funds for the Formula E race during his party's government.</p><ul><li>The High Court has ordered that the investigation should continue while Mr. Rama Rao cooperates with the authorities.</li><li>The next hearing for the case is scheduled for December 27.</li><li>Mr. Rama Rao has expressed his readiness to face the allegations legally and claims there is no corruption involved.</li></ul><blockquote>Mr. Rama Rao reiterated that the funds were allocated legally and are intended for development in Hyderabad.</blockquote><p>This decision allows K.T. Rama Rao to continue his work without the threat of arrest while the investigation is ongoing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/telangana-hc-provides-relief-to-kt-rama-rao-no-arrest-till-december-30-in-formula-e-race-case/article69009027.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/telangana-hc-provides-relief-to-kt-rama-rao-no-arrest-till-december-30-in-formula-e-race-case/article69009027.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India registers 'strong protest' with Dhaka over remarks by Bangladesh leader - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Protests Against Bangladesh Leader's Controversial Remarks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/PTI11-29-2024-000346B-0_1734695332580_1734695348851.jpg" alt="Randhir Jaiswal, the spokesperson of the Ministry of External Affairs, addresses a press conference.(PTI file photo)"><figcaption>Randhir Jaiswal, the spokesperson of the Ministry of External Affairs, addresses a press conference.(PTI file photo)</figcaption><p>The Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) of India has lodged a strong protest with the Bangladeshi government over remarks made by Mahfuj Alam, a key aide of the interim government of Bangladesh. Officials emphasized the need for responsible public comments from leaders.</p><ul><li>India's MEA expressed concern over controversial statements made by a Bangladeshi government aide.</li><li>Spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal reiterated India's interest in fostering relations with Bangladesh.</li><li>The Bangladeshi aide's Facebook post, which has since been deleted, claimed India should recognize a recent political upheaval in Bangladesh.</li><li>Recent violence against minorities in Bangladesh has raised concerns for India.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have registered our strong protest on this issue with the Bangladesh side. We would like to remind all concerned to be mindful of their public comments.” - Randhir Jaiswal</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the sensitive nature of India-Bangladesh relations and the potential for diplomatic tensions arising from public remarks by officials.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-registers-strong-protest-with-dhaka-over-remarks-by-bangladesh-leader-101734695038682.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-registers-strong-protest-with-dhaka-over-remarks-by-bangladesh-leader-101734695038682.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:50:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kia Syros Could Get An EV Version Soon, Launch Expected In 2026 - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kia Syros Could Get An EV Version Soon, Launch Expected In 2026</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> CarDekho.com</p><img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/67655f7b6bf7a.jpg" alt="Kia Syros EV India Launch Could Happen In 2026"><figcaption>Kia Syros EV India Launch Could Happen In 2026</figcaption><p>The Kia Syros is set to potentially launch its all-electric version in India by 2026, competing with other EVs like Tata Nexon EV and Mahindra XUV400 EV, and expected to offer a driving range of approximately 400 km.</p><ul><li>The Syros EV will likely be based on the reinforced K1 platform.</li><li>Design updates may include EV-specific features like revised bumpers.</li><li>The cabin layout will remain largely unchanged with EV-specific accents.</li><li>Expected pricing starts from Rs 15 lakh (ex-showroom).</li></ul><blockquote>“Although Kia is yet to reveal the battery pack and electric motor specifications for the Syros EV, we expect it to offer a claimed driving range of around 400 km.”</blockquote><p>The Syros EV aims to incorporate the familiar features of its ICE counterpart while introducing elements unique to electric vehicles, marking a significant shift in Kia's offerings in the Indian market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/kia-syros-ev-india-launch-could-happen-in-2026-33700.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/kia-syros-ev-india-launch-could-happen-in-2026-33700.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subjective walking speed is a quick, equipment-free tool for identifying metabolic health risks - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Subjective Walking Speed is a Quick, Equipment-Free Tool for Identifying Metabolic Health Risks</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Scientific Reports</p>
<img src="https://d2jx2rerrg6sh3.cloudfront.net/images/news/ImageForNews_798790_17346937764997245.jpg" alt="Young man running in the park at morning" title="Study: Association between subjective walking speed and metabolic diseases in individuals with obesity: a cross-sectional analysis. Image Credit: Arnav Pratap Singh/Shutterstock.com">
<figcaption>Image Credit: Arnav Pratap Singh/Shutterstock.com</figcaption>
<p>A recent study explores the relationship between self-reported walking speed and metabolic health risks in obese individuals, suggesting that evaluating perceived walking pace can be beneficial in public health.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The research includes over 24,000 adults from health checkups in Japan.</li>
  <li>Participants with a BMI over 25 and waist circumference above defined thresholds were classified as obese.</li>
  <li>45% of participants classified as obese reported faster walking speeds.</li>
  <li>Fast walking speed is associated with reduced risks of diabetes, hypertension, and dyslipidemia among obese individuals.</li>
  <li>Fast walking speed can lower the risk of these conditions by significant percentages, particularly highlighting benefits for metabolic health.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Fast walking speed can reduce the risks of diabetes and dyslipidemia by 30% and 3%, respectively."</blockquote>
<p>The findings underscore walking speed's role as a crucial factor in managing and preventing metabolic diseases in individuals suffering from obesity. Future research should focus on similar longitudinal studies to further validate these results.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20241220/Subjective-walking-speed-is-a-quick-equipment-free-tool-for-identifying-metabolic-health-risks.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/news/20241220/Subjective-walking-speed-is-a-quick-equipment-free-tool-for-identifying-metabolic-health-risks.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moderate drinkers may live longer than teetotalers, claims a study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Moderate drinkers may live longer than teetotalers, claims a study</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>This article discusses a study that suggests moderate drinkers may have a longer lifespan compared to those who abstain from alcohol entirely.</p><ul><li>The study analyzes various health outcomes related to alcohol consumption.</li><li>Moderate drinking is defined as one to two drinks per day.</li><li>Researchers found significant differences in longevity between moderate drinkers and teetotalers.</li></ul><blockquote>"The evidence is accumulating that moderate drinking can be beneficial for health, particularly in terms of longevity."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the study presents compelling evidence that moderate alcohol consumption may have advantages for longevity, though further research is needed to explore the underlying factors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/moderate-drinkers-may-live-longer-than-teetotalers-claims-a-study/articleshow/116499536.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/moderate-drinkers-may-live-longer-than-teetotalers-claims-a-study/articleshow/116499536.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI launches ChatGPT Beta for macOS apps - YourStory]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxNY3YzaDFqdnRUQ3FKemN0RHJGT3RWdHV5VTlJY1cwLURzbEFVZmZoQjdUcUUyMzdNVTlEbTVXTU5jeWV6YldxbktPeFdYNXZqVE1ONnhybk1ndHZXeExKVGRyLTlCVExUVDlFVDVhZ05leVNqeU9uOGdTb3lLcVNZMHY2MDNQNlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxNY3YzaDFqdnRUQ3FKemN0RHJGT3RWdHV5VTlJY1cwLURzbEFVZmZoQjdUcUUyMzdNVTlEbTVXTU5jeWV6YldxbktPeFdYNXZqVE1ONnhybk1ndHZXeExKVGRyLTlCVExUVDlFVDVhZ05leVNqeU9uOGdTb3lLcVNZMHY2MDNQNlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:13:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russian missiles strike Kyiv on the eve of holiday season (Photos) - Kyiv Independent]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://kyivindependent.com/russian-missiles-strike-kyiv-on-the-eve-of-holiday-season/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kyivindependent.com/russian-missiles-strike-kyiv-on-the-eve-of-holiday-season/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:10:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Croatia: 7-year-old killed, 5 injured in knife attack in Zagreb school, attacker detained - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/croatia-7-year-old-killed-5-wounded-in-knife-attack-in-zagreb-school-101734692388931.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/croatia-7-year-old-killed-5-wounded-in-knife-attack-in-zagreb-school-101734692388931.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:04:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shah Rukh & Suhana sing along to Levitating X Woh Ladki Jo at AbRam’s annual day; actor gets emotional on Swades act - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shah Rukh Khan and Suhana Khan’s videos enjoying the former’s songs at AbRam Khan’s annual function are the cutest thing you’ll see today</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Shah_Rukh_Suhana_1734691484482_1734691544620.jpg" alt="Shah Rukh Khan and Suhana Khan at AbRam Khan's annual day function" title="Shah Rukh Khan and Suhana Khan at AbRam Khan's annual day function"><figcaption>Shah Rukh Khan and Suhana Khan at AbRam Khan's annual day function</figcaption><p>Shah Rukh Khan and his daughter Suhana Khan were seen singing along to a popular mashup of his iconic songs during AbRam Khan's annual school function. Their performance has gone viral, capturing the hearts of many fans.</p><ul><li>The mashup of <i>Levitating</i> and <i>Woh Ladki Jo</i> was approved by Dua Lipa during her Indian tour.</li><li>Shah Rukh Khan joined in singing at the Dhirubhai Ambani School's annual function.</li><li>Another emotional moment featured Shah Rukh singing the title track of <i>Swades</i> as students paid tribute to the country.</li><li>Suhana Khan will star alongside Shah Rukh in the upcoming film <i>King</i>.</li></ul><blockquote>“Watching Shah Rukh be himself is always an honour!”</blockquote><p>This emotional display of family and patriotism at a school function resonated deeply with fans, showcasing the strong bond between Shah Rukh and Suhana.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/shah-rukh-suhana-sing-along-to-levitating-x-woh-ladki-jo-at-abram-s-annual-day-actor-gets-emotional-on-swades-act-101734691305518.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/shah-rukh-suhana-sing-along-to-levitating-x-woh-ladki-jo-at-abram-s-annual-day-actor-gets-emotional-on-swades-act-101734691305518.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:59:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Like to throw something different at India': Australia chief selector defends changes in squad before Bo - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgJBVV95cUxPMDRhQjNzVzJrRWRqc1V2ODEwYnQxT2ZjclhDbUpuV0E0bzhWWk14LW5VTU94Tmt5bmFBOTZKZHlZN1QtTkJ5VDJ3aTN0Q3lubExheEVOWjhZX3dpRXhHdmpsQWsydXQxWmttV21KQVZ4VlhVbFdDZHYwdS0wUjhaYkJaSndjamZhd3U0OEhRSmhSMEdHcEFrRjFHbUExLWFRSnhvTGtKcGRCeUdWM2lZdnc2X2ZUdkZrUkxaa1B4dG80M2pxeUZacngwWVNBNDZtekNfWjJrZ1B6dHFSTEJLOGw3eTVQaXJwdW85dGxtZHJUYnQ1QXZ1V2dpMzBHaVZhMVBXZjBzdFZtLWctVDVCQnYtRXFYWmJYckpXTVhlWUswM3VBUWNzSThJMHNFRkxhWEpQaGhR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgJBVV95cUxPMDRhQjNzVzJrRWRqc1V2ODEwYnQxT2ZjclhDbUpuV0E0bzhWWk14LW5VTU94Tmt5bmFBOTZKZHlZN1QtTkJ5VDJ3aTN0Q3lubExheEVOWjhZX3dpRXhHdmpsQWsydXQxWmttV21KQVZ4VlhVbFdDZHYwdS0wUjhaYkJaSndjamZhd3U0OEhRSmhSMEdHcEFrRjFHbUExLWFRSnhvTGtKcGRCeUdWM2lZdnc2X2ZUdkZrUkxaa1B4dG80M2pxeUZacngwWVNBNDZtekNfWjJrZ1B6dHFSTEJLOGw3eTVQaXJwdW85dGxtZHJUYnQ1QXZ1V2dpMzBHaVZhMVBXZjBzdFZtLWctVDVCQnYtRXFYWmJYckpXTVhlWUswM3VBUWNzSThJMHNFRkxhWEpQaGhR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Descendants of Aurangzeb riding rickshaws in Kolkata: UP CM Yogi Adityanath continues tirade against 'temple destroyers' - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yogi Adityanath's Remarks on Aurangzeb's Descendants in Kolkata</h1><p><strong>Published: </strong>20 December 2024, 10:56 IST</p><p>Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath has made controversial remarks regarding the descendants of those who destroyed Hindu temples, claiming they now struggle in Kolkata.</p><ul><li>Adityanath stated that the clan responsible for temple destruction, including by Mughal rulers like Aurangzeb, would become 'extinct'.</li><li>He mentioned that those connected to temple desecration currently ply rickshaws near Kolkata.</li><li>His comments come amid rising tensions following significant communal violence in Sambhal.</li><li>He emphasized the need to protect Sanatan Dharma to safeguard humanity.</li></ul><blockquote>“Their clan will be extinct… only Sanatan Dharma can establish peace in the world.”</blockquote><p>Adityanath's comments reflect ongoing communal tensions and evoke historical grievances regarding Hindu temples destroyed during Mughal rule.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/uttar-pradesh/descendants-of-aurangzeb-riding-rickshaws-in-kolkata-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-continues-tirade-against-temple-destroyers-3326523</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/uttar-pradesh/descendants-of-aurangzeb-riding-rickshaws-in-kolkata-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-continues-tirade-against-temple-destroyers-3326523</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:56:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R Ashwin Shows Off Post-Retirement Call Log, Features Sachin Tendulkar And Kapil Dev - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>R Ashwin Shows Off Post-Retirement Call Log, Features Sachin Tendulkar And Kapil Dev</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2r2m74m_r-ashwin_625x300_20_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="R Ashwin Shows Off Post-Retirement Call Log, Features Sachin Tendulkar And Kapil Dev"><figcaption>Screengrab © X/ashwinravi99</figcaption>
<p>Ravichandran Ashwin announced his retirement from international cricket, leaving behind an impactful legacy with 765 international wickets. He shared a heartwarming moment revealing messages from cricket icons Sachin Tendulkar and Kapil Dev after his retirement.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Ashwin retired with 765 international wickets and 537 Test wickets.</li>
  <li>Tributes have poured in from across the cricket community.</li>
  <li>He received messages from legends Sachin Tendulkar and Kapil Dev.</li>
  <li>Ashwin expressed gratitude for the respect and acknowledgment from his peers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>If someone told me 25 years ago that I would have a smartphone with me and the call log on the last day of my career as an Indian cricketer would look like this, I would have had a heart attack then only. Thanks Sachin and Kapil paaji.</blockquote>
<p>Tendulkar congratulated Ashwin, praising his journey and contributions to cricket.</p>
<p>Ashwin's retirement marks the end of an era, leaving behind a legacy of innovation and success in cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/r-ashwin-shows-off-post-retirement-call-log-features-sachin-tendulkar-and-kapil-dev-7291940</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/r-ashwin-shows-off-post-retirement-call-log-features-sachin-tendulkar-and-kapil-dev-7291940</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:55:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Acting like dictators': BJP leader CT Ravi slams Karnataka govt after arrest over 'derogatory' remarks - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Leader CT Ravi Criticizes Karnataka Government After Arrest Over Comments</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>An uproar has ensued following the arrest of an individual over alleged derogatory remarks, prompting BJP leader CT Ravi to label the Karnataka government as dictatorial.</p><ul><li>CT Ravi expressed strong criticism against the Karnataka government's actions.</li><li>The arrest is viewed by many as an infringement of free speech.</li><li>The incident has sparked a debate on government overreach and authoritarianism.</li></ul><blockquote>“This government is acting like dictators,” said CT Ravi, criticising the state's approach to dissent.</blockquote><p>The ongoing discourse illustrates a growing concern over freedom of expression in the current political climate.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/acting-like-dictators-bjp-leader-ct-ravi-slams-karnataka-govt-after-arrest-over-derogatory-remarks/articleshow/116500818.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/acting-like-dictators-bjp-leader-ct-ravi-slams-karnataka-govt-after-arrest-over-derogatory-remarks/articleshow/116500818.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Market Wrap: D-Street carnage extends to 5th day as Sensex crashes 1,176 pts, Nifty drops below 23,600 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxOY0w1d1U1YWVHTXFuZHNPR2ZnRlpFWkNKYm9MYnRFemRjejAxV29FS2tsSUo2VEVzZWlIVkNDa251dDlHbk9UdG1mLTk4amVKVU1KWnpjMDh1RW5PVjAtQlpqbjFyZ0hxZ2JfVzFjMlBXVV8wbVpjLTVjTXoyLVo1ejI0a25lR1JYUmVWUmx3Y0JJaklxYUVubkIxRzh4Z003b0VtWV9Yd2FCaHRBVmpPV2lSVUo1TW5zWFBfMk5pUjlVSlpITXl3SlZ5clNZbzlXZG1DWFZDZUFlMF9qY0pDLTMzVXNjeHg2NUJDb21Rc3NKWEt6aXB4UUswSFF2Vm1hd2fSAYcCQVVfeXFMTXczTWxjNGZQeUhsbW9KSVVfS0IzX3JYTS1iT0prZW9HS25wakJBUC1hQmVsVXpJblRBZE5EenR4YjRVZEhZdDJJRXRKaHdEM0NjOGdabk1SSmU0TGdQaVg4QWtUdWlscnRvZzVfSVpMbmlXc0FKb3IyUkI0cFk0Q1FIbWFvSmo2QXZsVkFXd010STJYY1pMWHE5ZTNuLU41QVBmaTZfUXpYSlQ2WEY0bTZKd0gtZ0NxbkxsRXhuYlpNYzBsWk1HSHBGUVRSOUJab2FlSDgxcUprcDgxT0JYN3RPbEZMS1djczE0RnkxUjNvYVpqd2EybEprWHBydHFwNEtyOHgwZ3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxOY0w1d1U1YWVHTXFuZHNPR2ZnRlpFWkNKYm9MYnRFemRjejAxV29FS2tsSUo2VEVzZWlIVkNDa251dDlHbk9UdG1mLTk4amVKVU1KWnpjMDh1RW5PVjAtQlpqbjFyZ0hxZ2JfVzFjMlBXVV8wbVpjLTVjTXoyLVo1ejI0a25lR1JYUmVWUmx3Y0JJaklxYUVubkIxRzh4Z003b0VtWV9Yd2FCaHRBVmpPV2lSVUo1TW5zWFBfMk5pUjlVSlpITXl3SlZ5clNZbzlXZG1DWFZDZUFlMF9qY0pDLTMzVXNjeHg2NUJDb21Rc3NKWEt6aXB4UUswSFF2Vm1hd2fSAYcCQVVfeXFMTXczTWxjNGZQeUhsbW9KSVVfS0IzX3JYTS1iT0prZW9HS25wakJBUC1hQmVsVXpJblRBZE5EenR4YjRVZEhZdDJJRXRKaHdEM0NjOGdabk1SSmU0TGdQaVg4QWtUdWlscnRvZzVfSVpMbmlXc0FKb3IyUkI0cFk0Q1FIbWFvSmo2QXZsVkFXd010STJYY1pMWHE5ZTNuLU41QVBmaTZfUXpYSlQ2WEY0bTZKd0gtZ0NxbkxsRXhuYlpNYzBsWk1HSHBGUVRSOUJab2FlSDgxcUprcDgxT0JYN3RPbEZMS1djczE0RnkxUjNvYVpqd2EybEprWHBydHFwNEtyOHgwZ3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:21:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experiencing Value, Nation, and Scale in the Borderlands - Economic and Political Weekly]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPSWRnRWM5Tk02SWRqWV9VZzFOVU5LOUZ6d245bjQyZXhNSlNNajJnd0pzRUF0RXo1MnlHcHBPMzNrMHBSb0Vma1hlRXI2bTltdXV1TnBfSDd0bHlWSkRBVDgzMzFNRjFyMlV4aFFqSE5ZWXU4dXhaMXBfbU5EaE9uRVhTbnVCS1EyeFhMdlVxZEprSVp1em9Xa2xZUEJQdDJTLUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPSWRnRWM5Tk02SWRqWV9VZzFOVU5LOUZ6d245bjQyZXhNSlNNajJnd0pzRUF0RXo1MnlHcHBPMzNrMHBSb0Vma1hlRXI2bTltdXV1TnBfSDd0bHlWSkRBVDgzMzFNRjFyMlV4aFFqSE5ZWXU4dXhaMXBfbU5EaE9uRVhTbnVCS1EyeFhMdlVxZEprSVp1em9Xa2xZUEJQdDJTLUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:20:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Seniors complained about Prithvi Shaw. He stayed out all night, reached hotel at 6 AM’: Selectors rubbish Insta rant - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Selectors Respond to Prithvi Shaw's Instagram Rant About Team Exclusion</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/19_12_2024-prithvi_shaw_4_23851607_m_1734687138855_1734687143504.jpeg" alt="Prithvi Shaw has been dropped from Mumbai's squad for the Vijay Hazare Trophy.(BCCI)"><figcaption>Prithvi Shaw has been dropped from Mumbai's squad for the Vijay Hazare Trophy.(BCCI)</figcaption><p>The ongoing turmoil surrounding Prithvi Shaw's cricket career intensifies as he has been excluded from Mumbai's squad for the upcoming Vijay Hazare Trophy following complaints about his fitness and discipline from team officials.</p><ul><li>Prithvi Shaw's Instagram post criticized his exclusion and highlighted his batting statistics.</li><li>Mumbai officials express concern over Shaw's fitness, citing his poor performance in the field during previous matches.</li><li>A senior official stated, "No one is Shaw's enemy. He is his own enemy," reflecting the sentiment within the Mumbai Cricket Association.</li><li>Shaw's habit of arriving late to training sessions has drawn criticism from teammates.</li><li>Mumbai's campaign begins with a match against Karnataka at the Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel B Ground.</li></ul><blockquote>"Even the seniors in the team have started complaining about his attitude now."</blockquote><p>The ongoing scrutiny of Shaw's performance and behavior raises questions about his future in cricket as he must address his fitness and discipline to reclaim his place in the team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/seniors-complained-about-prithvi-shaw-he-stayed-out-all-night-reached-hotel-at-6-am-selectors-rubbish-insta-rant-101734686733590.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/seniors-complained-about-prithvi-shaw-he-stayed-out-all-night-reached-hotel-at-6-am-selectors-rubbish-insta-rant-101734686733590.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:16:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Adjourned Sine Die, 'One Nation, One Election' Bills Referred to Joint Committee - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/parliament-winter-session-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-adjourned-nda-opposition-protest-ambedkar-row-bjp-mps-injured-9162588.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/parliament-winter-session-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-adjourned-nda-opposition-protest-ambedkar-row-bjp-mps-injured-9162588.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:14:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top US officials in Damascus to meet new Syrian rulers, State Department says - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/top-us-officials-damascus-meet-new-syrian-rulers-state-department-says-2024-12-20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/top-us-officials-damascus-meet-new-syrian-rulers-state-department-says-2024-12-20/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:14:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Market Crash: Nifty posts worst week of 2024, losing ₹19 lakh crore of investor wealth - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Crash: Nifty posts worst week of 2024, losing ₹19 lakh crore of investor wealth</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<p>The Nifty 50 index ended with significant losses, marking its worst week of 2024 and leading to a loss of nearly ₹19 lakh crore in investor wealth.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Nifty 50 index dropped over 350 points on Friday.</li>
<li>48 out of 50 Nifty stocks ended the week with losses.</li>
<li>The Sensex lost nearly 1,200 points during the same period.</li>
<li>IT stocks declined despite positive guidance from Accenture Plc.</li>
<li>Global market concerns from the US Federal Reserve's hawkish outlook affected investor sentiment.</li>
<li>Some stocks hit 52-week lows, including Reliance Industries and Tata Consumer Products.</li>
<li>Experts are watching critical support levels for potential market rebounds.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The market has been going through a little bit of turmoil... but in case, these levels do not hold, then I think that is a further slide towards 23,200 to 22,500.” - Vaishali Parekh, Prabhudas Lilladher</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while the current market conditions are challenging, experts suggest a potential recovery, driven by government expenditure in the upcoming months.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/stock-market-crash-nifty-50-sensex-sharp-fall-worst-week-of-2024-19-lakh-crore-investor-wealth-lost-19527326.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/stock-market-crash-nifty-50-sensex-sharp-fall-worst-week-of-2024-19-lakh-crore-investor-wealth-lost-19527326.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:07:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market crash: Sensex cracks over 1200 points; 5 factors why the Indian stock market is falling | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgJBVV95cUxPbU11aFJrSTE3eGJOREpNQWl0T1FtNzcxSzVsVmdPSzgxd3dvOFEtaVk3TmpWYXlHbklxSUNVUlZONWJJS3JOcUpvWV9WbGR2TVh6YUhSSzluc21ZLVVpeVREQUwyNkd6Wk9fS2V2bHZrdFJCSnJFNV81c05qOE9KelZ4NXlLOWt3dWI1UVVBWGRTR3ZUaVJGYWNTY0lYMHF4MkdzM3d5OXkyLU5Kenl3cUJXajYzdWNHRHlZdDdzaFhmcWFvYmF4VjZ6THJQaG8zTHlMakhCclFIYWlyaXBNaTR1ekIyT05WQk9SRUY0T3dkcmhxaEJxaThIbHJwbm9ld2NoSDNLMzQ1TGZhYzBZOFNSVk5pd9IBmwJBVV95cUxNX1d5bkhLcFhUYTZHMS1Va0hDU1hJb2pvdVgyV1FLMk1yRkV6WGM1eEFrZ0ZDdGZ5b09TaGRvenREN2luRl82Zzgxb2R3U2VXX3VwYkJhTVY5TUxNenRldEFVZkJlOV9tczZfb3NUamFMM0ZqQXM1VVJnb3FoaC1ib2Q2RTlneWh0X0w0LUtjc083d3ZCMTJMbFBUTDlTbHE0SUpibEp0ZnBseGVsemd2czY2dFh0dlZrNWhIRXlKYkFGNUV5WVBVZXB6Z2NBNkpvUm1rbVA0RFhSTTVzSVRJemVqSlZJLVoybUw4XzVUdVViMlEwY1RlN2Vabk9CRVZWNXdzUzd0aTVvNzNtbFlXTzlmSmY1UGsybmNv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgJBVV95cUxPbU11aFJrSTE3eGJOREpNQWl0T1FtNzcxSzVsVmdPSzgxd3dvOFEtaVk3TmpWYXlHbklxSUNVUlZONWJJS3JOcUpvWV9WbGR2TVh6YUhSSzluc21ZLVVpeVREQUwyNkd6Wk9fS2V2bHZrdFJCSnJFNV81c05qOE9KelZ4NXlLOWt3dWI1UVVBWGRTR3ZUaVJGYWNTY0lYMHF4MkdzM3d5OXkyLU5Kenl3cUJXajYzdWNHRHlZdDdzaFhmcWFvYmF4VjZ6THJQaG8zTHlMakhCclFIYWlyaXBNaTR1ekIyT05WQk9SRUY0T3dkcmhxaEJxaThIbHJwbm9ld2NoSDNLMzQ1TGZhYzBZOFNSVk5pd9IBmwJBVV95cUxNX1d5bkhLcFhUYTZHMS1Va0hDU1hJb2pvdVgyV1FLMk1yRkV6WGM1eEFrZ0ZDdGZ5b09TaGRvenREN2luRl82Zzgxb2R3U2VXX3VwYkJhTVY5TUxNenRldEFVZkJlOV9tczZfb3NUamFMM0ZqQXM1VVJnb3FoaC1ib2Q2RTlneWh0X0w0LUtjc083d3ZCMTJMbFBUTDlTbHE0SUpibEp0ZnBseGVsemd2czY2dFh0dlZrNWhIRXlKYkFGNUV5WVBVZXB6Z2NBNkpvUm1rbVA0RFhSTTVzSVRJemVqSlZJLVoybUw4XzVUdVViMlEwY1RlN2Vabk9CRVZWNXdzUzd0aTVvNzNtbFlXTzlmSmY1UGsybmNv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:00:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody" alt="Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1jhj1vd8_atul-subhash-_625x300_20_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>Atul Subhash's Mother Appeals for Custody</figcaption><p>In a poignant development, the mother of Atul Subhash, a Bengaluru engineer who died by suicide, has approached the Supreme Court for custody of her four-year-old grandson amidst allegations of harassment against Subhash's estranged wife and her family.</p><ul><li>The case revolves around multiple arrests linked to Subhash's suicide on December 9, which his family claims was prompted by harassment.</li><li>Anju Modi filed a habeas corpus petition for her grandson, whose whereabouts remain unknown despite claims he is in a boarding school.</li><li>The Supreme Court has asked the governments of Uttar Pradesh, Haryana, and Karnataka for clarity regarding the child’s location.</li><li>Nikita Singhania, Subhash's estranged wife, and her family members face charges related to abetment of suicide and are currently in custody.</li><li>Pawan Kumar, Subhash's father, demands to know the child's whereabouts and custody due to the family's concerns for his safety.</li><li>There is ongoing legal contention, including anticipatory bail requests concerning Nikita's uncle.</li></ul><blockquote>Bikas Kumar, Subhash's brother, stated, "Our fight will continue. We will not immerse the ashes of my brother till we get justice."</blockquote><p>The situation highlights serious familial disputes and legal battles regarding the welfare of a young child amidst tragic circumstances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/atul-subhash-nikita-singhania-techie-suicide-atul-subhashs-mother-moves-supreme-court-for-4-year-old-grandsons-custody-7293075</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/atul-subhash-nikita-singhania-techie-suicide-atul-subhashs-mother-moves-supreme-court-for-4-year-old-grandsons-custody-7293075</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:49:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atul Subhash's Mother Moves Supreme Court for 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody" alt="Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1jhj1vd8_atul-subhash-_625x300_20_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>Atul Subhash's Mother Appeals for Custody</figcaption><p>In a poignant development, the mother of Atul Subhash, a Bengaluru engineer who died by suicide, has approached the Supreme Court for custody of her four-year-old grandson amidst allegations of harassment against Subhash's estranged wife and her family.</p><ul><li>The case revolves around multiple arrests linked to Subhash's suicide on December 9, which his family claims was prompted by harassment.</li><li>Anju Modi filed a habeas corpus petition for her grandson, whose whereabouts remain unknown despite claims he is in a boarding school.</li><li>The Supreme Court has asked the governments of Uttar Pradesh, Haryana, and Karnataka for clarity regarding the child’s location.</li><li>Nikita Singhania, Subhash's estranged wife, and her family members face charges related to abetment of suicide and are currently in custody.</li><li>Pawan Kumar, Subhash's father, demands to know the child's whereabouts and custody due to the family's concerns for his safety.</li><li>There is ongoing legal contention, including anticipatory bail requests concerning Nikita's uncle.</li></ul><blockquote>Bikas Kumar, Subhash's brother, stated, "Our fight will continue. We will not immerse the ashes of my brother till we get justice."</blockquote><p>The situation highlights serious familial disputes and legal battles regarding the welfare of a young child amidst tragic circumstances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/atul-subhash-nikita-singhania-techie-suicide-atul-subhashs-mother-moves-supreme-court-for-4-year-old-grandsons-custody-7293075</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/atul-subhash-nikita-singhania-techie-suicide-atul-subhashs-mother-moves-supreme-court-for-4-year-old-grandsons-custody-7293075</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:49:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Kia Syros Variant-wise Features Explained - CarDekho]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kia Syros Variant-wise Features Explained</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> CarDekho.com</p><img src="https://stimg.cardekho.com/images/cms/carnewsimages/editorimages/67653ce00d314.jpg" alt="Kia Syros variant-wise features explained"><figcaption>Kia Syros variant-wise features explained</figcaption><p>The new Kia Syros is set to offer six variants: HTK, HTK (O), HTK Plus, HTX, HTX Plus, and HTX Plus (O). This sub-4m SUV features premium attributes not available in other Kia models.</p><ul><li>Entry-level HTK variant includes halogen headlights and safety features like 6 airbags.</li><li>HTK (O) variant adds roof rails and alloy wheels (diesel).</li><li>HTK Plus includes a panoramic sunroof and cruise control.</li><li>HTX variant upgrades to LED headlights and ventilated front seats.</li><li>HTX Plus introduces advanced features like a 12.3-inch digital driver’s display.</li><li>Top variant HTX Plus (O) includes a 360-degree camera and level 2 ADAS.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Kia Syros is expected to be launched in January 2025, with pricing starting around Rs 9 lakh.”</blockquote><p>The Kia Syros aims to fill a niche in the compact SUV market with advanced features across its variants.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/new-kia-syros-variantwise-features-explained-33699.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cardekho.com/india-car-news/new-kia-syros-variantwise-features-explained-33699.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX to Launch Two Private Lunar Landers in January 2025 - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaceX to Launch Two Private Lunar Landers in January 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/qlivLiUjeNY/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Launch Video"><figcaption>Launch Video Preview</figcaption><p>Two private lunar landers are set to be launched aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket in January 2025, marking a milestone in lunar exploration.</p><ul><li>The landers, from Firefly Aerospace and ispace, will launch from Florida's Space Coast.</li><li>ispace's ‘Resilience’ aims to land on Mare Frigoris, carrying five payloads including a water electrolyser.</li><li>Firefly's ‘Blue Ghost’ will land at Mare Crisium and deliver ten science instruments under NASA's program.</li><li>If successful, these missions will add to the achievements of private lunar landers.</li></ul><blockquote>“If successful, these missions will join the limited achievements of private companies in lunar landings,” said a space expert.</blockquote><p>The upcoming launch solidifies international interest in lunar exploration and could foster future collaborative missions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/spacex-falcon-9-to-launch-firefly-s-blue-ghost-and-ispace-s-resilience-in-january-7291893</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/spacex-falcon-9-to-launch-firefly-s-blue-ghost-and-ispace-s-resilience-in-january-7291893</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:30:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>