<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 18:16:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 18:16:50 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First case of bird flu reported in Louisiana, patient hospitalised - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxPWEFxU1phcUkwOU9oQmFVQm9VOTl3UWU3bGhLQ0JDTGVxc1ZPeUc2UlFiUHdZcjRKSTVXZnB3eVUzZWVuYUNuTVF5dV8yc3hNLVYxUkQ3TUxNMjBobHJfaUsyVmR4SzNmY3B1MWZBM08ycjBxRWxGN1Q3WFdWUXFSWnJHcndfb2lzNkJza1YwRXdhYmVvMk9uM290b2tPa0hRVTh3ZGE2RldJRTNlWXFlNFZqUHIyT2I3SmEtallpSWtoUjFtMjQycFdORmt3TXdsVlJYTmUwZGZCRElaNEZZUkZ2QTVtUk8tNWF3OGdsUHI0THhOWjFQMNIB_gFBVV95cUxQbzFqa3hMVnBQYS1EOWRtS0dVd2FBXzQ3LXRrYmZnaDNZaWFfakdvejNkMUVTUTl3Y09nelY4cGFhXzVoWHgxa2hPVHdtRjcwSC1rZU03WElOYmZTS1BDVHJpcDc5d2hCb2pDYU1hUURxaTBWVHRDalpTNnZQNHM2aU5mdFp1WW1IU3RnMFpZZ3c1ZW1ZOHdHY3o2LTdGaDBGeURTR25PdE5TOE1FVVhsQjNDOXNZMDA1cEY5VEI4a3V2YjRReXNhNG5lcjZyclAydDRRRGtHYk4wYWRNUUgyRVI4REJuenhUV0FSREJMaThBUlQ4bEJUM0t6MzdzZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxPWEFxU1phcUkwOU9oQmFVQm9VOTl3UWU3bGhLQ0JDTGVxc1ZPeUc2UlFiUHdZcjRKSTVXZnB3eVUzZWVuYUNuTVF5dV8yc3hNLVYxUkQ3TUxNMjBobHJfaUsyVmR4SzNmY3B1MWZBM08ycjBxRWxGN1Q3WFdWUXFSWnJHcndfb2lzNkJza1YwRXdhYmVvMk9uM290b2tPa0hRVTh3ZGE2RldJRTNlWXFlNFZqUHIyT2I3SmEtallpSWtoUjFtMjQycFdORmt3TXdsVlJYTmUwZGZCRElaNEZZUkZ2QTVtUk8tNWF3OGdsUHI0THhOWjFQMNIB_gFBVV95cUxQbzFqa3hMVnBQYS1EOWRtS0dVd2FBXzQ3LXRrYmZnaDNZaWFfakdvejNkMUVTUTl3Y09nelY4cGFhXzVoWHgxa2hPVHdtRjcwSC1rZU03WElOYmZTS1BDVHJpcDc5d2hCb2pDYU1hUURxaTBWVHRDalpTNnZQNHM2aU5mdFp1WW1IU3RnMFpZZ3c1ZW1ZOHdHY3o2LTdGaDBGeURTR25PdE5TOE1FVVhsQjNDOXNZMDA1cEY5VEI4a3V2YjRReXNhNG5lcjZyclAydDRRRGtHYk4wYWRNUUgyRVI4REJuenhUV0FSREJMaThBUlQ4bEJUM0t6MzdzZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 17:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pushpa 2 Box Office: Allu Arjun film shatter records on Saturday, Eyes 200cr second weekend in India - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Box Office: Allu Arjun film shatter records on Saturday, Eyes 200cr second weekend in India</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p>
<img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2024-12/1804463813_pushpa-5.jpg" alt="Pushpa 2" title="Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)">
<figcaption>Allu Arjun in Pushpa 2 (image courtesy of Mythri Movie Makers)</figcaption>
<p>The Second Saturday has significantly boosted Pushpa 2's position in its quest to break lifetime records, particularly that of Baahubali 2.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Pushpa 2 is projected to gross over Rs. 70 crore on its Second Saturday, surpassing Baahubali 2's record of Rs. 64.25 crore.</li>
    <li>The film is now on track to achieve the highest second weekend collection ever, potentially earning around Rs. 200 crore.</li>
    <li>Early estimates indicate an 80% growth in collections for the Hindi version compared to previous days.</li>
    <li>Pushpa 2 has passed the Rs. 900 crore milestone, with a total gross of approximately Rs. 925 crore and aiming for Rs. 1000 crore soon.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The trajectory is highly encouraging," indicating Pushpa 2's competitive race with Baahubali 2.</blockquote>
<p>As Pushpa 2 continues to break records, it sets a promising pace for future milestones in the Indian box office landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-allu-arjun-film-shatter-records-on-saturday-eyes-200cr-second-weekend-in-india-1362796</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-allu-arjun-film-shatter-records-on-saturday-eyes-200cr-second-weekend-in-india-1362796</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 16:55:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 smart ways to use turmeric for weight loss - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxPMlFuVjlPQ3NWUndwZzk5ZElYVnVoVDh6OFYyYkFxb3BwZ0s3V0tRelhLTmk3Z0FuWTFpbGhBbng2dkswX2JwaXNPMEEzMU9RUXpHbjNydkkzTTluQVd0b3lTTnR0ZHR0blBubUVDUFpSRDNkSHR2a3lEdmRjZGhSOG9YMGlmU09YYWM0al9SUndOVWd5V2RBaFlLcEh1MjFvTTZkTjhvLV9zUUhFN2pIR19uUUIxSGM5VW1tNzZWREs0VWZHWUI5cng0RGdXZ05hR0ljQXBSbFgxYXPSAdsBQVVfeXFMTzJRblY5T0NzVlJ3cGc5OWRJWFZ1aFQ4ejhWMmJBcW9wcGdLN1dLUXpYS05pN2dBblkxaWxoQW54NnZLMF9icGlzTzBBMzFPUVF6R24zcnZJM005bkFXdG95U050dGR0dG5Qbm1FQ1BaUkQzZEh0dmt5RHZkY2RoUjhvWDBpZlNPWGFjNGpfUlJ3TlVneVdkQWhZS3BIdTIxb002ZE44by1fc1FIRTdqSEdfblFCMUhjOVVtbTc2VkRLNFVmR1lCOXJ4NERnV2dOYUdJY0FwUmxYMWFz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxPMlFuVjlPQ3NWUndwZzk5ZElYVnVoVDh6OFYyYkFxb3BwZ0s3V0tRelhLTmk3Z0FuWTFpbGhBbng2dkswX2JwaXNPMEEzMU9RUXpHbjNydkkzTTluQVd0b3lTTnR0ZHR0blBubUVDUFpSRDNkSHR2a3lEdmRjZGhSOG9YMGlmU09YYWM0al9SUndOVWd5V2RBaFlLcEh1MjFvTTZkTjhvLV9zUUhFN2pIR19uUUIxSGM5VW1tNzZWREs0VWZHWUI5cng0RGdXZ05hR0ljQXBSbFgxYXPSAdsBQVVfeXFMTzJRblY5T0NzVlJ3cGc5OWRJWFZ1aFQ4ejhWMmJBcW9wcGdLN1dLUXpYS05pN2dBblkxaWxoQW54NnZLMF9icGlzTzBBMzFPUVF6R24zcnZJM005bkFXdG95U050dGR0dG5Qbm1FQ1BaUkQzZEh0dmt5RHZkY2RoUjhvWDBpZlNPWGFjNGpfUlJ3TlVneVdkQWhZS3BIdTIxb002ZE44by1fc1FIRTdqSEdfblFCMUhjOVVtbTc2VkRLNFVmR1lCOXJ4NERnV2dOYUdJY0FwUmxYMWFz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Srikanth Gives Leaks About 'Game Changer'.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Srikanth Gives Leaks About 'Game Changer'</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Unknown Date, GreatAndhra</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/srikanth31734193612.jpg" alt="Srikanth Gives Leaks About 'Game Changer'">
    <figcaption>Srikanth Gives Leaks About 'Game Changer'</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Srikanth, who plays a key role in the upcoming film 'Game Changer', has shared some insights about the movie, generating excitement among fans.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Srikanth assures that 'Game Changer' will exceed all expectations with unexpected twists and turns.</li>
    <li>The film is said to balance strong narratives with powerful elevations, making it appealing to audiences.</li>
    <li>Srikanth clarifies that there will be no sequel to 'Game Changer' and attributes shooting delays to scheduling challenges with the star-studded cast.</li>
    <li>The movie is set to release on January 10 as a Sankranthi treat, with Ram Charan's role as Appanna being a major highlight.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Audiences today love stories that combine strong narratives with powerful elevations. While some films focus solely on elevations, this one perfectly balances both. Shankar’s recent films may not have been successful, but this will not disappoint," Srikanth said.</blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> 'Game Changer' is anticipated to be a thrilling and well-balanced film, with Srikanth's leaks adding to the hype surrounding its release.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/srikanth-gives-leaks-about-game-changer-142741</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/srikanth-gives-leaks-about-game-changer-142741</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 16:26:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Double maths period, boring’: Priyanka Gandhi Vadra on PM Modi's parliament speech - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Double maths period, boring’: Priyanka Gandhi Vadra on PM Modi's parliament speech</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Priyanka_Gandhi_Vadra_1734190383716_1734190384026.jpg" alt="Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra speaks in the Lok Sabha during the Winter Session of Parliament on Friday.(Sansad TV)" title="Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra speaks in the Lok Sabha during the Winter Session of Parliament on Friday.(Sansad TV)">
<figcaption>Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra speaks in the Lok Sabha during the Winter Session of Parliament on Friday.(Sansad TV)</figcaption>
<p>Congress general secretary Priyanka Gandhi Vadra criticized Prime Minister Narendra Modi's recent speech in Parliament, describing it as unoriginal and boring, likening the experience to a tedious double mathematics class.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Priyanka Gandhi Vadra called PM Modi's address “double period of mathematics” and “boring”.</li>
    <li>She expressed disappointment, stating there was nothing new in his remarks.</li>
    <li>During the speech, PM Modi accused the Nehru-Gandhi family of undermining the Constitution throughout their rule.</li>
    <li>Modi emphasized that the Congress family's actions during their governance have had lasting negative impacts on Indian democracy.</li>
    <li>The Prime Minister recalled serious events, such as the Emergency, to highlight Congress's historical failures.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“(JP) Nadda ji was also rubbing hands but as soon as Modi ji looked at him, he started acting as if he is listening attentively. Amit Shah also had his hand on head, (Piyush) Goyal ji was going off to sleep... I had thought that the PM will say something new, something nice.” - Priyanka Gandhi Vadra</blockquote>
<p>The exchanges in Parliament highlight ongoing tensions between the ruling party and the opposition, reflecting broader debates about governance and historical accountability in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/double-maths-period-boring-priyanka-gandhi-vadra-on-pm-modis-parliament-speech-101734190105597.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/double-maths-period-boring-priyanka-gandhi-vadra-on-pm-modis-parliament-speech-101734190105597.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:58:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uproar in Lok Sabha after NDA cites Indira Gandhi’s letter on Savarkar - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Uproar in Lok Sabha after NDA cites Indira Gandhi’s letter on Savarkar</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Shiv-Sena-MP-Shrikant-Shinde-speaks-in-the-Lok-Sab_1734191630136.jpg" alt="Shiv Sena MP Shrikant Shinde speaks in the Lok Sabha on Saturday. (SansadTV YouTube)">
<figcaption>Shiv Sena MP Shrikant Shinde speaks in the Lok Sabha on Saturday. (SansadTV YouTube)</figcaption>
<p>Shiv Sena MP Shrikant Shinde's invocation of a letter from Indira Gandhi praising V D Savarkar led to heated debates in the Lok Sabha, escalating tensions between the NDA and Congress members.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Shinde read a letter from Indira Gandhi praising Savarkar's contributions to India's freedom movement.</li>
    <li>His statements prompted Congress MPs to demand a response from Rahul Gandhi, leading to disruptions in the House.</li>
    <li>Shinde accused Congress of ignoring constitutional matters and highlighted past violence during their tenure.</li>
    <li>BJP MP Nishikant Dubey criticized Congress, stating Indira Gandhi had funded Savarkar’s trust.</li>
    <li>Rahul Gandhi responded by suggesting that Indira Gandhi had disapproved of Savarkar's actions during the freedom struggle.</li>
    <li>Union minister Kiren Rijiju shared Indira Gandhi's letter, countering arguments made by Rahul Gandhi regarding Savarkar.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Savarkar apologised to the British... Gandhi ji went to jail, Nehru ji went to jail, but Savarkar ji sought forgiveness.” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote>
<p>This intense exchange in the Lok Sabha reflects the ongoing political tensions and the differing perspectives on historical figures in India's independence movement, underscoring the impact of history on current political discourse.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/clash-in-lok-sabha-after-nda-cites-indira-gandhi-s-letter-on-savarkar-101734191637733.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/clash-in-lok-sabha-after-nda-cites-indira-gandhi-s-letter-on-savarkar-101734191637733.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:53:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What happened during Assad's final hours in Syria: Deception, despair and flight - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What happened during Assad's final hours in Syria: Deception, despair and flight</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Syria-4_1734190503069_1734190650507.jpg" alt="A torn poster shows ousted Syrian President Bashar Assad at the entrance of the notorious security detention centre called Palestine Branch, in Damascus, Syria." title="A torn poster shows ousted Syrian President Bashar Assad at the entrance of the notorious security detention centre called Palestine Branch, in Damascus, Syria.">
<figcaption>A torn poster shows ousted Syrian President Bashar Assad at the entrance of the notorious security detention centre called Palestine Branch, in Damascus, Syria, Saturday, Dec. 14, 2024.(AP)</figcaption>
<p>The article discusses the final hours of Bashar al-Assad's rule in Syria, detailing his secretive plans to flee the country amidst collapsing power and escalating rebel control.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Assad's departure was planned and executed without informing key aides and family members.</li>
    <li>On the eve of his flight, he assured military chiefs of Russian support while masking the true dire situation.</li>
    <li>He fled to Russia on December 8, 2024, after disguising the flight under radar.</li>
    <li>Significant unrest in Damascus accompanied Assad's departure, with civilians celebrating the fall of his regime.</li>
    <li>There were no military rescue efforts from Russia or Iran despite previous support during the civil war.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Assad didn't even make a last stand. He didn't even rally his own troops," said Nadim Houri, executive director of the Arab Reform Initiative.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Bashar al-Assad's flight marked the end of his 24-year rule and the demise of his family's long-standing power, leaving a pivotal moment in Syria's tumultuous history.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-russia-damascus-civil-war-101734190324252.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-russia-damascus-civil-war-101734190324252.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:50:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Atul Subhash, Bengaluru Cop Dies By Suicide In Uniform, Blames Wife For Torture In Note - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After Atul Subhash, Bengaluru Cop Dies By Suicide In Uniform, Blames Wife For Torture In Note</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024, 19:37 IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Bengaluru cop dies by suicide (Photo: IANS)">
    <figcaption>Bengaluru cop dies by suicide (Photo: IANS)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A Bengaluru Police constable died by suicide in uniform, citing torture from his wife and in-laws in a note. This incident follows nationwide outrage over a similar case involving techie Atul Subhash.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The cop, identified as HC Thippanna, 34, allegedly took his life due to ongoing domestic issues.</li>
    <li>He committed suicide on the railway tracks and left behind a note blaming his wife and father-in-law for his troubles.</li>
    <li>Thippanna described being threatened by his father-in-law and expressed feelings of hopelessness.</li>
    <li>This tragedy is linked to recent discussions around the Atul Subhash suicide case, which has sparked debates on men's rights.</li>
    <li>Social media has seen a rise in discussions advocating for justice and men's rights following these incidents.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “On December 12, he called me at 7.26 p.m., spoke for 14 minutes, and threatened me,” Thippanna wrote in his note, highlighting the distress he faced.
</blockquote>
<p>This tragedy underscores the need for awareness and support regarding mental health and domestic issues.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/bengaluru-cop-dies-by-suicide-in-uniform-blames-wife-father-in-law-for-torture-in-final-note-techie-atul-subhash-9156102.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/bengaluru-cop-dies-by-suicide-in-uniform-blames-wife-father-in-law-for-torture-in-final-note-techie-atul-subhash-9156102.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:39:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Ek Bharat, Shreshtha Bharat': PM Modi presents 11 resolutions for India's future - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ek-bharat-shreshtha-bharat-pm-modi-presents-11-resolutions-for-indias-future/articleshow/116320565.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ek-bharat-shreshtha-bharat-pm-modi-presents-11-resolutions-for-indias-future/articleshow/116320565.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘I gave up sugar, honey, jaggery 4 years ago’: Saumya Tandon swears by these sugar-free desserts—Can you do it too? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>I gave up sugar, honey, jaggery 4 years ago: Saumya Tandon swears by these sugar-free desserts—Can you do it too?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Dec 14, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Saumya_Tandon_1734188766244_1734188766483.jpg" alt="Saumya Tandon’s sugar-free journey: A game-changer for your sweet tooth(Photo by Instagram/saumyas_world_)" title="Saumya Tandon’s sugar-free journey: A game-changer for your sweet tooth(Photo by Instagram/saumyas_world_)" />
<figcaption>Saumya Tandon’s sugar-free journey: A game-changer for your sweet tooth(Photo by Instagram/saumyas_world_)</figcaption>
<p>Actor Saumya Tandon shares her experience of living sugar-free for four years, relying on fruits and natural ingredients for her desserts. She advocates for a lifestyle that eliminates sugar and its substitutes while promoting healthier alternatives.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Saumya Tandon has not consumed sugar, honey, or jaggery for four years.</li>
    <li>She creates sugar-free desserts using fruits and dry fruits, calling it a transformative experience.</li>
    <li>Nutritionist Prachi Chandra discusses the psychology behind sugar cravings and their health implications.</li>
    <li>The WHO recommends limiting sugar intake to less than 10% of total energy, about 40g for adults a day.</li>
    <li>Chandra offers tips to manage sugar cravings, advocating for natural sugars from fruits and vegetables.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Craving once in a while is ok but frequent sugar cravings are not a good sign.” - Prachi Chandra</blockquote>
<p>This shift towards a sugar-free lifestyle highlights the benefits of natural sugars and encourages healthier eating habits. Saumya Tandon's journey serves as an inspiration for others looking to reduce their sugar intake and lead a healthier life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/i-gave-up-sugar-honey-jaggery-4-years-ago-saumya-tandon-swears-by-these-sugar-free-desserts-can-you-do-it-too-101734187580191.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/i-gave-up-sugar-honey-jaggery-4-years-ago-saumya-tandon-swears-by-these-sugar-free-desserts-can-you-do-it-too-101734187580191.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:10:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intermittent fasting could slow hair regeneration, says study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxQMGY3d1cwTTJUaEwtaVZFMEEya0ZZRnBkM2lDaDg1Z3hra2lOYjRlWlotMjVKVlN6M29OU01xMzNyVmg5dF9TVzR3LU5nc0F0XzlTSzlPbmZjbm94NmFvUjVIYUZCT18zdEpaVVVEMFF2ajcyWVhBN05rNHFGRGYtaDloS19CY3JmaUJnVXpwaFRqaFN6Q29SZEExNndjcTZIN0NoQ2VZUnloS0FnNnRtdGZqaVFoMjFiMVRSVkVNS2d6SElicVIyZnN1UTU4dmRrd2wweUljaFJHZnFMQXpqc19PQXFuY0xRVndaaDNsUGpNd9IB9wFBVV95cUxNandEbzh0d2Nic2NYbFRCTGdHS3ZwZHljQWNhNWxwX1A3T2UtNGd4MlBHbF9HVXlrajNSWm1GWnVEOHY3QmxSQzAtd1l1akw3V08zVDh0RVJsRkYteXYxczVMQkxQenRLNFBEZWpGeTQ0WmlNSVJ2dkR6ZVJxLWpiVjRFRGxYQV9yd0pyVXYxUk9ZLXZ6NFRPY1QyVGVycmZPWVctUUZOb3lTc1lPMGJRTkpIdHZVT3ptR2twczhqRzVYYjBnOWJBbHFJbHdmQllZTF92ZmNiMXVjNnhUNllKTVpqaTI3bUVxdzVtVmZfM192VTNHRFFB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxQMGY3d1cwTTJUaEwtaVZFMEEya0ZZRnBkM2lDaDg1Z3hra2lOYjRlWlotMjVKVlN6M29OU01xMzNyVmg5dF9TVzR3LU5nc0F0XzlTSzlPbmZjbm94NmFvUjVIYUZCT18zdEpaVVVEMFF2ajcyWVhBN05rNHFGRGYtaDloS19CY3JmaUJnVXpwaFRqaFN6Q29SZEExNndjcTZIN0NoQ2VZUnloS0FnNnRtdGZqaVFoMjFiMVRSVkVNS2d6SElicVIyZnN1UTU4dmRrd2wweUljaFJHZnFMQXpqc19PQXFuY0xRVndaaDNsUGpNd9IB9wFBVV95cUxNandEbzh0d2Nic2NYbFRCTGdHS3ZwZHljQWNhNWxwX1A3T2UtNGd4MlBHbF9HVXlrajNSWm1GWnVEOHY3QmxSQzAtd1l1akw3V08zVDh0RVJsRkYteXYxczVMQkxQenRLNFBEZWpGeTQ0WmlNSVJ2dkR6ZVJxLWpiVjRFRGxYQV9yd0pyVXYxUk9ZLXZ6NFRPY1QyVGVycmZPWVctUUZOb3lTc1lPMGJRTkpIdHZVT3ptR2twczhqRzVYYjBnOWJBbHFJbHdmQllZTF92ZmNiMXVjNnhUNllKTVpqaTI3bUVxdzVtVmZfM192VTNHRFFB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli reaches new milestone, joins Sachin Tendulkar in this elite list - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli reaches new milestone, joins Sachin Tendulkar in this elite list</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> NEW DELHI</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116320762,imgsize-138000,width-400,resizemode-4/116320762.jpg" alt="Virat Kohli reaches new milestone, joins Sachin Tendulkar in this elite list" title="(AP Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>(AP Photo)</figcaption>
<p>Virat Kohli has achieved a new milestone in his cricket career by becoming only the second player to feature in 100 or more international matches against Australia, a record that was previously held by Sachin Tendulkar.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kohli has played 28 Tests, 49 ODIs, and 23 T20Is against Australia.</li>
    <li>He has scored 5326 runs in 117 innings, with an average of 50.24, including 17 centuries and 27 half-centuries.</li>
    <li>Sachin Tendulkar played 39 Tests and 71 ODIs against Australia, amassing 3630 runs in Tests and 3077 runs in ODIs.</li>
    <li>Other notable players who have played over 80 matches against Australia include Desmond Haynes, MS Dhoni, and Vivian Richards.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Records are meant to be broken when Virat Kohli steps onto the field.”</blockquote>
<p>This achievement reinforces Kohli's status as one of the greats in cricket, continuing a legacy that includes legendary players like Sachin Tendulkar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxNZDdjNHdtSzk3UDV2LVRrMU80OFkxa1FFRF9Lb191aUlmeDVodUU3WG15SUtpdVFvUHdmcElydHJDd2UzUUQ4SGRRRUFnNXBlUzNIdnByRnVzSjBMT3dNRklNY2QzZmV5UUxrTHBTYm9YY1lJR2lOelVub2pqWlpVR19WOThXc05IaWxmMUt5a3dDc2xleVNuMWZ2NzdFWXREMXZHcVp5Yl8xbkhwaktyc1ZJdUp1ZlBIMWVuYS00MU10eVNXTS1EVVJheTRvU0hLa2NsbmFTWVRhWU52UXFHZTk3WGQxaG1zYnZWeXVxNDBMZXUtdVZsMzJNeFVGcXRf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxNZDdjNHdtSzk3UDV2LVRrMU80OFkxa1FFRF9Lb191aUlmeDVodUU3WG15SUtpdVFvUHdmcElydHJDd2UzUUQ4SGRRRUFnNXBlUzNIdnByRnVzSjBMT3dNRklNY2QzZmV5UUxrTHBTYm9YY1lJR2lOelVub2pqWlpVR19WOThXc05IaWxmMUt5a3dDc2xleVNuMWZ2NzdFWXREMXZHcVp5Yl8xbkhwaktyc1ZJdUp1ZlBIMWVuYS00MU10eVNXTS1EVVJheTRvU0hLa2NsbmFTWVRhWU52UXFHZTk3WGQxaG1zYnZWeXVxNDBMZXUtdVZsMzJNeFVGcXRf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi FM joins Arab, US diplomats to discuss Syria’s future - Arab News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saudi FM joins Arab, US diplomats to discuss Syria’s future</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Arab News</p>
<img src="https://www.arabnews.pk/sites/default/files/pictures/December/2999496/2024/syria_3_1.jpg" alt="Turkey's Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan" width="1200" height="707">
<figcaption>Turkey's Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan, left, speaks with US Secretary of State Antony Blinken during a meeting with the foreign ministers of the Arab Contact Group on Syria in Jordan's southern Red Sea coastal city of Aqaba, on Dec. 14, 2024. (AP)</figcaption>
<p>Top diplomats from the United States, Turkiye, the European Union, and Arab nations convened in Aqaba, Jordan, to discuss Syria's political future and the transition from President Bashar Assad's regime.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The meeting involved key players including US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan, and foreign ministers from various Arab nations.</li>
    <li>The focal point of discussions was the future of Syria and ensuring a political process that is inclusive and respects minority rights.</li>
    <li>Turkiye confirmed the resumption of its embassy operations in Damascus, indicating a major shift in its diplomatic stance.</li>
    <li>Russian and Iranian diplomats, Assad's primary supporters, were notably absent from the talks.</li>
    <li>Diplomats expressed concern over the importance of preventing a sectarian partition of Syria.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"It is a time of both opportunity but also real challenge for Syria." - Antony Blinken</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the meeting marks a significant step in international efforts to shape Syria's political landscape post-Assad, with a strong emphasis on collaboration among involved nations to support a stable and inclusive governance structure in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.arabnews.com/node/2583018/middle-east</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.arabnews.com/node/2583018/middle-east</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:54:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saira Banu recalls Raj Kapoor kneeling before Dilip Kumar after their marriage, shares Dilip Kumar's emot - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wJBVV95cUxQeXNibUVDWkFZWlZuaXJiX1lGLXRvbkJCVW5BVEFoRWdxTUJoS2tZSGp2bTFjOFhpMjBSSjFRM0xFb05lVEFrX3FUM0M2OUtKcGdNRGYwNEc1cS1rZ044V2dnR21QZXdCUFkxYlhQWWRYUXhiaGk3RDlwWUlQemVNR3RqQU9MWU5IVnFkem5UV2RUX1dyY0VRV3JSa2M3cDlYNjU3THhhQ2Q3dElRcVF3bFVhVnVZNXZPS2I1NWF4WmI5WXBydzBxOHVzaGI4dGMwc05mTXpILS1YNlRMYnVpNWozVllJeURSVmI5UVdJYWx6ZThSWmRwa21seDd2bjhqLU04djdHcVpYT0NCSnN1Y19yQXpGUmVsNU9fVGRwelJfVDZmOVppMkxMenpodDBYSmNwekJFbWpGTHdHQmo1STkteWlWSDROWkV6dVRKZ3ZPVDRmTUZuYWhuWUZmcFU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wJBVV95cUxQeXNibUVDWkFZWlZuaXJiX1lGLXRvbkJCVW5BVEFoRWdxTUJoS2tZSGp2bTFjOFhpMjBSSjFRM0xFb05lVEFrX3FUM0M2OUtKcGdNRGYwNEc1cS1rZ044V2dnR21QZXdCUFkxYlhQWWRYUXhiaGk3RDlwWUlQemVNR3RqQU9MWU5IVnFkem5UV2RUX1dyY0VRV3JSa2M3cDlYNjU3THhhQ2Q3dElRcVF3bFVhVnVZNXZPS2I1NWF4WmI5WXBydzBxOHVzaGI4dGMwc05mTXpILS1YNlRMYnVpNWozVllJeURSVmI5UVdJYWx6ZThSWmRwa21seDd2bjhqLU04djdHcVpYT0NCSnN1Y19yQXpGUmVsNU9fVGRwelJfVDZmOVppMkxMenpodDBYSmNwekJFbWpGTHdHQmo1STkteWlWSDROWkV6dVRKZ3ZPVDRmTUZuYWhuWUZmcFU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive: Russia pulling back but not out of Syria, sources say - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/russia-pulling-back-not-out-syria-sources-say-2024-12-14/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/russia-pulling-back-not-out-syria-sources-say-2024-12-14/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:33:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 3rd Test, Day 2, Brisbane weather forecast: Will it rain once again at the Gabba? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia 3rd Test, Day 2, Brisbane weather forecast: Will it rain once again at the Gabba?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/AP12-14-2024-000001B-1_1734185162562_1734185183645.jpg" alt="General view of covers on the pitch as it rain during play on day one.(AP)" title="General view of covers on the pitch as it rain during play on day one.(AP)">
<figcaption>General view of covers on the pitch as it rain during play on day one.(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Day 1 of the ongoing third Test match between India and Australia was severely affected by rain, leading to only 13.2 overs being played. The forecast for Day 2 suggests further rain could disrupt play.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Day 1 was cut short at the Gabba, with only 13.2 overs played due to rain.</li>
    <li>India's captain, Rohit Sharma, chose to bowl after winning the toss. The Australian openers ended the day unbeaten.</li>
    <li>Weather forecast indicates cloudy conditions and showers expected from 9 AM local time, lasting for about two hours.</li>
    <li>India has made changes to their lineup, including the inclusion of Ravindra Jadeja and Akash Deep.</li>
    <li>The visitors recently lost to Australia by 10 wickets in Adelaide, leveling the series at 1-1.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The temperature is expected to hover around 24-31 degrees Celsius on Day 2."</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing weather conditions and previous performances underscore the challenges both teams face as they strive for momentum in this closely contested series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-3rd-test-day-2-brisbane-weather-forecast-will-it-rain-once-again-at-the-gabba-101734184797805.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-3rd-test-day-2-brisbane-weather-forecast-will-it-rain-once-again-at-the-gabba-101734184797805.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:08:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 3rd Test Day 2 Hourly Weather Report: Brisbane Under 'Alert'. The Reason Is... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia 3rd Test Day 2 Hourly Weather Report: Brisbane Under 'Alert'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/24fkbgog_the-gabba-afp_625x300_14_December_24.jpg" title="India vs Australia 3rd Test Day 2 Hourly Weather Report: Brisbane Under 'Alert'. The Reason Is...">
<figcaption>Only 13.2 overs were bowled on Day 1 of the 3rd Test between India and Australia. © AFP</figcaption>
<p>Day 1 of the 3rd Test between India and Australia was heavily affected by rain, with only 13.2 overs played before the umpires called off play. The weather condition is expected to remain a concern on Day 2.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Day 1 saw Australia finishing at 28-0, with Khawaja 19 not out.</li>
    <li>Rain interruptions led to a half-hour delay, impacting play significantly.</li>
    <li>The Bureau of Meteorology issued a red alert for the region, warning of minor floods.</li>
    <li>Forecast predicts a medium chance of showers throughout Day 2.</li>
    <li>Play on Day 2 is set to start 30 minutes early, pending weather conditions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon." - Bureau of Meteorology</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, with adverse weather conditions continuing into Day 2, the match's progress remains uncertain, highlighting the challenges faced by both teams in adapting to the rain-affected play.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-3rd-test-day-2-hourly-weather-report-floods-expected-in-brisbane-7248416</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-3rd-test-day-2-hourly-weather-report-floods-expected-in-brisbane-7248416</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:02:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session LIVE: Citizenship Amendment Act reflects Mahatma Gandhi's vision, says PM Modi - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament Winter Session LIVE: ‘The slogan of 'garibi hatao' remained a jumla’, says PM Modi</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/PTI12-14-2024-RPT325B-0_1734185149495_1734185169474.jpg" alt="Parliament Session Live: Prime Minister Narendra Modi speaks in the Lok Sabha during the discussion on the 'glorious journey of 75 years of the India Constitution' in the ongoing Winter session of Parliament in New Delhi on Saturday." title="Parliament Session Live: Prime Minister Narendra Modi speaks in the Lok Sabha during the discussion on the 'glorious journey of 75 years of the India Constitution' in the ongoing Winter session of Parliament in New Delhi on Saturday." width="360" height="202" loading="lazy" decoding="async">
<figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi speaks in the Lok Sabha during the discussion on the 'glorious journey of 75 years of the India Constitution' in the ongoing Winter session of Parliament in New Delhi on Saturday.</figcaption>
<p>The Parliament Winter Session is currently underway, featuring debates on the Constitution. Prime Minister Narendra Modi addressed the Lok Sabha, making significant remarks about the government's achievements and criticizing the opposition.</p>
<ul>
    <li>PM Modi discussed the completion of 75 years of India's Constitution and highlighted his government's efforts towards financial inclusion.</li>
    <li>He claimed that the opposition lacks a true understanding of poverty and criticized the Congress Party's historical policies.</li>
    <li>Modi referred to the Congress' slogan "Garibi Hatao" as a mere political gimmick.</li>
    <li>He defended the Citizenship Amendment Act as embodying Mahatma Gandhi's vision for India.</li>
    <li>Debates featured critiques of past Congress leaders regarding their use of constitutional powers during their tenures.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>“The slogan of 'garibi hatao' remained a jumla”— PM Modi</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, PM Modi emphasized the importance of the Constitution as a unifying force for India, while engaging in sharp critiques against the Congress party's legacy and its responses to current socio-economic issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-constitution-debate-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-101734138429086.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-constitution-debate-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-101734138429086.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:59:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jr NTR shows solidarity with Allu Arjun over arrest for fan death during Pushpa 2 premiere - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jr NTR shows solidarity with Allu Arjun over arrest for fan death during Pushpa 2 premiere</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Jr_NTR_Allu_Arjun_1734182236705_1734182246673.jpg" alt="Jr NTR spoke to Allu Arjun over phone after he was released on interim bail." title="Jr NTR spoke to Allu Arjun over phone after he was released on interim bail.">
<figcaption>Jr NTR spoke to Allu Arjun over phone after he was released on interim bail.</figcaption>
<p>Jr NTR, while filming in Mumbai, reached out to Allu Arjun following his release on interim bail concerning a tragic incident during the Pushpa 2 premiere, where a fan died due to asphyxiation.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Allu Arjun was arrested in connection with a fan's death at the Pushpa 2 premiere and was released on interim bail.</li>
    <li>Numerous Tollywood celebrities, including Jr NTR and Vijay Deverakonda, showed support for Arjun after his return home.</li>
    <li>The stampede occurred as Arjun visited Sandhya Theatre for the film's premiere, causing chaos among fans.</li>
    <li>The police filed an FIR against Arjun and the theatre management, leading to his arrest.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Tarak is out of town and busy shooting... He called Allu Arjun as soon as he could once he heard that he was back home." - Source close to Jr NTR</blockquote>
<p>The incident highlights the intense fan fervor and the responsibilities of public figures in managing large crowds during events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/jr-ntr-shows-solidarity-to-allu-arjun-over-arrest-for-fan-death-during-pushpa-2-premiere-101734181577565.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/jr-ntr-shows-solidarity-to-allu-arjun-over-arrest-for-fan-death-during-pushpa-2-premiere-101734181577565.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:40:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weight-loss drugs are best for the rich, says liver doctor SK Sarin - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weight-loss drugs are best for the rich, says liver doctor SK Sarin</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Published By:</strong> Daphne Clarance</p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/dr-sk-sarin--director--institute-of-liver-and-biliary-sciences-143507514-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=mcUbaZzUnM6iPGKTrFAleXHjYF1T7M.x&amp;size=690:388" alt="Dr SK Sarin, Director, Institute of Liver and Biliary Sciences" width="690" height="388">
<figcaption>Dr SK Sarin, Director, Institute of Liver and Biliary Sciences at Agenda Aaj Tak event.</figcaption>
<p>Liver specialist Dr SK Sarin emphasized that popular weight-loss medications should only be used under strict medical supervision, warning that these drugs are primarily beneficial for the wealthy due to their high costs.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Dr Sarin advocates for healthier lifestyle choices over reliance on medications for weight loss.</li>
    <li>Weight-loss drugs like Ozempic (semaglutide) enhance metabolic processes but can lead to side effects.</li>
    <li>Dr Sarin believes exercise and an active lifestyle remain the best methods for weight management.</li>
    <li>Increased calorie intake can lead to serious health complications such as fatty liver disease.</li>
    <li>Weight-loss drugs may have significant side effects, including gastrointestinal issues and rapid weight regains.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The best method for most people is still to exercise, burn calories, and lead an active lifestyle.” - Dr SK Sarin</blockquote>
<blockquote>“These drugs are not a magic solution. Once you stop taking them, weight gain often resumes rapidly.” - Dr Naresh Trehan</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, both doctors underline the importance of sustainable lifestyle changes, as opposed to solely relying on weight-loss drugs which come with potential risks and complications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/health/story/weight-loss-drugs-ozempic-semaglutide-best-for-the-rich-liver-doctor-sk-sarin-dr-naresh-trehan-2649902-2024-12-14</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/health/story/weight-loss-drugs-ozempic-semaglutide-best-for-the-rich-liver-doctor-sk-sarin-dr-naresh-trehan-2649902-2024-12-14</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:32:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi's big attack on Cong over Emergency: ‘Constitution was torn apart, India turned into jail’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi's big attack on Cong over Emergency: ‘Constitution was torn apart, India turned into jail’</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Narendra_Modi_1734182037740_1734182037979.png" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi in the Lok Sabha.(Sansad TV)" title="Prime Minister Narendra Modi in the Lok Sabha.(Sansad TV)">
<figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi in the Lok Sabha.(Sansad TV)</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi criticized the Congress party over the imposition of Emergency in 1975, stating that it severely damaged the Constitution and civil liberties in India.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Modi referred to the Emergency as a time when "the Constitution was torn apart" and civil rights were suppressed.</li>
    <li>He claimed that under Congress rule, "all rights of the citizens were snatched" and there was significant media censorship.</li>
    <li>The Prime Minister specifically targeted the Gandhi family for their role in undermining the Constitution.</li>
    <li>He praised India's journey since the adoption of the Constitution, calling it "extraordinary" and emphasizing India as the "Mother of Democracy."</li>
    <li>Modi acknowledged the contributions of the Constitution makers and highlighted women's voting rights as a notable achievement.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “The Constitution was torn apart when it was completing 25 years; the Emergency was imposed (in 1975), all constitutional rights were snatched and the country was turned into a jail.” - PM Narendra Modi
</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Modi's statements reinforce the narrative of the Congress party's failures during the Emergency, while also celebrating the values and journey of Indian democracy since the Constitution's adoption.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modis-big-attack-on-cong-over-emergency-constitution-was-torn-apart-india-turned-into-jail-101734181201328.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modis-big-attack-on-cong-over-emergency-constitution-was-torn-apart-india-turned-into-jail-101734181201328.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli reacts to Kapil Dev’s offer of helping him, says, ‘I have no…’ - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli reacts to Kapil Dev’s offer of helping him, says, ‘I have no…’</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> DNA India</p>
<img src="https://cdn.dnaindia.com/sites/default/files/2024/12/14/2666863-image-2024-12-14t184716.403.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(1200,900)" alt="Vinod Kambli reacts to Kapil Dev’s offer of helping him, says, ‘I have no…’" title="Vinod Kambli reacts to Kapil Dev’s offer of helping him, says, ‘I have no…’">
<figcaption>Vinod Kambli acknowledges Kapil Dev's offer for rehabilitation support.</figcaption>
<p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli has responded positively to Kapil Dev's recently extended offer to assist him in entering rehab due to health and financial struggles.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kapil Dev, the captain of the 1983 World Cup-winning team, has offered to cover Kambli's rehab costs.</li>
    <li>Sunil Gavaskar has also shown support for Kambli, who has undergone rehab 14 times before.</li>
    <li>Kambli expressed gratitude towards his wife for managing their finances amid struggles.</li>
    <li>He confirmed his willingness to enter rehab, stating, “I will complete it and return. I will come back.”</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>"Bad (on his financial condition). But the manner in which my wife has handled everything, hats off to her... until I have my family with me, I'm not afraid of anything, anybody."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Kambli's situation has raised concern within the cricket community, prompting notable figures to offer their assistance and support.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/cricket/report-vinod-kambli-reacts-to-kapil-dev-s-offer-of-helping-him-says-i-have-no-hesitation-3122427</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/cricket/report-vinod-kambli-reacts-to-kapil-dev-s-offer-of-helping-him-says-i-have-no-hesitation-3122427</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan cricket: Controversial Amir retires from international stage - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/sports/2024/12/14/pakistan-cricket-controversial-amir-retires-from-international-stage</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/sports/2024/12/14/pakistan-cricket-controversial-amir-retires-from-international-stage</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:29:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session LIVE: PM Modi addresses Lok Sabha - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament Winter Session LIVE: ‘One family ruled for 55 years out of 75 years’, PM Modi's big attack on Congress</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Screenshot_2024-12-14_180611_1734181061356_1734181079130.png" alt="Parliament Session Live: Prime Minister Narendra Modi addresses the Lok Sabha during a debate on 75 years of India's Constitution." title="Parliament Session Live: Prime Minister Narendra Modi addresses the Lok Sabha during a debate on 75 years of India's Constitution." width="360" height="202" loading="lazy" decoding="async">
<figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi addresses the Lok Sabha during a debate on 75 years of India's Constitution.</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi delivered a powerful speech during the Lok Sabha debate, marking 75 years of India's Constitution, and launched a strong critique of the Congress party, accusing it of dynastic politics.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Modi claimed that one family ruled for 55 out of the 75 years of India's independence.</li>
    <li>He criticized former PM Rajiv Gandhi's overruling of the Shah Bano case, labeling it a violation of constitutional values.</li>
    <li>Modi stated that Indira Gandhi abused the Constitution during the National Emergency to preserve her power.</li>
    <li>He emphasized the need to uphold the Constitution as the foundation of national unity.</li>
    <li>Prime Minister highlighted women's significant role in the Constitution's formation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“One family ruled for 55 years out of 75 years,” PM Modi said, highlighting the impact of dynastic politics on democracy.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, PM Modi's address underscored the government's commitment to constitutional values amid ongoing political debates, revealing deep divisions in parliamentary discussions around the Constitution and its interpretation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-constitution-debate-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-101734138429086.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-constitution-debate-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-101734138429086.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:27:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Miss to Mrs! PV Sindhu gets engaged to Venkata Datta Sai. First Pic Out - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/badminton/miss-to-mrs-pv-sindhu-gets-engaged-to-venkata-datta-sai-first-pic-out/articleshow/116318325.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/badminton/miss-to-mrs-pv-sindhu-gets-engaged-to-venkata-datta-sai-first-pic-out/articleshow/116318325.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Industries appoints Ira Bindra as Group President for HR & Talent | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/reliance-industries-appoints-ira-bandra-as-group-president-for-hr-talent-11734177676716.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/reliance-industries-appoints-ira-bandra-as-group-president-for-hr-talent-11734177676716.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:05:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Captures Active Volcano Eruption On Jupiter's Moon Io, Ending 44-Year-Old Mystery | WATCH - Jagran English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Captures Active Volcano Eruption On Jupiter's Moon Io, Ending 44-Year-Old Mystery | WATCH</h1>

<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 12, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Jagran News</p>

<img src="https://imgeng.jagran.com/images/2024/12/14/article/image/NASA-(3)-1734177073397.jpg" alt="Jupiter's moon Io" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>Jupiter's moon Io (Image credits: NASA)</figcaption>

<p>NASA has made significant discoveries regarding Io, the most volcanically active body in our solar system, providing answers to longstanding questions about its volcanic activity.</p>

<ul>
    <li>NASA's Juno mission revealed that Io’s volcanoes are powered by individual magma chambers, not a global magma ocean.</li>
    <li>The findings end a 44-year-old mystery regarding the intense geological activity of Io.</li>
    <li>Observations indicate that Io's volcanic activity is influenced by its unique orbit around Jupiter, causing heat through gravitational interactions.</li>
    <li>New high-resolution images show volcanic features and fresh lava flows on Io's surface.</li>
    <li>Juno completed its 66th flyby over Jupiter and is scheduled for its next close approach in late December 2024.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>“Not very demure at all. But Jupiter's moon Io is still beautiful, constantly erupting volcanoes and all.” – NASA Solar System</blockquote>

<p>NASA continues to enhance our understanding of volcanic processes beyond Earth, contributing to broader knowledge of planetary geology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://english.jagran.com/world/nasa-captures-active-volcano-eruption-on-jupiters-moon-io-ending-44yearold-mystery-watch-10206818</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://english.jagran.com/world/nasa-captures-active-volcano-eruption-on-jupiters-moon-io-ending-44yearold-mystery-watch-10206818</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Protest erupts in Kolkata after Ex-RG Kar principal gets bail in rape case - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/protest-erupts-after-ex-rg-kar-principal-given-bail-in-trainee-doctor-rape-case-101734176814188.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/protest-erupts-after-ex-rg-kar-principal-given-bail-in-trainee-doctor-rape-case-101734176814188.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:46:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two power centres are recipe for disaster, says J-K Chief Minister Omar Abdullah - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxOdXJXb1ByMVdPV0hvN1o1VVk0Mm9zLTRCbk9rbHR0UG1weGZHc1hzY3ZIUmtzSkNYVmtlSWtJNXJGTnNHSUJXSWhJRnFjVzZkM082TkV4eFAwbWNWNWZZblpMeDhNSUx1RlZ2MF8tTWFPS3lLVkV3Z3VhbVNxRG5EdjZEU1cwQzRMMVpFMHdMRUNsMmpvdlhrSzNXYTFUV0UteVRvVXpSeFF4QUVMUGJwa1RHYkVnZm9KTXB2RzJHcGXSAcYBQVVfeXFMT1hyTnNHcXR4bzNhcFJsT2JoQ1hxSWgwNkxjT0ppVTZ6c3NRLUpVeFdVUnZvaUg5ODVKaFhyTkgxNlk2bmJManZPSzByM0NKbmZwdzFpLVYtYnU2ZXB6WUx3cy1MTmJKQUhNLXJjRm8xNFN0bmxsbzROTGRrcWtIcDVzajVOUENXOEQ2dFB3ZlFrX2NvVXlYSmMxVmR2cm5QeWMtRkc1bERUTlA3NW43dWM1NHZlVnZpNWgtRnJ5VnZhb3ZKTGl3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxOdXJXb1ByMVdPV0hvN1o1VVk0Mm9zLTRCbk9rbHR0UG1weGZHc1hzY3ZIUmtzSkNYVmtlSWtJNXJGTnNHSUJXSWhJRnFjVzZkM082TkV4eFAwbWNWNWZZblpMeDhNSUx1RlZ2MF8tTWFPS3lLVkV3Z3VhbVNxRG5EdjZEU1cwQzRMMVpFMHdMRUNsMmpvdlhrSzNXYTFUV0UteVRvVXpSeFF4QUVMUGJwa1RHYkVnZm9KTXB2RzJHcGXSAcYBQVVfeXFMT1hyTnNHcXR4bzNhcFJsT2JoQ1hxSWgwNkxjT0ppVTZ6c3NRLUpVeFdVUnZvaUg5ODVKaFhyTkgxNlk2bmJManZPSzByM0NKbmZwdzFpLVYtYnU2ZXB6WUx3cy1MTmJKQUhNLXJjRm8xNFN0bmxsbzROTGRrcWtIcDVzajVOUENXOEQ2dFB3ZlFrX2NvVXlYSmMxVmR2cm5QeWMtRkc1bERUTlA3NW43dWM1NHZlVnZpNWgtRnJ5VnZhb3ZKTGl3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:46:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session LIVE: BJP says ‘Rahul Gandhi insulted Constitution when he tore UPA bill’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament Winter Session LIVE: PM Modi to address Lok Sabha shortly</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/narendra_modi_purvodaya_plan_budget__1721789411358_1734178334855.jpg" alt="Parliament Session Live: Prime Minister Narendra Modi to address the Lok Sabha during a debate on 75 years of India's Constitution. (File image)" title="Parliament Session Live: Prime Minister Narendra Modi to address the Lok Sabha during a debate on 75 years of India's Constitution. (File image)" width="360" height="202" loading="lazy" decoding="async">
<figcaption>Parliament Session Live: Prime Minister Narendra Modi to address the Lok Sabha during a debate on 75 years of India's Constitution. (File image)</figcaption>
<p>The Parliament Winter Session is underway, with Prime Minister Modi set to address the Lok Sabha shortly amidst ongoing debates on the Constitution's 75th anniversary. Various members of the opposition have been vocal about their concerns during this special session.</p>
<ul>
    <li>PM Modi will speak on the second and final day of the Constitution debate initiated in Lok Sabha.</li>
    <li>Priyanka Gandhi Vadra made her maiden speech criticizing the ruling government on multiple issues.</li>
    <li>The opposition has been vocal in defending the Constitution and criticizing the BJP's policies.</li>
    <li>Congress members protested the alleged vandalization of a replica of the Constitution.</li>
    <li>The Winter Session began in November and will conclude on December 20.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Constitution is the protective shield of justice, unity, and freedom of expression.” - Priyanka Gandhi Vadra</blockquote>
<p>The session highlights intense political exchanges and critical discussions on the Constitution, emphasizing the significance of democratic values in India. Prime Minister Modi's upcoming address is highly anticipated amidst this heated political environment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-constitution-debate-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-101734138429086.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-constitution-debate-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-101734138429086.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:44:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>