<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 08:24:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 08:24:50 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What's Getting Cheaper And Costlier Post GST Council Meeting? Check Full List - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What's Getting Cheaper And Costlier Post GST Council Meeting? Check Full List</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2024/12/gst-council-55th-meeting-nirmala-sitharaman-2024-12-775ea7aa39ac93966584040ad4bbecfb.jpeg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="FM Nirmala Sitharaman addresses media after the GST Council meeting on December 21, 2024" title="FM Nirmala Sitharaman addresses media after the GST Council meeting on December 21, 2024"><figcaption>FM Nirmala Sitharaman addresses media after the GST Council meeting on December 21, 2024</figcaption><p>The GST Council has recommended several changes to GST rates aimed at reducing tax burdens in various sectors.</p><ul><li>Reduction in GST on Fortified Rice Kernel (FRK) to 5%.</li><li>Full exemption of GST on gene therapy.</li><li>Exemption on contributions to the Motor Vehicle Accident Fund.</li><li>No GST on transactions involving vouchers.</li><li>Clarification that penal charges by banks and NBFCs are not subject to GST.</li><li>Reduction in pre-deposit for appeals related to penalty amounts.</li></ul><blockquote>"The recommendations focus on simplifying tax processes and making essential services more accessible."</blockquote><p>This meeting's recommendations aim to provide relief to individuals and streamline compliance in the tax system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/tax/55th-gst-council-meeting-recommendations-cheaper-expensive-items-9164536.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/tax/55th-gst-council-meeting-recommendations-cheaper-expensive-items-9164536.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:49:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4-Year-Old Boy Run Over By Speeding Creta In Mumbai, Teen Driver Arrested - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOXzh6WHFwRE9fTzdsY2owT0szWmNhNVRBb2NRUzQ4eHVLV3ZoTzVzTk5nLXloR2R5LW9FXzBpaDV1c0RKLUliZ3c2R0pDdS1KYWxvS0MyMVZmNW9pMElDbWFQMldOaS0zRHREd0h3cXYxN0xRcXUxcEhvZUgtRklaTk1CSzNwME1VdE9jbUEtMXlXa0Q2Tmt4Q0s1ZnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOXzh6WHFwRE9fTzdsY2owT0szWmNhNVRBb2NRUzQ4eHVLV3ZoTzVzTk5nLXloR2R5LW9FXzBpaDV1c0RKLUliZ3c2R0pDdS1KYWxvS0MyMVZmNW9pMElDbWFQMldOaS0zRHREd0h3cXYxN0xRcXUxcEhvZUgtRklaTk1CSzNwME1VdE9jbUEtMXlXa0Q2Tmt4Q0s1ZnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:39:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Document verification, door-to-door checking': Delhi Police begins crackdown on illegal Bangladeshi immi - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Document verification, door-to-door checking: Delhi Police begins crackdown on illegal Bangladeshi immigrants</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>2023-10-20 <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><p>Delhi Police has initiated a comprehensive operation targeting illegal Bangladeshi immigrants through document verification and door-to-door checks.</p><ul><li>The operation aims to identify and detain individuals living in the city without proper documentation.</li><li>Police teams are conducting checks in identified hotspots known for housing illegal immigrants.</li><li>Community engagement is emphasized to facilitate reporting of suspected illegal residents.</li><li>The crackdown is part of a larger initiative to enhance law and order in the region.</li></ul><blockquote>“We urge the community to cooperate and report any suspicious individuals to maintain public safety,” a police spokesperson stated.</blockquote><p>This operation is designed to address the growing concerns about illegal immigration and its impact on security and public resources.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/document-verification-door-to-door-checking-delhi-police-begins-crackdown-on-illegal-bangladeshi-immigrants/articleshow/116559785.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/document-verification-door-to-door-checking-delhi-police-begins-crackdown-on-illegal-bangladeshi-immigrants/articleshow/116559785.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA, SpaceX to launch IMAP heliophysics mission in September 2025 - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA and SpaceX to Launch IMAP Mission in September 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> News9 Live</p><img width="802" height="464" src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/NASA-IMAP.jpg?w=802&amp;enlarge=true" alt="Illustration of the IMAP spacecraft. (Image Credit: NASA)." title="NASA IMAP"><figcaption>Illustration of the IMAP spacecraft. (Image Credit: NASA).</figcaption><p>Nasa and SpaceX are now aiming for the launch of the Interstellar Mapping and Acceleration Probe (IMAP) spacecraft in September 2025. The revised schedule allows for better preparation for the mission, which will explore the heliosphere and provide insights into energetic particles that affect human space exploration.</p><ul><li>IMAP will analyze and map particles streaming toward Earth from the heliosphere.</li><li>In addition to IMAP, two other heliophysics observatories will launch in 2025.</li><li>The observatories will help monitor solar activity and its effects on Earth.</li><li>All missions are targeted for the first Lagrange point (L1) for efficient monitoring of the Sun.</li></ul><blockquote>“These energetic particles can impact human explorers in flares, damage hardware, and is believed to play a role in the presence of life in the universe.”</blockquote><p>The launch will utilize a Falcon 9 rocket from Cape Canaveral Space Force Station, streamlining the process for deploying multiple missions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/nasa-spacex-to-launch-imap-heliophysics-mission-in-september-2025-2779268</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/nasa-spacex-to-launch-imap-heliophysics-mission-in-september-2025-2779268</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:06:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘We can bury anyone’: Private texts reveal Justin Baldoni's 'untraceable' plan to 'destroy' Blake Lively's reputation - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Private Messages Reveal Justin Baldoni's Alleged Plan Against Blake Lively</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 22, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Blake-Lively-and-Justin-Baldoni-01-2024_1734850046879_1734850186400.webp" alt="Blake Lively and Justin Baldoni starred together in It Ends With Us." title="Blake Lively and Justin Baldoni starred together in It Ends With Us."><figcaption>Blake Lively and Justin Baldoni starred together in It Ends With Us.</figcaption><p>Blake Lively has filed a lawsuit against co-star Justin Baldoni, alleging sexual harassment and a campaign to damage her reputation after she accused him of inappropriate conduct during filming.</p><ul><li>Lively's lawsuit reveals private text messages suggesting Baldoni's intent to orchestrate a smear campaign.</li><li>Baldoni discussed plans with publicists and a crisis management expert about how to handle potential fallout from the lawsuit.</li><li>The lawsuit demands measures to ensure a respectful work environment, citing multiple inappropriate behaviors by Baldoni.</li></ul><blockquote>“We can’t write we will destroy her” - Melissa Nathan on plans discussed with Baldoni.</blockquote><p>This situation has drawn significant media attention, highlighting the serious allegations of misconduct in the entertainment industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/private-texts-reveal-justin-baldonis-untraceable-plan-to-destroy-blake-livelys-reputation-it-ends-with-us-101734849957950.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/private-texts-reveal-justin-baldonis-untraceable-plan-to-destroy-blake-livelys-reputation-it-ends-with-us-101734849957950.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Faster walkers’ had significantly lower risk of diabetes, hypertension: Study - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Faster Walkers Have Lower Risk of Diabetes and Hypertension, Study Reveals</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p><p>This study reveals that individuals with faster walking speeds are at a significantly lower risk of metabolic conditions like diabetes and hypertension. Conducted by researchers from Japan, the findings suggest that even those with obesity can reduce their risks by improving their walking pace.</p><ol><li>Study involved nearly 25,000 participants with obesity or high waist circumference.</li><li>Faster walkers showed approximately 30% lower risk of diabetes.</li><li>Notable reductions were also observed in hypertension and dyslipidemia risks.</li><li>The findings link walking speed to overall health, particularly cardiorespiratory fitness.</li><li>Subjective walking speed could be easily integrated into health assessments.</li><li>Study emphasizes the value of promoting faster walking as a preventative measure for metabolic diseases.</li></ol><blockquote>“This study clarified that even individuals with obesity, who are at higher risk for metabolic diseases, have lower odds of hypertension, diabetes mellitus, and dyslipidemia if they report a fast subjective walking speed.” - Kojiro Ishii, lead researcher</blockquote><p>The study indicates that quick assessments of walking speed can help identify individuals at risk for metabolic disorders, particularly beneficial in healthcare settings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/health/faster-walkers-had-significantly-lower-risk-of-diabetes-hypertension-study/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/health/faster-walkers-had-significantly-lower-risk-of-diabetes-hypertension-study/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:49:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Speeding Creta SUV Kills Boy, 4, In Mumbai, Teen Driver Arrested - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>4-Year-Old Boy Run Over By Speeding Creta In Mumbai, Teen Driver Arrested</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9anvhfng_mumbai-accident_625x300_22_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="4-Year-Old Boy Run Over By Speeding Creta In Mumbai, Teen Driver Arrested"><figcaption>A four-year-old boy was killed in a tragic road accident in Mumbai.</figcaption><p>A four-year-old boy, Ayush Laxman Kinvade, has tragically lost his life after being struck by a speeding car driven by a teenager in Mumbai. The accident occurred near Ambedkar College in Wadala.</p><ul><li>The driver of the vehicle, Sandeep Gole, is a 19-year-old resident of Vile Parle.</li><li>The boy's family lives on the footpath, and the father is a worker.</li><li>This incident follows another serious accident in Kurla which resulted in seven deaths and numerous injuries.</li><li>From 2018-2022, Maharashtra reported 66,370 road accident fatalities, ranking among the highest in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“More than 7 lakh people have died across India in road accidents in the 2018-2022 period,” according to the Union Ministry of Road Transport and Highways.</blockquote><p>The tragic loss of Ayush Kinvade highlights ongoing issues with road safety in Mumbai and the urgent need for traffic regulations and enforcement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/speeding-car-kills-boy-4-in-mumbai-teen-driver-arrested-7306187</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/speeding-car-kills-boy-4-in-mumbai-teen-driver-arrested-7306187</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:31:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When devices can read human emotions without a camera: Study - Kalinga TV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxPZVdQNFp1ZU1mRTlfTzlfWU0xWFRIb2laZUxnQzNJdEJndWNNUTludmZfWWgxLWRrd0dXZ3V2Z0wyT2ozUF92U3pNNk9DejVGZUlDV2drN2hpYy1pejQyVUQ0dGpJVTUxZW5ReTVoNURsSldZRnpUNEtETHEyMlFsckROaW42TUd3ZDYyUFFEdDJhYWtRSGpzcw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxPZVdQNFp1ZU1mRTlfTzlfWU0xWFRIb2laZUxnQzNJdEJndWNNUTludmZfWWgxLWRrd0dXZ3V2Z0wyT2ozUF92U3pNNk9DejVGZUlDV2drN2hpYy1pejQyVUQ0dGpJVTUxZW5ReTVoNURsSldZRnpUNEtETHEyMlFsckROaW42TUd3ZDYyUFFEdDJhYWtRSGpzcw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:08:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohali building collapse: Body of man found, death toll climbs to two - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohali building collapse: Body of man found, death toll climbs to two</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ku93p/article69015163.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_22_2024_000033A.jpg" alt="Rescue operation continues after a multi-storey building collapsed in Mohali" title="Rescue operation continues after a multi-storey building collapsed in Mohali"><figcaption>Rescue operation continues after a multi-storey building collapsed in Mohali.</figcaption><p>The death toll in the Mohali building collapse rose to two as rescue operations continue. At least five people are feared trapped under the rubble following the collapse.</p><ul><li>The multi-storey building in Sohana village collapsed on the evening of December 21, 2024.</li><li>Rescue efforts involve National Disaster Response Team (NDRF), the Indian Army, and local state rescue teams.</li><li>An initial report suggests the collapse may have been caused by excavation work on an adjacent plot.</li><li>Major hospitals in Mohali were put on alert to handle potential casualties.</li><li>Two building owners have been booked in connection to the incident.</li></ul><blockquote>“Engineer Task Force with debris clearance machine & JCBs are operational at site,” Western Command, Indian Army.</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical as rescue teams work tirelessly to locate any more survivors under the debris.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/punjab/mohali-building-collapse-death-toll-rises-updates-december-22/article69015159.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/punjab/mohali-building-collapse-death-toll-rises-updates-december-22/article69015159.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13R vs. OnePlus 12R: Biggest expected upgrades - Tom's Guide]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMif0FVX3lxTFBFQzRkeGstRVczemdnZnFLeU1XZUt2OWt1WWt0RTBZVHIyVzljRHhRajBDcVIzSHdGbVFfbjBwRmZ2Z3hULTV4RkNsZUllaXlTVFk1OHNEbTJ5b0dxLV9KZENVbDR1dVY5WThzTWhPd1J1X2ZsUjRBR3N1TWVZa1k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMif0FVX3lxTFBFQzRkeGstRVczemdnZnFLeU1XZUt2OWt1WWt0RTBZVHIyVzljRHhRajBDcVIzSHdGbVFfbjBwRmZ2Z3hULTV4RkNsZUllaXlTVFk1OHNEbTJ5b0dxLV9KZENVbDR1dVY5WThzTWhPd1J1X2ZsUjRBR3N1TWVZa1k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:04:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ursid Meteor Shower Peaks: Here's how to watch the final celestial show of 2024 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxOakJ1OUZRVjVaOEo1WEtMaTZPMzdWSnIzMHNxU1B2UmFRRWJBUFp1OS1vbUlaZEM2WV9maUpMdF9RU29lMHl2Q2g3Z0NrS2prd2otZmo3UUNBOUE1a3VVOGdCVVJjM1NicnA4ellheGdIRmZBQ1MxTmRBTFpoUE1nbVlLMV80ZFFjVnQ5eVdKYXNlWDZ5ajdXNXpGeVBEdUEwajJ2OGZzc3I4RnhhNkQ1LWo5Y0NZei1Sc1NZckNUWTFOcjl1d29CZWFVYk5JM3FYNWwwTUNzYVFFQ0NhR19kSVUxQ2NZV3JxUFRGYlJVX0J6Z0tUX1cw0gH8AUFVX3lxTE5fbWROVnlNT3VwVzhEdUIwLWxBNnJ6LVVNZWF2OWFyRHpkbVJvb05TVE5qZ2toOWUtbTdHYl9SQktVSWNBTV9BTUZLb0RnZHVUeDZQMDZfQjl0YWVhcWVqVzZBbmk3UEdTQ0JrN3NlQkNvRFBjR25PTlliLWtaa1hLUlVuYWR2M3F5bXR4Q21Ba0FWek0yeU1UR3ptcHZaQ0FPUzdaX2x5X2xNbE5UckJQMGtaamp4bzE5MU9OUTl3RlNPdnFaY1ZCNWJWOVNWSmdPTmdyNTFNZUN6d0o2ckZGSXo1YVNfaTlGYnllWnRUWTU1U0d0NlRORXZERg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxOakJ1OUZRVjVaOEo1WEtMaTZPMzdWSnIzMHNxU1B2UmFRRWJBUFp1OS1vbUlaZEM2WV9maUpMdF9RU29lMHl2Q2g3Z0NrS2prd2otZmo3UUNBOUE1a3VVOGdCVVJjM1NicnA4ellheGdIRmZBQ1MxTmRBTFpoUE1nbVlLMV80ZFFjVnQ5eVdKYXNlWDZ5ajdXNXpGeVBEdUEwajJ2OGZzc3I4RnhhNkQ1LWo5Y0NZei1Sc1NZckNUWTFOcjl1d29CZWFVYk5JM3FYNWwwTUNzYVFFQ0NhR19kSVUxQ2NZV3JxUFRGYlJVX0J6Z0tUX1cw0gH8AUFVX3lxTE5fbWROVnlNT3VwVzhEdUIwLWxBNnJ6LVVNZWF2OWFyRHpkbVJvb05TVE5qZ2toOWUtbTdHYl9SQktVSWNBTV9BTUZLb0RnZHVUeDZQMDZfQjl0YWVhcWVqVzZBbmk3UEdTQ0JrN3NlQkNvRFBjR25PTlliLWtaa1hLUlVuYWR2M3F5bXR4Q21Ba0FWek0yeU1UR3ptcHZaQ0FPUzdaX2x5X2xNbE5UckJQMGtaamp4bzE5MU9OUTl3RlNPdnFaY1ZCNWJWOVNWSmdPTmdyNTFNZUN6d0o2ckZGSXo1YVNfaTlGYnllWnRUWTU1U0d0NlRORXZERg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:57:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Warns Of Big 120-ft Asteroid To Come Alarmingly Close To Earth On Christmas Eve: Will It Hit? - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Warns Of Big 120-ft Asteroid To Come Alarmingly Close To Earth On Christmas Eve: Will It Hit?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116556654,thumbsize-106690,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116556654.jpg" alt="Asteroid" title="Asteroid"><figcaption>Asteroid 2024 XN1</figcaption><p>This Christmas Eve, NASA has identified a fast-moving asteroid named 2024 XN1, measuring 120 feet across, which will make a close pass by Earth.</p><ul><li>The asteroid is expected to pass on December 24 at 8:27 am IST.</li><li>2024 XN1 will come within 7,220,000 kilometres of Earth.</li><li>It is traveling at a speed of 23,729 km/h.</li><li>This asteroid is not considered a threat as it is smaller than 150 meters and passes outside of hazardous range.</li><li>NASA monitors asteroids using a network of telescopes and the NEOWISE space telescope.</li></ul><blockquote>“Thanks to NASA’s vigilant tracking system, asteroid 2024 XN1’s flyby will be just another fascinating celestial event — nothing to fear!”</blockquote><p>This event serves as a reminder of the importance of monitoring near-Earth objects for potential threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/nasa-warns-of-big-120-ft-asteroid-to-come-alarmingly-close-to-earth-on-christmas-eve-will-it-hit-article-116556590</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/nasa-warns-of-big-120-ft-asteroid-to-come-alarmingly-close-to-earth-on-christmas-eve-will-it-hit-article-116556590</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA payload to study the effects of Lunar dust on mission equipment - Space Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/NASA_payload_to_study_the_effects_of_Lunar_dust_on_mission_equipment_999.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/NASA_payload_to_study_the_effects_of_Lunar_dust_on_mission_equipment_999.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:28:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BSNL eSIM to be Available by March 2025 - TelecomTalk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BSNL to Launch eSIM Services by March 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Telecom Talk</p><p><img src="https://telecomtalk.info/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bsnl-esim-to-be-available-by-march.png.webp" alt="bsnl esim to be available by march" /><figcaption>BSNL eSIM announcement</figcaption></p><p>Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL), a state-run Indian telecom company, is set to launch eSIM services by March 2025. Currently, eSIM services are provided by Reliance Jio, Bharti Airtel, and Vodafone Idea, but the market in India remains small due to limited device compatibility.</p><ul><li>BSNL's introduction of eSIM services marks a modernization of its network.</li><li>The company aims to roll out its 4G services nationally by June 2025.</li><li>BSNL has partnered with BCG (Boston Consulting Group) to improve its profitability and service offerings.</li></ul><blockquote>“BSNL is in the process of rolling out 4G services pan India, and the process is likely to be completed by June 2025,” said Sandeep Govil, director consumer mobility, BSNL board.</blockquote><p>This initiative is expected to improve customer access to high-speed network services at competitive tariffs, but BSNL faces challenges in matching the coverage level of private networks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidkFVX3lxTE1hbkIyZW9tM2xBM2hqT2Z6UTVlZElpV3I0dHRLR2xZem9ldWxOcDRpQW9lQzh2d2lIQ0l2eWZJa3NOOVg5Zm1Tc2hfdURma3hQN1VhTFIyUEVRZ05yeFc4VmZ3NFFPNWJneFBPNmtDdEZ1a3VPV0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidkFVX3lxTE1hbkIyZW9tM2xBM2hqT2Z6UTVlZElpV3I0dHRLR2xZem9ldWxOcDRpQW9lQzh2d2lIQ0l2eWZJa3NOOVg5Zm1Tc2hfdURma3hQN1VhTFIyUEVRZ05yeFc4VmZ3NFFPNWJneFBPNmtDdEZ1a3VPV0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:27:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man in flames walks 600m for help after Jaipur tanker blast, bystanders shoot videos - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jaipur-gas-tanker-blast-man-with-85-burns-walks-600-metres-for-help-but-bystanders-shoot-videos-101734842465539.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jaipur-gas-tanker-blast-man-with-85-burns-walks-600-metres-for-help-but-bystanders-shoot-videos-101734842465539.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:26:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AIIMS Doctors In Process Of Developing Low-Cost Cellular Therapy For Multiple Myeloma - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AIIMS Doctors In Process Of Developing Low-Cost Cellular Therapy For Multiple Myeloma</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: Times Now</strong></p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116557705,thumbsize-23758,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116557705.jpg" alt="AIIMS Doctors In Process Of Developing Low-Cost Cellular Therapy For Multiple Myeloma" title="AIIMS Doctors In Process Of Developing Low-Cost Cellular Therapy For Multiple Myeloma"><figcaption>Image Credits: iStock</figcaption><p>Doctors at AIIMS, Delhi, are developing a cost-effective antibody-based adaptive cellular therapy for treating multiple myeloma, aiming to make advanced treatments like CAR-T cell therapy more affordable for Indian patients.</p><ul><li>The therapy targets B-cell maturation antigen (BCMA) in multiple myeloma cells.</li><li>Research shows promising results in animal models, with plans for phase-1 clinical trials ahead.</li><li>Current CAR-T cell therapies are prohibitively expensive in India.</li><li>According to the National Cancer Registry, India had 14,61,427 new cancer cases in 2022, highlighting the need for accessible treatment options.</li></ul><blockquote>“Immunotherapies have the potential to transform cancer treatment, but their high cost limits their reach. Our work at AIIMS is focused on addressing this gap by developing affordable alternatives.” - Dr. Mayank Singh</blockquote><p>The progress made by AIIMS researchers is a hopeful step towards improving cancer treatment accessibility in India, particularly for multiple myeloma patients.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/health/aiims-doctors-in-process-of-developing-low-cost-cellular-therapy-for-multiple-myeloma-article-116557713</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/health/aiims-doctors-in-process-of-developing-low-cost-cellular-therapy-for-multiple-myeloma-article-116557713</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:15:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer: Ram Charan, SJ Suryah wow fans in Dallas with energetic dance moves - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer: Ram Charan, SJ Suryah wow fans in Dallas with energetic dance moves</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 22, 2024</strong> by Latest Telugu cinema news</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Game-Changer-2.jpg" alt="Ram Charan and SJ Suryah at the Game Changer event"><figcaption>Ram Charan and SJ Suryah captivating the audience during their performance.</figcaption><p>In Dallas, Ram Charan and SJ Suryah electrified fans with a dynamic dance performance at the promotional event for their upcoming film, Game Changer. The film, directed by Shankar Shanmugam, is set for release on January 10, 2025.</p><ul><li>Ram Charan is set to star in a dual role.</li><li>The film's soundtrack is gaining attention, especially the track “Ra Macha Macha”.</li><li>The event witnessed an enthusiastic crowd turnout.</li><li>Trailer release is anticipated soon.</li><li>Co-stars include Kiara Advani, Anjali, and others.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was amazing to see the crowd's reaction, and we had so much fun performing!” - Ram Charan</blockquote><p>As excitement builds for the film's release, further updates will be shared shortly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/game-changer-ram-charan-sj-suryah-wow-fans-in-dallas-with-energetic-dance-moves.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/game-changer-ram-charan-sj-suryah-wow-fans-in-dallas-with-energetic-dance-moves.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India can never permit others to have a veto on its choices: EAM Jaishankar - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India can never permit others to have a veto on its choices: EAM Jaishankar</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/9tezq7/article69015078.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Screenshot%202024-12-22%20102950.png" alt="EAM Jaishankar was conferred the 27th SIES Sri Chandrasekarendra Saraswati National Eminence Award." />
<figcaption>EAM Jaishankar was conferred the 27th SIES Sri Chandrasekarendra Saraswati National Eminence Award.</figcaption>
<p>External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar emphasized that India will not allow others to dictate its choices and will act in its national and global interest.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jaishankar made these remarks during a video message from Mumbai.</li>
  <li>He received the 27th SIES Sri Chandrasekarendra Saraswati National Eminence Award.</li>
  <li>Stressed that India must progress while maintaining its cultural identity.</li>
  <li>Highlighted the importance of Indian heritage in a globalized world.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Independence should never be confused with neutrality. We will do whatever is right in our national interest...” — Dr. S. Jaishankar</blockquote>
<p>The minister called for a recognition of India’s cultural strengths as a path to exercising influence globally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/india-can-never-permit-others-to-have-a-veto-on-its-choices-eam-jaishankar/article69015067.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/india-can-never-permit-others-to-have-a-veto-on-its-choices-eam-jaishankar/article69015067.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' box office collection day 17: The Allu Arjun film sees a jump on Saturday after crossing Rs 10 - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Pushpa 2' Surpasses ₹1000 Crores at the Box Office, Sees Significant Growth on Day 17</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116552810,imgsize-76668,width-400,resizemode-4/116552810.jpg" alt="'Pushpa 2' box office collection day 17: The Allu Arjun film sees a jump on Saturday after crossing Rs 1000 crores" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>'Pushpa 2' continues to perform well at the box office, surpassing major milestones.</figcaption>
<p>'Pushpa 2' is now in its third week and shows impressive endurance at the box office. On Saturday, the film experienced a remarkable 74% increase in earnings from Friday, reaching a total collection of ₹1029.9 crores.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Film made ₹14 crore on Friday and ₹25 crore on Saturday.</li>
  <li>Total collection is ₹1029.9 crore, with significant contributions from both Hindi and Telugu versions.</li>
  <li>The film is expected to surpass 'Baahubali 2' soon, which grossed ₹1040 crore.</li>
  <li>Christmas and New Year holidays are anticipated to further enhance its box office success.</li>
  <li>Ongoing negotiations between PVR Inox and the distributors for screen allocations are crucial for maintaining box office momentum.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Pushpa 2 will cross the ₹1040 crore mark in the coming week, possibly by Sunday night.”</blockquote>
<p>The consistent performance of 'Pushpa 2' highlights its popularity and the impact of festive seasons on box office collections, suggesting it could achieve even greater heights in the weeks to come.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-17-the-allu-arjun-film-sees-a-jump-on-saturday-after-crossing-rs-1000-crores/articleshow/116552829.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/pushpa-2-box-office-collection-day-17-the-allu-arjun-film-sees-a-jump-on-saturday-after-crossing-rs-1000-crores/articleshow/116552829.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Colleen Hoover lauds Blake Lively's ‘honesty’ after the actor slams Justin Baldoni with a lawsuit - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Colleen Hoover supports Blake Lively amid her sexual harassment lawsuit against Justin Baldoni.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/download_1734842096829_1734842101298.png" alt="Blake Lively claims Baldoni created a hostile work environment, detailing several demands in the suit. Baldoni’s attorney called the allegations false and accused Lively of trying to repair her reputation.(File Images)" title="Blake Lively claims Baldoni created a hostile work environment, detailing several demands in the suit. Baldoni’s attorney called the allegations false and accused Lively of trying to repair her reputation.(File Images)"><figcaption>Blake Lively claims Baldoni created a hostile work environment, detailing several demands in the suit. Baldoni’s attorney called the allegations false and accused Lively of trying to repair her reputation.(File Images)</figcaption><p>Colleen Hoover, the author of It Ends With Us, has publicly backed Blake Lively following recent controversies with Justin Baldoni for sexual harassment and retaliation involving the film adaptation of her book.</p><ul><li>Colleen Hoover praised Blake Lively's honesty and support via Instagram.</li><li>Lively filed a sexual harassment lawsuit against Baldoni on December 20, 2024.</li><li>The lawsuit accuses Baldoni of creating a hostile work environment and social manipulation.</li><li>Baldoni’s attorney denied the allegations, labeling them as false and outrageous.</li><li>Lively hopes her legal action will protect others who speak out against misconduct.</li></ul><blockquote>“Thank you for being exactly the human that you are. Never change. Never wilt.” - Colleen Hoover</blockquote><p>The ongoing legal battle highlights important issues of accountability and harassment in Hollywood.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/colleen-hoover-lauds-blake-livelys-honesty-after-the-actor-slams-justin-baldoni-with-a-lawsuit-101734839427172.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/colleen-hoover-lauds-blake-livelys-honesty-after-the-actor-slams-justin-baldoni-with-a-lawsuit-101734839427172.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:39:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Rare images of Helix Nebula shared by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Rare Images of Helix Nebula Shared by NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/nebula-6-1.jpg" alt="Helix Nebula" style="width: 100%; height: auto;">
<figcaption>Early view of the Helix Nebula captured by NASA.</figcaption>
<p>The article showcases seven stunning images of the Helix Nebula, released by NASA, illustrating its beauty and complexity through various perspectives and enhancements.</p>
<ul>
<li>Spiral Beauty: A wide-angle shot showcasing intricate spiral patterns.</li>
<li>The "Eye of God": A close-up view highlighting the nebula's striking blue center.</li>
<li>Ultraviolet Majesty: A UV-enhanced image revealing the central star's brightness.</li>
<li>Outer Halo Focus: A zoomed-out image showing the faint outer halos of gas.</li>
<li>3D Simulation View: A simulated view offering a glimpse into the nebula's complex structure.</li>
<li>Infrared Glow: An infrared image revealing hidden layers of dust and gas.</li>
<li>Composite Imagery: A multi-wavelength image displaying the nebula in full spectrum.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Thanks For Reading!"</blockquote>
<p>This collection of images not only highlights the aesthetic appeal of the Helix Nebula but also demonstrates the advancements in astronomical imaging and our understanding of such celestial phenomena.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-rare-images-of-helix-nebula-shared-by-nasa-7484113/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-rare-images-of-helix-nebula-shared-by-nasa-7484113/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:30:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Rare images of Helix Nebula shared by NASA - India.Com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Rare Images of Helix Nebula Shared by NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/nebula-6-1.jpg" alt="Helix Nebula" style="width: 100%; height: auto;">
<figcaption>Early view of the Helix Nebula captured by NASA.</figcaption>
<p>The article showcases seven stunning images of the Helix Nebula, released by NASA, illustrating its beauty and complexity through various perspectives and enhancements.</p>
<ul>
<li>Spiral Beauty: A wide-angle shot showcasing intricate spiral patterns.</li>
<li>The "Eye of God": A close-up view highlighting the nebula's striking blue center.</li>
<li>Ultraviolet Majesty: A UV-enhanced image revealing the central star's brightness.</li>
<li>Outer Halo Focus: A zoomed-out image showing the faint outer halos of gas.</li>
<li>3D Simulation View: A simulated view offering a glimpse into the nebula's complex structure.</li>
<li>Infrared Glow: An infrared image revealing hidden layers of dust and gas.</li>
<li>Composite Imagery: A multi-wavelength image displaying the nebula in full spectrum.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Thanks For Reading!"</blockquote>
<p>This collection of images not only highlights the aesthetic appeal of the Helix Nebula but also demonstrates the advancements in astronomical imaging and our understanding of such celestial phenomena.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-rare-images-of-helix-nebula-shared-by-nasa-7484113/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-rare-images-of-helix-nebula-shared-by-nasa-7484113/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:30:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Don't Confuse India's Independence With Neutrality': S Jaishankar - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNSkpRY29HODdMUjVPUVdxSVFLMWtSSDZUdndxOFJYMVBYWWtDS194ck13RFgtMUQzTm5yQ2NDZ0p2S2FkekpFMFp2NDVLMmNuckU3Qk55YjVoaVBuRVNISTg1WmYweDlGU3BqV0RxUzF2VUUzSnJ1U0RlbU1rTE1PTHFMdzdrV29XOTZxWHF2TC1DWmhseFYxM2pPcWRwdWE3UHJJM2xwQzY2LVJjSG5n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNSkpRY29HODdMUjVPUVdxSVFLMWtSSDZUdndxOFJYMVBYWWtDS194ck13RFgtMUQzTm5yQ2NDZ0p2S2FkekpFMFp2NDVLMmNuckU3Qk55YjVoaVBuRVNISTg1WmYweDlGU3BqV0RxUzF2VUUzSnJ1U0RlbU1rTE1PTHFMdzdrV29XOTZxWHF2TC1DWmhseFYxM2pPcWRwdWE3UHJJM2xwQzY2LVJjSG5n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:06:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Can Never Permit Others To Have Veto On Its Choices: S Jaishankar - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Don't Confuse India's Independence With Neutrality: S Jaishankar</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2cdc3e38_s-jaishankar_625x300_22_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="Don't Confuse India's Independence With Neutrality: S Jaishankar"><figcaption>S Jaishankar called India an "exceptional" nation.</figcaption><p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar stated that India cannot permit others to decide its choices and emphasized the difference between independence and neutrality. He spoke of India's journey towards rediscovering its identity amidst global pressures.</p><ul><li>Jaishankar stressed that India will act in its national interest without conforming to external pressures.</li><li>He highlighted India's exceptional status as a civilization state that can leverage its cultural strengths.</li><li>The Minister pointed to India's progress in addressing long-standing social issues such as poverty and discrimination.</li></ul><blockquote>"Independence should never be confused with neutrality. We will do whatever is right in our national interest and for global good without being intimidated to conform." - S Jaishankar</blockquote><p>In conclusion, India is positioned at a critical juncture, balancing its national ambitions with its commitment to global well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-can-never-permit-others-to-have-veto-on-its-choices-s-jaishankar-7305501</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-can-never-permit-others-to-have-veto-on-its-choices-s-jaishankar-7305501</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:06:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' night show leads cops to make dramatic arrest of druglord in Nagpur - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pushpa 2 Leads to Dramatic Druglord Arrest in Nagpur</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent Report<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>The ongoing popularity of the film 'Pushpa 2' has unexpectedly contributed to law enforcement efforts, culminating in the arrest of a notorious druglord in Nagpur.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Police conducted a night operation linked to the film's screenings.</li>
  <li>A significant cache of illegal substances was seized during the arrest.</li>
  <li>The operation highlights the intersection of entertainment and crime prevention.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Cinema can sometimes lead to real-world impacts beyond entertainment,” said a police spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>This incident showcases the unforeseen connections between popular culture and policing efforts, potentially inspiring similar actions in other areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/nagpur/pushpa-2-night-show-leads-cops-to-make-dramatic-arrest-of-druglord-in-nagpur/articleshow/116556062.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/nagpur/pushpa-2-night-show-leads-cops-to-make-dramatic-arrest-of-druglord-in-nagpur/articleshow/116556062.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. Navy’s F/18 Super Hornet Shot Down Over Red Sea In Friendly Fire; Both Pilots Recovered - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTFA5amI3UjBYcmh0MDFkd25hallZdzlLQ0FpVUUxOWYxME5qUzhqSWQ0LWE4dTJXWjdPdEFlZjFtdVdnWU5HSGRESjFTaTdoUVdWLXJsUk16VjEwcUJCREt4MXlQU0VrYk04eXNpSVhCUXZxX0lGSFZaNG5aMFBCQdIBfkFVX3lxTFA5amI3UjBYcmh0MDFkd25hallZdzlLQ0FpVUUxOWYxME5qUzhqSWQ0LWE4dTJXWjdPdEFlZjFtdVdnWU5HSGRESjFTaTdoUVdWLXJsUk16VjEwcUJCREt4MXlQU0VrYk04eXNpSVhCUXZxX0lGSFZaNG5aMFBCQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTFA5amI3UjBYcmh0MDFkd25hallZdzlLQ0FpVUUxOWYxME5qUzhqSWQ0LWE4dTJXWjdPdEFlZjFtdVdnWU5HSGRESjFTaTdoUVdWLXJsUk16VjEwcUJCREt4MXlQU0VrYk04eXNpSVhCUXZxX0lGSFZaNG5aMFBCQdIBfkFVX3lxTFA5amI3UjBYcmh0MDFkd25hallZdzlLQ0FpVUUxOWYxME5qUzhqSWQ0LWE4dTJXWjdPdEFlZjFtdVdnWU5HSGRESjFTaTdoUVdWLXJsUk16VjEwcUJCREt4MXlQU0VrYk04eXNpSVhCUXZxX0lGSFZaNG5aMFBCQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:54:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Faster walkers' are at significantly lower risk of diabetes, hypertension: Study - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxOd3poZHFuQzl4eUphY1RqeHFZT3BkLWFzTFZFTlpTckdIS2JuaGFGaWl3UEpKYmlURVlGYzNzVlIzbms0SDUyYTh5Tk5SWFc4Z1JtbFgxWFY0UkZuQ2xXYkN1a2FsRko3MHR0U0ltNWh3WTVjRmFfUDYzLTEtcGpHTTBEMXBfdHhiRkFiNHVuTGhIUENMOU40Szg5YUhzU1k1cnVmTlJpLWp5aEtWMzE3Q1VFeUxpRjZDVjEyYlBEOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxOd3poZHFuQzl4eUphY1RqeHFZT3BkLWFzTFZFTlpTckdIS2JuaGFGaWl3UEpKYmlURVlGYzNzVlIzbms0SDUyYTh5Tk5SWFc4Z1JtbFgxWFY0UkZuQ2xXYkN1a2FsRko3MHR0U0ltNWh3WTVjRmFfUDYzLTEtcGpHTTBEMXBfdHhiRkFiNHVuTGhIUENMOU40Szg5YUhzU1k1cnVmTlJpLWp5aEtWMzE3Q1VFeUxpRjZDVjEyYlBEOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:49:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telangana CM Revanth Reddy spits fire at Allu Arjun for 'inhuman act' after Sandhya theatre stampede - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telangana CM Revanth Reddy spits fire at Allu Arjun for 'inhuman act' after Sandhya theatre stampede</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Not Provided]</p><p>The article covers the strong criticism from Telangana Chief Minister Revanth Reddy directed at actor Allu Arjun regarding a tragic stampede incident at the Sandhya theatre.</p><ul><li>CM Revanth Reddy expressed outrage over the actor's involvement in the incident.</li><li>The stampede occurred during a film screening, raising concerns about crowd management.</li><li>The article highlights the potential for repercussions in the film industry.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is an inhuman act that should not be tolerated,” said CM Reddy.</blockquote><p>This incident has stirred significant public discourse on responsibilities during public events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/hyderabad/telangana-cm-revanth-reddy-spits-fire-at-allu-arjun-for-inhuman-act-after-sandhya-theatre-stampede/articleshow/116555889.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/hyderabad/telangana-cm-revanth-reddy-spits-fire-at-allu-arjun-for-inhuman-act-after-sandhya-theatre-stampede/articleshow/116555889.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["When Sundar Played Perth Test, R Ashwin Said...": Ex India Star Explains Retirement Reason - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ex-India Star R. Ashwin Explains Reasons for Retirement</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 19 December 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/si86mka_r-ashwin-retirement-afp_625x300_19_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="When Sundar Played Perth Test, R Ashwin Said..." /><figcaption>File photo of Ravichandran Ashwin © AFP</figcaption><p>Ravichandran Ashwin's sudden retirement during the series against Australia has sparked significant discussions in the cricketing community. The decision seems to have stemmed from Ashwin's recognition of his position in the team and his feelings about being dropped for key matches.</p><ul><li>Ashwin shocked fans and pundits by retiring in the middle of the series.</li><li>Former cricketer Aakash Chopra suggested that Ashwin's decision was influenced by Washington Sundar's selection in the Perth Test.</li><li>Captain Rohit Sharma had previously persuaded Ashwin to continue until the pink-ball Test.</li><li>Ashwin felt humiliated after being dropped from the Gabba Test after performing well in the pink-ball Test.</li></ul><blockquote>“But when Sundar played the Perth Test, then he said, that's it, I am done.” - Aakash Chopra</blockquote><p>The cricketing world continues to speculate why such a seasoned player like Ashwin made this abrupt choice, pointing to feelings of unvalued contributions on Ashwin's part.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/when-washington-sundar-played-perth-test-he-said-ex-india-star-on-r-ashwins-retirement-reason-7305401</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/when-washington-sundar-played-perth-test-he-said-ex-india-star-on-r-ashwins-retirement-reason-7305401</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:47:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan turn paparazzi into cheerleaders at Mumbai event; Katrina Kaif, Suhana Khan seen too. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan Turn Paparazzi into Cheerleaders at Mumbai Event</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 22, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Shah_Rukh_Khan_1734837096232_1734837108917.jpg" alt="Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan, Suhana Khan and Katrina Kaif attended a Mumbai event." title="Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan, Suhana Khan and Katrina Kaif attended a Mumbai event.">
<figcaption>Shah Rukh Khan, Gauri Khan, Suhana Khan and Katrina Kaif attended a Mumbai event.</figcaption>
<p>Shah Rukh Khan and Gauri Khan were among the many celebrities who attended a festive gathering at Mumbai’s Nita Mukesh Ambani Cultural Centre, where they charmed the paparazzi.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shah Rukh and Gauri rocked matching black outfits.</li>
  <li>They received cheers from fans upon arriving at the event.</li>
  <li>Other attendees included Katrina Kaif, Madhuri Dixit, and Suhana Khan.</li>
  <li>Shah Rukh Khan is set to appear in the upcoming film King.</li>
  <li>Shahid Kapoor's upcoming film Deva is scheduled for release on February 14, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“After posing for the paparazzi, Shah Rukh Khan smiled, blew a kiss, and flashed the thumbs-up sign.”</blockquote>
<p>This event highlighted the glamorous side of Bollywood and showcased the camaraderie among its stars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-gauri-khan-turn-paparazzi-into-cheerleaders-at-mumbai-event-katrina-kaif-suhana-khan-seen-too-watch-101734833677574.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shah-rukh-khan-gauri-khan-turn-paparazzi-into-cheerleaders-at-mumbai-event-katrina-kaif-suhana-khan-seen-too-watch-101734833677574.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:36:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>