<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 08:22:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 08:22:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Gave alcohol, slit their wrists': Man kills mother, 4 sisters in Lucknow hotel; father aided murders - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Gave alcohol, slit their wrists’: Man kills mother, 4 sisters in Lucknow hotel; father aided murders</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This shocking incident in Lucknow has led to the tragic loss of a mother and her four daughters, with the perpetrator and evidence of complicity from the father revealing deep family issues.</p><ul><li>A man reportedly intoxicated his mother and sisters before committing the murders.</li><li>The father is accused of aiding in the heinous acts.</li><li>The case has raised questions about domestic violence and mental health.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was a nightmare; we never imagined something so horrific could happen in our family,” said a close family friend.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the urgent need for better mental health support and domestic violence prevention measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/5-of-family-found-dead-in-lucknow-hotel/articleshow/116845116.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/5-of-family-found-dead-in-lucknow-hotel/articleshow/116845116.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 07:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Unveils New Mars Drone Design: A Larger, Enhanced Version Of Ingenuity Helicopter - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Unveils New Mars Drone Design: A Larger, Enhanced Version Of Ingenuity Helicopter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>NASA has unveiled the successor to its successful Ingenuity helicopter that has operated on Mars for over three years. The new drone, nicknamed the "Mars Chopper," has enhanced capabilities for scientific exploration.</p><img src="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/images/pia26375-nasas-mars-chopper-concept-rendering/" alt="Mars Chopper concept rendering"><figcaption>Mars Chopper concept rendering.</figcaption><p>This advanced drone is larger, weighing around the size of an SUV, and boasts a payload capacity of five kilograms for scientific instruments.</p><ul><li>The Mars Chopper can fly up to three kilometers and carry advanced imaging and analysis equipment.</li><li>It is designed to help scientists study large areas of terrain quickly, especially regions inaccessible to rovers.</li><li>Ingenuity, which weighed 1.8 kilograms, performed 72 flights far exceeding its original mission parameters.</li></ul><blockquote>"Scientists could use Chopper to study large swaths of terrain in detail, quickly – including areas where rovers cannot safely travel," NASA stated.</blockquote><p>Despite its improvements, the new model faces challenges following Ingenuity's crash due to navigation issues amidst the Martian terrain.</p><p>The Mars Chopper represents a major advancement in planetary exploration technology and the potential for future missions beyond Mars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-unveils-new-mars-drone-design-a-larger-enhanced-version-of-ingenuity-helicopter-7375898</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-unveils-new-mars-drone-design-a-larger-enhanced-version-of-ingenuity-helicopter-7375898</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 07:28:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poco X7 5G Series Launch Date Confirmed: Check Out Specifications - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Poco X7 5G Series Launch Date Confirmed: Check Out Specifications</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Poco Official Announcement</p><p>The Poco X7 5G series, including the X7 and X7 Pro models, is set to launch on January 9 in India, with availability through Flipkart. Details about the design and specifications have been revealed prior to the launch.</p><ul><li>Launch Date: January 9, 2025</li><li>Models: Poco X7 5G and Poco X7 Pro 5G</li><li>Purchase Platform: Flipkart</li><li>Design: Distinct styles with colors like black, yellow, silver, and green</li><li>Processor: X7 Pro will feature MediaTek Dimensity 8400-Ultra; base model to have Dimensity 7300-Ultra</li><li>Camera: Expected 50-megapixel main camera; Pro may get Sony IMX882 sensor</li><li>Display: 6.67-inch AMOLED with high resolution and refresh rate</li><li>Battery: X7 5G will have 5,110mAh; the Pro variant features a 6,000mAh battery</li></ul><blockquote>“With an array of powerful features and striking designs, the Poco X7 5G series is poised to capture attention when it launches early this year.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Poco X7 series is highly anticipated due to its innovative features and design, aiming to draw significant interest upon release.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/poco-x7-5g-series-launch-date-confirmed-check-out-specifications-1741089</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/poco-x7-5g-series-launch-date-confirmed-check-out-specifications-1741089</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 07:26:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bharat Ratna Demand For Manmohan Singh Gains Momentum After Telangana Assembly Resolution - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Demand for Bharat Ratna for Manmohan Singh Grows After Telangana Assembly Resolution</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Former PM Manmohan Singh (PTI/File)"><figcaption>Former PM Manmohan Singh (PTI/File)</figcaption><p>The Telangana Assembly has urged the Central government to confer the Bharat Ratna on former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, prompting many in Congress to support the initiative. Congress leaders are calling for the highest civilian award to honor his significant contributions.</p><ul><li>Telangana Assembly passes a resolution demanding Bharat Ratna for Manmohan Singh.</li><li>Congress Deputy Leader in the Rajya Sabha, Pramod Tiwari, emphasizes the need to acknowledge Singh's leadership.</li><li>Subharansh Kumar Rai mentions Singh's advocacy for key legislation such as the Right to Education and Right to Information.</li><li>BJP criticizes Congress for not acting on a previous recommendation to award Singh the Bharat Ratna.</li><li>Manmohan Singh recently passed away at the age of 92.</li></ul><blockquote>“I urge the Centre to accept the resolution. Manmohanji was a great leader of our country and he should be awarded the Bharat Ratna.” - Pramod Tiwari</blockquote><p>The push for the Bharat Ratna for Manmohan Singh highlights his acknowledged role in shaping modern India, suggesting a broader recognition of his legacy may be underway.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/more-in-congress-want-bharat-ratna-for-manmohan-singh-after-telangana-assembly-resolution-9174370.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/more-in-congress-want-bharat-ratna-for-manmohan-singh-after-telangana-assembly-resolution-9174370.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 07:17:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Very Beautiful Images Of Nebula Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Very Beautiful Images Of Nebula Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 1, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116849872/116849872.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=1186006" alt="6 Very Beautiful Images Of Nebula Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope"><figcaption>Credit: ESA/Hubble-NASA</figcaption><p>This article showcases six breathtaking images of nebulas taken by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting their beauty and cosmic significance.</p><ul><li>The Ghost Nebula (IC 63) is both a reflection and emission nebula about 550 light-years away.</li><li>The Horsehead Nebula, also known as Barnard 33, is located in the Orion constellation.</li><li>The Eagle Nebula features a towering structure of gas and dust that serves as a stellar nursery.</li><li>The Orion Nebula offers a view of a star-forming region containing over 3,000 stars.</li><li>The Lagoon Nebula (Messier 8) is a massive cloud of glowing gas recognized for its stellar nursery attributes.</li><li>The article includes captivating visuals and details about each nebula, emphasizing their ethereal beauty and cosmic relevance.</li></ul><blockquote>"These breathtaking images showcase the awe-inspiring beauty and intricate details of nebulae."</blockquote><p>The Hubble Space Telescope continues to provide invaluable insights into the cosmos, unveiling the splendor of nebulas across the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-very-beautiful-images-of-nebula-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/116849857.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-very-beautiful-images-of-nebula-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/116849857.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 06:59:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flipkart 'Big Bachat Days' sale: Deals and offers on iPhones, Pixels, more - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Flipkart 'Big Bachat Days' sale: Deals and offers on iPhones, Pixels, more</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 01 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p>
<img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" title="Flipkart Big Bachat Days sale" alt="Flipkart Big Bachat Days sale" width="826" height="465">
<figcaption>Flipkart Big Bachat Days sale</figcaption>
<p>E-commerce platform Flipkart is offering significant discounts on various smartphones as part of its "Big Bachat Days" sale from January 1 to January 5.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Offers include cashback, UPI discounts, and no-interest EMI options.</li>
  <li>Apple's iPhone 16 series models available with discounts up to Rs 7000.</li>
  <li>Google Pixel 9 series smartphones can have bank discounts of up to Rs 10,000.</li>
  <li>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 6 maximizes savings with discounts of Rs 12,500 with select banks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Customers can avail a discount of Rs 2000 on UPI transactions for purchasing an iPhone 16 series model."</blockquote>
<p>The sale promises extensive offers across popular smartphone brands, ensuring customers receive excellent value for their purchases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/flipkart-big-bachat-days-sale-deals-and-offers-on-iphones-pixels-more-125010100336_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/flipkart-big-bachat-days-sale-deals-and-offers-on-iphones-pixels-more-125010100336_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 06:59:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gave alcohol, suffocated, slit wrists: Son kills mother, 4 sisters in Lucknow hotel; father aided murders - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/5-of-family-found-dead-in-lucknow-hotel/articleshow/116845116.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/5-of-family-found-dead-in-lucknow-hotel/articleshow/116845116.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 06:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[20-minute workout guide for women to get rid of fat around waist - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxNRmVqU2MzdExOWE1IYUVjVUc4cUxPaEZKVUZiZUFFSkNlMVJQWDhURHdmd1pQekdNajB0Ujd0clRWWU9ZQlNRTmRjZXFSZXRaaW5pV3VLNkg5YkFWb2JSTEg5TDFNcUQweWpNLXBxNGNkb2pjSFI2NWx5Qk1zRkc5UDdtdFNLYUZVeUFhQmo3TVA0OFJIazJ5ZUZ4MHEwbFJxb0pvdktjNUxSOUtjWXA1cmRsUlpUTzk3bXdaQ2JlTUdJQTZBMnpuMXA1ZW43MHhvRkdIRmtNTkR3Wng5OXdQUjVhYmZQeXhRaUVjb1o0RUk4Q05rZ0HSAfYBQVVfeXFMTUZlalNjM3RMTlhNSGFFY1VHOHFMT2hGSlVGYmVBRUpDZTFSUFg4VER3ZndaUHpHTWowdFI3dHJUVllPWUJTUU5kY2VxUmV0WmluaVd1SzZIOWJBVm9iUkxIOUwxTXFEMHlqTS1wcTRjZG9qY0hSNjVseUJNc0ZHOVA3bXRTS2FGVXlBYUJqN01QNDhSSGsyeWVGeDBxMGxScW9Kb3ZLYzVMUjlLY1lwNXJkbFJaVE85N213WkNiZU1HSUE2QTJ6bjFwNWVuNzB4b0ZHSEZrTU5Ed1p4OTl3UFI1YWJmUHl4UWlFY29aNEVJOENOa2dB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxNRmVqU2MzdExOWE1IYUVjVUc4cUxPaEZKVUZiZUFFSkNlMVJQWDhURHdmd1pQekdNajB0Ujd0clRWWU9ZQlNRTmRjZXFSZXRaaW5pV3VLNkg5YkFWb2JSTEg5TDFNcUQweWpNLXBxNGNkb2pjSFI2NWx5Qk1zRkc5UDdtdFNLYUZVeUFhQmo3TVA0OFJIazJ5ZUZ4MHEwbFJxb0pvdktjNUxSOUtjWXA1cmRsUlpUTzk3bXdaQ2JlTUdJQTZBMnpuMXA1ZW43MHhvRkdIRmtNTkR3Wng5OXdQUjVhYmZQeXhRaUVjb1o0RUk4Q05rZ0HSAfYBQVVfeXFMTUZlalNjM3RMTlhNSGFFY1VHOHFMT2hGSlVGYmVBRUpDZTFSUFg4VER3ZndaUHpHTWowdFI3dHJUVllPWUJTUU5kY2VxUmV0WmluaVd1SzZIOWJBVm9iUkxIOUwxTXFEMHlqTS1wcTRjZG9qY0hSNjVseUJNc0ZHOVA3bXRTS2FGVXlBYUJqN01QNDhSSGsyeWVGeDBxMGxScW9Kb3ZLYzVMUjlLY1lwNXJkbFJaVE85N213WkNiZU1HSUE2QTJ6bjFwNWVuNzB4b0ZHSEZrTU5Ed1p4OTl3UFI1YWJmUHl4UWlFY29aNEVJOENOa2dB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal writes to Mohan Bhagwat, alleges deletion of votes and money distribution by BJP - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/does-rss-support-bjps-wrongdoings-arvind-kejriwal-asks-mohan-bhagwat/article69049149.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/does-rss-support-bjps-wrongdoings-arvind-kejriwal-asks-mohan-bhagwat/article69049149.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 06:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Openly distributing money': Arvind Kejriwal writes to RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat, asks whether it supports - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Questions RSS's Stance on BJP Support</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal has sent a letter to RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat, questioning whether the RSS supports the BJP's policies and actions.</p><ul><li>Kejriwal highlights issues of governance and public welfare.</li><li>He raises concerns about the distribution of money in politics.</li><li>The letter calls for accountability from the RSS regarding its influence on the BJP.</li></ul><blockquote>“In a democratic setup, transparency is crucial for public trust,” said Kejriwal.</blockquote><p>This dialogue indicates a growing tension between political entities and adds to the ongoing discussions about the role of political organizations in governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/openly-distributing-money-arvind-kejriwal-writes-to-rss-chief-mohan-bhagwat-asks-whether-it-supports-bjp/articleshow/116848283.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/openly-distributing-money-arvind-kejriwal-writes-to-rss-chief-mohan-bhagwat-asks-whether-it-supports-bjp/articleshow/116848283.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 06:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir Wanted Cheteshwar Pujara For Australia Tour. Here's What Happened Next - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Wanted Cheteshwar Pujara For Australia Tour, Stunning Selection Details Emerge</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/e64dqp1o_cheteshwar-pujara-afp_625x300_13_June_23.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Gautam Gambhir Wanted Cheteshwar Pujara For Australia Tour, Stunning Selection Details Emerge"><figcaption>File image of Cheteshwar Pujara. © AFP</figcaption><p>Team India head coach Gautam Gambhir is at odds with the BCCI regarding team selection. Reports indicate Gambhir is frustrated with the team's performance and has advocated for the return of Test specialist Cheteshwar Pujara for the Australian tour.</p><ul><li>Gambhir has faced challenges with team selection decisions made by the BCCI.</li><li>Despite India's victory in the Perth Test, Gambhir pushed for Pujara's inclusion.</li><li>Pujara, who has an average of 43.60 in 103 Test matches, hasn't played since the WTC final in 2023.</li><li>Gambhir's tenure has faced criticism regarding player performance and on-field execution.</li></ul><blockquote>Pujara is a veteran of 103 Test matches at an average of 43.60, and he played a key role in India's previous two series victories in Australia.</blockquote><p>Gambhir's plea for Pujara reveals tensions in team dynamics and strategy as India navigates the Australia series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-wanted-cheteshwar-pujara-for-australia-tour-heres-what-happened-next-7375059</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-wanted-cheteshwar-pujara-for-australia-tour-heres-what-happened-next-7375059</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 05:50:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In Pics | Celebrations across the globe as world welcomes in 2025 - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>In Pics | Celebrations across the globe as world welcomes in 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/New-year-1.jpg?w=630" alt="Fireworks over Sydney Opera House" height="405" width="607"><figcaption>Fireworks explode over the Sydney Opera House and Harbour Bridge during New Year’s celebrations in Sydney, Australia, January 1, 2025. AAP Image/Bianca De Marchi/via REUTERS</figcaption><p>Revellers around the world ring in the new year with parties, celebrations and fireworks, marking the arrival of 2025.</p><ul><li>Sydney features spectacular fireworks over its iconic landmarks.</li><li>Tokyo showcases stunning projection mapping on government buildings.</li><li>The Philippines celebrates with fireworks lighting up the skyline.</li><li>Bangkok hosts a vibrant celebration on the Chao Phraya river.</li><li>Hong Kong’s Victoria Harbour dazzles with fireworks.</li><li>Beijing's Shougang Park sees crowds cheering for the countdown.</li><li>Times Square in New York becomes the center of global attention with its iconic ball drop.</li><li>Paris lights up with a grand show around the Arc de Triomphe.</li><li>Rio de Janeiro celebrates with breathtaking fireworks over Copacabana Beach.</li><li>Berlin witnesses a lively atmosphere with festivities on the streets.</li></ul><blockquote>“A view of Times Square as confetti falls during the annual New Year's Eve celebration, Wednesday, Jan. 1, 2025, in New York.” - AP Photo/Heather Khalifa</blockquote><p>The global New Year celebrations highlight diverse cultures and traditions, uniting people in a joyful welcome to 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNZG9Fc2ZKM3d6MnViTFc1dE5ydmxQNTF2RFpKSzlScGxJRnlRUE5DQnlfMHRhWTNKMjhldmtVQU9vV3piaV85eld4alk0VnJGWjFUM0txU2JNWGMzYTZSalRoRzVYYnptemZYTllGU2QxclByQzU2YldPQnhMU1JqczJSVWZWMnlWLUhN0gGSAUFVX3lxTE9vWHZkdnk4dkk2VDdGRUVPNlhNWC1JNUl5S2ZNOUNKd29tQ3Mza0d3Z2NLbXAxNjB1RUlSbms5ZmYwdjZrWkY3NU9jVHNEUjl1Mnl2YjlUVWJ4bXFRTllGeXc2cktoa2ZGam1rMy1Fcy1mT0s0SFJvVjBIS2I0QlN4RDRwSVJ2cDB4VWRMYmxwbVZn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNZG9Fc2ZKM3d6MnViTFc1dE5ydmxQNTF2RFpKSzlScGxJRnlRUE5DQnlfMHRhWTNKMjhldmtVQU9vV3piaV85eld4alk0VnJGWjFUM0txU2JNWGMzYTZSalRoRzVYYnptemZYTllGU2QxclByQzU2YldPQnhMU1JqczJSVWZWMnlWLUhN0gGSAUFVX3lxTE9vWHZkdnk4dkk2VDdGRUVPNlhNWC1JNUl5S2ZNOUNKd29tQ3Mza0d3Z2NLbXAxNjB1RUlSbms5ZmYwdjZrWkY3NU9jVHNEUjl1Mnl2YjlUVWJ4bXFRTllGeXc2cktoa2ZGam1rMy1Fcy1mT0s0SFJvVjBIS2I0QlN4RDRwSVJ2cDB4VWRMYmxwbVZn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 05:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS: Without Jasprit Bumrah, the series might have been more one-sided, says Glenn McGrath - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Impact of Jasprit Bumrah's Absence on IND vs AUS Series, According to Glenn McGrath</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>Glenn McGrath remarked that without Jasprit Bumrah, the IND vs AUS series could have been more one-sided, indicating the significant impact the bowler's absence has on the team's performance.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jasprit Bumrah's absence noted as a crucial factor in the series outcome.</li>
  <li>McGrath suggests Bumrah's presence could have balanced the competition.</li>
  <li>The commentary highlights Bumrah's importance in the Indian bowling lineup.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Without Jasprit Bumrah, the series might have been more one-sided” - Glenn McGrath</blockquote>
<p>The comments underline the importance of key players in sports, especially in competitive series like India vs Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-without-jasprit-bumrah-the-series-might-have-been-more-one-sided-says-glenn-mcgrath/articleshow/116847601.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-without-jasprit-bumrah-the-series-might-have-been-more-one-sided-says-glenn-mcgrath/articleshow/116847601.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 05:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nishant Pitti steps down as Easy Trip Planners CEO; Rikant Pittie takes the helm | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nishant Pitti Resigns as CEO of Easy Trip Planners; Rikant Pittie Appointed as New CEO</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Easy Trip Planners recently announced the resignation of Nishant Pitti as CEO, effective January 1, and the appointment of Rikant Pittie, previously CFO, as the new CEO.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nishant Pitti resigned for personal reasons.</li>
  <li>Rikant Pittie is promoted to CEO from CFO; he is also Nishant's brother.</li>
  <li>Nishant sold a 1.4% stake in the company for ₹78 crore prior to his resignation.</li>
  <li>Rikant Pittie holds a significant stake in the company, amounting to 25.88%.</li>
  <li>Easy Trip Planners is the parent company of EaseMyTrip.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Nishant Pitti offloaded 4,99,52,163 shares at an average price of ₹15.68, realizing a transaction value of ₹78.32 crore.</blockquote>
<p>The transition in leadership at Easy Trip Planners marks a significant shift in the company's management, with the new CEO expected to steer the company into its next phase of growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/nishant-pitti-steps-down-as-easy-trip-planners-ceo-rikant-pittie-takes-the-helm-11735708345245.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/nishant-pitti-steps-down-as-easy-trip-planners-ceo-rikant-pittie-takes-the-helm-11735708345245.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 05:23:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nishant Pitti, Co-promoter of EaseMyTrip, resigns as CEO with immediate effect, cites personal reasons - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nishant Pitti Resigns as CEO of Easy Trip Planners</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC-TV18</p><img alt="Nishant Pitti" title="Nishant Pitti, Co-promoter of Easy Trip Planners, resigns as CEO with immediate effect" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Nishant Pitti, Co-promoter of Easy Trip Planners, resigns as CEO with immediate effect</figcaption><p>Nishant Pitti, a co-promoter of Easy Trip Planners, has resigned from his position as CEO, citing personal reasons.</p><ul><li>Pitti had planned to sell his remaining 14% stake in the company but only managed to sell 1.4% on Tuesday.</li><li>He has been associated with the company since 2008 and was re-appointed for a five-year term in May 2024.</li><li>Rikant Pittie has been appointed as the new CEO, effective immediately.</li><li>Retail shareholding in Easy Trip Planners has increased significantly since its IPO in 2021.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dear Board Members, I, Nishant Pitti, hereby tender my resignation from the position of CEO due to personal reasons with effect from January 01, 2025.”</blockquote><p>The resignation comes amidst ongoing stake sale activities by Pitti, who previously sold shares to retail investors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/nishant-pitti-easy-trip-planners-ease-my-trip-ceo-resigns-stake-sale-block-deal-share-price-reaction-19532728.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/nishant-pitti-easy-trip-planners-ease-my-trip-ceo-resigns-stake-sale-block-deal-share-price-reaction-19532728.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 05:17:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Future of Space Exploration with Autonomous Robots - Analytics Insight]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Future of Space Exploration with Autonomous Robots</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> May 6, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Analytics Insight</p><img src="https://media.assettype.com/analyticsinsight%2F2025-01-01%2Fsidexniz%2FFuture-of-Space-Exploration-with-Autonomous-Robots.jpg" alt="Future of Space Exploration with Autonomous Robots"><figcaption>Future of Space Exploration with Autonomous Robots</figcaption><p>Autonomous robots are revolutionizing space exploration by operating in dangerous environments and making real-time decisions, thereby enhancing mission efficiency and reducing costs.</p><ul><li>Autonomous robots explore dangerous environments like Mars and distant asteroids, ensuring mission success.</li><li>AI-powered robots make real-time decisions, adapting to unexpected situations for smooth operations.</li><li>These robots are ideal for extended space missions, operating for long durations.</li><li>They help reduce mission costs by eliminating human-related expenses and life support systems.</li><li>AI-driven robots enhance our understanding of celestial bodies and potential resources.</li><li>Autonomous robots work alongside astronauts, improving mission efficiency and safety.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.analyticsinsight.net/ampstories/tech-news/future-of-space-exploration-with-autonomous-robots</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.analyticsinsight.net/ampstories/tech-news/future-of-space-exploration-with-autonomous-robots</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 05:08:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Reasons to sip on Cinnamon Ginger Tea before bedtime - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/food-news/6-reasons-to-sip-on-cinnamon-ginger-tea-before-bedtime/articleshow/116836079.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/food-news/6-reasons-to-sip-on-cinnamon-ginger-tea-before-bedtime/articleshow/116836079.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir Wanted Cheteshwar Pujara For Australia Tour, Stunning Selection Details Emerge - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Wanted Cheteshwar Pujara For Australia Tour, Stunning Selection Details Emerge</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/e64dqp1o_cheteshwar-pujara-afp_625x300_13_June_23.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Gautam Gambhir Wanted Cheteshwar Pujara For Australia Tour, Stunning Selection Details Emerge"><figcaption>File image of Cheteshwar Pujara. © AFP</figcaption><p>Team India head coach Gautam Gambhir is at odds with the BCCI regarding team selection. Reports indicate Gambhir is frustrated with the team's performance and has advocated for the return of Test specialist Cheteshwar Pujara for the Australian tour.</p><ul><li>Gambhir has faced challenges with team selection decisions made by the BCCI.</li><li>Despite India's victory in the Perth Test, Gambhir pushed for Pujara's inclusion.</li><li>Pujara, who has an average of 43.60 in 103 Test matches, hasn't played since the WTC final in 2023.</li><li>Gambhir's tenure has faced criticism regarding player performance and on-field execution.</li></ul><blockquote>Pujara is a veteran of 103 Test matches at an average of 43.60, and he played a key role in India's previous two series victories in Australia.</blockquote><p>Gambhir's plea for Pujara reveals tensions in team dynamics and strategy as India navigates the Australia series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-wanted-cheteshwar-pujara-for-australia-tour-heres-what-happened-next-7375059</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-wanted-cheteshwar-pujara-for-australia-tour-heres-what-happened-next-7375059</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:41:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who Is Sivasri Skandaprasad? All About The Carnatic Singer Set To Marry BJP MP Tejasvi Surya - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who Is Sivasri Skandaprasad? All About The Carnatic Singer Set To Marry BJP MP Tejasvi Surya</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Published on: January 01, 2025, Source: unknown</p><p>Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) MP Tejasvi Surya is reportedly set to marry renowned Carnatic singer Sivasri Skandaprasad in Bengaluru. Although there hasn't been an official announcement, the wedding is anticipated to take place on March 4, 2025.</p><p><strong>Key Points:</strong></p><ul><li>Sivasri Skandaprasad is a renowned Carnatic singer and holds degrees in Bioengineering, Bharatanatyam, and Sanskrit.</li><li>She gained fame after PM Modi praised her 2014 devotional song on YouTube.</li><li>Sivasri has ventured into playback singing, contributing to films like 'Ponniyin Selvan: Part 1.'</li><li>Tejasvi Surya is a lawyer and currently serves as an MP for Bengaluru South.</li><li>Both share a passion for sports and physical endurance activities.</li></ul><blockquote>"This rendition by Sivasri Skandaprasad in Kannada beautifully highlights the spirit of devotion to Prabhu Shri Ram. Such efforts go a long way in preserving our rich cultural heritage," - PM Modi</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the upcoming union between Sivasri Skandaprasad and Tejasvi Surya is generating interest, promising to meld cultural heritage with public service in a high-profile marriage.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/entertainment/who-is-sivasri-skandaprasad-all-about-the-carnatic-singer-set-to-marry-bjp-mp-tejasvi-surya</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/entertainment/who-is-sivasri-skandaprasad-all-about-the-carnatic-singer-set-to-marry-bjp-mp-tejasvi-surya</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:32:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi greets India on New Year - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi greets India on New Year</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/jvjgtq/article69049037.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/20241231135L.jpg" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi." title="Prime Minister Narendra Modi." />
<figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi. | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption>
<p>Extending his greetings to the nation on the New Year, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on January 1, 2025, expressed his hopes for new opportunities, success, and endless joy.</p>
<ul>
<li>Modi wished for the year to bring health and prosperity for all.</li>
<li>President Droupadi Murmu also extended New Year greetings, urging collaboration for a brighter future.</li>
<li>Both leaders expressed hope for inclusiveness and sustainability in the New Year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Happy 2025! May this year bring everyone new opportunities, success and endless joy.” - PM Modi</blockquote>
<blockquote>“May the year 2025 bring joy, harmony and prosperity to all!” - President Droupadi Murmu</blockquote>
<p>This New Year marks a time for reflection and hope, with leaders calling for unity and progress in the upcoming year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/pm-modi-greets-nation-on-new-year/article69049031.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/pm-modi-greets-nation-on-new-year/article69049031.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I've Had Enough": Furious Gautam Gambhir Lashes Out At India Stars, Issues Stern Warning - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"I've Had Enough": Furious Gautam Gambhir Lashes Out At India Stars, Issues Stern Warning</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/ugg4tfko_virat-kohli-and-gautam-gambhir-afp_625x300_01_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="&quot;I've Had Enough&quot;: Furious Gautam Gambhir Lashes Out At India Stars, Issues Stern Warning"><figcaption>Gautam Gambhir and Virat Kohli in a conversation © AFP</figcaption><p>Gautam Gambhir, the head coach of the Indian cricket team, expressed his frustration over the team's performance, particularly in the recent Test matches against Australia.</p><ul><li>The Indian team is under pressure after losing the fourth Test, putting their chance to qualify for the World Test Championship final at risk.</li><li>Gambhir has criticized some players for not adhering to the team's game plan, which he has emphasized over the past six months.</li><li>His announcement of stricter measures against players failing to follow the strategy indicates a major shift in the team's management.</li><li>Crucial mistakes by players like Rishabh Pant and Virat Kohli have been highlighted as pivotal in the team's recent losses.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bahut ho gaya (I've had enough),” Gambhir told the Indian team after the loss in Melbourne.</blockquote><p>Gambhir's stern warning underscores a growing tension within the team as they navigate challenging situations and seek to improve their performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ive-had-enough-furious-gautam-gambhir-lashes-out-at-india-stars-issues-stern-warning-7374922</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ive-had-enough-furious-gautam-gambhir-lashes-out-at-india-stars-issues-stern-warning-7374922</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:16:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy New Year 2025: Best messages, quotes, and wishes to share on New Year's Eve - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Happy New Year 2025: Best messages, quotes, and wishes to share on New Year's Eve</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116800481,imgsize-1333120,width-400,resizemode-4/116800481.jpg" alt="Happy New Year 2025: Best messages, quotes, and wishes to share on New Year's Eve"><figcaption>Happy New Year 2025 celebration</figcaption><p>As we approach the start of a new year, New Year’s Eve is a time for reflection and sharing positive messages of hope and love with friends and family. It’s about sending good vibes for a brighter tomorrow.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>New Year’s messages help express kindness and hopes for the future.</li><li>Wishes for friends include expressions of happiness and unforgettable moments.</li><li>Family wishes emphasize love, togetherness, and blessings.</li><li>Colleagues receive messages that inspire teamwork and success.</li><li>Messages for partners focus on love and shared dreams.</li></ul><blockquote>“Here’s to another year of laughter, adventure, and making memories we’ll never forget! Cheers to 2025!”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, New Year wishes are a meaningful way to convey love and support as we step into 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/relationships/work/happy-new-year-2025-best-messages-quotes-images-and-wishes-to-share-on-new-years-eve/articleshow/116800468.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/relationships/work/happy-new-year-2025-best-messages-quotes-images-and-wishes-to-share-on-new-years-eve/articleshow/116800468.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['What a way to wrap up 2024': Viswanathan Anand congratulates Vaishali on clinching bronze in World Blitz - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgJBVV95cUxOWEZjUDhKb05SLWhOMmxIYnYzb1dBWVJPWU5yWDhCQzlqMy1pTjR5ekNfY3pvU2FXRFhxV2NYRXRncjhQY3lmSkVsTU1KRDFaWTZNQ1dqTjZtdDRRaUd4YkptTnlCNzlHQWdCTFBqZUE2LU45TXhZNlhtbVBwajNqYng5aDFiU3lTYnZjTmpreGJhbDUwU0wwamg0ZGw3VVlLeXN0OGVmcmROdURiMmJtYmpwUVFUemZROElmaFU3cGx4TnZoVXBGUm01NE9wSjQ4TlBLVGVGZGRSTlpvRkFvc2EtS3JNRGpOVVZocDcxRUkzNk9mZTdVV1FDN2FZbU9sanlwRkcwOFBhVWpzNGx4YUpQMndmSXVVMEHSAZ8CQVVfeXFMTkRHbW1ycEdyV092STNHM3k0M0xmTFRhYXNRaXRYTlZqYUZkcnNPQ2ZEVHRhcVNpbUxLc3hCWTZHRUh2VDAtY1NBY0RaV05SaEZuMkdRVTBOM1E2WUlTU29iV21CWWkwRDEyQXBZSnBjYXV4VVdEb3VkRzdRaFdibVNfLU9ic1BIZndxNFYwOTRla1FTelVTMVp4WFdvWWFUczFYVWhZcklQcTlxb0pla0xvMzVxelVNRGx2X2NBOHBUd2dyZ2N1VHA5LU02bDVFOUVBUG1sZ2U2YlBiU0NVOUQtUnhxNFAzV3N5X3h3ZWRGVHF0MktBOEk4YkdDRUY5ZjdraFRTMllYV2J0b0ZIcWFBdkg2YUNvOUxjeUxNX2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgJBVV95cUxOWEZjUDhKb05SLWhOMmxIYnYzb1dBWVJPWU5yWDhCQzlqMy1pTjR5ekNfY3pvU2FXRFhxV2NYRXRncjhQY3lmSkVsTU1KRDFaWTZNQ1dqTjZtdDRRaUd4YkptTnlCNzlHQWdCTFBqZUE2LU45TXhZNlhtbVBwajNqYng5aDFiU3lTYnZjTmpreGJhbDUwU0wwamg0ZGw3VVlLeXN0OGVmcmROdURiMmJtYmpwUVFUemZROElmaFU3cGx4TnZoVXBGUm01NE9wSjQ4TlBLVGVGZGRSTlpvRkFvc2EtS3JNRGpOVVZocDcxRUkzNk9mZTdVV1FDN2FZbU9sanlwRkcwOFBhVWpzNGx4YUpQMndmSXVVMEHSAZ8CQVVfeXFMTkRHbW1ycEdyV092STNHM3k0M0xmTFRhYXNRaXRYTlZqYUZkcnNPQ2ZEVHRhcVNpbUxLc3hCWTZHRUh2VDAtY1NBY0RaV05SaEZuMkdRVTBOM1E2WUlTU29iV21CWWkwRDEyQXBZSnBjYXV4VVdEb3VkRzdRaFdibVNfLU9ic1BIZndxNFYwOTRla1FTelVTMVp4WFdvWWFUczFYVWhZcklQcTlxb0pla0xvMzVxelVNRGx2X2NBOHBUd2dyZ2N1VHA5LU02bDVFOUVBUG1sZ2U2YlBiU0NVOUQtUnhxNFAzV3N5X3h3ZWRGVHF0MktBOEk4YkdDRUY5ZjdraFRTMllYV2J0b0ZIcWFBdkg2YUNvOUxjeUxNX2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['What a way to wrap up 2024': Viswanathan Anand congratulates Vaishali on clinching bronze in World Blitz Championship - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What a way to wrap up 2024: Viswanathan Anand congratulates Vaishali on clinching bronze in World Blitz Championship</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/STABLE_DIFFUSION_OUTCROP/ESD/53fa0ae7-3540-4430-a440-dd4b024123db__UwTT2r0f.jpg" alt="Viswanathan Anand congratulating Vaishali">
<figcaption>Vaishali's impressive performance at the tournament.</figcaption>
<p>Chess legend Viswanathan Anand has expressed his congratulations to Vaishali for her remarkable achievement in clinching a bronze medal at the World Blitz Championship.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Vaishali overcame tough competition to secure her spot.</li>
  <li>Anand's endorsement emphasizes her potential in the chess world.</li>
  <li>This achievement marks a significant milestone in Vaishali's career.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Her dedication and skill have truly shone through in this tournament," Anand remarked.</blockquote>
<p>This bronze medal not only highlights Vaishali's talent but also sets the stage for her future endeavors in competitive chess.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/chess/what-a-way-to-wrap-up-2024-viswanathan-anand-congratulates-vaishali-on-clinching-bronze-in-world-blitz-championship/articleshow/116845805.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/chess/what-a-way-to-wrap-up-2024-viswanathan-anand-congratulates-vaishali-on-clinching-bronze-in-world-blitz-championship/articleshow/116845805.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ranbir Kapoor runs to give Alia Bhatt a hug, snuggles with Raha as they welcome New Year with Neetu Kapoor, Soni Razdan - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ranbir Kapoor runs to give Alia Bhatt a hug, snuggles with Raha as they welcome New Year with Neetu Kapoor, Soni Razdan</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 01, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/01/550x309/alia_bhatt_1735702474265_1735702485480.jpg" alt="(L-R) Bharat Sahni, Neetu Kapoor, Riddhima Kapoor Sahni, Ranbir Kapoor, Raha Kapoor, Alia Bhatt, Soni Razdan, and Samara Sahni celebrated New Year together." />
<figcaption>(L-R) Bharat Sahni, Neetu Kapoor, Riddhima Kapoor Sahni, Ranbir Kapoor, Raha Kapoor, Alia Bhatt, Soni Razdan, and Samara Sahni celebrated New Year together.</figcaption>
<p>The Kapoor and Razdan families rang in the New Year together in a celebratory event on a huge lawn with fireworks.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Alia Bhatt and Ranbir Kapoor celebrated the New Year with their daughter, Raha Kapoor.</li>
  <li>The families included Soni Razdan, Neetu Kapoor, and Riddhima Kapoor Sahni, among others.</li>
  <li>Neetu shared joyful moments on Instagram, including a clip of Ranbir hugging Alia.</li>
  <li>The celebration featured a picturesque outdoor setup next to a swimming pool.</li>
  <li>Fans can look forward to Alia's film Alpha and Ranbir's upcoming projects like Animal Park.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The party’s just begun, and 2025 is ready to shine! #NewYearVibes. Happy New Year, Instagram Fam.” - Riddhima Kapoor Sahni</blockquote>
<p>The warm family gathering highlights the joy of togetherness as they welcomed the New Year with love and laughter.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/ranbir-kapoor-gives-alia-bhatt-a-tight-hug-raha-kapoor-snuggles-with-dad-welcome-new-year-with-neetu-kapoor-soni-razdan-101735699736036.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/ranbir-kapoor-gives-alia-bhatt-a-tight-hug-raha-kapoor-snuggles-with-dad-welcome-new-year-with-neetu-kapoor-soni-razdan-101735699736036.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:00:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suchir Balaji’s mother alleges ‘murder’, demands FBI investigation into OpenAI whistleblower’s death - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Suchir Balaji’s Mother Alleges Murder, Seeks FBI Investigation into Whistleblower's Death</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Fox News</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/56usus/article69048962.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/OpenAI_Whistleblower_Death_77670.jpg" alt="Suchir Balaji poses for a photo in Hawaii in 2018. Balaji was a former OpenAI engineer and whistleblower who died in November 2024. (Balaji Ramamurthy via AP)"><figcaption>Suchir Balaji poses for a photo in Hawaii in 2018. Balaji was a former OpenAI engineer and whistleblower who died in November 2024. (Balaji Ramamurthy via AP)</figcaption><p>Suchir Balaji's mother, Poornima Rao, has accused authorities of declaring her son's death a suicide when she believes it to be murder. She is calling for an FBI investigation into the circumstances surrounding his death.</p><ul><li>Suchir Balaji was found dead in his apartment in San Francisco.</li><li>His mother claims there were signs of struggle and that the apartment was ransacked.</li><li>A private autopsy contradicted the police report regarding the cause of death.</li><li>Elon Musk publicly expressed skepticism about the suicide ruling.</li><li>Balaji previously accused OpenAI of copyright violations related to generative AI.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's a cold blooded mu*d*r declared by authorities as suicide. We demand FBI investigation.” - Poornima Rao</blockquote><p>This case has garnered significant attention, highlighting concerns about the treatment of whistleblowers and the implications of AI technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/openai-whistleblower-suchir-balajis-mother-alleges-murder-demands-fbi-investigation-into-his-death/article69048961.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/openai-whistleblower-suchir-balajis-mother-alleges-murder-demands-fbi-investigation-into-his-death/article69048961.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI whistleblower Suchir Balaji’s mother alleges ‘murder’, demands FBI investigation into his death - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Suchir Balaji’s Mother Alleges Murder, Seeks FBI Investigation into Whistleblower's Death</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Fox News</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/56usus/article69048962.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/OpenAI_Whistleblower_Death_77670.jpg" alt="Suchir Balaji poses for a photo in Hawaii in 2018. Balaji was a former OpenAI engineer and whistleblower who died in November 2024. (Balaji Ramamurthy via AP)"><figcaption>Suchir Balaji poses for a photo in Hawaii in 2018. Balaji was a former OpenAI engineer and whistleblower who died in November 2024. (Balaji Ramamurthy via AP)</figcaption><p>Suchir Balaji's mother, Poornima Rao, has accused authorities of declaring her son's death a suicide when she believes it to be murder. She is calling for an FBI investigation into the circumstances surrounding his death.</p><ul><li>Suchir Balaji was found dead in his apartment in San Francisco.</li><li>His mother claims there were signs of struggle and that the apartment was ransacked.</li><li>A private autopsy contradicted the police report regarding the cause of death.</li><li>Elon Musk publicly expressed skepticism about the suicide ruling.</li><li>Balaji previously accused OpenAI of copyright violations related to generative AI.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's a cold blooded mu*d*r declared by authorities as suicide. We demand FBI investigation.” - Poornima Rao</blockquote><p>This case has garnered significant attention, highlighting concerns about the treatment of whistleblowers and the implications of AI technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/openai-whistleblower-suchir-balajis-mother-alleges-murder-demands-fbi-investigation-into-his-death/article69048961.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/openai-whistleblower-suchir-balajis-mother-alleges-murder-demands-fbi-investigation-into-his-death/article69048961.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anurag Kashyap opens up about why Kennedy wasn’t released, says he has lost the energy to fight: ‘Five of my films are lying unreleased’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anurag Kashyap opens up about why Kennedy wasn’t released, says he has lost the energy to fight: ‘Five of my films are lying unreleased’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/anurag-kashyap-kennedy.jpg?w=640" alt="anurag kashyap kennedy" width="640" height="356"><figcaption>Anurag Kashyap's Kennedy stars Rahul Bhat and Sunny Leone.</figcaption><p>Filmmaker Anurag Kashyap discusses the non-release of his film Kennedy and expresses dissatisfaction with the film industry.</p><ul><li>Kashyap reveals that Kennedy premiered at the 2023 Cannes Film Festival but remains unreleased.</li><li>He mentions five of his projects are currently in limbo and speaks about his detachment from Kennedy.</li><li>He expresses disgust with the film industry, stating it favors profits over creativity.</li><li>Kashyap reflects on the changing film ecosystem and the industry's fear of innovation.</li><li>He shares a personal experience of disappointment and heartbreak following the cancellation of a Netflix series.</li></ul><blockquote>“I have made five films that are lying unreleased. Where is Kennedy?”</blockquote><p>This conversation highlights Kashyap's struggles and critiques of the current state of the Hindi film industry, stressing the need for a focus on creativity and storytelling over financial considerations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/anurag-kashyap-opens-up-about-why-kennedy-wasnt-released-9752816/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/anurag-kashyap-opens-up-about-why-kennedy-wasnt-released-9752816/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir, Rohit Sharma To Be Grilled By BCCI. R Ashwin's Shock Retirement A Big Topic: Report - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI to Question Rohit Sharma and Gautam Gambhir Amidst Cricketing Controversies</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/dpbrov4o_rohit-sharma-and-gautam-gambhir_625x300_17_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Gautam Gambhir, Rohit Sharma"/><figcaption>File photo of Rohit Sharma and Gautam Gambhir</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team is facing scrutiny from the BCCI following a disappointing series that jeopardized World Test Championship qualification. Rohit Sharma's retirement speculation and Gautam Gambhir's decisions as coach are under review as discussions are expected post the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>India's cricket team experienced a string of poor performances, affecting their World Test Championship prospects.</li><li>Gautam Gambhir and Rohit Sharma are expected to face tough questioning from BCCI management.</li><li>Rohit Sharma has had a significant dip in performance, averaging less than 11 runs in his last 15 Test innings.</li><li>There are rumors regarding Rohit Sharma's possible retirement from Test cricket.</li><li>Gambhir's coaching choices, especially regarding player selections, are being evaluated.</li><li>Ravichandran Ashwin's abrupt retirement is also a matter of concern, although Gambhir reportedly had no role in this decision.</li></ul><blockquote>"If I was a selector now... I'd be saying, 'Rohit, thank you for your service. You've been a great player, but we're going to bring in Jasprit Bumrah as captain for the SCG.'" - Mark Waugh</blockquote><p>As the cricketing world watches closely, both Rohit and Gambhir must navigate this critical juncture in their careers, with long-term implications for the team at stake.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-rohit-sharma-to-be-grilled-by-bcci-r-ashwins-shock-retirement-a-big-topic-report-7374610</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-rohit-sharma-to-be-grilled-by-bcci-r-ashwins-shock-retirement-a-big-topic-report-7374610</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:18:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LPG prices: Indian OMCs slash commercial LPG cylinder prices in Delhi, Mumbai and other cities - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_AFBVV95cUxOQXZpTVN2Q0J6aU5jcGZBVmZCRVYwZ2ZBUENnQXVUUURhUHBxUElBSkV4MDBqY0VwVW1ZZVVGdlFSN3YyeEY2eGlMRkNaWkVFNjhtWWZPdmtPUGdoZmZXdGNOWF9LUkZxNHpBWXluUkRVc1RWcENxRmxIX0Zpc1phbVE3WmgtRnMtWDliRmdTcUNNQndkYlhzZ3F3MTZfTjVPaVhwa2EtN2pWbHBQWlNKSFVFWjBvQmg1VTZjcjFYUldUMGRxUE0tVU9zMkZtSDZTYlEtVXFhZ1RTaFBsT0ZLYko1UEZlM19uYVFXaDMyeTBvS1ZrQnVWZG9Vc1_SAYICQVVfeXFMTVJ1dUVJUGtldkxLeHoxTkpHeU5vUUc4cXZaZWtyWmxDbVZhbF9RaUZjODNMeDVSOVJBeUVYWDA1dzdtZ01HYTlCeVR2MkI1Mk1WTlBKcjlfMURxa0hNWXhWOUN2LXpLdHd6XzQ3amJxOUUzcWRBUS1BZloycUNZX1FXUkdnOUJXdk1kcU5jc3M5RDM0SEVGOWdYbldUcUlSRkhOY3V5VjJqQ00yMXp4X2taMU1GVUhucTF3NE1xUWJCYldIQ3FSTE9jS3dEMHdUb0FxX0tuUTZYSzNXT1RxcmUxcUYxc0tTQnRtaXBpSGVGWGx0TnEzeTdaZXJabjV4UTd3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_AFBVV95cUxOQXZpTVN2Q0J6aU5jcGZBVmZCRVYwZ2ZBUENnQXVUUURhUHBxUElBSkV4MDBqY0VwVW1ZZVVGdlFSN3YyeEY2eGlMRkNaWkVFNjhtWWZPdmtPUGdoZmZXdGNOWF9LUkZxNHpBWXluUkRVc1RWcENxRmxIX0Zpc1phbVE3WmgtRnMtWDliRmdTcUNNQndkYlhzZ3F3MTZfTjVPaVhwa2EtN2pWbHBQWlNKSFVFWjBvQmg1VTZjcjFYUldUMGRxUE0tVU9zMkZtSDZTYlEtVXFhZ1RTaFBsT0ZLYko1UEZlM19uYVFXaDMyeTBvS1ZrQnVWZG9Vc1_SAYICQVVfeXFMTVJ1dUVJUGtldkxLeHoxTkpHeU5vUUc4cXZaZWtyWmxDbVZhbF9RaUZjODNMeDVSOVJBeUVYWDA1dzdtZ01HYTlCeVR2MkI1Mk1WTlBKcjlfMURxa0hNWXhWOUN2LXpLdHd6XzQ3amJxOUUzcWRBUS1BZloycUNZX1FXUkdnOUJXdk1kcU5jc3M5RDM0SEVGOWdYbldUcUlSRkhOY3V5VjJqQ00yMXp4X2taMU1GVUhucTF3NE1xUWJCYldIQ3FSTE9jS3dEMHdUb0FxX0tuUTZYSzNXT1RxcmUxcUYxc0tTQnRtaXBpSGVGWGx0TnEzeTdaZXJabjV4UTd3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:14:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>