<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 08:24:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 08:24:59 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shreyas Iyer Set To Create History, Will Become 1st Indian Cricketer To Captain 3 IPL Teams - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shreyas Iyer to Make History as First Indian to Captain Three IPL Teams</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Shreyas Iyer will become first Indian player to captain three IPL teams. (Picture Credit: X/@PunjabKingsIPL and X/@ShreyasIyer15)"><figcaption>Shreyas Iyer will become first Indian player to captain three IPL teams. (Picture Credit: X/@PunjabKingsIPL and X/@ShreyasIyer15)</figcaption><p>Star Indian cricketer Shreyas Iyer has been appointed captain of Punjab Kings for the 2025 IPL season, making him the first Indian to lead three different IPL teams.</p><ul><li>Iyer will captain Punjab Kings starting from the IPL 2025 season, beginning March 21.</li><li>This marks Iyer's third team, following his previous roles with Delhi Capitals and Kolkata Knight Riders.</li><li>He has already won the IPL title with KKR in 2024 and led Delhi Capitals to the finals in 2020.</li><li>Iyer is now the 17th player to captain Punjab Kings in the IPL history.</li><li>He won 38 out of 70 matches as captain, ranking him as the sixth most successful captain in IPL history.</li></ul><blockquote>“Iyer created history as he became the first Indian player to captain three IPL teams.”</blockquote><p>This milestone highlights Iyer's significant impact on the league and showcases his leadership skills in one of cricket's most lucrative tournaments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/shreyas-iyer-set-to-create-history-will-become-1st-indian-cricketer-to-9186786.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/shreyas-iyer-set-to-create-history-will-become-1st-indian-cricketer-to-9186786.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 08:20:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balanced vegetarian diets for aspiring athletes: What you need to know - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Balanced Vegetarian Diets for Aspiring Athletes: What You Need to Know</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://indianexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/1_04cac4.jpg" alt="Balanced vegetarian diets for aspiring athletes: What you need to know" width="720" height="1280">
<figcaption>Balanced vegetarian diets for aspiring athletes: What you need to know</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses how vegetarian diets can effectively meet the nutritional needs of aspiring athletes, emphasizing critical nutrients for performance and recovery.</p>
<ul>
<li>Vegetarian athletes often struggle to meet protein, iron, calcium, vitamin B12, and omega-3 fatty acid needs.</li>
<li>Plant proteins from whole grains, quinoa, lentils, and beans can help fulfill protein requirements.</li>
<li>Combining vitamin C-rich foods with iron-rich meals can enhance iron absorption.</li>
<li>Vitamin B12 can be obtained from supplements or fortified foods like plant-based milks.</li>
<li>Sources of calcium and omega-3s include tofu, almonds, leafy greens, and flaxseeds.</li>
<li>A balanced vegetarian diet should focus on whole foods, seasonal fruits, healthy fats, and electrolyte-rich drinks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A balanced, whole-food-based vegetarian diet is crucial for aspiring athletes.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, athletes considering a vegetarian diet must be mindful of their nutritional intake to ensure optimal performance and recovery.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/web-stories/life-style/balanced-vegetarian-diets-for-aspiring-athletes-what-you-need-to-know/9774461/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/web-stories/life-style/balanced-vegetarian-diets-for-aspiring-athletes-what-you-need-to-know/9774461/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:30:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spacewalk Preps, Biology Research Wrap Up Week Aboard Station - Space Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQRFpnVFpWTU1jdkpFR2I2ZTF6ZWM0b0ZoVEdZbWpMSm53QldXVXJpM0gzVXdISC1KS0phYlA4NldDZkJONFNDdnktYkY3c2VTWUpnSXgwVG9RalBVVF91eGl4aUdrMEVScHVwYmlfUFFqa1ZBVEkwTVlYdmE1TGRnLU9nRVQ1WDZhZE81LVMwRGJiUmYyYlY5WkJ6U1VkYjREOGhHeF9VUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQRFpnVFpWTU1jdkpFR2I2ZTF6ZWM0b0ZoVEdZbWpMSm53QldXVXJpM0gzVXdISC1KS0phYlA4NldDZkJONFNDdnktYkY3c2VTWUpnSXgwVG9RalBVVF91eGl4aUdrMEVScHVwYmlfUFFqa1ZBVEkwTVlYdmE1TGRnLU9nRVQ1WDZhZE81LVMwRGJiUmYyYlY5WkJ6U1VkYjREOGhHeF9VUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JVC marks India comeback with Google TV-based QLED TV range: Details here - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JVC marks India comeback with Google TV-based QLED TV range: Details here</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Press Release</p><p>JVC (Japan Victor Company) has re-entered the Indian market with a new range of smart QLED televisions manufactured locally. The series includes seven different sizes starting from Rs 11,999, available on Amazon India during its Republic Day Sale.</p><img src='jvc-qled-tv.jpg' alt='JVC QLED TV'><figcaption>JVC's new range of QLED TVs.</figcaption><p>The JVC TVs, known as the AI Vision series, feature Google TV, up to 4K UHD resolution, 60Hz refresh rate, and support for HDR10. They come with various connectivity options and advanced audio technologies.</p><ul><li>Available sizes: 32-inch to 75-inch</li><li>Starting price: Rs 11,999</li><li>Powered by Google TV</li><li>Up to 4K UHD resolution</li><li>Supports popular streaming services</li></ul><blockquote>“We are thrilled to introduce JVC’s cutting-edge television range to Indian consumers. India is one of the fastest-growing markets in the world...” – Pallavi Singh, JVC TV India.</blockquote><p>JVC aims to achieve Rs 500 crore in revenue over the next three years by expanding its product range and enhancing customer engagement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/gadgets/jvc-marks-india-comeback-with-google-tv-based-qled-tv-range-details-here-125011300371_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/gadgets/jvc-marks-india-comeback-with-google-tv-based-qled-tv-range-details-here-125011300371_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:16:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Situation sensitive but stable’: Army Chief on LAC disengagement, J-K infiltration bids - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Situation sensitive but stable’: Army chief on India-China disengagement along LAC</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/10/PTI10_22_2024_000099B.jpg?w=640" alt="india-china LAC agreement" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Chief of the Army Staff General Upendra Dwivedi during a press conference, in New Delhi. (PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>Army Chief General Upendra Dwivedi addressed the disengagement efforts along the India-China border, stating that the situation across the LAC remains "sensitive but stable." He highlighted that traditional patrolling and grazing in areas like Depsang and Demchok have resumed.</p><ul><li>The army’s deployment along the LAC is described as balanced and robust, capable of handling any situation.</li><li>Focus on enhancing border infrastructure and capability development is underway.</li><li>General Dwivedi noted ongoing cross-border terrorism support from Pakistan in Jammu and Kashmir.</li><li>The situation in Manipur is reportedly under control due to proactive measures by security forces.</li></ul><blockquote>“In the last year, 60 percent of the terrorists eliminated in Jammu and Kashmir were from Pakistan,” said General Dwivedi.</blockquote><p>The Indian Army continues to monitor and address threats while striving for stability and peace in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/army-chief-lac-jammu-kashmir-situation-stable-9776048/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/army-chief-lac-jammu-kashmir-situation-stable-9776048/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:49:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SENSEX, NIFTY50 continue to bleed, down 12% from record highs; top factors behind the market's free fall - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxQRllhSmZsbFdGQUJpRTZVM2RmZkRPbkZUY0xWdVlUa0Q3Uzg3aC01bTYtN3BwSjhyZGxVVkhoRFQtRHUtaXZxR0g1Sno5UnoxRWZKSzNzVVdwU0xzbUtmSVJlaGF6MUVEa3Nxb2dYd2lGd3FFelMxcTEyNTdEMGJZMlpwMGxDRWhlTGJmbmdXcEtwTV8zdHdwaV82anNod2F5NUR0MDg0NFktQVhycFQ0eHV3a2NMazFYUVZ3V0YxZ1pOU1Z1Q2hhMmVIbjVkMlZnZS1OVEZSeDRINENkcXphNm1uX0FpLVphR25JY3BTeHVPRkU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxQRllhSmZsbFdGQUJpRTZVM2RmZkRPbkZUY0xWdVlUa0Q3Uzg3aC01bTYtN3BwSjhyZGxVVkhoRFQtRHUtaXZxR0g1Sno5UnoxRWZKSzNzVVdwU0xzbUtmSVJlaGF6MUVEa3Nxb2dYd2lGd3FFelMxcTEyNTdEMGJZMlpwMGxDRWhlTGJmbmdXcEtwTV8zdHdwaV82anNod2F5NUR0MDg0NFktQVhycFQ0eHV3a2NMazFYUVZ3V0YxZ1pOU1Z1Q2hhMmVIbjVkMlZnZS1OVEZSeDRINENkcXphNm1uX0FpLVphR25JY3BTeHVPRkU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:46:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daaku Maharaaj Box Office Collections: Second biggest opening for a NBK film - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daaku Maharaaj Box Office Collections: Second biggest opening for a NBK film</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p><div><img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/1531299210_daku1.jpg" alt="Daaku Maharaaj," title="NBK in Daaku Maharaaj (image courtesy of Sithara Ent)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>NBK in Daaku Maharaaj (image courtesy of Sithara Ent)</figcaption></div><p>Daaku Maharaaj recorded the second-biggest opening for an NBK starrer at the Indian box office, amassing Rs. 26 crore approx. The film had an unconventional Sunday release but it is common for Telugu films to release on off days during the Sankranti period.</p><ul><li>The biggest opening for NBK in Telugu states is Rs. 30.25 crore from Veera Simha Reddy.</li><li>Almost all of the business for Daaku Maharaaj came from the Telugu states at Rs. 23 crore approx.</li><li>The film is expected to perform significantly well during the Sankranti period.</li><li>Overseas, it opened nearly USD 1 million on its first day in the United States.</li></ul><blockquote>“The initial reception seems to be decent enough.”</blockquote><p>Daaku Maharaaj's success at the box office indicates a strong interest in Telugu cinema, particularly during advantageous release periods.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/daaku-maharaaj-box-office-collections-second-biggest-opening-for-a-nbk-film-1367091</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/daaku-maharaaj-box-office-collections-second-biggest-opening-for-a-nbk-film-1367091</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:42:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Apocalyptic Theories About the End of the Universe - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Apocalyptic Theories About the End of the Universe</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/webstories/uploads/2025/01/cropped-12-2025-01-3289075d5a344b48511df3e7d0342da0.jpg" alt="Apocalyptic Theories" />
<figcaption>Discover fascinating theories about how the universe might end.</figcaption>
<p>This article explores ten fascinating apocalyptic theories regarding the possible end of the universe, including the Big Crunch and vacuum decay, while delving into the scientific explanations behind these cosmic scenarios.</p>
<ul>
  <li>1. <strong>Big Crunch:</strong> The universe stops expanding and collapses in reverse into a singularity.</li>
  <li>2. <strong>Big Freeze:</strong> Expansion continues forever, leaving a dark, cold universe as all stars burn out.</li>
  <li>3. <strong>Big Rip:</strong> Dark energy accelerates expansion, tearing apart atoms and galaxies.</li>
  <li>4. <strong>Heat Death:</strong> The universe reaches maximum entropy, becoming an inert, lifeless cosmos.</li>
  <li>5. <strong>Vacuum Decay:</strong> A quantum event triggers a destructive bubble at lightspeed.</li>
  <li>6. <strong>Multiverse Collision:</strong> Our universe collides with another, leading to cosmic obliteration.</li>
  <li>7. <strong>Black Hole Era:</strong> Only black holes remain, consuming everything until they evaporate.</li>
  <li>8. <strong>False Vacuum Theory:</strong> The universe suddenly transitions to a catastrophic form.</li>
  <li>9. <strong>Entropy Reversal:</strong> If time reverses, unpredictable outcomes could end life.</li>
  <li>10. <strong>End of Dark Energy:</strong> A reversal of dark energy may lead to cosmic collapse.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Explore the science behind these cosmic doomsday scenarios!”</blockquote>
<p>This article presents insightful theories on the potential fates awaiting the universe, sparking curiosity about cosmic phenomena.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/10-apocalyptic-theories-about-the-end-of-the-universe-visual-story-2752067.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/10-apocalyptic-theories-about-the-end-of-the-universe-visual-story-2752067.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:41:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Z-Morh tunnel: Thousands brave winter chill to attend inauguration by PM Modi in Sonamarg - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxQbU5tb3FQQl9hNHFiVmVhaFdkNmlTOWNETHpWczJSdjEwd3E1WjVhTWVITk11Sjd6UHM4Y21CN1YtQUZ3bm5uUGJjWUw2ZXk3YWg2ZDE5NjNPSUFWMUo5S0pITC1sN0haOEw1UEFfVnFLV3lwa3BycFJRVUZ4OEhNWGRYVUZtZTdXMVllakk5a2hoZXhOTWdoWjFGdXMxVEMtNmMzLUxfZVdjbS16MjZ6NTJpaUtPcXNJZkgwb0t5c0Y1c2E3YlE1SDZiMWLSAdIBQVVfeXFMTXpTWWcwMkFHZTE2Ymc5UFlyUzlZbEdoNmlubnlMYW8yVmtQQUdNN3FmWWgxX2ZBRjRsd2ZrYUpDMnloRW1hSlJjU1lMTGtIbTZOSkJnV09Nc3lJQUFLSEdZUlA4TkpfZXZmN0JyY0FrZHhNcExRRjNfYzNQUHMtUmlzbWJYdlBBeF8zelNVMmhyN3RLdklYaWNoTGd4eHpQSHZET2V0enFSUWZxaHl1bTRYLXRURWp5UkRYZGtNNV9oMVVKdEk2TFoycUVjLW4zWVVB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxQbU5tb3FQQl9hNHFiVmVhaFdkNmlTOWNETHpWczJSdjEwd3E1WjVhTWVITk11Sjd6UHM4Y21CN1YtQUZ3bm5uUGJjWUw2ZXk3YWg2ZDE5NjNPSUFWMUo5S0pITC1sN0haOEw1UEFfVnFLV3lwa3BycFJRVUZ4OEhNWGRYVUZtZTdXMVllakk5a2hoZXhOTWdoWjFGdXMxVEMtNmMzLUxfZVdjbS16MjZ6NTJpaUtPcXNJZkgwb0t5c0Y1c2E3YlE1SDZiMWLSAdIBQVVfeXFMTXpTWWcwMkFHZTE2Ymc5UFlyUzlZbEdoNmlubnlMYW8yVmtQQUdNN3FmWWgxX2ZBRjRsd2ZrYUpDMnloRW1hSlJjU1lMTGtIbTZOSkJnV09Nc3lJQUFLSEdZUlA4TkpfZXZmN0JyY0FrZHhNcExRRjNfYzNQUHMtUmlzbWJYdlBBeF8zelNVMmhyN3RLdklYaWNoTGd4eHpQSHZET2V0enFSUWZxaHl1bTRYLXRURWp5UkRYZGtNNV9oMVVKdEk2TFoycUVjLW4zWVVB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:10:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Stunning Images Of Nebulas Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Stunning Images of Nebulas Captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/117192558/117192558.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=725443" alt="Stunning Nebulas Captured by NASA" />
<figcaption>Credit: ESA/Hubble-NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases seven breathtaking images taken by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting various nebulae across the universe.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Includes captivating images and descriptions of different nebulae.</li>
  <li>Features the Hubble's observations of star formation in various cosmic regions.</li>
  <li>Describes the astronomical significance and beauty of these celestial phenomena.</li>
  <li>Provides insights into the locations and characteristics of each nebula.</li>
  <li>Spotlights the technological advancements of the Hubble Space Telescope.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Astronomers captured stunning images to mark the ongoing contributions of the Hubble Space Telescope.”</blockquote>
<p>The article emphasizes the importance of these celestial imagery in expanding our understanding of the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-stunning-images-of-nebulas-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/117192528.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-stunning-images-of-nebulas-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/117192528.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:03:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IREDA share price jumps over 5% on strong guidance, ₹4,500-crore QIP buzz | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IREDA Share Price Rises Over 5% Amid Strong Guidance and QIP Plans</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Last updated on Monday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>IREDA share price jumped over 5% on Monday due to positive guidance from the company and plans for a ₹4,500-crore Qualified Institutional Placement (QIP), despite a broader stock market downturn.</p><ul><li>IREDA stock price increased by 5.51% to ₹212.30 on BSE.</li><li>Strong guidance followed by Q3 FY25 results showing a 27% growth in net profit.</li><li>Approval from the government for raising ₹4,500 crore through fresh equity.</li><li>The government likely to dilute up to 7% stake in IREDA via QIP.</li><li>Improvement in asset quality with NPAs down to 2.68% from 2.90% YoY.</li></ul><blockquote>“The fund-raising exercise aims to strengthen IREDA’s capital base, enabling the organization to scale its financing for renewable energy projects.” - IREDA</blockquote><p>The rise in IREDA's share price highlights investor confidence and the positive outlook for the renewable energy sector in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/ireda-share-price-jumps-over-5-on-strong-guidance-rs-4-500-crore-qip-buzz-11736747181302.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/ireda-share-price-jumps-over-5-on-strong-guidance-rs-4-500-crore-qip-buzz-11736747181302.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:52:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires live updates: More than 7.7 million people to face critical-fire weather conditions - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxNYnRBQlNVU3JrNkR0M0M5YjlxX09JSXAtaVdpc0ZrYzVtUUR3Z3U5c1BmaEJ4ME9rVkU5NkVfWDA5UTBZUkxwRExUQ1k4cFdVSUg5clBBOEFFbGZCOUVZMFlybXYwdzYwNGhqbVRTaEY2aThMdWhGeGJRTEZLUnNFVkNJRFdVTEZaQmlTOUFpbFRSYS00UmlJNVY3YnZlekVLeGRxa3BRWF9KeDQyQURzekZoWFJQS3JPVDAwX29zNHNJZE9BVXJOU0N1bkhzX2J1T0ZRTm1LUlA5cVBTaHlkWmhrai1qSEhPdmNjVdIB8gFBVV95cUxPUVFrZUR4UEFGYTFsM3dmRlA0YUVEbGhzXzhnc1A2Wm5XSEFmSDFZRVM1cElOTy1HMnZ0U1dnZmxWTi14clMtTk5IQ0R5ZFl5NTFzbXZPZFhhRU5QQ2p6cmN3UWlsc21jcFFES1VCMlA3TFBDTkl0VFpuaHJWbDBaZFlnTll0bzdUOUFWZzBYMEhhLW9HbHJUMW52N0VCT1h6X0JPOUZKSjE1XzVIcV9sQ25HUnU1UkFDUmZ6SFFXb2pGWnFGdnlWcFBDN25TbUVULXRvMDV6eDdLdjhQVVZtWW9YWlZWVHVoQS1fcjE2SU5EQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxNYnRBQlNVU3JrNkR0M0M5YjlxX09JSXAtaVdpc0ZrYzVtUUR3Z3U5c1BmaEJ4ME9rVkU5NkVfWDA5UTBZUkxwRExUQ1k4cFdVSUg5clBBOEFFbGZCOUVZMFlybXYwdzYwNGhqbVRTaEY2aThMdWhGeGJRTEZLUnNFVkNJRFdVTEZaQmlTOUFpbFRSYS00UmlJNVY3YnZlekVLeGRxa3BRWF9KeDQyQURzekZoWFJQS3JPVDAwX29zNHNJZE9BVXJOU0N1bkhzX2J1T0ZRTm1LUlA5cVBTaHlkWmhrai1qSEhPdmNjVdIB8gFBVV95cUxPUVFrZUR4UEFGYTFsM3dmRlA0YUVEbGhzXzhnc1A2Wm5XSEFmSDFZRVM1cElOTy1HMnZ0U1dnZmxWTi14clMtTk5IQ0R5ZFl5NTFzbXZPZFhhRU5QQ2p6cmN3UWlsc21jcFFES1VCMlA3TFBDTkl0VFpuaHJWbDBaZFlnTll0bzdUOUFWZzBYMEhhLW9HbHJUMW52N0VCT1h6X0JPOUZKSjE1XzVIcV9sQ25HUnU1UkFDUmZ6SFFXb2pGWnFGdnlWcFBDN25TbUVULXRvMDV6eDdLdjhQVVZtWW9YWlZWVHVoQS1fcjE2SU5EQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xiaomi Pad 7 goes on sale in India with introductory offers: Watch unboxing - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Xiaomi Pad 7 goes on sale in India with introductory offers: Watch unboxing</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 13 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> BS Tech</p><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" title="Xiaomi Pad 7" alt="Xiaomi Pad 7" width="826" height="465"><figcaption>Xiaomi Pad 7</figcaption><p>The Xiaomi Pad 7 has launched in India, featuring a productivity-focused interface powered by Qualcomm's Snapdragon 7 Plus Gen 3. Customers can enjoy introductory discounts and a range of accessories available for separate purchase.</p><ul><li>The tablet supports 8GB or 12GB of RAM with storage options of 128GB and 256GB.</li><li>Price starts at Rs 27,999 with various color options like Graphite Grey and Sage Green.</li><li>Customers can avail a Rs 1,000 discount on select ICICI Bank cards.</li><li>Specifications include an 11.2-inch LCD with 3200x2136 resolution and 144Hz refresh rate.</li></ul><blockquote>“Xiaomi Pad 7 is here to redefine productivity with its advanced features and accessories.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Xiaomi Pad 7 offers great technology at competitive pricing, along with attractive introductory offers for new customers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/xiaomi-pad-7-goes-on-sale-in-india-with-introductory-offers-watch-unboxing-125011300257_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/xiaomi-pad-7-goes-on-sale-in-india-with-introductory-offers-watch-unboxing-125011300257_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:45:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market today: BSE Sensex crashes 800 points & Nifty50 tests 23,200; rupee dips to life-time low of - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BSE Sensex Plummets 800 Points; Nifty50 Hits 23,200 as Rupee Reaches Record Low</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 3, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<img src="https://example.com/image.jpg" alt="Stock Market Crash" />
<figcaption>Stock market experiencing major downturn.</figcaption>
<p>Today, the BSE Sensex suffered a significant crash of 800 points, while the Nifty50 tested the 23,200 mark. The Indian rupee dipped to a lifetime low against the US dollar, reaching 86.</p>
<ul>
<li>BSE Sensex fell by 800 points, a severe drop.</li>
<li>Nifty50 touched 23,200 amid market volatility.</li>
<li>Rupee's value hit a record low of 86 against the US dollar.</li>
<li>Global market trends influenced the crash.</li>
<li>Investor sentiment has turned bearish.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"It's a tough day for investors as global uncertainties loom large over Indian markets." - Market Analyst</blockquote>
<p>This downturn highlights the increasing volatility of markets and the economic challenges faced by investors in the current climate.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/stock-market-today-bse-sensex-nifty50-january-13-2025-dalal-street-indian-equities-global-markets/articleshow/117188714.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/stock-market-today-bse-sensex-nifty50-january-13-2025-dalal-street-indian-equities-global-markets/articleshow/117188714.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13 Amazon Exchange offer: How to buy the latest OnePlus mobile under ₹40,000 - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 Amazon Exchange offer: How to buy the latest OnePlus mobile under ₹40,000</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 7 January 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><p>OnePlus 13, the latest flagship from OnePlus, is now available for open sale in India. Launched earlier this month, the phone is priced at ₹69,999. Here, let us tell you how you can get it for much less than that by combining two offers: an exchange offer and a bank discount.</p><h2>Here's how you can grab the OnePlus 13 for under ₹40,000</h2><p>Currently, the OnePlus 13 is selling at its full price of ₹69,999. However, if you have a compatible credit card, you can get an instant discount of ₹5,000. This brings the price down to ₹64,999.</p><p>To make the deal even better, exchange offers are available. For example, if you own a OnePlus 12, you can trade in your old phone for a good amount. Amazon is offering up to ₹28,500 for the exchange of a OnePlus 12 base model, provided the device is in optimal condition. After factoring in the exchange offer, the effective price drops to ₹36,499.</p><p>At this price, the OnePlus 13 becomes a value for money deal, especially since it features cutting-edge internals like the Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset. There are additional offers as well, such as no-cost EMI plans for up to 12 months.</p><h2>OnePlus 13: Should you buy?</h2><p>For its price, the OnePlus 13 is one of the most powerful smartphones available. It comes in fun colours, including Midnight (with a vegan leather back), Arctic Dawn, and Black Eclipse. It offers up to 1TB of storage and 24GB RAM, perfect for power users. The device features a 6,000mAh battery for long-lasting performance, and Hasselblad-tuned cameras have significant improvements, along with a refined design.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tech.hindustantimes.com/mobile/news/oneplus-13-amazon-exchange-offer-how-to-buy-the-latest-oneplus-mobile-under-rs-40000-71736746200469.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tech.hindustantimes.com/mobile/news/oneplus-13-amazon-exchange-offer-how-to-buy-the-latest-oneplus-mobile-under-rs-40000-71736746200469.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:37:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tripura High Court Seeks Updated Statistics Of HIV/ AIDS Patients In State - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tripura High Court Seeks Updated Statistics Of HIV/ AIDS Patients In State</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <span>Date not provided</span></p><p><strong>Source:</strong> <span>Live Law</span></p><p>The <b>Tripura High Court</b> has ordered the Tripura State AIDS Control Society to submit updated statistics regarding the incidence of HIV/AIDS patients, emphasizing the need to evaluate the effectiveness of ongoing measures against the rising trend of cases.</p><ul><li>The court is addressing the issue through a suo moto PIL and has requested the National AIDS Control Organization (NACO) for establishment approvals of new treatment centers.</li><li>The court noted existing facilities, including 24 Stand Alone Integrated Counseling & Testing Centres and 133 more integrated ones for testing services.</li><li>Enhanced support for high-risk groups is highlighted through various initiatives, including 23 Opioid Substitution Therapy centres.</li><li>A progress report from the Tripura State AIDS Control Society is mandated by the court.</li></ul><blockquote>“Three numbers of PPP model ICTC Centres and one number of Mobile ICTC Van is functional in the State.”</blockquote><p>The matter will be revisited in court on February 20.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/tripura-high-court/tripura-high-court-aids-control-statistics-of-hiv-patients-280746</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/tripura-high-court/tripura-high-court-aids-control-statistics-of-hiv-patients-280746</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:30:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can astronauts have sex in space, how will a child born in space look like? - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can Astronauts Have Sex in Space and What Would a Child Born in Space Look Like?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><figure><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/birth-in-space.png?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Can astronauts have sex in space, how will a child born in space look like?"><figcaption>Can astronauts have sex in space, how will a child born in space look like?</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Life Beyond Earth:</strong> Humans have long been fascinated by the possibility of life beyond Earth. As exploration progresses, questions surface about human reproduction in space. Can a human child be born in space?</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Pregnancy can potentially occur in space, but poses significant risks due to the unique environment.</li><li>Zero gravity can lead to a loss of bone density, making childbirth dangerous.</li><li>Radiation in space can cause genetic abnormalities or health issues for the fetus.</li><li>A child born in space could exhibit abnormal growth patterns due to the absence of gravity.</li><li>Previous animal experiments in space provided some insights but do not guarantee similar success in humans.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics:</h2><blockquote>“In zero gravity, astronauts lose bone density by up to 12 percent in just six months.”</blockquote><p>Ultimately, while the exploration of human life in space remains an exciting frontier, significant challenges must be addressed before reproduction in space becomes feasible.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/viral/can-astronauts-have-sex-in-space-how-will-a-child-born-in-space-look-like-7534054/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/viral/can-astronauts-have-sex-in-space-how-will-a-child-born-in-space-look-like-7534054/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:26:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Changer Box Office Collections: Ram Charan and Shankar film scores a mere 125cr weekend worldwide - PINKVILLA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Changer Box Office Collections: Ram Charan and Shankar film scores a mere 125cr weekend worldwide</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Pinkvilla</p>
<img width="855" height="855" src="https://www.pinkvilla.com/images/2025-01/1091731379_gc1.jpg" alt="Ram Charan," title="Ram Charan in Game Changer (image courtesy of AA Films)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Ram Charan in Game Changer (image courtesy of AA Films)</figcaption>
<p>Game Changer has faced a significant decline in box office collections, ending the weekend with a total of Rs. 125 crore globally.</p>
<ul>
<li>The film earned approximately Rs. 17.50 crore on its last day, bringing domestic collections to just under Rs. 100 crore.</li>
<li>Overseas revenue added another Rs. 25 crore, totaling Rs. 125 crore worldwide.</li>
<li>In the Telugu states, collections were particularly low, with only Rs. 6.50 crore reported on Sunday, one of the lowest figures for a major release.</li>
<li>Expectations were high for the film to exceed Rs. 100 crore due to the Sankranti holidays, but forecasts now suggest a closing around Rs. 75-80 crore in those regions.</li>
<li>The film's performance in other South Indian states was similarly weak, contributing to an overall disappointing performance.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It is essentially 'game over' for Game Changer as collections have plummeted to alarmingly low levels.”</blockquote>
<p>The disappointing box office performance of Game Changer marks a notable event in the current film landscape, reflecting significant struggles in achieving commercial success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/game-changer-box-office-collections-ram-charan-and-shankar-film-scores-a-mere-125cr-weekend-worldwide-1367068</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pinkvilla.com/entertainment/box-office/game-changer-box-office-collections-ram-charan-and-shankar-film-scores-a-mere-125cr-weekend-worldwide-1367068</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:21:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi to inaugurate Z-Morh tunnel: All you need to know - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi to Inaugurate Z-Morh Tunnel: All You Need to Know</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/x8p93o/article69094370.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/12205_13_1_2025_8_41_42_2_07_PRIMEMINISTERNARENDRAMODITOINAUGURATEZ_MORHTUNNELINSONAMARG_SGR_13_01_2025.JPG" alt="Paramilitary soldiers stand guard near Z-Morh Tunnel" title="Paramilitary soldiers stand guard near Z-Morh Tunnel at Gagangir area of Ganderbal in central Kashmir which is scheduled to be inaugurated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi."><figcaption>Paramilitary soldiers stand guard near Z-Morh Tunnel at Gagangir area of Ganderbal in central Kashmir.</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will inaugurate the strategically important Z-Morh tunnel in Ganderbal district of Jammu and Kashmir. This 6.5 km tunnel improves connectivity, making summer travel to Ladakh easier, and completes a significant infrastructure milestone that began in May 2015.</p><ul><li>The Z-Morh tunnel enhances all-weather connectivity, bypassing problematic avalanche and landslide routes.</li><li>It facilitates civilian and military access to the strategically critical Ladakh region.</li><li>The tunnel greatly reduces travel time between Srinagar and Sonamarg by allowing speeds up to 70 km/h.</li><li>It is expected to boost winter tourism in Sonamarg, making it accessible year-round.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Z-Morh tunnel will open Sonamarg to tourism all year round,” said Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah.</blockquote><p>This initiative marks a significant move towards improving infrastructure and boosting tourism in the region, with long-term benefits for both the local economy and military logistics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/jammu-and-kashmir/z-morh-tunnel-jammu-and-kashmir-sonamarg-all-you-need-to-know/article69094356.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/jammu-and-kashmir/z-morh-tunnel-jammu-and-kashmir-sonamarg-all-you-need-to-know/article69094356.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah, Kuldeep Yadav the reason behind India's delay in Champions Trophy squad announcement - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bumrah and Kuldeep's Fitness Concerns Delay India's Champions Trophy Squad Announcement</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/bumrah-getty-new-2022_1663936815295_1736742613705.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah suffered from back spasms during Sydney Test(Getty)"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah suffered from back spasms during Sydney Test(Getty)</figcaption><p>India's delayed announcement of the Champions Trophy squad is attributed to the fitness concerns regarding key players Jasprit Bumrah and Kuldeep Yadav. The selectors have reached a consensus to include them despite uncertainty about their fitness.</p><ul><li>Bangladesh, New Zealand, England, and Afghanistan have already announced their squads, while India has yet to do so.</li><li>The BCCI reportedly sought an extension for the squad announcement deadline, which was originally January 12.</li><li>Bumrah faces a potential absence from the Champions Trophy group-stage matches due to back injury concerns.</li><li>Kuldeep has been out since October due to a groin injury but is expected to recover by the end of January.</li><li>Selectors are considering including Mohammed Shami in the squad, who has recently returned to international cricket.</li></ul><blockquote>"All cricket boards had to send their preliminary teams by midnight of January 12."</blockquote><p>The delay poses challenges as the tournament is set to begin on February 19 in Pakistan and the UAE, but India still has a window to finalize their squad by February 13.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-kuldeep-yadav-the-reason-behind-indias-delay-in-champions-trophy-squad-announcement-101736742509524.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-kuldeep-yadav-the-reason-behind-indias-delay-in-champions-trophy-squad-announcement-101736742509524.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:51:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Jio launches 5.5G network in India with speed boost - Tech in Asia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNOXRoZDlTNnFWSGdEbk9feENvbDl3d3pRbi1QQklnMmxBQ09INlV0NnNoUTA5ZXprZDZGMl94bHZhZlgtT01CSUh3SkRRWUlFVElTZUZRME16Q1JibldHN0pxbk9pcG1UVEpfWTduQjh6LVpfT3JIWkE4ZFpCN0R2MFhiYmk5eDUzY2NF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNOXRoZDlTNnFWSGdEbk9feENvbDl3d3pRbi1QQklnMmxBQ09INlV0NnNoUTA5ZXprZDZGMl94bHZhZlgtT01CSUh3SkRRWUlFVElTZUZRME16Q1JibldHN0pxbk9pcG1UVEpfWTduQjh6LVpfT3JIWkE4ZFpCN0R2MFhiYmk5eDUzY2NF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rupee set for biggest single day fall in nearly two years: Key drivers explained - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rupee at Record Low: Dealers Explain Key Factors Behind the Drop</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 10:14 AM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Rupee at record low: Dealers explain key factors behind the drop" /><figcaption>Rupee at record low: Dealers explain key factors behind the drop</figcaption><p>The Indian rupee has plunged to a new low against the US dollar, crossing the 86.50/$ mark, driven by several key factors.</p><ul><li>**Strengthening US Dollar:** The dollar index has increased to its highest level in over two years due to strong US job growth and anticipation of slower Federal Reserve rate cuts.</li><li>**Surge in Crude Oil Prices:** Brent crude prices have risen, increasing import costs and widening India's trade deficit.</li><li>**Foreign Fund Outflows:** Consistent selling by foreign institutional investors has pressured the rupee further.</li><li>**Weak Domestic Market Sentiment:** Domestic equity markets have shown weakness, correlating with global trends.</li><li>**Declining Forex Reserves:** India’s forex reserves have decreased, impacting the currency's strength against external pressures.</li></ul><blockquote>“Forex traders warn of continued volatility, especially with the US dollar expected to remain strong.”</blockquote><p>This situation suggests ongoing volatility for the rupee, dependent on global market trends and domestic performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/currency/rupee-vs-dollar-biggest-single-day-fall-in-two-years-crude-oil-factors-19538895.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/currency/rupee-vs-dollar-biggest-single-day-fall-in-two-years-crude-oil-factors-19538895.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:44:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Country's not for sale': Ex-Trudeau ally Jagmeet Singh slams Trump over Canada annexation remarks - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Country's not for sale': Ex-Trudeau ally Jagmeet Singh slams Trump over Canada annexation remarks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>Jagmeet Singh, the former ally of Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, has publicly condemned remarks made by Donald Trump regarding the annexation of Canada. Singh asserts that Canada is not for sale and emphasizes the importance of national sovereignty.</p><ul><li>Singh rebukes Trump's comments on Canadian territory.</li><li>Calls for respect towards Canada's sovereignty.</li><li>Highlights the potential implications of such remarks on international relations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Canada is not for sale,” Singh stated emphatically.</blockquote><p>This event draws attention to the ongoing dynamics between Canada and the U.S., particularly regarding political rhetoric that could affect diplomatic relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/countrys-not-for-sale-ex-trudeau-ally-jagmeet-singh-slams-trump-over-canada-annexation-remarks/articleshow/117189385.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/countrys-not-for-sale-ex-trudeau-ally-jagmeet-singh-slams-trump-over-canada-annexation-remarks/articleshow/117189385.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Accused in Bengaluru cow horror arrested - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/accused-in-bengaluru-cow-horror-arrested/article69094299.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/accused-in-bengaluru-cow-horror-arrested/article69094299.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Standard Glass Lining shares list at 23% premium over IPO price on NSE - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPM1VmRTZxNWFUM0t6LTFENnoyRG9jNHYtT0kwTWU1Z3ZvY1Z3Y0liS3hIalppeEM5cjhFMzFzY0hmRTFWbjJQZHYxckRJdHhxU0QxVGM3blNiMHNzYjBuRDR3RGZpY3JVSUd5N2NGY0toZU9YTEF6MlBIVEJtVFdoTnRzZ1J1bzhISUppdXEyNERoNUthTkU5TGVZcnJmMUFyVnc0M0syVThkbDBhNThPeDd6RmxGMnZPN0tjRkFjY3o2S3NnN1R1cnlUUkV4TG0yWHRiRjl0Y2tydGdjT2pxYUxJUjjSAeoBQVVfeXFMTWxlUVY0NWl2Zmh6aVR6azNRbHdzbWVNU0FZMzdDOGdOaUJCOGNOY1VtZXpZaHNNX1I2SUo2RzZUcFBvWnRCdkQwVnhLSGowT096TTFvcXN2M3RNdnNINmZCNndnR0JvVGF0SW9xU3V3LUpYS0lSanhyMWdKazlXS0RpNGJBUDhNVUtZNTNlaEVocWhXRkU2ZUNYTlQxT3FaTExJMWJxWFQyaXR4bmx5YmpIeTNjZzJ2eHJMZUVMWnBtbWQ0akh1VXZQQkJxaHprWnQtY3BtY2FWbnZvSjI0dFZ5bEN3TEphMW5R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPM1VmRTZxNWFUM0t6LTFENnoyRG9jNHYtT0kwTWU1Z3ZvY1Z3Y0liS3hIalppeEM5cjhFMzFzY0hmRTFWbjJQZHYxckRJdHhxU0QxVGM3blNiMHNzYjBuRDR3RGZpY3JVSUd5N2NGY0toZU9YTEF6MlBIVEJtVFdoTnRzZ1J1bzhISUppdXEyNERoNUthTkU5TGVZcnJmMUFyVnc0M0syVThkbDBhNThPeDd6RmxGMnZPN0tjRkFjY3o2S3NnN1R1cnlUUkV4TG0yWHRiRjl0Y2tydGdjT2pxYUxJUjjSAeoBQVVfeXFMTWxlUVY0NWl2Zmh6aVR6azNRbHdzbWVNU0FZMzdDOGdOaUJCOGNOY1VtZXpZaHNNX1I2SUo2RzZUcFBvWnRCdkQwVnhLSGowT096TTFvcXN2M3RNdnNINmZCNndnR0JvVGF0SW9xU3V3LUpYS0lSanhyMWdKazlXS0RpNGJBUDhNVUtZNTNlaEVocWhXRkU2ZUNYTlQxT3FaTExJMWJxWFQyaXR4bmx5YmpIeTNjZzJ2eHJMZUVMWnBtbWQ0akh1VXZQQkJxaHprWnQtY3BtY2FWbnZvSjI0dFZ5bEN3TEphMW5R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICC Champions Trophy 2025: Complete list of squads and players of all 8 teams - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICC Champions Trophy 2025: Complete List of Squads and Players of All 8 Teams</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> February 19, 2025.<strong> Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>ICC Champions Trophy 2025 will take place in Pakistan and Dubai, featuring eight competing teams. Pakistan, as the reigning champions, will play host to the tournament which starts on February 19.</p>
<h2>Key Points:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The tournament kicks off with a match between Pakistan and New Zealand.</li>
<li>The semi-finals are scheduled for March 4 and 5 in Dubai and Lahore.</li>
<li>Pakistan and Australia have announced their squads, while India and South Africa are yet to finalize theirs.</li>
<li>The tournament will use a hybrid format due to India's decision not to play in Pakistan.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Complete Squads for Champions Trophy 2025:</h2>
<h3>Group A:</h3>
<p><strong>Pakistan:</strong> Mohammad Rizwan (C), Babar Azam, Tayyab Tahir, Irfan Khan Niazi, Sufyan Muqeem, Mohammad Hasnain, Abdullah Shafiq, Naseem Shah, Usman Khan, Shaheen Shah Afridi, Haris Rauf, Abrar Ahmed, Kamran Ghulam, Salman Ali Agha, Imam-ul-Haq, Fakhar Zaman, Hasibullah, Abbas Afridi.</p>
<p><strong>New Zealand:</strong> Mitchell Santner (c), Michael Bracewell, Mark Chapman, Devon Conway, Lockie Ferguson, Matt Henry, Tom Latham, Daryl Mitchell, Will O’Rourke, Glenn Phillips, Rachin Ravindra, Ben Sears, Nathan Smith, Kane Williamson, Will Young.</p>
<p><strong>Bangladesh:</strong> Nazmul Hossain Shanto (c), Soumya Sarkar, Tanzid Hasan, Tawhid Hridoy, Mushfiqur Rahim, MD Mahmud Ullah, Jaker Ali Anik, Mehidy Hasan Miraz, Rishad Hossain, Taskin Ahmed, Mustafizur Rahman, Parvez Hossai Emon, Nasum Ahmed, Tanzim Hasan Sakib, Nahid Rana.</p>
<h3>Group B:</h3>
<p><strong>England:</strong> Jos Buttler (c), Jofra Archer, Gus Atkinson, Jacob Bethell, Harry Brook, Brydon Carse, Ben Duckett, Jamie Overton, Jamie Smith, Liam Livingstone, Adil Rashid, Joe Root, Saqib Mahmood, Phil Salt, Mark Wood.</p>
<p><strong>Afghanistan:</strong> Hashmatullah Shahidi (c), Ibrahim Zadran, Rahmanullah Gurbaz, Sediqullah Atal, Rahmat Shah, Ikram Alikhil, Gulbadin Naib, Azmatullah Omarzai, Mohammad Nabi, Rashid Khan, AM Ghazanfar, Noor Ahmad, Fazalhaq Farooqi, Farid Malik, Naveed Zadran.</p>
<p><strong>Australia:</strong> Pat Cummins (c), Alex Carey, Nathan Ellis, Aaron Hardie, Josh Hazlewood, Travis Head, Josh Inglis, Marnus Labuschagne, Mitchell Marsh, Glenn Maxwell, Matt Short, Steve Smith, Mitchell Starc, Marcus Stoinis, Adam Zampa.</p>
<p><strong>South Africa:</strong> To Be Announced.</p>
<p>The tournament begins with anticipation and high stakes as teams finalize their rosters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/icc-champions-trophy-2025-complete-list-of-squads-and-players-for-all-8-teams-india-pakistan-australia-nz-sa-afg-eng-11736737469051.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/icc-champions-trophy-2025-complete-list-of-squads-and-players-for-all-8-teams-india-pakistan-australia-nz-sa-afg-eng-11736737469051.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:27:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[North Korean troop fatalities and injuries exceed 3,000 in Ukraine, Seoul says - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>North Korean Troop Fatalities and Injuries in Ukraine Exceed 3,000</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p>
<p>According to a South Korean lawmaker briefed by the National Intelligence Service, North Korean troop fatalities and injuries in Ukraine have likely exceeded 3,000. This includes approximately 300 deaths and around 2,700 injuries.</p>
<ul>
  <li>North Korea’s casualty figures in Ukraine are significantly high.</li>
  <li>The lawmaker mentioned that troops have been reportedly instructed to commit suicide to avoid capture.</li>
  <li>Captured soldiers have shown no intent to defect to South Korea; cooperation with Ukraine is possible if requested.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“North Korean authorities appear to have called for its troops to commit suicide by blowing themselves up to evade capture,” the lawmaker stated.</blockquote>
<p>This situation highlights the severe toll on North Korean forces amid ongoing conflict and raises concerns about the humanitarian implications of such strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/north-korean-troop-fatalities-injuries-exceed-3000-ukraine-seoul-says-2025-01-13/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/north-korean-troop-fatalities-injuries-exceed-3000-ukraine-seoul-says-2025-01-13/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi weather: shivers in cold wave, dense fog disrupts flight and train operations; IMD issues ‘orange alert’ across NCR - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Cold Wave: Flights and Trains Disrupted, IMD Issues Orange Alert</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/cities/Delhi/6vxl0f/article69094358.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI01_04_2025_000052A.jpg" alt="Commuters on a road during a cold and foggy winter morning, in New Delhi. File" title="Commuters on a road during a cold and foggy winter morning, in New Delhi. File"><figcaption>Commuters on a road during a cold and foggy winter morning, in New Delhi. File | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>Delhi is experiencing a cold wave with a recorded minimum temperature of 9.6 degrees Celsius. Dense fog has disrupted air and rail traffic, prompting the IMD to issue an orange alert.</p><ul><li>Minimum temperature recorded at 9.6 degrees Celsius, 2.2 degrees above normal.</li><li>Relative humidity at 99% with a predicted maximum of 19 degrees Celsius.</li><li>Significant delays in flights due to low visibility at Indira Gandhi International Airport.</li><li>Multiple train delays, including Purushottam Express delayed by 311 minutes.</li><li>Air Quality Index (AQI) recorded at 274, categorized as poor.</li><li>IMD forecasts persistent dense fog in the region.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dense fog conditions are very likely in the Delhi/NCR region,” IMD stated.</blockquote><p>The current weather conditions are causing significant disruptions in transportation and indicate a pressing need for public awareness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/imd-issues-orange-alert-across-delhi-ncr-dense-fog-condition-likely/article69094345.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/imd-issues-orange-alert-across-delhi-ncr-dense-fog-condition-likely/article69094345.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock market today: Sensex and Nifty tanks, rupee hits all-time low - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Crash: Sensex and Nifty Plummet as Rupee Hits Record Low</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/MOTHERSON-INDIA-SHARE-SALE-0_1727953160646_1736737595954.JPG" alt="Stock market crash: People walk past the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) building in Mumbai, India, March 9, 2020(Francis Mascarenhas/Reuters)" title="Stock market crash: People walk past the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) building in Mumbai, India, March 9, 2020(Francis Mascarenhas/Reuters)"><figcaption>Stock market crash: People walk past the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) building in Mumbai, India, March 9, 2020(Francis Mascarenhas/Reuters)</figcaption><p>The stock market faced a major setback on January 13, 2025, as the benchmark indices tumbled significantly. The BSE Sensex and NSE Nifty both reported steep declines, while the Indian rupee hit an all-time low against the US dollar.</p><ul><li>The BSE Sensex fell by 677.22 points (0.88%) to 76,701.69.</li><li>The NSE Nifty decreased by 212.90 points (0.91%) to 23,218.60.</li><li>The rupee reached an all-time low of 86.3537 per dollar.</li><li>Major losers among Sensex stocks included Zomato (-2.86%), Mahindra & Mahindra (-2.13%), and Power Grid Corporation (-2.07%).</li><li>In contrast, IndusInd Bank (+2.05%) and Axis Bank (+0.44%) were the only stocks that gained.</li></ul><blockquote>"The US dollar is currently rallying due to positive jobs data, impacting the currency exchange rate significantly."</blockquote><p>This downturn reflects broader concerns in the financial market, particularly in sectors like real estate, financial services, and consumer durables.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/stock-market-crash-sensex-tanks-nearly-700-points-on-open-nifty-down-over-200-101736737599073.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/stock-market-crash-sensex-tanks-nearly-700-points-on-open-nifty-down-over-200-101736737599073.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:01:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Online Court Hearing Hacked: Urgent Call for Stronger Cybersecurity in Courts - The420.in]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOVkt2TzcxcDl2TVk1NV9CaXQwQVhETTlfdlZycFBlREpxWWRMdUJLQm9RVldNMWdURmVhSDBSVFRaMV9DZk9lUXVIRGdCY0g3UkhZeTFHWUZYUTZoY1hsN2hWdnF6Q1F2TzRTZGNWSGFxRWd0cWREcVE3WGJmY0Ewb2I4ckpKSlRPZ3ZJMXpETFlxZU1oS09EaC1EVFozeDkxMnhGdmk3emNMVjJUTElESHA1NnZYdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOVkt2TzcxcDl2TVk1NV9CaXQwQVhETTlfdlZycFBlREpxWWRMdUJLQm9RVldNMWdURmVhSDBSVFRaMV9DZk9lUXVIRGdCY0g3UkhZeTFHWUZYUTZoY1hsN2hWdnF6Q1F2TzRTZGNWSGFxRWd0cWREcVE3WGJmY0Ewb2I4ckpKSlRPZ3ZJMXpETFlxZU1oS09EaC1EVFozeDkxMnhGdmk3emNMVjJUTElESHA1NnZYdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:01:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>