<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:25:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:25:03 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Want to Know the Truth About Kanury Rao: A Visionary Leader in the Immunology Field? - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Want to Know the Truth About Kanury Rao: A Visionary Leader in the Immunology Field?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>Dr. Kanury Rao is a prominent figure in immunology, known for his significant contributions to the field, particularly in cancer research and patient care. His dedication to understanding the immune system has led to advancements that improve health outcomes.</p>
<img src="https://example.com/image.jpg" alt="Dr. Kanury Rao">
<figcaption>Dr. Kanury Rao, a pioneer in immunology.</figcaption>
<h2>Key Points</h2>
<ul>
<li>Dr. Rao has significantly contributed to immunology, focusing on cancer immunotherapy and autoimmune disorders.</li>
<li>He co-founded PredOmix Technologies and is the head of the Drug Discovery Research Centre at THSTI.</li>
<li>His research aids in the development of critical vaccines and treatments.</li>
<li>Recognized with prestigious awards like the Shanti Swarup Bhatnagar Prize and the National Bioscience Award.</li>
<li>Despite facing false allegations in his career, he continued to focus on his research and contributions to the field.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Success requires a lot of hard work and dedication and sidelining all obstacles and difficulties in the path of success.” - Dr. Kanury Rao</blockquote>
<p>Dr. Rao’s contributions to immunology are vital in developing treatments for diseases affecting many lives. His resilience in overcoming challenges further exemplifies his dedication to advancing medical research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/content/specials/want-to-know-the-truth-about-kanury-rao-a-visionary-leader-in-the-immunology-field-124122301119_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/content/specials/want-to-know-the-truth-about-kanury-rao-a-visionary-leader-in-the-immunology-field-124122301119_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:12:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Incremental investment in cement sector will come only when profitability improves: Report | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Incremental Investment in Cement Sector Dependent on Profitability Improvements</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p><p>The Indian cement industry must improve its profitability significantly to attract future investments, as highlighted in a report by IKIGAI Asset Manager. The report states that EBITDA must exceed Rs1,000 per ton to justify returns on capital.</p><ul><li>The report cites a current EBITDA of Rs800 per ton, leading to a post-tax ROCE of only 3%.</li><li>Incremental investments will require doubling current profitability.</li><li>India's combined listed cement companies have a market capitalization exceeding USD100 billion.</li><li>Top four players are expected to account for over 75% of capacity additions by FY27.</li><li>More than 25% of limestone mines will expire by 2035, posing future challenges.</li><li>Shifting to renewable energy could reduce operational costs significantly.</li><li>Despite being the second-largest market, cement is among the cheapest commodities in India.</li><li>The growth in cement demand historically follows GDP growth, but pricing power remains low.</li></ul><blockquote>“Each Rs1 increase in cement price per bag could add Rs67 billion to the EBITDA of the top 10 players.”</blockquote><p>The future growth of the industry depends on demand dynamics, strategic pricing, and the adoption of cost-effective renewable energy solutions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/incremental-investment-in-cement-sector-will-come-only-when-profitability-improves-report-11735278911025.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/incremental-investment-in-cement-sector-will-come-only-when-profitability-improves-report-11735278911025.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:55:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IT firms with exposure to healthcare brace for immunity test | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IT firms with exposure to healthcare brace for immunity test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 18, 2023  <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/subscription/onepagecheckout/lm/staging/extensivepaywall/starpaper.png" alt="Healthcare Growth" /><figcaption>Growth in healthcare contributes positively to IT firms' earnings</figcaption><p>Select Indian IT companies find a silver lining in the healthcare sector, which helps to bolster their earnings amidst downturns in other areas.</p><ul><li>Persistent Systems reported 51% growth in healthcare revenue year-on-year over the last four quarters.</li><li>Its growth in healthcare offset declines in its hi-tech segment.</li><li>Increased traction in large healthcare deals contributed to this growth.</li></ul><blockquote>"The healthcare vertical has been a boon for select IT firms, especially during challenging times in other segments."</blockquote><p>This trend emphasizes the importance of adapting to market demands and diversifying service offerings in volatile economic conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/mark-to-market/it-firms-bfsi-healthcare-it-spending-wipro-persistent-systems-hcl-tech-us-healthcare-policies-interest-rate-fluctuation-11735275729355.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/mark-to-market/it-firms-bfsi-healthcare-it-spending-wipro-persistent-systems-hcl-tech-us-healthcare-policies-interest-rate-fluctuation-11735275729355.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:53:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus Buds Ace 2 With 12.4mm Drivers, Up to 43 Hours Total Battery Life Launched: Price, Features - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus Buds Ace 2 With Up to 43 Hours Total Playback Time Launched</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Thursday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/zgASV16Wvkw/hqdefault.jpg" alt="OnePlus Buds Ace 2"/><figcaption>OnePlus Buds Ace 2</figcaption><p>OnePlus has launched the Buds Ace 2 TWS earphones in China, featuring advanced audio technology and durability.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>12.4mm dynamic drivers with active noise cancellation (ANC).</li><li>IP55-rated for dust and water resistance.</li><li>Support for dual device connectivity and low latency up to 43ms.</li><li>Available for a promotional price starting at CNY 169.</li><li>Playback time of up to 12 hours on a single charge, and up to 43 hours with the case.</li></ul><blockquote>“The earphones come with support for ANC and BassWave 2.0 technology for enhanced bass experience.”</blockquote><p>The OnePlus Buds Ace 2 offer a competitive blend of high-quality audio features and robust design, making them an attractive option for TWS earphone consumers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/audio/news/oneplus-buds-ace-2-price-availability-specifications-features-launch-china-7341450</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/audio/news/oneplus-buds-ace-2-price-availability-specifications-features-launch-china-7341450</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:41:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PSU banks to cross ₹1.5 lakh cr profit in FY'25, low deposit mobilisation concern | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Public Sector Banks Expected to Surpass ₹1.5 Lakh Crore Profit in FY’25 Amid Deposit Concerns</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><p>Public sector banks (PSBs) are projected to exceed profits of ₹1.5 lakh crore in the fiscal year 2024-25, driven by low non-performing assets (NPAs) and strong credit growth.</p><ul><li>PSBs reported a 25% increase in net profit to ₹85,520 crore in H1’FY25.</li><li>The highest-ever net profit recorded was ₹1.41 lakh crore in FY24.</li><li>Gross NPA ratio improved to 3.12% as of September 2024, down from 14.58% in March 2018.</li><li>CRAR rose to 15.43%, exceeding RBI’s minimum requirement.</li><li>Challenges include slower deposit growth compared to credit growth and rising digital fraud incidents.</li></ul><blockquote>“We expect deposit rates to decline with a lag even if the rate cuts were to start from the upcoming MPC meeting.” - Sachin Sachdeva, ICRA Vice President</blockquote><p>Despite facing challenges like slower deposit growth and digital fraud, the banking sector's profitability is forecasted to remain strong as it continues to support economic growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/company-results/psu-banks-to-cross-rs-1-5-lakh-cr-profit-in-fy-25-low-deposit-mobilisation-concern-11735277583212.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/company-results/psu-banks-to-cross-rs-1-5-lakh-cr-profit-in-fy-25-low-deposit-mobilisation-concern-11735277583212.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:33:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh preferred his Maruti 800 over BMW: U.P. Minister recalls his experience with former PM - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manmohan Singh Preferred His Maruti 800 Over BMW, Reveals U.P. Minister</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/kw7hr1/article69032309.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/41-MANMOHAN-CEREMONIAL_RECEPTION-07-02-12-DEL.jpg" alt="Former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh’s humility and grounded nature were highlighted in a heartfelt social media memoir by Uttar Pradesh Minister of State for Social Welfare (Independent Charge) Asim Arun. File photo" /><figcaption>Former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh’s humility and grounded nature were highlighted in a heartfelt social media memoir by Uttar Pradesh Minister of State for Social Welfare (Independent Charge) Asim Arun.</figcaption><p>The recent tribute to former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh by U.P. Minister Asim Arun showcases Singh's deep connection with the middle class through his choice of a modest vehicle over luxury.</p><ul><li>Manmohan Singh preferred a Maruti Suzuki 800 over a BMW, reflecting his humility.</li><li>Arun shared personal anecdotes of his time as Singh's protection officer, highlighting Singh's simple lifestyle.</li><li>The former PM's death was noted shortly before the memoir was shared.</li></ul><blockquote>“Asim, I don't like travelling in this car (BMW). My car is the Maruti.”</blockquote><p>This choice symbolizes not just simplicity, but also Singh's commitment to the common man, making him a beloved figure in Indian politics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manmohan-singh-preferred-his-maruti-800-over-bmw-up-minister-recalls-his-experience-with-former-pm/article69032293.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manmohan-singh-preferred-his-maruti-800-over-bmw-up-minister-recalls-his-experience-with-former-pm/article69032293.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vivo Y29 5G launched in India at Rs.13999- Check out specs, features, and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vivo Y29 5G launched with MediaTek Dimensity 6300 processor and 5500mAh battery</h1><p><strong>Date: Dec 27, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/pc1_1735274037416_1735274046778.jpg" alt="Vivo Y29 5G launched at under Rs.15000, here’s everything it has to offer(Vivp)" title="Vivo Y29 5G launched at under Rs.15000, here’s everything it has to offer(Vivp)"><figcaption>Vivo Y29 5G launched at under Rs.15000, here’s everything it has to offer(Vivp)</figcaption></figure><p>Vivo has launched its new affordable Y-series smartphone, the Vivo Y29 5G in India at a starting price of just Rs.13999. The smartphone features a slimmer profile and attractive design, making it stand out. It packs a powerful processor for day-to-day tasks.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Price starts at Rs.13999 for 4GB+128GB storage.</li><li>Features a 6.68-inch LCD display with 120Hz refresh rate.</li><li>Packed with MediaTek Dimensity 6300 processor and up to 8GB RAM.</li><li>Offers 5500mAh battery with 44W fast charging and impressive playback time.</li><li>Available in Glacier Blue, Titanium Gold, and Diamond Black colors.</li></ul><blockquote>“The smartphone offers several AI-powered camera features such as AI Night Mode and AI Photo Enhance.”</blockquote><p>The Vivo Y29 5G is an appealing choice for budget-conscious consumers looking for feature-rich smartphones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/vivo-y29-5g-launched-in-india-at-rs-13999-check-out-specs-features-and-more-101735273998170.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/vivo-y29-5g-launched-in-india-at-rs-13999-check-out-specs-features-and-more-101735273998170.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:38:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mamata Machinery Share Price, IPO Listing Live Updates: IPO lists at 147% premium on NSE, shares up lock in upper circuit - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgJBVV95cUxQc3dyXy1Ybkl6YWxRWElYd1RQYmRsWHUtU2FkRXVYaDdxdlh3Mjl3bGQwUWV4VnVwTXlYRHd1Z1J2bDRsZm1MUU0wdTh3M3NjVmNkdlhKNE1WeGE0LWZSb1I0S1hsQ19qaFNheFpYZFZscHl1cTQ2V2VYZmp5RTNlY2pqVG4wZDVJM19rZnNoQ2hMTXgtZ1BLNkVveEZhd3FjYktNN21BTEZoNGhsR1J1X0tFb0t1Z1JVN3FGSHpiUlFQWFNGckJwNnNqam9WM2lpWEhRcnhTRUx4VXk1dnRaM3hlOFc2MG1mS012WGk0d0U3SDk2b2NXajc0N2JnXzBCTF9PNmZpXzNkYkFMSTBoM3gzc0NOcURRT2pkcTVWTGpEdVdta0FXazk0Z3FUUdIBtAJBVV95cUxPSl96YTZSSW9tcWItWUpVRVVOS1JOU0hNcUpocGxvM2lOc2hXQ1V4NG5FRUEwYThSSXJuSlNxT3VnemxSUG9BZkpqeTBVd09vSVlrT1JYZ2FHbTdONE5ma3V0bUVFWGliMFRkNWM2QThrVmpjQzJKdUVSQUw1VG85djF0Zjl4ZnN0aG85UXpPNk90ZmRabW83OGs5bVlOcEN2UUhwWlg1dU1OQVh1SmxVOFhYcEpsdkNRblVKRFRnZWZLOXllbFl4cnBjLWI1MFZkWjU5ZzlZZHQwQTQybVg3YnVoS0VtN01xQnJaMXBLZDZZbzVsT1FKRVBIZ2FsWmlLck9TS09VSUxpX3J4LXJmMTJFd2RMYW5Ca0lHdnVjbXFoVXhDQVN6NTRKUmtSS2xhR3pYcg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgJBVV95cUxQc3dyXy1Ybkl6YWxRWElYd1RQYmRsWHUtU2FkRXVYaDdxdlh3Mjl3bGQwUWV4VnVwTXlYRHd1Z1J2bDRsZm1MUU0wdTh3M3NjVmNkdlhKNE1WeGE0LWZSb1I0S1hsQ19qaFNheFpYZFZscHl1cTQ2V2VYZmp5RTNlY2pqVG4wZDVJM19rZnNoQ2hMTXgtZ1BLNkVveEZhd3FjYktNN21BTEZoNGhsR1J1X0tFb0t1Z1JVN3FGSHpiUlFQWFNGckJwNnNqam9WM2lpWEhRcnhTRUx4VXk1dnRaM3hlOFc2MG1mS012WGk0d0U3SDk2b2NXajc0N2JnXzBCTF9PNmZpXzNkYkFMSTBoM3gzc0NOcURRT2pkcTVWTGpEdVdta0FXazk0Z3FUUdIBtAJBVV95cUxPSl96YTZSSW9tcWItWUpVRVVOS1JOU0hNcUpocGxvM2lOc2hXQ1V4NG5FRUEwYThSSXJuSlNxT3VnemxSUG9BZkpqeTBVd09vSVlrT1JYZ2FHbTdONE5ma3V0bUVFWGliMFRkNWM2QThrVmpjQzJKdUVSQUw1VG85djF0Zjl4ZnN0aG85UXpPNk90ZmRabW83OGs5bVlOcEN2UUhwWlg1dU1OQVh1SmxVOFhYcEpsdkNRblVKRFRnZWZLOXllbFl4cnBjLWI1MFZkWjU5ZzlZZHQwQTQybVg3YnVoS0VtN01xQnJaMXBLZDZZbzVsT1FKRVBIZ2FsWmlLck9TS09VSUxpX3J4LXJmMTJFd2RMYW5Ca0lHdnVjbXFoVXhDQVN6NTRKUmtSS2xhR3pYcg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:30:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra colour variant leaked ahead of rumoured launch on January 22 - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra Colour Variant Leaked Ahead of Launch</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Nandini Yadav</p><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra is set to be unveiled at the Galaxy Unpacked event on January 22, with rumors of a new blue color variant circulating in advance.</p><ul><li>The Galaxy S25 series and Galaxy Ring are expected to launch at the event.</li><li>Recent leaks suggest a new blue color for the Galaxy S25 Ultra.</li><li>The S25 Ultra will feature 16GB of RAM in higher storage variants.</li><li>Pre-orders in South Korea are anticipated from January 24 to February 3, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“S25 Ultra. Blue.” - Leaker @iceuniverse</blockquote><p>The upcoming event is generating significant anticipation among fans, particularly for the new color options and specifications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-colour-variant-leaked-ahead-of-rumoured-launch-on-january-22-2656029-2024-12-27</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-colour-variant-leaked-ahead-of-rumoured-launch-on-january-22-2656029-2024-12-27</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:14:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICAI Result: 4 candidates top CA Final exam, country gets 11,500 new Chartered Accountants - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICAI CA Final Result 2024: A total of 11,500 candidates qualified as Chartered Accountants, the Insitute of Chartered Accountants of India (ICAI) has announced.</h1><p><strong>Date: Dec 27, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/icai_toppers_1735272423259_1735272441164.jpg" alt="Four candidates have secured all India 1st, 2nd and 3rd ranks in the ICAI CA Final November exam result(Posted on X by @theicai)" title="Four candidates have secured all India 1st, 2nd and 3rd ranks in the ICAI CA Final November exam result(Posted on X by @theicai)"><figcaption>Four candidates have secured all India 1st, 2nd and 3rd ranks in the ICAI CA Final November exam result(Posted on X by @theicai)</figcaption><p>The ICAI has announced that a total of 11,500 candidates have successfully qualified as Chartered Accountants this year, emphasizing the impressive performance of students.</p><ul><li>Heramb Maheshwari from Hyderabad and Rishab Ostwal R from Tirupati jointly secured the all-India first rank.</li><li>Riya Kunjankumar Shah from Ahmedabad is the second topper.</li><li>Kinjal Ajmera from Kolkata secured the third rank.</li><li>Total candidates who appeared: 66,987; total passed: 11,253 in Group 1 with a pass percentage of 16.8%.</li><li>In Group 2, 49,459 candidates wrote the exam; 10,566 passed with a pass percentage of 21.36%.</li><li>For candidates appearing in both groups, 30,763 showed up, with 4,134 passing (13.44% pass rate).</li></ul><blockquote>"Individual exam results can be accessed at the institute's result portal, icai.nic.in."</blockquote><p>The successful results of this examination highlight the continued demand and rigorous standards in the field of Chartered Accountancy in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/education/exam-results/icai-result-4-candidates-top-ca-final-exam-country-gets-11-500-new-chartered-accountants-101735269453745.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/education/exam-results/icai-result-4-candidates-top-ca-final-exam-country-gets-11-500-new-chartered-accountants-101735269453745.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:10:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser release postponed to Saturday after Manmohan Singh's demise - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Salman Khan's Sikandar Teaser Release Postponed After Manmohan Singh's Death</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/MixCollage-27-Dec-2024-09-12-AM-8006_1735270953051_1735270971714.jpg" alt="Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser launch postponed after Manmohan Singh's death." title="Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser launch postponed after Manmohan Singh's death."><figcaption>Salman Khan's Sikandar teaser launch postponed after Manmohan Singh's death.</figcaption></figure><p>On the occasion of Salman Khan's 59th birthday, the teaser launch for his upcoming film Sikandar was set for today but has been postponed following the death of former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh.</p><ul><li>The teaser was scheduled to be released at 11:07 AM on December 27, 2024.</li><li>The production house confirmed the postponement via their official social media handle.</li><li>Manmohan Singh passed away at age 92 due to age-related medical issues.</li><li>Singh was Prime Minister of India from 2004 to 2014 and was a significant figure in India's economic policy.</li></ul><blockquote>“In light of the passing of our esteemed former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh Ji, we regret to announce that the release of the Sikandar teaser has been postponed to 28th December 11:07 AM.” - Team Sikandar</blockquote><p>The portrayal of Salman Khan in Sikandar sparked excitement among fans, with further details expected to be shared on the new teaser release date.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/salman-khan-birthday-sikandar-teaser-release-postponed-to-saturday-after-manmohan-singh-death-101735270607733.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/salman-khan-birthday-sikandar-teaser-release-postponed-to-saturday-after-manmohan-singh-death-101735270607733.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:04:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UltraTech buys 8.69% stake from Star Cement promoter group for ₹851 crore - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UltraTech buys 8.69% stake from Star Cement promoter group for ₹851 crore</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><p>In a notable move in the cement industry, UltraTech Cement Ltd. has acquired an 8.69% stake in Star Cement Ltd. from its promoter group for ₹851 crore.</p><ul><li>UltraTech acquired the shares at ₹235 per share.</li><li>This stake is a non-controlling minority stake in Star Cement.</li><li>Star Cement, based in Meghalaya, reported a turnover of ₹2,910 crore in FY 2024.</li><li>UltraTech recently also acquired a 32.72% stake in India Cements, making it a subsidiary.</li><li>Star Cement boasts a 7.7 MTPA grinding capacity and a 26.5% market share in the north-eastern market.</li><li>The company is planning a ₹380 crore capex for the second half of FY 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>“The blocks are estimated to have geological limestone reserves of 63.9 million tonnes.”</blockquote><p>This acquisition indicates UltraTech's ongoing strategy of consolidation in the cement sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/ultratech-star-cement-share-price-acquisition-of-stake-block-deal-window-valuation-promoter-group-19530374.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/ultratech-star-cement-share-price-acquisition-of-stake-block-deal-window-valuation-promoter-group-19530374.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:40:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 2 LIVE Score: Rohit Sharma's Opening Stunt Flops As India Lose 1st Wicket - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 2 LIVE Score Updates</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>Live updates on the second day of the 4th Test match between India and Australia, highlighting key moments including a significant blow to India's KL Rahul.</p>
<ul>
<li>Pat Cummins takes a crucial wicket for Australia.</li>
<li>India faces challenges in batting before the tea break.</li>
<li>Key performances and statistics from the match are under review.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Pat Cummins' Ripper Hands India Big KL Rahul Blow Before Tea”</blockquote>
<p>This match is crucial for both teams as they contend for vital points in the series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-2-live-score-updates-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-7337467</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-2-live-score-updates-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-7337467</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:30:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravi Shastri, Sunil Gavaskar Rip Into Rohit Sharma's Captaincy Over 4th Test Tactics - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ravi-shastri-sunil-gavaskar-rip-into-rohit-sharmas-captaincy-over-4th-test-tactics-7340894</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ravi-shastri-sunil-gavaskar-rip-into-rohit-sharmas-captaincy-over-4th-test-tactics-7340894</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:19:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zupee Revolutionizes Ludo with a Focus on Skill and Strategy - Adgully]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxNNXdqUFF5S2ZaVm1ybkROM1RSNUM1NTR4eGxXYzlFWWZ6R1B2QW9CWlctMnd4bnZsODRZTlpUUTlkdW4xMXJ6VjhmN0JSQTVRWV9IOU94d1RnLUNmZE9OYVJlOVpSdW9OaXRtdWs1emJVSmxXUDNtWVV4UzQ1NzVmSVZkcjdsYXZRaEd5RHdFSWJmWS01ejdmVVlHLWU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxNNXdqUFF5S2ZaVm1ybkROM1RSNUM1NTR4eGxXYzlFWWZ6R1B2QW9CWlctMnd4bnZsODRZTlpUUTlkdW4xMXJ6VjhmN0JSQTVRWV9IOU94d1RnLUNmZE9OYVJlOVpSdW9OaXRtdWs1emJVSmxXUDNtWVV4UzQ1NzVmSVZkcjdsYXZRaEd5RHdFSWJmWS01ejdmVVlHLWU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:09:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS: Steve Smith's majestic innings ends in bizarre fashion at the MCG - Watch - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS: Steve Smith's majestic innings ends in bizarre fashion at the MCG - Watch</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116698505,imgsize-126698,width-400,resizemode-4/116698505.jpg" alt="Steve Smith's innings at the MCG"><figcaption>India's Akash Deep, left, celebrates the wicket of Australia's Steve Smith. (AP/PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>Steve Smith had an eventful day during the fourth Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy at the Melbourne Cricket Ground. He scored 140 runs, becoming the most successful century-maker against India in Test cricket history.</p><ul><li>Smith scored 140 runs off 197 balls, achieving his 34th Test century.</li><li>This innings made him the joint seventh-highest century-maker in Test cricket history.</li><li>He is now Australia's second-highest century-maker with 41 centuries, trailing Ricky Ponting.</li><li>Smith's innings ended in a bizarre manner when he accidentally hit the ball onto his back leg, dislodging a bail.</li><li>Despite the unusual dismissal, he left the field to a standing ovation from the crowd.</li></ul><blockquote>“His audacious attempt at a big shot highlighted his intent.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Steve Smith's remarkable performance at the MCG further cements his legacy as one of cricket's modern greats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-steve-smiths-majestic-innings-ends-in-bizarre-fashion-at-the-mcg-watch/articleshow/116698437.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-steve-smiths-majestic-innings-ends-in-bizarre-fashion-at-the-mcg-watch/articleshow/116698437.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tata Motors shares get an upgrade after a 37% drop from their peak on better risk-reward - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tata Motors Shares Upgraded After 37% Drop Amid Positive Risk-Reward Outlook</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p>
<img alt="Tata Motors shares upgrade" title="Tata Motors shares get an upgrade after a 37% drop from their peak on better risk-reward" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/uploads/2024/03/tata-motors-inaugurates-state-of-the-art-registered-vehicle-scrapping-facility-near-delhi-1.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360">
<figcaption>Tata Motors shares get an upgrade after a 37% drop from their peak on better risk-reward</figcaption>
<p>Brokerage firm DAM Capital has upgraded Tata Motors' rating from "neutral" to "buy" following a significant price drop, citing an improved risk-reward scenario.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Price target raised to ₹870, indicating an 18% potential upside.</li>
  <li>Current shares down nearly 40% from the recent peak of ₹1,170.</li>
  <li>Expected recovery in the auto sector by financial year 2026.</li>
  <li>Jaguar Land Rover's expected growth at a CAGR of 6.5% over 2025-2027.</li>
  <li>Among 36 analysts, 22 maintain a "buy" rating on the stock.</li>
  <li>Shares closed at ₹741.5, down 5% in 2024 so far.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The stock was the best Nifty 50 performer in 2023 and the only index stock that had doubled during the calendar year."</blockquote>
<p>The upgrade reflects a cautious optimism amidst near-term challenges, suggesting a potential turnaround for Tata Motors in the coming quarters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQSDluejN1bU9aVmxSRlRRS2dSYkJtZlhvbFh1N1lvc1NrN0hCSE5idmYyNXEydVIyNUxINUhURUEzMDlCNkJGODZxalRuTG1oelAyWHRGekx1SmFkY294OUNMakJzX1R5WEJwZm5NODdWSmZSVTVBYmFSU2ROZDF5a1R4S2ROYkRfNlpBbFhjNEJhZzJ6RzlCNV9zalFmVEZUek1VdVdYMUZnMTVYWXQ5U3lmQTZGeE5uMGp5TzA3ekNYdGV4RHfSAcsBQVVfeXFMUFZVcG55bVllcUg1MU50TTBqZE1ub3VhQkZGVEhodGVhXzRIUlB6eGg2UURkbUNVVk5NQUxHYnF4U1NsSGxtZ3M0Rk9tQzZmTnZ5S3J2c3dlNWFTWHV5UEM5OEliSnhhNFdmeWFqVmd4Rmg2VXQ3Rl9yLUQxNk4tTlZ2U0laMTlwc0tCYjAySFR5eWM1bEt6ekVpckdBbGh1djB5dklIRnUzZUh5UnY2SEtLR1JDNjdXSThkeGJaZURDNjE5VUZ6MnhsWXM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQSDluejN1bU9aVmxSRlRRS2dSYkJtZlhvbFh1N1lvc1NrN0hCSE5idmYyNXEydVIyNUxINUhURUEzMDlCNkJGODZxalRuTG1oelAyWHRGekx1SmFkY294OUNMakJzX1R5WEJwZm5NODdWSmZSVTVBYmFSU2ROZDF5a1R4S2ROYkRfNlpBbFhjNEJhZzJ6RzlCNV9zalFmVEZUek1VdVdYMUZnMTVYWXQ5U3lmQTZGeE5uMGp5TzA3ekNYdGV4RHfSAcsBQVVfeXFMUFZVcG55bVllcUg1MU50TTBqZE1ub3VhQkZGVEhodGVhXzRIUlB6eGg2UURkbUNVVk5NQUxHYnF4U1NsSGxtZ3M0Rk9tQzZmTnZ5S3J2c3dlNWFTWHV5UEM5OEliSnhhNFdmeWFqVmd4Rmg2VXQ3Rl9yLUQxNk4tTlZ2U0laMTlwc0tCYjAySFR5eWM1bEt6ekVpckdBbGh1djB5dklIRnUzZUh5UnY2SEtLR1JDNjdXSThkeGJaZURDNjE5VUZ6MnhsWXM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 02:41:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli puts arm around pitch invader as fan breaches security, sprints to hug Team India star during Melbourne Test - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli Embraces Pitch Invader During Melbourne Test</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-32_1735267206289_1735267218622.jpg" alt="A pitch invader is seen with India's Virat Kohli on the second day of the fourth cricket Test (AFP)"><figcaption>A pitch invader is seen with India's Virat Kohli on the second day of the fourth cricket Test (AFP)</figcaption><p>An unexpected disruption occurred on Day 2 of the Boxing Day Test at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG) when a pitch invader sprinted onto the field and attempted to hug Indian batting star Virat Kohli. The intruder diverted his attention from captain Rohit Sharma to Kohli, creating a dramatic moment.</p><ul><li>The pitch invader ran onto the field and hugged Kohli during the match.</li><li>Kohli wrapped his arm around the intruder before security intervened.</li><li>The incident caused a brief stoppage in play but the game resumed quickly.</li><li>This occurred amidst tensions from Kohli's previous altercation with debutant Sam Konstas on Day 1.</li><li>Kohli received significant attention following an incident where he clashed with Konstas, leading to a fine.</li></ul><blockquote>“With India expected to bat soon, there will certainly be a reaction from the Australian crowd when Virat Kohli comes to bat at the MCG.”</blockquote><p>This amusing yet brief interruption showcased the unpredictable nature of live sports, adding an unexpected moment to the day's events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-puts-arm-around-pitch-invader-as-fan-breaches-security-sprints-to-hug-team-india-star-during-melbourne-test-101735265310244.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-puts-arm-around-pitch-invader-as-fan-breaches-security-sprints-to-hug-team-india-star-during-melbourne-test-101735265310244.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 02:41:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 2 LIVE Score: Steve Smith Suffers Unlucky Dismissal, Australia 9-Down - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 2 LIVE Score Updates: Rohit Sharma's Opening Stunt Flops As India Lose 1st Wicket</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>The India vs Australia 4th Test continues with live updates as the first wicket falls for India, and Rohit Sharma's performance is under scrutiny.</p>
<ul>
<li>India loses its first wicket early in the match.</li>
<li>Rohit Sharma's performance was anticipated but did not meet expectations.</li>
<li>Live score updates are ongoing during the match.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Rohit Sharma's Opening Stunt Flops As India Lose 1st Wicket”</blockquote>
<p>This match is crucial for India as they aim to perform well against Australia in the ongoing series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-2-live-score-updates-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-7337467</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-2-live-score-updates-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-7337467</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 02:21:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh death: Are banks, schools closed today (December 27)? Check details - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manmohan Singh Death: Impact on Schools and Banks in India</h1><p><strong>Date: December 27, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/INDIA-POLITICS-MANMOHAN-SINGH-40_1735263746982_1735263764286.JPG" alt="Former prime minister Manmohan Singh's last rites will be performed on Saturday with full state honours. (File/Reuters)" title="Former prime minister Manmohan Singh's last rites will be performed on Saturday with full state honours. (File/Reuters)"><figcaption>Former prime minister Manmohan Singh's last rites will be performed on Saturday with full state honours. (File/Reuters)</figcaption><p>Former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh passed away at the age of 92. The Union government declared seven days of mourning, but so far, only Karnataka has officially declared a holiday for schools and colleges.</p><ul><li>The Union Cabinet will meet on December 27 to pay tribute to Manmohan Singh.</li><li>National Flag will be at half-mast with no official entertainment during the mourning period.</li><li>No official announcement yet on bank closures on December 27; digital banking services will remain operational.</li><li>Karnataka has declared a holiday for schools and colleges.</li><li>Awaiting announcements from other states regarding educational institutions.</li></ul><blockquote>“History will be kinder to me than the media.” - Manmohan Singh</blockquote><p>This event marks a significant moment in Indian history, as it affects political rituals and public observance nationwide.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/manmohan-singh-death-are-banks-schools-closed-today-december-27-check-details-101735263043682.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/manmohan-singh-death-are-banks-schools-closed-today-december-27-check-details-101735263043682.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 02:21:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli’s wedding photographer says the picture featuring the couple’s forehead ki - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli’s Wedding Photographer Shares Favorite Photo</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116697701,imgsize-136286,width-400,resizemode-4/116697701.jpg" alt="Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli’s wedding photographer reveals favorite photo."><figcaption>Photo of Anushka and Virat sharing a forehead kiss.</figcaption><p>Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli's wedding in Italy on December 11, 2017, continues to enchant fans. Their wedding photographer, Joseph Radhik, recently shared insights about his favorite photograph from the ceremony during a Reddit AMA.</p><ul><li>The photo features a black and white image of Virat kissing Anushka on her forehead.</li><li>Joseph described the photograph as looking posed but being “100% documentary.”</li><li>He expressed his joy while capturing the moment.</li><li>The couple is also in the news for planning to move to London permanently after their second child is born.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was a photo of Anushka and Virat on their wedding day. In black and white, with him kissing her on her forehead. This is easily my favourite photo because it looks posed, but is 100% documentary.” - Joseph Radhik</blockquote><p>This cherished moment highlights not only the couple's love but also the artistry of wedding photography, preserving intimate moments that resonate with fans even years later.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/anushka-sharma-and-virat-kohlis-wedding-photographer-reveals-his-favorite-moment/articleshow/116697704.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/anushka-sharma-and-virat-kohlis-wedding-photographer-reveals-his-favorite-moment/articleshow/116697704.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 02:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stock Market LIVE Updates: Sensex 500 pts higher at 79,000; Nifty at 23,900; Auto index jumps 2% - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market LIVE Updates: Sensex 350 pts higher at 78,850; Nifty at 23,850; Auto, Pharma rally</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" alt="Market, BSE, NSE, Nifty, Stock Market, investment"><figcaption>Market, BSE, NSE, Nifty, Stock Market, investment</figcaption><p>The Indian equity indices BSE Sensex and Nifty50 are experiencing an uptick, bolstered by positive movements in the auto and pharma sectors, despite a cloudy near-term economic outlook.</p><ul><li>At 11 AM, BSE Sensex up by 470.57 points (0.60%) at 78,943.05.</li><li>Nifty50 trades at 23,903.60, gain of 153.40 points (0.65%).</li><li>FIIs net sold Indian equities worth INR 2,376.67 crore while DIIs net bought shares worth INR 3,336.16 crore on December 26.</li><li>Auto sector indices up, led by Bajaj Auto (up 2.34%).</li><li>India’s market capitalization has grown to $5.18 trillion in 2024, ranking third globally in growth percentage.</li></ul><blockquote>“The outlook for growth in the second half is expected to improve.”</blockquote><p>The market shows resilience amidst global uncertainties, suggesting a cautious but optimistic sentiment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/stock-market-today-live-updates-sensex-today-nifty-dec-27-nse-bse-equity-mamata-ipo-gmp-unimech-ipo-124122700107_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/stock-market-today-live-updates-sensex-today-nifty-dec-27-nse-bse-equity-mamata-ipo-gmp-unimech-ipo-124122700107_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 02:14:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telangana CM Revanth Reddy announces Cabinet sub-committee 'to resolve problems of Telugu cinema' amid Pushpa 2 case - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telangana CM Revanth Reddy Announces Cabinet Sub-Committee for Telugu Cinema</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/Revanth_Reddy_1735264907932_1735264908248.jpg" alt="Telangana Chief Minister A. Revanth Reddy with actor Venkatesh Daggubati during a meeting with directors, producers and actors of Telugu film industry, Dec. 26, 2024. (PTI Photo)(PTI)"><figcaption>Telangana Chief Minister A. Revanth Reddy with actor Venkatesh Daggubati during a meeting with directors, producers and actors of Telugu film industry, Dec. 26, 2024. (PTI Photo)(PTI)</figcaption><p>Chief Minister Revanth Reddy recently addressed members of the Telugu film industry, outlining significant measures to support its growth and prosperity amidst ongoing controversies.</p><ul><li>A Cabinet Sub-Committee will be established to address the concerns of the Telugu film industry.</li><li>Film producer Dil Raju appointed as Chairman of the Film Development Corporation (FDC).</li><li>Government issued special orders for eight films and provided police grounds for filming Pushpa-2.</li><li>CM Reddy emphasizes promoting eco-tourism and temple tourism as part of industry support.</li><li>Criticism arises from BJP leader Amit Malviya regarding the government's alleged targeting of Tollywood.</li></ul><blockquote>CM Reddy stated, "A Cabinet Sub-Committee will be constituted to resolve the problems of the Telugu film industry."</blockquote><p>The Telangana government's response aims to enhance support for the Telugu film industry and address ongoing challenges, promoting cooperation with industry stakeholders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/telangana-cm-revanth-reddy-announces-cabinet-sub-committee-to-resolve-problems-of-telugu-cinema-amid-pushpa-2-case-101735264675033.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/telangana-cm-revanth-reddy-announces-cabinet-sub-committee-to-resolve-problems-of-telugu-cinema-amid-pushpa-2-case-101735264675033.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 02:04:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australia continue gallop with Smith's ton - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxOMlBHNUVxcFgzMk5oeXpJRnZJZF9vMHNzNmF6RmpaS0duVW83THgxdzJDV3VUb3N4czFqMGVUSkQ4X1VLUDhjc1JIMkFiVzRUX016eVdZZDlfNTFMcjc3V0FmNEZKLU5fT2FONGVsR3FIYURBSXo0U3k3YklvOHpTd2hvMGZFVjN0ejVDMDdtcw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxOMlBHNUVxcFgzMk5oeXpJRnZJZF9vMHNzNmF6RmpaS0duVW83THgxdzJDV3VUb3N4czFqMGVUSkQ4X1VLUDhjc1JIMkFiVzRUX016eVdZZDlfNTFMcjc3V0FmNEZKLU5fT2FONGVsR3FIYURBSXo0U3k3YklvOHpTd2hvMGZFVjN0ejVDMDdtcw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 01:43:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ricky Ponting blasts ICC for letting Virat Kohli go easily for Sam Konstas act; Gavaskar calls it ‘slap on the wrist’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ricky Ponting blasts ICC for letting Virat Kohli go easily for Sam Konstas act; Gavaskar calls it ‘slap on the wrist’</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/Screenshot_2024-12-27_065711_1735262854013_1735262861617.png" alt="Ricky Ponting and Sunil Gavaskar discuss ICC's sanction on Virat Kohli">
<figcaption>Ricky Ponting and Sunil Gavaskar discuss ICC's sanction on Virat Kohli</figcaption>
<p>Ricky Ponting has openly criticized the ICC for what he perceives to be a lenient punishment for Virat Kohli after a physical altercation during a Boxing Day Test.</p>
<ul>
<li>Ponting argues that Kohli's 20% match fee fine is insufficient given the seriousness of the incident.</li>
<li>Kohli was sanctioned for a shoulder bump against debutant Sam Konstas, classified as a Level 1 offence.</li>
<li>Legendary cricketer Sunil Gavaskar also supports the view that the penalty is inadequate, calling it a ‘slap on the wrist’.</li>
<li>Ponting emphasizes Kohli's role as a role model and believes stricter consequences are warranted.</li>
<li>The incident raises concerns over the message sent to younger players regarding acceptable conduct.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“That’s a slap on the wrist. All these players are highly paid professionals. Any fines will have to be a deterrent.” – Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote>
<p>The opinions expressed highlight the need for the ICC to enforce stronger disciplinary measures to maintain standards in professional cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ricky-ponting-blasts-icc-for-letting-virat-kohli-go-easily-for-sam-konstas-act-gavaskar-calls-it-slap-on-the-wrist-101735262639276.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ricky-ponting-blasts-icc-for-letting-virat-kohli-go-easily-for-sam-konstas-act-gavaskar-calls-it-slap-on-the-wrist-101735262639276.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 01:34:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 stunning images of space captured by NASA - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Stunning Images of Space Captured by NASA</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 27, 2024</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>DNA</p><img src="https://images1.dnaindia.com/images/DNA-EN/900x1600/2024/12/27/1735263008119_1.jpg" alt="8 stunning images of space captured by NASA"><figcaption>Credit: NASA</figcaption><p>This article showcases a collection of breathtaking images of space taken by NASA, illustrating the beauty and mystery of the universe.</p><ul><li>A Hubble image of the dying star CW Leonis creating a mesmerizing visual.</li><li>A serene depiction of the spiral galaxy UGC 12295 captured by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope.</li><li>An image of the isolated spiral galaxy UGC 9391 taken with Hubble's Wide Field Camera 3.</li><li>A vibrant image of the globular star cluster Terzan 12, showing starlight influenced by space dust.</li><li>Hubble captures a dense cloud of gas and dust in the image veiled by CB 130-3.</li><li>A radiant red-hued image that aligns with vibrant autumn colors.</li><li>An astonishing view of G35.2-0.7N, a celestial object in the constellation Aquila.</li><li>Additional images showcasing NASA's remarkable photography of celestial phenomena.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/viral/8-stunning-images-of-space-captured-by-nasa-1735262368987</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/viral/8-stunning-images-of-space-captured-by-nasa-1735262368987</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 01:31:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronauts Share Most Breathtaking Images of Earth From Space in 2024 - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronauts Capture Stunning Images of Earth from Space in 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Business Insider</p>
<img src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/12/AuroraFromISS2024-642x260.jpg" alt="Astronauts Share Most Breathtaking Images of Earth From Space in 2024">
<figcaption>An aurora radiates brightly above the Indian Ocean around the Soyuz MS-25 crew ship docked to the ISS. (NASA)</figcaption>
<p>This article features impressive images taken by astronauts from the International Space Station (ISS) throughout 2024, showcasing the beauty and fragility of our planet.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Astronauts take hundreds of photos from space each year.</li>
    <li>Images include breathtaking views of natural phenomena such as the aurora borealis and comet sightings.</li>
    <li>The overview effect profoundly impacts astronauts, altering their perspective on Earth.</li>
    <li>Upcoming plans for astronauts to return to Earth via SpaceX’s Crew Dragon after a prolonged stay on the ISS.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“How would you not want to take pictures and try and share that with the rest of humanity?” - NASA Astronaut Matt Dominick</blockquote>
<p>As the ISS approaches the end of its operational life, its legacy continues to inspire a sense of unity among nations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/astronauts-share-most-breathtaking-images-of-earth-from-space-in-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/astronauts-share-most-breathtaking-images-of-earth-from-space-in-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 01:23:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WHO chief Tedros narrowly escapes bombardment at Yemen's Sanaa airport - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WHO Chief Tedros Survives Bombardment at Yemen's Sanaa Airport</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 06:48 AM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/WHO-Director-General-Tedros-Adhanom-Ghebreyesus--R_1716575928371_1735262084427.jpg" alt="WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus (Reuters)" title="WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus (Reuters)">
<figcaption>WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus (Reuters)</figcaption>
<p>World Health Organization (WHO) Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus narrowly escaped an aerial bombardment at Sanaa International Airport in Yemen, which resulted in the deaths of at least two individuals.</p>
<ul>
<li>Tedros and colleagues were about to board a flight when the attack occurred.</li>
<li>One crew member was injured during the incident.</li>
<li>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres condemned the attack and called for respect for international law.</li>
<li>Airstrikes by the Israeli Air Force targeted Houthi military infrastructure in Yemen, including the airport.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our mission to negotiate the release of UN staff detainees and to assess the health and humanitarian situation in Yemen concluded today… At least two people were reported killed at the airport.” - Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus</blockquote>
<p>This tragic event highlights the precarious situation in Yemen, where conflict continues to pose significant threats to civilians and humanitarian missions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/who-chief-tedros-narrowly-escapes-bombardment-at-yemens-sanaa-airport-101735261594258.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/who-chief-tedros-narrowly-escapes-bombardment-at-yemens-sanaa-airport-101735261594258.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 01:18:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zoho CEO Sridhar Vembu reignites 70-hour work week debate, asks should we work to demographic suicide? His answer is... | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zoho CEO Sridhar Vembu reignites 70-hour work week debate, asks should we work to demographic suicide? His answer is...</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>In a recent post, Zoho CEO Sridhar Vembu revisited the contentious 70-hour work week debate, questioning its necessity for economic development and the impact of such work culture on demographics.</p><blockquote>The rationale behind the 70 hour work week is "it is necessary for economic development". If you look at East Asia - Japan, South Korea, Taiwan and China have all developed through extreme hard work, often imposing punitive levels of work on their own people.</blockquote><p>Key Points:</p><ul><li>Vembu argues that extreme work hours may not be necessary for economic growth.</li><li>He points out low birth rates in East Asian countries that prioritize hard work.</li><li>Questions the viability of success at the expense of personal well-being.</li><li>Calls for a balance between hard work and personal life.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/zoho-ceo-sridhar-vembu-reignites-70-hour-work-week-debate-asks-should-we-work-to-demographic-suicide-narayana-murthy-11735261658378.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/zoho-ceo-sridhar-vembu-reignites-70-hour-work-week-debate-asks-should-we-work-to-demographic-suicide-narayana-murthy-11735261658378.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 01:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China to build world's biggest dam near border; India waits & watches - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxQWGJFZy03MUhfYU5ReEM0b3RFeXp4dnZyNDRWUUM4TGMzMnYtdnVUZmtnLUlHX21SUkdCekxkMEtuTmdob0hKNkt2Y1d4WXVjMmdTZEJtYmVYLVFPUDNHWm5uWW1JX3JKcVJLeHpzTHNVOWUzYzdDc0xvbjJGc0JhOGpWRFBwVmpJWktmN0VPZmVBM283SU1ON3U0Nmpqa241SzVPLVZmVHNjb01uT2E3cmhMQWlhYWNOZFdnZmsyeXNUQUFtQm9Ud05xZWl2Zw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxQWGJFZy03MUhfYU5ReEM0b3RFeXp4dnZyNDRWUUM4TGMzMnYtdnVUZmtnLUlHX21SUkdCekxkMEtuTmdob0hKNkt2Y1d4WXVjMmdTZEJtYmVYLVFPUDNHWm5uWW1JX3JKcVJLeHpzTHNVOWUzYzdDc0xvbjJGc0JhOGpWRFBwVmpJWktmN0VPZmVBM283SU1ON3U0Nmpqa241SzVPLVZmVHNjb01uT2E3cmhMQWlhYWNOZFdnZmsyeXNUQUFtQm9Ud05xZWl2Zw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 01:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>