<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:21:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:21:48 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp To Stop Working On These Android Phones From January 2025: Full List - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp To Stop Working On These Android Phones From January 2025: Full List</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> December 23, 2024, 16:36 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The start of 2025 will mean end of WhatsApp support for these Android users" title="The start of 2025 will mean end of WhatsApp support for these Android users"><figcaption>The start of 2025 will mean end of WhatsApp support for these Android users</figcaption></figure><p>WhatsApp is going to stop working on millions of Android phones running outdated versions of the operating system starting January 2025. The update is necessary as the Meta-owned platform continues to evolve, introducing new features that require modern hardware.</p><ul><li>The platform will no longer support devices running Android KitKat and older versions.</li><li>Users with affected devices should upgrade to new smartphones to continue using WhatsApp.</li><li>Popular brands affected include Samsung, LG, Sony, and HTC.</li></ul><p><strong>Affected Samsung Models:</strong> Galaxy S3, Note 2, Ace 3, S4 Mini.<br><strong>Affected HTC Models:</strong> One X, One X+, Desire 500, Desire 601.<br><strong>Affected Sony Models:</strong> Xperia Z, Xperia SP, Xperia T, Xperia V.<br><strong>Affected LG Models:</strong> Optimus G, Nexus 4, G2 Mini, L90.<br><strong>Affected Motorola Models:</strong> Moto G, Razr HD, Moto E 2014.</strong></p><blockquote>WhatsApp supports chat and data backup via Google Drive, urging users to back up their data before the end of support date.</blockquote><p>This shift highlights the increasing demand for modern specifications in messaging apps, pushing users to continuously upgrade their devices to stay connected.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/tech/whatsapp-to-stop-working-on-these-android-phones-from-january-2025-full-list-9165301.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/tech/whatsapp-to-stop-working-on-these-android-phones-from-january-2025-full-list-9165301.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:38:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How this 24 year old man survived deadly brain disorder, Moyamoya disease - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How a 24-Year-Old Man Overcame Moyamoya Disease</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Straits Times</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116589323,imgsize-656793,width-400,resizemode-4/116589323.jpg" alt="How this 24 year old man survived deadly brain disorder, Moyamoya disease" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Chee Ming Heng: A Survivor of Moyamoya Disease</figcaption><p>In 2024, Chee Ming Heng, a 24-year-old, was diagnosed with the rare brain disorder known as Moyamoya disease. His journey highlights the challenges and recovery from this little-known condition.</p><ul><li>Chee experienced initial symptoms, including difficulty writing, holding cutlery, and facial drooping, leading to a hospital visit.</li><li>Further testing revealed he had Moyamoya disease, which primarily affects blood flow to the brain.</li><li>The disease is most common in Japan, Korea, and China, linked to conditions like Down syndrome and sickle cell anemia.</li><li>Common symptoms include headaches, seizures, and weakness.</li><li>Dr. Chen Min Wei performed a bypass operation on Chee, creating a new blood vessel to improve blood flow.</li><li>Chee had a successful recovery and had to relearn basic activities post-surgery.</li></ul><blockquote>“Post-operation, I had just woken up, and when they came, I was just happy to see them.” - Chee Ming Heng</blockquote><p>Chee's story sheds light on Moyamoya disease, offering hope to others facing similar struggles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/moyamoya-disease-how-this-24-year-old-man-survived-the-deadly-brain-disorder/articleshow/116589343.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/moyamoya-disease-how-this-24-year-old-man-survived-the-deadly-brain-disorder/articleshow/116589343.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parker Solar Probe to touch the Sun: Nasa won't know if it's dead or alive till... - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parker Solar Probe to Flyby the Sun on December 24, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 <strong>By:</strong> Sibu Kumar Tripathi</p>
<img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/parker-solar-probe-230821618-16x9_0.png?VersionId=6TKGz8qQ1Sb1u5CtYBlrb3_.ERnCQo6x&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Parker Solar Probe" title="The Parker Solar Probe was designed to study solar phenomena. (Photo: Nasa)" height="388">
<figcaption>The Parker Solar Probe was designed to study solar phenomena. (Photo: Nasa)</figcaption>
<p>Nasa's Parker Solar Probe is gearing up for a historic flyby of the Sun on Christmas Eve, December 24, 2024, passing within 6.1 million kilometers of the Sun's surface.</p>
<ul>
<li>The probe's closest approach will be the closest any human-made object has ever come to a star.</li>
<li>Last confirmed contact was on December 21, where all systems were functioning normally.</li>
<li>During the flyby, Parker will be out of contact with Earth due to intense conditions near the Sun.</li>
<li>Nick Pinkine, mission operations manager, emphasizes the significance of the flyby as uncharted territory.</li>
<li>Parker will transmit a beacon signal on December 27 to confirm its operational status after the flyby.</li>
<li>Its mission aims to enhance understanding of solar phenomena and impacts on space weather.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>No human-made object has ever passed this close to a star, so Parker will truly be returning data from uncharted territory.</blockquote>
<p>This mission could offer invaluable insights into solar activity, particularly during solar maximum, potentially affecting our understanding of the Sun's influence on Earth and beyond.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/parker-solar-probe-to-touch-the-sun-nasa-wont-know-if-its-dead-or-alive-2654013-2024-12-23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/parker-solar-probe-to-touch-the-sun-nasa-wont-know-if-its-dead-or-alive-2654013-2024-12-23</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:16:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honda and Nissan officially agree to talk merger; eye sales of 30 tn yen via potential deal - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/business/honda-and-nissan-officially-agree-to-talk-merger-eye-sales-of-30-tn-yen-via-potential-deal/articleshow/116593660.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/business/honda-and-nissan-officially-agree-to-talk-merger-eye-sales-of-30-tn-yen-via-potential-deal/articleshow/116593660.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:11:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kumar Vishwas Cites Ramayana In Veiled Dig at Shatrughan Sinha, Sonakshi: 'Teach Your Children...' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kumar Vishwas Cites Ramayana In Veiled Dig at Shatrughan Sinha, Sonakshi: 'Teach Your Children...'</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> December 23, 2024, 17:34 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='Kumar Vishwas's apparent dig at Sonakshi and Shatrughan Sinha sparked mixed reactions online.'/><figcaption>Kumar Vishwas's apparent dig at Sonakshi and Shatrughan Sinha sparked mixed reactions online. (Photo: X)</figcaption><p>Poet Kumar Vishwas stirred controversy with a veiled reference to actor Shatrughan Sinha and his daughter Sonakshi Sinha's interfaith marriage during a public event, urging people to teach their children the 'Ramayana'.</p><ul><li>Vishwas suggested in his comments that cultural teachings are essential to prevent losing family values.</li><li>His comments provoked a range of reactions on social media, with some criticizing him as inappropriate.</li><li>Congress spokesperson Supriya Shrinate rebuked Vishwas, emphasizing women's rights to make personal choices regarding marriage.</li><li>Sonakshi was married to actor Zaheer Iqbal in June, which is added context to Vishwas's comments.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Kumar Vishwas ji, you not only made a cheap comment on Sonakshi Sinha’s inter-religious marriage, but you also exposed your real thinking about women…” - Supriya Shrinate</p></blockquote><p>The incident exemplifies the ongoing discussion around cultural values and personal choices in Indian society.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/kumar-vishwas-cites-ramayana-in-veiled-dig-at-shatrughan-sinha-sonakshi-teach-your-children-9165377.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/kumar-vishwas-cites-ramayana-in-veiled-dig-at-shatrughan-sinha-sonakshi-teach-your-children-9165377.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:00:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OPPO confirms Reno 13 series launch for January 2025, shares design details - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/oppo-confirms-reno-13-series-launch-for-january-2025-shares-design-details-124122300387_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/oppo-confirms-reno-13-series-launch-for-january-2025-shares-design-details-124122300387_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:57:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intellect Design Arena, Suven Pharma, India Cements, Zomato, Sterling and Wilson Renewable Energy, ITC: Check top buzzing stocks of the day - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Buzzing Stocks of the Day: India Cements, Zomato, ITC and More</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Stock Market News</p><p>Domestic stocks were trading in the green in the afternoon deals on December 23, with a notable uptick in several stocks.</p><ul><li><strong>India Cements:</strong> Shares surged up to 11% after CCI approved the acquisition proposal by UltraTech Cement.</li><li><strong>Zomato:</strong> Shares dropped 3% after making its debut on the SENSEX, replacing JSW Steel.</li><li><strong>Metal Stocks:</strong> Increased trading observed in multiple steel manufacturers due to a government probe into imports.</li><li><strong>TeamLease Services:</strong> Trading 2% lower amidst new acquisitions.</li><li><strong>Siemens India:</strong> Shares fell nearly 3% due to lowered order expectations.</li><li><strong>Insurance Stocks:</strong> Experienced declines after GST Council deferred decisions affecting tax rates.</li><li><strong>Niva Bupa:</strong> Positive outlook sees shares rising over 2%.</li><li><strong>Intellect Design Arena:</strong> Trading over 12% higher amid a significant increase in trade volume.</li><li><strong>Suven Pharmaceuticals:</strong> Stock down 6% following acquisition announcements.</li><li><strong>ITC:</strong> Shares higher over 2% as the company finalizes its hotel business demerger.</li><li><strong>Sterling and Wilson Renewable Energy:</strong> Trading over 7% higher after receiving a significant order in Gujarat.</li></ul><p>The market showed a mixture of highs and lows, reflecting various underlying economic signals and company-specific news.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/intellect-design-arena-suven-pharma-india-cements-zomato-sterling-and-wilson-renewable-energy-itc-check-top-buzzing-stocks-of-the-day/article-136607/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/stocks/intellect-design-arena-suven-pharma-india-cements-zomato-sterling-and-wilson-renewable-energy-itc-check-top-buzzing-stocks-of-the-day/article-136607/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:49:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who Was Epigamia CEO Rohan Mirchandani, Who Died Of Cardiac Arrest At 41 - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Remembering Rohan Mirchandani, CEO of Epigamia Who Passed Away at 41</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>December 21, 2024 — <strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/prq8hs8g_rohan-mirchandani_625x300_22_December_24.jpeg" alt="Rohan Mirchandani" title="Who Was Epigamia CEO Rohan Mirchandani, Who Died Of Cardiac Arrest At 41"><figcaption>Rohan Mirchandani, CEO of Epigamia</figcaption><p>Rohan Mirchandani, co-founder of Epigamia, died suddenly from a cardiac arrest at the age of 41. He was instrumental in establishing Epigamia as India's leading Greek yoghurt brand.</p><ul><li>Mirchandani co-founded Drums Food International in 2013.</li><li>He greatly impacted the healthy food market through his work with Epigamia, which includes a range of yogurt and dairy products.</li><li>His vision was to grow the company’s revenue to ₹250 crore this fiscal year.</li><li>Rohan was highly educated, holding degrees from renowned institutions like NYU and Wharton.</li><li>He planned to expand into the Middle East market by 2025-26.</li></ul><blockquote>“All of us at the Epigamia family will deeply mourn this loss. Rohan was our mentor, friend, and leader.” - Epigamia Leadership Team</blockquote><p>This loss is a significant moment for the Epigamia team and all those who knew Rohan Mirchandani. His legacy is solidified in the company’s achievements and the lives he touched.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/who-was-rohan-mirchandani-epigamia-founder-dead-at-41-7312757</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/who-was-rohan-mirchandani-epigamia-founder-dead-at-41-7312757</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:42:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi polls: BJP releases 'Aarop Patra' against AAP government; Kejriwal reacts - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP's 'Aarop Patra' Targets AAP Ahead of Delhi Elections; Kejriwal Responds</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="BJP vs AAP Delhi Elections" />
<figcaption>BJP's campaign highlighting allegations against the AAP government.</figcaption>
<p>As the Delhi elections approach, the BJP has released a document dubbed 'Aarop Patra' containing accusations against the AAP government. Kejriwal's administration has responded to these claims, intensifying the political rivalry.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The BJP's 'Aarop Patra' accuses AAP of corruption and mismanagement.</li>
  <li>Kejriwal claims the BJP is using diversionary tactics to deflect attention from its failures.</li>
  <li>The political landscape in Delhi is heating up with various parties gearing up for the elections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is merely a tactic of distraction,” asserted Kejriwal, stressing that the BJP is afraid of losing the elections.</blockquote>
<p>The release of the 'Aarop Patra' marks a significant escalation in the election campaign, with both parties gearing up for a fierce political contest.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/delhi-polls-bjp-releases-aarop-patra-against-aap-govt-kejriwal-reacts/articleshow/116591901.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/delhi-polls-bjp-releases-aarop-patra-against-aap-govt-kejriwal-reacts/articleshow/116591901.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Don't Mess With Us’: Ex-Mossad Agents Make Sensational On-Air Revelation About Hezbollah Pager Plot - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Don't Mess With Us’: Ex-Mossad Agents Make Sensational On-Air Revelation About Hezbollah Pager Plot</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> CBS News</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Hezbollah pager blast: Ex-Mossad agents detail Israel's pager plot (Photo: AFP/CBS News)"><figcaption>Hezbollah pager blast: Ex-Mossad agents detail Israel's pager plot (Photo: AFP/CBS News)</figcaption></figure><p>This article reveals the covert operation conducted by Israeli spy agency Mossad to create and activate explosives disguised as pagers, targeting Hezbollah militants.</p><ul><li>The operation led to pager blasts in Lebanon in September 2024, killing several Hezbollah members and injuring around 3,000 people.</li><li>Two ex-Mossad agents provided insights into how they deceived Hezbollah into using explosives created by Israel.</li><li>Mossad set up shell companies to manufacture and sell the devices without Hezbollah's knowledge.</li><li>The blasts aimed not to kill but to incapacitate militants, creating fear and demonstrating superiority over Hezbollah.</li></ul><blockquote>CBS 60 minutes interviewed two recently retired senior (alleged) Mossad agents with leading roles in the “pager and walkie-talkie” operation which decimated Hezbollah. Watch this fascinating interview! <a href="https://t.co/SuxNUdqWX1" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/SuxNUdqWX1</a></blockquote><p>This operation represents one of the most notable and daring counterintelligence strategies in history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/israel-ex-mossad-agents-make-on-air-revelation-about-hezbollah-pager-plot-lebanon-middle-east-latest-updates-9165307.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/israel-ex-mossad-agents-make-on-air-revelation-about-hezbollah-pager-plot-lebanon-middle-east-latest-updates-9165307.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:33:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Indian drinks that can help reduce belly fat quickly - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxNWWF0c1VwYlpvaURtZkhYcDMzM1lrRDVRUk5fMVhwZ1Y2bzFjT3F5ZFAxQUYybGxtSTJIZFM0b0F1RU8yZTBYemhlYnVxdE0yVUdXaW9qdDZISWNNdnN2cmphREtUNmdNRzJCemlTYm1VeGJ4UmRLZTVhQ3B0dTlla085RGU2LWM1d1QyV2FNak1CQjF2QlBqUmF6SW5fX1FGZE1veXJydWZlUVJfWTlsNkRSdW9VRk9WWHhTcVN2QTNEWG4wT3ZxTDdWb3RxS2lWWVBaVGJFNDFMT3ZYbE11SEtVNEFydXh4dkHSAeoBQVVfeXFMTVlhdHNVcGJab2lEbWZIWHAzMzNZa0Q1UVJOXzFYcGdWNm8xY09xeWRQMUFGMmxsbUkySGRTNG9BdUVPMmUwWHpoZWJ1cXRNMlVHV2lvanQ2SEljTXZzdnJqYURLVDZnTUcyQnppU2JtVXhieFJkS2U1YUNwdHU5ZWtPOURlNi1jNXdUMldhTWpNQkIxdkJQalJhekluX19RRmRNb3lycnVmZVFSX1k5bDZEUnVvVUZPVlh4U3FTdkEzRFhuME92cUw3Vm90cUtpVllQWlRiRTQxTE92WGxNdUhLVTRBcnV4eHZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxNWWF0c1VwYlpvaURtZkhYcDMzM1lrRDVRUk5fMVhwZ1Y2bzFjT3F5ZFAxQUYybGxtSTJIZFM0b0F1RU8yZTBYemhlYnVxdE0yVUdXaW9qdDZISWNNdnN2cmphREtUNmdNRzJCemlTYm1VeGJ4UmRLZTVhQ3B0dTlla085RGU2LWM1d1QyV2FNak1CQjF2QlBqUmF6SW5fX1FGZE1veXJydWZlUVJfWTlsNkRSdW9VRk9WWHhTcVN2QTNEWG4wT3ZxTDdWb3RxS2lWWVBaVGJFNDFMT3ZYbE11SEtVNEFydXh4dkHSAeoBQVVfeXFMTVlhdHNVcGJab2lEbWZIWHAzMzNZa0Q1UVJOXzFYcGdWNm8xY09xeWRQMUFGMmxsbUkySGRTNG9BdUVPMmUwWHpoZWJ1cXRNMlVHV2lvanQ2SEljTXZzdnJqYURLVDZnTUcyQnppU2JtVXhieFJkS2U1YUNwdHU5ZWtPOURlNi1jNXdUMldhTWpNQkIxdkJQalJhekluX19RRmRNb3lycnVmZVFSX1k5bDZEUnVvVUZPVlh4U3FTdkEzRFhuME92cUw3Vm90cUtpVllQWlRiRTQxTE92WGxNdUhLVTRBcnV4eHZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunny Leone gets monthly grant under Chhattisgarh govt scheme. But there's a twist - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunny Leone gets monthly grant under Chhattisgarh govt scheme. But there's a twist</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/sunny_leone_chhattisgarh_1734937926897_1734937927185.jpg" alt="The man responsible for opening and operating an account in the name of actor Sunny Leone has been identified as Virendra Joshi(Girish Srivastav)">
<figcaption>The man responsible for opening and operating an account in the name of actor Sunny Leone has been identified as Virendra Joshi(Girish Srivastav)</figcaption>
<p>A man in Chhattisgarh has fraudulently opened an account in the name of actress Sunny Leone to illegally receive monthly government grants designated for women.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Chhattisgarh government provides ₹1,000 every month to married women through the 'Mahtari Vandan Yojana'.</li>
<li>Virendra Joshi allegedly opened the account under Sunny Leone's name and has been receiving money illegally.</li>
<li>Authorities are investigating the case and have frozen the fraudulent account.</li>
<li>The discovery has led to political tensions between the BJP and Congress parties regarding the effectiveness of the scheme.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Deepak Baij of Congress claims that over 50% of beneficiaries of the Mahtari Vandan Yojana are fake.</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights issues of fraud and portrayal of social welfare programs while raising questions about beneficiary verification processes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/sunny-leone-gets-monthly-grant-under-chhattisgarh-govt-scheme-but-theres-a-twist-101734934702489.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/sunny-leone-gets-monthly-grant-under-chhattisgarh-govt-scheme-but-theres-a-twist-101734934702489.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:27:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Novel solution for tackling pest menace in hostels | - UoH Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQUVlUcThNMkk2YjRlcWR1aHRPZ1hHNElieEQ3a28tREtZTzI5VmFCdEZUVk43Rk8xSEo3MEdsUUpSVjVyenFJUjkzcEtLRG5jYjl4SVRxWjVkbjlNaWlGV0hfUnRDc3hGbWZzVzlCMlJCVUQ1eDVIamo1Ymd4V2doWGVSN2Y?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQUVlUcThNMkk2YjRlcWR1aHRPZ1hHNElieEQ3a28tREtZTzI5VmFCdEZUVk43Rk8xSEo3MEdsUUpSVjVyenFJUjkzcEtLRG5jYjl4SVRxWjVkbjlNaWlGV0hfUnRDc3hGbWZzVzlCMlJCVUQ1eDVIamo1Ymd4V2doWGVSN2Y?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:12:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Used Practice Pitches For India, New For Australia? Curator Breaks Silence As Another Row Erupts - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPcXdPNzZvSktEVm9KSmE5M2dHYWh5bFNhVDR5V0dGX21oZFFsM01UOUd4dGtNWmRjQUhzelBGSy1mVHRMS1F1Tkh1LUp5TG8yYU5QeTNQaG9lMzkzczkyNDRlLTAtRVlvLW5zUWx1bnhrd2p1RUxDa0c5WDR0S0l3aGdGT2p4ZFVaMHVaY0pVMFFhREJFZWhWaUpTa1YxbEM4Z3J4ZkFfalFBWUZ1WEd2NV94OWxfWkh6YTNBMGp4VmZ3aHZpUGFQQ0hqc0ltQUVLbTFXYUZKWdIB3wFBVV95cUxOXzBhNDUzUGt4czJvOExMc3UzM3Jvb3JXODEzWGVzNlNKeTV0WHp1UjVVd0VpNFVkNGRwQnNUdFc4aHZLZ0E3eWpKRGJPMGp3TVhnbHllNS1ZNkxndmFYNzRYdTBOS0tkSll4MmFFT1ZNRGcxZm9oYXdfZjVSWEtWOERQQWdQMklfOThiQmExVmhpQW0wSmZnWThhTjBxa2dNa0llNXJKZkhtZ1A0QTYtMGtYZk1HbGNvZ180TFJJX2RXYlJvam5PdW5JN3pUNUxQUHQ4MUgxNFJWRW1vNFRj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPcXdPNzZvSktEVm9KSmE5M2dHYWh5bFNhVDR5V0dGX21oZFFsM01UOUd4dGtNWmRjQUhzelBGSy1mVHRMS1F1Tkh1LUp5TG8yYU5QeTNQaG9lMzkzczkyNDRlLTAtRVlvLW5zUWx1bnhrd2p1RUxDa0c5WDR0S0l3aGdGT2p4ZFVaMHVaY0pVMFFhREJFZWhWaUpTa1YxbEM4Z3J4ZkFfalFBWUZ1WEd2NV94OWxfWkh6YTNBMGp4VmZ3aHZpUGFQQ0hqc0ltQUVLbTFXYUZKWdIB3wFBVV95cUxOXzBhNDUzUGt4czJvOExMc3UzM3Jvb3JXODEzWGVzNlNKeTV0WHp1UjVVd0VpNFVkNGRwQnNUdFc4aHZLZ0E3eWpKRGJPMGp3TVhnbHllNS1ZNkxndmFYNzRYdTBOS0tkSll4MmFFT1ZNRGcxZm9oYXdfZjVSWEtWOERQQWdQMklfOThiQmExVmhpQW0wSmZnWThhTjBxa2dNa0llNXJKZkhtZ1A0QTYtMGtYZk1HbGNvZ180TFJJX2RXYlJvam5PdW5JN3pUNUxQUHQ4MUgxNFJWRW1vNFRj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:07:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Constipation Awareness Month 2024: 10 Changes Everyone Can Make To Their Diet For Better Digestion - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Constipation Awareness Month 2024: 10 Changes Everyone Can Make To Their Diet For Better Digestion</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> April 2, 2024 by NDTV</p>
<img title="Constipation Awareness Month 2024: 10 Changes Everyone Can Make To Their Diet For Better Digestion" alt="Constipation Awareness Month 2024: 10 Changes Everyone Can Make To Their Diet For Better Digestion" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/c8uelv9_constipation_625x300_02_April_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400">
<figcaption>Constipation Awareness Month 2024 aims to educate about dietary changes that improve digestion.</figcaption>
<p>December is recognized as Constipation Awareness Month, focusing on educating the public about constipation, its causes, and prevention methods. Chronic constipation can lead to serious complications, and dietary changes play a key role in managing this condition.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Increase fibre intake with soluble and insoluble sources.</li>
  <li>Stay hydrated by drinking at least eight glasses of water daily.</li>
  <li>Incorporate probiotics through foods like yogurt and fermented vegetables.</li>
  <li>Limit processed foods to enhance digestive efficiency.</li>
  <li>Eat regular, balanced meals to support digestive health.</li>
  <li>Chew food thoroughly to aid in digestion.</li>
  <li>Avoid excessive caffeine and alcohol to prevent dehydration.</li>
  <li>Incorporate healthy fats for better nutrient absorption.</li>
  <li>Include natural laxative foods like kiwis and prunes.</li>
  <li>Practice mindful eating for improved digestion.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Implementing these dietary changes can lead to significant improvements in digestive health, reducing the incidence of constipation and enhancing overall well-being.”</blockquote>
<p>It's vital to introduce these changes gradually and consult healthcare professionals for personalized advice.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/health/constipation-awareness-month-2024-10-changes-everyone-can-make-to-their-diet-for-better-digestion-7312739</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/health/constipation-awareness-month-2024-10-changes-everyone-can-make-to-their-diet-for-better-digestion-7312739</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:03:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parker Solar Probe to zoom past 6.1 mn kms from Sun on Christmas eve: NASA By IANS - Investing.com India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://in.investing.com/news/general-news/parker-solar-probe-to-zoom-past-61-mn-kms-from-sun-on-christmas-eve-nasa-4587913</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://in.investing.com/news/general-news/parker-solar-probe-to-zoom-past-61-mn-kms-from-sun-on-christmas-eve-nasa-4587913</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:59:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IPO News Live: Mamata Machinery, DAM Capital, Transrail Lighting, Concord Enviro Systems and Sanathan Textiles IPOs closing today - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAJBVV95cUxORG1VXzhpSDAtVWRvTjJ3N2RWT1AxMExFU1llcHBXXzZ0SlJWcmpRSzNVZVA3ZU9ONFhDOUxjTHA3NGppRnc0amxuS0RtV1hhNlFTN1hyNEhtdnB3eFlaRFl3emRtb2dUQnF3b0owUGZLSGtBaWNiOHJCeC1yUFc5eVRRN1hzY05sTUhmdVc3aGE0Vk5sM1czSGdCRkhCUHZTalFBLWZheWFjd0tFWVVVUDh0TDNYMm5ZSm9DYnZOMWFLUUF0ZGlfeGpOQndTTVZVOWMyLWc4Y2dtMlItY0V1ZmJUX081dzQyNHJ6QmlqeEg3anBYZENPemJWQW16N0s4bTNlRUJxd3JHdFBlYWZERzhkZVVIeW9ObVpINnZDY1R1dzFoTTBDM0ZkcVVhdEw2aFRKMg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAJBVV95cUxORG1VXzhpSDAtVWRvTjJ3N2RWT1AxMExFU1llcHBXXzZ0SlJWcmpRSzNVZVA3ZU9ONFhDOUxjTHA3NGppRnc0amxuS0RtV1hhNlFTN1hyNEhtdnB3eFlaRFl3emRtb2dUQnF3b0owUGZLSGtBaWNiOHJCeC1yUFc5eVRRN1hzY05sTUhmdVc3aGE0Vk5sM1czSGdCRkhCUHZTalFBLWZheWFjd0tFWVVVUDh0TDNYMm5ZSm9DYnZOMWFLUUF0ZGlfeGpOQndTTVZVOWMyLWc4Y2dtMlItY0V1ZmJUX081dzQyNHJ6QmlqeEg3anBYZENPemJWQW16N0s4bTNlRUJxd3JHdFBlYWZERzhkZVVIeW9ObVpINnZDY1R1dzFoTTBDM0ZkcVVhdEw2aFRKMg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:56:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[18% GST on caramelised popcorn sparks meme fest online. Best ones here - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>18% GST on Caramelised Popcorn Sparks Online Meme Fest</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/social-media-flooded-with-memes-on-popcorn-taxation-representational-image-from-pexels-232525530-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=HEK3Eqm2GUs5uOOMgKteQj.NGjcUX0dR&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="caramelised popcorn" title="Social media flooded with memes on popcorn taxation. (Representational image from Pexels)" height="388"><figcaption>Social media flooded with memes on popcorn taxation. (Representational image from Pexels)</figcaption><p>The GST Council’s decision to impose an 18% GST on caramelised popcorn has ignited a wave of memes on social media.</p><ul><li>Unpacked and unlabelled salted popcorn: 5% GST</li><li>Pre-packed and labelled ready-to-eat popcorn: 12% GST</li><li>Caramelised popcorn: 18% GST</li></ul><blockquote>One user joked about eating their last packet of caramelised popcorn before the price surges.</blockquote><p>The humorous reactions indicate the complexity of tax classifications and the rise of popcorn as a ‘luxury’ item online.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/trending-news/story/gst-council-18-gst-caramelised-popcorn-tax-sparks-meme-fest-online-2653970-2024-12-23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/trending-news/story/gst-council-18-gst-caramelised-popcorn-tax-sparks-meme-fest-online-2653970-2024-12-23</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:53:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steering, Throttle Fault May Be Behind Mumbai Ferry Crash, Crew Knew: Sources - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Steering, Throttle Fault May Be Behind Mumbai Ferry Crash, Crew Knew: Sources</h1><p><strong>Published on December 18, Source: Mumbai News</strong></p><p>The recent collision between a Navy boat and a passenger ferry in Mumbai resulted in tragic losses, likely due to technical issues with the naval vessel.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred on December 18, resulting in 15 deaths.</li><li>A technical malfunction in the steering assembly and throttle quadrant is believed to be the cause.</li><li>The Navy boat was reportedly speeding and lost control before the collision.</li><li>The ferry was carrying over 100 passengers and sank in the Arabian Sea.</li><li>Of the 113 people on both vessels, 15 perished, and 98 were rescued.</li><li>The ferry was overloaded, surpassing its licensed passenger capacity.</li><li>The Maharashtra Maritime Board has initiated an investigation and cancelled the ferry's license.</li></ul><blockquote>“The crew was aware of the malfunction when the collision took place.” - Survivor from the Navy vessel</blockquote><p>The tragedy highlights significant safety concerns in maritime operations and calls for a thorough investigation into the events leading to the accident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/mumbai-ferry-crash-steering-fault-caused-mumbai-ferry-crash-navy-crew-was-aware-sources-7312550</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/mumbai-ferry-crash-steering-fault-caused-mumbai-ferry-crash-navy-crew-was-aware-sources-7312550</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:36:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chandrababu Naidu & Revanth Reddy: A Meeting in Davos? - Gulte]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chandrababu Naidu & Revanth Reddy: A Meeting in Davos?</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> 12:06 pm, 23 December 2024</p>
<img width="1200" height="675" src="https://cdn.gulte.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/AP-and-Telangana-CM.jpg" alt="">
<figcaption>Chandrababu Naidu and Revanth Reddy during a previous meeting.</figcaption>
<p>The chief ministers of the Telugu states, Chandrababu Naidu and Revanth Reddy, are set to attend the upcoming World Economic Forum Summit in Davos, which begins on January 20. While this may be an opportunity for them to meet, their attendance will be in an individual capacity rather than a bilateral meeting.</p>
<ul>
<li>Both leaders have previously met to discuss post-bifurcation issues.</li>
<li>This will be Naidu’s first trip to Davos during his second tenure as a chief minister.</li>
<li>Revanth Reddy continues the tradition of attending the summit.</li>
<li>Maharashtra's chief minister Devendra Fadnavis will also be at Davos.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It has to be seen if they will orchestrate a meeting here to discuss political affairs of Telugu states.”</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming summit presents a significant platform for political discussions among the Telugu CMs, which could influence the region's governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gulte.com/political-news/331463/chandrababu-naidu-revanth-reddy-a-meeting-in-davos</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gulte.com/political-news/331463/chandrababu-naidu-revanth-reddy-a-meeting-in-davos</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:36:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Row Over Congress Link To Allu Arjun House Attack, All 6 Protesters Held Get Bail - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxPVHZZRGR5MTE5S0hqbll2azE0YVpwUHUwM1N5eUpWUjU1Mmpsd2pnUVBQTExkc2dINnZMVTVXb1lCQms2ckl3RjdCaVpaaXpRdmhWWGswYjdfTXJiaVdJZklFN2VYTV9NVzZnaWplNVdSYU9YOU1kajFycWlMYW1PUGI2ajlETG9KaU1TSFFuTUFWVDJ4aGw4NXdFcmswa29kNFJCa1FXcnE3Qm1WZTVCQjhQLUkyOG9mYmVVYmhzV0dOcnZFNEk0ejQ1YTJrcVdHYU1rdzVXT1ZPV0cxcld0Y1h30gHnAUFVX3lxTE54SWU2UERCaW9Pcl9KWW9QVDczU2JBbjhIVHNGOWRlV1YxYldTQlNkMjR0RzZ5Q24wcG1HUjFqNDFpcllTdF9HN1Z3MzRnOU1lamNhN2tlZFJ1YWN4Xy1mR0FRTkFyaF9OT2o5OUJRN01JeDZGNTVQNzdLWTF0b0swV01QejIzM3V6Sm5vTExYSV9oVnZHMEw0Ym1NMnQxMzNRYzF1aUJYYUFSX3NsQ2Etekw0QjhyM1JjYklvMWhLNUhzTkNNalEyTUhqQmdrYlBUTUxFaFFoQjV2dThsRjIxcHdoTHREZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxPVHZZRGR5MTE5S0hqbll2azE0YVpwUHUwM1N5eUpWUjU1Mmpsd2pnUVBQTExkc2dINnZMVTVXb1lCQms2ckl3RjdCaVpaaXpRdmhWWGswYjdfTXJiaVdJZklFN2VYTV9NVzZnaWplNVdSYU9YOU1kajFycWlMYW1PUGI2ajlETG9KaU1TSFFuTUFWVDJ4aGw4NXdFcmswa29kNFJCa1FXcnE3Qm1WZTVCQjhQLUkyOG9mYmVVYmhzV0dOcnZFNEk0ejQ1YTJrcVdHYU1rdzVXT1ZPV0cxcld0Y1h30gHnAUFVX3lxTE54SWU2UERCaW9Pcl9KWW9QVDczU2JBbjhIVHNGOWRlV1YxYldTQlNkMjR0RzZ5Q24wcG1HUjFqNDFpcllTdF9HN1Z3MzRnOU1lamNhN2tlZFJ1YWN4Xy1mR0FRTkFyaF9OT2o5OUJRN01JeDZGNTVQNzdLWTF0b0swV01QejIzM3V6Sm5vTExYSV9oVnZHMEw0Ym1NMnQxMzNRYzF1aUJYYUFSX3NsQ2Etekw0QjhyM1JjYklvMWhLNUhzTkNNalEyTUhqQmdrYlBUTUxFaFFoQjV2dThsRjIxcHdoTHREZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:33:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rozgar Mela | Record govt jobs provided in one-and-a-half years, says PM Modi - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Announces Record Government Jobs at Rozgar Mela</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/932poz/article69017920.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/ModiRozgar.jpg" alt="Minister Narendra Modi addressing the new recruits during the “Rozgar Mela” through video conferencing on Monday, December 23, 2024." title="Minister Narendra Modi addressing the new recruits during the “Rozgar Mela” through video conferencing on Monday, December 23, 2024."><figcaption>Minister Narendra Modi addressing the new recruits during the “Rozgar Mela” through video conferencing.</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi distributed over 71,000 appointment letters to newly appointed recruits, claiming his government has provided nearly 10 lakh permanent government jobs in the past year and a half.</p><ul><li>More than 71,000 appointment letters were distributed through video conferencing.</li><li>Nearly 10 lakh permanent government jobs have been provided in the last one and a half years.</li><li>Focus on youth, emphasizing honesty and transparency in recruitment.</li><li>Notable increase in women recruits and government support for their careers.</li><li>Over 29% of the new recruits belong to the OBC category, with significant representation from SC/ST as well.</li></ul><blockquote>"Rozgar Melas are empowering the youth and unlocking their potential. Best wishes to the newly inducted appointees." — Narendra Modi</blockquote><p>This initiative reflects the government's ongoing commitment to job creation and youth empowerment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rozgar-mela-record-govt-jobs-provided-in-one-and-a-half-years-says-pm-modi/article69017896.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rozgar-mela-record-govt-jobs-provided-in-one-and-a-half-years-says-pm-modi/article69017896.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ousted Syrian President Assad’s wife files for divorce, unhappy in Moscow: Report - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ousted Syrian President Assad’s Wife Files for Divorce, Reports Indicate Discontent in Moscow</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Unspecified News Source</p><p>As reports emerge, the wife of ousted Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, Asma al-Assad, is reportedly filing for divorce, indicating her unhappiness while living in Moscow.</p><ul><li>Asma al-Assad is considering divorce after relocating to Moscow.</li><li>Reports suggest discontent with her current situation and living conditions.</li><li>This development follows the recent political and military challenges faced by the Assad regime.</li></ul><blockquote>“The environment in Moscow has not been conducive to her happiness,” an insider reveals.</blockquote><p>This potential divorce marks a significant personal and political development amid Syria's ongoing crisis and raises questions about the future of the Assad family.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/ousted-syrian-president-assads-wife-files-for-divorce-unhappy-in-moscow-report/articleshow/116588308.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/ousted-syrian-president-assads-wife-files-for-divorce-unhappy-in-moscow-report/articleshow/116588308.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Advanced center for Asthma care launched in Chennai - Healthcare Radius]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthcareradius.in/clinical/advanced-center-for-asthma-care-launched-in-chennai</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcareradius.in/clinical/advanced-center-for-asthma-care-launched-in-chennai</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:17:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan's batting sensation Saim Ayub joins Virat Kohli in this elite list - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/pakistans-batting-sensation-saim-ayub-joins-virat-kohli-in-this-elite-list/articleshow/116589098.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/pakistans-batting-sensation-saim-ayub-joins-virat-kohli-in-this-elite-list/articleshow/116589098.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp to end support for older Android phones from January 1, 2025: Full list here - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp to End Support for Older Android Phones Starting January 1, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified; <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p>
<p>In a significant move, Meta announced that WhatsApp will cease to support older Android devices beginning January 1, 2025. Users operating on Android KitKat and older versions will be unable to run the app, impacting millions globally.</p>
<figure>
<img src="path_to_image_if_available.jpg" alt="WhatsApp logo">
<figcaption>WhatsApp logo</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>Key Points</h2>
<ul>
  <li>WhatsApp support will end for all Android devices running KitKat or older.</li>
  <li>Users are encouraged to back up their data to newer devices.</li>
  <li>Affected brands include Samsung, Motorola, HTC, LG, and Sony.</li>
  <li>Meta previously announced similar plans for older iPhones.</li>
  <li>Important backup tips provided to help users transition smoothly.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>"If you are still using one of these devices as your daily driver, the logical way forward is to back up all your WhatsApp data to a newer device."</p></blockquote>
<p>As WhatsApp phases out support for older systems, users must take proactive measures to move their data to updated devices to avoid losing access to their chat histories.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-whatsapp-to-end-support-for-older-android-phones-from-january-1-2025-full-list-here-3697963/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-whatsapp-to-end-support-for-older-android-phones-from-january-1-2025-full-list-here-3697963/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:08:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Science News | ⚡Upcoming NASA Missions 2025: List of Major NASA Missions Scheduled for Next Year - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxOZmlTQkh3bjN1MDZMYTlGaEhUc2xYNU9ucHI0T0VwX04xRHhVYXlmVC13Y3dfMHl6NUFjMmtYNnFwRkdaaTJvZ2hwZHpFdjRpYkFDOU45MG5qR2tuZVNfdkp6N01FdVNQalJydDZSYkRhUWY5UkRLbEIzc1hqdEtHM3VBQmhWSXhOdXUyQlR6a2NLWkxFOXN3NU9SSUdnbnNkMktXTFNBc1N2d21LaUlqeW9ZRkV1VzVSMUtRN0o2bnpLVURuUDdBVW5nX0hMU2NiaElPMl9BdWFIZXN60gHcAUFVX3lxTE5maVNCSHduM3UwNkxhOUZoSFRzbFg1T25wcjRPRXBfTjFEeFVheWZULXdjd18weXo1QWMya1g2cXBGR1ppMm9naHBkekV2NGliQUM5TjkwbmpHa25lU192Sno3TUV1U1BqUnJ0NlJiRGFRZjlSREtsQjNzWGp0S0czdUFCaFZJeE51dTJCVHprY0taTEU5c3c1T1JJR2duc2QyS1dMU0FzU3Z3bUtpSWp5b1lGRXVXNVIxS1E3SjZuektVRG5QN0FVbmdfSExTY2JoSU8yX0F1YUhlc3o?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxOZmlTQkh3bjN1MDZMYTlGaEhUc2xYNU9ucHI0T0VwX04xRHhVYXlmVC13Y3dfMHl6NUFjMmtYNnFwRkdaaTJvZ2hwZHpFdjRpYkFDOU45MG5qR2tuZVNfdkp6N01FdVNQalJydDZSYkRhUWY5UkRLbEIzc1hqdEtHM3VBQmhWSXhOdXUyQlR6a2NLWkxFOXN3NU9SSUdnbnNkMktXTFNBc1N2d21LaUlqeW9ZRkV1VzVSMUtRN0o2bnpLVURuUDdBVW5nX0hMU2NiaElPMl9BdWFIZXN60gHcAUFVX3lxTE5maVNCSHduM3UwNkxhOUZoSFRzbFg1T25wcjRPRXBfTjFEeFVheWZULXdjd18weXo1QWMya1g2cXBGR1ppMm9naHBkekV2NGliQUM5TjkwbmpHa25lU192Sno3TUV1U1BqUnJ0NlJiRGFRZjlSREtsQjNzWGp0S0czdUFCaFZJeE51dTJCVHprY0taTEU5c3c1T1JJR2duc2QyS1dMU0FzU3Z3bUtpSWp5b1lGRXVXNVIxS1E3SjZuektVRG5QN0FVbmdfSExTY2JoSU8yX0F1YUhlc3o?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:08:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Cements soars 11% as UltraTech Cement’s stake buyout gets CCI nod - Upstox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Cements soars 11% as UltraTech Cement’s stake buyout gets CCI nod</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Economic Times</p><p>Shares of India Cements surged 11% in early trade on Monday after the Competition Commission of India (CCI) approved UltraTech Cement Ltd’s controlling stake in The India Cements Ltd.</p><img src='image_url' alt='India Cements'><figcaption>India Cements stock performance on BSE</figcaption><p>Under the approved deal, UltraTech Cement will acquire a 32.72% stake in India Cements from its promoters and members of the promoter group, as well as from Sri Saradha Logistics Private Limited. UltraTech will make an open offer to acquire up to 26 percent more of the paid-up equity share capital of India Cements, taking its total potential shareholding to nearly 59%.</p><ul><li>CCI approved UltraTech Cement’s acquisition of 32.72% stake in India Cements.</li><li>UltraTech will also make an open offer to acquire an additional 26% stake.</li><li>The transaction aims to provide UltraTech majority control over India Cements.</li><li>India Cements stock was trading at ₹365.00, up 7.62% from Friday's close.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Proposed Combination envisages UltraTech Cement Limited’s acquisition of 32.72% of the paid-up equity share capital of The India Cements Limited.”</blockquote><p>This acquisition reflects UltraTech's strategic move to strengthen its position in the Indian cement market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://upstox.com/news/market-news/latest-updates/india-cements-soars-11-as-ultra-tech-cement-s-stake-buyout-gets-cci-nod/article-136569/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://upstox.com/news/market-news/latest-updates/india-cements-soars-11-as-ultra-tech-cement-s-stake-buyout-gets-cci-nod/article-136569/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:06:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Which Continent Is 90% Covered By Ice? - Jagran Josh]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Which Continent Is 90% Covered By Ice?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 23, Dec 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> jagranjosh.com</p>
<img src="https://img.jagranjosh.com/webstories/118800/pexels-photo-13663494-1734932799.webp" alt="Which Continent Is 90% Covered By Ice?">
<figcaption>Which Continent Is 90% Covered By Ice?</figcaption>
<p>Antarctica, the coldest continent on Earth, is covered by ice that constitutes about 90% of its land area, playing a vital role in global climate regulation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Antarctica contains over 90% of its landmass under thick ice.</li>
  <li>It holds approximately 60% of the world's fresh water.</li>
  <li>Temperatures in Antarctica can drop below -60°C (-76°F).</li>
  <li>No permanent human settlements exist; only temporary research stations.</li>
  <li>Antarctica’s glaciers are critical for global sea levels.</li>
  <li>Diverse wildlife such as penguins and seals are adapted to the harsh conditions.</li>
  <li>Home to international research stations studying climate change and other scientific fields.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Antarctica is crucial for understanding Earth's climate and ecosystems."</blockquote>
<p>This article emphasizes Antarctica's significance in global climate systems and the extreme conditions that define its environment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jagranjosh.com/web-stories/which-continent-is-90-covered-by-ice-118800</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jagranjosh.com/web-stories/which-continent-is-90-covered-by-ice-118800</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:06:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Unique methods astronauts use to maintain hygiene at International Space Station - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Unique Methods Astronauts Use to Maintain Hygiene at the International Space Station</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>December 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>India.com</p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/NASA-Astronaut-2.jpg" alt="NASA Astronaut" height="768" width="1280"><figcaption>NASA Astronaut</figcaption><p>Astronauts on the International Space Station (ISS) face unique challenges when it comes to hygiene due to the lack of traditional bathing facilities. Here are five creative methods they use to stay clean while orbiting the Earth.</p><ul><li>Astronauts brush their teeth with minimal water and wipe off excess toothpaste.</li><li>They use no-rinse shampoo for their hair, rubbing it in and towel-drying it without rinsing.</li><li>No-rinse body wipes replace baths for personal cleaning.</li><li>Instead of washing clothes, they wear disposable ones which are thrown away after use.</li><li>The crew regularly disinfects surfaces in the spacecraft to prevent bacteria build-up.</li></ul><blockquote>They routinely wipe down the spacecraft’s surfaces with disinfectant wipes and vacuum-cleaner-like devices to prevent bacteria from building up.</blockquote><p>Maintaining hygiene in space is crucial for health and wellbeing, showcasing the innovative adaptations required for life beyond Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/science/5-unique-methods-astronauts-use-to-maintain-hygiene-at-international-space-station-7485450/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/science/5-unique-methods-astronauts-use-to-maintain-hygiene-at-international-space-station-7485450/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>