<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:16:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red meat linked with cognitive decline and dementia, study reveals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Red Meat Linked to Cognitive Decline and Dementia, Study Reveals</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117307250,imgsize-148174,width-400,resizemode-4/117307250.jpg" alt="Red meat linked with cognitive decline and dementia, study reveals" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Image illustrating the link between red meat consumption and cognitive decline.</figcaption>
<p>A new study has found a significant correlation between increased consumption of red meat, particularly processed varieties, and a heightened risk of cognitive decline and dementia.</p>
<ul>
<li>Study involved 133,771 individuals monitored for up to 43 years.</li>
<li>Processed red meats (e.g., bacon and sausages) linked with a 13% higher risk of dementia.</li>
<li>Replacing processed red meat with healthier options like nuts and fish may reduce dementia risk.</li>
<li>Participants eating unprocessed red meat showed no significant difference in dementia risk when compared across serving amounts.</li>
<li>Each additional serving of processed red meat was associated with 1.61 years of faster brain aging.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Reducing how much red meat a person eats and replacing it with other protein sources and plant-based options could be included in dietary guidelines to promote cognitive health.” - Dong Wang, MD, ScD</blockquote>
<p>This research emphasizes the importance of dietary choices for maintaining cognitive health and suggests further exploration into diverse population impacts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/red-meat-linked-with-cognitive-decline-and-dementia-study-reveals/articleshow/117307250.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/red-meat-linked-with-cognitive-decline-and-dementia-study-reveals/articleshow/117307250.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cosmologist Rajendra Gupta visits Kerala University - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/cosmologist-rajendra-gupta-visits-kerala-university/article69105490.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/cosmologist-rajendra-gupta-visits-kerala-university/article69105490.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 healthy reasons to sprinkle pepper on your food during winter - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Healthy Reasons to Sprinkle Pepper on Your Food During Winter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117300286,imgsize-1794874,width-400,resizemode-4/117300286.jpg" alt="6 healthy reasons to sprinkle pepper on your food during winter" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>6 healthy reasons to sprinkle pepper on your food during winter</figcaption><p>Winter is a season when we seek warm and cozy foods that not only delight our taste senses but also keep us healthy and resistant to the cold. One spice that is sometimes ignored is black pepper, known for its medicinal benefits and distinct flavor.</p><ul><li>Black pepper cleanses the intestines and stomach due to its detoxifying properties.</li><li>It prevents constipation by improving digestive health.</li><li>According to dietitian Ginni Kalra, black pepper aids in weight loss by preventing the production of new fat cells.</li><li>Piperine in black pepper shows antitumor properties, helping to reduce cancer risks.</li><li>Black pepper boosts immunity due to its vitamin C content and antimicrobial properties.</li><li>When paired with dark chocolate, it enhances cardiovascular health.</li></ul><blockquote>“Black pepper can help you lose weight because it contains piperine, which prevents the production of new fat cells, thus assisting in the prevention of obesity.” - Ginni Kalra, Aakash healthcare, New Delhi</blockquote><p>This winter, consider adding black pepper to your meals as a simple way to enhance both flavor and health benefits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/6-healthy-reasons-to-sprinkle-pepper-on-your-food-during-winter/articleshow/117300164.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/6-healthy-reasons-to-sprinkle-pepper-on-your-food-during-winter/articleshow/117300164.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WPL 2025 Schedule out! Holders RCB take on Gujarat Giants in season opener on February 14 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WPL 2025 Schedule Released: RCB to Face Gujarat Giants in Opener</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> February 5, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article announces the schedule for the Women's Premier League (WPL) 2025, highlighting the season opener which features the defending champions, Royal Challengers Bangalore (RCB), against Gujarat Giants on February 14.</p><ul><li>The season opener will take place on February 14, 2025.</li><li>Royal Challengers Bangalore are the defending champions.</li><li>The match will be held at the M. Chinnaswamy Stadium in Bangalore.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are thrilled to start the season with such an exciting match,” said the WPL commissioner.</blockquote><p>This season promises to be competitive with the return of the marquee teams and players from last year's tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/wpl/wpl-2025-schedule-out-holders-rcb-take-on-gujarat-giants-in-season-opener-on-february-14/articleshow/117306396.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/wpl/wpl-2025-schedule-out-holders-rcb-take-on-gujarat-giants-in-season-opener-on-february-14/articleshow/117306396.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is the new norovirus strain causing a surge in infections in the US? Symptoms to know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is the new norovirus strain causing a surge in infections in the US? Symptoms to know</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong> December 5, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117306133,imgsize-54928,width-400,resizemode-4/117306133.jpg" alt="Is the new norovirus strain causing a surge in infections in the US? Symptoms to know" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Image depicting the increase in norovirus infections.</figcaption>
<p>Norovirus cases have surged recently, raising concerns among health authorities. This increase is attributed to a new strain, GII.17[P17], responsible for a significant portion of recent outbreaks.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The CDC reported 91 norovirus outbreaks in just one week, marking the highest number recorded in recent years.</li>
  <li>The GII.17 strain has been linked to nearly 70% of these outbreaks.</li>
  <li>Experts are uncertain if this strain causes more severe disease but suspect lower immunity is a contributing factor.</li>
  <li>Common symptoms include diarrhea, vomiting, nausea, stomach pain, fever, headache, and body aches.</li>
  <li>Preventive measures include washing hands with soap and hot water, as hand sanitizers are less effective.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It is too early to tell if this strain is associated with more severe norovirus disease,” said Jan Vinjé, PhD, Head of the CDC's National Calcivirus Laboratory.</blockquote>
<p>This increase in norovirus cases highlights the importance of hygiene and awareness about the virus, especially during the winter months when such infections tend to spike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/is-the-new-norovirus-strain-causing-a-surge-in-infections-in-the-us-symptoms-to-know/articleshow/117306173.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/is-the-new-norovirus-strain-causing-a-surge-in-infections-in-the-us-symptoms-to-know/articleshow/117306173.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Industries Q3 result highlights: From Jio, O2C, Retail to Oil & Gas, here’s how RIL performed - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Reliance Industries Q3 result highlights</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Reliance Industries Ltd (RIL), a major conglomerate led by Mukesh Ambani, reported strong Q3 FY25 earnings across its diverse business segments.</p><h2>Key Highlights of Reliance Q3 Results:</h2><ul><li>Net profit of ₹18,540 crore, up 7.4% YoY.</li><li>Consolidated revenue increased by 6.7% YoY to ₹2.40 lakh crore.</li><li>EBITDA grew 8% YoY to ₹43,789 crore.</li><li>Reliance Jio saw a profit increase of 26% to ₹6,861 crore.</li><li>Reliance Retail's revenue reached ₹79,595 crore, up 7% YoY.</li><li>Strong growth in the O2C business, with revenue of ₹149,595 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“Rapid scale up of 5G adoption... strengthens the Digital India mission.” - Akash M Ambani</blockquote><p>Overall, Reliance's performances reflect robust growth in digital services, retail expansion, and resilience in the O2C business despite market challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/reliance-industries-q3-result-highlights-from-jio-o2c-retail-to-oil-gas-here-s-how-ril-performed-11737038904768.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/reliance-industries-q3-result-highlights-from-jio-o2c-retail-to-oil-gas-here-s-how-ril-performed-11737038904768.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:01:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can exercise prevent most of our health issues? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can Exercise Prevent Most Health Issues?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117293807,imgsize-22562,width-400,resizemode-4/117293807.jpg" alt="Can exercise prevent most of our health issues?" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Can exercise prevent most of our health issues?</figcaption>
<p>Research indicates that regular exercise is crucial for preventing various health disorders. Benefits include improved heart and mental health, making it a fundamental component of a healthy lifestyle.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Exercise can significantly reduce the risk of chronic diseases such as heart disease, diabetes, and hypertension.</li>
    <li>Regular physical activity bolsters the immune system, enhancing the body’s ability to fight infections.</li>
    <li>Exercise contributes to better mental health by releasing endorphins, which improve mood and relieve stress.</li>
    <li>Weight management is facilitated by regular exercise, helping prevent obesity-related health issues.</li>
    <li>Physical activity strengthens bones and joints, reducing the risk of osteoporosis and arthritis.</li>
    <li>Cardiovascular exercises are vital for overall health, promoting heart and lung function.</li>
    <li>Incorporating exercise into daily routines can be simple and enjoyable.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Regular physical activity improves our quality of life in addition to preventing disease.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, making time for regular exercise can improve health outcomes, increase longevity, and enhance quality of life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/can-exercise-prevent-most-of-our-health-issues/articleshow/117293807.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/can-exercise-prevent-most-of-our-health-issues/articleshow/117293807.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Naxalites killed in encounter in Chhattisgarh's Bijapur - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>17 Naxalites Killed in Encounter in Chhattisgarh's Bijapur</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/PTI04-26-2023-000227B-0_1682508000785_1737037309832.jpg" alt="The operation involved personnel from the District Reserve Guard (DRG) of three districts, five battalions of CoBRA (Commando Battalion for Resolute Action, an elite CRPF jungle warfare unit), and the 229th battalion of the CRPF. (File)(PTI)" title="The operation involved personnel from the District Reserve Guard (DRG) of three districts, five battalions of CoBRA (Commando Battalion for Resolute Action, an elite CRPF jungle warfare unit), and the 229th battalion of the CRPF. (File)(PTI)"><figcaption>The operation involved personnel from the District Reserve Guard (DRG) of three districts, five battalions of CoBRA (Commando Battalion for Resolute Action, an elite CRPF jungle warfare unit), and the 229th battalion of the CRPF. (File)(PTI)</figcaption></img><p>As many as 17 Naxalites were killed during an anti-Naxalite operation in Chhattisgarh's Bijapur district.</p><ul><li>The encounter began around 9 am on Thursday in a forested area and continued until late evening.</li><li>This month, the total Naxalites killed in encounters in Chhattisgarh has reached 26.</li><li>No casualties were reported among security forces involved in the operation.</li></ul><blockquote>“As per preliminary information, 12 Naxalites were killed in the gunfight. Further details were awaited as a search operation was still underway.”</blockquote><p>The government has affirmed its commitment to countering Naxalism effectively in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/12-naxalites-killed-in-encounter-in-chhattisgarhs-bijapur-taking-monthly-toll-to-26-101737037238593.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/12-naxalites-killed-in-encounter-in-chhattisgarhs-bijapur-taking-monthly-toll-to-26-101737037238593.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:55:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 16 Pro Max price drops by Rs 7,000 - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iPhone 16 Pro Max Price Drops by Rs 7,000</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>January 2025 <strong>Source: </strong>India Today</p><img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2025/01/cropped-imageITG-1737038452961.png" alt="iPhone 16 Pro Max" /><figcaption>iPhone 16 Pro Max</figcaption><p>The iPhone 16 Pro Max is now available at a reduced price on multiple platforms, offering significant savings for potential buyers.</p><ul><li>The new price is Rs 1,37,900, down from the launch price of Rs 1,44,900.</li><li>Discounts of Rs 7,000 are now being applied across platforms like Amazon, Vijay Sales, and Flipkart.</li><li>Bank card offers may provide additional reductions in price.</li><li>The price mentioned is for the 256GB model.</li><li>The iPhone 16 Pro Max features a 6.9-inch display and is powered by the A18 Pro chip.</li><li>Enhanced camera features include a 48MP fusion camera and improved battery life.</li></ul><blockquote>"Expect a powerful performance compared to popular Android flagship phones."</blockquote><p>This is a great deal for anyone looking to purchase the iPhone 16 Pro Max at a lower price, with a combination of discounts and features that enhance its value.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/iphone-16-pro-max-price-drops-203014-16-01-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/iphone-16-pro-max-price-drops-203014-16-01-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:41:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Is Official: New Game Console Launches This Year - Hollywood Reporter]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/digital/nintendo-switch-2-console-coming-2025-1236110419/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/digital/nintendo-switch-2-console-coming-2025-1236110419/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:41:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech wrap Jan 16: Realme 14 Pro series, Samsung Galaxy S25, Google Chrome - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-wrap-jan-16-realme-14-pro-series-samsung-galaxy-s25-google-chrome-125011601022_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-wrap-jan-16-realme-14-pro-series-samsung-galaxy-s25-google-chrome-125011601022_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[32-inch smart TVs available at massive discount during Republic Day sale, starting from just Rs 7,000 - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Massive Discounts on 32-Inch Smart TVs During Republic Day Sale</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/smart-tvs-at-discount-1737037823.webp" alt="Smart TVs at discount" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>Smart TVs at discount</figcaption>
<p>E-commerce giant Amazon is currently hosting a Republic Day sale, offering substantial discounts on 32-inch smart TVs, with prices starting at just Rs 7,000.</p>
<ul>
<li>Discounts of up to 61% on various brands including Samsung, TCL, Sony, Xiaomi, and Acer.</li>
<li>The Xiaomi Smart TV A is now available for Rs 11,999, down from Rs 24,999.</li>
<li>The VW 32-inch Playwall is priced around Rs 6,000 to Rs 7,000 after a 59% discount.</li>
<li>TCL's 32-inch model is now priced at Rs 10,990 after a 50% discount.</li>
<li>The VW 32 inch Pro Series is available for Rs 8,999 after a 61% discount.</li>
<li>Acer’s QLED smart TV is priced at Rs 12,499 during the sale.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Now is the perfect time to take advantage of these deals” - Amazon spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>This sale provides excellent purchasing opportunities for those looking to upgrade their home entertainment experience without breaking the bank.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/32-inch-smart-tvs-available-at-massive-discount-during-republic-day-sale-starting-from-just-rs-7-000-2025-01-16-971633</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/32-inch-smart-tvs-available-at-massive-discount-during-republic-day-sale-starting-from-just-rs-7-000-2025-01-16-971633</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:31:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Maoists gunned down by security forces in Chhattisgarh’s Bijapur district - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maoist Encounter in Chhattisgarh: 12 Killed in Major Operation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/c88mym/article69105241.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI01_06_2025_000276B.jpg" alt="A file image of security forces in Chhattisgarh‘s Bijapur district" title="A file image of security forces in Chhattisgarh‘s Bijapur district"><figcaption>A file image of security forces in Chhattisgarh‘s Bijapur district | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>In a significant anti-Naxal operation, security forces killed at least twelve Maoists in Chhattisgarh's Bijapur district. This action follows an IED blast that resulted in the loss of eight security personnel's lives.</p><ul><li>The operation took place in the South Bastar region, which encompasses Bijapur, Dantewada, and Sukma districts.</li><li>The encounter started after a tip-off about the Maoist presence in a forested area.</li><li>A joint team from multiple security contingents engaged in intermittent gunfire with the Maoists throughout the day.</li><li>No casualties were reported on the side of the security forces.</li><li>This encounter marks a rise in anti-Naxal operations in 2024, with a total of 26 Maoists reported killed in encounters this year.</li></ul><blockquote>“There has been an upsurge in anti-Naxal operations since the end of 2023.”</blockquote><p>The operation underscores the ongoing challenges faced by security forces in combating Maoist insurgency in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/chhattisgarh/maoists-gunned-down-by-security-forces-in-chhattisgarhs-bijapur-district/article69105190.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/chhattisgarh/maoists-gunned-down-by-security-forces-in-chhattisgarhs-bijapur-district/article69105190.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan's attacker entered Jeh's room and demanded ₹1 crore? Police clarifies - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/saif-ali-khans-attacker-entered-jehs-room-and-demanded-1-crore-police-clarifies-101737036219181.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/saif-ali-khans-attacker-entered-jehs-room-and-demanded-1-crore-police-clarifies-101737036219181.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:20:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Attacker Entered Room Of Saif's Son Jeh, Demanded Rs 1 Crore: Sources - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/saif-ali-khans-attacker-demanded-rs-1-crore-at-his-house-7488346</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/saif-ali-khans-attacker-demanded-rs-1-crore-at-his-house-7488346</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:19:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams steps out on spacewalk after seven months in orbit - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunita Williams steps out on spacewalk after seven months in orbit</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/latest-news/lmquj0/article69105271.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/SunitaSpacewalk.jpg" alt="Sunita Williams during her spacewalk" />
<figcaption>It was the first spacewalk by NASA astronauts since an aborted one in 2024. Photo: X/@NASA</figcaption>
<p>Sunita Williams, the commander of the International Space Station, successfully completed her first spacewalk after more than seven months in orbit, addressing overdue outdoor repairs alongside NASA's Nick Hague.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Williams emerged on her first spacewalk since arriving at the ISS.</li>
  <li>Both astronauts undertook essential repairs as the station orbited 420 km above Turkmenistan.</li>
  <li>This marks Williams' eighth spacewalk throughout her career.</li>
  <li>The spacewalk comes after a previous one was aborted due to safety concerns with the astronaut suits.</li>
  <li>Future plans include another spacewalk with astronaut Butch Wilmore next week.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>LIVE: Two <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA_Astronauts?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NASA_Astronauts</a>, Nick Hague and Suni Williams, step outside of the <a href="https://twitter.com/Space_Station?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Space_Station</a> to support station upgrades, including repairs to our NICER (Neutron star Interior Composition Explorer) X-ray telescope. — NASA (@NASA) January 16, 2025</blockquote>
<p>This event marks a significant moment in NASA's spacewalk history and highlights the ongoing work of astronauts aboard the ISS.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/nasas-stuck-astronaut-sunita-williams-steps-out-on-spacewalk-after-seven-months-in-orbit/article69105113.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/nasas-stuck-astronaut-sunita-williams-steps-out-on-spacewalk-after-seven-months-in-orbit/article69105113.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Industries Q3 Results: PAT rises 7% YoY to Rs 18,540 crore, revenue up 7% - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6wFBVV95cUxNdER5dTdUZjU2WGVzTWlPcHZIZDZGeFVBM0V2ZWdYbi11dFhtZW04MFdMTVBUZkgyS05vOWFPLWMzMlNDTVdiMlN1amZFaEhBU0JZTExIRWZORlVlLVZIZW9QQ2Y1czRIa0NQb2ZlaEFmZlQ4WW01SmxydFp4dG81U0VMX3Jwa1pTZlh6N3FNbm5xa050MnJpZG53R1FGV045cmlHMEUydFRpQm1LZVZHSXprc09mR0RzWmVFNEZ0YVpHZWJWLTZWNDlXWHpPYVJ6ZE5NSzJYMzJkWFdiSDZQYS1fWi15NlFRelo00gHwAUFVX3lxTE9DM284all5V196ZXZSSDJpWHJOcDFpTlBvVzlxTFdSU1VZZUM4SlQzaUF2R3dMaExRdDhKN3J1SUJWQnBsYVlvQndQZks1NmFnblY0UXlGMHQ3U2xrM25ialJkVDQ1NDQtT05PMzBNYmpLNWZCQXlMZE9hczlhT3p6WDJkMWtzUDZFRzRoYWFWdGNjWXljdXpWX1hVVVpNUzRURk9QMGZxdTFnTmctb2hzS3RFM0dLOGVTeGdhMTVRWDdORk1tT0hVc3pFdm5HZW5xbk9TSmtMVlYxWW1qS3FvWWhjTzlvMFdMNGZ3WWNIVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6wFBVV95cUxNdER5dTdUZjU2WGVzTWlPcHZIZDZGeFVBM0V2ZWdYbi11dFhtZW04MFdMTVBUZkgyS05vOWFPLWMzMlNDTVdiMlN1amZFaEhBU0JZTExIRWZORlVlLVZIZW9QQ2Y1czRIa0NQb2ZlaEFmZlQ4WW01SmxydFp4dG81U0VMX3Jwa1pTZlh6N3FNbm5xa050MnJpZG53R1FGV045cmlHMEUydFRpQm1LZVZHSXprc09mR0RzWmVFNEZ0YVpHZWJWLTZWNDlXWHpPYVJ6ZE5NSzJYMzJkWFdiSDZQYS1fWi15NlFRelo00gHwAUFVX3lxTE9DM284all5V196ZXZSSDJpWHJOcDFpTlBvVzlxTFdSU1VZZUM4SlQzaUF2R3dMaExRdDhKN3J1SUJWQnBsYVlvQndQZks1NmFnblY0UXlGMHQ3U2xrM25ialJkVDQ1NDQtT05PMzBNYmpLNWZCQXlMZE9hczlhT3p6WDJkMWtzUDZFRzRoYWFWdGNjWXljdXpWX1hVVVpNUzRURk9QMGZxdTFnTmctb2hzS3RFM0dLOGVTeGdhMTVRWDdORk1tT0hVc3pFdm5HZW5xbk9TSmtMVlYxWW1qS3FvWWhjTzlvMFdMNGZ3WWNIVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:02:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Sale 2025: Price drop deals on front load washing machines; Save up to 42% on LG, Samsung, Bosch, IFB and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-sale-2025-price-drop-deals-on-front-load-washing-machines-save-up-to-42-on-lg-samsung-bosch-ifb-and-more-101736927023111.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-sale-2025-price-drop-deals-on-front-load-washing-machines-save-up-to-42-on-lg-samsung-bosch-ifb-and-more-101736927023111.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:00:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Sale 2025: Price drop deals on front load washing machines; Save up to 42% on LG, Samsung, Bosch, IFB and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-sale-2025-price-drop-deals-on-front-load-washing-machines-save-up-to-42-on-lg-samsung-bosch-ifb-and-more-101736927023111.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-sale-2025-price-drop-deals-on-front-load-washing-machines-save-up-to-42-on-lg-samsung-bosch-ifb-and-more-101736927023111.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:00:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 console revealed in first trailer: Here's all you need to know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxQX3dIdHhoY2xMdVV5UG1abmc0blpsOTBxUjVGb3pZR0d1bkoxNUl6WkNrUkp1a2hsNVFhYUxEZXRRRjJqUGZpaDhIVm85cXctbmpPRXNXaUFLem1wSld0ZnJ3bzBLcnBmQmxXUEFTcWJ1RUhaV0hvWWxaUW9mWGxKNlJjbXpSV3FBc3F0X0d0bXV0Nk5yYUZhSG5UUWNGNkJpRXo2QTdFc2lORWZpRjk0NWNLWDZvMkFxRWRQT21kSFBLOFZ4Y2NXQVphV3pHek9UdGhWajQtNjA4S3AwMUFNYVRvNEhvSWptLXJ0dFdWQdIB9AFBVV95cUxQd0lqUGRwR1lrN2tSSk1kTDh5RXczZjhCeVktVmxJUEJ1UVhueE9sMy1ORGt3aVRjTGxNUVVhNTJXb2M1cE9rWXByd2libU9GX0lYc2tRRVhkWGVwMEM2QjJSMnJWRGxSWVlBQ251cUVQalJmNkFpSjJobzROaUd5eDNUVVBqLWZJMzJ3MWlQUlZDMXJDaHcyUU1KczZueFA0Q3VTaUFSaDdPcHNDbXNRQ1hkaW13X2w1M1ZLVEk4eHo3bTVNRHBabzVQYUxMRjUzdTE0R3hURTJzOUFOYWowd0NOLVRZR0k3NWI0Z0xoXy1NNUFO?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxQX3dIdHhoY2xMdVV5UG1abmc0blpsOTBxUjVGb3pZR0d1bkoxNUl6WkNrUkp1a2hsNVFhYUxEZXRRRjJqUGZpaDhIVm85cXctbmpPRXNXaUFLem1wSld0ZnJ3bzBLcnBmQmxXUEFTcWJ1RUhaV0hvWWxaUW9mWGxKNlJjbXpSV3FBc3F0X0d0bXV0Nk5yYUZhSG5UUWNGNkJpRXo2QTdFc2lORWZpRjk0NWNLWDZvMkFxRWRQT21kSFBLOFZ4Y2NXQVphV3pHek9UdGhWajQtNjA4S3AwMUFNYVRvNEhvSWptLXJ0dFdWQdIB9AFBVV95cUxQd0lqUGRwR1lrN2tSSk1kTDh5RXczZjhCeVktVmxJUEJ1UVhueE9sMy1ORGt3aVRjTGxNUVVhNTJXb2M1cE9rWXByd2libU9GX0lYc2tRRVhkWGVwMEM2QjJSMnJWRGxSWVlBQ251cUVQalJmNkFpSjJobzROaUd5eDNUVVBqLWZJMzJ3MWlQUlZDMXJDaHcyUU1KczZueFA0Q3VTaUFSaDdPcHNDbXNRQ1hkaW13X2w1M1ZLVEk4eHo3bTVNRHBabzVQYUxMRjUzdTE0R3hURTJzOUFOYWowd0NOLVRZR0k3NWI0Z0xoXy1NNUFO?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo unveils Switch 2, its new hybrid console - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/gaming/nintendo-unveils-switch-2-its-new-hybrid-console-9782610/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/gaming/nintendo-unveils-switch-2-its-new-hybrid-console-9782610/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's stuck astronaut steps out on a spacewalk after 7 months in orbit - The Albertan]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Astronaut Completes Spacewalk After 7 Months in Orbit</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> March 9, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Associated Press</p>
<img src="https://apnews.com/article/boeing-starliner-astronauts-nasa-space-566cc98e9b77df9c12c4206445c7c112" alt="Astronaut Suni Williams" />
<figcaption>In this photo provided by NASA, astronaut Suni Williams tries on and evaluates her spacesuit aboard the International Space Station on Jan. 9, 2025. (NASA via AP)</figcaption>
<p>One of NASA’s astronauts, Suni Williams, stepped out on her first spacewalk after spending over seven months in orbit at the International Space Station (ISS).</p>
<ul>
  <li>Williams and NASA’s Nick Hague performed overdue repair work during the spacewalk.</li>
  <li>The astronauts had been stuck when their planned return was delayed due to issues with Boeing's Starliner capsule.</li>
  <li>Spacewalks were previously halted due to a malfunction involving water leaking into the airlock.</li>
  <li>This marked Williams' eighth spacewalk and her first since the alleged incident.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It was the first spacewalk by NASA astronauts since an aborted one last summer,” said Marcia Dunn, the Associated Press.</blockquote>
<p>This event highlights the ongoing challenges faced by NASA's crew during missions, especially with equipment reliability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thealbertan.com/world-news/nasas-stuck-astronaut-steps-out-on-a-spacewalk-after-7-months-in-orbit-10084096</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thealbertan.com/world-news/nasas-stuck-astronaut-steps-out-on-a-spacewalk-after-7-months-in-orbit-10084096</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:18:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan's staff shares details of the chilling attack: 'Intruder entered younger son Jeh's room,... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saif Ali Khan's staff shares details of the chilling attack: 'Intruder entered younger son Jeh's room, demanded Rs 1 cr'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250116130751_saif-ali-khan-family.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Saif Ali Khan's staff shares details of the chilling attack: 'Intruder entered younger son Jeh's room, demanded Rs 1 cr'" title="Saif Ali Khan's staff shares details of the chilling attack: 'Intruder entered younger son Jeh's room, demanded Rs 1 cr'" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>An incident at Saif Ali Khan's residence.</figcaption><p>A staff member at Saif Ali Khan's residence provided a detailed statement to the Bandra Police about a terrifying robbery attempt, describing how an intruder demanded Rs 1 crore before attacking her and the actor.</p><ul><li>An armed intruder entered the residence early morning.</li><li>Demand for Rs 1 crore led to an aggressive confrontation.</li><li>Several individuals, including the actor, were injured during the incident.</li><li>The police are actively investigating the robbery attempt.</li></ul><blockquote>"The nurse described the frightening ordeal in which the robber's actions escalated quickly..."</blockquote><p>The disturbing nature of the incident has left both the staff and Saif Ali Khan shaken, prompting a thorough investigation by law enforcement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/saif-ali-khan-s-staff-shares-details-of-the-chilling-attack-intruder-entered-younger-son-jeh-s-room-demanded-rs-1-cr-article-12912538.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/entertainment/saif-ali-khan-s-staff-shares-details-of-the-chilling-attack-intruder-entered-younger-son-jeh-s-room-demanded-rs-1-cr-article-12912538.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:08:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Republic Day offer: iPhone 14 on EMI with affordable down payment on Flipkart - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iPhone 14 Available on Easy EMI During Flipkart Republic Day Sale</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>The Flipkart Republic Day Sale offers an opportunity to purchase the iPhone 14 with minimal down payments and affordable EMI options through the Bajaj Finserv Insta EMI Card.</p><figure><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='iPhone 14' /><figcaption>iPhone 14 available at promotional prices.</figcaption></figure><p>This year’s Republic Day Sale is set to transform consumers' shopping experiences, making premium products more accessible.</p><ul><li>Exclusive offers on the iPhone 14 series during Flipkart's biggest sale of the year.</li><li>The Bajaj Finserv Insta EMI Card allows for high-value purchases with low monthly instalments.</li><li>Pre-qualified loan amounts of up to Rs. 3 lakh enable consumers to buy additional products without financial burden.</li><li>Flexible repayment options from 1 to 60 months cater to different financial situations.</li><li>Zero foreclosure charges offer complete financial freedom for early payoffs.</li></ul><blockquote>“Make this Republic Day memorable with your new iPhone 14.”</blockquote><p>Take advantage of special benefits and ensure a seamless shopping experience during the Flipkart Republic Day Sale.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/focus/republic-day-offer-iphone-14-on-emi-with-affordable-down-payment-on-flipkart-11736932062005.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/focus/republic-day-offer-iphone-14-on-emi-with-affordable-down-payment-on-flipkart-11736932062005.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:59:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1896 born Swami Sivananda has attended every Kumbh Mela in 100 years - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Swami Sivananda Celebrates 100 Years of Attending Kumbh Mela</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> 16 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p>
<p>Padma Shri recipient Swami Sivananda has attended every Kumbh Mela in major Indian cities for the past century, showcasing profound spiritual commitment and dedication.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Born on August 8, 1896, in a humble family.</li>
  <li>Has attended Kumbh Mela across Prayagraj, Nashik, Ujjain, and Haridwar.</li>
  <li>Emphasizes early rising and yoga for maintaining good health.</li>
  <li>A diet of boiled food without oil or salt, avoids dairy products.</li>
  <li>Refuses donations and has maintained a simple lifestyle.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Start your day early and dedicate at least half-an-hour to yoga,” emphasizes Swami Sivananda.</blockquote>
<p>His life and teachings reflect a blend of simplicity, discipline, and spirituality, urging modern society to embrace healthy living.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/uttar-pradesh/1896-born-swami-sivananda-has-attended-every-kumbh-mela-in-100-years-3358413</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/uttar-pradesh/1896-born-swami-sivananda-has-attended-every-kumbh-mela-in-100-years-3358413</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:42:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pope Francis falls at Santa Marta house, hurts his arm - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pope Francis Falls and Injures His Arm at Santa Marta</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 12, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Vatican News</p>
<p>Pope Francis suffered a fall at his residence, the Casa Santa Marta, resulting in minor injuries to his arm. This incident raises concerns about the Pope's health as he continues to lead the Catholic Church.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The fall occurred while the Pope was in the Casa Santa Marta.</li>
  <li>Initial reports indicate that he sustained a minor injury to his arm.</li>
  <li>The Vatican assured the public that the Pope is recovering well.</li>
  <li>Concerns about the Pope's mobility have increased, given his age and previous health issues.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Pope Francis is a resilient leader, and we are hopeful for his swift recovery and continued guidance to the Church." - Vatican Official</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while the Pope's fall is concerning, it is a reminder of his dedication and resilience in his role despite the challenges of age.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/pope-francis-falls-at-santa-marta-house-hurts-his-arm/articleshow/117302012.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/pope-francis-falls-at-santa-marta-house-hurts-his-arm/articleshow/117302012.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress Moves Supreme Court In Support Of Places Of Worship Act - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/congress-moves-supreme-court-in-support-of-places-of-worship-act-9191103.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/congress-moves-supreme-court-in-support-of-places-of-worship-act-9191103.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:29:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Places of Worship Act: 139-year-old Congress moves Supreme Court to defend the Act of 1991 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Places of Worship Act: 139-year-old Congress moves Supreme Court to defend the Act of 1991</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/todays-paper/psanmo/article67156165.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/TH03-KDR-GyanvaGOHBIOJEP.4.jpg.jpg" alt="The Gyanvapi mosque. " /><figcaption>The Gyanvapi mosque. | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The Indian National Congress (INC) has filed an application in the Supreme Court to defend the Places of Worship Act of 1991, emphasizing its role in safeguarding secularism in India.</p><ul><li>The Act preserves the character of religious places as they existed on August 15, 1947.</li><li>INC asserts that any challenge to the Act threatens communal harmony and India's secular fabric.</li><li>The party claims to be the architect of the Act, having passed it during the 10th Lok Sabha.</li><li>The Supreme Court recently barred civil courts from hearing new suits about reclaiming places of worship.</li><li>The INC highlights the importance of the Act in protecting the right to freedom of religion.</li></ul><blockquote>“The POWA is essential to safeguard secularism in India and the present challenge appears to be a motivated and malicious attempt to undermine established principles of secularism.” - Indian National Congress</blockquote><p>The INC aims to emphasize the constitutional importance of the POWA to the apex court, calling it a fundamental protection for India's secular country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/139-year-old-inc-moves-supreme-court-to-defend-places-of-worship-act/article69104486.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/139-year-old-inc-moves-supreme-court-to-defend-places-of-worship-act/article69104486.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sebi halts trading in this SME stock after PE touches unheard levels of 4,00,000 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxPYnF1a3NTV0h0bE1CU2h6OHFPN0twMlMzUGluRXFBb1kxRFB5Z0o5YWs1UzBRTVRNWGs5SFo2X29ZY3RjUW1xN0llZlUtdEFoZXhsNUE2SUE1VFJIT1JlRmQzUzJwQ014M1NXMzh5aThCbmNWZ3V0OC14ZEZhaFBFMHVFeG5mSmgtbzRPREFlTnhybUFsaVVOcVh3b0N4ZTdRRVZWOUtPTzNzZFFQRkRMelg5dnNnNjJrM3Q5YlJIS0xLb0lEbXM4V1FjaDllWld3UTgtSjdkamY2Y1Y3OXgyLVBJbGgwcGfSAewBQVVfeXFMUDBxUHdXZDY4dGxTTU9ZaEpQZnJLekRHdVpDNnVDYXd3WkYxYi05QUFzLUJQTG9Yc3ZOdjRtTThLRE1lcDZTZVRmTXMzOTVNTklLTjgySjY1RkdGeUpibFNnaExwQnFMZzlKZWRZTDYwVDRtVTZfMnA4aS05dllYRXkyeTlRUGE1S3c1c1N6T2dZNk1QZk5USktIMnhPR29Nc29Wa1FUSUxPcDdMdllBMGdvRjI0ak9TSDNwcVRCdzd6R2Jncl9vSXpjc19jLWtubG51YnJuRmtIbVhoek14N2hWVjM4Wnc4SUFid1M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxPYnF1a3NTV0h0bE1CU2h6OHFPN0twMlMzUGluRXFBb1kxRFB5Z0o5YWs1UzBRTVRNWGs5SFo2X29ZY3RjUW1xN0llZlUtdEFoZXhsNUE2SUE1VFJIT1JlRmQzUzJwQ014M1NXMzh5aThCbmNWZ3V0OC14ZEZhaFBFMHVFeG5mSmgtbzRPREFlTnhybUFsaVVOcVh3b0N4ZTdRRVZWOUtPTzNzZFFQRkRMelg5dnNnNjJrM3Q5YlJIS0xLb0lEbXM4V1FjaDllWld3UTgtSjdkamY2Y1Y3OXgyLVBJbGgwcGfSAewBQVVfeXFMUDBxUHdXZDY4dGxTTU9ZaEpQZnJLekRHdVpDNnVDYXd3WkYxYi05QUFzLUJQTG9Yc3ZOdjRtTThLRE1lcDZTZVRmTXMzOTVNTklLTjgySjY1RkdGeUpibFNnaExwQnFMZzlKZWRZTDYwVDRtVTZfMnA4aS05dllYRXkyeTlRUGE1S3c1c1N6T2dZNk1QZk5USktIMnhPR29Nc29Wa1FUSUxPcDdMdllBMGdvRjI0ak9TSDNwcVRCdzd6R2Jncl9vSXpjc19jLWtubG51YnJuRmtIbVhoek14N2hWVjM4Wnc4SUFid1M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:13:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Air pollution exposure in pre-pregnancy months linked to higher obesity risk in kids: Study - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Study Links Pre-Pregnancy Air Pollution to Higher Obesity Risk in Children</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> January 16, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/pregnancy_air_pollution_1737029283902_1737029287612.jpg" alt="Researchers recruited mother-child pairs from Shanghai to understand how exposure to PM2.5, PM10 and nitrous oxide pollution during preconception impacted children's growth in the first two years of life. (Shutterstock)" title="Researchers recruited mother-child pairs from Shanghai to understand how exposure to PM2.5, PM10 and nitrous oxide pollution during preconception impacted children's growth in the first two years of life. (Shutterstock)"><figcaption>Researchers recruited mother-child pairs from Shanghai to understand how exposure to PM2.5, PM10 and nitrous oxide pollution during preconception impacted children's growth in the first two years of life. (Shutterstock)</figcaption></figure><p>A recent study involving over 5,800 mother-child pairs from China found a link between pre-pregnancy air pollution exposure and increased risks of obesity in children up to age 2.</p><ul><li>Increased air pollution exposure prior to pregnancy correlated with higher body mass index (BMI) and obesity risk factors in children.</li><li>The study found a significant increase in BMI associated with rising levels of PM2.5 and PM10 pollutants.</li><li>Environmental exposures pre-pregnancy can have lasting health effects on children, including obesity.</li><li>Recommendations for expecting parents include measures to reduce air pollution exposure.</li></ul><blockquote>"The magnitude is small, but because air pollution is widespread... the risk of exposure on children's obesity may be substantial." - Zhanghua Chen</blockquote><p>The findings suggest the importance of air quality during the months leading up to conception, advocating for higher awareness and proactive steps to mitigate exposure for future parents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/air-pollution-exposure-in-pre-pregnancy-months-linked-to-higher-obesity-risk-in-kids-affecting-growth-rate-study-101737028500681.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/air-pollution-exposure-in-pre-pregnancy-months-linked-to-higher-obesity-risk-in-kids-affecting-growth-rate-study-101737028500681.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:11:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>