<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:13:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:13:17 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Israel deploys US THAAD system for first time - what is it - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Deploys US THAAD System for First Time</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of Israel</p><p>This article discusses Israel's recent deployment of the US THAAD (Terminal High Altitude Area Defense) system, marking its first operational use. The THAAD system is designed to protect against short, medium, and intermediate-range ballistic missiles.</p><ul><li>The THAAD system was deployed amidst growing regional tensions.</li><li>This marks a significant step in Israel's missile defense strategy.</li><li>The system's effectiveness in real-world scenarios is yet to be fully evaluated.</li></ul><blockquote>“The deployment of THAAD is a crucial enhancement to our defense capabilities,” said an Israeli military official.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the THAAD deployment symbolizes a deepening military cooperation between the US and Israel and reflects the ongoing threats in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/watch-israel-deploys-us-thaad-system-for-first-time-what-is-it/articleshow/116739376.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/watch-israel-deploys-us-thaad-system-for-first-time-what-is-it/articleshow/116739376.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New planet in our solar system? Scientists find hidden body 5-7 times size of Earth that orbits Sun in 20,000 years | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxOS3lVLXBmQUZVSWRsbExkaFZESExsaVRMRjJieHpiYmFXYkgyYnp3YkV6SHBXdDlWZl9DWWV5YlVldTZxcXY5MGVWMHpzMUhiQ3BSMFNMOWU5MlpONHpkakV2R1g3VmM4NTJ2Q2N3T3Y1cTN2em1nRkFzRWRXOW5TaXVvaDRMU2NQX3J2UGZmek93emJKeS0ycThvQ3g5bjJWSVhUS0ZrVFFjbEhoV09PLTJwZk55eWtUbTNlZnJUSW5MQnZrdUVMUmtEcVdJbzZ1WTNEdlc0blFCak5ySkVvWXRBTXZWeVh5eVR0MFJlSWlENHQwSTF1bkpoTXFwMFlJOVHSAYcCQVVfeXFMUG9zaHhaNDZhdm0tMkFXUEZvRHZwTWNXSXBWRWsxTUxreDhpMFhuRFMtZGtSd0wwenM0dUdjSEdwQWJlYlZlT09ROVFUd3lqLU53MXZLMkxMb1JlMlVBQWdlYTZSRU8wNFBpcWJ1Y3VyZkZNSWh3SEFXc0ZuN2hhRHVyeWpjay11a0Q2dmstbHE1ZFFmX0hUM1RIQUZGUGo3eU9VSl9sMmRURG81UjFnbFIzc2tWR01uOWZ4cTUxLVB0SE9TTzBoQlhtQWxOTHE4TWYzWjMzRnIwbEtlUkpxOWlzYXV5X1Qwc0VBeERhak5Icnl6QWItSE8yZDVwek01Z3I3dXVkVVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxOS3lVLXBmQUZVSWRsbExkaFZESExsaVRMRjJieHpiYmFXYkgyYnp3YkV6SHBXdDlWZl9DWWV5YlVldTZxcXY5MGVWMHpzMUhiQ3BSMFNMOWU5MlpONHpkakV2R1g3VmM4NTJ2Q2N3T3Y1cTN2em1nRkFzRWRXOW5TaXVvaDRMU2NQX3J2UGZmek93emJKeS0ycThvQ3g5bjJWSVhUS0ZrVFFjbEhoV09PLTJwZk55eWtUbTNlZnJUSW5MQnZrdUVMUmtEcVdJbzZ1WTNEdlc0blFCak5ySkVvWXRBTXZWeVh5eVR0MFJlSWlENHQwSTF1bkpoTXFwMFlJOVHSAYcCQVVfeXFMUG9zaHhaNDZhdm0tMkFXUEZvRHZwTWNXSXBWRWsxTUxreDhpMFhuRFMtZGtSd0wwenM0dUdjSEdwQWJlYlZlT09ROVFUd3lqLU53MXZLMkxMb1JlMlVBQWdlYTZSRU8wNFBpcWJ1Y3VyZkZNSWh3SEFXc0ZuN2hhRHVyeWpjay11a0Q2dmstbHE1ZFFmX0hUM1RIQUZGUGo3eU9VSl9sMmRURG81UjFnbFIzc2tWR01uOWZ4cTUxLVB0SE9TTzBoQlhtQWxOTHE4TWYzWjMzRnIwbEtlUkpxOWlzYXV5X1Qwc0VBeERhak5Icnl6QWItSE8yZDVwek01Z3I3dXVkVVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:48:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus Open 2 alleged leaks suggest upgraded design, IPX8 rating, and Snapdragon 8 Elite SoC | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus Open 2 alleged leaks suggest upgraded design, IPX8 rating, and Snapdragon 8 Elite SoC</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified; <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Tech giant OnePlus is reportedly gearing up to launch the OnePlus Open 2, a successor to its 2023 foldable model, scheduled for early next year. Leaks suggest significant upgrades in design and specifications.</p><ul><li>Refined design featuring a larger circular camera module with a rearranged triple-camera setup.</li><li>IPX8 water resistance rating, an improvement over the IPX4 rating of its predecessor.</li><li>Powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset, with options for up to 16GB RAM and 1TB storage.</li><li>Display specs include an 8-inch LTPO main screen with 2K resolution and 120Hz refresh rate.</li><li>Expected camera capabilities: triple 50MP rear sensors and dual selfie cameras (32MP and 20MP).</li><li>5,900mAh battery with 80W wired fast charging support.</li></ul><p>As OnePlus prepares for the global launch of its flagship OnePlus 13 on January 7, 2025, the OnePlus 12 has also seen a price reduction, making it an attractive option for buyers seeking a premium smartphone at a lower cost.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/oneplus-open-2-alleged-leaks-suggest-upgraded-design-ipx8-rating-and-snapdragon-8-elite-soc-11735377805122.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/oneplus-open-2-alleged-leaks-suggest-upgraded-design-ipx8-rating-and-snapdragon-8-elite-soc-11735377805122.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:47:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal accuses BJP of blocking welfare schemes in Delhi, vows to implement Mahila Samman and San - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Accuses BJP of Hindering Welfare Initiatives in Delhi</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal has accused the BJP government of obstructing key welfare schemes aimed at empowering women and providing healthcare in the nation’s capital.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kejriwal criticized the BJP for stalling the implementation of the Mahila Samman Yojana and Sanjeevani Yojana.</li>
    <li>He vowed to push forward with these initiatives regardless of the political obstacles.</li>
    <li>The Chief Minister emphasized the importance of these schemes in improving the lives of women and providing essential health services.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We will not let the BJP hinder our welfare schemes. The people of Delhi deserve these benefits.”</blockquote>
<p>In summary, Kejriwal's firm stance against the BJP highlights the ongoing political tensions while reaffirming his commitment to welfare in Delhi.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/kejriwal-accuses-bjp-of-blocking-welfare-schemes-in-delhi-vows-to-implement-mahila-samman-and-sanjeevani-yojana-despite-opposition-/articleshow/116737803.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/kejriwal-accuses-bjp-of-blocking-welfare-schemes-in-delhi-vows-to-implement-mahila-samman-and-sanjeevani-yojana-despite-opposition-/articleshow/116737803.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal Slams BJP Over Blockage of Welfare Schemes in Delhi - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Accuses BJP of Blocking Welfare Schemes in Delhi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a recent address, Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal accused the BJP of obstructing welfare schemes in the capital while pledging to implement welfare initiatives such as the Mahila Samman and Sanjeevani Yojana.</p><ul><li>Kejriwal states the BJP's actions hinder welfare programs aimed at the marginalized.</li><li>He emphasized the importance of women's empowerment through the Mahila Samman initiative.</li><li>The Sanjeevani Yojana aims to enhance healthcare services in Delhi.</li><li>Kejriwal's statements reflect ongoing political tensions between his party and the BJP.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are committed to ensuring that these welfare schemes reach the people who need them the most.” - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote><p>This statement highlights Kejriwal's commitment to social welfare amidst political challenges, emphasizing the government's focus on uplifting women and improving healthcare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/kejriwal-accuses-bjp-of-blocking-welfare-schemes-in-delhi-vows-to-implement-mahila-samman-and-sanjeevani-yojana-despite-opposition-/articleshow/116737803.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/kejriwal-accuses-bjp-of-blocking-welfare-schemes-in-delhi-vows-to-implement-mahila-samman-and-sanjeevani-yojana-despite-opposition-/articleshow/116737803.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study shows shocking link between hair products and cancer; here are the details - The Week]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Study shows shocking link between hair products and cancer; here are the details</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> European Journal of Obstetrics and Gynaecology and Reproductive Biology</p><p>This article discusses a recent study highlighting the risks associated with chemicals in hair dyes and chemical straighteners, including potential links to breast and ovarian cancer.</p><ul><li>A study published in 2024 indicates that hair products often contain harmful chemicals.</li><li>These chemicals can disrupt hormones and are associated with cancer risks.</li><li>Common harmful chemicals include aromatic amines, parabens, and formaldehyde.</li><li>Women are at greater risk due to higher usage of these products.</li><li>Recommendations include minimizing the use of such products and opting for safer alternatives.</li></ul><blockquote>“Hair products often contain chemicals…giving rise to concerns about the possible adverse effects such as hormonal disturbances and carcinogenicity.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, increased awareness and caution are essential for consumers regarding the use of chemical-laden hair products.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theweek.in/news/health/2024/12/28/study-shows-shocking-link-between-hair-products-and-cancer-details-research.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theweek.in/news/health/2024/12/28/study-shows-shocking-link-between-hair-products-and-cancer-details-research.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:04:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inside Salman Khan's Jamnagar birthday bash with family, friends, fireworks, and Anant Ambani - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Inside Salman Khan's Jamnagar Birthday Bash with Family and Friends</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/Salman_Khan_birthday_1735376259566_1735376272802.png" alt="Salman Khan travelled to Jamnagar to celebrate his birthday." title="Salman Khan travelled to Jamnagar to celebrate his birthday."><figcaption>Salman Khan travelled to Jamnagar to celebrate his birthday.</figcaption><p>Actor Salman Khan celebrated his 59th birthday in Jamnagar, Gujarat, surrounded by family and friends. The event featured fireworks and was hosted by the Ambanis, with several moments shared on social media.</p><ul><li>Salman celebrated with family and close friends.</li><li>Videos and pictures from the birthday bash were widely shared.</li><li>Deanne Panday shared multiple photos showcasing the birthday festivities.</li><li>A neon sign and portrayal of love for Salman were prominent features.</li><li>Friends from the film industry including Varun Dhawan and Ajay Devgn sent their wishes.</li><li>Salman's notable past films include 'Hum Aapke Hain Koun' and 'Dabangg'.</li><li>He is set to star in 'Sikandar', releasing during Eid 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“Happy Birthday @beingsalmankhan” - Deanne Panday</blockquote><p>Overall, the birthday bash was a heartfelt celebration of Salman Khan’s life, showcasing love and camaraderie among family and friends.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/inside-salman-khan-jamnagar-birthday-bash-with-family-friends-fireworks-anant-ambani-sohail-khan-101735372627596.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/inside-salman-khan-jamnagar-birthday-bash-with-family-friends-fireworks-anant-ambani-sohail-khan-101735372627596.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:59:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Attention women! 10 signs you might have low estrogen - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxNN2VHeUlaeTlWU19SSEpOMkZNYmZqRURvM3YzRUZoOEN6MXJjRXRDNHY0VE5zUmNncXdIeGo5VlhQdWxuMkxkOVR5TFJFMTlBWXozeHJ6cWF0b1lPTjItdzZpYUdlU1NtbW9wd0hmVjgxdUw0anhTbldpdFVtaDhiejI4SXF5bTJndkNnRVpkVzctRVIyS0RGbG51RVFWSG50WFVvYTl3M2RjU2tVRGtwSjhINDM4S3VubWg3bktSWXY2T2dzaTExY3VHeDRzMFlhdm9ZWlVFVWszdXhFSnlOSkZqTm1VUdIB5gFBVV95cUxNN2VHeUlaeTlWU19SSEpOMkZNYmZqRURvM3YzRUZoOEN6MXJjRXRDNHY0VE5zUmNncXdIeGo5VlhQdWxuMkxkOVR5TFJFMTlBWXozeHJ6cWF0b1lPTjItdzZpYUdlU1NtbW9wd0hmVjgxdUw0anhTbldpdFVtaDhiejI4SXF5bTJndkNnRVpkVzctRVIyS0RGbG51RVFWSG50WFVvYTl3M2RjU2tVRGtwSjhINDM4S3VubWg3bktSWXY2T2dzaTExY3VHeDRzMFlhdm9ZWlVFVWszdXhFSnlOSkZqTm1VUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxNN2VHeUlaeTlWU19SSEpOMkZNYmZqRURvM3YzRUZoOEN6MXJjRXRDNHY0VE5zUmNncXdIeGo5VlhQdWxuMkxkOVR5TFJFMTlBWXozeHJ6cWF0b1lPTjItdzZpYUdlU1NtbW9wd0hmVjgxdUw0anhTbldpdFVtaDhiejI4SXF5bTJndkNnRVpkVzctRVIyS0RGbG51RVFWSG50WFVvYTl3M2RjU2tVRGtwSjhINDM4S3VubWg3bktSWXY2T2dzaTExY3VHeDRzMFlhdm9ZWlVFVWszdXhFSnlOSkZqTm1VUdIB5gFBVV95cUxNN2VHeUlaeTlWU19SSEpOMkZNYmZqRURvM3YzRUZoOEN6MXJjRXRDNHY0VE5zUmNncXdIeGo5VlhQdWxuMkxkOVR5TFJFMTlBWXozeHJ6cWF0b1lPTjItdzZpYUdlU1NtbW9wd0hmVjgxdUw0anhTbldpdFVtaDhiejI4SXF5bTJndkNnRVpkVzctRVIyS0RGbG51RVFWSG50WFVvYTl3M2RjU2tVRGtwSjhINDM4S3VubWg3bktSWXY2T2dzaTExY3VHeDRzMFlhdm9ZWlVFVWszdXhFSnlOSkZqTm1VUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tipsters Leak OnePlus Open 2 Alleged Renders, Slimmer Design Expected - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tipsters Leak OnePlus Open 2 Alleged Renders, Slimmer Design Expected</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Smartprix</p>
<img src="INSERT_IMAGE_URL_HERE" alt="OnePlus Open 2 Render">
<figcaption>Leaked render of the OnePlus Open 2 showcasing its design.</figcaption>
<p>The upcoming OnePlus Open 2 is set to debut early next year, featuring a slimmer profile and upgraded specifications compared to its predecessor.</p>
<ul>
<li>Expected to use the Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset.</li>
<li>Leaked renders show a larger camera module with a new design layout.</li>
<li>Rumored to have an IPX8 water resistance rating.</li>
<li>Display expected to be 8-inch LTPO with a 2K resolution.</li>
<li>Triple rear camera setup: 50 MP + 50 MP + 50 MP for various photography needs.</li>
<li>Expected to have a battery capacity of 5,900 mAh.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"OnePlus Open 2. Larger yet thinner than the OnePlus Open (sub-10 mm folded). IPX8 rating (vs. IPX4 on the Open)." — Noah Cat</blockquote>
<p>This smartphone is anticipated to compete closely with the upcoming Oppo Find N5, expected to launch shortly after.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/oneplus-open-2-leaks-alleged-renders-design-camera-battery-specifications-1740363</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/oneplus-open-2-leaks-alleged-renders-design-camera-battery-specifications-1740363</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:13:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madras High Court orders SIT probe into Anna University sexual assault, directs ₹25 lakh compensation for victim - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Madras High Court Orders SIT Probe into Anna University Sexual Assault Case</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2024-12-28T07:47:21.547Z" title="2024-12-28 07:47">28 Dec 2024, 7:47 am</time>, <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><div><figure><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justices SM Subramaniam and V Lakshminarayan" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Justices SM Subramaniam and V Lakshminarayan</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Madras High Court has directed a Special Investigation Team (SIT) to investigate the sexual assault of a 19-year-old student from Anna University, amidst concerns of police negligence in handling the case.</p><ul><li>The Court ordered an interim compensation of ₹25 lakh to the victim.</li><li>Police are instructed to provide protection to the victim and her family.</li><li>A SIT will be formed with three Indian Police Service officers due to the ongoing investigation's shortcomings.</li><li>The High Court condemned the victim-blaming language in the First Information Report (FIR).</li><li>The Court highlighted the need to protect women's rights and dignity.</li></ul><blockquote>"The deplorable language of the FIR paves the way for victim blaming. It is shocking."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Court emphasized that the society must work towards protecting women and ensuring that they do not face judgment based on their gender.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/madras-high-court-orders-sit-probe-into-anna-university-sexual-assault-case</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/madras-high-court-orders-sit-probe-into-anna-university-sexual-assault-case</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:47:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Angry fans slam paparazzi for revealing Varun Dhawan and Natasha Dalal's daughter Lara's face without their consent - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Angry Fans Slam Paparazzi for Revealing Varun Dhawan and Natasha Dalal's Daughter Lara's Face Without Consent</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/varun_1735371930053_1735371930419.jpg" alt="Varun Dhawan and Natasha Dalal became parents to daughter Lara in June this year." title="Varun Dhawan and Natasha Dalal became parents to daughter Lara in June this year."><figcaption>Varun Dhawan and Natasha Dalal became parents to daughter Lara in June this year.</figcaption><p>Varun Dhawan and wife Natasha Dalal were recently spotted with their daughter Lara at the Mumbai airport, where the paparazzi captured her face without parental consent, sparking outrage among fans.</p><ul><li>Fans criticized the paparazzi for invading privacy.</li><li>Varun has not publicly revealed his daughter’s face before this incident.</li><li>Comments on social media convey strong disapproval of the paparazzi's actions.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is such a gross invasion of a child’s privacy. Disgusting behaviour!!”</blockquote><p>This incident raises important questions about privacy boundaries for public figures and their families.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/angry-fans-slam-paparazzi-for-revealing-varun-dhawan-and-natasha-dalals-daughter-laras-face-without-their-consent-101735369884244.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/angry-fans-slam-paparazzi-for-revealing-varun-dhawan-and-natasha-dalals-daughter-laras-face-without-their-consent-101735369884244.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:47:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How space junk endangers Earth's orbit: All you need to know about 'Kessler Syndrome' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How Space Junk Endangers Earth's Orbit: Understanding Kessler Syndrome</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116735788,imgsize-1591013,width-400,resizemode-4/116735788.jpg" alt="How space junk endangers Earth's orbit: All you need to know about 'Kessler Syndrome'" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>This is an AI-generated image, used for representational purposes only. (Picture credit: DALL-E)</figcaption><p>Space debris is increasingly problematic as Earth's orbit becomes congested, potentially leading to Kessler Syndrome, a catastrophic cascade of collisions in space.</p><ul><li>Kessler Syndrome refers to the chain reaction of collisions in space that creates more debris.</li><li>Since the 1950s, over 50,000 tons of material have been launched into orbit, with approximately 13,000 tons remaining.</li><li>Active satellite constellations like SpaceX's Starlink are exacerbating the situation.</li><li>High-speed orbital debris poses a significant threat, causing the ISS to perform avoidance maneuvers frequently.</li><li>Efforts to mitigate space debris include cleanup technologies and international regulations.</li></ul><blockquote>"Proactive measures are essential to prevent irreversible damage to our orbital environment." - Dr. Nilton Renno, University of Michigan</blockquote><p>Experts stress the importance of addressing space debris before it leads to catastrophic consequences in Earth's orbit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/what-is-kessler-syndrome-how-space-junk-endangers-earths-orbit/articleshow/116735696.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/what-is-kessler-syndrome-how-space-junk-endangers-earths-orbit/articleshow/116735696.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Magnus Carlsen was given enough time to change his jeans. We didn't ban him; could've played': FIDE CEO - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FIDE CEO Explains Magnus Carlsen's Disqualification Over Dress Code</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/World-No-1-Magnus-Carlsen-at-the-World-Rapid-and-B_1735370913395_1735370925942.jpg" alt="World No.1 Magnus Carlsen at the World Rapid and Blitz Tournament.(FIDE)"><figcaption>World No.1 Magnus Carlsen at the World Rapid and Blitz Tournament.(FIDE)</figcaption><p>FIDE CEO Emil Sutovski stated that Magnus Carlsen was given ample opportunity to change into formal attire before being disqualified from the World Rapid and Blitz Championship for wearing jeans, which violated tournament regulations.</p><ul><li>Sutovski clarified that Carlsen was not banned but failed to comply with the dress code.</li><li>He noted that rules must apply to all participants and highlighted previous penalties for similar violations.</li><li>Carlsen expressed frustration with FIDE's dress code policies and decided to withdraw from the Blitz section of the tournament.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am pretty tired of FIDE, so I want no more of this. I don't want anything to do with them.” - Magnus Carlsen</blockquote><p>The situation underscores the ongoing tension between tournament regulations and player preferences regarding dress codes in chess.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/magnus-carlsen-was-given-enough-time-to-change-his-jeans-we-didnt-ban-him-couldve-played-fide-ceo-101735364642841.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/magnus-carlsen-was-given-enough-time-to-change-his-jeans-we-didnt-ban-him-couldve-played-fide-ceo-101735364642841.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:37:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Periya double murder: Court finds 14 guilty including CPM ex-MLA Kunhiraman, acquits 10, to award sentence on Jan 3 - Onmanorama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxQVm83V3JFTXJobk1QSUNldXNJUmhhVUlfTE8yWEpSdEVqMWgzcmE4dnU2Q1pqbzBrV0h0OVRXUXZGVmhLOWJSUGt5N2FkRURNZXFHdHRSbFB1dUtxMHdFaUtnejhoTnBzZ2RnSXhYYjdFd1lfcFBXWF9UMTRwd3FJT0ZlWG1NemIxYndZLXp4U2hoUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxQVm83V3JFTXJobk1QSUNldXNJUmhhVUlfTE8yWEpSdEVqMWgzcmE4dnU2Q1pqbzBrV0h0OVRXUXZGVmhLOWJSUGt5N2FkRURNZXFHdHRSbFB1dUtxMHdFaUtnejhoTnBzZ2RnSXhYYjdFd1lfcFBXWF9UMTRwd3FJT0ZlWG1NemIxYndZLXp4U2hoUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:37:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Time In 147 Years: Nitish Kumar Reddy, Washington Sundar Hurt Australia Bad; Achieve Historic .. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxQNzI3QkU4Nms4STgxeGJJcVdMRm5rTUV5ME1qbmpNcm5aYy1zSEJFaE55VVJCZFo5WmhVd0RfdjFYSS1kbjNqaERRWmhtbWV3LTNpci0wM1huWkJ5ZjBpTkJiRzMwMHZuTmJjRjBiOFlwY1ZFWDhxTEZWeWE3dHd0bTg3eVJ5WlZuYlc4N1p4Z0hsSHg2UWdVS3IzVlhxUHNZS0hhTzd1YlRpVzM1Vk5Ub3FOaHNsRy1ZZjRIT1J2RjdjdENzd1RpeEhzaDIyTlBDb19Pb3REU1lMQmg0M2xiNkdfNFNDTVNFakduSXlGTWJfWnp60gH8AUFVX3lxTE9yb20yV1pFbHZYMU92NzNINF8yeG9sV0dJUVlnQ0pWeHo2ZlNwYnV0U1BBMUhRQlAwdm1DNk03eWNVUnNfaElwbnVidFVTZ3BVNlpLNEo5TEVJOGMxZGJwd1lQWW1YcmR1M0JNVnNOd2twUUVldk00dm01cHJlTWtZRmF4bmhFQU8wbFZNd004a1dzVFZEdHpVaHZLbHZPQmRyMDhMMTduWUwwVWFMOGRqcnRwelZsUW5ReGU2U3E0Mk1VTEVZYUt2MXdTa2xUaURpNDdFS0ZTZVhVU25LWGlRNVIzaVpLM01DczNXRGlVTWtXRnZNTFkwcWUyeQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxQNzI3QkU4Nms4STgxeGJJcVdMRm5rTUV5ME1qbmpNcm5aYy1zSEJFaE55VVJCZFo5WmhVd0RfdjFYSS1kbjNqaERRWmhtbWV3LTNpci0wM1huWkJ5ZjBpTkJiRzMwMHZuTmJjRjBiOFlwY1ZFWDhxTEZWeWE3dHd0bTg3eVJ5WlZuYlc4N1p4Z0hsSHg2UWdVS3IzVlhxUHNZS0hhTzd1YlRpVzM1Vk5Ub3FOaHNsRy1ZZjRIT1J2RjdjdENzd1RpeEhzaDIyTlBDb19Pb3REU1lMQmg0M2xiNkdfNFNDTVNFakduSXlGTWJfWnp60gH8AUFVX3lxTE9yb20yV1pFbHZYMU92NzNINF8yeG9sV0dJUVlnQ0pWeHo2ZlNwYnV0U1BBMUhRQlAwdm1DNk03eWNVUnNfaElwbnVidFVTZ3BVNlpLNEo5TEVJOGMxZGJwd1lQWW1YcmR1M0JNVnNOd2twUUVldk00dm01cHJlTWtZRmF4bmhFQU8wbFZNd004a1dzVFZEdHpVaHZLbHZPQmRyMDhMMTduWUwwVWFMOGRqcnRwelZsUW5ReGU2U3E0Mk1VTEVZYUt2MXdTa2xUaURpNDdFS0ZTZVhVU25LWGlRNVIzaVpLM01DczNXRGlVTWtXRnZNTFkwcWUyeQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:35:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ambani family hosts Salman Khan's 'Bhaijaan'-themed birthday bash in Jamnagar; Deanne Panday, Sohail Khan - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ambani Family Hosts Salman Khan's 'Bhaijaan'-themed Birthday Bash in Jamnagar</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert date here] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116734666,imgsize-82240,width-400,resizemode-4/116734666.jpg" alt="Ambani family hosts Salman Khan's 'Bhaijaan'-themed birthday bash in Jamnagar; Deanne Panday, Sohail Khan share INSIDE PICS"><figcaption>Grand birthday bash for Salman Khan hosted by Ambani family.</figcaption><p>The Ambani family organized a lavish birthday party for actor Salman Khan in Jamnagar, Gujarat, featuring stunning decorations and a festive atmosphere.</p><ul><li>Salman celebrated his birthday with family and friends after having an intimate gathering at his sister's home.</li><li>The party included large thematic decorations inspired by Salman's film career and iconic characters.</li><li>Guests included close family members and several industry friends celebrating with vibrant festivities.</li><li>A spectacular firework display marked the midnight celebration.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite facing several threats this year, Salman Khan arrived smiling and relaxed at the bash.”</blockquote><p>The event showcased the deep bond between Salman Khan and the Ambani family, with vibrant celebrations reflecting Salman's cinematic journey.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/ambani-family-hosts-salman-khans-bhaijaan-themed-birthday-bash-in-jamnagar-deanne-panday-sohail-khan-share-inside-pics/articleshow/116734155.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/ambani-family-hosts-salman-khans-bhaijaan-themed-birthday-bash-in-jamnagar-deanne-panday-sohail-khan-share-inside-pics/articleshow/116734155.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court livid after Punjab says "helpless" to provide medical aid to Jagjit Dallewal - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court livid after Punjab says "helpless" to provide medical aid to Jagjit Dallewal</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 28 Dec 2024, 7:28 am</p><p>The Supreme Court expressed frustration over the Punjab government's inability to provide medical assistance to Jagjit Singh Dallewal, a farmer leader on a fast unto death protesting for minimum support prices.</p><ul><li>The Punjab government's claim of being 'helpless' due to protesting farmers blocking aid was rejected by the Court.</li><li>Justices Surya Kant and Sudhanshu Dhulia emphasized the need for compliance with previous Court orders to provide medical aid.</li><li>There is concern regarding the legality of the farmers obstructing medical assistance to Dallewal.</li><li>The Court allowed more time for the Punjab government to comply with orders and suggested seeking assistance from the Central government.</li><li>The situation is considered delicate, with warnings about potential consequences if medical aid is not administered promptly.</li></ul><blockquote><p>"When you (eventually) give him some aid, it may be too little too late." — Justice Dhulia</p></blockquote><p>The Court will further hear the case on December 31, stressing the imperative of compliance with its requests to protect Dallewal's well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/supreme-court-livid-punjab-says-helpless-provide-medical-aid-jagjit-dallewal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/supreme-court-livid-punjab-says-helpless-provide-medical-aid-jagjit-dallewal</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:28:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NDA created 'unnecessary controversy' over Manmohan Singh's cremation, memorial: Ashok Gehlot - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gehlot Accuses NDA of Controversy Over Manmohan Singh's Memorial</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/s5znqx/article69036381.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/02_RVM_8443.jpg" alt="Former Rajasthan Chief Minister Ashok Gehlot. File" title="Former Rajasthan Chief Minister Ashok Gehlot. File"><figcaption>Former Rajasthan Chief Minister Ashok Gehlot. File | Photo Credit: The Hindu</figcaption><p>Ashok Gehlot, former Rajasthan chief minister, criticized the NDA government for creating unnecessary controversy surrounding the cremation and memorial of former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh.</p><ul><li>Gehlot claims public pressure led to BJP's plans for a future memorial for Singh.</li><li>Manmohan Singh, the architect of India's economic reforms, passed away at 92.</li><li>Gehlot highlighted inconsistencies in how the BJP has handled tributes to leaders from different parties.</li><li>Singh's last rites were conducted at Nigam Bodh Ghat, a location Gehlot argues is not special enough for a leader of Singh's stature.</li></ul><blockquote>“The NDA government has created an unnecessary controversy over the cremation and memorial of a great personality like Dr Manmohan Singh.” - Ashok Gehlot</blockquote><p>In summary, Gehlot's comments reflect broader concerns about the treatment of prominent political figures and the legacy of Singh's contributions to India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/nda-created-unnecessary-controversy-over-manmohan-singhs-cremation-memorial-ashok-gehlot/article69036369.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/nda-created-unnecessary-controversy-over-manmohan-singhs-cremation-memorial-ashok-gehlot/article69036369.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World rapid and blitz chess: After Carlsen disqualification, India's Arjun Erigaisi in joint lead - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arjun Erigaisi Joins Leaders After Carlsen's Disqualification at World Chess Championship</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 28 December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> New York</p><p>Indian grandmaster Arjun Erigaisi has become one of four co-leaders at the World rapid and blitz chess championship following a day of remarkable gameplay, especially after the disqualification of five-time world champion Magnus Carlsen for violating dress code rules.</p><ul><li>Arjun Erigaisi, along with Volodar Murzin, Alexander Grischuk, and Duda Jan-Kryzstof, are all tied with seven points after round 9.</li><li>Magnus Carlsen was fined $200 and subsequently disqualified for wearing jeans, which are not allowed by tournament rules.</li><li>Arjun's chances for winning are boosted significantly following Carlsen's exit, known for his dominance in rapid chess.</li><li>In the women's event, Koneru Humpy leads with 6.5 points alongside compatriots D Harika and Wenjun Ju of China.</li></ul><blockquote>“The day belonged to Arjun who defeated Robson Ray of the United States and later won against Shant Sargsyan of Armenia.”</blockquote><p>With only four rounds remaining, the championship is heating up, promising an exciting finish as leaders prepare for their matches ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/sports/world-rapid-and-blitz-chess-after-carlsen-disqualification-indias-arjun-erigaisi-in-joint-lead-3334679</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/sports/world-rapid-and-blitz-chess-after-carlsen-disqualification-indias-arjun-erigaisi-in-joint-lead-3334679</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:18:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The rise and reign of India’s beauty baroness Shahnaz Husain | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Rise and Reign of Shahnaz Husain: India's Beauty Baroness</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> Company Business News</p>
<p>Shahnaz Husain, turning 80 last month, is celebrated as a pioneer in organic green beauty in India, influencing the beauty industry long before the term 'influencer' became popular. She combined her marketing savvy with a forward-thinking approach to beauty trends.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Recognized as one of India's original influencers, shaping beauty standards since the 1970s.</li>
  <li>Established a highly sought-after brand with a strong identity centered around her name.</li>
  <li>Her marketing strategy inspired thousands of women to pursue her beauty products.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Such was the power of her marketing that thousands of young women wanted a totemic vial of cream from Shahnaz Husain.”</blockquote>
<p>Shahnaz Husain's legacy demonstrates the empowerment of women in entrepreneurship and the impact of innovative marketing in the beauty sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/the-rise-and-reign-of-india-s-beauty-baroness-shahnaz-husain-11735367006629.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/the-rise-and-reign-of-india-s-beauty-baroness-shahnaz-husain-11735367006629.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:36:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 3 Live Updates: Nitish Reddy Hits Maiden Ton But Bad Light Stops Play In Melbourne - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxQNnRnY1BFUjctRUpUZmpNdWE0NFJac0R3bE5felFlN2o5VVVHY0otVVJUaVI5TGpQRGw0eGN5aHBrNWRmMDlObGw3TWVDZTN2ZlBfWVI3cUlMRnVoZDJ5aGR5QjlJQ1I1OVZLbHVoS0Q5bnFYaS1EZENUSGM2VktxQ1BOQV9GUEtVeU5jTG1vUllKbUFoZ0lKWVVJUkN2aHd1R1NOdThBR19jcnpBdmxvdTVRRU9XdTBjWXY4Qjdwa0xfTThralVJVFZDcmliUFFLQ2VLd1pxOUhBWkp5NlYtNU9Cd25JY2dPSGoxTExRS0tIcVhzdTQ0VVlPV2h6d9IBhgJBVV95cUxNZHlFS2JUUTZZclpNdEJBaHM2RVUyRlphakJOMzJia3BJZEN3Y3R0dkw4eGlkZS05WmF6S2N6ZENldjZpTGMtOFI1ZkloQ2trMHBEZmhpNGdBNDk2N1JzdjFXcktrWG9wN19wTFU5SVdOZGRpMjVzVFBJa01DMTZFN2dORTk2NjRXYjQwY2cwc3VSVHhyQVcyaHRrcXg1WUJud2xHY1hpUGtKRTVzbFluaFNIZEV1M1l5QlRIbmh0LVV0X2FjWG1BM2NJMEJzUVRJMmgxUDl5M0tZTkJWaVh5QzYwUk9ybGdmRWJiOEtQLVFySl9ZVVBKM1hmMWdaa3RodUxyQlFB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_gFBVV95cUxQNnRnY1BFUjctRUpUZmpNdWE0NFJac0R3bE5felFlN2o5VVVHY0otVVJUaVI5TGpQRGw0eGN5aHBrNWRmMDlObGw3TWVDZTN2ZlBfWVI3cUlMRnVoZDJ5aGR5QjlJQ1I1OVZLbHVoS0Q5bnFYaS1EZENUSGM2VktxQ1BOQV9GUEtVeU5jTG1vUllKbUFoZ0lKWVVJUkN2aHd1R1NOdThBR19jcnpBdmxvdTVRRU9XdTBjWXY4Qjdwa0xfTThralVJVFZDcmliUFFLQ2VLd1pxOUhBWkp5NlYtNU9Cd25JY2dPSGoxTExRS0tIcVhzdTQ0VVlPV2h6d9IBhgJBVV95cUxNZHlFS2JUUTZZclpNdEJBaHM2RVUyRlphakJOMzJia3BJZEN3Y3R0dkw4eGlkZS05WmF6S2N6ZENldjZpTGMtOFI1ZkloQ2trMHBEZmhpNGdBNDk2N1JzdjFXcktrWG9wN19wTFU5SVdOZGRpMjVzVFBJa01DMTZFN2dORTk2NjRXYjQwY2cwc3VSVHhyQVcyaHRrcXg1WUJud2xHY1hpUGtKRTVzbFluaFNIZEV1M1l5QlRIbmh0LVV0X2FjWG1BM2NJMEJzUVRJMmgxUDl5M0tZTkJWaVh5QzYwUk9ybGdmRWJiOEtQLVFySl9ZVVBKM1hmMWdaa3RodUxyQlFB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:36:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple iPhone 16 Pro Gets Massive Discount With Additional Bank Offers; Check Specs And Discounted Price - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/lifestyle/shopping/apple-iphone-16-pro-gets-massive-discount-with-additional-bank-offers-check-specs-and-discounted-price/ar-AA1wBw2U</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/lifestyle/shopping/apple-iphone-16-pro-gets-massive-discount-with-additional-bank-offers-check-specs-and-discounted-price/ar-AA1wBw2U</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:32:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 superfoods to prevent Alzheimer's disease - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxOa1RVSnFhX3IxNE50TzZGLUxZbTlBa29fcEhPSE4xMHFncUkxQUFVc0ZSOHJDQ0lhekpqeDJXUWFVSzhZMXBUWkMwcVo2NlJKd05CNFE3RTQ4QXUxVGU0ZWNaRDR0UlVYQ2k3UUpPZDdiN01NTjRobVJUSHZJSi1Oc3plQlpNTTdtNnJORVNZUmNfQlVsNGtxLXBwNEJKTlBPYUVaRkhUZDVrMVo3RklMUFRkR0FBQkgtOG5PVzlyY0pNX01NRm93NWpWNk5QRHREY2VyUzg0RmTSAdgBQVVfeXFMTmtUVUpxYV9yMTROdE82Ri1MWW05QWtvX3BIT0hOMTBxZ3FJMUFBVXNGUjhyQ0NJYXpKangyV1FhVUs4WTFwVFpDMHFaNjZSSndOQjRRN0U0OEF1MVRlNGVjWkQ0dFJVWENpN1FKT2Q3YjdNTU40aG1SVEh2SUotTnN6ZUJaTU03bTZyTkVTWVJjX0JVbDRrcS1wcDRCSk5QT2FFWkZIVGQ1azFaN0ZJTFBUZEdBQUJILThuT1c5cmNKTV9NTUZvdzVqVjZOUER0RGNlclM4NEZk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxOa1RVSnFhX3IxNE50TzZGLUxZbTlBa29fcEhPSE4xMHFncUkxQUFVc0ZSOHJDQ0lhekpqeDJXUWFVSzhZMXBUWkMwcVo2NlJKd05CNFE3RTQ4QXUxVGU0ZWNaRDR0UlVYQ2k3UUpPZDdiN01NTjRobVJUSHZJSi1Oc3plQlpNTTdtNnJORVNZUmNfQlVsNGtxLXBwNEJKTlBPYUVaRkhUZDVrMVo3RklMUFRkR0FBQkgtOG5PVzlyY0pNX01NRm93NWpWNk5QRHREY2VyUzg0RmTSAdgBQVVfeXFMTmtUVUpxYV9yMTROdE82Ri1MWW05QWtvX3BIT0hOMTBxZ3FJMUFBVXNGUjhyQ0NJYXpKangyV1FhVUs4WTFwVFpDMHFaNjZSSndOQjRRN0U0OEF1MVRlNGVjWkQ0dFJVWENpN1FKT2Q3YjdNTU40aG1SVEh2SUotTnN6ZUJaTU03bTZyTkVTWVJjX0JVbDRrcS1wcDRCSk5QT2FFWkZIVGQ1azFaN0ZJTFBUZEdBQUJILThuT1c5cmNKTV9NTUZvdzVqVjZOUER0RGNlclM4NEZk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viswanathan Anand on Magnus Carlsen incident: He simply refused to follow rules, left us with little choice - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Viswanathan Anand on Magnus Carlsen incident: ‘He simply refused to follow rules, left us with little choice’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>Viswanathan Anand, deputy president of chess' global governing body, comments on Magnus Carlsen's unexpected exit from the FIDE World Rapid and Blitz Championship due to a dress code violation.</p><ul><li>Carlsen was fined for wearing jeans at the event.</li><li>Anand stated that Carlsen's refusal to comply with dress code rules left FIDE with no choice but to un-pair him.</li><li>Anand indicated options were provided to Carlsen to rectify the situation, but he chose not to follow them.</li><li>Examples were given of other players who complied with the dress code.</li></ul><blockquote>“He simply refused to follow rules, left us with little choice,” said Anand.</blockquote><p>The incident highlights the importance of adhering to regulations in professional events, which can lead to significant consequences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/chess/viswanathan-anand-on-magnus-carlsen-he-simply-refused-to-follow-rules-9748433/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/chess/viswanathan-anand-on-magnus-carlsen-he-simply-refused-to-follow-rules-9748433/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Snowfall grounds 80% flights at Srinagar airport - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQeUVXMHRWNGNkMElqYkpBSTJjSFBWMFdENlcxX295X0czZUdhUnk1Vlg1bjRsUy1zRElnMTJWa0ZSMmZ0MG82Z3JXUFZmOFJsZEVYOFZwV2JPZXlBaDAyd1pwTlg5Z2liYW5UNHlzd19UMnVsUV9NVTdyVHpWVF9WN18weFNkb1E1WkJMdUJ0eTl0T191cnfSAZsBQVVfeXFMTkxvcDVBNGJYSXNVS3NhQ0FBNDk3WGhrVE1sbl8wcDE5VFNqcHJyNXZJM3pEWDNhMHNiSEgzZkRIdVF6WG5xMnU1NEZOQzZJV0FhU2d3NFl2NXFIc0xyeXhxcnlLRVZDeEVocHk2eUtHb3JXOE85WHpWdHRmdVdyaG51ZVpHQjB1bFhhY3hkdC1ralZrSnRuV2ZZNUU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQeUVXMHRWNGNkMElqYkpBSTJjSFBWMFdENlcxX295X0czZUdhUnk1Vlg1bjRsUy1zRElnMTJWa0ZSMmZ0MG82Z3JXUFZmOFJsZEVYOFZwV2JPZXlBaDAyd1pwTlg5Z2liYW5UNHlzd19UMnVsUV9NVTdyVHpWVF9WN18weFNkb1E1WkJMdUJ0eTl0T191cnfSAZsBQVVfeXFMTkxvcDVBNGJYSXNVS3NhQ0FBNDk3WGhrVE1sbl8wcDE5VFNqcHJyNXZJM3pEWDNhMHNiSEgzZkRIdVF6WG5xMnU1NEZOQzZJV0FhU2d3NFl2NXFIc0xyeXhxcnlLRVZDeEVocHk2eUtHb3JXOE85WHpWdHRmdVdyaG51ZVpHQjB1bFhhY3hkdC1ralZrSnRuV2ZZNUU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:52:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025 stock picks from Religare Broking with up to 29% upside potential - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxPY0dpdW1kQ1dLejEwTkZEOUFLa1QwbXh2QUxFN0lMUTJUalpraUFoYktOSnRVaTJhYnliMGZibUE3aWR0NUtIMWNaWl84UWZMUEhFWjU2d1FqUU51b19pdlRrMWhkTWI5S0t6SVRMZlVIY1Y3V3NkenE4LUdYa0xJLWNXUHNIdG5senlJX05xY3B0ZjRfaXN5ZFUxTkJPRlc2d2dXMVFwdWs2YmFacFdkX1k4MTY3RlQtdEt3VjR2OWFJY3FtalY3eFdIenI2ZzhyNmpWc1Zsc2s?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxPY0dpdW1kQ1dLejEwTkZEOUFLa1QwbXh2QUxFN0lMUTJUalpraUFoYktOSnRVaTJhYnliMGZibUE3aWR0NUtIMWNaWl84UWZMUEhFWjU2d1FqUU51b19pdlRrMWhkTWI5S0t6SVRMZlVIY1Y3V3NkenE4LUdYa0xJLWNXUHNIdG5senlJX05xY3B0ZjRfaXN5ZFUxTkJPRlc2d2dXMVFwdWs2YmFacFdkX1k4MTY3RlQtdEt3VjR2OWFJY3FtalY3eFdIenI2ZzhyNmpWc1Zsc2s?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:39:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 breathtaking NASA wallpapers for space enthusiasts - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Breathtaking NASA Wallpapers for Space Enthusiasts</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/900x1600/NASA_1725611592371_1735292208029.png" alt="NASA Wallpaper" />
<figcaption>Photo Credit: NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases eight stunning wallpapers from NASA that cater to space enthusiasts, highlighting breathtaking imagery and interesting space facts.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nasa's imagery captures the beauty and intricacy of space, including images of planets, galaxies, and nebulae.</li>
  <li>Each wallpaper represents significant aspects of space exploration and scientific discovery.</li>
  <li>Stunning visuals serve as a reminder of the vastness and wonder of the universe.</li>
  <li NASA has discovered thousands of exoplanets and continues to expand our understanding of the cosmos.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These breathtaking wallpapers are more than just pictures; they’re a glimpse into the wonders of our universe.”</blockquote>
<p>This collection not only provides visually appealing art but also ignites curiosity about the universe, encouraging viewers to appreciate the ongoing exploration of space.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/trending/8-breathtaking-nasa-wallpapers-for-space-enthusiasts-101735291886467.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/trending/8-breathtaking-nasa-wallpapers-for-space-enthusiasts-101735291886467.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:35:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In T.N., where dengue cases hit 26,000 this year, tracking every case, forecasting outbreaks is helping prevent deaths - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dengue Cases Surge in Tamil Nadu: Effective Surveillance and Forecasting Help Prevent Deaths</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/f3iz3y/article69036162.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/CORPORATION%20FOGGING%20MEDICAL%20CAMP%20DENGUE%20FEVER%20HEALTH_05.jpg" alt="Dengue prevention measures in Tamil Nadu" title="Dengue prevention measures in Tamil Nadu" /><figcaption>Dengue prevention measures in Tamil Nadu.</figcaption><p>Tamil Nadu has recorded over 26,000 cases of dengue this year. Public health officials have implemented improved surveillance and reporting systems to manage outbreaks effectively and prevent deaths.</p><ul><li>As of December 26, Tamil Nadu recorded 26,740 dengue cases and 13 deaths.</li><li>Surveillance has allowed for better identification and reporting of cases, preventing mortality.</li><li>Dengue cases have been reported throughout the year, with increased incidence during the monsoon season.</li><li>The highest number of cases since 2012, with a comparison to previous years detailing cases and deaths.</li></ul><blockquote>“So, while the initial rise in cases was manageable, we stepped up surveillance to ensure that no case went unreported.” - T. S. Selvavinayagam, Director of Public Health and Preventive Medicine.</blockquote><p>The proactive measures in Tamil Nadu have shown a significant impact on managing dengue outbreaks and protecting public health effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/in-tn-where-dengue-cases-hit-26000-this-year-tracking-every-case-forecasting-outbreaks-is-helping-prevent-deaths/article69034837.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/in-tn-where-dengue-cases-hit-26000-this-year-tracking-every-case-forecasting-outbreaks-is-helping-prevent-deaths/article69034837.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA confirms solar probe has made record-breaking close approach to the Sun - Euronews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Parker Solar Probe Makes Historic Close Approach to the Sun</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Latest Update</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>The Parker Solar Probe has successfully made the closest approach to the Sun, setting a record by coming within six million kilometers of the Sun's surface.</p><ul><li>The probe passed through the Sun's outer atmosphere, known as the corona.</li><li>It achieved speeds of 690,000 kph during its close approach.</li><li>The heat shield of the Parker can withstand temperatures reaching up to 1,370 degrees Celsius.</li><li>This mission aims to provide insights into the reasons behind the Sun's corona being significantly hotter than its surface.</li><li>Parker Solar Probe was launched in 2018 and is expected to continue orbiting the Sun until at least September.</li></ul><blockquote>“Parker Solar Probe was developed as part of NASA’s Living With a Star program to explore aspects of the Sun-Earth system that directly affect life and society,” said NASA in a statement.</blockquote><p>This successful mission is a significant step in understanding solar phenomena and their impact on Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.euronews.com/2024/12/28/nasa-confirms-solar-probe-has-made-record-breaking-close-approach-to-the-sun</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.euronews.com/2024/12/28/nasa-confirms-solar-probe-has-made-record-breaking-close-approach-to-the-sun</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:26:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA confirms Parker Solar Probe made close approach to the Sun - Euronews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Parker Solar Probe Makes Historic Close Approach to the Sun</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Latest Update</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>The Parker Solar Probe has successfully made the closest approach to the Sun, setting a record by coming within six million kilometers of the Sun's surface.</p><ul><li>The probe passed through the Sun's outer atmosphere, known as the corona.</li><li>It achieved speeds of 690,000 kph during its close approach.</li><li>The heat shield of the Parker can withstand temperatures reaching up to 1,370 degrees Celsius.</li><li>This mission aims to provide insights into the reasons behind the Sun's corona being significantly hotter than its surface.</li><li>Parker Solar Probe was launched in 2018 and is expected to continue orbiting the Sun until at least September.</li></ul><blockquote>“Parker Solar Probe was developed as part of NASA’s Living With a Star program to explore aspects of the Sun-Earth system that directly affect life and society,” said NASA in a statement.</blockquote><p>This successful mission is a significant step in understanding solar phenomena and their impact on Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.euronews.com/2024/12/28/nasa-confirms-solar-probe-has-made-record-breaking-close-approach-to-the-sun</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.euronews.com/2024/12/28/nasa-confirms-solar-probe-has-made-record-breaking-close-approach-to-the-sun</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:26:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>