<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 17:19:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 17:19:54 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How can India still qualify for 2025 WTC Final - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Path to the 2025 World Test Championship Final</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Date not provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116445382,imgsize-43832,width-400,resizemode-4/116445382.jpg" alt="How can India still qualify for 2025 WTC Final" title="(Pic Credit - X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>(Pic Credit - X)</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team remains in contention for the 2025 World Test Championship (WTC) Final even after a draw against Australia at Gabba. To secure their spot, India must win both remaining Tests in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>India is currently ranked third in the WTC standings.</li><li>To guarantee qualification, India must achieve victories in both remaining Tests.</li><li>They need Australia to suffer losses in their matches against Sri Lanka for a better chance.</li><li>Different scenarios have been outlined for India's qualification based on their performance and Australia's results.</li></ul><blockquote>“If India lose the series 1-2, they will finish with a percentage points of 51.75, effectively ruling them out of contention for the WTC final.”</blockquote><p>The stakes are high for India as they aim to secure their place in the WTC Final through a combination of their performance and other teams' results.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/how-can-india-still-qualify-for-2025-wtc-final/articleshow/116445406.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/how-can-india-still-qualify-for-2025-wtc-final/articleshow/116445406.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 16:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fed expected to slash interest rates, yet dot plot could show doubts over further cuts ahead - FXStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fed dot plot on focus as markets fully price in 25 bps interest-rate cut</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> FXStreet</p><p>The Federal Reserve is expected to cut the policy interest rate by 25 basis points at its last meeting of 2024, with crucial insights to be drawn from Fed Chairman Powell’s statements and the updated dot plot.</p><ul><li>The Federal Reserve is widely expected to lower the policy rate by 25 bps at the last meeting of 2024.</li><li>Fed Chairman Powell’s remarks and the revised dot plot could provide important clues about the interest-rate outlook.</li><li>The US Dollar’s valuation could be impacted significantly heading into the Christmas holiday.</li></ul><blockquote>“While we think the Fed will remain keen on projecting additional policy easing for 2025, our view is that guidance regarding the pace of rate cuts will be more cautious going forward. This might be interpreted as a hawkish rate cut by market participants.” - TD Securities analysts</blockquote><p>The Fed's meeting is scheduled for December 2024 to announce monetary policy decisions, with implications for the USD based on the dot plot and press conference statements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fxstreet.com/news/federal-reserve-widely-expected-to-cut-interest-rates-despite-recent-inflation-uptick-202412181100</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fxstreet.com/news/federal-reserve-widely-expected-to-cut-interest-rates-despite-recent-inflation-uptick-202412181100</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 benefits of eating 2 dried apricots every morning - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Benefits of Eating 2 Dried Apricots Every Morning</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116436480.jpg?imgsize=1112965&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="8 benefits of eating 2 dried apricots every morning">
<figcaption>8 Benefits of Eating 2 Dried Apricots Every Morning</figcaption>
<p>This article highlights the health advantages of incorporating two dried apricots into your morning routine, detailing eight specific benefits.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Dried apricots promote digestive health by containing natural fiber.</li>
  <li>They boost skin health with vitamins and antioxidants.</li>
  <li>They provide a light, filling breakfast alternative.</li>
  <li>Potassium in dried apricots aids in maintaining heart health.</li>
  <li>They contribute to improved vision thanks to beta-carotene.</li>
  <li>Dried apricots can enhance energy levels due to natural sugars and minerals.</li>
  <li>They strengthen bones with calcium and magnesium.</li>
  <li>They serve as a remedy for iron deficiency, supporting red blood cell production.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Adding small, healthy habits to daily routine can have a big impact on overall well-being.” - Aadya Jha</blockquote>
<p>Incorporating two dried apricots each morning provides numerous health benefits, supporting digestion, heart health, and overall wellness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/8-benefits-of-eating-2-dried-apricots-every-morning/photostory/116436253.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/8-benefits-of-eating-2-dried-apricots-every-morning/photostory/116436253.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Priyanka Gandhi, Anurag Thakur to be part of 31-member JPC on 'One Nation One Election' bill - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Priyanka Gandhi, Anurag Thakur to be part of 31-member JPC on 'One Nation One Election' bill</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not Provided</p><p>This article discusses the formation of a 31-member Joint Parliamentary Committee (JPC) that will review the 'One Nation One Election' bill, with key members including Priyanka Gandhi and Anurag Thakur.</p><ul><li>The JPC will evaluate the implications of holding simultaneous elections in India.</li><li>Priyanka Gandhi represents the Congress Party, while Anurag Thakur represents the BJP.</li></ul><blockquote>“This bill aims to streamline the electoral process in India,” said a member of the JPC.</blockquote><p>The establishment of this committee marks a significant step in the legislative process regarding election reforms in the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/priyanka-gandhi-anurag-thakur-to-be-part-of-31-member-jpc-on-one-nation-one-election-bill/articleshow/116444780.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/priyanka-gandhi-anurag-thakur-to-be-part-of-31-member-jpc-on-one-nation-one-election-bill/articleshow/116444780.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 16:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Myth busted? Vitamin D won't prevent falls or fractures, here's what a new study says - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Myth busted? Vitamin D won't prevent falls or fractures, here's what a new study says</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>This article discusses a recent study that challenges the long-held belief that Vitamin D effectively prevents falls and fractures among older adults.</p><ul><li>The study found no significant difference in fall or fracture rates among participants taking Vitamin D compared to those who were not.</li><li>Researchers emphasize the need for alternative strategies to prevent falls in the elderly.</li><li>The findings call for a reevaluation of dietary supplements for fall prevention.</li></ul><blockquote>“This study suggests that simply increasing Vitamin D intake may not be enough to prevent falls and fractures.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while Vitamin D is crucial for bone health, it may not be the solution for preventing falls and fractures as previously believed.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/myth-busted-vitamin-d-wont-prevent-falls-or-fractures-heres-what-a-new-study-says/articleshow/116444740.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/myth-busted-vitamin-d-wont-prevent-falls-or-fractures-heres-what-a-new-study-says/articleshow/116444740.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 16:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chronic Inflammation Driven by Diet May Contribute to Colorectal Cancer, Study Finds - Pharmacy Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chronic Inflammation Driven by Diet May Contribute to Colorectal Cancer, Study Finds</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 10, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gut</p><img alt="Depiction of colorectal cancer tumor growth" title="Depiction of colorectal cancer tumor growth" src="https://cdn.sanity.io/images/0vv8moc6/pharmacytimes/787739a982c553b30225d7231a7e1e1e2d7da0b5-7200x4050.jpg?fit=crop&amp;auto=format"><figcaption>Depiction of colorectal cancer tumor growth Image Credit: © Dr_Microbe - stock.adobe.com</figcaption><p>Researchers have discovered a potential link between ultra-processed foods and an increased risk of colorectal cancer (CRC), suggesting that chronic inflammation from such diets encourages tumor growth.</p><ul><li>The study published in <em>Gut</em> indicates that a Western diet high in ultra-processed foods contributes to tumor growth through inflammation.</li><li>CRC rates are rising, particularly among individuals under 50; this demographic is seeing a 13% increase in cancer cases over the past decade.</li><li>Dr. Timothy Yeatman highlights that unhealthy diets lead to increased inflammation, impacting the body’s healing ability.</li><li>The investigation showed an imbalance of pro-inflammatory lipid mediators in CRC affected tissue.</li><li>Prevention through a balanced diet may significantly reduce CRC risks.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is well known that patients with unhealthy diets have increased inflammation in their bodies.” - Dr. Timothy Yeatman</blockquote><p>This study emphasizes the importance of diet in cancer prevention and encourages further exploration into the role of nutrition in health outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pharmacytimes.com/view/chronic-inflammation-driven-by-diet-may-contribute-to-colorectal-cancer-study-finds</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pharmacytimes.com/view/chronic-inflammation-driven-by-diet-may-contribute-to-colorectal-cancer-study-finds</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:53:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Near-Earth object alert! 84-foot asteroid heads towards Earth. Will it collide or pass safely? Details her - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAJBVV95cUxOcWtxYmR6OE8wTE9uN2VHQVBWNjBDR1N6cVBYMUdlVWNOWjNHT2lmWHJEUGdvZ2dxMEQ3R2QwMUVfS0ZBNWVQX1llUGdnc3M0T2Y1cE1GV1R5STdhQTJsb0xLd0t4clpsY21US3JFRExicXpPNG5oS0dwbEZGRGs1MGVmR09LcFhzVi1xcFY5bTNNS3BfODFrY2lyZUVERnYyRzZzRnV5UUtjWnZxZUx1MnozNHVBTURWWkotUVNra0hrWkVEVkw5ZlowckVLdjdaMDRVTlhlUnlRRmdRWVN0ZVN2eXgwTHV1MnE2akp2RmlhMVI1ZnFweXlnLVN5b01oQ1lYdENYVWFSelhR0gGSAkFVX3lxTFBsMDd3SzAtamRxQy1lSEpFVmFLcHBZZVE3N2tRc2VfQXUtdmprc3drUlQ3VjdxRzVueTY5d01qNTVFRmtLQkFHRFY4ZDJRd19qQWRqZzVJNU5KdTQ0NmxyVHg0TW9HdXdsQmliTUpEX1BjaWN0RFdoNEF6R3FyVzVMbE5hcjJHLUo1dndYbzNMc2pmQ0RILXVKS1VHdTV6YWpxSHJoYXVQSDg3azlrdl9jREVreXR5NVpnTnBYc01kcF9CUEZqM3JxekJpYklZVzhqT3hJWDRxenk5NG1oMlpQSXppeVdaN3hmRTdjVW9hdWZSb2xIcnNjaFYyMDNvUUZFcDBtZ19aQmh0cmdyaFFqVXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAJBVV95cUxOcWtxYmR6OE8wTE9uN2VHQVBWNjBDR1N6cVBYMUdlVWNOWjNHT2lmWHJEUGdvZ2dxMEQ3R2QwMUVfS0ZBNWVQX1llUGdnc3M0T2Y1cE1GV1R5STdhQTJsb0xLd0t4clpsY21US3JFRExicXpPNG5oS0dwbEZGRGs1MGVmR09LcFhzVi1xcFY5bTNNS3BfODFrY2lyZUVERnYyRzZzRnV5UUtjWnZxZUx1MnozNHVBTURWWkotUVNra0hrWkVEVkw5ZlowckVLdjdaMDRVTlhlUnlRRmdRWVN0ZVN2eXgwTHV1MnE2akp2RmlhMVI1ZnFweXlnLVN5b01oQ1lYdENYVWFSelhR0gGSAkFVX3lxTFBsMDd3SzAtamRxQy1lSEpFVmFLcHBZZVE3N2tRc2VfQXUtdmprc3drUlQ3VjdxRzVueTY5d01qNTVFRmtLQkFHRFY4ZDJRd19qQWRqZzVJNU5KdTQ0NmxyVHg0TW9HdXdsQmliTUpEX1BjaWN0RFdoNEF6R3FyVzVMbE5hcjJHLUo1dndYbzNMc2pmQ0RILXVKS1VHdTV6YWpxSHJoYXVQSDg3azlrdl9jREVreXR5NVpnTnBYc01kcF9CUEZqM3JxekJpYklZVzhqT3hJWDRxenk5NG1oMlpQSXppeVdaN3hmRTdjVW9hdWZSb2xIcnNjaFYyMDNvUUZFcDBtZ19aQmh0cmdyaFFqVXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:53:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Now Lets Few Developers Use 01 Reasoning Model in API - AutoGPT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OpenAI Now Lets Few Developers Use 01 Reasoning Model in API</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> OpenAI</p><img src="https://autogpt.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CMC_banner-1.jpg" alt="O1 Reasoning Model"><figcaption>OpenAI's 01 reasoning model interface</figcaption><p>OpenAI has launched its 01 reasoning model in its API, offering select developers in the “tier 5” usage category access starting December 17, 2024. This model is designed to improve the accuracy of AI responses.</p><ul><li>The 01 reasoning model performs self-checks on its answers, enhancing reliability.</li><li>Developers must meet specific criteria, including spending $1,000 with OpenAI and having an established account.</li><li>New features include function calling, developer messages, reasoning effort parameters, and image analysis.</li><li>The model is more expensive than previous versions, reflecting its advanced capabilities.</li></ul><blockquote>“Even though the pricing and access restrictions might limit its initial adoption, 01’s potential to reshape industries is undeniable.”</blockquote><p>The launch of 01 represents a significant advancement in AI, focusing on precision and reliability for developers in various industries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://autogpt.net/openai-now-lets-few-developers-use-01-reasoning-model-in-api/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://autogpt.net/openai-now-lets-few-developers-use-01-reasoning-model-in-api/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:39:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lawyer Sana Raees Khan comes out in support of Allu Arjun after his arrest for Pushpa 2 stampede: 'Holdin - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lawyer Sana Raees Khan comes out in support of Allu Arjun after his arrest for Pushpa 2 stampede: 'Holding him accountable for actions...'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116443571,imgsize-57794,width-400,resizemode-4/116443571.jpg" alt="Lawyer Sana Raees Khan comes out in support of Allu Arjun" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Lawyer Sana Raees Khan supports Allu Arjun following his recent arrest.</figcaption><p>Lawyer Sana Raees Khan has publicly supported actor Allu Arjun after his arrest connected to a fan's death during a stampede at the screening of Pushpa 2. She argues that crowd management is the responsibility of event organizers, not the actor.</p><ul><li>Sana Raees Khan claims Allu Arjun is not at fault for the tragic incident.</li><li>The lawyer emphasizes that event organizers, rather than actors, are responsible for crowd control.</li><li>Allu Arjun's interim bail suggests his arrest may not have been justified.</li><li>Sana stresses the need for professional event management and safety measures during public gatherings.</li><li>The incident involved a stampede that resulted in the death of a 35-year-old woman and injuries to her son.</li></ul><blockquote>Sana Raees Khan stated, "Blaming him for incidents beyond his control is unfair and sets a concerning example for the entertainment industry."</blockquote><p>The legal and societal implications of this incident highlight the importance of proper management at large events and protecting both fans and performers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/lawyer-sana-raees-khan-comes-out-in-support-of-allu-arjun-after-his-arrest-for-pushpa-2-stampede-holding-him-accountable-for-actions-/articleshow/116443571.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/lawyer-sana-raees-khan-comes-out-in-support-of-allu-arjun-after-his-arrest-for-pushpa-2-stampede-holding-him-accountable-for-actions-/articleshow/116443571.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ambedkar remarks: Shah should either step down or PM should sack him, says Congress chief - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Demands Amit Shah's Resignation Over Ambedkar Remarks</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> December 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/a7n4az/article69001558.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/5331_18_12_2024_18_41_28_2__DSC1852.JPG" alt="Congress president Mallikarjun Kharge addresses a press conference at the party headquarters in New Delhi on December 18, 2024." />
<figcaption>Congress president Mallikarjun Kharge addresses a press conference at the party headquarters in New Delhi on December 18, 2024.</figcaption>
<p>Congress president Mallikarjun Kharge has called for the resignation of Home Minister Amit Shah following controversial remarks made regarding B.R. Ambedkar.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kharge stated that PM Modi should remove Shah if he does not resign.</li>
    <li>The Congress party has intensified protests against Shah’s comments with demonstrations nationwide.</li>
    <li>Shah's remarks were perceived as disrespectful towards the architect of the Constitution, leading to widespread condemnation.</li>
    <li>Other political leaders, including Mamata Banerjee and M.K. Stalin, criticized Shah’s comments, labeling them casteist and anti-Dalit.</li>
    <li>Kharge demanded Shah apologize to the nation for what he termed an insult.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If there is no resignation, there will be protests all over the country.” – Mallikarjun Kharge</blockquote>
<p>The backlash continues to grow as political leaders unite against perceived disrespect for Ambedkar, with increasing calls for accountability within the government.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/ambedkar-remarks-kharge-demands-modi-sack-amit-shah-by-midnight/article69001398.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/ambedkar-remarks-kharge-demands-modi-sack-amit-shah-by-midnight/article69001398.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai boat accident: Video shows speedboat ramming Elephanta Cave ferry - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Boat Accident: Video Shows Speedboat Ramming Elephanta Cave Ferry</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/ANI-20241218391-0_1734532956512_1734532973343.jpg" alt="A boat carrying 85 passengers capsizes near the Gateway of India, in Mumbai on Wednesday.(Indian Coast Guard)"><figcaption>A boat carrying 85 passengers capsizes near the Gateway of India, in Mumbai on Wednesday.(Indian Coast Guard)</figcaption><p>A tragic ferry accident occurred in Mumbai where a speedboat collided with the Neelkamal ferry, resulting in multiple casualties and extensive rescue operations by the Indian Coast Guard.</p><ul><li>Two passengers confirmed dead, with total fatalities rising to 13 as search operations continue.</li><li>More than 80 individuals rescued by the Indian Coast Guard and Navy personnel.</li><li>The incident occurred when an Indian Navy craft lost control during engine trials.</li><li>The Neelkamal ferry was transporting 85 passengers to the Elephanta Caves.</li><li>Extensive search and rescue efforts involve multiple Navy and Coast Guard vessels, as well as helicopters.</li><li>Local authorities and fishermen assisted in rescue operations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Deeply saddened by the loss of precious lives in the collision... Extensive search & rescue efforts are ongoing.” - Defence Minister Rajnath Singh</blockquote><p>The tragedy highlights the importance of maritime safety regulations and the swift response of rescue teams in emergencies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/video-shows-the-moment-speed-boat-rammed-into-elephanta-cave-ferry-watch-101734531145025.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/video-shows-the-moment-speed-boat-rammed-into-elephanta-cave-ferry-watch-101734531145025.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:10:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[13 dead after ferry with over 100 passengers capsizes near Gateway of India in Mumbai; rescue operations - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>13 Dead After Ferry Capsizes Near Gateway of India in Mumbai</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>In a tragic incident, a ferry carrying over 100 passengers capsized near the Gateway of India in Mumbai, resulting in the deaths of 13 individuals. Rescue operations are currently underway to locate survivors and assist those in distress.</p><ul><li>Incident occurred near the Gateway of India, a popular tourist destination.</li><li>Over 100 passengers were on board the ferry at the time of the accident.</li><li>Rescue teams are actively involved in recovery efforts.</li><li>Authorities have initiated an investigation into the cause of the accident.</li></ul><blockquote>“The situation is dire, and we are doing everything possible to save lives.” - Local Official</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the need for improved safety measures in maritime transport, especially in densely populated tourist areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ferry-with-passengers-capsizes-near-gateway-of-india-in-mumbai-rescue-operations-underway/articleshow/116438808.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ferry-with-passengers-capsizes-near-gateway-of-india-in-mumbai-rescue-operations-underway/articleshow/116438808.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Aravind visits Pushpa 2 premiere stampede victim in hospital; says this about Allu Arjun's absence - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Aravind visits Pushpa 2 premiere stampede victim in hospital; remarks on Allu Arjun's absence</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/Allu_Aravind_1734529397031_1734529397535.jpg" alt="Allu Aravind, father of Allu Arjun, during a press conference at his residence, in Hyderabad.(PTI)"><figcaption>Allu Aravind, father of Allu Arjun, during a press conference at his residence, in Hyderabad.(PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>A tragic incident at the premiere of Pushpa 2: The Rule led to the death of a woman and her son's hospitalization due to a stampede. Allu Aravind visited the affected boy in the hospital and spoke about Allu Arjun's absence regarding the situation.</p><ul><li>A stampede occurred at the Pushpa 2 premiere, resulting in one death and a young boy hospitalized.</li><li>Allu Aravind visited the hospitalized boy and expressed support for his recovery.</li><li>Allu Arjun's absence at the hospital has raised questions; Aravind explained legal constraints preventing visitation.</li><li>Arjun is facing legal action related to the incident, having been arrested and later released on bail.</li></ul><blockquote>“I just visited Sri Tej in the ICU. The boy has been recovering slowly... We are ready to support in any way we can to help him recover.” - Allu Aravind</blockquote><p>The incident has sparked significant discussion regarding crowd safety and the responsibilities of public figures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/allu-aravind-visits-pushpa-2-premiere-stampede-victim-in-hospital-says-this-about-allu-arjuns-absence-101734528754078.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/allu-aravind-visits-pushpa-2-premiere-stampede-victim-in-hospital-says-this-about-allu-arjuns-absence-101734528754078.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:55:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi claims 2 Cong workers killed due to ‘excessive police force’ in UP, Assam - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rahul Gandhi claims Congress workers killed due to ‘excessive police force’ in UP, Assam</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/Prabhat_Pandey_and_Mridul_Islam_1734532287221_1734532287542.jpg" alt="Congress claimed its members Prabhat Pandey (left) and Mridul Islam died due to &quot;police force&quot; in UP and Assam respectively.(Rahul Gandhi/X)" title="Congress claimed its members Prabhat Pandey (left) and Mridul Islam died due to &quot;police force&quot; in UP and Assam respectively.(Rahul Gandhi/X)">
  <figcaption>Congress claimed its members Prabhat Pandey (left) and Mridul Islam died due to "police force" in UP and Assam respectively.(Rahul Gandhi/X)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Leader of opposition Rahul Gandhi alleged that two Congress workers died due to excessive police force during protests in Uttar Pradesh and Assam.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Prabhat Pandey and Mridul Islam were the deceased Congress workers.</li>
  <li>Gandhi condemned the actions of police and called for justice for the families of the victims.</li>
  <li>The Congress party was protesting against various issues including violence in Manipur.</li>
  <li>Police claimed no injurious actions occurred during the protests.</li>
  <li>Post-mortem examinations are pending to ascertain the exact causes of death.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I offer my deepest condolences to their grieving loved ones. These families deserve full justice.” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote>
<p>This incident raises concerns over police conduct during protests and highlights ongoing political tensions in the regions ruled by the BJP.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-claims-2-cong-workers-killed-due-to-excessive-police-force-in-up-assam-101734531507750.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-claims-2-cong-workers-killed-due-to-excessive-police-force-in-up-assam-101734531507750.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:55:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["When Rahul Dravid, Sachin Tendulkar Left...": Ashwin's Emotional 'Transition' Speech To Team India - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQWm1KQzFXaVJlOGJsQ0Zac1M5MzBUSm4zcFdSaktQUXNTcWJCN0NNdnMwX3poYTJPV1BhUk9oWFRMUTd0QlFVNnlqUnN2alQwZ1QxTlJOWU5jTkd4QTRQUHI1Q0pHbW9fdGRyTm9sdlVKNE9wTG9hZnNDTk9iQnhTdElYMFVhWEp4MnZzR0xzbWJKOUlrX1hsOXNaRXdLNjFjVWhOOGpSYW9HZGxuY0hHaDctNHFjRkZlWFVObGZZQjU0UDR4VllCWmRBdm1WUlV6dXhWcEtaQVZNeXRjaEYyRDln0gHqAUFVX3lxTE1HV1pmNFVLcTNUQWg2WXUzMURqdGRSTldHeXNPSGlzU2Zfb2d5ajlENzBHSElWT2JHd2FSUUJPTmpyZXlTUklYNUQwcGU4bWF5cnFMd09vdTBaV2ppTVdUWDRUQ2xTdVl5OElDaXQyY1M5WDFDLVNxUnlYNXUzNHR4RE41THhqaDhWeTVvbm9Ralp3V0k4dmYwVnVVdHo0WkxlejhoWF82azB4SVRVeFZyNW5ySkJIWlNYcVZTRzNucG1jNHBPTE5BNTdodWUzajJjbFpmeHB5WFNQVFlpMHJmMnp6U2RvYkxBUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQWm1KQzFXaVJlOGJsQ0Zac1M5MzBUSm4zcFdSaktQUXNTcWJCN0NNdnMwX3poYTJPV1BhUk9oWFRMUTd0QlFVNnlqUnN2alQwZ1QxTlJOWU5jTkd4QTRQUHI1Q0pHbW9fdGRyTm9sdlVKNE9wTG9hZnNDTk9iQnhTdElYMFVhWEp4MnZzR0xzbWJKOUlrX1hsOXNaRXdLNjFjVWhOOGpSYW9HZGxuY0hHaDctNHFjRkZlWFVObGZZQjU0UDR4VllCWmRBdm1WUlV6dXhWcEtaQVZNeXRjaEYyRDln0gHqAUFVX3lxTE1HV1pmNFVLcTNUQWg2WXUzMURqdGRSTldHeXNPSGlzU2Zfb2d5ajlENzBHSElWT2JHd2FSUUJPTmpyZXlTUklYNUQwcGU4bWF5cnFMd09vdTBaV2ppTVdUWDRUQ2xTdVl5OElDaXQyY1M5WDFDLVNxUnlYNXUzNHR4RE41THhqaDhWeTVvbm9Ralp3V0k4dmYwVnVVdHo0WkxlejhoWF82azB4SVRVeFZyNW5ySkJIWlNYcVZTRzNucG1jNHBPTE5BNTdodWUzajJjbFpmeHB5WFNQVFlpMHJmMnp6U2RvYkxBUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:41:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech wrap Dec 18: Samsung Galaxy Unpacked, Realme 14x 5G, JioTag Go, more - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-wrap-dec-18-samsung-galaxy-unpacked-realme-14x-5g-jiotag-go-more-124121800951_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-wrap-dec-18-samsung-galaxy-unpacked-realme-14x-5g-jiotag-go-more-124121800951_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravichandran Ashwin retirement reactions: Virat Kohli shares emotional note; ‘Had a long journey together since 2010,’ says Rohit Sharma - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravichandran Ashwin retirement reactions: Virat Kohli shares emotional note; ‘Had a long journey together since 2010,’ says Rohit Sharma</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/yf0am1/article69000204.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_18_2024_000091B.jpg" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin celebrates taking wickets." /><figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin celebrates after taking wickets during a match.</figcaption><p>Ravichandran Ashwin announced his retirement from international cricket on December 18, 2024, concluding an illustrious career. His retirement was met with emotional responses from teammates and cricketing legends.</p><ul><li>Ashwin announced his retirement following the third Test match of the Border-Gavaskar series.</li><li>He is the second highest wicket-taker from India with 765 wickets, achieving significant milestones throughout his career.</li><li>Teammates like Rohit Sharma and Virat Kohli expressed their heartfelt emotions and gratitude during this momentous occasion.</li></ul><blockquote>“What a career he had.” - Pravin Amre</blockquote><p>The cricketing community has celebrated Ashwin’s achievements while expressing sadness at his departure from the sport.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sport/ravichandran-ashwin-retirement-indian-spinner-live-updates-december-18-2024/article68999215.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sport/ravichandran-ashwin-retirement-indian-spinner-live-updates-december-18-2024/article68999215.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Corruption case against ex-French President Nicolas Sarkozy upheld by country’s highest court - CNN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/18/europe/france-sarkozy-corruption-case-upheld-intl/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/18/europe/france-sarkozy-corruption-case-upheld-intl/index.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India’s Record Gold Import Said to Be Due to Calculation Error - Bloomberg]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=1487eaf1-bd5d-11ef-affe-b7048f6da64f&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAyNC0xMi0xOC9pbmRpYS1zLXJlY29yZC1nb2xkLWltcG9ydC1zYWlkLXRvLWJlLWR1ZS10by1jYWxjdWxhdGlvbi1lcnJvcg==</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=1487eaf1-bd5d-11ef-affe-b7048f6da64f&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAyNC0xMi0xOC9pbmRpYS1zLXJlY29yZC1nb2xkLWltcG9ydC1zYWlkLXRvLWJlLWR1ZS10by1jYWxjdWxhdGlvbi1lcnJvcg==</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:09:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Lack of trust with West': Russia pursuing stronger ties with India - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia Strengthens Ties with India Amidst Lack of Trust with West</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> News Outlet</p><p>In the face of deteriorating relations with Western nations, Russia is actively seeking to bolster its diplomatic and economic ties with India. This shift reflects a strategic pivot aimed at fostering stronger partnerships beyond the traditional West-centric alliances.</p><ul><li>Russia's dissatisfaction with Western sanctions and criticism has prompted a search for reliable partners.</li><li>Trade deals and military cooperation are significant aspects of the growing relationship with India.</li><li>India's non-aligned stance aligns with Russia's desire to engage nations that prioritize sovereignty.</li></ul><blockquote>“This cooperation is essential for both nations to counter Western influence,” a diplomatic source remarked.</blockquote><p>The evolving Russia-India relationship signals a significant geopolitical shift, with both nations looking to enhance their influence in a multipolar world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/lack-of-trust-with-west-russia-pursuing-stronger-ties-with-india/articleshow/116441422.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/lack-of-trust-with-west-russia-pursuing-stronger-ties-with-india/articleshow/116441422.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament session LIVE: 'Congress distorting facts,' says Amit Shah on Ambedkar remark row - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament session LIVE: 'Congress distorting facts,' says Amit Shah on Ambedkar remark row</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>December 18, 2024 | <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/Shah_presser_1734523675355_1734523687762.png" alt="Parliament session LIVE: Amit Shah addresses press conference" title="Parliament session LIVE: Amit Shah addresses press conference" width="360" height="202" loading="lazy" decoding="async"><figcaption>Parliament session LIVE: Amit Shah addresses press conference</figcaption></div><p>The Congress party has strongly criticized Union Home Minister Amit Shah for his comments regarding Dr. BR Ambedkar, demanding an apology amid ongoing tensions in Parliament.</p><ul><li>The Winter Session of Parliament is nearing its end, concluding on December 20, with multiple bills on the agenda.</li><li>Amit Shah accused Congress of distorting facts and misrepresenting his comments on Ambedkar during recent debates.</li><li>Shah emphasized that he had praised Ambedkar's contributions while alleging that the Congress party has historically insulted him.</li><li>Opposition members have called for Shah's resignation over his remarks, prompting protests.</li><li>Shah declared that the uproar is an attempt by Congress to deflect attention from its electoral failures.</li></ul><blockquote>“The people who denied Babasaheb Ambedkar are the ones trying to protest in his name,” Amit Shah stated.</blockquote><p>As the session unfolds, tensions escalate, with Congress leaders continuing their demands for accountability from the BJP.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-session-live-rajya-sabha-lok-sabha-amit-shah-one-nation-one-election-bill-latest-updates-today-december-18-101734492559242.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-session-live-rajya-sabha-lok-sabha-amit-shah-one-nation-one-election-bill-latest-updates-today-december-18-101734492559242.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 13:46:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2 dead after ferry with passengers capsizes near Gateway of India in Mumbai; rescue operations underway - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ferry Capsizes Near Gateway of India, Resulting in Two Fatalities</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> <em>October 24, 2023</em> | <strong>Source:</strong> <em>Times of India</em></p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Ferry capsizing" />
<figcaption>Ferry capsizing near Gateway of India.</figcaption>
<p>A tragic incident occurred when a ferry with passengers capsized near the Gateway of India in Mumbai, leading to the death of two individuals. Rescue operations are currently underway to assist any survivors.</p>
<ul>
<li>The incident took place in the afternoon, and the ferry was reportedly overloaded.</li>
<li>Emergency services and local authorities swiftly initiated a rescue operation.</li>
<li>Witnesses described scenes of panic and chaos as the ferry capsized.</li>
<li>Authorities are investigating the cause of the incident.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We are doing everything we can to rescue those who are still unaccounted for,” said a local official.</blockquote>
<p>This incident has sparked discussions about safety regulations for passenger ferries in Mumbai.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ferry-with-passengers-capsizes-near-gateway-of-india-in-mumbai-rescue-operations-underway/articleshow/116438808.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ferry-with-passengers-capsizes-near-gateway-of-india-in-mumbai-rescue-operations-underway/articleshow/116438808.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My words twisted; Congress anti-Ambedkar, anti-Constitution, says Amit Shah - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxPa1l6RXBGVjV4VmFuV3lMQkJCaTljZkc1cV9QSjhCVU44bVBOdWp2VmpfUmFpWl9JNTFCNUFFN0dPRGd3NU5MZkhDVC1Ja3M2WTh6d2lDcWhNUXBEcS1jVXFCS3BYYmV6OUhZVHFBaTdmZDZabHdBQlJpTWZNOEdzbHVwNmxycVZhOE9KYnl6d1E4Y3VyaHNKaDFSSzF1OXhVb0oxM0tBdlJyTWthWlliRlJXZk1sb3BHSEJBWklTWGMzVHpBUmhNR2w3YTYxekRJQ0x2MHFyc25IbVVxZGfSAeQBQVVfeXFMUGlBSlI2Ry1Ia3lYS3JfMHU4bmI2TlZyaXgyVGFaeTVBdHZtcW9TaVhuX1FXeHlVZ1NUV1NkTnhybVhxVHFkTjUzU3pFdWJSQlpoUFFLQmktRF83bUpDOVlMX2wzN3MxWGZzYmpaMllsRGdkeEVEeXBKblNDczc0QlI4OGhrN080dzhrdlFDT3RlZGN3cDJkTUVTZnBOdHVkWjNpVjEyNzc3eEdxYlo5TTVaeFFEbmVWWGtRVUtmbmxDSWw4RTBaY1BsNENWZHd0am9QS0xxOVFoazhvNDlTQkwzMF9r?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxPa1l6RXBGVjV4VmFuV3lMQkJCaTljZkc1cV9QSjhCVU44bVBOdWp2VmpfUmFpWl9JNTFCNUFFN0dPRGd3NU5MZkhDVC1Ja3M2WTh6d2lDcWhNUXBEcS1jVXFCS3BYYmV6OUhZVHFBaTdmZDZabHdBQlJpTWZNOEdzbHVwNmxycVZhOE9KYnl6d1E4Y3VyaHNKaDFSSzF1OXhVb0oxM0tBdlJyTWthWlliRlJXZk1sb3BHSEJBWklTWGMzVHpBUmhNR2w3YTYxekRJQ0x2MHFyc25IbVVxZGfSAeQBQVVfeXFMUGlBSlI2Ry1Ia3lYS3JfMHU4bmI2TlZyaXgyVGFaeTVBdHZtcW9TaVhuX1FXeHlVZ1NUV1NkTnhybVhxVHFkTjUzU3pFdWJSQlpoUFFLQmktRF83bUpDOVlMX2wzN3MxWGZzYmpaMllsRGdkeEVEeXBKblNDczc0QlI4OGhrN080dzhrdlFDT3RlZGN3cDJkTUVTZnBOdHVkWjNpVjEyNzc3eEdxYlo5TTVaeFFEbmVWWGtRVUtmbmxDSWw4RTBaY1BsNENWZHd0am9QS0xxOVFoazhvNDlTQkwzMF9r?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blockbuster market debut: Mobikwik shares close with 89% gains; Vishal Mega Mart, Sai Life rally around... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/ipo/blockbuster-market-debut-mobikwik-shares-close-with-89-gains-vishal-mega-mart-sai-life-rally-around-40-12893135.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/ipo/blockbuster-market-debut-mobikwik-shares-close-with-89-gains-vishal-mega-mart-sai-life-rally-around-40-12893135.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:56:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyderabad YouTuber Prasad Behara held for sexually harassing co-actor - The Siasat Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hyderabad YouTuber Prasad Behara held for sexually harassing co-actor</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 18, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Siasat Daily</strong></p>
<figure>
  <img fetchpriority="high" src="https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Prasad-Behara-780x470.jpg" alt="Hyderabad YouTuber Prasad Behara held for sexually harassing co-actor" width="1200" height="900">
  <figcaption>Hyderabad YouTuber Prasad Behara held for sexually harassing co-actor</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A popular YouTuber Prasad Behara was arrested by the Jubilee Hills police on charges of sexual harassment after a co-actor accused him of inappropriate behavior during filming.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Prasad was accused of touching the victim inappropriately during the shooting of the web series Pellivaramandi.</li>
  <li>The victim withdrew from the series but later worked with him on another project, Mechanic, where harassment allegedly continued.</li>
  <li>The victim reported explicit remarks and further inappropriate physical contact during the Mechanic shoot.</li>
  <li>On December 11, the situation escalated with an alleged attack by Prasad during filming.</li>
  <li>A complaint was filed with the Jubilee Hills police, leading to Prasad's arrest and judicial custody for 14 days.</li>
  <li>A case has been registered under sections 75(2), 79, 351(2) of BNS.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The harassment continued during the Mechanic shoot, with unwelcome comments and physical contact reported by the victim."</blockquote>
<p>Further investigation is ongoing as the case draws public attention to issues of harassment in the entertainment industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.siasat.com/hyderabad-youtuber-prasad-behara-held-for-sexually-harassing-co-actor-3150264/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.siasat.com/hyderabad-youtuber-prasad-behara-held-for-sexually-harassing-co-actor-3150264/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shahid Kapoor, Kriti Sanon to reunite for the 2nd time in Homi Adajania's Cocktail 2: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shahid Kapoor, Kriti Sanon to reunite for the 2nd time in Homi Adajania's Cocktail 2: Report</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/Teri_Baaton_Mein_Aisa_Uljha_Jiya_1707613416052_1734523432738.jpg" alt="Kriti Sanon and Shahid Kapoor had previously worked together in Teri Baaton Mein Aisa Uljha Jiya." title="Kriti Sanon and Shahid Kapoor had previously worked together in Teri Baaton Mein Aisa Uljha Jiya.">
<figcaption>Kriti Sanon and Shahid Kapoor had previously worked together in Teri Baaton Mein Aisa Uljha Jiya.</figcaption>
<p>A sequel to the 2012 film Cocktail is reportedly underway, with Shahid Kapoor and Kriti Sanon reuniting for the project directed by Homi Adajania.</p>
<ul>
<li>The sequel will be based on a story written by Luv Ranjan.</li>
<li>Dinesh Vijan is set to produce the film.</li>
<li>The film will feature a love triangle and is in search of another female lead.</li>
<li>Shahid and Kriti expressed excitement about the script after their previous collaboration in Teri Baaton Mein Aisa Uljha Jiya.</li>
<li>The casting process is ongoing, with filming expected to start in May 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“After the success of Teri Baaton Mein Aisa Uljha Jiya, Shahid Kapoor and Kriti Sanon are reuniting on Cocktail 2. The duo loved the script and are excited to venture into the world of this romantic comedy,” a source has shared.</blockquote>
<p>This upcoming sequel aims to capture the charm and intrigue established in the original film, which was a significant success upon its release.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/shahid-kapoor-kriti-sanon-to-reunite-for-the-2nd-time-in-homi-adajanias-cocktail-2-report-101734522887535.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/shahid-kapoor-kriti-sanon-to-reunite-for-the-2nd-time-in-homi-adajanias-cocktail-2-report-101734522887535.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:40:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal announces new health scheme for Delhi's elderly population - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Introduces Health Scheme for Elderly in Delhi Ahead of Elections</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/PTI12-16-2024-000399B-0_1734513128237_1734513186089.jpg" alt="Former Delhi CM and AAP national convener Arvind Kejriwal with supporters during his padyatra in Badarpur area ahead of the Delhi Assembly elections, in New Delhi.(PTI)"><figcaption>Former Delhi CM and AAP national convener Arvind Kejriwal with supporters during his padyatra in Badarpur area ahead of the Delhi Assembly elections, in New Delhi.(PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>Arvind Kejriwal, the national convener of the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP), announced a new health scheme called 'Sanjeevani Yojana' for elderly citizens in Delhi, promising free treatment in government and private hospitals.</p><ul><li>The scheme is aimed at citizens over 60 years old.</li><li>There will be no upper limit on the cost of treatment.</li><li>Registration will begin shortly with AAP workers assisting at home.</li><li>The scheme will be implemented once AAP wins the upcoming elections.</li></ul><blockquote>“There are a lot of errors in the central government's scheme and Delhi government has launched a better scheme correcting those errors,” said Delhi Minister Saurabh Bhardwaj.</blockquote><p>This announcement follows a face-off with the BJP regarding the implementation of the Central government's Aayushmaan Bharat scheme.</p><p>In conclusion, this move is part of AAP's strategy to capitalize on healthcare issues ahead of elections, promising enhanced support for seniors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/kejriwal-announces-new-health-scheme-for-delhis-elderly-ahead-of-election-101734511576454.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/kejriwal-announces-new-health-scheme-for-delhis-elderly-ahead-of-election-101734511576454.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:25:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foxconn has discussed making bid for Nissan | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPSFM4WUxWQUUyc0pXbGJYWmJLenQwMjE4a09kQUJCa0hSbXkxcXRHaDNxcXI5dEZnUWw1aW5RYTU1ejM1RXRNNDJfNENyR0llS2JGbDQ1MEcyemdSQzhieGdZLUl6R2twOW12OVpHdlZ4TnpkaElnMzBIeTNPV19tdUh1dWVBby1ZZWVFYl8wNXQzWFFGVUEtZmNUaklNczB5MzZQX3JR0gGrAUFVX3lxTE5JVDJaSHpkaEJMcm8zTGlIREVpUnlidks3MTE2MDlmQk1lWTJPcE45T3pXR0ZpcS1EX2J2clFFM1JEb2NkOUFvcTJWeWVHdml0bENXakFwWko4dFNSSWprSURrTlVIS3g3SHE0OWRfZDk0b1hiOGxybHZneV9RSFVnX0c0VWtEczV3OXFWV3JoOGpsUS1sMFJ5OG0zWVlRbThIczZ0MEJ5V2pMYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPSFM4WUxWQUUyc0pXbGJYWmJLenQwMjE4a09kQUJCa0hSbXkxcXRHaDNxcXI5dEZnUWw1aW5RYTU1ejM1RXRNNDJfNENyR0llS2JGbDQ1MEcyemdSQzhieGdZLUl6R2twOW12OVpHdlZ4TnpkaElnMzBIeTNPV19tdUh1dWVBby1ZZWVFYl8wNXQzWFFGVUEtZmNUaklNczB5MzZQX3JR0gGrAUFVX3lxTE5JVDJaSHpkaEJMcm8zTGlIREVpUnlidks3MTE2MDlmQk1lWTJPcE45T3pXR0ZpcS1EX2J2clFFM1JEb2NkOUFvcTJWeWVHdml0bENXakFwWko4dFNSSWprSURrTlVIS3g3SHE0OWRfZDk0b1hiOGxybHZneV9RSFVnX0c0VWtEczV3OXFWV3JoOGpsUS1sMFJ5OG0zWVlRbThIczZ0MEJ5V2pMYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:25:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA schedules return of Starliner crew in March - Daily Excelsior]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxQU2tXVzVudUh4Xy1wM2w1S1ltanZxTWt5WUpWZVVtRkFuM3R3NzJvWnc1czF5M01lNnlzNENNeUNGMzA1aDA2ZDk5SFZEWEItdDlQdUZfNi10WFo2RVhwSnRnRE1QUGdnb3RyeFFOZ1o1NnEzOFFoeHJ4cmhrZHdJS0RxSmIyQ1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxQU2tXVzVudUh4Xy1wM2w1S1ltanZxTWt5WUpWZVVtRkFuM3R3NzJvWnc1czF5M01lNnlzNENNeUNGMzA1aDA2ZDk5SFZEWEItdDlQdUZfNi10WFo2RVhwSnRnRE1QUGdnb3RyeFFOZ1o1NnEzOFFoeHJ4cmhrZHdJS0RxSmIyQ1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:09:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More than 500 species infected, 300 billion birds dead due to avian flu H5N1: WHO - Down To Earth Magazine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Over 500 Species Infected and 300 Billion Birds Dead from H5N1: WHO Warns</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 18 Dec 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> World Health Organization</p><p>The Highly Pathogenic Avian Influenza (HPAI) H5N1 has infected over 500 species and led to over 300 billion bird deaths globally. The UN has reported that the virus poses significant risks to both wildlife and human livelihoods, particularly in poultry-dependent regions.</p><ul><li>HPAI H5N1 has spread to 108 countries and has infected numerous wildlife species.</li><li>The virus poses a threat to food security and livelihoods, especially for poultry farmers.</li><li>Seventy-six human cases of H5N1 have been reported in 2024, primarily among farm workers.</li><li>The WHO urges increased surveillance and preventive measures regarding the virus.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no evidence so far that the H5N1 viruses have adapted to spread between people,” said Maria Van Kerkhove, WHO.</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the need for a multi-sectoral approach to address avian influenza's spread.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/health/more-than-500-species-infected-300-billion-birds-dead-due-to-avian-flu-h5n1-who</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.downtoearth.org.in/health/more-than-500-species-infected-300-billion-birds-dead-due-to-avian-flu-h5n1-who</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>