<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Headlines Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 07:16:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Headlines.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 07:16:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court Pauses High Court Order Over Ayushman Bharat Scheme In Delhi - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Pauses High Court Order Over Ayushman Bharat Scheme In Delhi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified; <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>The Supreme Court has temporarily halted a Delhi High Court ruling that mandated the Delhi government to execute a Memorandum of Understanding to facilitate the implementation of the Ayushman Bharat Health Infrastructure Mission (PM-ABHIM) scheme.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court issued notices to the central government, AIIMS, and the Municipal Corporation of Delhi in response to a petition from the Delhi government against the High Court ruling.</li><li>Last month, the Delhi High Court ordered the MoU to be signed by January 5.</li><li>The AAP government argues against the scheme, claiming that Delhi has better benefits under its own health schemes.</li><li>This issue could escalate political tensions between the BJP and AAP ahead of crucial government elections in the city.</li><li>The Delhi government's counsel contends that signing the MoU would overstep the central government’s authority regarding health policy.</li></ul><blockquote>The High Court stated, “Not implementing the ABHIM Scheme in Delhi would not be justified since 33 States and UTs have already implemented it.”</blockquote><p>This development highlights ongoing political friction regarding health policy and governance between the central and Delhi state authorities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/supreme-court-pauses-high-court-order-over-ayushman-bharat-implementation-in-delhi-7493738</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/supreme-court-pauses-high-court-order-over-ayushman-bharat-implementation-in-delhi-7493738</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:53:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Great Republic Day sale: "Blockbuster deals” on laptops with Intel processors and minimum... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amazon Great Republic Day Sale Offers Blockbuster Deals on Laptops</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 / 12:21 IST</p>
<p>Amazon's first major sale of the year features significant discounts on laptops, particularly those with Intel processors and a minimum of 8GB RAM. Here are the top 5 deals highlighted.</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250117065115_Amazon-sale.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Amazon sale" title="Amazon sale" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>Amazon Sale Promotion</figcaption>
<ul>
    <li><strong>HP 15 with Intel Core i5 processor:</strong> Available at Rs 41,490, featuring 16GB RAM and 512GB storage.</li>
    <li><strong>Lenovo Slim3 with Intel Core i7 processor:</strong> Now priced at Rs 57,240 with 16GB RAM and 512GB SSD.</li>
    <li><strong>Asus VivoBook with Intel Core i5 processor:</strong> Offered at Rs 43,740, includes 16GB RAM and 512GB storage.</li>
    <li><strong>Dell 15 with Intel Core i3 processor:</strong> Available for Rs 27,990, comes with a free antivirus program.</li>
    <li><strong>Lenovo Ideapad with Ultra 9 processor:</strong> Priced at Rs 92,740, features 32GB RAM and 1TB SSD.</li>
</ul>
<p>This sale presents a great opportunity for customers looking to purchase high-quality laptops at reduced prices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-blockbuster-deals-on-laptops-with-intel-processors-and-minimum-8gb-ram-article-12913091.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-blockbuster-deals-on-laptops-with-intel-processors-and-minimum-8gb-ram-article-12913091.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:51:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Consulate inaugurated in Bengaluru, visa services to start soon, says Eric Garcetti - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Consulate inaugurated in Bengaluru, visa services to start soon, says Eric Garcetti</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/GheUSI3XIAA3Q8D_1737094774846_1737094780500.jpg" alt="External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar and US Ambassador Eric Garcetti lead the inauguration ceremony.(X/Tejasvi Surya)" /><figcaption>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar and US Ambassador Eric Garcetti lead the inauguration ceremony.(X/Tejasvi Surya)</figcaption><p>The United States has officially inaugurated its consulate in Bengaluru with plans to start visa services soon. This was marked by a ceremony led by External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar and US Ambassador Eric Garcetti.</p><ul><li>The consulate will initially operate from a temporary location at the JW Marriott Hotel.</li><li>Jaishankar emphasized the importance of having a permanent US diplomatic presence in Bengaluru.</li><li>Karnataka Deputy Chief Minister DK Shivakumar called the opening a significant event.</li><li>BJP MP Tejasvi Surya noted the consulate's importance for local residents.</li><li>Garcetti confirmed that visa services will commence in the future.</li></ul><blockquote>“It has been something long in waiting...” - S Jaishankar</blockquote><p>The establishment of the consulate underscores Bengaluru's global importance, with a commitment from the US to enhance its diplomatic presence in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/bengaluru-news/us-consulate-inaugurated-in-bengaluru-visa-services-to-start-soon-says-eric-garcetti-101737094163389.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/bengaluru-news/us-consulate-inaugurated-in-bengaluru-visa-services-to-start-soon-says-eric-garcetti-101737094163389.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:23:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stargazers in Hyderabad, don’t miss this rare chance to spot 4 planets in the night sky - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPQzZ6N2RyRzJaNGtVM096Nnd4ekNYT0pJS3RPLXdjRVAyVUZyWDd0a3VsX0NoSTZIQjNRcE9aRzVKYnpGbWZKZ19pUlFtOFFfaDNHcUFyUVAxMkI3TTdNYy1MdkotTnhIdHhlX1pGZVRON01BSUxBc1dWZG00bm13elhWSld2N1F4cVJ5WWVxdE5jdmxHUWktUlBjX3l5S2NRc3lmNHM5TThqYkwwQWZpdnZn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPQzZ6N2RyRzJaNGtVM096Nnd4ekNYT0pJS3RPLXdjRVAyVUZyWDd0a3VsX0NoSTZIQjNRcE9aRzVKYnpGbWZKZ19pUlFtOFFfaDNHcUFyUVAxMkI3TTdNYy1MdkotTnhIdHhlX1pGZVRON01BSUxBc1dWZG00bm13elhWSld2N1F4cVJ5WWVxdE5jdmxHUWktUlBjX3l5S2NRc3lmNHM5TThqYkwwQWZpdnZn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:13:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Star's Champions Trophy Spot In Danger As Domestic Cricket Absence Angers BCCI: Report - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sanju Samson's Absence from Domestic Cricket Raises Concerns Ahead of Champions Trophy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/4i9gjk_sc_625x300_17_January_25.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="India Star's Domestic Cricket Absence Angers BCCI Ahead Of Champions Trophy: "Spends Time In Dubai...""><figcaption>File photo of Indian cricket team © AFP</figcaption><p>Sanju Samson's decision to skip the Vijay Hazare Trophy for Kerala may jeopardize his selection for the Champions Trophy. The BCCI emphasizes the importance of domestic cricket for national players, and Samson's absence has led to discontent among selectors.</p><ul><li>Sanju Samson's non-participation in the Vijay Hazare Trophy could cost him a spot in the Champions Trophy.</li><li>BCCI has clearly stated that players must participate in domestic competitions to be eligible for international selection.</li><li>Samson has faced issues with his state team, the Kerala Cricket Association, which may hinder his domestic play.</li><li>The current leading wicket-keeping options for the Champions Trophy are Rishabh Pant and Dhruv Jurel, with Samson trailing behind.</li><li>Selectors are looking for valid reasons for Samson's absence, which remains unclear.</li></ul><blockquote>“The selectors would want a valid reason. Otherwise, it will be difficult to consider him for the ODI season.” - BCCI sources</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the tension between individual choices and team obligations in professional sports, especially in cricket where domestic performance heavily influences national selection.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/india-stars-champions-trophy-spot-in-danger-as-domestic-cricket-absence-angers-bcci-report-7493440</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/india-stars-champions-trophy-spot-in-danger-as-domestic-cricket-absence-angers-bcci-report-7493440</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:13:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Realme to supercharge smartphone design with 300% boost to ID talent, 450% R&D investment in 2025 | Exclusive - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Realme to Boost Smartphone Design and R&D Investments by 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> financialexpress.com</p><figure><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="800" height="533" src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Sky-Li-2.jpg" alt="Sky Li - Founder and CEO of Realme"><figcaption>Sky Li – Founder and CEO of Realme</figcaption></figure><p>Realme's founder and CEO, Sky Li, discusses the company's ambitious plans for 2025, including a 450% increase in R&D investment and a 300% boost in Industrial Design talent. The Realme 14 Pro series, aimed at tech-savvy youth, focuses on innovation, design aesthetics, and advanced camera capabilities.</p><ul><li>The target market for the Realme 14 Pro series consists of young adults valuing innovation and performance.</li><li>Realme aims to enhance user experience with India-specific software and colour variants.</li><li>Notable growth in 2024 included an 117% rise in Western Europe and 281% in Latin America.</li><li>The 14 Pro series focuses on high-performance features like advanced camera technology and impressive battery life.</li><li>Significant investment in quad-curved display technology emphasizing user experience.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“India remains a key pillar of our success, where we [have] reinforced our position as the most popular smartphone brand among the youth.” - Sky Li</p></blockquote><p>The Realme 14 Pro series showcases the company’s focus on innovation, targeting an expansion in both local and global markets. Their commitment to R&D will significantly influence future smartphone design and user experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-realme-to-supercharge-smartphone-design-with-300-boost-to-id-talent-450-rampd-investment-in-2025-exclusive-3717823/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-realme-to-supercharge-smartphone-design-with-300-boost-to-id-talent-450-rampd-investment-in-2025-exclusive-3717823/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:58:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli had a neck sprain, participation in Ranji Trophy 'subject to availability' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli's Neck Sprain: Ranji Trophy Participation Uncertain</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p><p>Indian cricket star Virat Kohli has suffered a neck sprain, raising doubts about his availability for the upcoming Ranji Trophy matches.</p><ul><li>Kohli's injury could affect his participation in the Ranji Trophy.</li><li>The BCCI will assess his condition before the selection.</li><li>This injury comes at a crucial time for Kohli and the Indian team.</li></ul><blockquote>“His participation will depend on his recovery and fitness levels,” said a source.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Kohli's injury is a concern for both him and the cricketing community as they await updates on his fitness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/virat-kohli-had-a-neck-sprain-participation-in-ranji-trophy-subject-to-availability/articleshow/117321685.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/virat-kohli-had-a-neck-sprain-participation-in-ranji-trophy-subject-to-availability/articleshow/117321685.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shraddha Kapoor confirms relationship with Rahul Mody? Rumoured love birds twin in matching outfits in cute pic - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shraddha Kapoor Confirms Relationship with Rahul Mody</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/ssss_1737090857181_1737090880461.jpg" alt="Shraddha Kapoor shares cute picture with rumoured boyfriend Rahul Mody." title="Shraddha Kapoor shares cute picture with rumoured boyfriend Rahul Mody.">
<figcaption>Shraddha Kapoor shares cute picture with rumoured boyfriend Rahul Mody.</figcaption>
<p>Shraddha Kapoor is making headlines for sharing a cute matching outfits picture with her rumored boyfriend, Rahul Mody, on Instagram, further fueling their relationship rumors.</p>
<ul>
<li>Shraddha Kapoor shared a photo with Rahul Mody in matching night dresses on Instagram.</li>
<li>They were seen twinning, although only their lower bodies were visible.</li>
<li>Shraddha previously shared a picture enjoying a vada pav date with Rahul, putting split rumors to rest.</li>
<li>The couple was recently spotted together in Mumbai after a dinner date.</li>
<li>Shraddha has a successful film, Stree 2, and is set to star in Nagin.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“May I always bully you into taking me for vada pav,” said Shraddha Kapoor in her social media post.</blockquote>
<p>This adorable post has only added to the excitement surrounding Shraddha Kapoor's personal life and upcoming projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shraddha-kapoor-confirms-relationship-with-rahul-mody-rumoured-love-birds-twin-in-matching-outfits-in-cute-pic-101737087478545.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/shraddha-kapoor-confirms-relationship-with-rahul-mody-rumoured-love-birds-twin-in-matching-outfits-in-cute-pic-101737087478545.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:39:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R.G. Kar doctor case: Court to pronounce judgement on rape-murder on January 18 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rg-kar-doctor-case-court-to-pronounce-judgement-in-rape-murder-on-january-18/article69107613.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rg-kar-doctor-case-court-to-pronounce-judgement-in-rape-murder-on-january-18/article69107613.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TikTok ban: Biden hands over Chinese app's fate to Trump before White House exit - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Hands Over TikTok's Fate to Trump Ahead of Exit</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/USA-BIDEN-TRUMP-0_1737091248514_1737091287126.JPG" alt="President Joe Biden will not enforce a law banning TikTok as he's passed on the app's fate to President-elect Donald Trump, who takes office in a few days. (REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque)" title="President Joe Biden will not enforce a law banning TikTok as he's passed on the app's fate to President-elect Donald Trump, who takes office in a few days. (REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque)"><figcaption>President Joe Biden will not enforce a law banning TikTok as he's passed on the app's fate to President-elect Donald Trump, who takes office in a few days. (REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque)</figcaption><p>As President Biden prepares to leave office, he will not enforce a TikTok ban enacted by Congress, transferring the decision to President-elect Trump, who has previously expressed both support and opposition to the app.</p><ul><li>Biden will not enforce the upcoming TikTok ban before his departure.</li><li>The law requires TikTok's parent company, ByteDance, to divest by January 19.</li><li>Trump's administration may work to extend the deadline for a potential deal.</li><li>Senate leaders showed bipartisan support for extending the deadline to avoid disruption for users.</li><li>The Supreme Court is considering a legal challenge to the TikTok ban.</li></ul><blockquote>Chuck Schumer stated, “It’s clear that more time is needed to find an American buyer and not disrupt the lives and livelihoods of millions of Americans.”</blockquote><p>As TikTok's future remains uncertain, it will be crucial to watch how the new administration handles the app's potential ban and its implications for users and the digital landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/tiktok-ban-biden-hands-over-chinese-apps-fate-to-trump-before-white-house-exit-101737090464497.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/tiktok-ban-biden-hands-over-chinese-apps-fate-to-trump-before-white-house-exit-101737090464497.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:23:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan fans angry over mean jokes and memes on actor's stabbing, ask trolls to ‘have some shame' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/saif-ali-khan-fans-angry-over-mean-jokes-on-actor-stabbing-ask-trolls-to-have-some-shame-101737087695284.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/saif-ali-khan-fans-angry-over-mean-jokes-on-actor-stabbing-ask-trolls-to-have-some-shame-101737087695284.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 05:00:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['India cricketers to cover notebooks with brown paper', '11th point is ban YouTube': BCCI diktat gives free run to memes - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Implements Strict Guidelines for Indian Cricketers Post-Trophy Loss</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/TOPSHOT-CRICKET-AUS-IND-7_1737087673969_1737087686141.jpg" alt="BCCI's guidelines for Indian cricketers" title="BCCI's guidelines for Indian cricketers"><figcaption>The Border-Gavaskar Trophy loss against Australia has resulted in the BCCI taking harsh action to bring Team India back on track. (Photo by DAVID GRAY / AFP)(AFP)</figcaption><p>The Border-Gavaskar Trophy loss against Australia has prompted the BCCI to take strict actions aimed at restoring Team India’s performance. Following a review meeting with coaches and key players, the board has established new guidelines for centrally contracted players.</p><ul><li>Mandatory participation in domestic tournaments for selection.</li><li>Restrictions on family travel and personal baggage during tours.</li><li>Prohibition of personal endorsements and shoots during series.</li><li>Disciplinary action for non-compliance, including bans from tournaments.</li><li>Mandatory use of the team bus on match days, regardless of family presence.</li><li>Ban on personal chefs, security, and stylists during tours.</li></ul><blockquote>“These guidelines have been issued to promote discipline, unity, and a positive team environment.” - BCCI Statement</blockquote><p>The changes have led to a wave of memes on social media, with many poking fun at the BCCI's approach, likening it to running a school.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-cricketers-to-cover-notebooks-with-brown-paper-11th-point-is-ban-youtube-bcci-diktat-gives-free-run-to-memes-101737087223288.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-cricketers-to-cover-notebooks-with-brown-paper-11th-point-is-ban-youtube-bcci-diktat-gives-free-run-to-memes-101737087223288.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 04:31:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four dead, 15 injured after bus collides with lorry in Andhra Pradesh's Chittoor - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/vijayawada/several-injured-after-bus-collides-with-lorry-in-andhra-pradeshs-chittoor/articleshow/117319211.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/vijayawada/several-injured-after-bus-collides-with-lorry-in-andhra-pradeshs-chittoor/articleshow/117319211.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 04:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four dead, 15 injured after bus collides with lorry in Andhra Pradesh's Chittoor - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/vijayawada/several-injured-after-bus-collides-with-lorry-in-andhra-pradeshs-chittoor/articleshow/117319211.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/vijayawada/several-injured-after-bus-collides-with-lorry-in-andhra-pradeshs-chittoor/articleshow/117319211.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 04:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai News Live Updates: Saif Ali Khan’s survival a narrow escape, knife missed spine by millimetre, reveals doctor - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/mumbai-news-live-updates-actor-saif-ali-khan-attack-9781447/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/mumbai-news-live-updates-actor-saif-ali-khan-attack-9781447/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 04:09:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai News Live Updates: Saif Ali Khan’s survival a narrow escape, knife missed spine by millimetre, reveals doctor - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/mumbai-news-live-updates-actor-saif-ali-khan-attack-9781447/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/mumbai-news-live-updates-actor-saif-ali-khan-attack-9781447/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 04:09:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Lionel Messi came, Kylian Mbappé was a little jealous': Neymar spills secrets of PSG days - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Neymar Reveals Secrets from PSG Days Involving Messi and Mbappé</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>Neymar shares anecdotes from his time at Paris Saint-Germain, discussing the dynamics between himself, Lionel Messi, and Kylian Mbappé.</p><ul><li>Neymar describes Messi's arrival at PSG and the impact it had on the team.</li><li>He mentions moments that hinted at jealousy from Mbappé regarding Messi's status.</li><li>The interview provides insights into the relationships formed between the star players.</li></ul><blockquote>Neymar stated, "Lionel Messi came, Kylian Mbappé was a little jealous."</blockquote><p>This retrospective on Neymar's time at PSG offers fans a glimpse into the locker room atmosphere and the interplay between three of football's biggest stars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/football/top-stories/lionel-messi-came-kylian-mbapp-was-a-little-jealous-neymar-spills-secrets-of-psg-days/articleshow/117318397.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/football/top-stories/lionel-messi-came-kylian-mbapp-was-a-little-jealous-neymar-spills-secrets-of-psg-days/articleshow/117318397.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infosys shares tank 6% amid likely weak Q4, uncertainty over wage hike impact - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPQVNBb0paT1pmTnJpM1R4N2RLbjQ2QW95TnJxeXM2bWxMZkZmWnAweWhSNjE1SHFLb2Zoa3lRdV93NWRaNDU0UVUzMXRxNE53YjJjNzNVcU1TcjlyTGQ0b1BRRDdPSUYzNEdsYWZ1Y1JDQlk4a1ZnZklhRE1BN3FPRWd3QU9jcFlhZXFrZ05IRjUxckxlRWZ4SEVXd25VeWluZU1MTkVvZXBqNzBnVGJwc2xkVXVsNzFwVjc4b1RkdnU0N0ZOUVpxS0NKRDhEbFpWaUFkSll0UdIB3AFBVV95cUxQSWJpNUtacFczVmRsaHR6SFdGOFRzSTBINDJVWnJkdmU3Q2EtREp3NG4temRGRlNtSnV2ZUR2YXZsNTRfdm5jV1dDY2dRblRYUW1iLVBVQ2FnN3dBbjVPSGJpSnRTbWo5ZjZpbXJJN3h2ZHVta240czNZcTlqSVhXTHJpcDVEWDJsRmstaVZRVURkZkhIQ0h1ZWQxMzJjNFJaNlcwSW5QMThUWTZleUJqS2o2RmNqbndZZWtuYlpqRlB0MmdpenMxd1V3bHZjdl84bjZ3RDlYc3Iyc29O?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPQVNBb0paT1pmTnJpM1R4N2RLbjQ2QW95TnJxeXM2bWxMZkZmWnAweWhSNjE1SHFLb2Zoa3lRdV93NWRaNDU0UVUzMXRxNE53YjJjNzNVcU1TcjlyTGQ0b1BRRDdPSUYzNEdsYWZ1Y1JDQlk4a1ZnZklhRE1BN3FPRWd3QU9jcFlhZXFrZ05IRjUxckxlRWZ4SEVXd25VeWluZU1MTkVvZXBqNzBnVGJwc2xkVXVsNzFwVjc4b1RkdnU0N0ZOUVpxS0NKRDhEbFpWaUFkSll0UdIB3AFBVV95cUxQSWJpNUtacFczVmRsaHR6SFdGOFRzSTBINDJVWnJkdmU3Q2EtREp3NG4temRGRlNtSnV2ZUR2YXZsNTRfdm5jV1dDY2dRblRYUW1iLVBVQ2FnN3dBbjVPSGJpSnRTbWo5ZjZpbXJJN3h2ZHVta240czNZcTlqSVhXTHJpcDVEWDJsRmstaVZRVURkZkhIQ0h1ZWQxMzJjNFJaNlcwSW5QMThUWTZleUJqS2o2RmNqbndZZWtuYlpqRlB0MmdpenMxd1V3bHZjdl84bjZ3RDlYc3Iyc29O?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:57:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea investigators to file request to extend President Yoon's detention - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korean Investigators Seek to Extend President Yoon's Detention</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p>
<img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/4RE54PYVJBLTJGXLAOMX6DVIXQ.jpg?auth=1c059ba69aff506a3e1f5bf6dbe4d0909042a42382ccb594b3c6e8ff5d3d6c09&amp;width=3120&amp;quality=80" alt="Police stand guard outside Seoul Detention Center where impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is held in custody in Uiwang"><figcaption>Police stand guard outside Seoul Detention Center where impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is held in custody in Uiwang, South Korea. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption>
<p>South Korea's anti-corruption agency is requesting to extend the detention of President Yoon Suk Yeol following his refusal to be questioned by investigators. He is embroiled in a legal challenge regarding accusations of insurrection related to his brief imposition of martial law in December.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Authorities face a deadline to release President Yoon or extend his detention.</li>
  <li>Investigators expect to file a request for a detention warrant for up to 20 days.</li>
  <li>The Seoul court has rejected Yoon's challenge against his arrest.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I think you can consider it almost finished," a CIO official stated regarding the investigation.</blockquote>
<p>The situation highlights ongoing political turmoil in South Korea and the implications of Yoon's actions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/south-koreas-yoon-recalled-questioning-detention-deadline-looms-2025-01-16/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/south-koreas-yoon-recalled-questioning-detention-deadline-looms-2025-01-16/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian national, Sai Varshith Kandula, sentenced to 8 years for attempted attack on White House - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian National Sentenced to 8 Years for Attempted Attack on White House</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/b5bsgs/article68173762.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/White_House_Truck_Crash_62079.jpg" alt="Attempted attack on the White House" /><figcaption>A U.S. Park Police officer inspects a security barrier for damage in Lafayette Square park near the White House.</figcaption><p>Indian national Sai Varshith Kandula was sentenced to eight years for an attempted attack on the White House with a rented truck, aiming to overthrow the U.S. government.</p><ul><li>Kandula pled guilty to willful injury to U.S. property.</li><li>He drove a truck onto a sidewalk and crashed into security barriers near the White House.</li><li>He brandished a Nazi flag after the crash, promoting a dictatorship.</li><li>Kandula caused an estimated $4,322 in damage.</li><li>He had planned the attack for weeks, trying to acquire armed guards and larger vehicles.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kandula's intent was to replace the democratically elected government with a dictatorship fueled by ideology of Nazi Germany,” stated the Department of Justice.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights significant security concerns and the urgency of addressing radical ideologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/indian-national-sai-varshith-kandula-sentenced-to-8-years-for-attempted-attack-on-white-house/article69107380.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/indian-national-sai-varshith-kandula-sentenced-to-8-years-for-attempted-attack-on-white-house/article69107380.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Emergency box office collection Day 1 early estimates: Kangana Ranaut starrer off to a slow start - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Emergency Box Office Collection Day 1 Early Estimates: Kangana Ranaut Starrer Off to a Slow Start</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117317125,imgsize-20950,width-400,resizemode-4/117317125.jpg" alt="Emergency box office collection Day 1 early estimates: Kangana Ranaut starrer off to a slow start" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Kangana Ranaut in Emergency</figcaption><p>The much-anticipated political drama 'Emergency' has had a sluggish start at the box office according to early estimates, with initial earnings around Rs 1 lakh.</p><ul><li>The film is expected to earn between Rs 2-3 crore net in India by the end of Day 1.</li><li>Kangana announced a special pricing of Rs 99 for tickets on Cinema Lovers Day to boost sales.</li><li>Advance ticket sales have outstripped its competitor 'Azaad', but overall numbers remain weak.</li><li>The film addresses a significant historical period in Indian politics from 1975 to 1977, featuring Kangana as Indira Gandhi.</li></ul><blockquote>“Watch Emergency at Rs 99,” said Kangana Ranaut, highlighting the promotional ticket pricing.</blockquote><p>Despite its slow start, 'Emergency' has the potential to pick up pace during the day, competing against other films.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/emergency-box-office-collection-day-1-early-estimates-kangana-ranaut-starrer-off-to-a-slow-start-earns-rs-1-lakh-from-morning-shows/articleshow/117317114.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/box-office/emergency-box-office-collection-day-1-early-estimates-kangana-ranaut-starrer-off-to-a-slow-start-earns-rs-1-lakh-from-morning-shows/articleshow/117317114.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australia flex batting depth to set England an improbable 308 - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gardner's Century and King's Five-for Give Australia ODI Series Sweep</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p><figure><img src="https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/placeholder-16-9.png" alt="Ashleigh Gardner celebrates her maiden ODI century, Australia vs England, 3rd ODI, Women's Ashes, Hobart, January 17, 2025"><figcaption>Ashleigh Gardner celebrates her maiden ODI century&nbsp;&nbsp;•&nbsp;&nbsp;Getty Images</figcaption></figure><p>Ashleigh Gardner scored her maiden international century, leading Australia to an 86-run victory over England in the third ODI, securing a 6-0 lead in the series.</p><ul><li>Ashleigh Gardner scored an impressive 102 runs off 102 balls.</li><li>McGrath contributed a solid 55 runs, while Mooney added 50 runs.</li><li>King took 5 wickets for 46 runs, while Schutt took 3 for 57.</li><li>Australia scored 308 for 8, while England could only manage 222 runs.</li><li>Both Beaumont and Sciver-Brunt scored half-centuries for England.</li><li>Australia now requires just two points to retain the Ashes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Gardner's run-a-ball century rescued Australia from 59 for 4.”</blockquote><p>This victory places Australia in a strong position to retain the Ashes, showcasing their dominant performance in the series thus far.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/women-s-ashes-2024-25-1426615/australia-women-vs-england-women-3rd-odi-1426625/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/women-s-ashes-2024-25-1426615/australia-women-vs-england-women-3rd-odi-1426625/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:11:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi fog today: Several flights delayed at IGI airport; AQI improves after rain - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-air-quality-rain-delhi-ncr-noida-ghaziabad-fog-aqi-imd-weather-news-101737080617597.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-air-quality-rain-delhi-ncr-noida-ghaziabad-fog-aqi-imd-weather-news-101737080617597.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:10:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Industries shares in focus after Q3 results beats estimates. Should you buy, sell and hold? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxPN1NwQXZITDJLOFJMUFB1VlhtWnB4dUtEWm9MQl8yNnJXX2FwczE5aFMxcUVoenFIcTlpdHdjbHFxUlp4VjZyZUczcU9LYlduOHdUVndjZ3A4Tnl4eEV6eUc5RmtZZ18zUFFSVWd3WVdTdEx0bHNqVEZxdkhvMkM5MTU4a1ZmU0VNNUY0VlJMVGZncFBYYWVOVVY3ZlY3RlpHdmFFOFhzTnpRNXRTSFR6bFBvVjBnQk9lSHQ4bDBXaURnRF92U1ZjM28wMXZySHFHUkJSRzNqQ1ZwS1dxai1TSTFrdlpsYkMzbWZGXy1ScGxpZGJVaXFjUkVnYXpPS0550gGGAkFVX3lxTE1kOVFRb3hBRWZhc0gzbkhQVEczU3dHME9BbnNyd1BfaGRfR1BEWFFGYjdyYnNXdTBXR0VDQVJVM0VkU1Y0Z3FKT1JQWkVBQTB0cXNzdkRlWk9DcE5yTEdNVVFLRjZTSkJqN3FyRjkxS1R4MkRkbk5VZXM2R01rYXgtOWFuRmgwUUJGSUQ5dktWSnBFeXVXdmxiX1VfNzNTZktoaTUxcTVLVU5sRENDTEs5VVJIeDM5ZV9KRURGZy1feUVNakJlX3d6RFI3NlhBMlBBa0ZRWW5Wc1g5UFE4NHpqMUNMVW8xR1hycFdMcUQtd29mS0JJRnZYdkNqcXBfVHdkcHFYS0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxPN1NwQXZITDJLOFJMUFB1VlhtWnB4dUtEWm9MQl8yNnJXX2FwczE5aFMxcUVoenFIcTlpdHdjbHFxUlp4VjZyZUczcU9LYlduOHdUVndjZ3A4Tnl4eEV6eUc5RmtZZ18zUFFSVWd3WVdTdEx0bHNqVEZxdkhvMkM5MTU4a1ZmU0VNNUY0VlJMVGZncFBYYWVOVVY3ZlY3RlpHdmFFOFhzTnpRNXRTSFR6bFBvVjBnQk9lSHQ4bDBXaURnRF92U1ZjM28wMXZySHFHUkJSRzNqQ1ZwS1dxai1TSTFrdlpsYkMzbWZGXy1ScGxpZGJVaXFjUkVnYXpPS0550gGGAkFVX3lxTE1kOVFRb3hBRWZhc0gzbkhQVEczU3dHME9BbnNyd1BfaGRfR1BEWFFGYjdyYnNXdTBXR0VDQVJVM0VkU1Y0Z3FKT1JQWkVBQTB0cXNzdkRlWk9DcE5yTEdNVVFLRjZTSkJqN3FyRjkxS1R4MkRkbk5VZXM2R01rYXgtOWFuRmgwUUJGSUQ5dktWSnBFeXVXdmxiX1VfNzNTZktoaTUxcTVLVU5sRENDTEs5VVJIeDM5ZV9KRURGZy1feUVNakJlX3d6RFI3NlhBMlBBa0ZRWW5Wc1g5UFE4NHpqMUNMVW8xR1hycFdMcUQtd29mS0JJRnZYdkNqcXBfVHdkcHFYS0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:06:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anushka Sharma can't stay with Virat Kohli for more than 14 days during India tours: What BCCI family travel policy says - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anushka Sharma can't stay with Virat Kohli for more than 14 days during India tours</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/17/550x309/anushka_dipika_1737082652507_1737082659827.jpg" alt="File photo of Anushka Sharma and Dipika Pallikal" title="File photo of Anushka Sharma and Dipika Pallikal"><figcaption>File photo of Anushka Sharma and Dipika Pallikal</figcaption><p>The BCCI has announced that players' wives and children cannot accompany them for more than 14 days during long overseas tours. This rule is part of a new family travel policy aimed at maintaining discipline and operational efficiency.</p><ul><li>The BCCI's family travel policy allows players to have their partners and children visit them for one visit per series lasting up to two weeks if they are outside India for over 45 days.</li><li>Shared accommodation for visitors will be covered by the BCCI, but all other expenses will be the player's responsibility.</li><li>Visits must be scheduled at a single time agreed upon by the coach, captain, and GM operations.</li><li>Any deviations from this policy need pre-approval from the coach and captain.</li></ul><blockquote>“Non-compliance may lead to disciplinary action as deemed appropriate by the BCCI.”</blockquote><p>This decision may impact personal well-being and relationships, especially for players like Virat Kohli, who have previously enjoyed the presence of their partners during tours.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/anushka-sharma-cant-stay-with-virat-kohli-for-more-than-14-days-during-india-tours-what-bcci-family-travel-policy-says-101737082179869.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/anushka-sharma-cant-stay-with-virat-kohli-for-more-than-14-days-during-india-tours-what-bcci-family-travel-policy-says-101737082179869.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu says deal to release Hamas-held hostages has been reached - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Netanyahu Announces Deal for Release of Hamas-held Hostages</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png" alt="Supporters and family members of hostages kidnapped during the deadly October 7, 2023, attack on Israel by Hamas, gather next to a slogan formed of candles on a road during a protest ahead of a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, in Tel Aviv, Israel, on January 16, 2025" title="Supporters and family members of hostages kidnapped during the deadly October 7, 2023, attack on Israel by Hamas, gather next to a slogan formed of candles on a road during a protest ahead of a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, in Tel Aviv, Israel, on January 16, 2025"><figcaption>Supporters and family members of hostages during a protest in Tel Aviv, January 16, 2025 | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>The office of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced a deal has been reached for the release of hostages held by Hamas, with a political-security cabinet convening to discuss the details.</p><ul><li>Netanyahu's office confirmed agreements on a deal to release the hostages.</li><li>The families of the hostages have been informed and preparations are being made for their return.</li><li>If approved, the truce would start on Sunday, enabling the exchange of Israeli hostages for Palestinian prisoners.</li><li>The deal was mediated by Qatar and the United States, announced on Wednesday.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Prime Minister ordered the political-security cabinet to convene tomorrow (Friday). The government will then convene to approve the deal,” Netanyahu’s office stated.</blockquote><p>Should this deal be approved, it could mark a significant step towards a ceasefire and a resolution to the ongoing conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/netanyahu-says-deal-to-release-hamas-held-hostages-has-been-reached/article69107335.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/netanyahu-says-deal-to-release-hamas-held-hostages-has-been-reached/article69107335.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning Regarding '10-Point Diktat' For Indian Cricket Team .. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning Regarding '10-Point Diktat' For Indian Cricket Team Stars</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/qcmgaih_sc_625x300_17_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605' alt='BCCI's New Policy' /><figcaption>File photo of Indian cricket team © AFP</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has enforced a new policy for senior players following recent disappointing performances to promote discipline and team unity.</p><ul><li>Restrictions introduced on personal shoots and endorsements during tours.</li><li>Players must attend BCCI functions and cannot leave practice sessions early.</li><li>Families allowed limited visits on long tours (only two weeks).</li><li>Mandatory participation in domestic matches for national team consideration.</li><li>Disciplinary actions outlined for non-compliance, including suspensions and fee deductions.</li></ul><blockquote>“All players are expected to adhere strictly to the above guidelines. Non-compliance may lead to disciplinary action as deemed appropriate by the BCCI.”</blockquote><p>This policy aims to ensure players remain committed to their training and the overall cricketing structure in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:57:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning Regarding '10-Point Diktat' For Indian Cricket Team Stars - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning For Indian Cricket Team Stars</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/qcmgaih_sc_625x300_17_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="'Sanctions, IPL Ban And...': BCCI's Big Warning For Indian Cricket Team Stars"><figcaption>File photo of Indian cricket team © AFP</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has introduced a strict new policy for senior cricketers, requiring adherence to a 10-point diktat in light of the team's recent performance issues. This policy includes restrictions on personal endorsements and mandates players to remain disciplined during tours.</p><ul><li>The BCCI restricts family and personal staff from tours to promote discipline and unity.</li><li>Players will be required to participate in domestic matches to be eligible for national selection.</li><li>Non-compliance may result in suspension and financial penalties.</li><li>Exceptions to the policy require approval from BCCI officials.</li></ul><blockquote>“This policy ensures that players remain connected to the domestic cricket ecosystem, fostering talent development, maintaining match fitness, and strengthening the overall domestic structure.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the BCCI's stringent new rules aim to reinforce discipline among players and enhance their commitment to the team, with clear consequences for non-adherence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/sanctions-ipl-ban-and-bccis-big-warning-regarding-10-point-diktat-for-indian-cricket-team-stars-7490760</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:57:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China population shrinks for third year even with more babies born - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's Population Decline Continues Despite Increase in Births</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>China has reported a continued decrease in its population for the third consecutive year, even as the birth rate shows a slight increase.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The overall population has experienced a shrinkage, indicating a demographic crisis.</li>
  <li>Increased birth rates have not been sufficient to counterbalance the aging population.</li>
  <li>Government measures to encourage higher birth rates have yet to produce the desired results.</li>
  <li>Experts are concerned about the long-term economic implications of this trend.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This trend could lead to significant economic challenges in the future, including a shrinking workforce." - Demographic Expert</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing demographic shift highlights the complexity of population management and the urgent need for targeted policy interventions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/china-population-shrinks-for-third-year-even-with-more-babies-born/articleshow/117317118.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/china-population-shrinks-for-third-year-even-with-more-babies-born/articleshow/117317118.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Eclipses Indian Navy In AIP-Submarine Tech! Set To Widen The Gap With Chinese Hangor-Class Subs - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNbXAtU1hzeVpnU1huY2R2Zm9qaHItSUljWHZNanAxMW45N0dmNzFnRFhjcDdfX2l6amRuUzNkb2sxUXZlS012YlhZRUd5MHZueXMydnEtMkRNMkk2MldRNFA2bEM4ZGgzLURuLWc1ZzZ0bkhYV0FoLUZHdGpmSVBXTWJB0gGCAUFVX3lxTE1tcC1TWHN5WmdTWG5jZHZmb2poci1JSWNYdk1qcDExbjk3R2Y3MWdEWGNwN19faXpqZG5TM2RvazFRdmVLTXZiWFlFR3kwdm55czJ2cS0yRE0ySTYyV1E0UDZsQzhkaDMtRG4tZzVnNnRuSFhXQWgtRkd0amZJUFdNYkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNbXAtU1hzeVpnU1huY2R2Zm9qaHItSUljWHZNanAxMW45N0dmNzFnRFhjcDdfX2l6amRuUzNkb2sxUXZlS012YlhZRUd5MHZueXMydnEtMkRNMkk2MldRNFA2bEM4ZGgzLURuLWc1ZzZ0bkhYV0FoLUZHdGpmSVBXTWJB0gGCAUFVX3lxTE1tcC1TWHN5WmdTWG5jZHZmb2poci1JSWNYdk1qcDExbjk3R2Y3MWdEWGNwN19faXpqZG5TM2RvazFRdmVLTXZiWFlFR3kwdm55czJ2cS0yRE0ySTYyV1E0UDZsQzhkaDMtRG4tZzVnNnRuSFhXQWgtRkd0amZJUFdNYkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:51:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>