<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:29:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:29:07 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why do we get headaches after drinking red wine? Research says the culprit is… - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why do we get headaches after drinking red wine? A new research tried to find the culprit and found a compound in the grape skin.&nbsp;</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/red_wine_headache_1734425093674_1734425099864.jpg" alt="Over the years, many components of red wine have been blamed for headaches. However, the culprit lies in grape skin. (Shutterstock)" title="Over the years, many components of red wine have been blamed for headaches. However, the culprit lies in grape skin. (Shutterstock)"><figcaption>Over the years, many components of red wine have been blamed for headaches. However, the culprit lies in grape skin. (Shutterstock)</figcaption><p>Red wine is notorious for causing headaches, a phenomenon long blamed on various components such as sulfites and tannins. However, recent research led by experts from the University of California-Davis identifies a compound in grape skin as the likely culprit.</p><ul><li>Research highlights that phenolic compounds in grape skins are implicated in red wine headaches.</li><li>The study found quercetin in grape skins as a significant inhibitor of the enzyme ALDH, leading to the accumulation of acetaldehyde.</li><li>This accumulation may cause flushed skin and headaches due to slower metabolic processing of alcohol.</li><li>Sun-exposed grapes produce more quercetin; many inexpensive red wines are made from less sun-exposed grapes.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“The researchers stated that this second step is slower for people with flushed skin since their ALDH is inefficient.”</p></blockquote><p>Understanding the chemical compounds in red wine can help guide consumers and inform future wine production practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/why-do-we-get-headaches-after-drinking-red-wine-research-says-the-culprit-is-101734422054667.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/why-do-we-get-headaches-after-drinking-red-wine-research-says-the-culprit-is-101734422054667.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:18:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Its official: Having this daily comfort drink can increase lifespan by 2 years! - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/its-official-having-this-daily-comfort-drink-can-increase-lifespan-by-2-years/articleshow/116393955.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/its-official-having-this-daily-comfort-drink-can-increase-lifespan-by-2-years/articleshow/116393955.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The hidden dangers: 10 reasons why vaping is injurious to health - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQSGV4eTJ4MDJzNlVrbDdqdGsyVGJBaUdHSUMzQVV6d1MyWXhmcHdIZ3lhaEtYcWU2UGwxV2NQa2Y3UEdTeHE3RXVaRS00WnRLT1lSUl8yYkl2dk1yU3B1ckVlVjRQeFp3RGY5WHhGN2NRV0FReC00SHJXUjNxYkkzaVFUTlJ6c3ZWNGZlZWxxeUstNzdaY1VFdUZFR0h3SncwVjFOU19JR1dlRGhYamEySVdrQnVEM2JIeW9qX01hWdIBvwFBVV95cUxQSGV4eTJ4MDJzNlVrbDdqdGsyVGJBaUdHSUMzQVV6d1MyWXhmcHdIZ3lhaEtYcWU2UGwxV2NQa2Y3UEdTeHE3RXVaRS00WnRLT1lSUl8yYkl2dk1yU3B1ckVlVjRQeFp3RGY5WHhGN2NRV0FReC00SHJXUjNxYkkzaVFUTlJ6c3ZWNGZlZWxxeUstNzdaY1VFdUZFR0h3SncwVjFOU19JR1dlRGhYamEySVdrQnVEM2JIeW9qX01hWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQSGV4eTJ4MDJzNlVrbDdqdGsyVGJBaUdHSUMzQVV6d1MyWXhmcHdIZ3lhaEtYcWU2UGwxV2NQa2Y3UEdTeHE3RXVaRS00WnRLT1lSUl8yYkl2dk1yU3B1ckVlVjRQeFp3RGY5WHhGN2NRV0FReC00SHJXUjNxYkkzaVFUTlJ6c3ZWNGZlZWxxeUstNzdaY1VFdUZFR0h3SncwVjFOU19JR1dlRGhYamEySVdrQnVEM2JIeW9qX01hWdIBvwFBVV95cUxQSGV4eTJ4MDJzNlVrbDdqdGsyVGJBaUdHSUMzQVV6d1MyWXhmcHdIZ3lhaEtYcWU2UGwxV2NQa2Y3UEdTeHE3RXVaRS00WnRLT1lSUl8yYkl2dk1yU3B1ckVlVjRQeFp3RGY5WHhGN2NRV0FReC00SHJXUjNxYkkzaVFUTlJ6c3ZWNGZlZWxxeUstNzdaY1VFdUZFR0h3SncwVjFOU19JR1dlRGhYamEySVdrQnVEM2JIeW9qX01hWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:09:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Men Use Bat Poop To Grow Cannabis, Both Die Due To This Medical Condition - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Men Die from Fungal Infection Linked to Bat Poop Used in Cannabis Cultivation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 17 Dec 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Science</p><img src="https://feeds.abplive.com/onecms/images/uploaded-images/2024/05/04/1c6f59d394c30dae9dc74b73d2e8d9f41714819784515742_original.jpg?impolicy=abp_cdn&amp;imwidth=1200&amp;height=675" alt="Men Use Bat Poop To Grow Cannabis Both Die Due To This Medical Condition"><figcaption>Men use bat poop for cannabis cultivation, leading to fatal infections.</figcaption><p>Two men in New York died of a rare fungal lung infection, histoplasmosis, after using bat droppings as fertilizer for cannabis.</p><ul><li>The men were aged 59 and 64, and both had a history of cultivating cannabis for personal use.</li><li>They inhaled spores from the fungus <em>Histoplasma capsulatum</em> found in bat guano.</li><li>Symptoms included fever, chronic cough, and significant weight loss, leading to respiratory failure.</li><li>Doctors warn of the dangers of using bat guano as fertilizer for any plants.</li><li>Histoplasmosis cannot spread between people or pets, but can be severe in those with weakened immune systems.</li></ul><blockquote>“Their deaths serve as a warning about the potential dangers of using bat guano as a fertilizer.”</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the risks of using animal droppings as fertilizers without understanding the associated health hazards.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/trending/men-use-bat-poop-to-grow-cannabis-both-die-due-to-this-medical-condition-1738086</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/trending/men-use-bat-poop-to-grow-cannabis-both-die-due-to-this-medical-condition-1738086</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:03:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 reasons to have dragon fruit daily - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>9 Reasons to Include Dragon Fruit in Your Daily Diet</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116390923.jpg?imgsize=695966&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="9 reasons to have dragon fruit daily">
<figcaption>9 reasons to have dragon fruit daily</figcaption>
<p>Dragon fruit is not just visually appealing; it also boasts numerous health benefits that make it a fantastic addition to your daily diet.</p>
<ul>
<li>Dragon fruit is low in calories (only 60 calories per 100 grams), which makes it a nutritious breakfast option.</li>
<li>It is packed with essential nutrients, including vitamin C, magnesium, iron, and fiber.</li>
<li>This fruit is high in dietary fiber, promoting healthy digestion and preventing constipation.</li>
<li>Dragon fruit aids in weight management due to its high water content and fiber, making you feel full longer.</li>
<li>It is rich in antioxidants like flavonoids and betacyanins, which combat oxidative stress and reduce inflammation.</li>
<li>High levels of vitamin C enhance collagen production, improving skin elasticity and reducing aging signs.</li>
<li>Dragon fruit supports the immune system, helping ward off illnesses.</li>
<li>It contains plant compounds that help lower bad cholesterol while increasing good cholesterol.</li>
<li>For people with diabetes, dragon fruit can stabilize blood sugar levels due to its fiber content.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Including dragon fruit in your daily diet can yield multiple health benefits, from supporting heart health to improving digestion."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, adding dragon fruit to your diet can be a tasty way to enhance your health. Its unique blend of nutrients and benefits makes it a worthy choice for anyone looking to improve their well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/9-reasons-to-have-dragon-fruit-daily/photostory/116390603.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/9-reasons-to-have-dragon-fruit-daily/photostory/116390603.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Causes, symptoms and treatment of bowel cancer: A rising health risk among youngsters - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/causes-symptoms-and-treatment-of-bowel-cancer-a-rising-health-risk-among-youngsters-article-12891812.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/causes-symptoms-and-treatment-of-bowel-cancer-a-rising-health-risk-among-youngsters-article-12891812.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:53:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study finds hot dogs and processed meats can shorten healthy life by up to 36 minutes per serving - The Jerusalem Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Study finds hot dogs and processed meats can shorten healthy life by up to 36 minutes per serving</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> DECEMBER 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Jerusalem Post</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.jpost.com/image/upload/q_auto/c_fill,g_faces:center,h_537,w_822/639512" width="290" height="260" alt="Is it worth 36 minutes of your life?" title="Recent study suggests items like hot dogs, cheeseburgers shorten people's healthy life time.">
  <figcaption>Is it worth 36 minutes of your life? Recent study suggests items like hot dogs, cheeseburgers shorten people's healthy life time. (photo credit: siamionau pavel. Via Shutterstock)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A recent study conducted by the University of Michigan reveals that certain processed foods, such as hot dogs and cheeseburgers, may significantly reduce healthy life expectancy. The findings suggest that dietary changes can lead to improved health outcomes.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study finds that a single serving of a hot dog can reduce healthy life by 36 minutes.</li>
  <li>Cheeseburgers reduce healthy life by 9 minutes, while sugary drinks can add another 12 minutes to that total.</li>
  <li>Research evaluated over 5,800 types of American foods based on their health impacts.</li>
  <li>Processed meats are shown to adversely affect health and are linked to chronic diseases.</li>
  <li>Alternatives like legumes and fish can potentially increase healthy lifespan.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The need for dietary changes aimed at improving human health is clear," said Dr. Olivier Jolliet, the head of the University of Michigan study.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, shifting towards a healthier diet by incorporating less processed foods and more plant-based alternatives may enhance longevity and well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jpost.com/science/science-around-the-world/article-833766</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jpost.com/science/science-around-the-world/article-833766</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why do we need more magnesium during winter? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why do we need more magnesium during winter?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>As winter approaches, the need for magnesium increases significantly among individuals. This essential mineral plays a crucial role in various bodily functions and is vital for maintaining health during colder months.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Magnesium helps regulate body temperature and maintain energy levels during winter.</li>
  <li>It contributes to stronger immune function, which is particularly important when flu season hits.</li>
  <li>Insufficient magnesium can lead to increased fatigue and mood fluctuations.</li>
  <li>Natural food sources and supplements can help meet the increased demand.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In the winter, our bodies require more magnesium for optimal functioning.”</blockquote>
<p>Understanding the importance of magnesium and ensuring adequate intake can significantly enhance overall wellbeing during the colder months.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-do-we-need-more-magnesium-during-winter/articleshow/116391261.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-do-we-need-more-magnesium-during-winter/articleshow/116391261.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magnesium Benefits: Why do we need more magnesium during winter? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why Increased Magnesium Intake is Essential During Winter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Date Not Specified | <strong>Source: </strong>Source Not Specified</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116391300,imgsize-401805,width-400,resizemode-4/116391300.jpg" alt="Why do we need more magnesium during winter?" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Image illustrating the importance of magnesium during winter.</figcaption><p>As winter arrives, our bodies face new challenges. The days grow shorter, temperatures drop, and our routines shift, impacting our health. Magnesium plays a crucial role in helping navigate the colder months.</p><ul><li>Magnesium regulates mood and helps combat Seasonal Affective Disorder (SAD).</li><li>It aids in handling stress by regulating the HPA axis and enhancing GABA's relaxing effects.</li><li>Magnesium supports immune function, helping to fend off winter illnesses.</li><li>It is critical for heart health and blood circulation during cold weather.</li><li>Magnesium improves sleep quality, countering disruptions from reduced daylight.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ensuring sufficient magnesium intake can help stabilize your mood and improve overall mental well-being during the darker months.”</blockquote><p>Incorporating magnesium-rich foods or supplements during winter can support both physical and mental health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-do-we-need-more-magnesium-during-winter/articleshow/116391261.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-do-we-need-more-magnesium-during-winter/articleshow/116391261.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How To Tackle Declining Sperm Count In Men? - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPbExFRHA2Wm5jVWFpaFlPWFVqRTRDV1FGS3QyaEVLM1BxRGppZktHd0Y5ZjhLXzAybW9HWVhzampXcTdTenNIOHNWOWZMUGJBZGJ4dWVhc3NWOE02RS1PeFI0d0dIN0l2TVdFN3pXRHY0QmdVbVhpNkFpV1l4dkwwWGFSdHo0eTlPYTh6bDNRZ2QxUUMwaVY3c0RZOHREN05IT21reWQwVlhCaURsMGsxWk930gGyAUFVX3lxTE9sTEVEcDZabmNVYWloWU9YVWpFNENXUUZLdDJoRUszUHFEamlmS0d3RjlmOEtfMDJtb0dZWHNqaldxN1N6c0g4c1Y5ZkxQYkFkYnh1ZWFzc1Y4TTZFLU94UjR3R0g3SXZNV0U3eldEdjRCZ1VtWGk2QWlXWXh2TDBYYVJ0ejR5OU9hOHpsM1FnZDFRQzBpVjdzRFk4dEQ3TkhPbWt5ZDBWWEJpRGwwazFaT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPbExFRHA2Wm5jVWFpaFlPWFVqRTRDV1FGS3QyaEVLM1BxRGppZktHd0Y5ZjhLXzAybW9HWVhzampXcTdTenNIOHNWOWZMUGJBZGJ4dWVhc3NWOE02RS1PeFI0d0dIN0l2TVdFN3pXRHY0QmdVbVhpNkFpV1l4dkwwWGFSdHo0eTlPYTh6bDNRZ2QxUUMwaVY3c0RZOHREN05IT21reWQwVlhCaURsMGsxWk930gGyAUFVX3lxTE9sTEVEcDZabmNVYWloWU9YVWpFNENXUUZLdDJoRUszUHFEamlmS0d3RjlmOEtfMDJtb0dZWHNqaldxN1N6c0g4c1Y5ZkxQYkFkYnh1ZWFzc1Y4TTZFLU94UjR3R0g3SXZNV0U3eldEdjRCZ1VtWGk2QWlXWXh2TDBYYVJ0ejR5OU9hOHpsM1FnZDFRQzBpVjdzRFk4dEQ3TkhPbWt5ZDBWWEJpRGwwazFaT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 06:57:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Back and neck pain in winter? Here's how to protect your spine health when it gets cold outside - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/back-and-neck-pain-in-winter-here-s-how-to-protect-your-spine-health-when-it-gets-cold-outside-article-12891647.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/back-and-neck-pain-in-winter-here-s-how-to-protect-your-spine-health-when-it-gets-cold-outside-article-12891647.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 06:42:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 non-genetic causes of high blood pressure (that you can change) - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxPYTFObFpBZ2s2Zk5KaVMtLTJrZjlvSkJRNzlhcTg0ZXR6Q1FycjJvM3pEemFRaVRtSThMYzZZRzBXOTJ3cGUyQ1pqTUZyTzJhdnhHTHhhSUZsQ0dsalJMRUxZQWZPeGMzUkFiYVJNLTZJTWhKa294YzM2NHN1b2VhTldILVZKdkpBWnpDT3hsQ2lnQUVtYkd4MlVTUjN2VFFmWDhjNW5IbkZoM2R6TFM2ZW1laWszNU15U0VPb1JVckhUZGhxUXJzWUFLdGpORHI0bmZuS0tTMzFpbUtVVkJHUTNYYkRKY2xadUdVVE1rU192QmJS0gH0AUFVX3lxTE9hMU5sWkFnazZmTkppUy0tMmtmOW9KQlE3OWFxODRldHpDUXJyMm8zekR6YVFpVG1JOExjNllHMFc5MndwZTJDWmpNRnJPMmF2eEdMeGFJRmxDR2xqUkxFTFlBZk94YzNSQWJhUk0tNklNaEprb3hjMzY0c3VvZWFOV0gtVkp2SkFaekNPeGxDaWdBRW1iR3gyVVNSM3ZUUWZYOGM1bkhuRmgzZHpMUzZlbWVpazM1TXlTRU9vUlVySFRkaHFRcnNZQUt0ak5EcjRuZm5LS1MzMWltS1VWQkdRM1hiREpjbFp1R1VUTWtTX3ZCYlI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxPYTFObFpBZ2s2Zk5KaVMtLTJrZjlvSkJRNzlhcTg0ZXR6Q1FycjJvM3pEemFRaVRtSThMYzZZRzBXOTJ3cGUyQ1pqTUZyTzJhdnhHTHhhSUZsQ0dsalJMRUxZQWZPeGMzUkFiYVJNLTZJTWhKa294YzM2NHN1b2VhTldILVZKdkpBWnpDT3hsQ2lnQUVtYkd4MlVTUjN2VFFmWDhjNW5IbkZoM2R6TFM2ZW1laWszNU15U0VPb1JVckhUZGhxUXJzWUFLdGpORHI0bmZuS0tTMzFpbUtVVkJHUTNYYkRKY2xadUdVVE1rU192QmJS0gH0AUFVX3lxTE9hMU5sWkFnazZmTkppUy0tMmtmOW9KQlE3OWFxODRldHpDUXJyMm8zekR6YVFpVG1JOExjNllHMFc5MndwZTJDWmpNRnJPMmF2eEdMeGFJRmxDR2xqUkxFTFlBZk94YzNSQWJhUk0tNklNaEprb3hjMzY0c3VvZWFOV0gtVkp2SkFaekNPeGxDaWdBRW1iR3gyVVNSM3ZUUWZYOGM1bkhuRmgzZHpMUzZlbWVpazM1TXlTRU9vUlVySFRkaHFRcnNZQUt0ak5EcjRuZm5LS1MzMWltS1VWQkdRM1hiREpjbFp1R1VUTWtTX3ZCYlI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India sets up the first diabetes biobank in Chennai. Here's why this is significant - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India sets up the first diabetes biobank in Chennai. Here's why this is significant</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Publication Date: [Not Specified], Source: Firstpost</p><div id="nwartbximg"><p><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/12/pixabay-scientists-in-a-lab-2024-12-16b719f6e07f5ff1f9f3bc20c581e88c.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="India sets up the first diabetes biobank in Chennai. Here's why this is significant" title="India sets up the first diabetes biobank in Chennai. Here's why this is significant"></p><p>The diabetes biobank, a collaboration between the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) and the Madras Diabetes Research Foundation (MDRF), promises to boost scientific research and treatment for diabetes. Image for Representation. Pixabay</p></div><p><strong>Introduction:</strong> India has established the country’s first-ever diabetes biobank in Chennai, aiming to enhance scientific research and treatment for diabetes.</p><ol><li>The biobank is a collaboration between the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) and the Madras Diabetes Research Foundation (MDRF).</li><li>It houses an extensive collection of blood samples from various types of diabetes, including Type 1, Type 2, and gestational diabetes.</li><li>The biobank will facilitate advanced research on the causes of diabetes and related disorders.</li><li>It could help in the identification of novel biomarkers for early diagnosis and the development of personalized treatment strategies.</li><li>The biobank will support longitudinal studies to track diabetes progression and complications.</li><li>Blood samples come from two major ICMR-funded studies: The ICMR-INDIAB and the Registry of People with Diabetes in India at a Young Age at Onset.</li></ol><blockquote>“This diabetes biobank could help in the identification of novel biomarkers for early diagnosis and the development of personalized treatment strategies,” an article in the Indian Journal of Medical Research stated.</blockquote><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The establishment of India's first diabetes biobank is a significant step towards improving diabetes research and treatment, potentially benefiting millions affected by the disease.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/health/india-icmr-first-diabetes-biobank-chennai-13845086.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/health/india-icmr-first-diabetes-biobank-chennai-13845086.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 05:58:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 best foods to reduce inflammation, from avocado to peppers - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/9-best-foods-to-reduce-inflammation-health-benefits-of-ginger-benefits-of-avocado-green-tea-benefits-nutrition-in-tomatoes-benefits-of-grapes-visual-story-2693714.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/9-best-foods-to-reduce-inflammation-health-benefits-of-ginger-benefits-of-avocado-green-tea-benefits-nutrition-in-tomatoes-benefits-of-grapes-visual-story-2693714.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 05:25:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[​9 foods that sharpen brain and improve memory power - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxQd0pXTEpfRjF5UHM3WnZYNExtX3RGdHhwcWxpTnVLQWZxTFJqMmNKcURlRlFXQTNiTlFvRjdIel9OMk5ncFVIa1RFZVdoWlpmOUpPdFpEUmdyMmk5a2hrN2x0NVFBQjJtaThXcjFyWmZ1WGw0QVZsd2F4X3VybkFGNDRGSERYN2tpT2RQUVMzWm4xX1ZuUmVXbGJsbnN6S29YSXcwS3JWQndPSktTb2psSklfaWFURUVRRWdJVUFtNHpvb2hSQXk4SnMyRkF3MHdBb3VrT1g1RlNZRktIZktwb1ozTF_SAeQBQVVfeXFMUHdKV0xKX0YxeVBzN1p2WDRMbV90RnR4cHFsaU51S0FmcUxSajJjSnFEZUZRV0EzYk5Rb0Y3SHpfTjJOZ3BVSGtURWVXaFpaZjlKT3RaRFJncjJpOWtoazdsdDVRQUIybWk4V3IxclpmdVhsNEFWbHdheF91cm5BRjQ0RkhEWDdraU9kUFFTM1puMV9WblJlV2xibG5zektvWEl3MEtyVkJ3T0pLU29qbEpJX2lhVEVFUUVnSVVBbTR6b29oUkF5OEpzMkZBdzB3QW91a09YNUZTWUZLSGZLcG9aM0xf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxQd0pXTEpfRjF5UHM3WnZYNExtX3RGdHhwcWxpTnVLQWZxTFJqMmNKcURlRlFXQTNiTlFvRjdIel9OMk5ncFVIa1RFZVdoWlpmOUpPdFpEUmdyMmk5a2hrN2x0NVFBQjJtaThXcjFyWmZ1WGw0QVZsd2F4X3VybkFGNDRGSERYN2tpT2RQUVMzWm4xX1ZuUmVXbGJsbnN6S29YSXcwS3JWQndPSktTb2psSklfaWFURUVRRWdJVUFtNHpvb2hSQXk4SnMyRkF3MHdBb3VrT1g1RlNZRktIZktwb1ozTF_SAeQBQVVfeXFMUHdKV0xKX0YxeVBzN1p2WDRMbV90RnR4cHFsaU51S0FmcUxSajJjSnFEZUZRV0EzYk5Rb0Y3SHpfTjJOZ3BVSGtURWVXaFpaZjlKT3RaRFJncjJpOWtoazdsdDVRQUIybWk4V3IxclpmdVhsNEFWbHdheF91cm5BRjQ0RkhEWDdraU9kUFFTM1puMV9WblJlV2xibG5zektvWEl3MEtyVkJ3T0pLU29qbEpJX2lhVEVFUUVnSVVBbTR6b29oUkF5OEpzMkZBdzB3QW91a09YNUZTWUZLSGZLcG9aM0xf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:54:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fifteenth Meeting of the WHO South-East Asia Regional Immunization Technical Advisory Group - World Health Organization]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fifteenth Meeting of the WHO South-East Asia Regional Immunization Technical Advisory Group</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 20–23 August 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Meeting report</p><figure><img src="https://iris.who.int/bitstream/handle/10665/379829/SEA-Immun-162.pdf.jpg?sequence=4" alt="Fifteenth Meeting of the WHO South-East Asia Regional Immunization Technical Advisory Group"></figure><figcaption>Fifteenth Meeting of the WHO South-East Asia Regional Immunization Technical Advisory Group</figcaption><p>The Fifteenth Meeting of the World Health Organization’s (WHO) South-East Asia Regional Immunization Technical Advisory Group (SEAR-ITAG) was held from 20 to 23 August 2024 in New Delhi, India. It provides expert advice on immunization and the prevention of vaccine-preventable diseases.</p><ul><li>Setting regional priorities for immunization and vaccines;</li><li>Reviewing policies and strategies for VPD control, elimination, and eradication;</li><li>Making recommendations on national immunization policies;</li><li>Advising on new vaccines and their introduction;</li><li>Promoting high-quality VPD surveillance;</li><li>Ensuring the quality and safety of vaccines;</li><li>Guiding public-private partnerships in vaccination;</li><li>Identifying and reviewing research topics in immunization.</li></ul><p>WHO Team: Immunization & Vaccines Development, SEARO Regional Office for the South East Asia</p><p>Editors: World Health Organization. Regional Office for South-East Asia</p><p><strong>WHO Reference Number:</strong> SEA-Immun-162</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/sea-immun-162</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/sea-immun-162</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:47:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 morning habits for healthy digestion - Health shots]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>9 Morning Habits for Healthy Digestion</h1><p><strong>Published Dec 17, 2024 by Healthshots</strong></p><img src="https://images.healthshots.com/healthshots/en/images/2024/12/16/original/digestion_1734336070857.jpg" alt="Healthy Digestion"><figcaption>Image Credits: Adobe Stock</figcaption><p>Maintaining a healthy digestion is essential to promote overall well-being. Start your day with these 9 habits that promise to keep your digestion on track.</p><ul><li><strong>Have a Healthy Breakfast:</strong> A balanced breakfast with fiber, healthy fats, and protein jumpstarts metabolism.</li><li><strong>Chew Well:</strong> Proper chewing breaks down food for better nutrient absorption and reduces digestive issues.</li><li><strong>Do Not Overeat:</strong> Eating in moderation helps prevent indigestion and bloating.</li><li><strong>Avoid Spice:</strong> Spicy foods can cause digestive problems; opt for milder meals.</li><li><strong>Drink Tulsi Tea:</strong> Known for its digestive properties, it helps soothe the stomach.</li><li><strong>Practice Yoga:</strong> Gentle yoga poses promote digestive enzyme flow and relieve bloating.</li><li><strong>Drink Plenty of Water:</strong> Staying hydrated aids digestion and flushes out toxins.</li><li><strong>Meditate to Reduce Stress:</strong> Mindfulness can help mitigate stress-related digestive issues.</li><li><strong>Take a Short Walk After Breakfast:</strong> A light walk helps stimulate digestion and improve circulation.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthshots.com/web-stories/morning-habits-for-healthy-digestion-171734333165628.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthshots.com/web-stories/morning-habits-for-healthy-digestion-171734333165628.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:30:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lung cancer rising among non-smokers in India; doctors raise concern - mid-day.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxOYm1ZblpLVHkyclBKOWQtdFltZ2NFTFVsWTFwWXlRTldoaUtKUG81TkpISkl5U0s3NERYaEdlWVRJbldObVFSSkMyTkVfZDZxNGdNVFBrU1lPVGtSVTVlR2VZb094bmFlMHBHQ09vSlNRNXpIdFBEZlN6aFVjQXFkWEU2NVBmaEpjaFB2UXpodGk5NXZkRThyTWFRaXJEVzdTUmRydWZzQVVQa2RNT2wtV05VeDUzY3FGMFdoVjVZaHNBNUM3YjE1UHh3SGxxMGJ2TXpV0gHYAUFVX3lxTFBYU0NSWWhuTUZDY0FSUDhBci1JZ21jZ1RJS2dNdGZfVEJGR1ZVOVJIaTJBcTYxZ29KNlRuNFZkQzlnUjIxTmFnZVZHV3NyYjB2bTFqakYyQWtTNDZZSERlUnRnbUh5WURoeFJhMmRxVzBFN2dONjR4eEhNRVlWX0xzNEZTRXktSnpvalJyTjlKZjItamZRTUFlU3YxY2hRUUY4R095WWEtZkktbU4yVmEzT2IzYUYxTld2TjNuczd4SklKWTRNdFE5Z1JSY253MURQNnBtX1RabA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxOYm1ZblpLVHkyclBKOWQtdFltZ2NFTFVsWTFwWXlRTldoaUtKUG81TkpISkl5U0s3NERYaEdlWVRJbldObVFSSkMyTkVfZDZxNGdNVFBrU1lPVGtSVTVlR2VZb094bmFlMHBHQ09vSlNRNXpIdFBEZlN6aFVjQXFkWEU2NVBmaEpjaFB2UXpodGk5NXZkRThyTWFRaXJEVzdTUmRydWZzQVVQa2RNT2wtV05VeDUzY3FGMFdoVjVZaHNBNUM3YjE1UHh3SGxxMGJ2TXpV0gHYAUFVX3lxTFBYU0NSWWhuTUZDY0FSUDhBci1JZ21jZ1RJS2dNdGZfVEJGR1ZVOVJIaTJBcTYxZ29KNlRuNFZkQzlnUjIxTmFnZVZHV3NyYjB2bTFqakYyQWtTNDZZSERlUnRnbUh5WURoeFJhMmRxVzBFN2dONjR4eEhNRVlWX0xzNEZTRXktSnpvalJyTjlKZjItamZRTUFlU3YxY2hRUUY4R095WWEtZkktbU4yVmEzT2IzYUYxTld2TjNuczd4SklKWTRNdFE5Z1JSY253MURQNnBtX1RabA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These 9 Nuts And Seeds Are A Must For Couples Trying To Conceive - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Must-Eat Nuts and Seeds for Couples Trying to Conceive</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 2024<strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/couple-trying-to-conceive-nuts-and-seeds-1.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=710&amp;h=467" alt="Couples trying to conceive nuts and seeds"><figcaption>Must-eat Nuts And Seeds For Couples Trying To Conceive</figcaption><p>It is vital to focus on diet while trying to conceive. A balanced diet can enhance fertility in men and women, improving their chances of getting pregnant. Below are essential nuts and seeds to include in the diet.</p><ul><li><strong>Brazil Nuts:</strong> Provides selenium which supports thyroid health and improves egg and sperm quality.</li><li><strong>Walnuts:</strong> Rich in omega-3 and vitamin E, enhances sperm motility and protects eggs from damage.</li><li><strong>Almonds:</strong> Loaded with vitamin E, supports female fertility and protects sperm integrity.</li><li><strong>Pistachios:</strong> Rich in arginine, promotes blood flow for better sperm health.</li><li><strong>Raisins:</strong> Helps regulate menstrual cycles and supports ovulation.</li><li><strong>Sunflower Seeds:</strong> Rich in vitamin E, increases sperm count and motility.</li><li><strong>Pumpkin Seeds:</strong> High in zinc, essential for sperm and egg production.</li><li><strong>Flax Seeds:</strong> Improves egg and sperm quality.</li><li><strong>Chia Seeds:</strong> Maintains hormonal balance and improves fertility.</li></ul><blockquote>“Always consult a specialist or a doctor for more information pertaining to your health and history.”</blockquote><p>Incorporating these nuts and seeds can be beneficial for couples looking to conceive, promoting better health and fertility overall.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/photo-gallery/nuts-seeds-couples-conceive-fertility-conception-pregnancy-health-almonds-walnuts-chia-seeds-pistachios-raisins-1163342/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/photo-gallery/nuts-seeds-couples-conceive-fertility-conception-pregnancy-health-almonds-walnuts-chia-seeds-pistachios-raisins-1163342/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 03:30:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[People with THIS blood group have good immunity - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/people-with-this-blood-group-have-good-immunity/articleshow/116376146.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/people-with-this-blood-group-have-good-immunity/articleshow/116376146.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 03:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bavarian Nordic partners with SII for Mpox vaccine production - DrugsControl.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiY0FVX3lxTE1CN2tjak5EX19lVldwVlpUZjZpWkFsYWxqdHJGYkRhZzNtSnY2ZHBZbVhLUGZhVmVFZW4weUZ1dWpQZVk0U0JsVWVZMDZfWWlMZFFOeHBRTWlZaEwxTUEyaDk0WQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiY0FVX3lxTE1CN2tjak5EX19lVldwVlpUZjZpWkFsYWxqdHJGYkRhZzNtSnY2ZHBZbVhLUGZhVmVFZW4weUZ1dWpQZVk0U0JsVWVZMDZfWWlMZFFOeHBRTWlZaEwxTUEyaDk0WQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 02:14:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Staying sharp: Study explores how brain changes may affect financial skills - Science Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>chrome-error://chromewebdata/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">chrome-error://chromewebdata/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 02:04:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As holiday season approaches, experts warn that high-intensity drinking is worse than binge-drinking - Asianet Newsable]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxQWEw1b0RlU0puN3g3U2U3R1MzaVZtMHJKSU9fVkdTcWxoR3FESUxLVUhnQzlENzFZa1JKR01mSzNlTWdHQ1lMa2lhX296c2pVR1M5bC05S3lNdi1udUs1Vlo2RDlhYnI4OXQxbk5vOW1fSlYxUjI4TGIzaG00Wm5Vc1NiSE1xSXV1VWpYQkNxTFFNeHY4NmdKcGxWX2xXMkVSZ1JYZkhHbVFPYXNodTd5MW1pT0lOQ1k3eFdzVGktREwwQzhyamN3Y1l3UnVPUHpDQUNiNjNEMVlRTVctMWFkTUpqNmtEaW9x0gHuAUFVX3lxTFBHdzBuTnVWc3k0bWNNRk50dGZ2dTI0Q3RUS080c214dDRwbFp3SGhwZkx5VEp1NTdlQlVmM0tTXzVWSFN2cDBtc0JjaTh1SjNRZGtvU0NaRVB6alBoTkJTTFZ2TDN2M2ZGc3AxS3NBZVJySUNLdVlRSXRaSldXdWRlbFBueTVsNjd4SUVsZ0dBbXZNLVVnak9xWHpjN0hRX2lIelZWbVVtcWRrcFRQd0IxUTUwbkViUy00NHRGUm1nU29LNXVBZ2Q1UlBleEsxeXNFMzlYeWNESEtVdS1Ud3MtOVUzazlPTnJqckd4VUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxQWEw1b0RlU0puN3g3U2U3R1MzaVZtMHJKSU9fVkdTcWxoR3FESUxLVUhnQzlENzFZa1JKR01mSzNlTWdHQ1lMa2lhX296c2pVR1M5bC05S3lNdi1udUs1Vlo2RDlhYnI4OXQxbk5vOW1fSlYxUjI4TGIzaG00Wm5Vc1NiSE1xSXV1VWpYQkNxTFFNeHY4NmdKcGxWX2xXMkVSZ1JYZkhHbVFPYXNodTd5MW1pT0lOQ1k3eFdzVGktREwwQzhyamN3Y1l3UnVPUHpDQUNiNjNEMVlRTVctMWFkTUpqNmtEaW9x0gHuAUFVX3lxTFBHdzBuTnVWc3k0bWNNRk50dGZ2dTI0Q3RUS080c214dDRwbFp3SGhwZkx5VEp1NTdlQlVmM0tTXzVWSFN2cDBtc0JjaTh1SjNRZGtvU0NaRVB6alBoTkJTTFZ2TDN2M2ZGc3AxS3NBZVJySUNLdVlRSXRaSldXdWRlbFBueTVsNjd4SUVsZ0dBbXZNLVVnak9xWHpjN0hRX2lIelZWbVVtcWRrcFRQd0IxUTUwbkViUy00NHRGUm1nU29LNXVBZ2Q1UlBleEsxeXNFMzlYeWNESEtVdS1Ud3MtOVUzazlPTnJqckd4VUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 02:00:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Afflicted with flu? Take rest at home - China Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE1Dd3lsRGZ6S0o1N0tQVDNCNFFPc1U0N0kwT0E2UzQ2dXV5UkJZWEd6WFl4LWhyb0prYm13VmtKakR5MVNRZ3pSU1lKNHRySllTR0hhU2VBOU85MGJZdXVEd1FzNkkzNERTakVldG5VRzFIMGg4aE1FbVdiLTRrZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE1Dd3lsRGZ6S0o1N0tQVDNCNFFPc1U0N0kwT0E2UzQ2dXV5UkJZWEd6WFl4LWhyb0prYm13VmtKakR5MVNRZ3pSU1lKNHRySllTR0hhU2VBOU85MGJZdXVEd1FzNkkzNERTakVldG5VRzFIMGg4aE1FbVdiLTRrZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 01:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intermittent fasting may lead to hair loss, says Chinese study - South First]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQdTk3Q2hNUV95Q05iWFNSUXdFVnowazZZRDVjZjRkRWVzYUE5RkJhVzhfUHI4SVhycDlhcHVVUXJ1TXo1TExhM0pBMVlpYzZvdUhuRG9hcm1vLXBFdlpwb1AtYlZ4bTVSYWZ2TFBicE96WTFyUzNPVi1CNzRfbGFUX3NLUVpEaVJOdVZ2djgydTctOFlxWEwtX3dldw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQdTk3Q2hNUV95Q05iWFNSUXdFVnowazZZRDVjZjRkRWVzYUE5RkJhVzhfUHI4SVhycDlhcHVVUXJ1TXo1TExhM0pBMVlpYzZvdUhuRG9hcm1vLXBFdlpwb1AtYlZ4bTVSYWZ2TFBicE96WTFyUzNPVi1CNzRfbGFUX3NLUVpEaVJOdVZ2djgydTctOFlxWEwtX3dldw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 01:32:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1 Vape Equals 30 Cigarettes' Nicotine - Mirage News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>One Vape Contains the Nicotine Equivalent of 30 Cigarettes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> UCSF News</p><p>This article highlights the alarming statistics surrounding vaping among U.S. middle and high school students, particularly the increased nicotine potency of modern vapes and the health implications of this trend.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Over 1.6 million U.S. students reported vaping in 2023, with nearly 90% using flavored products.</li><li>Vape cartridges now can contain nicotine equivalent to 600 cigarettes.</li><li>Vaping's health risks, particularly regarding lung disease and cardiovascular health, remain unclear.</li><li>Youths face increased risks of nicotine addiction due to the potency and delivery mechanism of vapes.</li></ul><blockquote>"The earlier you are exposed to nicotine, the more likely you are to become addicted." - Dr. Pamela Ling</blockquote><p>The growing prevalence of vaping among youth raises concerns regarding addiction and long-term health outcomes. Understanding these risks is crucial as we navigate the current vaping landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.miragenews.com/1-vape-equals-30-cigarettes-nicotine-1379894/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.miragenews.com/1-vape-equals-30-cigarettes-nicotine-1379894/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 01:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tips To Protect Your Heart Health During Smog Season - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tips to Protect Your Heart Health During Smog Season</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='While stepping outside, ensure you wear a mask to cover the nose and mouth.(Representative/File Photo)'/><figcaption>While stepping outside, ensure you wear a mask to cover the nose and mouth.(Representative/File Photo)</figcaption><p>The onset of winter brings concerns for individuals with heart issues, as cold weather and increased pollution levels can negatively affect heart health. Pollutants can lead to inflammation in blood vessels, plaque buildup, and an increased risk of heart attacks and strokes.</p><ul><li>Limit outdoor activities on days with poor air quality.</li><li>Wear a mask when going outside to filter polluted air.</li><li>Stay hydrated to support cardiovascular health.</li><li>Monitor blood pressure regularly during smog season.</li><li>Pay attention to symptoms of heart stress such as shortness of breath and chest discomfort.</li><li>Schedule regular health checkups and ECG tests.</li><li>Maintain a heart-healthy diet rich in anti-inflammatory foods.</li><li>Engage in regular exercise, avoiding excessive exertion in polluted conditions.</li><li>Use an air purifier to reduce indoor pollutants.</li><li>Track local air quality using apps for better safety measures.</li></ul><blockquote>“Monitoring air quality indexes (AQI) and staying indoors when pollution levels are high is crucial for heart health.”</blockquote><p>Taking measure to protect heart health during smog season is essential, especially for vulnerable individuals. By following these tips, one can mitigate the impact of pollution and cold weather on cardiovascular health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/tips-to-protect-your-heart-health-during-smog-season-9124342.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/tips-to-protect-your-heart-health-during-smog-season-9124342.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India sets up its first diabetes biobank - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Sets Up Its First Diabetes Biobank</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/1odx7v/article68993537.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_A_person_receives_a__2_1_VRDKG1DP.jpg" alt="A person receives blood sugar test. File" title="A person receives blood sugar test. File" />
<figcaption>A person receives blood sugar test. File | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption>
<p>Aimed at facilitating advanced research on diabetes, the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) in collaboration with the Madras Diabetes Research Foundation (MDRF) has set up the country’s first diabetes biobank in Chennai.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The biobank will gather, process, store, and distribute biospecimens for scientific studies.</li>
  <li>A variety of blood samples from different types of diabetes have been stored for future studies.</li>
  <li>The initiative aims to identify novel biomarkers for early diagnosis and develop personalized treatment strategies.</li>
  <li>A government study indicated a rising prevalence of diabetes among the general population in India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The biobank could help in the identification of novel biomarkers for early diagnosis and the development of personalised treatment strategies.” - Dr. V. Mohan</blockquote>
<p>The establishment of this biobank represents a significant step in addressing the diabetes epidemic in India, promising better management and prevention strategies for the condition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/india-sets-up-its-first-diabetes-biobank-chennai/article68992294.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/india-sets-up-its-first-diabetes-biobank-chennai/article68992294.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 23:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 superfoods that contain high protein and low calorie - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Superfoods High in Protein and Low in Calories</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2024/12/16/900x1600/pexels-photo-3622475_1734350074018.jpeg" alt="FUEL YOUR BODY" /><figcaption>FUEL YOUR BODY</figcaption><p>Nutrient-rich foods are essential for health. Low-calorie, high-protein diets support weight management and muscle growth, although a balanced diet is crucial for overall well-being.</p><ul><li>Chickpeas: High in fiber and protein, great for salads, hummus, or as snacks.</li><li>Prawns: Low-calorie, rich in omega-3 and B vitamins, similar protein to chicken but fewer calories.</li><li>Sprouts: Enhance meals with essential nutrients and protein.</li><li>Tuna: 23 grams of protein per serving, perfect for quick meals.</li><li>Broccoli: Surprisingly high in protein for a vegetable.</li><li>Protein Bars: Convenient for extra protein but watch calorie intake.</li></ul><blockquote>"Nutrient-rich foods are vital for health. Low-calorie, high-protein diets aid weight management and muscle growth."</blockquote><p>The emphasis on incorporating these superfoods can contribute significantly to a healthy diet while helping manage calorie intake.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/6-superfoods-that-contain-high-protein-and-low-calorie-visual-story-11734348297635.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/6-superfoods-that-contain-high-protein-and-low-calorie-visual-story-11734348297635.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:06:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Step Up! Here's How to Start a Healthy Walking Habit - HealthDay]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Step Up! Here's How to Start a Healthy Walking Habit</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="" width="100%" height="100%">
<figcaption>Adobe Stock</figcaption>
<p>Starting a walking routine is simple and requires minimal equipment, making it accessible for many.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Walking can improve sleep, memory, and anxiety.</li>
  <li>Benefits include lowering blood pressure, reducing diabetes risk, and boosting immunity.</li>
  <li>Integrating walking into daily life is easy and convenient.</li>
  <li>Walking at a brisk pace is linked to burning calories and reducing health risks.</li>
  <li>Strategies like keeping walking shoes handy can help maintain the habit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Taking just a few more steps per day, that's a great way to get started.” - Amanda Paluch</blockquote>
<p>Conclusion: Walking is an effective way to improve overall health and well-being, requiring minimal resources and offering substantial benefits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthday.com/a-to-z-health/exercise-and-fitness/step-up-heres-how-to-start-a-healthy-walking-habit</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthday.com/a-to-z-health/exercise-and-fitness/step-up-heres-how-to-start-a-healthy-walking-habit</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:30:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>