<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:30:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:30:26 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV virus in India: Two suspected cases detected in Maharashtra's Nagpur - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Virus in India: Two Suspected Cases Detected in Maharashtra's Nagpur</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/hmpv_1736154077379_1736227143393.jpg" alt="A child has been detected with HMPV infection at private hospital in Gujarat's Ahmedabad. (Pixabay/Representative)"><figcaption>A child has been detected with HMPV infection at private hospital in Gujarat's Ahmedabad. (Pixabay/Representative)</figcaption><p>Two suspected cases of HMPV in Nagpur have been identified, with both patients being 7 and 13 years old. The health authorities are sending samples for examination at AIIMS Nagpur.</p><ul><li>Five cases of HMPV have been detected in India, including two in Bengaluru and one in Ahmedabad.</li><li>The recent patients in Nagpur tested positive and have been treated and discharged.</li><li>Union Health Minister JP Nadda reassured the public, stating the virus poses no new threat and health systems are prepared.</li><li>HMPV is not a new virus, first identified in 2001, and spreads through the air, more commonly in winter.</li></ul><blockquote>“Health experts have clarified that HMPV is not a new virus. It was first identified in 2001.” - JP Nadda, Union Health Minister</blockquote><p>The government is ensuring ongoing monitoring and preparedness in response to HMPV cases in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hnpv-detected-in-maharashtra-2-suspected-cases-of-human-metapneumovirus-found-in-nagpur-101736226811003.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hnpv-detected-in-maharashtra-2-suspected-cases-of-human-metapneumovirus-found-in-nagpur-101736226811003.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:24:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's HMPV count reaches 7, latest cases reported in Tamil Nadu - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's HMPV Count Reaches 7, Latest Cases Reported in Tamil Nadu</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> TOI</p>
<p>India has reported seven cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in children across various states. The Union Health Minister has reassured that the situation is under control.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Seven confirmed cases of HMPV in children across Bengaluru, Nagpur, Tamil Nadu, and Ahmedabad.</li>
  <li>Union Health Minister J.P. Nadda says there is no risk of a COVID-like outbreak.</li>
  <li>Notable cases include a three-month-old girl who recovered after treatment in Bengaluru.</li>
  <li>The virus is self-limiting and typically resolves with symptomatic care.</li>
  <li>No significant surge in respiratory illnesses reported in Tamil Nadu.</li>
  <li>Financial markets reacted negatively, with significant drops in the Sensex and Nifty indices.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"HMPV infections are self-limiting and resolve with symptomatic care, including adequate hydration and rest." - Supriya Sahu, Health Secretary, Tamil Nadu</blockquote>
<p>Ongoing surveillance and preventive measures are being implemented as health officials monitor the situation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/indias-hmpv-count-reaches-7-latest-cases-reported-in-tamil-nadu/articleshow/117006987.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/indias-hmpv-count-reaches-7-latest-cases-reported-in-tamil-nadu/articleshow/117006987.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:24:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[France confirms first mpox variant case - theSun]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>France Confirms Its First Case of the New Mpox Variant</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Monday</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Health Ministry of France</p>
<p>France has reported its first instance of the mpox virus variant, identified as clade 1b, in the Brittany region. This confirmation comes following a high alert status from the World Health Organization regarding the epidemic.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The case was confirmed in a person who has not traveled to central Africa but was in contact with travelers from that region.</li>
  <li>Mpox can be transmitted through infected animals and human-to-human contact.</li>
  <li>The virus leads to symptoms such as fever, muscular aches, and skin lesions.</li>
  <li>The WHO continues to monitor the outbreak, having declared an emergency in August and renewed it in November.</li>
  <li>Mpox variants have been reported globally, with Clade 1b noted in 80 countries, including 19 in Africa.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Rapid action” is advised for European nations to contain the latest variant, according to the WHO.</blockquote>
<p>The situation is being monitored as inquiries proceed to trace the infection's origin and contact network.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thesun.my/world-news/france-confirms-first-mpox-variant-case-BO13488955</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thesun.my/world-news/france-confirms-first-mpox-variant-case-BO13488955</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 cases of HMPV detected; no cause for concern: Nadda - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Cases of HMPV Detected; No Cause for Concern: Nadda</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent Update<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Health Minister Nadda has addressed concerns regarding the detection of seven cases of HMPV (Human Metapneumovirus), assuring the public that there is no cause for alarm.</p><ul><li>Seven cases of HMPV have been reported.</li><li>Health Minister emphasizes that there is no immediate threat to the public.</li><li>Precautionary measures are advised but no drastic actions are needed.</li><li>The government is monitoring the situation closely.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no cause for concern currently, but we advise the public to stay informed and adhere to health protocols.”</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the importance of health awareness and the government's proactive measures in monitoring potential health risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/7-cases-of-hmpv-detected-no-cause-for-concern-nadda/articleshow/117004366.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/7-cases-of-hmpv-detected-no-cause-for-concern-nadda/articleshow/117004366.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 21:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First U.S. bird flu death reported in Louisiana patient, officials say - The Washington Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First U.S. Bird Flu Death Reported in Louisiana</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 18, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Louisiana Department of Health</p><p>A Louisiana man has become the first person in the United States to die of avian influenza, state health officials reported Monday. The patient had underlying medical conditions and was hospitalized weeks ago in critical condition.</p><ul><li>The patient was older than 65 and had been in contact with sick and dead birds on his property.</li><li>He was hospitalized with severe respiratory illness related to the H5N1 bird flu virus.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a serious situation, and we must remain vigilant,” state officials stated.</blockquote><p>The death of this patient raises concerns about the potential human health risks of avian influenza and emphasizes the need for continued monitoring and preventive measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2025/01/06/bird-flu-first-human-death-us/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2025/01/06/bird-flu-first-human-death-us/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 21:49:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Louisiana reports first human death in US from bird flu - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Louisiana Reports First Human Death in US from Bird Flu</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Publication Date Needed] | <strong>Source:</strong> Associated Press</p>
<p>A patient in Louisiana has become the first human in the US to die of bird flu. The Louisiana department of health reported that the patient, over the age of 65 with underlying medical conditions, contracted H5N1 after exposure to birds.</p>
<ul>
  <li>This is the first human case in the US linked to exposure to backyard birds.</li>
  <li>A genetic analysis suggested that the virus mutated within the patient, potentially leading to severe illness.</li>
  <li>There are no additional H5N1 cases or evidence of person-to-person transmission identified.</li>
  <li>The current public health risk for the general public is deemed low.</li>
  <li>66 confirmed bird flu infections have been reported in the US since March last year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The department expresses its deepest condolences to the patient’s family and friends as they mourn the loss of their loved one.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while the public health risk remains low, individuals working with birds or livestock are at a higher risk of exposure to H5N1.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jan/06/first-human-death-bird-flu-louisiana</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jan/06/first-human-death-bird-flu-louisiana</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 21:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[America’s first bird flu death reported in Louisiana - CNN International]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>America’s First Bird Flu Death Reported in Louisiana</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p>
<img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/ap24361859677442.jpg?c=original" alt="The patient had been hospitalized with severe bird flu after exposure to a backyard flock and to wild birds.">
<figcaption>The patient had been hospitalized with severe bird flu after exposure to a backyard flock and to wild birds.</figcaption>
<p>The first confirmed human death from H5N1 bird flu has been reported in Louisiana, marking a significant health concern. The individual had pre-existing health conditions and had been in contact with infected birds.</p>
<ul>
<li>The patient, over 65, had underlying health issues and was hospitalized after exposure to both domestic and wild birds.</li>
<li>Health officials have not identified any other human cases linked to this infection.</li>
<li>Experts warn that H5N1 is a severe strain; the case fatality rate globally is about 50% based on reported infections.</li>
<li>The CDC is monitoring the virus's evolution, noting genetic changes that may enhance its infectiousness in humans.</li>
<li>Guidance has been issued for individuals working with or in contact with birds, stressing the importance of avoiding sick animals.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The evolution of the virus is concerning but highlights how we need to prevent each possible spillover infection to reduce the risk of onward transmission to others.” - Dr. Seema Lakdawala</blockquote>
<p>The death has raised alarms over the potential spread of H5N1, although authorities maintain that the immediate risk to the general public remains low.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://edition.cnn.com/2025/01/06/health/bird-flu-death-louisiana/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://edition.cnn.com/2025/01/06/health/bird-flu-death-louisiana/index.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 20:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV Symptoms And Treatment: How Common Is The Virus And How To Take Care Of Its Patients? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Symptoms And Treatment: How Common Is The Virus And How To Take Care Of Its Patients?</h1><p><strong>Last Updated: </strong><time>January 06, 2025, 23:06 IST</time></p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="HMPV: The WHO is already providing timely updates regarding the situation in China. (News18 Hindi)" title="HMPV: The WHO is already providing timely updates regarding the situation in China. (News18 Hindi)"><figcaption>HMPV: The WHO is already providing timely updates regarding the situation in China. (News18 Hindi)</figcaption></figure><p>The Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) has detected two cases of human metapneumovirus (HMPV) in Karnataka. A three-month-old girl and an eight-month-old boy with bronchopneumonia are recovering, with no recent travel history.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>HMPV cases are detected due to routine surveillance.</li><li>The virus can cause symptoms similar to the common cold and can lead to more severe respiratory issues.</li><li>Around 10% to 12% of respiratory illnesses in children are attributed to HMPV.</li><li>Most cases are mild, but some may require medical attention if symptoms worsen.</li><li>Preventive measures include hand washing and avoiding close contact with infected individuals.</li></ul><blockquote>"It is important to note that neither of the patients has any history of international travel."</blockquote><p>Given the lack of unusual surges in respiratory illnesses, HMPV seems to be manageable in the current context, according to health authorities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/hmpv-symptoms-and-treatment-how-common-is-the-virus-and-how-to-take-care-of-its-patients-9178693.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/hmpv-symptoms-and-treatment-how-common-is-the-virus-and-how-to-take-care-of-its-patients-9178693.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 20:07:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Global HMPV Tracker: Tamil Nadu Detects 2 Cases, India's Tally Rises To 5 - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Global HMPV Tracker: Tamil Nadu Detects 2 Cases, India's Tally Rises To 5</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>The first reported instances of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in India were confirmed, with a total of five cases. This includes two cases in Tamil Nadu, as the health ministry warns of the ongoing respiratory virus that has recently gained global attention.</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/1c0t3qog_covid-india_625x300_27_December_22.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" alt="" />
<figcaption>Image depicting HMPV prevalence in India.</figcaption>
<ul>
  <li>Five cases of HMPV confirmed in India, first detected in Bengaluru.</li>
  <li>Affected infants show no recent travel history, ruling out external exposure.</li>
  <li>Health departments in multiple states issue guidelines similar to COVID-19 protocols.</li>
  <li>The virus primarily affects children below five, older adults, and those with weakened immune systems.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Union Health Minister JP Nadda stated, "HMPV is not a new virus. It was first identified in 2001 and it has been circulating in the entire world since many years." </blockquote>
<p>The emergence of HMPV highlights the importance of ongoing monitoring and public health preparedness in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-hmpv-tracker-karnataka-maharashtra-issue-guidelines-amid-rising-cases-china-hmpv-virus-scare-bengaluru-virus-7409815</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-hmpv-tracker-karnataka-maharashtra-issue-guidelines-amid-rising-cases-china-hmpv-virus-scare-bengaluru-virus-7409815</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 18:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sugary drinks linked to millions of new diabetes and heart disease cases – study - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sugary Drinks Linked to Millions of New Diabetes and Heart Disease Cases</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Monday, source: Nature Medicine</p>
<img src="https://example.com/image.jpg" alt="Sugary Drinks" />
<figcaption>A global study finds sugary drinks responsible for millions of diabetes and heart disease cases.</figcaption>
<p>A new global study reveals that sugary drinks contribute to over 2.2 million new diabetes cases and 1.1 million heart disease cases annually worldwide, highlighting severe health inequalities, especially in low- and middle-income countries.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sugary drinks contribute to 24% of new diabetes cases in Latin America and the Caribbean.</li>
  <li>In sub-Saharan Africa, these drinks are linked to 21% of new diabetes cases and 11% of heart disease cases.</li>
  <li>Countries like Colombia, Mexico, and South Africa are particularly affected, with sugary drinks responsible for 48% and nearly one-third of diabetes cases respectively.</li>
  <li>Regular consumption of sugary drinks is linked to numerous health issues, including weight gain and metabolic disorders.</li>
  <li>Experts warn that the rise in diabetes cases may overwhelm healthcare systems.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“As a species, we need to address sugar-sweetened beverage consumption.” - Dariush Mozaffarian</blockquote>
<p>The study authors advocate for public health initiatives, regulations on advertising, and sugar taxes to mitigate rising health issues associated with sugary drinks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/jan/06/global-health-inequalities-sugary-drinks-diabetes-heart-disease-africa-latin-america-influencers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/jan/06/global-health-inequalities-sugary-drinks-diabetes-heart-disease-africa-latin-america-influencers</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 17:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases LIVE: 5 cases in India, govt asks people to not panic as #lockdown trends - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Cases LIVE: 5 cases in India, govt asks people to not panic as #lockdown trends</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/hmpv_virus_india__1736157385724_1736157385994.jpg" alt="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat." loading="lazy"><figcaption>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</figcaption><p>India has confirmed five cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) amidst rising fears resembling the Covid pandemic. However, health officials assure the public that there is no need to panic as HMPV is not a new virus but similar to the regular flu.</p><ul><li>The first five confirmed cases are located in Karnataka, Gujarat, and Tamil Nadu, primarily affecting children.</li><li>Health officials emphasize that existing vaccinations for flu and Covid provide immunity against HMPV.</li><li>Government officials are appealing to the public to stay calm as the situation is being closely monitored.</li><li>Health Minister JP Nadda has reassured citizens that HMPV is an existing pathogen, not a cause for alarm.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is nothing to worry about and people need not panic, it is a mild form of the common cold.” - Dr. Sharan Prakash, Karnataka Minister for Medical Education</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while the recent detection of HMPV has raised concerns, health authorities stress that it is manageable and does not warrant panic among the public.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 17:28:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sugary drinks may cause more than 330,000 deaths a year, study suggests - Channel3000.com - WISC-TV3]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sugary Drinks Linked to Over 330,000 Deaths Annually, Study Reveals</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p><p>This new study indicates that sugary beverages may contribute to more than 330,000 deaths each year due to diabetes and cardiovascular disease, highlighting a significant public health concern.</p><ul><li>The study published in <em>Nature Medicine</em> analyzed global consumption data of sugar-sweetened beverages.</li><li>Latin America and the Caribbean show the highest prevalence of cardiovascular-related deaths linked to these drinks.</li><li>Younger male adults in urban areas with higher education are identified as the most affected demographic.</li><li>The effects of sugary drinks on health, especially in relation to diabetes and heart disease, are emphasized.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a public health crisis, requiring urgent action.” - Dr. Dariush Mozaffarian</blockquote><p>The study underscores the necessity for urgent action against sugary drink consumption to prevent further health crises.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.channel3000.com/news/sugary-drinks-may-cause-more-than-330-000-deaths-a-year-study-suggests/article_38198618-c258-507f-aa60-ece8f8aa94cf.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.channel3000.com/news/sugary-drinks-may-cause-more-than-330-000-deaths-a-year-study-suggests/article_38198618-c258-507f-aa60-ece8f8aa94cf.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 16:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases LIVE: ‘Virus not new’, says govt as #lockdown trends on X; India's case tally now 5 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Cases LIVE: ‘Virus not new’, says govt as #lockdown trends on X; India's case tally now 5</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/hmpv_virus_india__1736157385724_1736157385994.jpg" alt="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat."><figcaption>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed five cases so far.</figcaption><p>The Indian government confirmed five cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) and reassured the public that the virus is not new and is similar to regular flu. This reassurance comes as concerns, amplified on social media, led to the trending of #lockdown.</p><ul><li>India's case count includes five confirmed cases: two in Karnataka, one in Gujarat, and two in Tamil Nadu, all detected in children.</li><li>Health officials emphasized that HMPV has been circulating for years and poses less risk compared to Covid-19.</li><li>Health Minister JP Nadda stated that regular flu vaccinations provide immunity against HMPV.</li><li>Government agencies are monitoring the situation and urging the public not to panic.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no reason to panic,” said Health Minister JP Nadda.</blockquote><p>This public reassurance aims to alleviate fear surrounding the HMPV cases as India takes proactive measures to manage public health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:51:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases LIVE: ‘Virus not new, no need to panic’, says govt as #lockdown trends on X - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV cases LIVE: ‘Virus not new, no need to panic’, says govt as #lockdown trends on X</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/hmpv_virus_india__1736157385724_1736157385994.jpg" alt="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat." title="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.">
<figcaption>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</figcaption>
<p>The government reassured the public that HMPV is not a new virus after confirming three cases in India. Health experts emphasize there is no need to panic as the virus resembles a regular flu.</p>
<ul>
<li>Three cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) confirmed in India, two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</li>
<li>Cases detected in children; health officials stress that there is no cause for alarm.</li>
<li>Regular flu shots provide immunity; HMPV is not as transmissible as Covid-19.</li>
<li>Health ministry reports no unusual surge in related respiratory illnesses in the country.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“HMPV has been circulating for years and there is no reason to panic.” – Health Minister JP Nadda</blockquote>
<p>The health officials are actively monitoring the situation, ensuring preparedness to handle any potential increase in respiratory illnesses.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:53:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV not new virus in India: Health Ministry says as cases detected - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Not a New Virus in India, Health Ministry Clarifies Amid Cases</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 06, 2025 by The Hindu</p><div><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/oujhuf/article69069108.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/PTI08_13_2024_000249A.jpg" alt="Union Health Minister J.P. Nadda. File." width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Union Health Minister J.P. Nadda. File. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption></div><p>The Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) is already in circulation globally, including in India, with cases reported but no alarming increase according to the Health Ministry. Health experts assure that the virus is not new and precautions are necessary.</p><ul><li>The HMPV has been circulating since its identification in 2001.</li><li>Current cases in India do not involve individuals with travel history.</li><li>Health systems remain vigilant without significant risk to the public.</li><li>Precautions similar to those for common cold are recommended.</li><li>Health Departments are monitoring and issuing advisories to handle potential spread.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s a known virus that causes respiratory infections, mostly mild.” - Soumya Swaminathan, former chief scientist, WHO</blockquote><p>Overall, there is no reason for panic as the health systems are managing the situation effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/hmpv-not-new-virus-in-india-health-ministry-says-as-cases-detected/article69067772.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/hmpv-not-new-virus-in-india-health-ministry-says-as-cases-detected/article69067772.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV infections surging in northern China, but not in the Netherlands - NL Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxNZndsVks5bXFTZUFqR0s3b2FVMW1LamIySmVIWlhWMjRRcmtEcW1HWGkwaGZzeDlHZGpYNEVkME5KWEhQYkhZRHd1cElZWnJhdXppUFhPa1ZEOEdEcnRyUlRmYi1xbWNwdHBDV3lraVFJX3RLNVhxbFlHTzNFZWtZWUF6ZEUtOFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxNZndsVks5bXFTZUFqR0s3b2FVMW1LamIySmVIWlhWMjRRcmtEcW1HWGkwaGZzeDlHZGpYNEVkME5KWEhQYkhZRHd1cElZWnJhdXppUFhPa1ZEOEdEcnRyUlRmYi1xbWNwdHBDV3lraVFJX3RLNVhxbFlHTzNFZWtZWUF6ZEUtOFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Global HMPV Tracker: Karnataka, Maharashtra, Delhi Issue Guidelines As 3 Cases Reported In India - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Global HMPV Tracker: Karnataka, Maharashtra, Delhi Issue Guidelines As 3 Cases Reported In India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>Three cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) were confirmed in India, marking the first reported instances of the virus in the country. The Union health ministry is monitoring the situation closely.</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/1c0t3qog_covid-india_625x300_27_December_22.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738"><figcaption>Image showing a health alert regarding respiratory viruses</figcaption><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Confirmed cases in Bengaluru and Ahmedabad.</li><li>Guidelines issued by Karnataka, Maharashtra, and Delhi governments.</li><li>Most of the Indian population is reportedly immune to HMPV.</li></ul><blockquote>“HMPV is not a new virus. It has been part of the circulating flu virus in India for long.” - Dr. Harshal R Salve</blockquote><p>The outbreak has prompted precautions similar to those taken during the COVID-19 pandemic, as health officials remain vigilant.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-hmpv-tracker-karnataka-maharashtra-issue-guidelines-amid-rising-cases-china-hmpv-virus-scare-bengaluru-virus-7409815</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-hmpv-tracker-karnataka-maharashtra-issue-guidelines-amid-rising-cases-china-hmpv-virus-scare-bengaluru-virus-7409815</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:26:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV virus cases LIVE: 3 cases in India; experts say virus old, ‘don’t unnecessarily panic' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: ‘Virus not new, no need to panic’, says govt as #lockdown trends on X</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/hmpv_virus_india__1736157385724_1736157385994.jpg" alt="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat." title="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat."><figcaption>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</figcaption></div><p>The Indian government confirmed three cases of the Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in children, urging the public not to panic as this virus has been known for years.</p><ul><li>Three cases of HMPV confirmed in India: two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</li><li>All cases detected in children without recent travel history.</li><li>Health minister reassures public about the virus being non-new and similar to flu.</li><li>Health experts highlight flu shots as a form of immunity against HMPV.</li><li>No immediate cause for alarm, according to health officials and experts.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no need to panic over HMPV as it is not a new pathogen and results in regular flu-like symptoms.” - Union Health Minister JP Nadda</blockquote><p>The government is taking measures to monitor the situation and ensure public safety. The public is encouraged to follow standard health precautions to prevent respiratory infections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:04:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV virus cases LIVE: 3 cases in India; Karnataka issues advisory titled ‘Do Not Panic’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: 3 cases in India; Karnataka issues advisory titled ‘Do Not Panic’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/hmpv_virus_india__1736157385724_1736157385994.jpg" alt="HMPV Virus confirmation in India" title="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat."><figcaption>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</figcaption><p>India has confirmed its first three cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), prompting health officials to reassure the public that the virus is akin to regular flu and not a new threat.</p><ul><li>Three cases of HMPV have been confirmed in India: two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat, all in children.</li><li>Health officials emphasize that HMPV is not a new pathogen, and flu and Covid vaccinations provide immunity.</li><li>The Karnataka government has issued an advisory titled 'Do Not Panic, Be Aware'.</li><li>Symptoms resemble those of the common cold, with serious cases leading to bronchitis or pneumonia.</li><li>Experts highlight the importance of routine surveillance and public awareness about HMPV.</li></ul><blockquote>“HMPV is an existing flu virus causing respiratory issues and is not a cause for panic,” said Karnataka Health Minister Dinesh Gundu Rao.</blockquote><p>This outbreak underscores the need for vigilance and proper health measures as health authorities monitor and respond to HMPV cases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:55:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 longevity goals to set for a healthier, happier 2025 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Longevity Goals to Set for a Healthier, Happier 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116995092,imgsize-18438,width-400,resizemode-4/116995092.jpg" alt="7 longevity goals to set for a healthier, happier 2025" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>7 longevity goals to improve health and happiness in 2025.</figcaption><p>As the new year approaches, it's a great time to lay out wellness and happiness goals to make 2025 memorable. Focusing on longevity involves adding quality to your years, not just quantity.</p><ul><li>Walk 10,000 steps every day to stay fit and healthy.</li><li>Get proper sleep, aiming for 7 to 8 hours each night.</li><li>Try new hobbies to keep your brain engaged and active.</li><li>Drink plenty of water—8 liters a day is recommended.</li><li>Eat healthy food to maintain energy and productivity.</li><li>Socialize and connect with friends and communities.</li><li>Laugh regularly, as laughter is a great mood booster.</li></ul><blockquote>“Laughter is the best medicine.”</blockquote><p>By setting these goals, you can focus on both health and happiness, making the upcoming year one to cherish.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/7-longevity-goals-to-set-for-a-healthier-happier-2025/articleshow/116995069.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/7-longevity-goals-to-set-for-a-healthier-happier-2025/articleshow/116995069.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Global HMPV Tracker: Karnataka, Maharashtra, Delhi Issue Guidelines As Cases Rise - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Global HMPV Tracker: Karnataka, Maharashtra, Delhi Issue Guidelines As Cases Rise</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Recent</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Union Health Ministry</p><p>The article reports the first confirmed cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in India, with cases in Bengaluru and Ahmedabad. The Union health ministry is proactively monitoring the situation.</p><ul><li>Three cases of HMPV confirmed in India.</li><li>Affected infants are from Bengaluru and Ahmedabad, with no recent travel history.</li><li>Karnataka, Maharashtra, and Delhi governments have issued preparedness guidelines.</li><li>HMPV is a respiratory virus recognized worldwide, particularly affecting young children and those with weakened immune systems.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Indian Council of Medical Research (IMCR) will continue to track trends in HMPV circulation throughout the year.”</blockquote><p>The emergence of HMPV cases underscores the need for vigilant health measures and monitoring.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-hmpv-tracker-karnataka-maharashtra-issue-guidelines-amid-rising-cases-china-hmpv-virus-scare-bengaluru-virus-7409815</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-hmpv-tracker-karnataka-maharashtra-issue-guidelines-amid-rising-cases-china-hmpv-virus-scare-bengaluru-virus-7409815</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:00:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is the ‘vomiting bug’ norovirus? Explained - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What is the ‘vomiting bug’ norovirus? Explained</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> January 06, 2025 04:25 pm IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/2cacyz/article69067919.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_iStock-1264508383_2_1_B296HBHC.jpg" alt="Norovirus Image" />
<figcaption>Photograph used for representational purposes only | Photo Credit: Getty Images/iStockphoto</figcaption>
<p>The article provides an overview of norovirus, also known as the 'vomiting bug', which has seen increased outbreaks during winter in the United States while India faces other viral issues. It outlines the virus’s symptoms, transmission, and preventive measures.</p>
<ul>
<li>Norovirus is responsible for vomiting and diarrhea, part of the Caliciviridae family of viruses.</li>
<li>It was first identified in 1968 in Norwalk, Ohio.</li>
<li>Symptoms include stomach pain, nausea, diarrhea, and vomiting, appearing within 12 to 48 hours after exposure.</li>
<li>The virus spreads through contaminated food, water, surfaces, and close contact with infected individuals.</li>
<li>No specific treatment exists; hydration and rest are recommended.</li>
<li>Preventive measures include hand washing, cooking seafood thoroughly, and disinfecting surfaces.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Norovirus is the leading cause of vomiting and diarrhea in the United States.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, understanding norovirus is essential for prevention and control, particularly in crowded settings during outbreak seasons.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/what-is-the-vomiting-bug-norovirus-explained/article69067844.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/what-is-the-vomiting-bug-norovirus-explained/article69067844.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can antibiotics work against HMPV virus? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxNV3BrVl9lZmx4T0pOS2tya3UtSm1sQTFVN054Tk45UzM4dW1zMmZqZ2lPSmctc09IVWViVjIzS2dWTmgwdnBVRzVEM2lyTEVmd192OXBVeVh6LVhJM2hnM2dxZFpTUzJobWVkS1lOZVRwZmZDR0N0dXdRdHNJZHg5MlpmQUExd1YzNmJxZ2dfR1FsVURhWGl3UXgyWU5CS05tNnR6Yk5jQnJETDFZaGc3OGNiODdTYk9UVFNkQWo4UkNLVEpScm5MalhpZ1FsNXJMdXFTS3Fn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxNV3BrVl9lZmx4T0pOS2tya3UtSm1sQTFVN054Tk45UzM4dW1zMmZqZ2lPSmctc09IVWViVjIzS2dWTmgwdnBVRzVEM2lyTEVmd192OXBVeVh6LVhJM2hnM2dxZFpTUzJobWVkS1lOZVRwZmZDR0N0dXdRdHNJZHg5MlpmQUExd1YzNmJxZ2dfR1FsVURhWGl3UXgyWU5CS05tNnR6Yk5jQnJETDFZaGc3OGNiODdTYk9UVFNkQWo4UkNLVEpScm5MalhpZ1FsNXJMdXFTS3Fn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Long COVID Breakthrough: Spike Proteins Persist in Brain for Years - SciTechDaily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Long COVID Breakthrough: Spike Proteins Persist in Brain for Years</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 29 November 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Cell Host & Microbe</p><p>Researchers have discovered that the SARS-CoV-2 spike protein persists in the brain and skull bone marrow for years after infection, potentially leading to chronic inflammation and neurodegenerative diseases.</p><h4>Key Points:</h4><ul><li>The SARS-CoV-2 spike protein can linger in the brain’s protective layers and skull bone marrow for up to four years.</li><li>The spike protein's presence may lead to chronic inflammation and increased risk of neurodegenerative diseases.</li><li>mRNA vaccines significantly reduce spike protein levels in the brain.</li><li>The research employs a novel AI-powered imaging technique to visualize previously undetectable spike protein distributions.</li><li>Approximately 400 million individuals globally may carry significant amounts of spike protein caused by Long COVID.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is not just an individual health issue – it is a societal challenge.” – Prof. Ali Ertürk</blockquote><p>The findings open new avenues for diagnosing and treating long-term neurological effects of COVID-19 and suggest a need for further research and therapeutic interventions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/long-covid-breakthrough-spike-proteins-persist-in-brain-for-years/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scitechdaily.com/long-covid-breakthrough-spike-proteins-persist-in-brain-for-years/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 09:18:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases in India: After Bengaluru, Gujarat reports its first case; third nationwide - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gujarat Reports First Human Metapneumovirus Case in India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<div>
  <figure>
    <img height="225" width="300" alt="Covid pandemic hmpv virus surge china" src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116989099,width-300,height-225,imgsize-2683349,resizemode-75/covid-pandemic-hmpv-virus-surge-china.jpg">
    <figcaption>Gujarat reports its first HMPV case (Representational image)</figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p>Gujarat has confirmed its first case of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), making it the third case in India. The Health Ministry reassures the public amidst rising respiratory illness concerns.</p>
<ul>
  <li>First HMPV case confirmed in Gujarat, two prior cases in Bengaluru.</li>
  <li>No need for public panic, robust surveillance systems in place.</li>
  <li>Kerala advises caution for vulnerable populations due to reports of an outbreak in China.</li>
  <li>ICMR assures no significant increase in related respiratory illnesses in India.</li>
  <li>Refresh on HMPV's global circulation and current cases in the country.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Health Minister Veena George emphasizes: "We should all pay attention to some things... There are no reports of any viruses likely to become a pandemic or spread quickly at this time."</blockquote>
<p>Authorities stress monitoring and caution, particularly for those most at risk, while ensuring the public remains informed and calm.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/hmpv-case-gujarat-first-human-metapneumovirus-case-bengaluru-gujarat-reports-its-first-case-third-in-india/articleshow/116989120.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/hmpv-case-gujarat-first-human-metapneumovirus-case-bengaluru-gujarat-reports-its-first-case-third-in-india/articleshow/116989120.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 08:42:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two unusual hand symptoms that could signal lung cancer according to UK experts - Daily Record]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dailyrecord.co.uk/news/health/two-unusual-hand-symptoms-could-34423699</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dailyrecord.co.uk/news/health/two-unusual-hand-symptoms-could-34423699</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 07:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2 Babies Diagnosed With HMPV Virus In Bengaluru, No Travel History: Centre - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Two Babies Diagnosed With HMPV Virus In Bengaluru</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today <strong>Source:</strong> The Centre</p><p>The report highlights two cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in Bengaluru, marking the first occurrences in India. One of the infants has been discharged, while the other is still recovering.</p><ul><li>3-month-old and 8-month-old babies diagnosed with HMPV.</li><li>No recent travel history for affected families.</li><li>HMPV monitoring initiated by ICMR and related health bodies.</li><li>Health Ministry convened a meeting for preparedness against HMPV.</li><li>The virus can lead to mild respiratory symptoms but may cause serious complications.</li></ul><blockquote>“Both cases were identified through routine surveillance for multiple respiratory viral pathogens...” - Centre statement</blockquote><p>The monitoring of HMPV and respiratory viruses is crucial, especially in light of the increase in respiratory illnesses observed in other regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/3-month-old-and-8-month-old-babies-diagnosed-with-hmpv-in-bengaluru-7409670</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/3-month-old-and-8-month-old-babies-diagnosed-with-hmpv-in-bengaluru-7409670</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 06:11:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV virus in India: 8-month-old baby tests positive for HMPV in Bengaluru - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV in India: 8-month-old baby tests positive for HMPV in Bengaluru</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 06, 2025 11:23 am IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/djkwef/article69067139.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20250104237L.jpg" alt="A teacher of Gurukul School Of Art at Lalbaug in Mumbai makes a painting on the Human Meta-pneumo Virus (HMPV) outbreak in China, on January 4, 2024." title="A teacher of Gurukul School Of Art at Lalbaug in Mumbai makes a painting on the Human Meta-pneumo Virus (HMPV) outbreak in China, on January 4, 2024." /><figcaption>A teacher of Gurukul School Of Art at Lalbaug in Mumbai makes a painting on the Human Meta-pneumo Virus (HMPV) outbreak in China. Photo Credit: DEEPAK SALVI</figcaption><p>Karnataka has reported the first case of Human Meta-pneumo Virus (HMPV) with an eight-month-old baby testing positive at a private hospital in Bengaluru.</p><ul><li>The baby tested positive for HMPV and Human Rhinovirus/Enterovirus on January 3, according to tests from Baptist Hospital.</li><li>The sample has been sent to the National Institute of Virology for further confirmation.</li><li>Karnataka’s Principal Secretary stated that HMPV typically affects children under 11 and doesn't require immediate panic.</li><li>A meeting has been convened on January 6 to discuss the situation.</li></ul><blockquote>“This may not be the first case as monitoring was not being done earlier. However, there is no need to panic as HMPV is like any other respiratory virus, which causes common cold and flu-like symptoms.” - Harsh Gupta</blockquote><p>Authorities are monitoring the situation closely while encouraging public awareness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/bangalore/eight-month-old-baby-tests-positive-for-hmpv-in-bengaluru-private-hospital/article69067099.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/bangalore/eight-month-old-baby-tests-positive-for-hmpv-in-bengaluru-private-hospital/article69067099.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First HMPV cases in India: Two Bengaluru infants test positive - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First HMPV Cases in India: Two Bengaluru Infants Test Positive</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p>
<p>Two infants from Bengaluru have tested positive for Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), marking the first reported cases of this virus in India.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The infants were hospitalized with respiratory symptoms.</li>
  <li>Health experts are raising awareness about HMPV and its transmission methods.</li>
  <li>HMPV can lead to severe respiratory illnesses, particularly in young children and the elderly.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p>"HMPV is known to cause respiratory infections that can be serious, especially in vulnerable populations." - Health Official</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emergence of HMPV highlights the need for public vigilance and proper healthcare practices to manage respiratory diseases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/8-month-old-baby-tests-positive-for-hmpv-in-bengaluru/articleshow/116982378.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/8-month-old-baby-tests-positive-for-hmpv-in-bengaluru/articleshow/116982378.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Rabbit Fever' in Humans Has Surged in The Last Decade, CDC Reports - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Rabbit Fever' in Humans Has Surged in The Last Decade, CDC Reports</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Science Alert</p><img src='https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/01/rabbit-face-642x260.jpg' alt='close crop of a brown rabbit's face in front of grassy background'><figcaption>Contact with infected rabbits is just one of the ways humans can become infected with tularemia. (Adria Photography/Getty Images)</figcaption><p>The CDC has reported a significant surge in cases of tularemia, also known as 'rabbit fever', over the past decade in the United States. The disease, caused by the bacterium <em>Francisella tularensis</em>, can be transmitted through various means, including bites from infected ticks and contact with infected animals.</p><ul><li>Over the last decade, there were 2,462 recorded cases of tularemia from 2011-2022.</li><li>The incidence rate is 56% higher than in the previous decade (2001-2010).</li><li>Tularemia can be transmitted by aerosolization when lawn mowing over infected nests.</li><li>Children aged five to nine and men aged 65-84 are among the most affected demographics.</li><li>Incidence among First Nations is around five times greater than among White individuals.</li></ul><blockquote>The case fatality rate of tularemia is typically less than 2 percent but can be higher depending on clinical manifestation and infecting strain.</blockquote><p>Improved reporting methods and laboratory tests may contribute to the recent increase in detected cases. Greater awareness and rapid treatment are essential for managing this disease.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/rabbit-fever-in-humans-has-surged-in-the-last-decade-cdc-reports</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/rabbit-fever-in-humans-has-surged-in-the-last-decade-cdc-reports</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:19:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>