<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 04:23:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 04:23:44 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A golden age of cancer treatment? – podcast - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A Golden Age of Cancer Treatment? – Podcast</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Guardian</p><img alt="Sample analysis tubes at the Institute of Cancer Research." src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c3e5839a14d0ddf46029a3229e833abe4de7d500/0_117_3500_2100/master/3500.jpg?width=445&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none" width="445" height="267" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Photograph: Stefan Wermuth/Reuters</figcaption><p>This article discusses advances in cancer treatment that have transformed options available for patients, including personalized treatments and new technologies, while acknowledging ongoing challenges.</p><ul><li>Historically, cancer treatment options were limited to surgery, radiation, and chemotherapy.</li><li>Billions of dollars have been invested in new cancer treatment technologies, including immunotherapy and artificial intelligence.</li><li>Despite advancements, challenges remain in the distribution of these new technologies to patients globally.</li><li>The article highlights personal stories, such as that of Abbie Halls, who participated in a successful clinical trial.</li></ul><blockquote>“How to distribute these expensive new technologies to everyone who needs them?”</blockquote><p>The advancements in cancer treatment are promising, but attention is needed to ensure equitable access to these innovative therapies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2025/jan/17/a-golden-age-for-cancer-treatment-podcast</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2025/jan/17/a-golden-age-for-cancer-treatment-podcast</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:00:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diabetics, here’s what happens to the body if you skip breakfast - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diabetics, here’s what happens to the body if you skip breakfast</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/11/diabetes-pexels-2.jpg?w=640" alt="Skipping breakfast can set off a cascade of physiological and psychological effects, complicating blood sugar management and increasing the risk of long-term complications. (Source: Pexels)" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Skipping breakfast can set off a cascade of physiological and psychological effects, complicating blood sugar management and increasing the risk of long-term complications. (Source: Pexels)</figcaption><p>For those with diabetes, breakfast is critical for maintaining balanced blood sugar levels and supporting overall health. Skipping breakfast can lead to both physiological and psychological complications.</p><ul><li>Skipping breakfast can lead to elevated blood sugar levels later in the day.</li><li>It can worsen insulin resistance.</li><li>Missing this essential meal increases the risk of long-term health complications.</li><li>Breakfast provides vital nutrients necessary for metabolic balance.</li><li>It can lead to psychological effects such as mood swings and increased hunger.</li></ul><h2>Healthy breakfast tips for diabetics</h2><p>Individuals with diabetes should prioritize a well-balanced breakfast, including low glycaemic index carbohydrates, lean proteins, healthy fats, and fibre-rich foods.</p><blockquote>“To optimise blood sugar control, individuals with diabetes should prioritize a well-balanced breakfast,” said Kanikka Malhotra, consultant dietician and diabetes educator.</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/what-happens-to-body-skipping-breakfast-as-diabetic-9676068/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/what-happens-to-body-skipping-breakfast-as-diabetic-9676068/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coffee in the morning is best for heart health, says study: Can this routine work for you? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Coffee in the morning is best for heart health, says study: Can this routine work for you?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/coffee_f24cc3.jpg?w=640" alt="coffee, heart health, morning coffee," width="640" height="360"><figcaption>The study found that morning coffee drinkers were 31 per cent less likely to die from cardiovascular disease compared to non-coffee drinkers. (Credit: pexels.com)</figcaption><p>The study suggests that drinking coffee in the morning may lead to lower risks of cardiovascular diseases compared to consuming it throughout the day.</p><ul><li>Morning coffee drinkers are 31% less likely to die from cardiovascular disease.</li><li>The study involved 40,725 adults in the US.</li><li>Dr. Komal Shah highlights the importance of sleep quality and its relation to coffee consumption timing.</li><li>Overconsumption of caffeine can lead to heightened blood pressure and poor sleep quality.</li><li>Moderate coffee consumption under 300 mg per day is recommended.</li></ul><blockquote>“These findings suggest that morning coffee consumption may have beneficial effects on cardiovascular health at the population level.” - Study conclusion</blockquote><p>Overall, the study advocates for morning coffee as a healthier routine that could protect against heart-related issues, emphasizing moderation and timing in consumption.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/coffee-morning-best-heart-health-study-routine-work-9783367/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/coffee-morning-best-heart-health-study-routine-work-9783367/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US CDC recommends faster testing for bird flu in hospitalized patients - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQdW1zTm0xY1cxa3QtRzhXbWJzMVNEcjJTZGdWd3FuYTlRVEhWZXFqaG9MTVQ2a0prekcwN1k3OG5MeHFDWS05MUtoS2dFdUR0bEJjSVYya0t6elBPY0dWOHM3M2h6amN3ejV5WWF6dmM3ZTI5UUltZnNZZm9NanJCRWdVaEdpckdiMGZxSkM1a2NFb0ZlZDY1bXU2RVJ3NU1zZzM2UXVhNlVfc2xib3pXSHhSQjR0OGhoNF81Z3A2eDcwblViZVRSTWJiR1pLRHdKWEVxLdIB2gFBVV95cUxOaVZvRzU2dnZ5U0RybkRpaFNPTko4ZHotSjVTRlpsUFdjOUwxaktOaXhBMVFnYm0zeEIwNS1kUXlDRGprdVBaRGpKWVBKY084eWo5cENuWW1CdHlWVTRhUnlzOWQ4MWtObU9lVnpvakxkLTZuZDNkT0FIOENGSjU1SXh1TUlob3U0SWVEcEhaU1k0aTJfVDJEVkhvRmV5NW5FcEdWZ3FndHFuMHd6a1hGbkFSMS1hVzNWUU11UWI0U0xiVGRja2ZVdGZfeDQ0V3JvdnNBck1zVzQ2dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQdW1zTm0xY1cxa3QtRzhXbWJzMVNEcjJTZGdWd3FuYTlRVEhWZXFqaG9MTVQ2a0prekcwN1k3OG5MeHFDWS05MUtoS2dFdUR0bEJjSVYya0t6elBPY0dWOHM3M2h6amN3ejV5WWF6dmM3ZTI5UUltZnNZZm9NanJCRWdVaEdpckdiMGZxSkM1a2NFb0ZlZDY1bXU2RVJ3NU1zZzM2UXVhNlVfc2xib3pXSHhSQjR0OGhoNF81Z3A2eDcwblViZVRSTWJiR1pLRHdKWEVxLdIB2gFBVV95cUxOaVZvRzU2dnZ5U0RybkRpaFNPTko4ZHotSjVTRlpsUFdjOUwxaktOaXhBMVFnYm0zeEIwNS1kUXlDRGprdVBaRGpKWVBKY084eWo5cENuWW1CdHlWVTRhUnlzOWQ4MWtObU9lVnpvakxkLTZuZDNkT0FIOENGSjU1SXh1TUlob3U0SWVEcEhaU1k0aTJfVDJEVkhvRmV5NW5FcEdWZ3FndHFuMHd6a1hGbkFSMS1hVzNWUU11UWI0U0xiVGRja2ZVdGZfeDQ0V3JvdnNBck1zVzQ2dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:16:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Groundbreaking Huntington Study Reveals Somatic DNA-Repeat Expansion - Genetic Engineering & Biotechnology News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Groundbreaking Huntington Study Reveals Somatic DNA-Repeat Expansion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>This study uncovers the mechanism by which the HTT gene mutation leads to Huntington’s disease, paving the way for potential therapies.</p><ul><li>The mutation in the HTT gene causes Huntington’s disease.</li><li>It was found that the mutation initially seems harmless but later becomes toxic.</li><li>The research reveals how CAG repeat expansions over time contribute to cell death.</li><li>Using data from over 500,000 cells, researchers observed significant CAG repeat expansions in striatal projection neurons.</li><li>The findings have implications for potential therapies to delay symptom onset and disease progression.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a really different way of thinking about how a mutation brings about a disease.” - Steve McCarroll, PhD</blockquote><p>Overall, this study provides insights that could lead to new therapeutic strategies for Huntington’s as well as related disorders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.genengnews.com/topics/translational-medicine/groundbreaking-huntington-study-reveals-somatic-dna-repeat-expansion/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.genengnews.com/topics/translational-medicine/groundbreaking-huntington-study-reveals-somatic-dna-repeat-expansion/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:41:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[COVID-19 dramatically raises the risk of developing ME/CFS - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>COVID-19 Raises Risk of Developing ME/CFS</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Journal of General Internal Medicine</p>
<img src="https://d2jx2rerrg6sh3.cloudfront.net/images/news/ImageForNews_800233_17370716123082449.jpg" alt="COVID-19 dramatically raises the risk of developing ME/CFS">
<figcaption>Incidence and Prevalence of Post-COVID-19 Myalgic Encephalomyelitis: A Report from the Observational RECOVER-Adult Study. Image Credit: CKA / Shutterstock</figcaption>
<p>The recent study examines the correlation between COVID-19 and the increased incidence of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), highlighting the urgent need for better diagnostics and care.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study found a significant increase in the risk of developing ME/CFS after a SARS-CoV-2 infection.</li>
  <li>4.5% of participants with COVID-19 showed symptoms matching ME/CFS criteria at six months, compared to 0.6% in uninfected controls.</li>
  <li>The prevalence of post-exertional malaise was reported by 24% of infected individuals.</li>
  <li>89% of diagnosed ME/CFS patients also had long COVID symptoms.</li>
  <li>The study emphasized the importance of early recognition and comprehensive care strategies for post-COVID conditions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"These findings emphasized the need for early recognition of ME/CFS symptoms following SARS-CoV-2 infections."</blockquote>
<p>The growing body of evidence suggests that COVID-19 significantly increases the risk of ME/CFS, requiring urgent attention to public health responses and necessary healthcare interventions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250116/COVID-19-dramatically-raises-the-risk-of-developing-MECFS.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250116/COVID-19-dramatically-raises-the-risk-of-developing-MECFS.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 23:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India: Wearable Tech Mimics Pain to Detect Stress - OpenGov Asia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wearable Tech Mimics Pain to Detect Stress</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> OpenGov Asia</p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://cdn.opengovasia.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Article-Sam_Ind-Jan-17-emb.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="258"><figcaption>Image credits: Press Information Bureau</figcaption><p>Scientists from JNCASR in Bengaluru have developed a wearable device that senses stress by mimicking the human body's response to pain, paving the way for efficient health monitoring systems.</p><ul><li>The device uses a silver wire network embedded in stretchable material.</li><li>It detects strain and learns from it, mimicking pain responses seen in the human body.</li><li>This adaptive ability allows it to adjust its electrical response over time.</li><li>The technology could transform healthcare and robotics by providing real-time stress detection.</li><li>It's inspired by nociceptors, which detect pain and trigger protective responses.</li><li>Published in Materials Horizons by the Royal Society of Chemistry.</li></ul><blockquote>“This novel wearable device represents a significant step forward in the development of more intelligent, adaptable technology.”</blockquote><p>This development signifies a major leap in creating technology that is more aligned with human physiological responses, enhancing the possibilities of healthcare and robotic applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://opengovasia.com/2025/01/17/india-wearable-tech-mimics-pain-to-detect-stress/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://opengovasia.com/2025/01/17/india-wearable-tech-mimics-pain-to-detect-stress/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 23:43:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Long overdue, short term regimen for TB set to be a game changer - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Short-term Regimen for MDR-TB: A Potential Game Changer</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 17, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><p>Multidrug resistant tuberculosis (MDR-TB) poses significant health risks, particularly in India, where 27% of cases reported to the WHO in 2023 originated. New shorter treatment regimens, specifically the BPaL regimen, may revolutionize MDR-TB management.</p><ul><li>MDR-TB has a high risk of death, with 30-40% mortality.</li><li>Current long treatments involve more drugs and are difficult to adhere to.</li><li>The BPaL regimen offers a promising alternative with fewer oral medications over a shorter duration.</li><li>Monitoring adherence and testing for drug susceptibility are crucial for effective treatment.</li><li>Health system preparedness and community education are essential for successful implementation.</li></ul><blockquote>“A shorter regimen is transformative but not the answer to all the issues that persist in TB.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while the introduction of new regimens marks progress, comprehensive approaches addressing systemic issues in TB treatment and care are necessary for long-term success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/long-overdue-short-term-regimen-for-tb-set-to-be-a-game-changer/article69099696.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/long-overdue-short-term-regimen-for-tb-set-to-be-a-game-changer/article69099696.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 23:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review highlights current understanding of Nipah virus features - Medical Xpress]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Review Highlights Current Understanding of Nipah Virus Features</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Medical Xpress</p><figure><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2025/nipah-virus-epidemiolo.jpg" alt="Nipah virus: epidemiology, pathogenesis, treatment, and prevention" title="Credit: Limei Wang, Denghui Lu, Maosen Yang, Shiqi Chai, Hong Du, Hong Jiang" width="800" height="530"><figcaption>Credit: Limei Wang, Denghui Lu, Maosen Yang, Shiqi Chai, Hong Du, Hong Jiang</figcaption></figure><p>Nipah virus (NiV), a zoonotic paramyxovirus, poses significant human health risks due to high fatality rates and potential for human-to-human transmission. A review titled "Nipah virus: epidemiology, pathogenesis, treatment, and prevention" discusses these features in the journal <i>Frontiers of Medicine</i>.</p><ul><li>Nipah virus has recurrent outbreaks primarily in South and Southeast Asia, first identified in Malaysia in 1998.</li><li>The virus can infect a variety of hosts, with bats being the natural reservoir and pigs acting as intermediate hosts.</li><li>Human infections have occurred in multiple countries, including Malaysia, Singapore, and India.</li><li>NiV manifests with flu-like symptoms and severe neurological complications, with no specific antiviral treatment available.</li><li>Prevention measures include surveillance and changes in agricultural practices to reduce exposure.</li><li>Latest research discusses vaccine development, including virus-like and mRNA-based vaccines, although none are approved for human use yet.</li></ul><blockquote>The review underscores the need for a multidisciplinary approach to address the NiV threat, including the development of effective therapeutics and vaccines.</blockquote><p>The findings highlight the importance of continued research and public health measures to mitigate the risks associated with Nipah virus.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-01-highlights-current-nipah-virus-features.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-01-highlights-current-nipah-virus-features.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 21:34:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alcohol Consumption Linked to Seven Types of Cancer - University of Miami]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Alcohol Consumption Linked to Seven Types of Cancer</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> InventUM</p>
<img src="https://i0.wp.com/news.med.miami.edu/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/img-HHS-alcohol-feature-v2.jpg?resize=1795%2C825&amp;ssl=1" alt="Woman's hand rejecting more alcohol from wine bottle in bar">
<figcaption></figcaption>
<p>The U.S. surgeon general has issued an advisory linking alcohol to seven types of cancer, emphasizing the need for warning labels on alcoholic beverages about this risk. Researchers at Sylvester Comprehensive Cancer Center stress the importance of this advisory in changing public behavior and oncology practices.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The surgeon general's report highlights that alcohol is the third-leading preventable cause of cancer.</li>
  <li>Alcohol is linked to over 100,000 cancer cases and 20,000 related deaths annually in the U.S.</li>
  <li>The association between alcohol intake and increased cancer risk has been acknowledged for decades.</li>
  <li>Experts are hopeful that labeling will lead to greater public awareness and behavior change regarding alcohol consumption.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Alcohol consumption is certainly a worsening public health problem and we’re going to be in trouble if people continue drinking as they are.” - Dr. Patricia Jones</blockquote>
<p>This advisory signals a significant opportunity to address alcohol consumption as a modifiable risk factor for cancer.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.med.miami.edu/alcohol-consumption-linked-to-seven-types-of-cancer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.med.miami.edu/alcohol-consumption-linked-to-seven-types-of-cancer/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 21:01:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Necrotizing Pancreatitis Following Acute Appendicitis: A Case Report of a Complex Clinical Course and Diagnostic Challenges - Cureus]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAJBVV95cUxPVHdaUmFNT0ZsOExIRm9uSlViZUNnM3NUalFycjRkSWpja1JiY1hfNGdTb3o1Qnl0cXVvZkFIeUpIMll2VDY4ZDZuZUN0Z1BqSDRKcTkxeFRtTmtBYkFodlhiQ203RWFNZDluQlJiVkJoYzRodExBZWtNbFNJNFZDNlRCNVZUN1cybFNhTUdxbmQ0NUt5eTlsZ2dCOWpYTFdnZWVvRHVjQ0lSR1BSSnN6N20ySWliczJ2RVZ4cXBvTFJtZTBSYklRS0RtSWNXbWZXS20zdllqSjlEc244cjBiVlVvREJ1aTVzTlJFalFFUFk5MWl5S3dmazZTM0UwUko1TmR6bHoxNGVGWVNy?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAJBVV95cUxPVHdaUmFNT0ZsOExIRm9uSlViZUNnM3NUalFycjRkSWpja1JiY1hfNGdTb3o1Qnl0cXVvZkFIeUpIMll2VDY4ZDZuZUN0Z1BqSDRKcTkxeFRtTmtBYkFodlhiQ203RWFNZDluQlJiVkJoYzRodExBZWtNbFNJNFZDNlRCNVZUN1cybFNhTUdxbmQ0NUt5eTlsZ2dCOWpYTFdnZWVvRHVjQ0lSR1BSSnN6N20ySWliczJ2RVZ4cXBvTFJtZTBSYklRS0RtSWNXbWZXS20zdllqSjlEc244cjBiVlVvREJ1aTVzTlJFalFFUFk5MWl5S3dmazZTM0UwUko1TmR6bHoxNGVGWVNy?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 20:53:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian scientists develop wearable devices to detect stress - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian Scientists Develop Wearable Devices to Detect Stress</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 16, Source: New Delhi</p><p>The Jawaharlal Nehru Centre for Advanced Scientific Research in Bengaluru has created a novel wearable device capable of detecting stress.</p><ul><li>The device uses a silver wire network on stretchable material to sense strain.</li><li>It mimics pain perception and adapts its electrical response to stretching.</li><li>The technology could enhance health monitoring systems that respond to stress in real-time.</li></ul><blockquote>“These pain-like responses in the device pave the way for future smart wearable systems that can help doctors detect stress,” researchers stated.</blockquote><p>The innovative approach could help mitigate the health threats posed by stress, such as high blood pressure and heart disease.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/health/indian-scientists-develop-wearable-devices-to-detect-stress/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/health/indian-scientists-develop-wearable-devices-to-detect-stress/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:51:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surprise finding sheds light on what causes Huntington's disease, a devastating fatal brain disorder - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxQYVY4dlZ0QXo0dTk2MGIxMVVycW5BNEROOFJkWnhtT3ZEQU1MYU5FRFhPT2wydTNyN0lWRHBYVlprcmFfSzBBUUNVaVFJdklVbllpR2tlTl9OUzU4RzFLSHVPRHJNUm1LMEFENWpJMVFLa0czMkhNOFZXYW5ZSWxBMF9uVXh5Ykh3RllLdE9zWFFPYW4yWXp0QTVkT3FrQ2xDZk15VGtHNERuT0RRZVVUVkdJUlBwUVlPazZUSXZkRDA1S1lKOGZaUzJkaUdYQXJSUHhSdmRQbk96ZERVbF9YSjBsYzZWc3I4eHFTS19KajLSAfYBQVVfeXFMTXJDTHF3RURocXdPNzV0UGV5bWt4OV9vT3B3cG56bjV0d1pzS3l3a0N2Zk5HR2NyWG5sZDd3SFozY1BSdkU5MGloVUVIUmhjV3JJbG1RVng3WkpQLTBjZnZUcml2NTR4Y242QWNkYzdManl4VGo4Z0FMUmVCWExxN0o5V3hsbGpENS1uUzFxODRkOW10c3R1SWh0ZlE4RHdBS1Izc2FFMVdLMVFEOURfdHNiQW1fM3BSQUpNeTJnZGk1cW8zM3FMWnNNdHREbXNMVmNRV1BTM2NacUgxaUlkWEJ0T0F6aFkwamlMY3l3ekZyQmMzNG9R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxQYVY4dlZ0QXo0dTk2MGIxMVVycW5BNEROOFJkWnhtT3ZEQU1MYU5FRFhPT2wydTNyN0lWRHBYVlprcmFfSzBBUUNVaVFJdklVbllpR2tlTl9OUzU4RzFLSHVPRHJNUm1LMEFENWpJMVFLa0czMkhNOFZXYW5ZSWxBMF9uVXh5Ykh3RllLdE9zWFFPYW4yWXp0QTVkT3FrQ2xDZk15VGtHNERuT0RRZVVUVkdJUlBwUVlPazZUSXZkRDA1S1lKOGZaUzJkaUdYQXJSUHhSdmRQbk96ZERVbF9YSjBsYzZWc3I4eHFTS19KajLSAfYBQVVfeXFMTXJDTHF3RURocXdPNzV0UGV5bWt4OV9vT3B3cG56bjV0d1pzS3l3a0N2Zk5HR2NyWG5sZDd3SFozY1BSdkU5MGloVUVIUmhjV3JJbG1RVng3WkpQLTBjZnZUcml2NTR4Y242QWNkYzdManl4VGo4Z0FMUmVCWExxN0o5V3hsbGpENS1uUzFxODRkOW10c3R1SWh0ZlE4RHdBS1Izc2FFMVdLMVFEOURfdHNiQW1fM3BSQUpNeTJnZGk1cW8zM3FMWnNNdHREbXNMVmNRV1BTM2NacUgxaUlkWEJ0T0F6aFkwamlMY3l3ekZyQmMzNG9R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:43:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drinking Green Tea Daily Can Help In Keeping Your Brain Healthy, Reveals Study - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Drinking Green Tea Daily Can Help In Keeping Your Brain Healthy, Reveals Study</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Green tea is already widely recognised for its effectiveness in aiding weight loss." title="Green tea is already widely recognised for its effectiveness in aiding weight loss." />
<figcaption>Green tea is already widely recognised for its effectiveness in aiding weight loss.</figcaption>
<p>Recent research published in npj Science of Food suggests that daily consumption of green tea can contribute to better brain health, reducing the risk of cognitive decline and providing protective benefits as people age.</p>
<ul>
<li>Green tea improves cognitive function and may help prevent age-related mental decline.</li>
<li>Participants consuming 600 ml of green tea daily showed 3% less brain damage compared to those drinking 200 ml or less.</li>
<li>Green tea is rich in antioxidants and anti-inflammatory compounds, particularly epigallocatechin gallate.</li>
<li>In comparison, coffee did not show significant benefits for brain health, emphasizing the advantages of green tea.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Drinking about three cups of green tea a day could be beneficial for brain health."</blockquote>
<p>This study highlights the potential health benefits of green tea, suggesting it is a preferable beverage for those concerned about cognitive health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness/drinking-green-tea-daily-can-help-in-keeping-your-brain-healthy-reveals-study-9190903.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness/drinking-green-tea-daily-can-help-in-keeping-your-brain-healthy-reveals-study-9190903.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:28:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tanzania says no sign of Marburg outbreak in the country - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tanzania Reports No Signs of Marburg Outbreak</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/World_4_1734523380663_1734523416539.jpg" alt="Tanzania says no sign of Marburg outbreak in the country" title="Tanzania says no sign of Marburg outbreak in the country">
<figcaption>Tanzania says no sign of Marburg outbreak in the country</figcaption>
<p>The government of Tanzania has confirmed that no individuals in the country have tested positive for the Marburg virus, despite reports from the World Health Organization of suspected cases.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The WHO reported at least eight deaths believed to be from the Marburg virus in northwest Tanzania.</li>
    <li>Tanzania's health minister stated that all lab results for suspected cases returned negative.</li>
    <li>Victims displayed typical symptoms associated with Marburg virus, including headache, high fever, and vomiting blood.</li>
    <li>The Marburg virus has a fatality rate as high as 88% and is related to the Ebola virus.</li>
    <li>In response to the suspected cases, Tanzania deployed experts to investigate and collect specimens for testing.</li>
    <li>Tanzania experienced its first Marburg outbreak in 2023, with nine cases and six deaths reported.</li>
    <li>The government has enhanced disease surveillance measures following these reports.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“As of 15th January 2025, laboratory results for all suspected individuals were negative for Marburg virus.” - Jenista Mhagama, Health Minister</blockquote>
<p>The Tanzanian government emphasizes its preparedness and response to viral outbreaks, particularly after criticism during the COVID-19 pandemic for data transparency and preventive measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/tanzania-says-no-sign-of-marburg-outbreak-in-the-country-101737055140735.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/tanzania-says-no-sign-of-marburg-outbreak-in-the-country-101737055140735.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NIMH awards $1.5 million grant for long COVID neurological research - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NIMH awards $1.5 million grant for long COVID neurological research</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>The National Institute of Mental Health has awarded a significant grant of $1.5 million to Jianyang Du, PhD, for research on neurological disorders caused by long COVID-19.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The project will explore the cellular mechanisms of long COVID.</li>
  <li>Dr. Du's team has developed a mouse model to study the infection effects.</li>
  <li>The research aims to unveil how the virus impacts brain function.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I would like to express my gratitude to Dr. Qian Ge, my postdoctoral fellow, for her significant contributions to the grant application... the progress of this work would not have been possible without his generous assistance.”<br>— Dr. Jianyang Du, PhD</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This research may lead to new treatments that alleviate the suffering associated with long COVID and address health disparities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250116/NIMH-awards-2415-million-grant-for-long-COVID-neurological-research.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250116/NIMH-awards-2415-million-grant-for-long-COVID-neurological-research.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sierra Leone Reports First Mpox Cases as Democratic Republic of Congo Accelerates Vaccine Drive - Health Policy Watch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sierra Leone Reports First Mpox Cases As Democratic Republic Of Congo Accelerates Vaccine Drive</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Health Policy Watch</p><img src="https://healthpolicy-watch.news/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Jean-Kaseya-Africa-CDC--e1737051204712-1024x607.jpg" alt="Dr Jean Kaseya, director Africa CDC" width="1024" height="607"><figcaption>Dr Jean Kaseya, director Africa CDC, at press briefing Thursday.</figcaption><p>A new mpox outbreak in Sierra Leone and a rising case toll across Africa are fueling urgent calls for stronger containment efforts, even as the Democratic Republic of Congo speeds up its mpox vaccine drive.</p><ul><li>Sierra Leone has reported its first mpox cases, with two confirmed infections having no known travel history.</li><li>Health authorities are monitoring 25 contacts linked to the confirmed cases.</li><li>Africa has seen 77,888 mpox cases over the past year, with 1,321 deaths reported in 2024.</li><li>Dr. Jean Kaseya described the outbreak as a major public health emergency.</li><li>China recently reported its first case of Clade 1b mpox, connected to a traveler from Africa.</li><li>Rwanda’s successful Marburg virus response is highlighted as a model for epidemic control.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are seeing a sharp increase in cases compared to 2023, and this remains a significant threat to public health in Africa.” — Dr. Jean Kaseya</blockquote><p>The emergence of mpox cases in Sierra Leone, along with rising infections across Africa, poses critical challenges that require immediate global collaboration and local containment efforts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://healthpolicy-watch.news/sierra-leone-reports-first-mpox-cases-as-democratic-republic-of-congo-accelerates-vaccine-drive/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://healthpolicy-watch.news/sierra-leone-reports-first-mpox-cases-as-democratic-republic-of-congo-accelerates-vaccine-drive/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:55:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cancer deaths decline in US, but rates among women and young adults are rising: Report - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cancer deaths decline in US, but rates among women and young adults are rising: Report</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>Health News</p>
<p>Cancer death rates in the US have decreased overall; however, there is a concerning uptick in rates among women and young adults. This report highlights the contrasting trends that merit attention for future healthcare strategies.</p>
<ul>
<li>Cancer mortality rates overall have seen a decline.</li>
<li>Women and young adults are experiencing rising cancer incidence and mortality rates.</li>
<li>Public health responses and targeted interventions are urgently needed to address these changes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Despite overall progress in combatting cancer, the rising rates among vulnerable populations indicate a need for renewed focus and research." - Health Expert</blockquote>
<p>The divergent trends in cancer mortality reveal an ongoing public health challenge, calling for enhanced awareness and proactive measures to prevent and treat cancer in affected demographics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/cancer-deaths-decline-in-us-but-rates-among-women-and-young-adults-are-rising-report/articleshow/117309691.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/cancer-deaths-decline-in-us-but-rates-among-women-and-young-adults-are-rising-report/articleshow/117309691.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TiLoop Mesh implant offers hope & healing to breast cancer patient - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>TiLoop Mesh Implant Offers Hope and Healing to Breast Cancer Patient</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: N/A</strong>, <strong>Source: N/A</strong></p><p>The TiLoop mesh implant presents a promising advancement in the treatment and recovery of breast cancer patients, potentially improving their quality of life.</p><ul><li>Introduction of the TiLoop mesh implant as a new treatment option.</li><li>Positive patient outcomes and enhanced recovery experiences reported.</li><li>Focus on the innovation in breast cancer surgery and support.</li></ul><blockquote>"This implant has changed my life and given me hope for the future." – Patient testimonial</blockquote><p>This innovative approach could redefine recovery strategies for breast cancer, highlighting the importance of research in improving patient outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/tiloop-mesh-implant-offers-hope-healing-to-breast-cancer-patient/articleshow/117309611.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/tiloop-mesh-implant-offers-hope-healing-to-breast-cancer-patient/articleshow/117309611.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fiber-rich food has anti-cancer properties, says study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fiber-rich food has anti-cancer properties, says study</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>This article examines the findings of a recent study that highlights the potential anti-cancer properties of fiber-rich foods. It suggests that incorporating these foods into the diet might help reduce cancer risk.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study found a strong correlation between high fiber intake and lower cancer rates.</li>
  <li>Fiber-rich foods include fruits, vegetables, whole grains, and legumes.</li>
  <li>Participants who consumed more fiber had a significantly lower risk of developing various types of cancer.</li>
  <li>The researchers emphasized the importance of dietary choices in cancer prevention.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Increasing your fiber intake can be a simple yet effective way to improve your overall health and potentially reduce cancer risk," said the lead researcher.</blockquote>
<p>The findings of this study underscore the significance of dietary fiber in our health and open up discussions on nutrition as a key factor in cancer prevention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/fiber-rich-food-has-anti-cancer-properties-says-study/articleshow/117309068.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/fiber-rich-food-has-anti-cancer-properties-says-study/articleshow/117309068.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dance programme brings joy to seniors with Parkinson’s - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dance Programme Brings Joy to Seniors with Parkinson’s</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This article discusses a dance program aimed at enhancing the quality of life for seniors suffering from Parkinson’s disease through the joy of movement and social interaction.</p><ul><li>The programme incorporates various dance styles tailored to seniors.</li><li>Participants report increased mobility and reduced symptoms of Parkinson’s.</li><li>Social interaction during the sessions helps build community and reduce isolation.</li><li>Healthcare professionals endorse the benefits of dance therapy for Parkinson’s patients.</li></ul><blockquote>“I never thought I could move like this again. It’s not just about dancing; it’s about feeling alive,” a participant remarked.</blockquote><p>The program highlights the therapeutic power of dance in improving both physical and emotional health for seniors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/pune/dance-programme-brings-joy-to-seniors-with-parkinsons/articleshow/117308953.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/pune/dance-programme-brings-joy-to-seniors-with-parkinsons/articleshow/117308953.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cancer cases rising for women and younger adults in US, report finds - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cancer cases rising for women and younger adults in US, report finds</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> American Cancer Society</p>
<p>Certain types of cancer, especially among women and younger adults, are on the rise according to a new report from the American Cancer Society. This marks a significant shift in cancer trends, particularly highlighting a higher diagnosis rate among women than men.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The report analyzes cancer rates in the US from 1991 to 2021.</li>
  <li>For the first time since the early 1900s, cancer diagnoses in women under 65 have surpassed those in men of the same age group.</li>
  <li>Over 2 million new cancer cases and 618,000 cancer deaths are anticipated this year.</li>
  <li>Breast cancer and thyroid cancer are notable increases for women.</li>
  <li>Native Americans are at a higher risk for certain cancers compared to white populations.</li>
  <li>Cancer mortality has decreased by 34% since 1991, largely due to technological advances and improved detection.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Cancer is the number one leading cause of death for all folks under the age of 85,” - William Dahut, chief scientific officer for ACS.</blockquote>
<p>While the trends are concerning, the report points to progress in reducing cancer mortality through early detection and a societal decline in smoking. Continued efforts are essential to address disparities in cancer care.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/jan/16/cancer-young-women-adults</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/jan/16/cancer-young-women-adults</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How intermittent fasting can help people with obesity; know 2 key benefits - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How Intermittent Fasting Can Help People with Obesity; Know 2 Key Benefits</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117308934,imgsize-1604332,width-400,resizemode-4/117308934.jpg" alt="How intermittent fasting can help people with obesity; know 2 key benefits" title="(Image: Canva)"><figcaption>(Image: Canva)</figcaption><p>A recent study shows that intermittent fasting can provide significant benefits to individuals struggling with obesity, suggesting it as an effective weight loss strategy.</p><ul><li>The study conducted in Spain involved 197 participants aged 30 to 60 who followed intermittent fasting for 12 weeks.</li><li>Results indicated an average weight loss of 5.3 to 6.8 pounds during the study.</li><li>Two key benefits identified were improved metabolic health and effective weight management.</li><li>Intermittent fasting helps in regulating blood sugar levels and reducing inflammation.</li></ul><blockquote>“Intermittent fasting limits the eating window and overall calorie intake, leading to better weight management.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, intermittent fasting emerges as a promising approach for individuals with obesity, contributing to weight loss and better metabolic health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/how-intermittent-fasting-can-help-people-with-obesity-know-2-key-benefits/articleshow/117308892.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/how-intermittent-fasting-can-help-people-with-obesity-know-2-key-benefits/articleshow/117308892.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 high-protein fruits to lose weight, gain muscle - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 High-Protein Fruits to Help Lose Weight and Gain Muscle</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117308784,imgsize-2038188,width-400,resizemode-4/117308784.jpg" alt="8 high-protein fruits to lose weight, gain muscle" title="(Image: Canva)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>8 High-Protein Fruits</figcaption><p>Fruits are essential for a balanced diet, rich in nutrients that help in digestion, lower disease risk, and maintain gut health. While fruits are generally low in protein, some varieties offer more than 1 gram of protein, making them beneficial for those looking to lose weight and gain muscle.</p><ul><li><strong>Passion Fruit:</strong> 5 grams of protein per cup, rich in fiber and vitamins.</li><li><strong>Jackfruit:</strong> 2.8 grams of protein per cup; nutritious alternative to meat.</li><li><strong>Pomegranate:</strong> 2.9 grams of protein per cup, beneficial for heart health.</li><li><strong>Apricots:</strong> 2.3 grams of protein per cup (4.4 grams when dried), high in fiber and antioxidants.</li><li><strong>Blackberries:</strong> 2 grams of protein per cup, supports gut health.</li><li><strong>Guava:</strong> 1.4 grams of protein per cup, rich in Vitamin C.</li><li><strong>Raisins:</strong> Highly nutritious, improve heart health, recommended quantity is one handful.</li><li><strong>Orange:</strong> 1.2 grams of protein, good source of Vitamin C.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/food-news/8-high-protein-fruits-to-lose-weight-gain-muscle/articleshow/117308693.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/food-news/8-high-protein-fruits-to-lose-weight-gain-muscle/articleshow/117308693.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Peripheral artery disease – the biggest killer you’ve probably never heard of - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Peripheral Artery Disease – the biggest killer you’ve probably never heard of</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Toeache_Freepik.jpg" alt="Peripheral artery disease">
<figcaption>Recognising the signs of a foot at risk – constant pain in the toes, a foot wound that won’t heal or dark discolouration to one or more toes – and seeking help quickly may just save someone’s foot. (Photo: Freepik)</figcaption>
<p>This article highlights the urgent issue of peripheral artery disease (PAD), a condition that often goes unnoticed but can lead to amputation and significantly impacts health outcomes for many, especially the elderly.</p>
<ul>
  <li>PAD affects over 10% of individuals aged 65 and older in the UK.</li>
  <li>The condition leads to the narrowing of leg arteries, significantly increasing the risk of heart attacks and strokes.</li>
  <li>In 2023, over 3,500 amputations were performed in the UK due to PAD.</li>
  <li>A study indicated that focused improvements in treatment pathways can reduce amputation risks by up to 57%.</li>
  <li>Awareness of PAD is low, resulting in delayed treatment and unnecessary amputations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The survival of people with chronic limb-threatening ischaemia is worse than many cancers – less than 50 per cent will be alive five years from diagnosis.”</blockquote>
<p>The article stresses the importance of early detection and treatment of PAD to prevent severe health consequences, advocating for improved awareness and timely intervention in healthcare settings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/peripheral-artery-disease-the-biggest-killer-youve-probably-never-heard-of-9780293/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/peripheral-artery-disease-the-biggest-killer-youve-probably-never-heard-of-9780293/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:30:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yellow Fever and Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccines Mix Well - Vax-Before-Travel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yellow Fever and Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccines Mix Well</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> February 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Vaccine Journal</p><p>This article discusses the immune response to the yellow fever vaccine when co-administered with the pneumococcal conjugate vaccine. It highlights a recent study that concluded there is no negative impact on the seroresponse to the yellow fever vaccine when given alongside PCV13.</p><ul><li>The study showed over 85% seroprotection for yellow fever vaccine across all groups.</li><li>No evidence was found of the non-inferiority of the seroresponse to the yellow fever vaccine when co-administered with PCV.</li><li>The yellow fever virus is now endemic in parts of Africa and the Americas, with vaccination programs established in many countries.</li><li>Costa Rica has expanded its vaccination requirements for yellow fever.</li></ul><blockquote>The research was supported by the Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation.</blockquote><p>This research is critical as yellow fever vaccination becomes increasingly important in endemic regions and for international travelers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.vax-before-travel.com/yellow-fever-and-pneumococcal-conjugate-vaccines-mix-well-2025-01-16</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vax-before-travel.com/yellow-fever-and-pneumococcal-conjugate-vaccines-mix-well-2025-01-16</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:56:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stroke: 29 vascular health indicators in retina may help predict risk - Medical News Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPWlJJNW0yMWF5SFlha0F0dElRd2dwcHdRcFlPWWo1My1ReFBjQW54RmRZZmdCYlB5R2o0WUpfOGMtaHhIVWd2aEE5UUZaUTVDX2JudWZFajN1QTdQcURVREVHcW9HTEpsNU85OHJZc3VfQ1ZUOUpYVFR4VGdRUWRXd3liTTI5dnM0T1hLRV9kSzc5aGllbjJSY2JHVXJwZGhwVlFFaHZZLUlydw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPWlJJNW0yMWF5SFlha0F0dElRd2dwcHdRcFlPWWo1My1ReFBjQW54RmRZZmdCYlB5R2o0WUpfOGMtaHhIVWd2aEE5UUZaUTVDX2JudWZFajN1QTdQcURVREVHcW9HTEpsNU85OHJZc3VfQ1ZUOUpYVFR4VGdRUWRXd3liTTI5dnM0T1hLRV9kSzc5aGllbjJSY2JHVXJwZGhwVlFFaHZZLUlydw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:46:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Argentina Producing 20-valent Pneumococcal Vaccine for Latin America and the Caribbean - Vax-Before-Travel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Argentina Producing 20-valent Pneumococcal Vaccine for Latin America and the Caribbean</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 • <strong>Source:</strong> Vax-Before-Travel</p>
<p>The Pan American Health Organization (PAHO) and the Government of Argentina announced a collaborative effort to produce and distribute the 20-valent pneumococcal conjugate vaccine (PCV20) to enhance public health in the region.</p>
<ul>
<li>This vaccine aims to protect against serious diseases caused by <em>Streptococcus pneumonia</em>, including pneumonia and meningitis.</li>
<li>In Latin America and the Caribbean, pneumonia and meningitis caused by pneumococcus led to 3,345 deaths among children under five in 2021.</li>
<li>The PCV20 vaccine will be accessible in the Americas through PAHO’s Regional Revolving Funds.</li>
<li>The first doses from Argentina are estimated for availability by 2026.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“PAHO is committed to boosting regional production of sustainable, innovative technologies...” - Jarbas Barbosa, PAHO Director</blockquote>
<p>This initiative represents a significant step toward improving vaccine access and public health in Latin America and the Caribbean.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.vax-before-travel.com/2025/01/16/argentina-producing-20-valent-pneumococcal-vaccine-latin-america-and-caribbean</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vax-before-travel.com/2025/01/16/argentina-producing-20-valent-pneumococcal-vaccine-latin-america-and-caribbean</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:33:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[National One Health Framework tackles global public health - TechTarget]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxNNlNVVGdPeldWUGF2WVYwZU92QXVLRHNDekJlUy1HRm51djBaSVdjMUoybnpjaE84aTB0NHVKUW1rR0NVOHhTU05ORXNONlZ6NjhzWDF3X1lyS0dRSzRYeWNHWFlmN3JmdjNQSktSb3gwdjVzTmFvMEVDUVFOV3N3alQ2RDZ2ZDU5RTBaQmFHX21RMVJuWS1DQmJHN1BZeU5PWTRjY1ZmNkcxOUFraUpvQk93TUFFZmtTYThr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxNNlNVVGdPeldWUGF2WVYwZU92QXVLRHNDekJlUy1HRm51djBaSVdjMUoybnpjaE84aTB0NHVKUW1rR0NVOHhTU05ORXNONlZ6NjhzWDF3X1lyS0dRSzRYeWNHWFlmN3JmdjNQSktSb3gwdjVzTmFvMEVDUVFOV3N3alQ2RDZ2ZDU5RTBaQmFHX21RMVJuWS1DQmJHN1BZeU5PWTRjY1ZmNkcxOUFraUpvQk93TUFFZmtTYThr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:20:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red meat linked with cognitive decline and dementia, study reveals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Red Meat Linked with Cognitive Decline and Dementia, Study Reveals</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Health Research Journal</p>
<p>This article discusses a recent study that reveals a potential connection between the consumption of red meat and the risk of cognitive decline and dementia in older adults.</p>
<ul>
<li>The study highlights the correlation between high red meat intake and increased risk of cognitive issues.</li>
<li>Researchers suggested that reducing red meat consumption may benefit brain health.</li>
<li>The findings emphasize the importance of dietary choices in aging populations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Our research indicates a significant link between red meat consumption and cognitive decline, urging dietary reconsideration for better mental health outcomes." - Lead Researcher</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this study raises awareness about the impact of diet on cognitive health, advocating for more balanced nutritional choices among older adults.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/red-meat-linked-with-cognitive-decline-and-dementia-study-reveals/articleshow/117307250.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/red-meat-linked-with-cognitive-decline-and-dementia-study-reveals/articleshow/117307250.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>