<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:19:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:19:27 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bhagyashree tries lai ki sabzi, says ‘it’s great for weight watchers’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bhagyashree Experiments with Lai Ki Sabzi, Praises Its Health Benefits</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/08/bhagyashree_1600_insta.jpg?w=640" alt="bhagyashree" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Bhagyashree shared her experience tasting Lai Ki Sabzi (Source: Bhagyashree/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Bhagyashree shared her experience tasting lai ki sabzi, a dish made with bottle gourd leaves and bamboo shoots. She praises the dish for its nutrients and suitability for weight watchers.</p><ul><li>Lai Ki Sabzi is a dish from Arunachal Pradesh.</li><li>It is made with bottle gourd leaves and bamboo shoots, enhanced by bhoot jolokia.</li><li>Bhagyashree claims it's light but flavorful, perfect for weight watchers.</li><li>Bhoot jolokia may aid in fat burning and boost metabolism.</li><li>The article highlights the nutritional benefits of both bottle gourd leaves and bamboo shoots.</li><li>Traditional ingredients like these can offer diverse health benefits compared to regular vegetables.</li></ul><blockquote>“This dish has almost all the important nutrients your body needs. It’s great for weight watchers.” - Bhagyashree</blockquote><p>Bhagyashree's endorsement of Lai Ki Sabzi emphasizes the nutritional value of traditional ingredients, encouraging its inclusion in a wholesome diet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/food-wine/bhagyashree-tries-arunachal-pradeshs-lai-ki-sabzi-9651122/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/food-wine/bhagyashree-tries-arunachal-pradeshs-lai-ki-sabzi-9651122/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:30:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 after-dinner rituals that can help in digestion, prevent bloating - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 After-Dinner Rituals to Aid Digestion and Prevent Bloating</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> TimesOfIndia.com</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116886690.jpg?imgsize=39420&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="10 after-dinner rituals that can help in digestion, prevent bloating">
<figcaption>10 after-dinner rituals that can help in digestion, prevent bloating</figcaption>
<p>Adopting simple after-dinner rituals can promote better digestion and avoid bloating. Every little effort can lead to a healthier gut and overall fitness.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Consume probiotics like yogurt or kefir at dinner to enhance gut health.</li>
  <li>Chew fennel seeds after meals to minimize bloating and gas.</li>
  <li>Take a light 10–15 minute walk after dinner to aid digestion.</li>
  <li>Drink warm water or herbal tea to relax digestive muscles.</li>
  <li>Stay hydrated by drinking water between meals without gulping after eating.</li>
  <li>Engage in gentle stretches to relieve tension in the abdomen.</li>
  <li>Avoid lying down for 2–3 hours post-meal to prevent acid reflux.</li>
  <li>Massage your abdomen to stimulate digestion and reduce discomfort.</li>
  <li>Opt for light desserts like fruit or dark chocolate to avoid heavy digestive loads.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Every little effort can be rewarded with a healthy gut and overall fitness.</blockquote>
<p>This article highlights various practices that can improve digestion and comfort after meals, emphasizing the importance of simple daily routines.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/10-after-dinner-rituals-that-can-help-in-digestion-prevent-bloating/photostory/116886148.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/10-after-dinner-rituals-that-can-help-in-digestion-prevent-bloating/photostory/116886148.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jellyfish sting: When does it become deadly? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jellyfish sting: When does it become deadly?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<p>This article discusses the risks associated with jellyfish stings, particularly focusing on when they can become lethal. It highlights the symptoms of serious reactions and provides guidelines on seeking medical help.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Jellyfish stings can cause mild to severe reactions.</li>
    <li>Certain species, like the box jellyfish, are known for their deadly venom.</li>
    <li>Immediate medical attention is crucial for severe stings.</li>
    <li>Symptoms of a serious sting include difficulty breathing and chest pain.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Understanding the signs of a serious jellyfish sting can be a matter of life and death."</blockquote>
<p>The article emphasizes the importance of awareness and education regarding jellyfish stings to prevent fatalities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/jellyfish-sting-when-does-it-become-deadly/articleshow/116870027.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/jellyfish-sting-when-does-it-become-deadly/articleshow/116870027.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Irregular sleep patterns increase heart attack and stroke risk by 26%, study finds - The Jerusalem Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Irregular Sleep Patterns Linked to Increased Risk of Heart Attack and Stroke</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-02T17:45:00+02:00">January 2, 2025</time> | <strong>Source:</strong> Jerusalem Post</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://images.jpost.com/image/upload/q_auto/c_fill,g_faces:center,h_537,w_822/641836" width="290" height="260" alt="Irregular sleep patterns increase heart attack and stroke risk by 26%, study finds. Illustration. (photo credit: WildSnap. Via Shutterstock)" title="Irregular sleep patterns increase heart attack and stroke risk by 26%, study finds. Illustration.">
<figcaption>Irregular sleep patterns increase heart attack and stroke risk by 26%, study finds. Illustration. (photo credit: WildSnap. Via Shutterstock)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A new study suggests that maintaining consistent sleep schedules may reduce the risk of heart disease and stroke. Researchers found that irregular sleep patterns are associated with a higher likelihood of serious cardiovascular events, even among individuals who get enough sleep each night.</p>
<ul>
<li>The study involved 72,269 participants aged 40 to 79 tracked over eight years.</li>
<li>Irregular sleep patterns resulted in a 26% higher risk of serious cardiovascular events.</li>
<li>Regular sleep schedules are emphasized as being crucial for health, regardless of sleep duration.</li>
<li>Sleep Regularity Index (SRI) measures the consistency of sleep patterns.</li>
<li>Disruptions in sleep can lead to hormonal imbalances and inflammation, boosting cardiovascular risks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"For optimal health, it is advisable to go to sleep and wake up at the same time every day, with a deviation of no more than 30 minutes." - Professor Jean-Philippe Chaput</blockquote>
<p>The findings underline the importance of regular sleep patterns for cardiovascular health, suggesting that public health guidelines should focus more on sleep regularity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jpost.com/science/science-around-the-world/article-835806</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jpost.com/science/science-around-the-world/article-835806</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study: One Cigarette Decreases Life Expectancy by 20 Minutes - Tobacco Reporter]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>One Cigarette Decreases Life Expectancy by 20 Minutes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Tobacco Reporter</p><p>A new study reveals that smoking just one cigarette can reduce life expectancy by an average of 20 minutes, with significant variations between genders.</p><ul><li>The study was conducted by researchers at University College London and commissioned by the U.K. Department for Health and Social Care.</li><li>Men lose about 17 minutes of life expectancy per cigarette, while women lose about 22 minutes.</li><li>According to Sarah Jackson, lead author, smoking a pack of cigarettes results in nearly seven hours of life lost.</li><li>The research utilized data from the British Doctors Study and the Million Women Study, revealing that smokers can lose around 10 years of life compared to non-smokers.</li><li>Quitting smoking can reclaim some of this lost life expectancy, especially if done at a younger age.</li></ul><blockquote>“The time they’re losing is time that they could be spending with their loved ones in fairly good health.” - Sarah Jackson</blockquote><p>The findings underline the long-term health benefits of quitting smoking at any age, emphasizing that cessation can prevent further life expectancy loss.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/01/02/study-one-cigarette-decreases-life-expectancy-by-20-minutes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/01/02/study-one-cigarette-decreases-life-expectancy-by-20-minutes/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:41:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avoid direct exposure to cold, docs caution as cardiac & BP troubles on rise - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Avoid Direct Exposure to Cold: Medical Experts Warn of Rising Cardiac and Blood Pressure Issues</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [date not provided]<strong>Source:</strong> [source not provided]</p><p>This article discusses the increasing incidence of cardiac and blood pressure-related problems as a result of cold exposure, urging caution from medical professionals.</p><ul><li>Medical experts are warning against direct exposure to cold temperatures.</li><li>Reported rise in cardiac and blood pressure disorders during colder months.</li><li>Public health advisories suggest protective measures for vulnerable populations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Cold weather can exacerbate underlying health conditions, particularly for those with pre-existing cardiac issues.”</blockquote><p>The rise in cold-related health issues underscores the need for vigilance as temperatures drop, especially among at-risk groups.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/patna/avoid-direct-exposure-to-cold-docs-caution-as-cardiac-bp-troubles-on-rise/articleshow/116890987.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/patna/avoid-direct-exposure-to-cold-docs-caution-as-cardiac-bp-troubles-on-rise/articleshow/116890987.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mission Rabies to assist Cavelossim p’yat on dog attacks - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mission Rabies to assist Cavelossim p’yat on dog attacks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>Mission Rabies is set to aid Cavelossim in addressing the rising incidents of dog attacks in the community.</p><ul><li>Mission Rabies will conduct vaccination drives in the region.</li><li>The initiative aims to reduce stray dog populations and improve community safety.</li><li>There is a growing concern among residents about uncontrolled dog attacks.</li></ul><blockquote>"This program is essential for the wellbeing of both the animals and the people in Cavelossim." - Local Community Leader</blockquote><p>The collaboration is a significant step towards ensuring public safety and addressing the strays issue in Cavelossim.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/goa/mission-rabies-to-assist-cavelossim-pyat-on-dog-attacks/articleshow/116890304.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/goa/mission-rabies-to-assist-cavelossim-pyat-on-dog-attacks/articleshow/116890304.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[30 Minutes of Aerobic Exercise Weekly Cuts Body Fat in Adults With Overweight or Obesity - Clinical Advisor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>30 Minutes of Aerobic Exercise Weekly Cuts Body Fat in Adults With Overweight or Obesity</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Published on JAMA Network Open</p>
<img src="https://www.clinicaladvisor.com/wp-content/themes/hm-advisor-child/assets/svg/key-point_icon.svg" alt="Aerobic Exercise Key Points" width="100" height="100" />
<figcaption>Aerobic exercise linked to reduced body weight and waist circumference.</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses a review that found that just 30 minutes of aerobic exercise per week can significantly reduce body weight and body fat among adults who are overweight or obese.</p>
<ul>
<li>30 minutes of aerobic exercise per week linked to moderate reductions in body weight, waist circumference, and body fat measures.</li>
<li>Study involved 116 randomized clinical trials with 6,880 participants.</li>
<li>Each 30 minutes of aerobic exercise results in a reduction of 0.52 kg in body weight and 0.56 cm in waist circumference.</li>
<li>Increased quality of life, but also increased mild-to-moderate adverse events mainly related to musculoskeletal symptoms.</li>
<li>More significant reductions in body metrics were observed with more extended exercise durations, especially at 150 minutes per week.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our results suggest that aerobic training exceeding 150 minutes per week at moderate intensity or greater may be needed to achieve associations with clinically important reductions,” the authors write.</blockquote>
<p>This review emphasizes the importance of integrating regular aerobic exercise into health regimens for those with overweight or obesity, highlighting that even modest amounts can yield meaningful health benefits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.clinicaladvisor.com/news/aerobic-exercise-weekly-cuts-body-fat-in-adults-with-overweight-or-obesity/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.clinicaladvisor.com/news/aerobic-exercise-weekly-cuts-body-fat-in-adults-with-overweight-or-obesity/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is ‘art of living’ the antidote to depression? Study sheds light on the benefits - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is ‘art of living’ the antidote to depression? Study sheds light on the benefits</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/depression_1735825830009_1735825830299.jpg" alt="Researchers are trying to alter between decreasing the negative thoughts, as well as improving positive thoughts to manage depression symptoms. (Pexels)"><figcaption>Researchers are trying to alter between decreasing the negative thoughts, as well as improving positive thoughts to manage depression symptoms. (Pexels)</figcaption><p>The study observed that self-reflection and a positive approach can help improve the symptoms of depression. Researchers found that combining traditional therapies with art of living techniques benefited patients.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The study involved 161 participants diagnosed with mild to severe depression.</li><li>Participants were divided into three groups: psychotherapy only, psychotherapy with self-reflection, and a control group with no treatment.</li><li>The self-reflection group reported the most significant improvements in life satisfaction and depression management.</li><li>While the practices showed immediate benefits, the effects diminished after three months without continued practice.</li></ul><blockquote>“While art of living practices can have immediate impact on people with depression, the effects may decrease without continuation of the practice.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, integrating self-reflection and positivity can enhance wellbeing for those suffering from depression, but long-term benefits may require ongoing commitment to these practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/is-art-of-living-the-antidote-to-depression-study-sheds-light-on-the-benefits-101735825683704.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/is-art-of-living-the-antidote-to-depression-study-sheds-light-on-the-benefits-101735825683704.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:42:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Time to learn a new language? Study says being bilingual slows down the progression of Alzheimer’s disease - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Study Finds Bilingualism May Slow Alzheimer's Progression</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/brain_health_1735827779239_1735827779392.jpg" alt="The deterioration of cognitive health might be slowed in Alzehimer's if one is bilingual. (Shutterstock)" title="The deterioration of cognitive health might be slowed in Alzehimer's if one is bilingual. (Shutterstock)">
<figcaption>The deterioration of cognitive health might be slowed in Alzehimer's if one is bilingual. (Shutterstock)</figcaption>
<p>Research suggests that being bilingual may help slow cognitive decline associated with Alzheimer’s disease, particularly by protecting the hippocampus, which is critical for memory.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study published in the journal <em>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</em> indicates bilingual individuals experience slower hippocampal shrinkage.</li>
  <li>People with Alzheimer's who speak multiple languages maintain better memory function compared to monolinguals.</li>
  <li>Bilingualism may serve as a protective factor against cognitive decline.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Speaking multiple languages may offer a form of brain protection, possibly by maintaining the volume of memory-related brain areas.”</blockquote>
<p>The findings highlight the potential benefits of bilingualism in healthcare and cognitive longevity, suggesting that learning new languages could be a valuable New Year resolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/time-to-learn-a-new-language-study-says-being-bilingual-slows-down-the-progression-of-alzheimer-s-disease-101735827554439.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/time-to-learn-a-new-language-study-says-being-bilingual-slows-down-the-progression-of-alzheimer-s-disease-101735827554439.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:38:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Covid vibes, multiple viruses spreading': Is China hiding a new epidemic? Here's what we know - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Covid vibes, multiple viruses spreading: Is China hiding a new epidemic? Here's what we know</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250102140721_china.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Crowded Hospitals in China" title="Crowded Hospitals in China" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Crowded hospitals in China amid rumors of an epidemic.</figcaption><p>There are increasing concerns about multiple viruses spreading in China, reminiscent of the COVID pandemic. Videos and reports suggest that hospitals are overwhelmed and a state of health emergency may be in effect.</p><ul><li>Social media posts indicate a severe flu outbreak, with significant overcrowding in hospitals.</li><li>Viruses reported include Influenza A, HMPV, and others, alongside COVID-19.</li><li>Claims of a health emergency being declared due to the rapid spread of these viruses.</li></ul><blockquote>"Hospitals in China are overwhelmed by a severe 'flu' outbreak, including Influenza A and HMPV, drawing comparisons to the 2020 COVID surge."</blockquote><p>This situation highlights ongoing public health challenges in China and raises questions about the transparency of information being shared.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/covid-vibes-multiple-viruses-spreading-is-china-hiding-a-new-epidemic-here-s-what-we-know-12902391.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/covid-vibes-multiple-viruses-spreading-is-china-hiding-a-new-epidemic-here-s-what-we-know-12902391.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:11:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is there an epidemic brewing in China? - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is China facing a hidden epidemic? Shocking hospital footage sparks global panic!</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 2, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> indiatodayglobal</p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/is-there-an-epidemic-spreading-in-china-024925954-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=iSRyS15phJAQerI0D2Bin3Ur_w4ZVoqb&amp;size=690:388" alt="Is There an Epidemic Spreading in China?" width="690" height="388">
<figcaption>Is There an Epidemic Spreading in China?</figcaption>
<p>Social media platforms have been inundated with alarming claims about a new epidemic spreading across China. Users are sharing videos showing overcrowded hospitals and suggesting the rapid spread of multiple respiratory viruses, including Influenza A, HMPV, Mycoplasma pneumoniae, and COVID-19. These unverified reports have sparked widespread concern.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The videos depict crowded hospitals but lack official evidence of an epidemic.</li>
  <li>Health authorities and the WHO have not confirmed any emergency status.</li>
  <li>There is a call for the public to rely on verified information to avoid misinformation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It is crucial for the public to rely on verified information from trusted health authorities.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, despite the viral nature of the videos, there is no credible evidence to support claims of an epidemic in China at this time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/is-there-an-epidemic-brewing-in-china-2658817-2025-01-02</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/is-there-an-epidemic-brewing-in-china-2658817-2025-01-02</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:53:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revolutionizing Addiction Care: How a Simple Smartphone App Could Transform Fight Against Opioid Abuse - Elets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxPYzMxcEd1Y3liVDVzNkhOSVNUcmlSaFlHNDNfa3BhZ0pkTTI3Sk5wSklIM0JCSHdvM0lUdUpXUzY4NldTX2FUUkc1X1BlZEcwLVE4cktmSjJBUmM2OFZZakF5djk4WW9tVk9YQ1J3S2Y0MzdQSDBHSmpUbWNnN20tV2tuTjJ4SC00NzctSmxob1RydUVoT0xmblVEbTU4bmdQVFlnb0x1cWVHYTVRNEhPUEdKQkhYbmVCVHVYWmtNXzNBS3dJUl9xenltSFUyTG41RWtXc3NJY21VUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxPYzMxcEd1Y3liVDVzNkhOSVNUcmlSaFlHNDNfa3BhZ0pkTTI3Sk5wSklIM0JCSHdvM0lUdUpXUzY4NldTX2FUUkc1X1BlZEcwLVE4cktmSjJBUmM2OFZZakF5djk4WW9tVk9YQ1J3S2Y0MzdQSDBHSmpUbWNnN20tV2tuTjJ4SC00NzctSmxob1RydUVoT0xmblVEbTU4bmdQVFlnb0x1cWVHYTVRNEhPUEdKQkhYbmVCVHVYWmtNXzNBS3dJUl9xenltSFUyTG41RWtXc3NJY21VUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:42:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Want to Get Fit in 2025? These Are the Two Best Exercises for Beginners, According to a PT - Men's Health UK]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Two Best Exercises for Beginners According to a PT</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Men's Health</p><p>If you're looking to start a fitness journey, personal trainer Mike Chang recommends two simple exercises that beginners can easily integrate into their routine.</p><ul><li>Exercise 1: Push-ups - A beginner-friendly variation using a table for support.</li><li>Exercise 2: Squats - Another supported variation that helps develop mobility and strength.</li><li>Five-minute workouts are effective for beginners and can lead to stronger, longer workout sessions over time.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is such a great way to start back into an exercise routine. Don't worry about doing something super tough, super big. Just five minutes [is enough]." - Mike Chang</blockquote><p>Starting with small, manageable workouts can help build consistency and strength over time, setting the foundation for more intense workouts in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.menshealth.com/uk/fitness/a63320917/two-best-exercises-for-beginners/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.menshealth.com/uk/fitness/a63320917/two-best-exercises-for-beginners/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:15:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shalini Passi shares 10 skincare secrets for radiant skin - Health shots]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shalini Passi shares 10 skincare secrets for radiant skin</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 2 January 2025, 06:41pm IST</p><img src="https://images.healthshots.com/healthshots/en/uploads/2025/01/02171802/skincare.jpg" alt="Skincare Tips" width="370" height="207"><figcaption>Skincare Tips by Shalini Passi</figcaption><p>Shalini Passi, known from Fabulous Lives of Bollywood Wives, shares her top 10 skincare tips for maintaining a radiant complexion at 49 years old. Here's how she achieves her glow.</p><ul><li>Embraces natural ingredients</li><li>Detox with warm lemon water</li><li>Enjoys beetroot smoothie</li><li>Meditates in the morning</li><li>Performs weightlifting and Pilates</li><li>Prioritizes beauty sleep</li><li>Practices clean eating</li></ul><blockquote>“Natural ingredients are key to my skincare routine.”</blockquote><p>Shalini's tips emphasize the importance of natural care and lifestyle choices for healthy skin.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthshots.com/photos/shalini-passi-shares-10-skincare-tips/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthshots.com/photos/shalini-passi-shares-10-skincare-tips/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:11:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s why ‘worrisome’ mutations in bird flu virus infecting Canadian teenager have raised alarms - Down To Earth Magazine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Here’s why ‘worrisome’ mutations in bird flu virus infecting Canadian teenager have raised alarms</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-02T12:47:34.849Z">02 Jan 2025, 12:47 pm</time></p><p>Researchers have raised alarms regarding mutations in the H5N1 bird flu virus, evidenced by a recent case involving a 13-year-old girl in British Columbia who was hospitalized after contracting this strain. The potential for human-to-human transmission is being closely monitored.</p><ul><li>A 13-year-old girl from British Columbia contracted the H5N1 virus with significant mutations.</li><li>Mutations linked to increased virulence were found in her samples.</li><li>Another case in Louisiana showed a similar strain in a worker exposed to infected birds.</li><li>The patient had significant symptoms but was discharged after treatment.</li><li>Calls for coordinated responses from medical and agricultural authorities have been emphasized.</li></ul><blockquote>“The mutations evident in the Canadian case highlight the urgent need for vigilant surveillance of emerging mutations and assessment of the threat of human-to-human transmission,” researchers stated.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the emergence of these mutations underscores the importance of ongoing surveillance and collaboration to prevent potential outbreaks of H5N1 among humans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/health/heres-why-worrisome-mutations-in-bird-flu-virus-infecting-canadian-teenager-have-raised-alarms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.downtoearth.org.in/health/heres-why-worrisome-mutations-in-bird-flu-virus-infecting-canadian-teenager-have-raised-alarms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:47:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bedtime tales are more than children's stories: Study shows they are metaphors for sleep-related problems - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bedtime tales are more than children's stories: Study shows they are metaphors for sleep-related problems</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/bedtime_stories_1735815956499_1735815956664.jpg" alt="Children throw a fit when they have to go to sleep and often they are read stories to calm down." title="Children throw a fit when they have to go to sleep and often they are read stories to calm down.">
<figcaption>Children throw a fit when they have to go to sleep and often they are read stories to calm down. (Shutterstock)</figcaption>
<p>This study suggests that popular children's bedtime stories like Snow White and Goldilocks serve as metaphors for various sleep-related issues, educating children on the importance of sleep.</p>
<ul>
<li>Bedtime stories are a common ritual for helping children wind down for sleep.</li>
<li>The research published in the British Medical Journal explores the deeper meanings behind fairytales.</li>
<li>Stories analyzed include Snow White, The Princess and the Pea, Goldilocks, and Peter Pan, each relating to sleep disorders.</li>
<li>The BEARS screener is introduced as a tool for identifying children's sleep problems.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These behaviours are often associated with sleep disorders like obstructive sleep apnea, which affects sleep quality and leads to daytime behavioural difficulties.”</blockquote>
<p>The findings emphasize the educational potential of bedtime stories in promoting healthy sleep habits among children.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/bedtime-tales-are-more-than-childrens-stories-study-shows-they-are-metaphors-for-sleep-related-problems-101735814938232.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/bedtime-tales-are-more-than-childrens-stories-study-shows-they-are-metaphors-for-sleep-related-problems-101735814938232.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:44:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Korean scientists repair cancer cells to become normal, healthy: Report - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPZUd5cVdkVzBvQkhrVFR3U0ZFQThoLTJBbFNGNmo3WUZLSUJsdlZ5d281ZXdoWGtpczhUSnl6OFFES0NEYl9ocllIbGF4WE1KTXVheDVjOU1xZ2UzZkpobVZjMzNmVlBkVFdweWtVNkZxMUhUZG5za0hSaW9jNHp5YTlybHRfR2FneXA0bEVFckJ6NGhYVHloNGlUbEcza0JYdkExcE93Yy15emJWeUxxbG5oQXhlZmdVSGpKeEg0QmtYazI0ZlHSAcsBQVVfeXFMTnRaX1ZFWjYxUHVVdmNaaTRkM0stTGdoRl82eWF5bzdKaFhoTnE5bHlLYWRveEpqdzd0TU8zOEdhTUlfaDNDOHN3cUZ6M3dhZVhCWjZnVlBXS3pSaU5KSDJ3dWFsMGp6aHBKQkJkYzZ0ZU85NzVxb3BPOXNYcGZfQS1NRWZWcHRFdnVBcGlOd2hudldRRmdxNkRLTTZxeTBUTlhraHpXMFl6LTB6QzFrWk84aXFQU0poZlhNUzh4Zm10MDJBaF9EUl9GUTg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPZUd5cVdkVzBvQkhrVFR3U0ZFQThoLTJBbFNGNmo3WUZLSUJsdlZ5d281ZXdoWGtpczhUSnl6OFFES0NEYl9ocllIbGF4WE1KTXVheDVjOU1xZ2UzZkpobVZjMzNmVlBkVFdweWtVNkZxMUhUZG5za0hSaW9jNHp5YTlybHRfR2FneXA0bEVFckJ6NGhYVHloNGlUbEcza0JYdkExcE93Yy15emJWeUxxbG5oQXhlZmdVSGpKeEg0QmtYazI0ZlHSAcsBQVVfeXFMTnRaX1ZFWjYxUHVVdmNaaTRkM0stTGdoRl82eWF5bzdKaFhoTnE5bHlLYWRveEpqdzd0TU8zOEdhTUlfaDNDOHN3cUZ6M3dhZVhCWjZnVlBXS3pSaU5KSDJ3dWFsMGp6aHBKQkJkYzZ0ZU85NzVxb3BPOXNYcGZfQS1NRWZWcHRFdnVBcGlOd2hudldRRmdxNkRLTTZxeTBUTlhraHpXMFl6LTB6QzFrWk84aXFQU0poZlhNUzh4Zm10MDJBaF9EUl9GUTg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:15:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhancing health and nutrition for the elderly in India - Observer Research Foundation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxQQ19kcjBDb0VGN0U5V0lnZlBadDctMDZTQ2w0dEFPUE9QX0VFOHBXdGEyZFpPZWRZYlhWQ3lsZWtERXI4a1ltMWMxT0RWYUlxZW1VRnd0bnQteGpFTmcwRTRoSU15MFN3YnNoZVFoSHc3blhZYnRQOXgtVHY3SE9YVmlCMUZ2MERORzhKbG5SZnBhVHlGanA1Mmp3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxQQ19kcjBDb0VGN0U5V0lnZlBadDctMDZTQ2w0dEFPUE9QX0VFOHBXdGEyZFpPZWRZYlhWQ3lsZWtERXI4a1ltMWMxT0RWYUlxZW1VRnd0bnQteGpFTmcwRTRoSU15MFN3YnNoZVFoSHc3blhZYnRQOXgtVHY3SE9YVmlCMUZ2MERORzhKbG5SZnBhVHlGanA1Mmp3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:14:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elderly woman reduces knee pain naturally with one major dietary change - Watch video - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elderly woman reduces knee pain naturally with one major dietary change – Watch video</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> india.com</p><figure><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Untitled-design-2025-01-02T174302.899.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Knee pain is common in elderly women (Freepik)"><figcaption>Knee pain is common in elderly women (Freepik)</figcaption></figure><p>A recent video highlights how dietary changes helped an elderly woman significantly reduce her knee pain, avoiding the need for surgery.</p><ul><li>Knee pain is a common issue, particularly among elderly women.</li><li>A doctor shared insights on how increased protein intake positively impacted the woman’s health.</li><li>Key changes in her diet included consuming more high-protein foods like eggs, paneer, meat, and legumes while reducing rice and wheat.</li><li>Dr. Sayajirao Gaikwad noted a 75% improvement in her knee pain.</li><li>The woman's condition improved without the need for knee replacement surgery.</li></ul><blockquote>“With just putting them on high protein foods we see change in quality of their life. Our elder deserve nutrient dense foods.” – Dr. Sayajirao Gaikwad</blockquote><p>This case demonstrates the potential of dietary interventions in managing chronic pain and enhancing quality of life for the elderly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/health/elderly-woman-reduces-knee-pain-naturally-with-one-major-dietary-change-watch-video-7509832/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/health/elderly-woman-reduces-knee-pain-naturally-with-one-major-dietary-change-watch-video-7509832/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:13:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India will launch the world's most expensive satellite in..., It will scan nearly all land and ice every 12 d - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAJBVV95cUxQaXhlVVFKUERjdWxnTmdSdjhTWEJ5TThQU20tQm5OcGVZX0RlVFpZNzhDSnhYRlZJQTlrUk9wY2RNSG5ud01uVlZ4Z294Ujd2RWtnWFFqU2E5ZmI3cmtHRU0yTkpLZFBUbXZfZXRKdDVNeWF1cUVsMEtTV2Nwb2FaWE1KN2dzMFpsUzNmeE9tTVJrRjdRV1BxVDhCWjlmZEpGQl9IUnlOUENiNTQ3d1F3bHB0T19XZUNFVWVtVFA4bmNScVJTd1dDbS1ENF9xWjA1UGd6eGk1R1I3OHVhREl5SWVoejYybXJnakl4S0RHZ3hKNFBScHNHb3JYVlJnbWxIX2d4RWZzQWUyNjg20gGSAkFVX3lxTE5YMFhQT0l1ZllSb1M4T0FyNVV2RlJKd3pSSWItcWs3OTEtcGFiNW1HVG1selRKQThxRWkzbHF3OGxhd0dlUEUzMXJzUkpaaUZPQ0cwYU5PcFdFRGlpNzRyWTZmaG9TZDRTclk4SFhwQ1A4eG01UlM0SFZGbDRZX0tGWTBnRFNMOUswakFEUjNhcXltSjB2YXVmbDBBR1FDYWE4cjlKaHpLdHc4dXctSDFoV1E4VGo1YVNFdDViZ2pwOVA2QWNwRmJvajljN3NKZzZ5UG93Z1BmUkNoNUgxX3NtUjIxUUhfRWZfUXJpd1FJcEFpT1ZJLUR4SkhUdjh3X1RYenhZcHF2RXlJVzl5dENQbFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAJBVV95cUxQaXhlVVFKUERjdWxnTmdSdjhTWEJ5TThQU20tQm5OcGVZX0RlVFpZNzhDSnhYRlZJQTlrUk9wY2RNSG5ud01uVlZ4Z294Ujd2RWtnWFFqU2E5ZmI3cmtHRU0yTkpLZFBUbXZfZXRKdDVNeWF1cUVsMEtTV2Nwb2FaWE1KN2dzMFpsUzNmeE9tTVJrRjdRV1BxVDhCWjlmZEpGQl9IUnlOUENiNTQ3d1F3bHB0T19XZUNFVWVtVFA4bmNScVJTd1dDbS1ENF9xWjA1UGd6eGk1R1I3OHVhREl5SWVoejYybXJnakl4S0RHZ3hKNFBScHNHb3JYVlJnbWxIX2d4RWZzQWUyNjg20gGSAkFVX3lxTE5YMFhQT0l1ZllSb1M4T0FyNVV2RlJKd3pSSWItcWs3OTEtcGFiNW1HVG1selRKQThxRWkzbHF3OGxhd0dlUEUzMXJzUkpaaUZPQ0cwYU5PcFdFRGlpNzRyWTZmaG9TZDRTclk4SFhwQ1A4eG01UlM0SFZGbDRZX0tGWTBnRFNMOUswakFEUjNhcXltSjB2YXVmbDBBR1FDYWE4cjlKaHpLdHc4dXctSDFoV1E4VGo1YVNFdDViZ2pwOVA2QWNwRmJvajljN3NKZzZ5UG93Z1BmUkNoNUgxX3NtUjIxUUhfRWZfUXJpd1FJcEFpT1ZJLUR4SkhUdjh3X1RYenhZcHF2RXlJVzl5dENQbFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:02:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian scientists show hormone melatonin can treat Parkinson's - The Hans India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNNjQzWTlaeGFUNzZBMFc1WGk4ZXBJXzg0NmJFLUxRWDRIeFAtRG82QklKMTR1RmpzdHJLampzV2hnQ2RHcnhQalNPTGVBNlc0eHExeG5PdFBfOWh2MzltWlp3SFpkSGZKUS05eU9lMjJsY1hWaTR0THZFV21PbnZ4bmZwZmJnbVgzdGR0U2VybnpwZ1JEZXkzYWlBWUtycTRrajlxTE9OUlRxRUpjZWpnUHl0cC1qQdIBuwFBVV95cUxORzkwZVh4X3I3bWlmSEpBQUhJUzJjWGxuYnBxZFkwNkxJYU8ycmNyMVV3WWlpWFF6M3MyUkZMamRYVzJDeXRDQjBFQlVUaVJra05PVHd1SF8yZ0J2cDhfUEVRbEJjSFMyRzV5ZWVpbGF6d0NJZlB1UVVRWmpkQTdidkowTURyZWRzNmhkOEFCUGZZRWNBNFVlNWRwV3dsUEpJamRYeV9RcUFxd1VCVkd3d0tzTzRlQnZYYm1B?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNNjQzWTlaeGFUNzZBMFc1WGk4ZXBJXzg0NmJFLUxRWDRIeFAtRG82QklKMTR1RmpzdHJLampzV2hnQ2RHcnhQalNPTGVBNlc0eHExeG5PdFBfOWh2MzltWlp3SFpkSGZKUS05eU9lMjJsY1hWaTR0THZFV21PbnZ4bmZwZmJnbVgzdGR0U2VybnpwZ1JEZXkzYWlBWUtycTRrajlxTE9OUlRxRUpjZWpnUHl0cC1qQdIBuwFBVV95cUxORzkwZVh4X3I3bWlmSEpBQUhJUzJjWGxuYnBxZFkwNkxJYU8ycmNyMVV3WWlpWFF6M3MyUkZMamRYVzJDeXRDQjBFQlVUaVJra05PVHd1SF8yZ0J2cDhfUEVRbEJjSFMyRzV5ZWVpbGF6d0NJZlB1UVVRWmpkQTdidkowTURyZWRzNmhkOEFCUGZZRWNBNFVlNWRwV3dsUEpJamRYeV9RcUFxd1VCVkd3d0tzTzRlQnZYYm1B?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:58:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Norovirus Cases Spike In US, Minnesota Worst Hit - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Norovirus Cases Spike In US, Minnesota Worst Hit</h1><p><strong>Updated:</strong> Thursday, January 02, 2025, 05:15 PM IST</p><p>It's now established worldover after coronavirus pandemic that news about public health and public health as a whole, is something to be taken seriously. United States Centers for Disease Control (CDC) has now flagged that norovirus cases have seen a spike in the US. It is not yet known what is causing the spike and the CDC is monitoring the situation.</p><ul><li>Norovirus outbreaks are typically seen in winter, but this season is seeing a significant increase in cases.</li><li>On December 5, 2023, the CDC reported 91 cases in just 7 days, a drastic increase compared to previous years.</li><li>In the years 2020-2024, the highest number of cases recorded in the same time frame was 56.</li><li>Over 40 of the recent cases have been reported in Minnesota, double the usual count.</li></ul><blockquote>“We want to make sure people are aware of this increase in norovirus outbreaks and taking steps to prevent spreading illness to family or friends,” said Jessica Hancock-Allen, the director of the infectious disease division at the Minnesota Department of Health.</blockquote><p>This spike in norovirus cases highlights the need for public awareness and preventive measures, especially as the situation develops.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/world/norovirus-cases-spike-in-us-minnesota-worst-hit</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/world/norovirus-cases-spike-in-us-minnesota-worst-hit</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:45:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Size of pupils during sleep could be key to how brain forms strong memories, mice study suggests - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Size of pupils during sleep could be key to how brain forms strong memories, mice study suggests</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://images.hindustantimes.com/default/550x309.jpg" alt="HT Image" title="HT Image">
<figcaption>HT Image</figcaption>
<p>A recent study on mice indicates that the size of pupils during sleep—whether contracted or dilated—could play a critical role in how the brain forms long-lasting memories, potentially providing insights for improving human memory.</p>
<ul>
<li>The study reveals that while asleep, the brain consolidates memories by replaying recent experiences.</li>
<li>Research from Cornell University tracked pupil movements in mice to observe memory replay.</li>
<li>Newer memories are replayed during pupil contraction; older memories during pupil dilation.</li>
<li>The findings might aid in addressing memory integration challenges in artificial neural networks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Non-REM sleep is when the actual memory consolidation happens... very short periods of time undetectable by humans, like 100 milliseconds.” - Azahara Oliva</blockquote>
<p>This research offers vital insights into the mechanisms of memory consolidation and may inform future studies on memory enhancement in humans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/science/size-of-pupils-during-sleep-could-be-key-to-how-brain-forms-strong-memories-mice-study-suggests-101735818093791.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/science/size-of-pupils-during-sleep-could-be-key-to-how-brain-forms-strong-memories-mice-study-suggests-101735818093791.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take Charge of Your Well-Being in 2025 - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Take Charge of Your Well-Being in 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2024/11/healthy-food-2024-11-422bef4abec370ee6ad71ec243513386.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Embrace the opportunity to make meaningful changes nourishing your body, staying active, and cultivating a positive mindset" title="Embrace the opportunity to make meaningful changes nourishing your body, staying active, and cultivating a positive mindset" loading="eager"><figcaption>Embrace the opportunity to make meaningful changes nourishing your body, staying active, and cultivating a positive mindset</figcaption><p>As we step into 2025, the role of nutrition in achieving long-term health cannot be overstated. Prioritizing essential nutrients has become essential. This approach is an investment in our future health and happiness.</p><ul><li>Nutrition is now about balancing macronutrients and micronutrients.</li><li>Rising awareness leads to increased demand for nutrient-dense foods.</li><li>Oral nutritional supplements can help fill nutritional gaps.</li><li>Different life stages require tailored nutritional needs.</li><li>Incorporating key nutrients like proteins, omega-3s, vitamins, and minerals into daily meals is crucial.</li></ul><blockquote>“As people become more mindful of their eating habits, the demand for nutrient-dense foods is rising.” - Dr. Priti Thakor</blockquote><p>Small changes can lead to significant health improvements, and regular physical activity is crucial for maintaining overall well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-take-charge-of-your-well-being-in-2025-9175420.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-take-charge-of-your-well-being-in-2025-9175420.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:41:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indulged in constant snacking and drinking during new year celebration? Here's how it affects health and what you can do - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgJBVV95cUxNb0hWR3JmT1NBaFpSTEtGVlNidEMxV050R1A5R20tMmNLVy1Gc2RJMzJoM2VHTngyOTM2cWdSQjRFRENvd1V5dmJsNFlsbFZKT0hhaFExREZrZW00UWhPeG9RVU1vMndSZkdxXzdIZzVDN05aRlZDQ1JaSFJuMm5QZ3A0X1BIM0dlXy11RXpueDBMSDNMT3d6bGdxN19wcWhmWU1XYkFDQkFzYnVzeTVHb25ZRTE5RTVWRXFTX211Qy1BT0JXaW44azFqV3pLMmhzUUY0VVBrZHdQZGV0ajJuX0MyWGdCWml6eVE5TDdBTXNNa2M5Q08tOUZOUTNPaEdGMW0zNlh4UnN5Ym5PcF9LekJZZHlsZ9IBmwJBVV95cUxNZDhod2dsOTZuSHN3T0NVWG1yLWZiMWgtYlVRa3RNc0RiVFg5NmgwZWRkaFBlN0Vpd0RaQzdtbEZtRUJKei1mVnBOQkZTWHpaT2xSX2RlNVpSdm04S0htVVo3R3NTN25pd3Ffd2lfREVQTmt3NHdjbmtTR3hQQzZocktQeERWZWdXYnY3WDgtUThrSTRWZFc5T3F5cFZYT2xTQjIxMzRfM3RqZEdOUEE3NkQwc0k5N3FQUVJYWkFYeWtNVE9iTV9WNW5Dd21RbzMyUXBmby1UVEFQVGJFd21UNHVCOHZaMG9nclU2czJUMWNIdGZEX05UOUlmcEdRajNvU3dDZENEaWZndUN5ZGJMbnd4U0lDemJBSV9R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgJBVV95cUxNb0hWR3JmT1NBaFpSTEtGVlNidEMxV050R1A5R20tMmNLVy1Gc2RJMzJoM2VHTngyOTM2cWdSQjRFRENvd1V5dmJsNFlsbFZKT0hhaFExREZrZW00UWhPeG9RVU1vMndSZkdxXzdIZzVDN05aRlZDQ1JaSFJuMm5QZ3A0X1BIM0dlXy11RXpueDBMSDNMT3d6bGdxN19wcWhmWU1XYkFDQkFzYnVzeTVHb25ZRTE5RTVWRXFTX211Qy1BT0JXaW44azFqV3pLMmhzUUY0VVBrZHdQZGV0ajJuX0MyWGdCWml6eVE5TDdBTXNNa2M5Q08tOUZOUTNPaEdGMW0zNlh4UnN5Ym5PcF9LekJZZHlsZ9IBmwJBVV95cUxNZDhod2dsOTZuSHN3T0NVWG1yLWZiMWgtYlVRa3RNc0RiVFg5NmgwZWRkaFBlN0Vpd0RaQzdtbEZtRUJKei1mVnBOQkZTWHpaT2xSX2RlNVpSdm04S0htVVo3R3NTN25pd3Ffd2lfREVQTmt3NHdjbmtTR3hQQzZocktQeERWZWdXYnY3WDgtUThrSTRWZFc5T3F5cFZYT2xTQjIxMzRfM3RqZEdOUEE3NkQwc0k5N3FQUVJYWkFYeWtNVE9iTV9WNW5Dd21RbzMyUXBmby1UVEFQVGJFd21UNHVCOHZaMG9nclU2czJUMWNIdGZEX05UOUlmcEdRajNvU3dDZENEaWZndUN5ZGJMbnd4U0lDemJBSV9R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:31:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Secrets to younger-looking skin: 5 must-know tips - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOWXhTaW5mUEVlQWl1bmNVY0lzNkZOSE9PeEtEUTFpaHFQcjRIa2pNU2VnSlFiY1c1WnVENFdnMWNOQkdqVlhTR3dJMlZxNVJTN2tNQ2NUekhIeGo5RTlGam1GX09WMmxlb19NOEVkbU1FUUlsWFdpM1otSXBDdi1RTEdEY0pOcWc5VXo2MjZHSVJNaFo1V21HN2M5cm1sVjhjaF9XQThKcm96N0ZnbHN4WQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOWXhTaW5mUEVlQWl1bmNVY0lzNkZOSE9PeEtEUTFpaHFQcjRIa2pNU2VnSlFiY1c1WnVENFdnMWNOQkdqVlhTR3dJMlZxNVJTN2tNQ2NUekhIeGo5RTlGam1GX09WMmxlb19NOEVkbU1FUUlsWFdpM1otSXBDdi1RTEdEY0pOcWc5VXo2MjZHSVJNaFo1V21HN2M5cm1sVjhjaF9XQThKcm96N0ZnbHN4WQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:30:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Noroviurs cases in US sees a surge; here's what you can do to avoid getting infected - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Surge in Norovirus Cases in the US: Prevention Tips to Stay Safe</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116881114,imgsize-993535,width-400,resizemode-4/116881114.jpg" alt="Norovirus cases in the US" title="(Image: Canva)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Image: Canva</figcaption><p>Norovirus cases are experiencing a significant surge in the US, with recent CDC reports indicating a notable increase in infections compared to previous years.</p><ul><li>The CDC reported 91 cases in the first week of December.</li><li>Norovirus is a leading cause of foodborne illnesses worldwide.</li><li>Approximately 900 deaths occur annually due to norovirus among individuals over 65.</li><li>Symptoms include nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, and stomach cramps, usually appearing within 12-48 hours after exposure.</li><li>Preventive measures include frequent hand washing with soap and water.</li></ul><blockquote>“Washing your hands with soap and water for at least 20 seconds is mandatory,” the CDC advises.</blockquote><p>As norovirus continues to spread, following recommended guidelines can help individuals avoid infection and reduce transmission rates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/noroviurs-cases-in-us-sees-a-surge-heres-what-you-can-do-to-avoid-getting-infected/articleshow/116881129.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/noroviurs-cases-in-us-sees-a-surge-heres-what-you-can-do-to-avoid-getting-infected/articleshow/116881129.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shaping the Future: Innovations Transforming Metastatic Breast Cancer Care - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shaping the Future: Innovations Transforming Metastatic Breast Cancer Care</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Innovations in Metastatic Breast Cancer Care" />
<figcaption>In the last few years, the groundbreaking strides in advanced and targeted therapies, immunotherapy, artificial intelligence, and next-generation diagnostics have given a renewed sense of hope to patients and healthcare providers.</figcaption>
<p>The landscape of Metastatic Breast Cancer (MBC) care in India and globally is undergoing a shift, driven by cutting-edge advancements in medicine and technology.</p>
<ul>
<li>About 60% of Indian cases are diagnosed with breast cancer in stages III and IV.</li>
<li>Advanced targeted therapies and immunotherapy are delivering unprecedented efficacy.</li>
<li>AI precision medicine enhances early detection and personalized therapy planning.</li>
<li>Liquid biopsies are revolutionizing diagnostics for metastatic breast cancer.</li>
<li>These innovations significantly improve patient outcomes and quality of life.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These innovations will further reshape the treatment care of Metastatic Breast Cancer Technologies and therapies, which were supposed to extend life, have instead restored hope and dignity in metastatic breast cancer patients.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the integration of technology and advanced therapies in metastatic breast cancer treatment is setting the stage for a brighter future, allowing patients to lead longer and better lives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-shaping-the-future-innovations-transforming-metastatic-breast-cancer-care-9175243.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-shaping-the-future-innovations-transforming-metastatic-breast-cancer-care-9175243.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:28:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nano-formulation of darkness hormone could be therapeutic solution for Parkinson's disease - Department Of Science & Technology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxPTUdCa2hKZC0wVXZVTGJxM09zR0F0N3BFSDNJRUxpTkt4VlExMWlfb1JBT1pJWDBLYXNGY0hqYlp3VWlPYlY4ekpTc1EwbDFlYnBpZ1BqalFoeVo3TkgyRFdabXd5MWk0ZWh4ckIzcXdWanJKRmtMWjR5N2RyaUV1a1NEblN1NUxfZGlzNE8zOXBmdE9uUVhCbmVJa3VzN29EeTVB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxPTUdCa2hKZC0wVXZVTGJxM09zR0F0N3BFSDNJRUxpTkt4VlExMWlfb1JBT1pJWDBLYXNGY0hqYlp3VWlPYlY4ekpTc1EwbDFlYnBpZ1BqalFoeVo3TkgyRFdabXd5MWk0ZWh4ckIzcXdWanJKRmtMWjR5N2RyaUV1a1NEblN1NUxfZGlzNE8zOXBmdE9uUVhCbmVJa3VzN29EeTVB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:27:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>