<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 19:16:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 19:16:55 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weight-loss drugs take over year of 2024: Bloomberg - Xinhua]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE0zUTR0dzQ5ZjZfWklna0pCVHZBa0hwTEJZTVI4dTJmSVk1aVRhUkl3d3NDQnd2N3MycXRaWlhxcVFHekxOMFVYX051N1RkSEhBamlpSS1qcW4zWTYtSmZnWnZtaldoRUNzRTBSRUNVTFo1OHRuMTMzbWFwMko?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE0zUTR0dzQ5ZjZfWklna0pCVHZBa0hwTEJZTVI4dTJmSVk1aVRhUkl3d3NDQnd2N3MycXRaWlhxcVFHekxOMFVYX051N1RkSEhBamlpSS1qcW4zWTYtSmZnWnZtaldoRUNzRTBSRUNVTFo1OHRuMTMzbWFwMko?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 18:26:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[COVID-19 infection not linked to changes in MS symptom severity - Medical Xpress]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>COVID-19 infection not linked to changes in MS symptom severity</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Neurology</p><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2024/covid-19-infection-not.jpg" alt="COVID-19 infection not linked to changes in MS symptom severity" width="800" height="530"><figcaption>COVID-19 infection not linked to changes in MS symptom severity</figcaption><p>COVID-19 infection is not associated with immediate changes in multiple sclerosis (MS) symptom severity or disability, according to a study published online.</p><ul><li>The study examined 796 participants with COVID-19 infections and 1,336 uninfected individuals.</li><li>Findings indicated that MS symptoms and disability did not significantly differ between cohorts.</li><li>The immediate effect of COVID-19 on MS symptom severity was minimal.</li></ul><blockquote>"These findings enhance our general understanding of the consequences of infection in people with MS and are reassuring regarding the impact of COVID-19 on the course of MS," the authors write.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the study reassures that COVID-19 does not significantly impact the symptoms or disability of patients with multiple sclerosis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2024-12-covid-infection-linked-ms-symptom.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medicalxpress.com/news/2024-12-covid-infection-linked-ms-symptom.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 17:50:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breakthrough sunscreen protects and cools your skin simultaneously: All you want to know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Breakthrough sunscreen protects and cools your skin simultaneously: All you want to know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This article discusses a new sunscreen innovation that provides protection while also cooling the skin. It highlights the unique properties and benefits of the product.</p><ul><li>The sunscreen offers enhanced protection against UV rays.</li><li>It incorporates cooling technology for comfort during wear.</li><li>The product aims to address common sunscreen complaints such as greasiness and irritation.</li></ul><blockquote>"This sunscreen not only shields your skin but also provides an instant cooling effect, making it perfect for hot days."</blockquote><p>This new sunscreen could revolutionize the way consumers approach sun protection, making it a more pleasant experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/breakthrough-sunscreen-protects-and-cools-your-skin-simultaneously-all-you-want-to-know/articleshow/116690056.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/breakthrough-sunscreen-protects-and-cools-your-skin-simultaneously-all-you-want-to-know/articleshow/116690056.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 17:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A global polio resurgence and the need to reevaluate the basics - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A Global Polio Resurgence and the Need to Reevaluate Our Approach</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 26, 2024 10:48 pm IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/nf1og4/article69030062.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/20241117076L.jpg" alt="Children show their ink-marked fingers after being administered with polio drops by healthcare workers as part of the Pulse Polio Program, at New Gardiner Road Hospital in New Delhi." width="100%" height="100%"></p><figcaption>Children show their ink-marked fingers after being administered with polio drops by healthcare workers as part of the Pulse Polio Program, at New Gardiner Road Hospital in New Delhi.</figcaption></p><p>The article discusses the recent resurgence of polio worldwide, emphasizing the critical need for vigilant vaccination and monitoring. The World Health Organization (WHO) has reported environmental samples of poliovirus detected in several European countries, indicating an ongoing risk.</p><ul><li>The resurgence includes cases in Pakistan, Cameroon, and Nigeria, with ongoing vaccine-derived poliovirus circulation.</li><li>WHO emphasizes the importance of vaccination to prevent paralysis and death from poliovirus.</li><li>A recent debate on the best vaccination approach—the replacement of the oral polio vaccine (OPV) with the inactivated polio vaccine (IPV)—is highlighted.</li><li>Research suggests respiratory transmission may play a more significant role than previously acknowledged.</li></ul><blockquote>“Vaccination of every vulnerable child is essential to ensure that the virus cannot lead to lifelong paralysis or even death.” - Robb Butler, Director, Communicable Diseases, Environment and Health at WHO/Europe.</blockquote><p>This global health challenge underscores the need for immediate action in vaccination strategies to safeguard future generations against polio.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/tamil-nadu/a-global-polio-resurgence-and-the-need-to-reevaluate-the-basics/article69026816.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/tamil-nadu/a-global-polio-resurgence-and-the-need-to-reevaluate-the-basics/article69026816.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 17:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Which infectious disease is likely to be biggest emerging problem in 2025? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Which infectious disease is likely to be biggest emerging problem in 2025?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: N/A</strong> | <strong>Source: Indian Express</strong></p><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="667" src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/bird-flu_200_tashi-tobgyal.jpg?resize=600,334" alt="bird flu"><figcaption>When influenza cases start increasing in animals such as birds, there is always a worry that it could jump to humans (Express Photo by Tashi Tobgyal)</figcaption><p>The article discusses concerns among public health officials regarding emerging infectious diseases, particularly as COVID-19 recedes. It highlights the potential threat posed by the H5N1 influenza virus and compares it with ongoing threats such as malaria, HIV, and tuberculosis.</p><ul><li>COVID-19 has raised awareness of the potential for new infectious diseases.</li><li>Malaria, HIV, and tuberculosis currently kill around 2 million people annually.</li><li>H5N1 bird flu is spreading among birds and recently infecting cattle in the US.</li><li>There has been a significant increase in human bird flu cases in 2023.</li><li>H5N1 has a high mortality rate in humans but does not currently spread between people.</li><li>A mutation could potentially enable human-to-human transmission of H5N1.</li><li>Governments are preparing for the possibility of a pandemic by acquiring vaccines and planning responses.</li></ul><blockquote>If this strain of bird flu makes that switch and can start transmitting between humans, governments must act quickly to control the spread.</blockquote><p>The article concludes that while H5N1 poses a potential threat, existing diseases must also be prioritized in public health initiatives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/which-infectious-disease-likely-biggest-emerging-problem-in-2025-9744863/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/which-infectious-disease-likely-biggest-emerging-problem-in-2025-9744863/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 17:00:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[COVID-19 Infection Not Linked to Changes in MS Symptom Severity - HealthDay]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>COVID-19 Infection Not Linked to Changes in MS Symptom Severity</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 26, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> HealthDay News</p><p>COVID-19 infection is not associated with immediate changes in multiple sclerosis (MS) symptom severity or disability, according to a study published online Dec. 23 in <em>Neurology</em>.</p><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='COVID-19 and MS study illustration'><figcaption>Illustration regarding the study of COVID-19's impact on MS symptoms.</figcaption><p>Key Points:</p><ul><li>The study examined the effects of COVID-19 on MS symptoms using the SymptoMScreen (SMSS).</li><li>Involved 796 COVID-19 infected participants and 1,336 uninfected participants.</li><li>Findings showed no significant difference in SMSS scores between the cohorts before or after COVID-19 infection.</li></ul><blockquote>"These findings enhance our general understanding of the consequences of infection in people with MS and are reassuring regarding the impact of COVID-19 on the course of MS," the authors write.</blockquote><p>Overall, the study provides reassurance that COVID-19 does not worsen MS symptom severity or lead to increased disability in affected individuals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthday.com/healthpro-news/neurology/covid-19-infection-not-linked-to-changes-in-ms-symptom-severity</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthday.com/healthpro-news/neurology/covid-19-infection-not-linked-to-changes-in-ms-symptom-severity</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 16:52:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atogepant Superior for Efficacy, Functional Measures in Migraine - HealthDay]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Atogepant Superior for Efficacy, Functional Measures in Migraine</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 26, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> HealthDay News</p><p>The recent study published in <em>Neurology</em> highlights that atogepant 60 mg once daily demonstrates greater efficacy and improved functional measures for adults suffering from migraine compared to placebo.</p><ul><li>Atogepant significantly reduced the number of migraine days in various studies.</li><li>Results showed better efficacy in trials ADVANCE, ELEVATE, and PROGRESS.</li><li>Published results indicate improved quality of life scores for patients using atogepant.</li><li>The study addresses an important need for effective preventive treatments in migraine management.</li></ul><blockquote>"The analyses reported here demonstrate the early efficacy and functional improvements of atogepant and address a key unmet need of providing preventive treatment options with early benefits across the spectrum of migraine disease state severity." - Richard B. Lipton, M.D.</blockquote><p>The findings underscore the potential of atogepant as a promising option for migraine sufferers, providing hope for earlier intervention and improved quality of life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthday.com/healthpro-news/pain-management/atogepant-superior-for-efficacy-functional-measures-in-migraine</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthday.com/healthpro-news/pain-management/atogepant-superior-for-efficacy-functional-measures-in-migraine</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 16:43:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nile rats and Black Death: Mummy reveals bubonic plague in Egypt 3,290 years ago - The Jerusalem Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nile rats and Black Death: Mummy reveals bubonic plague in Egypt 3,290 years ago</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Jerusalem Post</p>
<img src="https://images.jpost.com/image/upload/q_auto/c_fill,g_faces:center,h_537,w_822/640825" width="290" height="260" alt="Did Nile rats spread the Black Death? Infected mummy shows bubonic plague existed in Egypt 3,290 years ago. Illustration." title="Did Nile rats spread the Black Death? Infected mummy shows bubonic plague existed in Egypt 3,290 years ago. Illustration.">
<figcaption>Did Nile rats spread the Black Death? Infected mummy shows bubonic plague existed in Egypt 3,290 years ago. Illustration. (photo credit: Irene Groebner. Via Shutterstock)</figcaption>
<p>Researchers have uncovered the oldest confirmed case of the plague outside Eurasia in an ancient Egyptian mummy, suggesting that the deadly disease was present in North Africa thousands of years before the Black Death devastated Europe.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The mummy revealed traces of Yersinia pestis DNA.</li>
  <li>Radiocarbon dating places the mummy at approximately 3,290 years ago.</li>
  <li>Findings support the theory that bubonic plague circulated in North Africa long before the Middle Ages.</li>
  <li>Symptoms described in ancient texts correlate with plague characteristics.</li>
  <li>Studies indicate that Yersinia pestis existed globally thousands of years prior to known pandemics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The bubonic plague was responsible for the deaths of more than 20 million people in Europe alone.</blockquote>
<p>The presence of plague DNA in the mummy indicates that the individual suffered severe symptoms before death, raising questions about whether this was an isolated case or part of a broader epidemic.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jpost.com/archaeology/archaeology-around-the-world/article-834951</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jpost.com/archaeology/archaeology-around-the-world/article-834951</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 16:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 morning habits to get rid of stomach discomfort - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQeXY5QlJMdlQ5dmhtNHQyVDJHSW42TUphTjJFYWNWSklHQ2VIYkNRbWU1d2VZRWw5VTA1akNVanJJSUlEQnVGNExTblN6dnJjYXBSSWM4ZzZMaWZxazdhd3VhdmlmNThzb3IxRWdlMFZLOFg2cXJqTXZCYURLN0dndFljZ1A0aUVpeHhSZ084Y3B5NUk2cXpUNnRYZlp5MkFCa2F3Sld3dXdhUzlBWW1OU2VlQ0dFTkRodTVwOWRQUkxFLUJ5VXZGV1VQQm1fZmZ2eWctR3k3aTVzMVdZNWpwSUtn0gHiAUFVX3lxTFB5djlCUkx2VDl2aG00dDJUMkdJbjZNSmFOMkVhY1ZKSUdDZUhiQ1FtZTV3ZVlFbDlVMDVqQ1VqcklJSURCdUY0TFNuU3p2cmNhcFJJYzhnNkxpZnFrN2F3dWF2aWY1OHNvcjFFZ2UwVks4WDZxcmpNdkJhREs3R2d0WWNnUDRpRWl4eFJnTzhjcHk1STZxelQ2dFhmWnkyQUJrYXdKV3d1d2FTOUFZbU5TZWVDR0VORGh1NXA5ZFBSTEUtQnlVdkZXVVBCbV9mZnZ5Zy1HeTdpNXMxV1k1anBJS2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQeXY5QlJMdlQ5dmhtNHQyVDJHSW42TUphTjJFYWNWSklHQ2VIYkNRbWU1d2VZRWw5VTA1akNVanJJSUlEQnVGNExTblN6dnJjYXBSSWM4ZzZMaWZxazdhd3VhdmlmNThzb3IxRWdlMFZLOFg2cXJqTXZCYURLN0dndFljZ1A0aUVpeHhSZ084Y3B5NUk2cXpUNnRYZlp5MkFCa2F3Sld3dXdhUzlBWW1OU2VlQ0dFTkRodTVwOWRQUkxFLUJ5VXZGV1VQQm1fZmZ2eWctR3k3aTVzMVdZNWpwSUtn0gHiAUFVX3lxTFB5djlCUkx2VDl2aG00dDJUMkdJbjZNSmFOMkVhY1ZKSUdDZUhiQ1FtZTV3ZVlFbDlVMDVqQ1VqcklJSURCdUY0TFNuU3p2cmNhcFJJYzhnNkxpZnFrN2F3dWF2aWY1OHNvcjFFZ2UwVks4WDZxcmpNdkJhREs3R2d0WWNnUDRpRWl4eFJnTzhjcHk1STZxelQ2dFhmWnkyQUJrYXdKV3d1d2FTOUFZbU5TZWVDR0VORGh1NXA5ZFBSTEUtQnlVdkZXVVBCbV9mZnZ5Zy1HeTdpNXMxV1k1anBJS2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Correlation of Dental and Periodontal Status With HIV Presence and Initial CD4 Counts: An Albanian Prospective Observational Study - Cureus]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgJBVV95cUxONVpHQWUxV2h5bkdIQmZDamozQ0h4Q3dVTE9aSGFRYmNYLWJIZURtR2tvdk5NbjNzUTctQTJjeWZjUEQzWVdVODFBQkJ1RnV2SnRfZjhSM0pEcWdpNEVOUDV2b3JMck5WTGpMNzdhenRRQjI5T0MtellTMXY3NDNyVDR1bDJrTEdaWnByMVFiWVpCSDFDbjJ5bURzNFlURjMtQ3pEQXVFUGtyZ0RzakRtLW9SYXMwc09kQklUU1FZYXpRQ1dJeU03RE5UMzcyem9WbnRucW1rSlZOZVRrd1B2cHlMVHc4U3h6cGlKLTNhTF82bmJSdFNCdmR5bEpZdEJsVGdwakdNVXgtTWJWMVVSb3hjdi1CZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgJBVV95cUxONVpHQWUxV2h5bkdIQmZDamozQ0h4Q3dVTE9aSGFRYmNYLWJIZURtR2tvdk5NbjNzUTctQTJjeWZjUEQzWVdVODFBQkJ1RnV2SnRfZjhSM0pEcWdpNEVOUDV2b3JMck5WTGpMNzdhenRRQjI5T0MtellTMXY3NDNyVDR1bDJrTEdaWnByMVFiWVpCSDFDbjJ5bURzNFlURjMtQ3pEQXVFUGtyZ0RzakRtLW9SYXMwc09kQklUU1FZYXpRQ1dJeU03RE5UMzcyem9WbnRucW1rSlZOZVRrd1B2cHlMVHc4U3h6cGlKLTNhTF82bmJSdFNCdmR5bEpZdEJsVGdwakdNVXgtTWJWMVVSb3hjdi1CZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 16:23:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Laser Patterning Technology Revolutionizes Stent Surgery for Cardiovascular Diseases - HospiMedica]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAJBVV95cUxON1lsS0E1d0RLOFhNdTBYZFdPbUJGb25STWk0dFc1bHhxZUpsejNVRG0yOTVWd0JaRk9VSWxkck5wQ0ZNVzBXdUFIbzJsUWpNU2hReHdVQlRscDZZMU1EQnJ4czFyV0pQWDdqLTV3S0w2blQ1c3U4UW9FNHpCRHpnQVRHV3I5cTJ4Q3phdjRsLTU0VDZJeDVyQ19YT3lEeHZIblB1V1dBY3dIT3BSYXlkQ2JhRUhIZlI3alhQQ0VmNXI0Vm9fVFc5VnFzczBia2NyV1RtMW9lZlZ2WFQwNWZzNVhFWWptRlBNd1hGZjVwem5MVHE2YXV3Y2ZtejZWOHJ2Y2M0WFNKQjY1MnpGNTEwRm55TFh5VFpiTGZBUk4wLXJHbUNYV3JzUk9Ka1NzdUd3RHU0QTg3b1dnbW82NjFySEYyd3nSAfYBQVVfeXFMUEpPNWZubFRaNTRTNGNfNnQ0eXViVlMyVFpHcF84TDVyVDBDUV9hVVotUDI5V2Q2eFRXampNU2xpZEZ3SWVpUDFKQ2s1TzZMME9XZVJxZlE5QWVaSUhpdU53dkRxcndDWGhMLWUxcm1Pc0lha1pYMjJaUzRJbkV2SXZoWVhXVmF0aVBpTWMzQ0ptdUdydlY4N1NQV2h1Nm1UcmZubWItNTRNcDQtdk5DbnNPRGVWVlBiZ3JtWHFFYjJSMld5czRFUWM3aUVjYThxVzBjTDBOdEFIU2xMdTlqT3dSUm16bWpFdzZURkhYQnFnWUtDVmhR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAJBVV95cUxON1lsS0E1d0RLOFhNdTBYZFdPbUJGb25STWk0dFc1bHhxZUpsejNVRG0yOTVWd0JaRk9VSWxkck5wQ0ZNVzBXdUFIbzJsUWpNU2hReHdVQlRscDZZMU1EQnJ4czFyV0pQWDdqLTV3S0w2blQ1c3U4UW9FNHpCRHpnQVRHV3I5cTJ4Q3phdjRsLTU0VDZJeDVyQ19YT3lEeHZIblB1V1dBY3dIT3BSYXlkQ2JhRUhIZlI3alhQQ0VmNXI0Vm9fVFc5VnFzczBia2NyV1RtMW9lZlZ2WFQwNWZzNVhFWWptRlBNd1hGZjVwem5MVHE2YXV3Y2ZtejZWOHJ2Y2M0WFNKQjY1MnpGNTEwRm55TFh5VFpiTGZBUk4wLXJHbUNYV3JzUk9Ka1NzdUd3RHU0QTg3b1dnbW82NjFySEYyd3nSAfYBQVVfeXFMUEpPNWZubFRaNTRTNGNfNnQ0eXViVlMyVFpHcF84TDVyVDBDUV9hVVotUDI5V2Q2eFRXampNU2xpZEZ3SWVpUDFKQ2s1TzZMME9XZVJxZlE5QWVaSUhpdU53dkRxcndDWGhMLWUxcm1Pc0lha1pYMjJaUzRJbkV2SXZoWVhXVmF0aVBpTWMzQ0ptdUdydlY4N1NQV2h1Nm1UcmZubWItNTRNcDQtdk5DbnNPRGVWVlBiZ3JtWHFFYjJSMld5czRFUWM3aUVjYThxVzBjTDBOdEFIU2xMdTlqT3dSUm16bWpFdzZURkhYQnFnWUtDVmhR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 16:21:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Health Resolutions You Must Make For 2025 - NDTV Doctor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNdWdsQ1k0MC1HR3FMbUcxM1pnMWtFR1JHODYzUXliajFSYmF3cVloZTNIelVsWmliUllmdnpZN0FIRXRHbVpMSE9icWVBVEZlNUNhS2pkMUt1WVp5dnBpMkM1SzVjcjZrdjRObFlrLTM5VXcteVV0WmdWVGp6bjFWcmF1YWQtLWNNazItaWRwZ1hHdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNdWdsQ1k0MC1HR3FMbUcxM1pnMWtFR1JHODYzUXliajFSYmF3cVloZTNIelVsWmliUllmdnpZN0FIRXRHbVpMSE9icWVBVEZlNUNhS2pkMUt1WVp5dnBpMkM1SzVjcjZrdjRObFlrLTM5VXcteVV0WmdWVGp6bjFWcmF1YWQtLWNNazItaWRwZ1hHdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 16:03:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is now called MASLD - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD) is Now Called MASLD</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/belly-fat_1600_getty.jpg" alt="belly fat"><figcaption>It is essential to reduce belly fat (Source: Getty Images/Thinkstock)</figcaption><p>This article explains the rebranding of Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD) to Metabolic Dysfunction-Associated Steatotic Liver Disease (MASLD) and highlights its implications for diagnosis and treatment.</p><ul><li>The term MASLD emphasizes the metabolic dysfunction as the primary cause of liver disease.</li><li>About 25% of people globally are affected by MASLD, with rates rising significantly in those with type 2 diabetes or obesity.</li><li>Non-invasive diagnostic methods such as FibroScan and MRI are increasing diagnostic accuracy.</li><li>Focus on early diagnosis can lead to preventative measures and treatment interventions.</li></ul><blockquote>“These interventions can help lower the long-term risks of heart disease, liver failure, and cirrhosis.” - Dr. Sameer Bhati</blockquote><p>This change in terminology indicates a shift towards a patient-centered approach in dealing with liver health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/liver-health-what-is-masld-not-nafld-terms-difference-bias-experts-9741719/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/liver-health-what-is-masld-not-nafld-terms-difference-bias-experts-9741719/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 16:00:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uncertain significance and molecular insights of CPLANE1 variants in prenatal diagnosis of Joubert syndrome: a case report - BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxOcl9DNE8yUm0wMy1RNHJZaUl3blFwdkczeHpwOUFIdzJmNF9QZy1tM2ZSSFpmVlZUQkNGTE1PeC1iTWVZdnV4N0k2ZUhzSlRTUnp3SDJlem12ZTVfc2FCellZUXpLTUJJLXR0MVlZX2k5LVVRTEtPXzZISzdfeGJrVmFEV01fbDBMYldFcg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxOcl9DNE8yUm0wMy1RNHJZaUl3blFwdkczeHpwOUFIdzJmNF9QZy1tM2ZSSFpmVlZUQkNGTE1PeC1iTWVZdnV4N0k2ZUhzSlRTUnp3SDJlem12ZTVfc2FCellZUXpLTUJJLXR0MVlZX2k5LVVRTEtPXzZISzdfeGJrVmFEV01fbDBMYldFcg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 15:41:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foods that keep you warm in the winters - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Foods That Keep You Warm in the Winters</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><p>As winter approaches, certain foods can help keep your body warm and cozy during the colder months.</p><ul><li>Warm beverages like herbal teas and hot cocoa are comforting and hydrating.</li><li>Hearty soups made with seasonal vegetables provide nourishment and warmth.</li><li>Spices such as ginger, cinnamon, and chili pepper can boost metabolism and create a warming effect.</li><li>Complex carbohydrates, like whole grains, help sustain energy levels in colder weather.</li><li>Including healthy fats from nuts and avocados can also aid in keeping warm.</li></ul><blockquote>“Eating warm and hearty meals is essential for comfort during the winter.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, incorporating warming foods into your diet can enhance your comfort and well-being as temperatures drop.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/foods-that-keep-you-warm-in-the-winters/articleshow/116674133.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/foods-that-keep-you-warm-in-the-winters/articleshow/116674133.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 15:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Whooping Cough Cases Soaring In The US Showing No Signs Of Slowing Down: CDC Warns - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Whooping Cough Cases Soaring In The US Showing No Signs Of Slowing Down: CDC Warns</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>October 2023<br><strong>Source: </strong>The Health Site</p><figure><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/whooping-cough-cases-US-1.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="Whooping Cough Cases Soaring In The US, Showing No Signs Of Slowing Down: CDC Warns" width="900" height="375"><figcaption>If you suspect you or your child has a whooping cough, consult a healthcare professional for proper diagnosis and treatment immediately! (Photo: Freepik)</figcaption></figure><p>Whooping cough, also known as pertussis, is on the rise in the US, with cases reported to be six times higher than last year. This poses a significant threat, particularly to children, and highlights the need for strict health measures.</p><ul><li>Over 32,000 cases reported this year.</li><li>Symptoms start mild but can lead to severe coughing fits.</li><li>Highly contagious; spread through respiratory droplets.</li><li>Infants under one year are especially vulnerable.</li><li>Vaccination is the best prevention method.</li></ul><blockquote>“Vaccination rates among US children have fallen, increasing vulnerability to outbreaks.”</blockquote><p>Health authorities stress the importance of vaccination and seeking prompt treatment to combat this rising threat.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/whooping-cough-cases-soaring-in-the-us-showing-no-signs-of-slowing-down-cdc-warns-1167044/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/whooping-cough-cases-soaring-in-the-us-showing-no-signs-of-slowing-down-cdc-warns-1167044/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 15:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delayed-Onset White Matter Lesions on Brain MRI in Recurrent Non-cerebral Plasmodium falciparum Imported Malaria Without Neurological Symptoms - Cureus]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwJBVV95cUxObWJuQW5GRUFUdmk3WTlHOFRQMXozT2tQYWRjeVYyVFNvN0QxRjIzZHNCTl9FckdocFRoWUpQbU13b3lUUEd2RWNBRDJtOWVRQ3FNV2FFZW52TTFvY2hMeUxYNFNxamtGX0poVE1uMnU2QXRUenM0QXI3UGhvcHpFZHhlUWZTZ1BjdlNCb1FzcFpyOFFBRGZaTUl2cWc4LXVlNnNQako2MS1VYTlTT3JvdFl4a2RQLTNtZExReFZNVmNGSFJmVlBrMmN2Y0xCZHFoOGR4TDhlckFZMUFTSFJOaHhpWGRsckdfdEFtLTNnODlsUmdLb2pRX3Vab0V3UkRoQ3ZUdDhRQmMxSVFfN2gwVF9xU2RjZkZ6ZXA5TjI4cFotbF9WMTk4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwJBVV95cUxObWJuQW5GRUFUdmk3WTlHOFRQMXozT2tQYWRjeVYyVFNvN0QxRjIzZHNCTl9FckdocFRoWUpQbU13b3lUUEd2RWNBRDJtOWVRQ3FNV2FFZW52TTFvY2hMeUxYNFNxamtGX0poVE1uMnU2QXRUenM0QXI3UGhvcHpFZHhlUWZTZ1BjdlNCb1FzcFpyOFFBRGZaTUl2cWc4LXVlNnNQako2MS1VYTlTT3JvdFl4a2RQLTNtZExReFZNVmNGSFJmVlBrMmN2Y0xCZHFoOGR4TDhlckFZMUFTSFJOaHhpWGRsckdfdEFtLTNnODlsUmdLb2pRX3Vab0V3UkRoQ3ZUdDhRQmMxSVFfN2gwVF9xU2RjZkZ6ZXA5TjI4cFotbF9WMTk4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 14:48:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another pandemic in the making as America loses control of Bird Flu; who is to blame? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/another-pandemic-in-the-making-as-america-loses-control-of-bird-flu-who-is-to-blame/articleshow/116687816.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/another-pandemic-in-the-making-as-america-loses-control-of-bird-flu-who-is-to-blame/articleshow/116687816.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 14:47:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Whooping cough cases in the US hit the highest in a decade - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Whooping cough cases in the US hit the highest in a decade</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Health News</p><p>The United States has recorded the highest cases of whooping cough in ten years, prompting health officials to urge vaccination.</p><ul><li>Cases have surged due to decreased vaccination rates.</li><li>Public health campaigns are being intensified to encourage immunization.</li><li>Infants and young children are particularly vulnerable to the disease.</li></ul><blockquote>"Vaccination is key to preventing outbreaks and protecting our children," said Dr. Smith, a pediatric infectious disease specialist.</blockquote><p>Health officials stress the importance of maintaining high vaccination coverage to prevent future outbreaks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/whooping-cough-cases-in-the-us-hit-the-highest-in-a-decade/articleshow/116687664.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/whooping-cough-cases-in-the-us-hit-the-highest-in-a-decade/articleshow/116687664.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 14:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red meat and Diabetes: Should we rethink our plate? - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Red meat and Diabetes: Should we rethink our plate?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Lancet</p><div><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/12/Red-Meat-NYC-Reuters-2024-12-601860b36319a738951e21b21101b598.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Red meat and Diabetes: Should we rethink our plate?" title="Red meat and Diabetes: Should we rethink our plate?"><figcaption>Prices are seen on a selection of red meat in Manhattan, New York City, US, March 29, 2022. File Image/Reuters</figcaption></div><p>A groundbreaking study has revealed a concerning connection between red meat consumption and type 2 diabetes, a condition impacting over 462 million people worldwide. This research indicates that both unprocessed and processed red meat intake raises the risk of diabetes significantly across different populations.</p><ul><li>The study included nearly 2 million participants from 20 countries.</li><li>A high intake of unprocessed red meat (e.g., beef, lamb, pork) and processed meat (e.g., bacon, salami) linked to increased diabetes incidence.</li><li>The research observed a weaker link between poultry consumption and diabetes risk.</li><li>Type 2 diabetes is a severe public health issue with high long-term health implications.</li></ul><blockquote>“Red meat has high levels of saturated fat and can disrupt insulin sensitivity.”</blockquote><p>Given these findings, a reduction in red meat consumption is advised, particularly in light of current dietary recommendations that suggest limiting daily intake to about 70g.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/health/red-meat-and-diabetes-should-we-rethink-our-plate-13847804.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/health/red-meat-and-diabetes-should-we-rethink-our-plate-13847804.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 14:35:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New AI Tool Identifies Diabetes Using Voice Analysis - MPO-mag]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNM1cyRGZmRE1IYnJEZlh4VVpVR1E4N0E3bWJxaUFENUN4Rk9oTHBpcnRTdEVYVi1ERTZhVy0yWDlQTm56QTRJV1hEaDVCbW1KVHM4dkViOEJZZUpFYlByeUQ5dmdTdzRyVzU3aHZlTHp3R21VVXJ6clFQSlJWVjdlX2dvNEk5aVBKajhaRGw3MDk3alJ5ZUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNM1cyRGZmRE1IYnJEZlh4VVpVR1E4N0E3bWJxaUFENUN4Rk9oTHBpcnRTdEVYVi1ERTZhVy0yWDlQTm56QTRJV1hEaDVCbW1KVHM4dkViOEJZZUpFYlByeUQ5dmdTdzRyVzU3aHZlTHp3R21VVXJ6clFQSlJWVjdlX2dvNEk5aVBKajhaRGw3MDk3alJ5ZUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 14:33:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NHS to Trial Groundbreaking AI Tool to Predict Type 2 Diabetes Risk Years in Advance - Elets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxQWDhpaVNsNVA1MmpWaE9sQTcwNElmdW1SMnlMM0FjcHBTX2lYaVlqNHdNYW5WQUNFT3p4aEZheUMwcmJZMElwSVNCbklWN20wZFhTMjV0c1lmUWZmMmhNR0JLTnJtWjFDWk9jMGV6TENCVk5UcXdaclItS05EWjhiVWEtanhyaS1DcEFrX2pZNUpNbzZtNUJEWEE1U1pfLTZpZzJZSHVBV1FyS3ZwdUk3b0lyaGNaYXdKVHdSbTh0R0pXY00?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxQWDhpaVNsNVA1MmpWaE9sQTcwNElmdW1SMnlMM0FjcHBTX2lYaVlqNHdNYW5WQUNFT3p4aEZheUMwcmJZMElwSVNCbklWN20wZFhTMjV0c1lmUWZmMmhNR0JLTnJtWjFDWk9jMGV6TENCVk5UcXdaclItS05EWjhiVWEtanhyaS1DcEFrX2pZNUpNbzZtNUJEWEE1U1pfLTZpZzJZSHVBV1FyS3ZwdUk3b0lyaGNaYXdKVHdSbTh0R0pXY00?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 14:07:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Expect more pandemics to sweep the globe in the coming decades - Livescience.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Expect More Pandemics to Sweep the Globe in the Coming Decades</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Life Science</p>
<p>Pandemics, the global spread of infectious diseases, are expected to increase in frequency. Historical pandemics like the Black Death and Spanish flu highlight the severity that past outbreaks have had on humanity. Recent events, including COVID-19, illustrate that the threat is very much active, and understanding the underlying causes may help avert future outbreaks.</p>
<h2>Key Points</h2>
<ul>
<li>Increased opportunities for pandemics arise due to the disruption of ecosystems.</li>
<li>Climate change and biodiversity loss contribute to the emergence of new diseases.</li>
<li>Historical pandemics demonstrate the impact of infectious diseases on global populations.</li>
<li>The increase in human-wildlife contact can lead to transferring diseases from wildlife to humans.</li>
<li>A planetary health approach is necessary to address the root causes of pandemics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Until we effectively address the unsustainable impact we are having on our planet, pandemics will continue to occur."</blockquote>
<p>Overall, proactive measures addressing climate change and protecting biodiversity are crucial to mitigate the risk of future pandemics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livescience.com/health/viruses-infections-disease/expect-more-pandemics-to-sweep-the-globe-in-the-coming-decades</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livescience.com/health/viruses-infections-disease/expect-more-pandemics-to-sweep-the-globe-in-the-coming-decades</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 energy-rich foods to fuel your day - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Energy-Rich Foods to Fuel Your Day</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 26, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>DNA</p>
<img src="https://images1.dnaindia.com/images/DNA-EN/900x1600/2024/12/26/1735189828797_muesli486832960720.jpg" alt="6 energy-rich foods to fuel your day">
<figcaption>Image source: DNA</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses six foods that can help maintain energy levels throughout the day, emphasizing their nutritional benefits.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Fresh Foods:</strong> Essential nutrients support health and energy.</li>
  <li><strong>Bananas:</strong> Great source of natural sugars, potassium, and fiber.</li>
  <li><strong>Oats:</strong> Rich in fiber and complex carbohydrates for slow energy release.</li>
  <li><strong>Lean Protein:</strong> Helps repair muscles and maintain stable blood sugar.</li>
  <li><strong>Nuts and Seeds:</strong> High in fiber, protein, and healthy fats for sustained energy.</li>
  <li><strong>Water:</strong> Vital for nutrient absorption and metabolism.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>This information is not DNA's opinion but obtained from media reports.</blockquote>
<p>Incorporating these energy-rich foods into your diet can significantly enhance your daily energy levels and overall well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/lifestyle/6-energy-rich-foods-to-fuel-your-day-1735189592086</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/lifestyle/6-energy-rich-foods-to-fuel-your-day-1735189592086</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 13:53:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Infosys-backed Bengaluru Startup is Beating Cancer with Genomics & AI - AIM]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This Infosys-backed Bengaluru Startup is Beating Cancer with Genomics & AI</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>AIM</p><figure><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdblLasOMdnMeMrtEpika-iyuDnsjVc6lyqPAPdA2n0fzz9Sb1A3jWgX62KyhlS_rJby_qT3rEnNx2vTZDoxTgJ-mQbvKYO3_pmpBaFZUQ0kbfoAxIAhrODLxzuwQPrWPnQQi3eDw?key=ZzApHvgdHkm3JGhDcNg1Mv3N" alt=""><figcaption>Analysis of Gene Fusions across functional categories and cancer types using 4baseCare’s study. Source: 4baseCare</figcaption></figure><p>This article discusses how 4baseCare, a Bengaluru-based oncology precision startup, is transforming cancer treatment in India through genomics and AI. The company recently received significant investment from Infosys Innovation Fund, enabling it to adopt advanced techniques for targeted cancer therapies.</p><ul><li>4baseCare was founded in 2018 by Hitesh Goswami and Kshitij Rishi.</li><li>The startup has received close to $1 million investment from Infosys Innovation Fund.</li><li>Genome testing for oncology in India has rapidly increased, growing from 5,000-6,000 tests in 2019 to approximately 2 lakh tests now.</li><li>There are challenges in precision oncology in India, including awareness among oncologists and availability of effective drugs.</li><li>4baseCare is leveraging AI for data interpretation and has developed a clinical genomic digital twin model for personalized treatment.</li></ul><blockquote>“The whole team, right from the logistics team who picks up a sample, I tell them, ‘Guys, you have no idea which sample you might pick up, and that will change the whole family’s life.'” - Hitesh Goswami</blockquote><p>The work being done by 4baseCare reflects a significant step toward personalized cancer treatment in India, despite existing challenges and obstacles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://analyticsindiamag.com/ai-startups/this-infosys-backed-bengaluru-startup-is-beating-cancer-with-genomics-ai/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://analyticsindiamag.com/ai-startups/this-infosys-backed-bengaluru-startup-is-beating-cancer-with-genomics-ai/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 13:36:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Male infertility: Simple lifestyle hacks, diet plan to supercharge your sperm health - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Male Infertility: Simple Lifestyle Hacks and Diet Plan to Boost Sperm Health</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 26, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/26/550x309/male_infertility_1735212987931_1735213079796.jpeg" alt="Male fertility is declining worldwide—Here's what you can do about it now.(Photo by Pexels)" title="Male fertility is declining worldwide—Here's what you can do about it now.(Photo by Pexels)">
<figcaption>Male fertility is declining worldwide—Here's what you can do about it now.(Photo by Pexels)</figcaption>
<p>Nearly 1 in 7 couples struggle with infertility, often due to male factors. This article explores the declining trend of male fertility and offers lifestyle and dietary recommendations to improve sperm health.</p>
<ul>
<li>Male fertility is crucial for conception, with lifestyle, diet, and health impacting sperm quality.</li>
<li>Key sperm health indicators include quantity, movement (motility), and structure (morphology).</li>
<li>Obesity, smoking, and certain medications can negatively affect sperm quality.</li>
<li>Healthy lifestyle changes can significantly enhance fertility outcomes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Boosting male fertility requires a holistic approach...” - Dr. Sabia Mangat</blockquote>
<p>Improving male fertility is essential for families trying to conceive, and understanding sperm health can guide men towards better reproductive outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/male-infertility-simple-lifestyle-hacks-diet-plan-to-supercharge-your-sperm-health-101735211330572.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/male-infertility-simple-lifestyle-hacks-diet-plan-to-supercharge-your-sperm-health-101735211330572.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 13:34:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 countries with most cancer rates, see where India stands - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxOUUZHVnF4bUtCc0pJOUdURlAwMGw3dmZBSXExczlWaGVlR3RtLXF4Mlk4TTlBYTBXSHpMbEFUbGJaR05yQ2pNaGNiN3VpdHc5Um5VV01UQTd4OV81UGVEZWtGOENqazI1ejlTT2xaM0pnQ1dZa2EzZEhhdWpHOGM1V2pCUnJwbUlCWTNwWnVFdkM0ZmZlUUlxWGJCWVduUVNTLUtZY1RpSUdJZ0VPb0hfSVJ4OHB4MW1peFl2SXZtQlJvX1doMGdITXd0bUZrbld4U2tIdjV2VnY4VFdjbGdFT2FwWmlIVFlfdDRPT01R0gHuAUFVX3lxTE5RRkdWcXhtS0JzSkk5R1RGUDAwbDd2ZkFJcTFzOVZoZWVHdG0tcXgyWThNOUFhMFdIekxsQVRsYlpHTnJDak1oY2I3dWl0dzlSblVXTVRBN3g5XzVQZURla0Y4Q2prMjV6OVNPbFozSmdDV1lrYTNkSGF1akc4YzVXakJScnBtSUJZM3BadUV2QzRmZmVRSXFYYkJZV25RU1MtS1ljVGlJR0lnRU9vSF9JUng4cHgxbWl4WXZJdm1CUm9fV2gwZ0hNd3RtRmtuV3hTa0h2NXZWdjhUV2NsZ0VPYXBaaUhUWV90NE9PTVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxOUUZHVnF4bUtCc0pJOUdURlAwMGw3dmZBSXExczlWaGVlR3RtLXF4Mlk4TTlBYTBXSHpMbEFUbGJaR05yQ2pNaGNiN3VpdHc5Um5VV01UQTd4OV81UGVEZWtGOENqazI1ejlTT2xaM0pnQ1dZa2EzZEhhdWpHOGM1V2pCUnJwbUlCWTNwWnVFdkM0ZmZlUUlxWGJCWVduUVNTLUtZY1RpSUdJZ0VPb0hfSVJ4OHB4MW1peFl2SXZtQlJvX1doMGdITXd0bUZrbld4U2tIdjV2VnY4VFdjbGdFT2FwWmlIVFlfdDRPT01R0gHuAUFVX3lxTE5RRkdWcXhtS0JzSkk5R1RGUDAwbDd2ZkFJcTFzOVZoZWVHdG0tcXgyWThNOUFhMFdIekxsQVRsYlpHTnJDak1oY2I3dWl0dzlSblVXTVRBN3g5XzVQZURla0Y4Q2prMjV6OVNPbFozSmdDV1lrYTNkSGF1akc4YzVXakJScnBtSUJZM3BadUV2QzRmZmVRSXFYYkJZV25RU1MtS1ljVGlJR0lnRU9vSF9JUng4cHgxbWl4WXZJdm1CUm9fV2gwZ0hNd3RtRmtuV3hTa0h2NXZWdjhUV2NsZ0VPYXBaaUhUWV90NE9PTVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The ideal breakfast for diabetics to combat blood sugar spikes - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Ideal Breakfast for Diabetics to Combat Blood Sugar Spikes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/900x1600/breakfast2839_1735139475911_1735139485537.jpg" alt="Ideal Breakfast" /><figcaption>Delicious breakfast options for diabetics.</figcaption><p>This article explores the best breakfast foods to help diabetics maintain stable blood sugar levels and boost energy throughout the day.</p><ul><li>Fiber-rich meals with rolled oats, whole grains, and raw fruits.</li><li>Healthy fats from avocado, nuts, and seeds to balance meals.</li><li>High-quality protein sources like eggs, tofu, or Greek yogurt.</li><li>Low glycemic index fruits such as berries and apples.</li><li>Staying hydrated with detox water for better health.</li><li>Mindful eating practices with smaller portion sizes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Fiber slows carb absorption and keeps sugar levels steady.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, incorporating these dietary strategies can help diabetics enjoy a nutritious breakfast while effectively managing their blood sugar levels.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/lifestyle/the-ideal-breakfast-for-diabetics-to-combat-blood-sugar-spikes-101735138637614.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/lifestyle/the-ideal-breakfast-for-diabetics-to-combat-blood-sugar-spikes-101735138637614.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 13:00:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winter Causing Surge in Heart Conditions? Cardiologist Provides Eye-Opening Insights, Suggests 5 Preventive Tips - HerZindagi English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Winter Causing Surge in Heart Conditions? Cardiologist Provides Eye-Opening Insights, Suggests 5 Preventive Tips</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> HerZindagi</p><p>As winter approaches, concerns rise regarding the increased incidence of heart conditions. This article discusses the recent tragic deaths of prominent figures and highlights expert insights on the implications of cold weather on heart health, along with preventive measures to mitigate risks.</p><ul><li>Winter sees a reported 53% rise in heart attack risks compared to other seasons.</li><li>Cold weather causes blood vessels to constrict, increasing blood pressure and heart strain.</li><li>Respiratory infections common in winter can exacerbate heart conditions.</li><li>Cholesterol levels may worsen in winter, impacting heart health.</li><li>Individuals with pre-existing conditions, the elderly, and smokers are at higher risk.</li></ul><h2>5 Preventive Tips</h2><ol><li><strong>Dietary Habits:</strong> Focus on seasonal superfoods and avoid unhealthy options.</li><li><strong>Regular Exercise:</strong> Engage in indoor workouts and maintain warm-up routines.</li><li><strong>Stay Hydrated:</strong> Drink enough water to support circulation.</li><li><strong>Lifestyle Changes:</strong> Dress warmly and manage stress.</li><li><strong>Health Checkups:</strong> Regular checkups and monitoring of cholesterol are essential.</li></ol><blockquote>“Recognizing early warning signs of a heart attack—such as chest pain, shortness of breath, excessive sweating, and fatigue—is critical for timely medical intervention.” – Dr. Anjan Siotia</blockquote><p>This article emphasizes the importance of proactive measures for maintaining heart health during the winter months.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.herzindagi.com/health/can-winter-lead-to-surge-in-heart-conditions-cardiologist-provides-insights-suggests-preventive-tips-article-1012763</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.herzindagi.com/health/can-winter-lead-to-surge-in-heart-conditions-cardiologist-provides-insights-suggests-preventive-tips-article-1012763</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sound advice: 9 tips to prevent hearing loss - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxPcHhmQzJKOThKQ3VrSHgwem8wanJfeGo4cWZtaFlXYWR1WjROV3hCeEJ4ZU40RlFqT2NGcGprUFpYdmI3bjc3Um8xVnptQ1Rkc1FPRHhvUkc3amRCSGVJNFZoMEd0aFZoZmlPcFRnWGZSdzJVQk12VUMzdWExeTdGRXh2MmstN2VfSG5iVkJ0VlBaNk1vRm84MXhvRjFXVGNpWlBzStIBpAFBVV95cUxPcHhmQzJKOThKQ3VrSHgwem8wanJfeGo4cWZtaFlXYWR1WjROV3hCeEJ4ZU40RlFqT2NGcGprUFpYdmI3bjc3Um8xVnptQ1Rkc1FPRHhvUkc3amRCSGVJNFZoMEd0aFZoZmlPcFRnWGZSdzJVQk12VUMzdWExeTdGRXh2MmstN2VfSG5iVkJ0VlBaNk1vRm84MXhvRjFXVGNpWlBzSg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxPcHhmQzJKOThKQ3VrSHgwem8wanJfeGo4cWZtaFlXYWR1WjROV3hCeEJ4ZU40RlFqT2NGcGprUFpYdmI3bjc3Um8xVnptQ1Rkc1FPRHhvUkc3amRCSGVJNFZoMEd0aFZoZmlPcFRnWGZSdzJVQk12VUMzdWExeTdGRXh2MmstN2VfSG5iVkJ0VlBaNk1vRm84MXhvRjFXVGNpWlBzStIBpAFBVV95cUxPcHhmQzJKOThKQ3VrSHgwem8wanJfeGo4cWZtaFlXYWR1WjROV3hCeEJ4ZU40RlFqT2NGcGprUFpYdmI3bjc3Um8xVnptQ1Rkc1FPRHhvUkc3amRCSGVJNFZoMEd0aFZoZmlPcFRnWGZSdzJVQk12VUMzdWExeTdGRXh2MmstN2VfSG5iVkJ0VlBaNk1vRm84MXhvRjFXVGNpWlBzSg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 12:56:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>