<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:22:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:22:53 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tips To Protect Your Heart Health During Smog Season - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tips To Protect Your Heart Health During Smog Season</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="While stepping outside, ensure you wear a mask to cover the nose and mouth.(Representative/File Photo)"><figcaption>While stepping outside, ensure you wear a mask to cover the nose and mouth.(Representative/File Photo)</figcaption><p>The cold weather and increased pollution levels during smog season can significantly impact heart health. It is vital to adopt measures to protect the heart as polluted air can lead to serious cardiovascular issues.</p><ul><li>Limit outdoor activities during high pollution days.</li><li>Wear a mask to filter out harmful particles.</li><li>Stay hydrated to lessen the impact of pollution.</li><li>Regularly monitor blood pressure and heart stress symptoms.</li><li>Have routine health checkups and cardiac screenings.</li><li>Maintain a heart-healthy diet rich in antioxidants.</li><li>Engage in regular, moderate exercise.</li><li>Use air purifiers to improve indoor air quality.</li><li>Track local air quality index for informed outdoor activity.</li></ul><blockquote>“Recognize the signs of dehydration and take necessary steps to maintain water balance, reducing strain on the heart.”</blockquote><p>By following these tips, individuals can better safeguard their heart health during the challenging smog season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/tips-to-protect-your-heart-health-during-smog-season-9124342.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/tips-to-protect-your-heart-health-during-smog-season-9124342.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 16:50:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unexpected colon cancer warning: This change in stool thickness could signal trouble - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unexpected Colon Cancer Warning: Change in Stool Thickness</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown, <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>Recent findings suggest that a change in stool thickness may indicate a potential risk of colon cancer, urging individuals to be vigilant about their digestive health.</p><ul><li>Researchers highlight that a sudden change in stool thickness could be a warning sign.</li><li>Doctors advise monitoring digestive health closely.</li><li>The importance of early detection and seeking medical advice for changes in bowel habits.</li></ul><blockquote>“Awareness of these changes can lead to early diagnosis and better outcomes,” health experts suggest.</blockquote><p>Monitoring your digestive health can be crucial. If you notice any sudden changes, consult with a healthcare provider promptly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/unexpected-colon-cancer-warning-this-change-in-stool-thickness-could-signal-trouble/articleshow/116375941.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/unexpected-colon-cancer-warning-this-change-in-stool-thickness-could-signal-trouble/articleshow/116375941.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 16:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Column | How can I boost my immune system as I age? Here’s what the science says. - The Washington Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>chrome-error://chromewebdata/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">chrome-error://chromewebdata/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 16:31:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mooli Patta Benefits: 8 health reasons to not throw away radish leaves - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mooli Patta Benefits: 8 Health Reasons to Not Throw Away Radish Leaves</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> TimesOfIndia.com</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116369693.jpg?imgsize=1441459&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="Mooli Patta Benefits" />
<figcaption>Mooli Patta Benefits: 8 health reasons to not throw away radish leaves</figcaption>
<p>Radish leaves, often discarded, are packed with nutrients and provide various health benefits. This article highlights eight important reasons to incorporate them into your diet.</p>
<ul>
<li>Rich source of nutrients, including vitamins A, C, and K.</li>
<li>Aids in digestion due to high dietary fiber content.</li>
<li>Detoxifies the body by flushing out toxins.</li>
<li>Boosts immunity, especially during the winter season.</li>
<li>Supports skin health with antioxidant properties.</li>
<li>Regulates blood sugar levels, beneficial for diabetes.</li>
<li>Offers anti-inflammatory properties reducing joint pain.</li>
<li>Versatile in cooking: can be added to soups, dals, or made into chutney.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Radish leaves are often overlooked and discarded; here are 8 reasons why you should never throw them away.”</blockquote>
<p>This article emphasizes that incorporating radish leaves into your diet can lead to significant health advantages.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/mooli-patta-benefits-8-health-reasons-to-not-throw-away-radish-leaves/photostory/116369663.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/mooli-patta-benefits-8-health-reasons-to-not-throw-away-radish-leaves/photostory/116369663.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where Bird Flu Has Jumped to Humans Since 2003 - Statista]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Infographic: Where Bird Flu Has Jumped to Humans Since 2003</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<strong>Source:</strong> Statista</p><img src="https://cdn.statcdn.com/Infographic/images/normal/33683.jpeg" alt="Infographic: Where Bird Flu Has Jumped to Humans Since 2003 | Statista" width="1200" height="1200"><figcaption>This chart shows the cumulative number of confirmed H5N1 cases worldwide between 2003 and November 1, 2024.</figcaption><p>Bird flu, particularly the H5N1 strain, has been affecting poultry and causing significant outbreaks among humans, particularly in the US and Cambodia.</p><ul><li>57 confirmed human cases of H5N1 reported worldwide between January 1, 2024, and November 1, 2024.</li><li>Majority of cases occurred in the United States (44) and Cambodia (10), with other cases reported in Australia, China, and Vietnam.</li><li>Of the cases in 2024, three were fatal: two in Cambodia and one in Vietnam.</li><li>From 2003 to 2009, there were 468 cases and 282 deaths worldwide, with Indonesia recording 134 fatalities.</li><li>Cases in Europe included just two in Spain in 2022, with additional reported cases in the UK.</li></ul><blockquote>“Data from the World Health Organization shows...”</blockquote><p>This infographic highlights the importance of ongoing surveillance and the need for public awareness regarding H5N1 and its potential impacts on health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.statista.com/chart/33683/cumulative-number-of-confirmed-h5n1-cases-worldwide/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statista.com/chart/33683/cumulative-number-of-confirmed-h5n1-cases-worldwide/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 16:17:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Antiretroviral therapy centre to come up in private medical college hospital in Coimbatore - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Antiretroviral Therapy Centre to Come Up in Private Medical College Hospital in Coimbatore</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 16, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/tamil-nadu/le4d0/article68932771.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/SJM.png" alt="" width="100%" height="100%">
<figcaption>Antiretroviral therapy centre image</figcaption>
<p>In a major boost to the efforts in combating Human Immunodeficiency Virus/Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (HIV/AIDS) in Coimbatore district, the work of setting up the first antiretroviral therapy (ART) centre at a private medical college hospital in Coimbatore is in progress.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The first ART centre will be established at KMCH Institute of Health Sciences and Research.</li>
  <li>Currently, the district has two ART centres functioning at Coimbatore Medical College Hospital and District Headquarters Hospital in Pollachi.</li>
  <li>There are an additional six link-ART centres at various government hospitals.</li>
  <li>The district offers 24 integrated counselling and testing centres (ICTC) for free HIV testing and counselling.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“People in the priority category are routinely tested for HIV/AIDS,” said DAPCU Programme Manager D. Gopalakrishnan.</blockquote>
<p>The district is executing targeted intervention programmes for high-risk groups through NGOs, aiming to increase awareness and testing amongst populations at risk.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Coimbatore/antiretroviral-therapy-centre-to-come-up-in-private-medical-college-hospital-in-coimbatore/article68993011.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Coimbatore/antiretroviral-therapy-centre-to-come-up-in-private-medical-college-hospital-in-coimbatore/article68993011.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 15:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Serum Institute ties up with Bavarian Nordic to manufacture Mpox vaccine - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/health/serum-institute-ties-up-with-bavarian-nordic-to-manufacture-mpox-vaccine-124121601219_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/health/serum-institute-ties-up-with-bavarian-nordic-to-manufacture-mpox-vaccine-124121601219_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 15:46:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diabetes-Friendly Snacking: Harness the Power of American Pecan Pairings - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diabetes-Friendly Snacking: Harness the Power of American Pecan Pairings</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 - <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><p>Managing diabetes effectively involves choosing the right snacks. American pecans are highlighted as a nutritious option to help maintain healthy blood glucose levels and control hunger.</p><ul><li>American pecans contain only 4 grams of carbohydrate per serving (19 halves).</li><li>They provide 3 grams of fiber and 3 grams of plant-based protein.</li><li>The low glycemic index of pecans does not cause blood sugar spikes.</li><li>Pecans support heart health with their monounsaturated fats and vitamins.</li><li>Portion control is essential, recommended up to three snacks per day.</li><li>Mindful snacking, such as pairing pecans with carbohydrates like fruit, is encouraged.</li><li>Various snack ideas include trail mixes, yogurt parfaits, and pecan energy bites.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pecans have a very low glycemic index... and can offset the effects of higher glycemic index foods.” - Dr. Varun Katyal, Nutritionist and Health Expert.</blockquote><p>Incorporating pecans into a diabetes-friendly snack routine provides nutrients and helps manage blood sugar levels while delivering lasting satisfaction.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/brandhub/pr-release/diabetes-friendly-snacking-harness-the-power-of-american-pecan-pairings/article68992814.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/brandhub/pr-release/diabetes-friendly-snacking-harness-the-power-of-american-pecan-pairings/article68992814.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 15:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revolutionary diabetes drug outperforms Metformin: Here's how it can transform health - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Revolutionary diabetes drug outperforms Metformin: Here's how it can transform health</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Kumamoto University</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116374095,imgsize-20544,width-400,resizemode-4/116374095.jpg" alt="Revolutionary diabetes drug outperforms Metformin" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Revolutionary diabetes drug outperforms Metformin</figcaption>
<p>Researchers at Kumamoto University have developed a novel compound HPH-15 that effectively reduces blood glucose and fat accumulation, outperforming Metformin, potentially transforming diabetes treatment.</p>
<ul>
  <li>HPH-15 has dual effects: lowering blood glucose and combating fat accumulation.</li>
  <li>The compound outperforms Metformin by activating AMPK at lower doses.</li>
  <li>Significantly reduces fat accumulation and improves glucose uptake.</li>
  <li>Exhibits additional antifibrotic properties aimed at combating liver fibrosis.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This compound holds transformative potential for diabetes treatment, offering benefits beyond blood sugar regulation.” - Professor Mikako Fujita</blockquote>
<p>The breakthrough compound HPH-15 could lead to a revolutionary change in diabetes management and address obesity-related complications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/revolutionary-diabetes-drug-outperforms-metformin-heres-how-it-can-transform-health/articleshow/116374093.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/revolutionary-diabetes-drug-outperforms-metformin-heres-how-it-can-transform-health/articleshow/116374093.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 15:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Men with a history of cannabis use show less cognitive decline, says a study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/men-with-a-history-of-cannabis-use-show-less-cognitive-decline-says-a-study/articleshow/116373401.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/men-with-a-history-of-cannabis-use-show-less-cognitive-decline-says-a-study/articleshow/116373401.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekend Warrior Physical Activity Pattern Lowers Mild Dementia Risk - Neurology Advisor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weekend Warrior Physical Activity Pattern Lowers Mild Dementia Risk</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Published in the <em>British Journal of Sports Medicine</em></p>
<p>This study suggests that a weekend warrior physical activity pattern is linked to a lower risk of mild dementia based on findings from a longitudinal analysis.</p>
<ul>
<li>Study used the Mexico City Prospective Study, tracking participants aged 35 and older.</li>
<li>Participants categorized into four cohorts: weekend warriors, regularly active, no exercise, and mixed.</li>
<li>Mild dementia was assessed using the Mini Mental State Examination (MMSE).</li>
<li>The weekend warrior cohort showed a significant reduction in dementia risk compared to those who did not exercise.</li>
<li>The study found that engaging in sport or exercise at least once or twice a week could theoretically eliminate up to 13% of mild dementia cases.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This study has important implications for policy and practice because the weekend warrior physical activity pattern may be a more convenient option for busy people around the world.”</blockquote>
<p>The findings highlight a potential public health strategy to incorporate physical activity into the routines of busy individuals to mitigate risks of dementia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.neurologyadvisor.com/news/weekend-warrior-physical-activity-pattern-lowers-mild-dementia-risk/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.neurologyadvisor.com/news/weekend-warrior-physical-activity-pattern-lowers-mild-dementia-risk/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No, Soursop, a fruit, cannot cure cancer - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/lifestyle/wellness/story/no-soursop-a-fruit-cannot-cure-cancer-2650598-2024-12-16</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/lifestyle/wellness/story/no-soursop-a-fruit-cannot-cure-cancer-2650598-2024-12-16</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:23:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Many U.S. States Are Affected by Bird Flu? - Statista]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Infographic: How Many U.S. States Are Affected by Bird Flu?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 12, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Statista</p><div><img src="https://cdn.statcdn.com/Infographic/images/normal/33680.jpeg" alt="Infographic: How Many U.S. States Are Affected by Bird Flu? | Statista" width="1200" height="1200"><figcaption>This chart shows the number of dairy herds with H5N1 cases in the United States recorded by the CDC between Mar. 25, 2024 to Dec. 12, 2024.</figcaption></div><p>The H5N1 virus has been detected in 16 states, with California being the most affected. Since March 2024, 845 dairy herds across the U.S. have reported cases.</p><ul><li>The H5N1 virus was confirmed in 630 herds in California.</li><li>Recent cases include 294 in California and one in Nevada.</li><li>The public health risk currently remains low with no human transmission reported.</li></ul><blockquote>“The current public health risk is considered low, with no cases of person-to-person transmission recorded.”</blockquote><p>This infographic highlights the spread of H5N1 in the U.S. dairy industry and the ongoing monitoring by health authorities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.statista.com/chart/33680/number-of-dairy-herds-with-h5n1-cases-in-the-united-states/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statista.com/chart/33680/number-of-dairy-herds-with-h5n1-cases-in-the-united-states/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:22:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genetic testing for breast cancer: When and why it might be right for you - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Genetic testing for breast cancer: When and why it might be right for you</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p>
<img src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/breast-cancer-5.jpg?w=802&amp;enlarge=true" alt="Genetic testing for breast cancer: When and why it might be right for you">
<figcaption>Genetic testing for breast cancer: When and why it might be right for you</figcaption>
<p>Genetic testing for breast cancer is pivotal for women with specific risk factors linked to family history. This testing identifies mutations like BRCA1 and BRCA2, significantly influencing prevention strategies.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Breast cancer is the most common cancer among women in India, with 1 in 28 women at risk.</li>
    <li>5-10% of breast cancer cases are hereditary, often linked to BRCA mutations.</li>
    <li>Genetic testing allows for personalized healthcare strategies, improving early detection and preventative actions.</li>
    <li>Testing is crucial for identifying elevated risks from mutations such as PALB2 and TP53.</li>
    <li>Enhanced monitoring, medication, and preventive surgeries are management strategies following genetic testing.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Genetic testing is crucial for identifying individuals at risk and implementing lifesaving early prevention strategies.” - Dr Suruchi Agarwal, Head of Scientific Affairs, MedGenome</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, genetic testing empowers individuals by providing critical information regarding their cancer risks and guiding informed healthcare decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/health/health-news/genetic-testing-for-breast-cancer-when-and-why-it-might-be-right-for-you-2774972</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/health/health-news/genetic-testing-for-breast-cancer-when-and-why-it-might-be-right-for-you-2774972</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:06:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Fat Burner for Men: Top 10 Men’s Fat Burning Supplements of 2025 - AccessWire]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.accesswire.com/955402/best-fat-burner-for-men-top-10-mens-fat-burning-supplements-of-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.accesswire.com/955402/best-fat-burner-for-men-top-10-mens-fat-burning-supplements-of-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:04:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Fat Burner for Men: Top 10 Men’s Fat Burning Supplements of 2025 - Newswire]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Best Fat Burner for Men: Top 10 Men’s Fat Burning Supplements of 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 16, 2024</strong></p>
<p><strong>Source: Newswire</strong></p>
<p>Choosing the best fat burner for men can be challenging with numerous options available. The right fat burner can support weight loss by boosting metabolism, reducing appetite, and enhancing energy levels.</p>
<img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Fat Burner Supplements' />
<figcaption>Top-rated fat burning supplements for men.</figcaption>
<p>Here are the top-rated fat burning supplements for men in 2025:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Capsiplex BURN</strong>: Best men's fat burner overall.</li>
  <li><strong>PhenQ</strong>: Best belly fat burner for men.</li>
  <li><strong>Clenbutrol</strong>: Best for bodybuilding and cutting cycles.</li>
  <li><strong>CalmLean</strong>: Best stimulant-free fat burner.</li>
  <li><strong>Instant Knockout Cut</strong>: Best 2-in-1 fat burner and appetite suppressant combo.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The best fat burners for men can help support your weight loss journey by boosting metabolism and increasing energy levels.”</blockquote>
<p>This guide provides insights into selecting the most effective fat-burning supplements based on various factors like ingredients, effectiveness, and user reviews.</p>
<p>In conclusion, choosing the right fat-burning supplement can enhance your weight loss journey, but pairing it with a healthy lifestyle is essential.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newswire.com/news/best-fat-burner-for-men-top-10-men-s-fat-burning-supplements-of-2025-22488574</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newswire.com/news/best-fat-burner-for-men-top-10-men-s-fat-burning-supplements-of-2025-22488574</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mpox vaccine update: Serum Institute of India inks deal with Bavarian Nordic to produce the jab | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/news/mpox-vaccine-update-serum-institute-of-india-inks-deal-with-bavarian-nordic-to-produce-the-jab-11734355331873.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/news/mpox-vaccine-update-serum-institute-of-india-inks-deal-with-bavarian-nordic-to-produce-the-jab-11734355331873.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:56:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With winter comes joint pain: How to stay fitter - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>With Winter Comes Joint Pain: How to Stay Fitter</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 <strong>By:</strong> Shyam Balasubramanian</p><img loading="lazy" title="" alt="" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/mediamanager/india_today_insight.jpg?IzvocAu7gyMv.UA3nBmTl5xRnm990vx3"><figcaption>Nearly 62 million Indians suffer from osteoarthritis, particularly affected in winter.</figcaption><p>Winter often exacerbates joint pain, particularly for those with existing conditions. This article offers insights into managing discomfort during colder months.</p><ul><li>Winter can increase joint pain related to arthritis due to factors like reduced mobility and muscle stiffness.</li><li>Exercise, such as yoga and swimming, can help alleviate pain and improve mobility.</li><li>Consult an orthopedic surgeon for tailored treatment instead of self-prescribing painkillers.</li><li>A comprehensive treatment plan is essential for effective management of joint pain.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/india-today-insight/story/with-winter-comes-joint-pain-how-to-stay-fitter-2650500-2024-12-16</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/india-today-insight/story/with-winter-comes-joint-pain-how-to-stay-fitter-2650500-2024-12-16</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:36:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highly drug-resistant cholera strain is spreading rapidly: What scientists are saying - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:36:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Lifestyle Guide to Maximising Your Chances of Conception; Expert Weighs In - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Lifestyle Guide to Maximising Your Chances of Conception; Expert Weighs In</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116368924,thumbsize-1284483,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116368924.jpg" alt="Image - Canva" title="Image - Canva"><figcaption>Dr. Umesh N Jindal discusses lifestyle factors affecting IVF success.</figcaption><p>This article provides expert insights on maximizing conception chances through various lifestyle changes, especially focusing on diet, exercise, and sleep.</p><ul><li>IVF leads to over 500,000 births annually but can be supported by lifestyle choices.</li><li>A Mediterranean-style diet may improve IVF success rates, particularly for women under 35.</li><li>Maintaining a healthy weight can enhance ovulatory cycles and hormonal balance.</li><li>Moderate exercise like swimming and light yoga benefits IVF patients, while intense workouts can harm hormone levels.</li><li>Consistent sleep of 7-8 hours can regulate reproductive hormones crucial for IVF.</li><li>Alcohol and caffeine adversely affect fertility, with recommendations for moderation or cessation.</li></ul><blockquote>“Women who sleep seven to eight hours per night are more likely to conceive than those with irregular or inadequate sleep.” - Dr. Umesh N Jindal</blockquote><p>In conclusion, adopting a healthy lifestyle can significantly enhance the effectiveness of IVF and improve the chances of conception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/health/how-to-improve-fertility-in-women-and-men-article-116368881</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/health/how-to-improve-fertility-in-women-and-men-article-116368881</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WHO urges member countries in Southeast Asia to bolster efforts to end TB - India Narrative]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxPalZScXFjdVJJSXdmYTduMDJyVndpVHJ6ZnozMWhocmcyWksxeTR3X1JTOEVIMVh1QUtYQjVwOWY3YWstc1EySzRqZzB4WEhyOWxIbVdtOXdERHJmRy1YcHdLQTgtTktkSWQ4WUllR21ZRzd0UkMtcWJZZGEyZXlVRU13djBkOTFrX1RMcnp4X05zLWF1dVBDZmFpelktTFQ3cERTbmVvNThqdzB4Q3h0aGhka2tucWxnZkIxSG1lUkowVENSMm5n0gHMAUFVX3lxTFBRTWVDaVltdVp1c19jaHN3MGUxODAzdmpRcHdkQnV0VU5VOWIzRTE5VTd6UUVHMHVRLVdhQlpfVUlja3B2ZGtkYld5OXR1MUh0bjRoaVFOUzVLSU1DOWRUSEdxMmg2bTdidS16eVJuT1pJOHp5NExjbFh6Vm5GRDY3RmM2YlBzcm81WWdFLVFKR2h5cDZvOFBXREx4SFdQaXpIdXBDbGNtRGVZZFlRbzFPcHRQdUJvQ3RWLVBSalhsT3NTWmotSk50NkFtRg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxPalZScXFjdVJJSXdmYTduMDJyVndpVHJ6ZnozMWhocmcyWksxeTR3X1JTOEVIMVh1QUtYQjVwOWY3YWstc1EySzRqZzB4WEhyOWxIbVdtOXdERHJmRy1YcHdLQTgtTktkSWQ4WUllR21ZRzd0UkMtcWJZZGEyZXlVRU13djBkOTFrX1RMcnp4X05zLWF1dVBDZmFpelktTFQ3cERTbmVvNThqdzB4Q3h0aGhka2tucWxnZkIxSG1lUkowVENSMm5n0gHMAUFVX3lxTFBRTWVDaVltdVp1c19jaHN3MGUxODAzdmpRcHdkQnV0VU5VOWIzRTE5VTd6UUVHMHVRLVdhQlpfVUlja3B2ZGtkYld5OXR1MUh0bjRoaVFOUzVLSU1DOWRUSEdxMmg2bTdidS16eVJuT1pJOHp5NExjbFh6Vm5GRDY3RmM2YlBzcm81WWdFLVFKR2h5cDZvOFBXREx4SFdQaXpIdXBDbGNtRGVZZFlRbzFPcHRQdUJvQ3RWLVBSalhsT3NTWmotSk50NkFtRg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:09:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Want to boost immunity in winter? Drink a glass of coconut milk daily, know other benefits - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Boost Your Immunity This Winter with Coconut Milk</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/coconut-milk-1734354072.webp" alt="Drink a glass of coconut milk to boost immunity" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>Drink a glass of coconut milk to boost immunity in winter.</figcaption>
<p>Coconut milk is packed with nutrients, including antioxidants, making it a great addition to your health regimen during winter. Regular consumption can offer several health benefits.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Strengthens Immune System:</strong> Coconut milk has antibacterial, antiviral, and antifungal properties that can enhance your immunity.</li>
  <li><strong>Aids Weight Loss:</strong> It boosts metabolism and helps in burning fat, making it helpful for those on a weight loss journey.</li>
  <li><strong>Beneficial for Skin:</strong> It reduces signs of aging and helps in maintaining moisturized and glowing skin.</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>(This article is for general information, please consult a doctor before adopting any remedy)</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> Incorporating coconut milk into your daily diet during winter can lead to significant health benefits, particularly for your immune system, weight management, and skin health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/lifestyle/food/want-to-boost-immunity-in-winter-drink-a-glass-of-coconut-milk-daily-know-other-benefits-2024-12-16-966516</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/lifestyle/food/want-to-boost-immunity-in-winter-drink-a-glass-of-coconut-milk-daily-know-other-benefits-2024-12-16-966516</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:06:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Do Gym Injuries Increase in Winter? Expert Shares Key Insights on Cold Season Fitness Risks - HerZindagi English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxPd0xNVnV4M1FuOHRNZzhDMU50d1VTOGtId3FJLTJyYnZia2RBb25qSEpIZmd4WGU2VzdwX0dzWjBGV0R0TjBiZlRPTnp5blRfWUFDczV1X3Z4ZWZwWnBTXzFGTktnRkpnY1ZRck85QWhKZ2l5aERmZGJLdVFIVmdGcExhN0Fud1kxZlNEN3lTQTNOaEo2QTVxRGw4T29NaWVCa3NaZEVkanRwOUhhbldmYVFmc0lsdlA1Z0pRZ01qOEwyeGt4RHNJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxPd0xNVnV4M1FuOHRNZzhDMU50d1VTOGtId3FJLTJyYnZia2RBb25qSEpIZmd4WGU2VzdwX0dzWjBGV0R0TjBiZlRPTnp5blRfWUFDczV1X3Z4ZWZwWnBTXzFGTktnRkpnY1ZRck85QWhKZ2l5aERmZGJLdVFIVmdGcExhN0Fud1kxZlNEN3lTQTNOaEo2QTVxRGw4T29NaWVCa3NaZEVkanRwOUhhbldmYVFmc0lsdlA1Z0pRZ01qOEwyeGt4RHNJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:00:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highly drug-resistant cholera strain is spreading rapidly: What scientists are saying - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/highly-drug-resistant-cholera-strain-is-spreading-rapidly-what-scientists-are-saying/articleshow/116370886.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/highly-drug-resistant-cholera-strain-is-spreading-rapidly-what-scientists-are-saying/articleshow/116370886.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highly drug-resistant cholera strain is spreading rapidly. What scientists are saying - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Highly Drug-Resistant Cholera Strain is Spreading Rapidly: What Scientists are Saying</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 12, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> New England Journal of Medicine</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116370929,imgsize-16174,width-400,resizemode-4/116370929.jpg" alt="Highly drug-resistant cholera strain is spreading rapidly: What scientists are saying"><figcaption>Image showing the spread of the cholera strain.</figcaption><p>A highly drug-resistant strain of cholera has emerged, resistant to ten antibiotics and spreading across multiple countries, raising serious health concerns.</p><ul><li>First identified during Yemen's 2018-2019 cholera outbreak.</li><li>Detected in Lebanon, Kenya, Tanzania, Comoros Islands, and a recent outbreak in Mayotte, France.</li><li>Study conducted by the National Reference Center for Vibrios and Cholera, published in the New England Journal of Medicine.</li><li>Approximately 1.3 to 4 million cholera cases globally each year, with 21,000 to 143,000 deaths.</li><li>Cholera can cause severe acute watery diarrhea, potentially fatal if untreated.</li></ul><blockquote>“This study demonstrates the need to strengthen global surveillance of the cholera agent...” - Professor François-Xavier Weill, Institut Pasteur</blockquote><p>Immediate attention is necessary to address this outbreak and prevent its escalation into a larger crisis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/highly-drug-resistant-cholera-strain-is-spreading-rapidly-what-scientists-are-saying/articleshow/116370886.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/highly-drug-resistant-cholera-strain-is-spreading-rapidly-what-scientists-are-saying/articleshow/116370886.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Benefits and risks of using a heating pad before bed - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxQcEQySnJjVjdLazYtQ3owUU9pVzdWUHNmYmprNDlkVDFDaENZZmZrRWNWMWw0Wm5JbUtrMkFHSGR5a0ZjVDJYSW95aFA2ZTB6X21CTjVPRVlIbnl2TUdPR295bTl5VlI1N0VTcXV0c2dtUzNXbGl4aFdrVlE0LWpYY0lHS2dNYWlvT1VINkJSU1BRejdpMUdTVWJRLTRwcTFZTkVEU0hwMVJDdjJt0gGsAUFVX3lxTFBwRDJKcmNWN0trNi1DejBRT2lXN1ZQc2Ziams0OWRUMUNoQ1lmZmtFY1YxbDRabkltS2syQUdIZHlrRmNUMlhJb3loUDZlMHpfbUJONU9FWUhueXZNR09Hb3ltOXlWUjU3RVNxdXRzZ21TM1dsaXhoV2tWUTQtalhjSUdLZ01haW9PVUg2QlJTUFF6N2kxR1NVYlEtNHBxMVlORURTSHAxUkN2Mm0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxQcEQySnJjVjdLazYtQ3owUU9pVzdWUHNmYmprNDlkVDFDaENZZmZrRWNWMWw0Wm5JbUtrMkFHSGR5a0ZjVDJYSW95aFA2ZTB6X21CTjVPRVlIbnl2TUdPR295bTl5VlI1N0VTcXV0c2dtUzNXbGl4aFdrVlE0LWpYY0lHS2dNYWlvT1VINkJSU1BRejdpMUdTVWJRLTRwcTFZTkVEU0hwMVJDdjJt0gGsAUFVX3lxTFBwRDJKcmNWN0trNi1DejBRT2lXN1ZQc2Ziams0OWRUMUNoQ1lmZmtFY1YxbDRabkltS2syQUdIZHlrRmNUMlhJb3loUDZlMHpfbUJONU9FWUhueXZNR09Hb3ltOXlWUjU3RVNxdXRzZ21TM1dsaXhoV2tWUTQtalhjSUdLZ01haW9PVUg2QlJTUFF6N2kxR1NVYlEtNHBxMVlORURTSHAxUkN2Mm0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:45:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World Malaria Report 2024: India achieves 69% drop in Malaria Cases - AffairsCloud.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQclF2Y01fNkVMaVp6cmpXSnV2VC1oOE10YlgxWlR2Y1RXaVI1am12QVFDTDNRRWdrTkFhQ3BTbGtvRXJEb3dmXzRBYnlVWGd3dTRHNVF6aG9WcF9Dal9MMjh3WDRQZnB4bHlKZTg0eGotLWRjbDNWSHhYdkhrSXgwa2ZEQzJRRWwwb21CMWdlOEZFSFl4TlHSAZsBQVVfeXFMUHRNakdxRk91RXlFT0E0NXB0eEVTZ0R3NlZaMGs3TXVVMVY3UzZWY3ZBZXgxQ3B4QnBiUTVSRzdra1JWWF9ReGktQ0tndEZpNzZ2cXRCTmw0WlFsWnFFMDZkbDJSNmNJZWFaTmtWeU1jS1haWURPQmZWNV9UT2tqc29WbjQtV1ZKZWtRVUxWYlRBOEVVZ2Exc1pnODg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQclF2Y01fNkVMaVp6cmpXSnV2VC1oOE10YlgxWlR2Y1RXaVI1am12QVFDTDNRRWdrTkFhQ3BTbGtvRXJEb3dmXzRBYnlVWGd3dTRHNVF6aG9WcF9Dal9MMjh3WDRQZnB4bHlKZTg0eGotLWRjbDNWSHhYdkhrSXgwa2ZEQzJRRWwwb21CMWdlOEZFSFl4TlHSAZsBQVVfeXFMUHRNakdxRk91RXlFT0E0NXB0eEVTZ0R3NlZaMGs3TXVVMVY3UzZWY3ZBZXgxQ3B4QnBiUTVSRzdra1JWWF9ReGktQ0tndEZpNzZ2cXRCTmw0WlFsWnFFMDZkbDJSNmNJZWFaTmtWeU1jS1haWURPQmZWNV9UT2tqc29WbjQtV1ZKZWtRVUxWYlRBOEVVZ2Exc1pnODg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:24:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doctors raise concern over rising lung cancers among non-smokers in India - The Hans India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxObVBjQm9RTmE3VHhnUGExUUx1cmdWQ1VnUFlwdnRMTTRIOFllcUlWZW5WRi04WjRlekQ2U0VabTJMNlhwcGs2bE13MjNDVncwdE55ck1VY3ktYjF1WGJRaDNIYldXaHZ6aE9BNWI1TmVKV0ltS2E1QTE5a0Y3VUpSRWwyd1NVYjRZSlV3cC1KV0ZaaWNyNktlcXM2YTJpZFZBblZON0VUSDRPbklvVmRwUEU3VWM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxObVBjQm9RTmE3VHhnUGExUUx1cmdWQ1VnUFlwdnRMTTRIOFllcUlWZW5WRi04WjRlekQ2U0VabTJMNlhwcGs2bE13MjNDVncwdE55ck1VY3ktYjF1WGJRaDNIYldXaHZ6aE9BNWI1TmVKV0ltS2E1QTE5a0Y3VUpSRWwyd1NVYjRZSlV3cC1KV0ZaaWNyNktlcXM2YTJpZFZBblZON0VUSDRPbklvVmRwUEU3VWM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:14:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 Simple Rules for Effective Fat Loss: Tips from Fitness Expert Sunil Shetty - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Simple Rules for Effective Fat Loss: Tips from Fitness Expert Sunil Shetty</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Including protein in every meal can help preserve muscle mass and boost metabolism." />
<figcaption>Including protein in every meal can help preserve muscle mass and boost metabolism.</figcaption>
<p>Losing fat is crucial for improving health by reducing the risk of conditions like heart disease and diabetes. Fitness expert Sunil Shetty shares eight actionable tips that can help you burn fat faster without major lifestyle changes.</p>
<ul>
<li>Create a Calorie Deficit: Burn more calories than you consume by monitoring food intake.</li>
<li>Avoid Liquid Calories: Choose water, green tea, or black coffee over sugary drinks.</li>
<li>Exercise at Least 3 Times a Week: Combine strength training with cardio for better results.</li>
<li>Include Protein in Every Meal: Helps to keep you full and preserves muscle mass.</li>
<li>Load Up on Vegetables: Low in calories but high in fiber to help you feel full.</li>
<li>Sleep 7-9 Hours Each Night: Quality sleep is essential for effective fat loss.</li>
<li>Increase Your Daily Steps: Aim for 10,000 steps per day to enhance activity.</li>
<li>Be Consistent and Enjoy the Journey: Track progress and celebrate small wins.</li>
</ul>
<p>Sunil emphasizes that consistency is key and that individuals should find enjoyable ways to stay active and maintain a balanced diet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-8-simple-rules-for-effective-fat-loss-tips-from-fitness-expert-sunil-shetty-9152731.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-8-simple-rules-for-effective-fat-loss-tips-from-fitness-expert-sunil-shetty-9152731.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:56:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 New Year Resolutions to Boost Your Heart Health - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 New Year Resolutions to Boost Your Heart Health</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Embracing and adopting a healthy lifestyle can lower the risk of developing heart conditions, leading to a healthy heart." title="Embracing and adopting a healthy lifestyle can lower the risk of developing heart conditions, leading to a healthy heart."><figcaption>Embracing and adopting a healthy lifestyle can lower the risk of developing heart conditions, leading to a healthy heart.</figcaption></figure><p>This article discusses practical New Year’s resolutions to improve heart health and promotes realistic goals rather than overly restrictive ones.</p><ul><li><strong>Sit Less and Move More:</strong> Incorporate movement into your day.</li><li><strong>Eat More Whole Foods:</strong> Prioritize whole foods for better heart health.</li><li><strong>Stop Having Sweetened Beverages:</strong> Limit sugar intake, especially from drinks.</li><li><strong>Prioritize Sleep:</strong> Aim for 7-8 hours of sleep for overall health.</li><li><strong>Spend Less Time On Your Phone:</strong> Engage more with your surroundings.</li><li><strong>Quit Alcohol and Smoking:</strong> Important for lowering blood pressure.</li><li><strong>Go for Yearly Health Check-Ups:</strong> Regular check-ups can catch issues early.</li></ul><blockquote>Setting realistic goals is key to achieving sustainable heart health improvements.</blockquote><p>Making these resolutions could lead to significant long-term benefits for heart health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-5-new-year-resolutions-to-boost-your-heart-health-9158166.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/health-and-fitness-5-new-year-resolutions-to-boost-your-heart-health-9158166.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:50:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>