<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:22:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:22:14 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What’s behind joint pains this winter? Orthos and nutritionists tell you how to keep moving despite them - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What’s behind joint pains this winter? Orthos and nutritionists tell you how to keep moving despite them</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/joint-pain.jpg?w=640" alt="joint pain exercise during winters" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Exposure to cold causes the blood vessels to constrict so that they can conserve heat, so blood flow to the limbs is reduced, causing stiffness and pain. (Photo: Freepik)</figcaption><p>Is the cold limiting your movement because of stiff and painful joints, preventing you from exercise? Experts say this is not uncommon because the chill triggers swelling in the tissues and bones, reducing the range of motion and increasing pain.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The cold causes blood vessels to constrict, reducing blood flow to limbs.</li><li>This can lead to stiffness and increased joint pain.</li><li>Experts provide insights on managing winter joint pain through exercise and nutrition.</li></ul><blockquote>“The chill triggers swelling in the tissues and bones, reducing the range of motion and increasing pain.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, understanding the impact of cold on joint health can help individuals find ways to alleviate discomfort and maintain mobility during winter.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/joint-pain-winter-orthos-nutritionist-9775841/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/joint-pain-winter-orthos-nutritionist-9775841/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scarlet fever cases on rise in Hyderabad: Here’s what every parent needs to know - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPdTNsdkxMMTlzaUtFLVM5ejR4QTV2ellzcl94Uk5ocE1wcFNpdXhBNTJXMFlzRjNxLTFXUHJEa0R5MjRBcjRaakJpWUo3NGRTME5XXzZtZHdFZnBEMGxOVEhELVFFRzc5Wl85UkVHakZ3emFpa05QNEUzcFVud3NmbnM0VVdnNHRNNjZGUmtqTVBkSTd3MmloLW15WThsYXdKNVY0OW82TG0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPdTNsdkxMMTlzaUtFLVM5ejR4QTV2ellzcl94Uk5ocE1wcFNpdXhBNTJXMFlzRjNxLTFXUHJEa0R5MjRBcjRaakJpWUo3NGRTME5XXzZtZHdFZnBEMGxOVEhELVFFRzc5Wl85UkVHakZ3emFpa05QNEUzcFVud3NmbnM0VVdnNHRNNjZGUmtqTVBkSTd3MmloLW15WThsYXdKNVY0OW82TG0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:27:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gut microbiome: Fibre-rich diet, not just probiotics, strengthens your gut against harmful bacteria - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gut microbiome: Fibre-rich diet, not just probiotics, strengthens your gut against harmful bacteria</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/08/20240807062539_Benefits-of-high-fibre-diet-for-healthy-gut-whole-grain-cereals.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Diet tips: Eating fibre-rich foods such as vegetables, beans, and whole grains promotes the growth of protective bacteria (Image: Canva)" title="Diet tips: Eating fibre-rich foods such as vegetables, beans, and whole grains promotes the growth of protective bacteria (Image: Canva)" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>Diet tips: Eating fibre-rich foods such as vegetables, beans, and whole grains promotes the growth of protective bacteria (Image: Canva)</figcaption>
<p>Your gut microbiome aids digestion and plays a vital role in protecting you from infections. Recent research shows that a fibre-rich diet is essential for creating an environment that naturally repels harmful bacteria.</p>
<ul>
  <li>A diet rich in fibre from vegetables, legumes, and whole grains supports protective bacteria growth.</li>
  <li>The gut microbiome consists of trillions of organisms crucial for digestion and infection protection.</li>
  <li>Harmful bacteria like Klebsiella pneumoniae and E. coli can overgrow due to poor diet and inflammation.</li>
  <li>Research indicates that the microbiome's composition can predict susceptibility to infections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Simply introducing probiotics to 'starve out' harmful bacteria isn’t enough. Instead, the focus should be on creating a gut environment that naturally prevents these bacteria from thriving.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, prioritizing a fibre-rich diet may be more effective than relying solely on probiotics for gut health protection.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/gut-microbiome-fibre-rich-diet-not-just-probiotics-strengthens-your-gut-against-harmful-bacteria-article-12908685.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/gut-microbiome-fibre-rich-diet-not-just-probiotics-strengthens-your-gut-against-harmful-bacteria-article-12908685.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:52:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tripura High Court Seeks Updated Statistics Of HIV/ AIDS Patients In State - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tripura High Court Seeks Updated Statistics Of HIV/ AIDS Patients In State</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> February 20, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p><p>The <b>Tripura High Court</b> has ordered the Tripura State AIDS Control Society to provide updated statistics on the incidence of HIV/AIDS to evaluate the effectiveness of current interventions.</p><ul><li>The court is examining the steps taken to combat the rise in HIV/AIDS cases.</li><li>New ART centres and monitoring units are being established in the Khowai and Gomati Districts.</li><li>The Tripura State AIDS Control Society plans to increase its budget for operationalizing new facilities.</li><li>There are currently numerous testing and counseling centres operating in the state.</li><li>The court has scheduled a follow-up on this matter.</li></ul><blockquote>“Over a period of 5/6 years TSACS has increased the number of Opioid Substitution Therapy (OST) centres from 5 to 23.”</blockquote><p>The court continues to push for transparency and accountability in the management of HIV/AIDS resources and statistics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/tripura-high-court/tripura-high-court-aids-control-statistics-of-hiv-patients-280746</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/tripura-high-court/tripura-high-court-aids-control-statistics-of-hiv-patients-280746</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:30:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases in northern provinces declining: China - Zee Business]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Declining HMPV Cases in Northern China: Health Officials Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Chinese health officials announced that cases of the Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) are declining in northern provinces due to improved detection methods.</p><ul><li>Wang Liping, a researcher from the Chinese CDC, stated that the increase in cases was primarily a result of better detection technologies.</li><li>The rate of positive cases among children aged 14 and below has started to decline.</li><li>HMPV has been present for several decades and first emerged in 2001 in the Netherlands.</li><li>Concerns over rising cases in China were dismissed as part of annual winter respiratory trends.</li><li>India has reported about 10 cases mostly in children.</li></ul><blockquote>“Respiratory infections tend to peak during the winter season in the Northern Hemisphere.” - Mao Ning</blockquote><p>The overall severity and spread of respiratory diseases appears reduced compared to the previous year, according to health authorities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.zeebiz.com/world/news-hmpv-cases-in-india-china-northern-provinces-declining-human-metapneumovirus-respiratory-illness-symptoms-cure-precautions-mask-338709</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zeebiz.com/world/news-hmpv-cases-in-india-china-northern-provinces-declining-human-metapneumovirus-respiratory-illness-symptoms-cure-precautions-mask-338709</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:22:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV virus in India: Does your health insurance policy cover outbreaks - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV virus in India: Does your health insurance policy cover outbreaks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p><p>Seven cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) have been reported in India, raising concerns among parents. The government has called for increased surveillance, while schools and organizations warn the public to be cautious.</p><ul><li>Seven recent cases of HMPV affecting infants and toddlers in India.</li><li>Government advice on enhancing surveillance measures.</li><li>Importance of reviewing health insurance policies regarding coverage for viral infections.</li><li>Major health insurers affirm that HMPV treatment is usually covered under comprehensive health policies.</li><li>Advice from experts about policy specifics, including deductibles and co-payments, and the need to review policy terms.</li></ul><blockquote>“The rise in HMPV cases this winter highlights the critical importance of accessible, comprehensive healthcare coverage.” - Amitabh Jain, Star Health Insurance</blockquote><p>In conclusion, reviewing health insurance coverage for HMPV and maintaining hygiene practices is vital amid rising cases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/finance/personal-finance/hmpv-virus-in-india-does-your-health-insurance-policy-cover-outbreaks-125010900930_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/finance/personal-finance/hmpv-virus-in-india-does-your-health-insurance-policy-cover-outbreaks-125010900930_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:26:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[224 cholera cases recorded in Angola with 18 deaths - United News of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxOdDFtOElJN0EzWDI4WGZHV2FKbmZIZ010TDBDZzJxQnFWa252YndpcGZlVjhDei01eGNwSXVoYnpHN0JmdWRWS0xNemphNlNDS0FGM0d4Z0k5bUkwRk5jaktpN2xUX3J1ejRybWRLY2xqX0xyMzl5aVV3TGFXUjJ6VjY4aTlJcUprYXQ0WC1wemJwcnVqRHNNTlZ6dDE1cDRXRzgtMg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxOdDFtOElJN0EzWDI4WGZHV2FKbmZIZ010TDBDZzJxQnFWa252YndpcGZlVjhDei01eGNwSXVoYnpHN0JmdWRWS0xNemphNlNDS0FGM0d4Z0k5bUkwRk5jaktpN2xUX3J1ejRybWRLY2xqX0xyMzl5aVV3TGFXUjJ6VjY4aTlJcUprYXQ0WC1wemJwcnVqRHNNTlZ6dDE1cDRXRzgtMg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV on decline in northern China, says health official - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPNDlKcmN5aEhoSmROMS1QWG56THpoYmg1bTM4YlNnUUxxazNfODRTQnRjVjJzRlI0ZkhRVVM5eG1HbEVjZzAxVmM2TVdDNGNtRTRXVUhCa2FVcjM3Z0U4SlcwOXk4WVZPbVI5enh3bE1oM2FQR3VlRXh1c1dZYkRuaXR2Z3VaWjFrX243Yl9ydXhPSjY5czRtMm9ud9IBnwFBVV95cUxNT0FROWhNRWZkU1BJMl90WklFWmEyYW1CM3lDVFBRemF2Zzh5OXZhWnpKS0sxSWFKcVZBZTFLYThmZlpmWWdqSnQ1Y0J6dWdSWjJqMXJtU3A1allqaDAxTi0xcDBOR2ZaZFQ0UHU5SEhjVlgxRTNrTzBXRVMwdGg5QXJKTDdXQkl2ZDZGZ1RnRV9wY18wQ0F0ZEpzbW14SUk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPNDlKcmN5aEhoSmROMS1QWG56THpoYmg1bTM4YlNnUUxxazNfODRTQnRjVjJzRlI0ZkhRVVM5eG1HbEVjZzAxVmM2TVdDNGNtRTRXVUhCa2FVcjM3Z0U4SlcwOXk4WVZPbVI5enh3bE1oM2FQR3VlRXh1c1dZYkRuaXR2Z3VaWjFrX243Yl9ydXhPSjY5czRtMm9ud9IBnwFBVV95cUxNT0FROWhNRWZkU1BJMl90WklFWmEyYW1CM3lDVFBRemF2Zzh5OXZhWnpKS0sxSWFKcVZBZTFLYThmZlpmWWdqSnQ1Y0J6dWdSWjJqMXJtU3A1allqaDAxTi0xcDBOR2ZaZFQ0UHU5SEhjVlgxRTNrTzBXRVMwdGg5QXJKTDdXQkl2ZDZGZ1RnRV9wY18wQ0F0ZEpzbW14SUk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:32:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is your Vitamin C intake enough? Know which foods have the highest levels - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is Your Vitamin C Intake Enough? Know Which Foods Have the Highest Levels</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/indian-express-57.jpg?w=640" alt="Vitamin C" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Vitamin C is essential for various health functions and should be included in your diet.</figcaption>
<p>Vitamin C, or ascorbic acid, is crucial for healing, preventing infections, and maintaining overall health. Despite its availability in various foods, many individuals do not meet the recommended daily intake.</p>
<ul>
<li>The recommended daily intake for women is 75 mg and for men is 90 mg, with certain groups requiring more.</li>
<li>Vitamin C supports white blood cell production, collagen synthesis, and acts as an antioxidant.</li>
<li>Key food sources include citrus fruits, bell peppers, strawberries, broccoli, and papaya.</li>
<li>Acerola cherries are exceptionally rich in vitamin C but may not be widely available fresh.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Vitamin C helps improve iron absorption from plant-based foods and reduce the severity of cold symptoms."</blockquote>
<p>Ensuring adequate vitamin C intake is essential for maintaining health, and there are many delicious food sources available in the diet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/vitamin-c-intake-oranges-leon-grapefruits-nutrients-9775623/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/vitamin-c-intake-oranges-leon-grapefruits-nutrients-9775623/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:04:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV detected in 10-month-old baby in India's Assam - People's Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiY0FVX3lxTE5YSWFVU2NHZTRzRkt2QnJaOTc5UXN1Tlp1b291WTc4NjdDVTl5NTNlUTBzQjRPUEJBaGhydlB3emFfa1k2TU5HV1NZUUQ2SURUR195cmJqdWJEMjJpRDE5QkJsTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiY0FVX3lxTE5YSWFVU2NHZTRzRkt2QnJaOTc5UXN1Tlp1b291WTc4NjdDVTl5NTNlUTBzQjRPUEJBaGhydlB3emFfa1k2TU5HV1NZUUQ2SURUR195cmJqdWJEMjJpRDE5QkJsTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weight Loss Story: This 68-year-old defeated diabetes and lost 11 Kg in 6 months through low-carb diet - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weight Loss Story: This 68-year-old defeated diabetes and lost 11 Kg in 6 months through low-carb diet</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img src="https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/bb83e0c7cb6ba13a840f8a1dda0a0433.png" alt="Weight Loss Image">
<figcaption>A 68-year-old individual shares their inspiring weight loss story.</figcaption>
<p>This article highlights the journey of a 68-year-old who managed to defeat diabetes and lose 11 kg over six months by following a low-carb diet regimen.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The individual adopted a strict low-carb diet.</li>
  <li>They lost a total of 11 kg within six months.</li>
  <li>Not only did they lose weight, but they also improved their diabetic condition.</li>
  <li>The article includes tips and strategies related to low-carb dieting.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This diet changed my life. I feel healthier and more energetic than ever.”</blockquote>
<p>This inspiring story showcases the effectiveness of dietary changes in managing health conditions, particularly diabetes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/weight-loss/weight-loss-story-this-68-year-old-defeated-diabetes-and-lost-11-kg-in-6-months-through-low-carb-diet/articleshow/117180417.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/weight-loss/weight-loss-story-this-68-year-old-defeated-diabetes-and-lost-11-kg-in-6-months-through-low-carb-diet/articleshow/117180417.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rate of HMPV infections in northern China declining, Chinese health official says - Daily Excelsior]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPeUZlaWEza2RWM0NQTGhUSnBRSnB6N2hFUEJZeU0ydEVEZ3N5UFYwV0V1YlFoOFpuNEJDME1FWHZ6NlpKUWM0S3N6aXh6azBrYnZHLWg2R0lJYnhGWnJBdzFXaXBfbFp2Y211a29ZUHh3dUV6dU5YcjNWbWpRUGd0U3JaOVp5ZHk4VXF2UzBrblVxYnF4UU15SjFhZFRQOEg3M2ZtU2VFelRPcFp6aXhjNi13?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPeUZlaWEza2RWM0NQTGhUSnBRSnB6N2hFUEJZeU0ydEVEZ3N5UFYwV0V1YlFoOFpuNEJDME1FWHZ6NlpKUWM0S3N6aXh6azBrYnZHLWg2R0lJYnhGWnJBdzFXaXBfbFp2Y211a29ZUHh3dUV6dU5YcjNWbWpRUGd0U3JaOVp5ZHk4VXF2UzBrblVxYnF4UU15SjFhZFRQOEg3M2ZtU2VFelRPcFp6aXhjNi13?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 23:59:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Dairy-Free and High-Protein Options for Vegans - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Dairy-Free and High-Protein Options for Vegans</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p>
<img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2025/01/13/900x1600/pexels-mastercowley-11533_1736740824975_1736740830630.jpg" alt="FUEL YOUR DAY">
<figcaption>FUEL YOUR DAY</figcaption>
<p>A protein-rich diet can support muscle strength, enhance feelings of fullness, and aid in weight loss. A thoughtfully planned vegan diet can provide all essential nutrients, including protein.</p>
<ul>
<li>Seitan: Nearly 25 grams of protein per 3.5 ounces (100 grams).</li>
<li>Tofu, Tempeh, and Edamame: 12–20 grams of protein per 3.5 ounces (100 grams).</li>
<li>Lentils: 18 grams of protein per cooked cup (198 grams).</li>
<li>Beans (Kidney beans, black beans, pinto beans, and chickpeas): Around 15 grams of protein per cooked cup (170 grams).</li>
<li>Green Peas: Nearly 9 grams of protein per cooked cup (160 grams).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>A thoughtfully planned vegan diet can provide all essential nutrients, including protein.</blockquote>
<p>This article provides valuable insights into high-protein, dairy-free food options for vegans, useful for anyone looking to enhance their diet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-dairy-free-and-high-protein-options-for-vegans-visual-story-11736740708973.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-dairy-free-and-high-protein-options-for-vegans-visual-story-11736740708973.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 22:46:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Does Drinking Alcohol Affect Your Health? - VOA Learning English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxNSkVFeWc0QVhORW85Rm92SkNJZmtVMWFlSlJmZXY2WVdyVEZCRjRoa213dEV1NlU3U3hYQXBXVjgxOHhBSkNKX2VfU2hrWDJOZC1mdFZZbFdHSE8xLWtIeEtTVV9FSC1SN1dxUUZjdUJnN1lpWlVBZEgwYVJpeWhkMGhqUVJUQlhZSjdHYzZOQ2dTM0VzQmdmM3lBZFXSAZ8BQVVfeXFMUE1qNVdVeHdNVEZjeENsZDBreFJlcHF1THNta2g3NFk3bnY2V0xlMXlfMkNKOWhEZzVUTnlVaGM3Vm10clU3ZWtBelQwM0tHdUh5a2Q1NkpUNmY4cDIyMnFrc0gxMnI1VVdnSi1aWG0teVRINHFYTENNd0RPbEIxclNQV1FXdVFnQVI4WENrNC1KWXN4YnBtVXB3LVF1dUFr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxNSkVFeWc0QVhORW85Rm92SkNJZmtVMWFlSlJmZXY2WVdyVEZCRjRoa213dEV1NlU3U3hYQXBXVjgxOHhBSkNKX2VfU2hrWDJOZC1mdFZZbFdHSE8xLWtIeEtTVV9FSC1SN1dxUUZjdUJnN1lpWlVBZEgwYVJpeWhkMGhqUVJUQlhZSjdHYzZOQ2dTM0VzQmdmM3lBZFXSAZ8BQVVfeXFMUE1qNVdVeHdNVEZjeENsZDBreFJlcHF1THNta2g3NFk3bnY2V0xlMXlfMkNKOWhEZzVUTnlVaGM3Vm10clU3ZWtBelQwM0tHdUh5a2Q1NkpUNmY4cDIyMnFrc0gxMnI1VVdnSi1aWG0teVRINHFYTENNd0RPbEIxclNQV1FXdVFnQVI4WENrNC1KWXN4YnBtVXB3LVF1dUFr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 21:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samples of 2 Nagpur kids test positive for HMPV at AIIMS too, but unfit for genome sequencing - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxQc29VSVVab3dTYjJpdEFRckpacnRLV2FrTjRCaTkxbV8tdmtzMW1HbzAxNkEtTFk1dm5JZl9nbF9rOS1TVGlMSjhVOG1ob2EtcHd2eW5HZjRoSUVKaDQzU09xTFNrZzZVT20xYkI2YWFyUV9zUWV1M09WVEpnTnFLNkhyekRpWldTbUMtT2xrR0NOcUw5S1Y0Tmt3SmlhMk84aEtqdXFjMEhCN0F0RnhWNV9EUFluNENrNXBKTGJoQWVyTVJiQmNMV1NhbUVjRldaV05HaUNTYkRYRjZNSXNwTy1iY0xhZnRpWEpJY3ZETzJjUzQ5WEJYcTRn0gH_AUFVX3lxTE9rQVdFek0zQjVIbndvcGgteGlsSXJiX1UzSEwyQjZFSk1oQ3FrZDhXc19lOEN0NzMzY1JiczNZQkRSUkhnTE1TdEZpU1p6VTAwXzNaMVhrNVl5SHVIeHZJdjdCdVpCRHdVSS00LVRFUG5MVUVnUi1LR2o2N21wVjZlaUNBNVlSLXBZNHV4VlhHb3I2Q21KRVNvMXI5RkR5aEVRai1wYzB3MmZNaXNoZVBRWENuSW1kbkxwaFlBMVZBMzMtYV9URnNqNS1uaURLblBjUVJvdlh4Q0RzNzVVWmFvMl9JZ3RMeGRfakE2S1A1ZWJVaWRwd3E4OGFCUFpjMA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxQc29VSVVab3dTYjJpdEFRckpacnRLV2FrTjRCaTkxbV8tdmtzMW1HbzAxNkEtTFk1dm5JZl9nbF9rOS1TVGlMSjhVOG1ob2EtcHd2eW5HZjRoSUVKaDQzU09xTFNrZzZVT20xYkI2YWFyUV9zUWV1M09WVEpnTnFLNkhyekRpWldTbUMtT2xrR0NOcUw5S1Y0Tmt3SmlhMk84aEtqdXFjMEhCN0F0RnhWNV9EUFluNENrNXBKTGJoQWVyTVJiQmNMV1NhbUVjRldaV05HaUNTYkRYRjZNSXNwTy1iY0xhZnRpWEpJY3ZETzJjUzQ5WEJYcTRn0gH_AUFVX3lxTE9rQVdFek0zQjVIbndvcGgteGlsSXJiX1UzSEwyQjZFSk1oQ3FrZDhXc19lOEN0NzMzY1JiczNZQkRSUkhnTE1TdEZpU1p6VTAwXzNaMVhrNVl5SHVIeHZJdjdCdVpCRHdVSS00LVRFUG5MVUVnUi1LR2o2N21wVjZlaUNBNVlSLXBZNHV4VlhHb3I2Q21KRVNvMXI5RkR5aEVRai1wYzB3MmZNaXNoZVBRWENuSW1kbkxwaFlBMVZBMzMtYV9URnNqNS1uaURLblBjUVJvdlh4Q0RzNzVVWmFvMl9JZ3RMeGRfakE2S1A1ZWJVaWRwd3E4OGFCUFpjMA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How a breast cancer doctor faced the disease she helped others battle - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How a Breast Cancer Doctor Faced the Disease She Helped Others Battle</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a profound personal journey, a breast cancer doctor confronts the very illness she has dedicated her career to combating.</p><ul><li>The doctor shares her experience transitioning from caregiver to patient.</li><li>She discusses the emotional and psychological challenges faced during her diagnosis.</li><li>Insights on how her medical expertise influenced her treatment choices.</li><li>Assessing the impact of her experience on her practice and patient interactions.</li></ul><blockquote>"My role as a doctor has given me a unique perspective, but nothing prepared me for the journey of being a patient."</blockquote><p>This narrative not only sheds light on the struggles of patients but also emphasizes the importance of empathy in medicine.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/how-a-breast-cancer-doctor-faced-the-disease-she-helped-others-battle/articleshow/117180639.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/how-a-breast-cancer-doctor-faced-the-disease-she-helped-others-battle/articleshow/117180639.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rethinking protein: Doctors call for balanced nutrition, highlight risks of overconsumption - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rethinking Protein: Doctors Call for Balanced Nutrition, Highlight Risks of Overconsumption</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>This article discusses the importance of balanced nutrition with a focus on protein consumption. Medical professionals highlight the potential health risks associated with excessive protein intake.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Calls for a shift in dietary recommendations concerning protein consumption.</li>
  <li>Emphasizes the health risks associated with overconsumption of protein.</li>
  <li>Advises on the importance of a well-rounded diet including various nutrients.</li>
  <li>Supports the idea of individualized nutrition plans tailored to personal health needs.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Overconsumption of protein can lead to various health issues that may not be immediately apparent."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, health experts urge for a reevaluation of dietary guidelines to ensure that protein is consumed in moderation as part of a balanced diet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/rethinking-protein-doctors-call-for-balanced-nutrition-highlight-risks-of-overconsumption/articleshow/117180608.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/rethinking-protein-doctors-call-for-balanced-nutrition-highlight-risks-of-overconsumption/articleshow/117180608.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boost your health this winter with these nutrient-rich exotic fruits - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Boost Your Health This Winter with Nutrient-Rich Exotic Fruits</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> indiatodayglobal</p><div><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/pomegranate-285359254-16x9.jpg?VersionId=X6RpKEY0ijvEhdrYSmZZdRcQN3PN28Nk&amp;size=690:388" alt="Winter fruits: Persimmon, Pomelo, Pomegranate" width="690" height="388"><figcaption>Winter fruits: Persimmon, Pomelo, Pomegranate</figcaption></div><p>This winter, explore exotic fruits like guava, kumquat, kiwi, persimmons, and pomegranate to boost nutrition and add vibrant flavours to your diet. These unique options offer health benefits and exciting tastes.</p><ul><li>Guava is rich in vitamin C, fiber, and antioxidants.</li><li>Kumquats can be eaten whole; they have a sweet peel and a tart flesh.</li><li>Kiwi is packed with vitamin C, fiber, and potassium, offering a sweet-tart flavor.</li><li>Star fruit presents a unique shape and mild flavor, high in vitamin C.</li><li>Persimmons come in two varieties, both offering vitamins A and C.</li><li>Pomelo is milder than grapefruit and rich in nutrients.</li><li>Pomegranate is loaded with antioxidants and adds flavor to dishes.</li></ul><blockquote>“These unusual fruits provide winter diets with variation and variety and also introduce an array of health benefits.”</blockquote><p>Incorporating these fruits into your winter diet can enhance both your health and culinary experience. Don’t miss the opportunity to try these exotic options for a more vibrant and nutrient-rich winter.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/boost-your-health-this-winter-with-these-nutrient-rich-exotic-fruits-glbs-2663772-2025-01-13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/boost-your-health-this-winter-with-these-nutrient-rich-exotic-fruits-glbs-2663772-2025-01-13</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:35:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV outbreak: Amid global concern, Chinese official says cases in northern China declining - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV outbreak: Cases in Northern China Declining Amid Global Concern</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><div id="story-featured-image"><figure><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/hmpv-3-1736703321.webp" alt="HMPV" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Representational image.</figcaption></figure></div><p>The rate of infections with the flu-like human metapneumovirus (HMPV) in northern China is declining, according to a health official, amidst international concern over a potential pandemic.</p><ul><li>The recent outbreak of HMPV has raised alarms similar to COVID-19 due to images of overwhelmed hospitals.</li><li>The virus has been present for decades, and most children contract it by age 5.</li><li>Symptoms include fever, cough, and nasal congestion, usually resolving on their own.</li><li>Current trends show declining rates of positive cases, especially among patients aged 14 and below.</li><li>No vaccines or specific treatments are available for HMPV; preventive measures are advised.</li></ul><blockquote>“The human metapneumovirus is not a new virus, and has been with humans for at least several decades.” - Wang Liping, Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention</blockquote><p>The situation appears manageable with no significant medical resource shortages reported. Experts express cautious optimism as flu infections are expected to decline in the coming weeks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/news/world/hmpv-outbreak-amid-global-concern-chinese-official-says-cases-in-northern-china-declining-2025-01-12-970939</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/news/world/hmpv-outbreak-amid-global-concern-chinese-official-says-cases-in-northern-china-declining-2025-01-12-970939</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:35:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 morning shots that help burn fat and reduce weight - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Morning Shots to Burn Fat and Reduce Weight</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> TimesOfIndia.com</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/117152491.jpg?imgsize=1256196&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="7 morning shots that help burn fat and reduce weight"><figcaption>7 morning shots that help burn fat and reduce weight</figcaption>
<p>Starting your day with the right drink can significantly impact your weight loss journey. Morning shots are small, power-packed drinks that can boost metabolism, improve digestion, and help burn fat. Here are 7 weight-loss-friendly shots tailored for an Indian lifestyle.</p>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Lemon and Honey Shot:</strong> A metabolism booster made with lemon juice and honey in warm water.</li>
    <li><strong>Jeera Water Shot:</strong> A traditional remedy using soaked cumin seeds to aid digestion and weight loss.</li>
    <li><strong>Amla Shot:</strong> A drink made from fresh amla, rich in vitamin C, to enhance metabolism and immunity.</li>
    <li><strong>Cinnamon and Honey Shot:</strong> A combination that helps regulate blood sugar and curb cravings.</li>
    <li><strong>Ginger and Lemon Shot:</strong> A zesty drink that stimulates metabolism and improves digestion.</li>
    <li><strong>Methi Water Shot:</strong> Fenugreek water to suppress appetite and balance blood sugar levels.</li>
    <li><strong>Turmeric and Black Pepper Shot:</strong> A drink promoting weight loss and overall wellness with curcumin.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Pair these shots with a balanced diet and regular exercise for the best results."</blockquote>
<p>Incorporating these simple shots into your morning routine can provide a boost to your weight loss goals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/7-morning-shots-that-help-burn-fat-and-reduce-weight/photostory/117152452.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/7-morning-shots-that-help-burn-fat-and-reduce-weight/photostory/117152452.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explained: How to protect yourself from norovirus, Covid-19, flu, and RSV - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How to Protect Yourself from Norovirus, COVID-19, Flu, and RSV</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><p>In the winter months, many are susceptible to illnesses such as flu and COVID-19. Understanding how these viruses spread and how to protect oneself is vital for health during this season.</p><ul><li>Norovirus is spread through contaminated surfaces and can lead to vomiting and diarrhea.</li><li>Common cold symptoms include a runny nose and sore throat, while flu symptoms can be more intense.</li><li>COVID-19 can lead to severe respiratory symptoms and loss of taste or smell.</li><li>Handwashing is crucial in preventing the spread of these viruses.</li><li>Cleaning surfaces and self-isolation if symptomatic are recommended practices.</li><li>Vaccines are available for COVID-19 and flu, but not for norovirus.</li></ul><blockquote>“If you do get sick, prompt testing can help determine whether you have COVID-19 or influenza.”</blockquote><p>Maintaining good hygiene and staying informed can help mitigate the risks associated with these viruses during the winter months.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/health/explained-how-to-protect-yourself-from-norovirus-covid-19-flu-and-rsv-125011200619_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/health/explained-how-to-protect-yourself-from-norovirus-covid-19-flu-and-rsv-125011200619_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:03:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California man dies from an unusual lung cancer spread from another person - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California man dies from an unusual lung cancer spread from another person</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>A California man has tragically passed away due to a rare form of lung cancer that was transmitted from another person, highlighting the potential for cancer to be spread in ways not previously understood.</p><ul><li>The lung cancer in question is particularly unusual and raises questions about transmission methods.</li><li>Medical experts call for further research into the mechanisms of cancer spread.</li><li>This incident has sparked discussions about public health and cancer awareness.</li></ul><blockquote>"This case underscores the necessity for increased awareness and understanding of how lung cancer can manifest in unexpected ways."</blockquote><p>This event illuminates the need for continued research in cancer transmission and awareness in public health practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/california-man-dies-from-an-unusual-lung-cancer-spread-from-another-person/articleshow/117176600.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/california-man-dies-from-an-unusual-lung-cancer-spread-from-another-person/articleshow/117176600.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What happens to your body if you eat raw onions every day? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What Happens to Your Body If You Eat Raw Onions Every Day?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/onionsss.jpg?w=640" alt="onions" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>The sulfur compounds, quercetin and the mineral chromium found in onions improve insulin sensitivity (Source: Freepik)</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the health benefits and possible risks of consuming raw onions daily, highlighting their effect on insulin sensitivity and gut health, as well as their blood-thinning properties.</p>
<ul>
<li>Onions are rich in sulfur compounds and quercetin, which are beneficial antioxidants.</li>
<li>They help improve insulin sensitivity and protect heart health.</li>
<li>Regular consumption can aid gut health due to their fiber content.</li>
<li>Potential digestive discomfort, such as gas or bloating, may occur for some individuals.</li>
<li>Blood thinning properties make them beneficial but caution is advised for those on medication.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Eating onions with lemon juice and black pepper was a daily routine for me, and I noticed my immune system getting so much better.” – Vriti Srivastav, holistic dietitian</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while raw onions offer numerous health benefits, individual tolerance varies, and moderation is key.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/food-wine/what-happens-to-your-body-if-you-eat-raw-onions-every-day-9490734/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/food-wine/what-happens-to-your-body-if-you-eat-raw-onions-every-day-9490734/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:30:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Addicted to reels? It can cause high blood pressure, hypertension, finds study - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Addicted to reels? It can cause high blood pressure, hypertension, finds study</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250112135243_MixCollage-12-Jan-2025-07-22-PM-7305.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="The study was conducted based on time spent watching reels during bedtime. (Representational image: Unsplash)" title="The study was conducted based on time spent watching reels during bedtime. (Representational image: Unsplash)" width="770" height="431" />
<figcaption>The study was conducted based on time spent watching reels during bedtime. (Representational image: Unsplash)</figcaption>
<p>Recent research indicates a correlation between watching social media reels at bedtime and hypertension among young and middle-aged individuals in China.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study surveyed 4,318 participants, revealing increased susceptibility to high blood pressure with more screen time on reels.</li>
  <li>Findings were shared by cardiologist Dr. Deepak Krishnamurthy, emphasizing reel addiction as a major health risk.</li>
  <li>The study suggests that watching reels before sleep contributes to sympathetic arousal, heightening blood pressure risks.</li>
  <li>Researchers recommend limiting screen time while maintaining a healthy lifestyle to prevent hypertension.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Apart from being a major distraction and waste of time, reel addiction is also associated with high #BloodPressure in young and middle-aged people. Time to #UnInsta!!</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the study raises awareness about the health implications of excessive screen time, especially during bedtime, highlighting the need for moderation and lifestyle adjustments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/addicted-to-reels-it-can-cause-high-blood-pressure-hypertension-finds-study-12908431.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/addicted-to-reels-it-can-cause-high-blood-pressure-hypertension-finds-study-12908431.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:53:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More children test positive for mumps in Alappuzha - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>More children test positive for mumps in Alappuzha</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Local Health Report</p><p>The Alappuzha district is currently experiencing a rise in mumps infections among school students, prompting health officials to take action.</p><ul><li>At least five students at Eramalloor and four at Punnapra have tested positive.</li><li>The total infections at Eramalloor school have risen to 28, including a previous outbreak affecting 23 students.</li><li>Schools in the area have been closed for 21 days due to the outbreak.</li><li>Surveillance and preventive measures have been intensified by health department officials.</li><li>Mumps is primarily a disease in children but can also affect adolescents and adults, causing swelling of the salivary glands.</li></ul><blockquote>Mumps is a contagious disease caused by a virus that primarily affects children but could also infect adolescents and adults.</blockquote><p>This outbreak of mumps highlights the importance of vaccination and public health measures to control infectious diseases among school-aged children.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/more-children-test-positive-for-mumps-in-alappuzha/article69091922.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/more-children-test-positive-for-mumps-in-alappuzha/article69091922.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 reasons to add dragon fruit to your diet - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxORzZVejZMNkZ4SDdsRWNZUXFFc0hBckMxNG85WlJ3a3lYR05ma1lEMXFCeFoxY2dXcmZ2czl4Mk4tYVNQYm5UUVIwTGF4NHl6QXd1bUlEWWNPUGRrX0g2ajAxUlZBRmI0QktxOTExcmhpWW9WdHVLQ0FFOF9WTGt4V2prRHg0SE5ZVDR2SE0yQTg0dnFrRDJjdW9lbE5OVTQ3Q1BIanBPUmNEMUxfTXF4M2ZvNkh5VjFNTUtycnFpeWJOTUs0VzB3UGIyS2xqZ0U0Sml2RmJKYlfSAdgBQVVfeXFMTkc2VXo2TDZGeEg3bEVjWVFxRXNIQXJDMTRvOVpSd2t5WEdOZmtZRDFxQnhaMWNnV3JmdnM5eDJOLWFTUGJuVFFSMExheDR5ekF3dW1JRFljT1Bka19INmowMVJWQUZiNEJLcTkxMXJoaVlvVnR1S0NBRThfVkxreFdqa0R4NEhOWVQ0dkhNMkE4NHZxa0QyY3VvZWxOTlU0N0NQSGpwT1JjRDFMX01xeDNmbzZIeVYxTU1LcnJxaXliTk1LNFcwd1BiMktsamdFNEppdkZiSmJX?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxORzZVejZMNkZ4SDdsRWNZUXFFc0hBckMxNG85WlJ3a3lYR05ma1lEMXFCeFoxY2dXcmZ2czl4Mk4tYVNQYm5UUVIwTGF4NHl6QXd1bUlEWWNPUGRrX0g2ajAxUlZBRmI0QktxOTExcmhpWW9WdHVLQ0FFOF9WTGt4V2prRHg0SE5ZVDR2SE0yQTg0dnFrRDJjdW9lbE5OVTQ3Q1BIanBPUmNEMUxfTXF4M2ZvNkh5VjFNTUtycnFpeWJOTUs0VzB3UGIyS2xqZ0U0Sml2RmJKYlfSAdgBQVVfeXFMTkc2VXo2TDZGeEg3bEVjWVFxRXNIQXJDMTRvOVpSd2t5WEdOZmtZRDFxQnhaMWNnV3JmdnM5eDJOLWFTUGJuVFFSMExheDR5ekF3dW1JRFljT1Bka19INmowMVJWQUZiNEJLcTkxMXJoaVlvVnR1S0NBRThfVkxreFdqa0R4NEhOWVQ0dkhNMkE4NHZxa0QyY3VvZWxOTlU0N0NQSGpwT1JjRDFMX01xeDNmbzZIeVYxTU1LcnJxaXliTk1LNFcwd1BiMktsamdFNEppdkZiSmJX?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ice Baths for Stress: New research says cold water could sharpen your mind and improve sleep - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ice Baths for Stress: New research says cold water could sharpen your mind and improve sleep</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date not provided<br><strong>Source:</strong> Source not provided</p>
<p>This article explores the potential benefits of ice baths on mental sharpness and sleep quality based on new research findings.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Recent studies suggest that cold water exposure may have positive effects on cognitive function.</li>
  <li>Ice baths are gaining popularity among individuals seeking to improve their sleep patterns.</li>
  <li>Research indicates that cold water therapy could enhance resilience to stress.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Cold exposure has been linked to improved mood and cognitive clarity."</blockquote>
<p>The findings suggest that incorporating ice baths into one's routine might not only be beneficial for physical recovery but also for mental health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/ice-baths-for-stress-new-research-says-cold-water-could-sharpen-your-mind-and-improve-sleep/articleshow/117174565.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/ice-baths-for-stress-new-research-says-cold-water-could-sharpen-your-mind-and-improve-sleep/articleshow/117174565.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[14,700 confirmed mpox cases reported in 2024 in Africa: WHO - Yes Punjab]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>14,700 confirmed mpox cases reported in 2024 in Africa: WHO</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Yes Punjab News</p>
<p>About 14,700 confirmed mpox cases, including 66 deaths, were reported in 20 African countries from January 2024 to January 5, 2025, the World Health Organization (WHO) said.</p>
<ul>
<li>The confirmed cases represent only a subset of suspected cases, with many remaining untested due to limited diagnostic capacity.</li>
<li>The outbreak is driven by multiple clades of the virus, especially the Clade Ib variant, which is spreading predominantly in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC).</li>
<li>Imported mpox cases from travel have been detected outside Africa, primarily among adults who traveled during their incubation periods.</li>
<li>The ongoing outbreak was declared a public health emergency of continental security by the Africa CDC in mid-August 2024.</li>
<li>The WHO activated its highest level of global alert for mpox, marking the second time in two years.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We urge member states to sustain and strengthen mpox surveillance to improve case detection and reporting.” - WHO</blockquote>
<p>Mpox, also known as monkeypox, is a rare viral disease that spreads through body fluids, respiratory droplets, and contaminated materials, causing symptoms like fever and rash.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://yespunjab.com/14700-confirmed-mpox-cases-reported-in-2024-in-africa-who/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://yespunjab.com/14700-confirmed-mpox-cases-reported-in-2024-in-africa-who/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:34:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fibre may help protect your gut from overgrowth of harmful bugs: Study - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fibre May Protect Gut Health Against Harmful Bacteria: New Study</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> (Date not provided), <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/fibre-2.jpg" alt="Future research will integrate additional tools, such as metabolomics (studying chemicals microbes produce) and transcriptomics (studying how genes are activated), to create a clearer picture of how the gut ecosystem works for our health benefit." />
<figcaption>Image Credit: Freepik</figcaption>
<p>This new study reveals how a healthy gut environment, influenced by diet, can inhibit harmful bacteria such as Enterobacteriaceae, offering insights into gut health management.</p>
<ul>
<li>The study analyzed over 12,000 stool samples globally, indicating a strong link between gut microbiome composition and the presence of harmful bacteria.</li>
<li>Fatty acids produced by bacteria like Faecalibacterium are crucial in preventing the overgrowth of harmful microbes.</li>
<li>Co-colonisers of harmful bacteria demonstrate adaptability, suggesting that gut conditions play a significant role in bacterial survival.</li>
<li>Findings may lead to alternative methods for preventing infections without antibiotics by promoting beneficial bacteria instead.</li>
<li>The research highlights the need for further studies on global microbiome diversity and its implications for health.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Instead of killing harmful bacteria directly, we could boost the co-excluders or create diets that support their growth.”</blockquote>
<p>This research underscores the importance of dietary fibres in maintaining gut health and could pave the way for new treatments targeting harmful bacteria.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/fibre-may-help-protect-your-gut-from-overgrowth-of-harmful-bugs-study-9774693/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/fibre-may-help-protect-your-gut-from-overgrowth-of-harmful-bugs-study-9774693/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:30:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases in northern China declining, says country's health official - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV cases in northern China declining, says country's health official</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p> <figure> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/HMPV_1736679171766_1736679172042.jpg" alt="Wang Liping, second left, a researcher for the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention speaks during a press briefing in Beijing, Sunday, Jan. 12, 2025.(AP)" title="Wang Liping, second left, a researcher for the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention speaks during a press briefing in Beijing, Sunday, Jan. 12, 2025.(AP)"> <figcaption>Wang Liping, second left, a researcher for the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention speaks during a press briefing in Beijing, Sunday, Jan. 12, 2025.(AP)</figcaption> </figure> <p>The Chinese health authorities have reported a decline in human metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases, alleviating concerns amid a global focus on respiratory illnesses.</p> <ul> <li>HMPV is a frequent respiratory virus causing mild symptoms similar to a cold.</li> <li>China stated recent increases in case detection were due to improved detection methods, not a new surge of the virus.</li> <li>Research indicates that many adults have immunity, but the virus is more severe in infants or immunocompromised individuals.</li> <li>Reports of hospitals being overwhelmed have not been verified; WHO noted no unusual outbreaks.</li> <li>No vaccines or specific treatments are available for HMPV.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“At present, the rate of positive cases in human metapneumovirus detection is fluctuating, and the rate of positive cases in northern provinces is declining,” - Wang Liping.</blockquote> <p>Overall, the situation appears to be under control, with no significant shortages of medical resources reported.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/hmpv-cases-in-northern-china-declining-says-countrys-health-official-101736677964239.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/hmpv-cases-in-northern-china-declining-says-countrys-health-official-101736677964239.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:28:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>