<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:22:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:22:43 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Annual malaria cases at 2 mn in 2023, down 97% since 1947: Health ministry - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Annual malaria cases at 2 mn in 2023, down 97% since 1947: Health ministry</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> October 2023  <strong>Source:</strong> Ministry of Health and Family Welfare</p>
<p>India has made significant strides towards eradicating malaria, reducing annual cases to 2 million in 2023 from 7.5 crore in 1947, according to the latest report from the Health Ministry.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Cases have fallen from 11,69,261 in 2015 to 2,27,564 in 2023, and deaths reduced from 384 to just 83.</li>
  <li>24 states and UTs are categorized as having a low malaria burden (Category 1) by 2023.</li>
  <li>India exited from WHO's High Burden to High Impact group in 2024.</li>
  <li>Projects like Integrated Vector Management have successfully disrupted the transmission cycle.</li>
  <li>Community engagement and healthcare integration have strengthened malaria prevention efforts.</li>
  <li>India aims to eliminate malaria by 2030 with a significant focus on targeted interventions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"India’s commitment to capacity building and research has also been a cornerstone of its success." - Ministry of Health</blockquote>
<p>The substantial decrease in malaria cases over the decades showcases India's successful public health interventions and the determination to achieve a malaria-free status by 2030.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/annual-malaria-cases-at-2-mn-in-2023-down-97-since-1947-health-ministry-124122500665_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/annual-malaria-cases-at-2-mn-in-2023-down-97-since-1947-health-ministry-124122500665_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:02:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dinga Dinga Virus Raises Global Health Concerns in Uganda - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dinga Dinga Virus Raises Global Health Concerns in Uganda</h1>
<p><strong>Updated: Wednesday, December 25, 2024, 21:31 [IST]</strong></p>
<img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2024/12/dinga-dinga-virus-jpg-1735141964058_1735141965413-600x338.jpg" alt="Dinga Dinga Virus" width="600" height="338">
<figcaption>Dinga Dinga Virus</figcaption>
<p>A new virus, identified as 'Dinga Dinga,' has emerged in Uganda, raising alarms similar to those experienced during the coronavirus pandemic. Preliminary reports indicate it is particularly affecting women and teenage girls, with approximately 300 cases reported in the Bandibugyo district.</p>
<ul>
<li>The United Nations warns of a potential epidemic linked to the Dinga Dinga virus.</li>
<li>Symptoms include fever and uncontrollable shivering, with behavior reported to resemble dancing in affected individuals.</li>
<li>There is an ongoing investigation into the transmission modes and the development of a cure.</li>
<li>The outbreak in Uganda coincides with a viral outbreak in the Democratic Republic of Congo, further complicating health challenges in the region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The importance of international cooperation and preparedness in the face of such unpredictable health crises cannot be overstated.”</blockquote>
<p>Health authorities are urging people to seek medical attention if they exhibit symptoms and are emphasizing the infectious nature of this new virus.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/international/dinga-dinga-virus-raises-global-health-concerns-in-uganda-011-4025855.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/international/dinga-dinga-virus-raises-global-health-concerns-in-uganda-011-4025855.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:01:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three Red Flag Signs of Diabetes You May Spot During Christmas Celebration; Easy Ways to Slash the Risk - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Three Red Flag Signs of Diabetes You May Spot During Christmas Celebration; Easy Ways to Slash the Risk</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116659494,thumbsize-39496,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116659494.jpg" alt="Three Red Flag Signs of Diabetes You May Spot During Christmas Celebration" title="Three Red Flag Signs of Diabetes You May Spot During Christmas Celebration">
<figcaption>Three Red Flag Signs of Diabetes</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the risks of diabetes during the busy holiday season and highlights key symptoms to look for, along with tips for prevention.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Around 537 million people globally are living with diabetes.</li>
  <li>Christmas indulgence can cause blood sugar levels to rise.</li>
  <li>Three typical symptoms of diabetes are polydipsia (excessive thirst), polyuria (increased urination), and blurred vision.</li>
  <li>Preventive measures include maintaining a low-carb diet, exercising regularly, and staying hydrated.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Over the Christmas period there are lots of events during which people will overindulge.” - Dr. Adam Staten</blockquote>
<p>Overall, it’s crucial to monitor health especially during festive seasons when lifestyle changes can lead to health risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/health/three-red-flag-signs-of-diabetes-you-may-spot-during-christmas-celebration-easy-ways-to-slash-the-risk-article-116657649</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/health/three-red-flag-signs-of-diabetes-you-may-spot-during-christmas-celebration-easy-ways-to-slash-the-risk-article-116657649</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists develop scan that unravels secrets of lung function - Ahmedabad Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxObVI1MGV6blVlSGJBdjVRTnVpVVdTWVowZGhqd1ZYbWNVT3kzclFvRVZzR25lYm9EZzF4cl9NR29sTTFvUjJfczNpdmZmMUVlRm9HcndTOFVJU1pLdmVSNG4wNGxSNDNFUUx4NXkyNnNmWjVieEpPM2hsdHRZdGVBRTZ3ZlpES01kbjhUeE0zUEtjRHh3MDVzalcwWU1ZczBnaWhoeWpYWXM2ZHE5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxObVI1MGV6blVlSGJBdjVRTnVpVVdTWVowZGhqd1ZYbWNVT3kzclFvRVZzR25lYm9EZzF4cl9NR29sTTFvUjJfczNpdmZmMUVlRm9HcndTOFVJU1pLdmVSNG4wNGxSNDNFUUx4NXkyNnNmWjVieEpPM2hsdHRZdGVBRTZ3ZlpES01kbjhUeE0zUEtjRHh3MDVzalcwWU1ZczBnaWhoeWpYWXM2ZHE5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:08:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Malaria cases, deaths drop significantly by 80 pc from 2015-2023: Centre By IANS - Investing.com India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQR296X2VCYllkR0JVZjZ3QU1JcUN5UGk2ZUZ1UnV0TXFDZ2h3bVJmNE44S1dqaDRnZDFEMzRtdVhMTkxvLVYtZ3pvVk9ld0M5N05YaDJ1eW1QTmxJSW1kNzRweU10M2ZQc0drRzEwUHBTWnBKZUJ0Tm12a19ZeE9YY0ozT01QOTJDQWZ4VEMxS3R2MlcweGlraTN1ZU1jX3NIbXZ3UWVCNFBzS3N3aFlLME5CQ3FTbU4zbU1LOQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQR296X2VCYllkR0JVZjZ3QU1JcUN5UGk2ZUZ1UnV0TXFDZ2h3bVJmNE44S1dqaDRnZDFEMzRtdVhMTkxvLVYtZ3pvVk9ld0M5N05YaDJ1eW1QTmxJSW1kNzRweU10M2ZQc0drRzEwUHBTWnBKZUJ0Tm12a19ZeE9YY0ozT01QOTJDQWZ4VEMxS3R2MlcweGlraTN1ZU1jX3NIbXZ3UWVCNFBzS3N3aFlLME5CQ3FTbU4zbU1LOQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:48:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Ingredients That Can Help Lower Sugar Spike During Christmas Festivities - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Ingredients That Can Help Lower Sugar Spike During Christmas Festivities</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p>
<img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Cinnamon-And-Ginger.webp?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=710&amp;h=467" alt="Cinnamon And Ginger">
<figcaption>Cinnamon And Ginger</figcaption>
<p>You can confidently navigate the holiday season without compromising your health by effortlessly incorporating these health-boosting ingredients into your festive meals.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cinnamon And Ginger:</strong> Regulate blood sugar levels while enhancing festive meals.</li>
<li><strong>Turmeric And Apple Cider Vinegar:</strong> Improve insulin sensitivity and reduce inflammation.</li>
<li><strong>Nuts And Legumes:</strong> Rich in healthy fats and fiber to stabilize blood sugar.</li>
<li><strong>Leafy Greens And Chia Seeds:</strong> Packed with nutrients that help slow digestion.</li>
<li><strong>Berries And Dark Chocolate:</strong> Source of antioxidants to control sugar spikes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Cinnamon and ginger are not just delicious additions to meals. They also regulate blood sugar levels.”</blockquote>
<p>These ingredients provide delicious and healthy options for your holiday meals, allowing you to enjoy the festivities without worrying about sugar spikes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/photo-gallery/ingredients-that-can-help-lower-sugar-spike-during-christmas-festivities-1166435/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/photo-gallery/ingredients-that-can-help-lower-sugar-spike-during-christmas-festivities-1166435/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:20:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parkinson’s patients have a surprising taste for mayonnaise and olive oil, study reveals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parkinson’s Patients Have a Surprising Taste for Mayonnaise and Olive Oil, Study Reveals</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This article discusses a study that uncovers surprising preferences in taste among Parkinson’s patients, highlighting their inclination towards mayonnaise and olive oil.</p><ul><li>Study reveals specific food preferences among Parkinson's patients.</li><li>Focus on the surprising popularity of mayonnaise and olive oil.</li><li>Potential implications for dietary recommendations for patients.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our findings can help improve the quality of life by tailoring dietary options to these patients.”</blockquote><p>This study sheds light on the nuanced dietary preferences of those with Parkinson’s, suggesting that understanding these tastes can optimize their nutrition and health outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/parkinsons-patients-have-a-surprising-taste-for-mayonnaise-and-olive-oil-study-reveals/articleshow/116656483.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/parkinsons-patients-have-a-surprising-taste-for-mayonnaise-and-olive-oil-study-reveals/articleshow/116656483.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mpox: Belgium Detects First Case Of Clade 1b Strain; WHO Tags It As 'Especially Concerning' - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mpox: Belgium Detects First Case Of Clade 1b Strain; WHO Tags It As 'Especially Concerning'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p><figure><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/mpox-virus-1.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="Mpox: Belgium Detects First Case Of Clade 1b Strain; WHO Tags It As 'Especially Concerning'" width="900" height="375"><figcaption>Mpox: Belgium Detects First Case Of Clade 1b Strain; WHO Tags It As 'Especially Concerning'</figcaption></figure><p>Mpox continues to be a global concern with Belgium reporting its first case of the Clade 1b strain, marking it as the eighth non-African country to do so. The WHO has noted the rapid spread linked to sexual contact.</p><ul><li>Belgium reports first case of Clade 1b strain of mpox.</li><li>The strain is spreading faster through sexual contact, not animal to human transmission.</li><li>Other detected countries include Canada, Germany, Sweden, Thailand, the UK, and the US.</li><li>Initially emerged in the DRC, now spreading among young adults and potentially children.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is spreading among young adults via close physical contact, often sexual contact,” WHO stated.</blockquote><p>While mpox can be transmitted from animals, recent outbreaks suggest human-to-human contact is a major factor in its spread, particularly through sexual activities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/mpox-belgium-detects-first-case-of-clade-1b-strain-who-tags-it-as-especially-concerning-1166586/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/mpox-belgium-detects-first-case-of-clade-1b-strain-who-tags-it-as-especially-concerning-1166586/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brain chemicals work together in controlling eating, says study - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPdkh1Rm5ONGloRmVpdFVnd0hSN2NyOHRSVTc5amtNRE5QdjFiRVJyOWwyVkJtR1JrR1lkQ29YRFdCei1SRmx5c0xmSHBMeVI4ZDJ4MWRPZzVTT0k4dzJkT01LS3JDakNVUW1TQVR2TmJIZmlXT256UkY5bFlFaFlIOXBES1Ixa0FmMEtZdVh1QmdpWjQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPdkh1Rm5ONGloRmVpdFVnd0hSN2NyOHRSVTc5amtNRE5QdjFiRVJyOWwyVkJtR1JrR1lkQ29YRFdCei1SRmx5c0xmSHBMeVI4ZDJ4MWRPZzVTT0k4dzJkT01LS3JDakNVUW1TQVR2TmJIZmlXT256UkY5bFlFaFlIOXBES1Ixa0FmMEtZdVh1QmdpWjQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:31:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drinking tea and cancer can lower the risk of some cancers: Report - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/entertainment/lifestyle/news-drinking-tea-and-cancer-can-lower-the-risk-of-some-cancers-report-786742</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/entertainment/lifestyle/news-drinking-tea-and-cancer-can-lower-the-risk-of-some-cancers-report-786742</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Essential steps to combat antibiotic resistance - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Essential Steps to Combat Antibiotic Resistance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://indianexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1_83cd03.jpg" width="720" alt="" height="1280" layout="responsive"><figcaption>Image illustrating the campaign against antibiotic resistance.</figcaption><p>This article presents critical steps for individuals to take in order to combat the growing issue of antibiotic resistance. It emphasizes responsible antibiotic use and preventive measures to reduce infection rates.</p><ul><li>Only take antibiotics when prescribed by a healthcare professional and complete the full course of treatment.</li><li>Antibiotics are ineffective against viruses; avoid using them for viral infections such as the common cold or flu.</li><li>Good hygiene practices can help prevent infections, thereby reducing the need for antibiotics.</li><li>Stay up-to-date with vaccinations to prevent infections that may require antibiotic treatment.</li><li>Support food sources that minimize excessive antibiotic use in animal feed.</li><li>Fighting antibiotic resistance requires funding for international research and improved infection control measures.</li></ul><blockquote>"Fighting antibiotic resistance requires funding international programmes and research projects for improved infection control, antibiotic management, and the creation of novel therapies."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, responsible antibiotic use and preventive health measures are essential to combating antibiotic resistance, which poses a significant threat to public health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/web-stories/wellness/essential-steps-to-combat-antibiotic-resistance/9702341/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/web-stories/wellness/essential-steps-to-combat-antibiotic-resistance/9702341/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:15:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Healthy Holiday Eating Tips: 7 Ways To Enjoy Festive Meals While Making Healthier Choices - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Healthy Holiday Eating Tips: 7 Ways To Enjoy Festive Meals While Making Healthier Choices</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Healthy-Holiday-Eating-Tips-1.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=710&amp;h=467" alt="Health Holiday Eating Tips"><figcaption>Holiday Season Healthy Eating Tips</figcaption><p>The holiday season is all about indulging in your favourite festive foods while celebrating with friends and family. The key is to eat in moderation and stay healthy despite the variety of foods available.</p><ul><li>Focus on the social aspect of festive meals.</li><li>Plan ahead by consuming light, healthy snacks before big meals.</li><li>Prioritise whole, unprocessed foods.</li><li>Be mindful of portion sizes; use smaller plates.</li><li>Make healthier switches with ingredients.</li><li>Stay hydrated to control hunger.</li><li>Savour your food by eating slowly and mindfully.</li><li>Don't feel guilty about enjoying festive treats in moderation.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/photo-gallery/healthy-holiday-eating-tips-7-ways-to-enjoy-festive-meals-while-making-healthier-choices-1166639/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/photo-gallery/healthy-holiday-eating-tips-7-ways-to-enjoy-festive-meals-while-making-healthier-choices-1166639/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:43:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Homemade Ginger Cough Drops In 10 Mins - You Just Need 2 Ingredients - NDTV Food]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Homemade Ginger Cough Drops In 10 Mins - You Just Need 2 Ingredients</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Food</p><p>When the winter chill sets in and coughs and sore throats become an unwelcome companion, we often turn to store-bought remedies. But what if you could whip up a natural, chemical-free alternative right at home in just 10 minutes? Chef Neha Deepak Shah recently shared a simple recipe for homemade ginger cough drops on Instagram, and it's a game-changer.</p><img src='https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCyMtwxC6IJ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading' alt='Homemade Ginger Cough Drops'><figcaption>Homemade Ginger Cough Drops</figcaption><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Ingredients: 1 cup jaggery, 1/4 cup ginger juice.</li><li>Jaggery soothes throat irritation while ginger juice combats inflammation.</li><li>Cooking involves combining ingredients, heating, and testing for consistency.</li><li>Cough drops can be stored in an airtight container for weeks.</li></ul><blockquote>Chef Neha's special tip: Always use silicone or metal moulds to set the cough drops, as they withstand high heat.</blockquote><p>These ginger cough drops are a healthier alternative to store-bought options, being free from processed sugar and preservatives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://food.ndtv.com/food-drinks/homemade-ginger-cough-drops-in-10-mins-you-just-need-2-ingredients-7325277</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://food.ndtv.com/food-drinks/homemade-ginger-cough-drops-in-10-mins-you-just-need-2-ingredients-7325277</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:43:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blood sugar control is possible with diet, novel drugs and tech: What are takeaways from 2024? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Blood sugar control is possible with diet, novel drugs and tech: What are takeaways from 2024?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This year has witnessed transformative advancements in diabetes management, focusing on dietary habits and innovative technologies for better blood sugar control.</p><ul><li>Advancements in wearable devices allow real-time glucose monitoring.</li><li>Research on traditional diets shows potential benefits in managing diabetes risks.</li><li>New drug therapies aim to enhance insulin sensitivity.</li><li>Genetic studies may lead to personalized treatment plans for diabetes patients.</li><li>Mental health support is increasingly recognized for young Type 1 diabetes patients.</li><li>Urban lifestyle factors contribute to Type 2 diabetes prevalence, especially in India.</li><li>Innovations like closed-loop systems and smart insulin pumps are revolutionizing management of diabetes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Urbanization, sedentary habits, air pollution, stress, and unhealthy diets are key triggers for Type 2 diabetes spiralling in India.”</blockquote><p>Overall, 2024 signifies a pivotal year for diabetes management, combining dietary wisdom with modern technology to improve patient outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/blood-sugar-control-diet-novel-drugs-tech-takeaways-2024-9743834/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/blood-sugar-control-diet-novel-drugs-tech-takeaways-2024-9743834/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:39:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5-Minute Morning Yoga Routine To Calm The Mind - HerZindagi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5-Minute Morning Yoga Routine To Calm The Mind</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> HerZindagi</p><img src="https://images.herzindagi.info/webstories/37731/1-1735040007.webp" alt="Yoga Routine Image"><figcaption>Image Credit: canva</figcaption><p>Mornings can often feel rushed and chaotic, leaving little room to prepare your mind for the day ahead. Here is a five-minute morning yoga routine to calm your mind. Tap to read!</p><ul><li><h2>Padmasana</h2><p>Calms the mind and increases concentration.</p></li><li><h2>Halasana</h2><p>Increases blood circulation to the brain and activates brain function.</p></li><li><h2>Pranayama</h2><p>A breathing exercise that enhances mental clarity and reduces stress.</p></li><li><h2>Vrikshasana</h2><p>Improves mental stability and concentration.</p></li><li><h2>Surya Namaskar</h2><p>Improves posture, flexibility, and overall health.</p></li><li><h2>Tadasana</h2><p>Strengthens the nervous system and centers focus on awareness.</p></li></ul><blockquote>“This information has been taken from the famous YouTube channel beyoutifulliving. The channel has more than twelve thousand subscribers.”</blockquote><p>If you liked the story, then kindly share and spread the love. Follow HerZindagi for more updates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.herzindagi.com/web-stories/health/morning-yoga-routine-to-calm-the-mind-ws-37731</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.herzindagi.com/web-stories/health/morning-yoga-routine-to-calm-the-mind-ws-37731</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Long-Term Exposure to Air Pollution Linked to Blood Clots - Cancer Health Treatment News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Long-Term Exposure to Air Pollution Linked to Blood Clots</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> National Institutes of Health</p><img src='https://cdn.poz.com/153922_iStock-1141520118.jpg_ff3361e9-2aca-4d88-9e2d-0402f7704dc9.jpg' alt='Ecological catastrophy smokestacks billowing smoke'><figcaption>Ecological catastrophy smokestacks billowing smoke</figcaption><p>Air pollution has long been associated with inflammation and various diseases. A recent study reveals a significant link between long-term air pollution exposure and increased risks for blood clots.</p><ul><li>A study involving 6,651 U.S. adults over 17 years uncovered a correlation between air pollution and venous thromboembolism (VTE).</li><li>Approximately 3.7% of participants developed blood clots requiring hospital care.</li><li>Increased exposure to specific air pollutants was linked to a risk increase of 39% to over 200% for developing VTE.</li><li>VTE can have serious consequences, including complications and death.</li></ul><blockquote>“The likelihood of this outcome was linked to a risk increase based on long-term exposure to three different types of air pollutants.”</blockquote><p>This study highlights the importance of air quality and its implications for cardiovascular health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cancerhealth.com/article/longterm-exposure-air-pollution-linked-blood-clots</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cancerhealth.com/article/longterm-exposure-air-pollution-linked-blood-clots</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:58:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 yoga asanas to control high uric acid levels - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Yoga Asanas to Control High Uric Acid Levels</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 25, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> DNA</p><img src="https://images1.dnaindia.com/images/DNA-EN/900x1600/2024/12/24/1735035728002_pexelsphoto8244383.webp" alt="7 yoga asanas to control high uric acid levels"><figcaption>7 yoga asanas to control high uric acid levels</figcaption><p>High levels of uric acid can impact general health by causing diabetes and joint pain. Yoga is a useful tool for managing it. Here are 7 asanas to reduce uric acid and promote better well-being.</p><ul><li>Ardha Matsyendrasana - Improves blood circulation and stimulates the kidneys.</li><li>Bhujangasana (Cobra Pose) - Enhances blood circulation and promotes kidney function.</li><li>Dhanurasana (Bow Pose) - Detoxifies and lowers uric acid while increasing digestion.</li><li>Pavanmuktasana (Wind-Relieving Pose) - Promotes improved kidney function and reduces gas.</li><li>Savasana (Death Pose) - Supports relaxation and reduces inflammation.</li><li>Trikonasana (Triangle Pose) - Boosts kidneys and improves detoxification.</li><li>Halasana (Plow Pose) - Aids in the removal of toxins and lowers uric acid levels.</li></ul><blockquote>This information is not DNA's opinion but obtained from media reports.</blockquote><p>Incorporating these yoga asanas into regular practice can be a helpful approach in managing high uric acid levels.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/lifestyle/7-yoga-asanas-to-control-high-uric-acid-levels-1735035545134</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/lifestyle/7-yoga-asanas-to-control-high-uric-acid-levels-1735035545134</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:30:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists develop scan that unravels secrets of lung function - Gujarat Samachar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Develop Scan that Unravels Secrets of Lung Function</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Publication Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Gujarat Samachar Digital</p><img src="https://static.gujaratsamachar.com/content_image/content_image_1e22d8b6-f154-4331-b055-757b7aede220.jpeg" alt="Lung Scan Image"><figcaption>New scanning method for lung function</figcaption><p>A team of scientists has developed a new method of scanning lungs that reveals the effects of treatment on lung function in real time, particularly for lung transplants.</p><ul><li>The scan allows visualization of air movement in and out of the lungs for various lung conditions.</li><li>Researchers from Newcastle University demonstrated the scan's effectiveness in patients with asthma, COPD, and post-lung transplant.</li><li>Professor Andrew Fisher emphasized the scan's potential to detect issues in transplanted lungs earlier than traditional tests.</li><li>The method utilizes a special gas, perfluoropropane, that is detectable in MRI scans.</li><li>This could improve clinical trials and management of lung diseases.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our scans show where there is patchy ventilation in patients with lung disease...” - Professor Pete Thelwall</blockquote><p>The advancement in scanning technology presents a promising future for lung disease management and emphasizes the importance of early intervention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://english.gujaratsamachar.com/news/science-technology/scientists-develop-scan-that-unravels-secrets-of-lung-function</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://english.gujaratsamachar.com/news/science-technology/scientists-develop-scan-that-unravels-secrets-of-lung-function</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:12:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brain map clarifies neuronal connectivity behind motor function: Study - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Brain Map Clarifies Neuronal Connectivity Behind Motor Function</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 25, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/brain_1735115474858_1735115475085.jpg" alt="Know how the brain communicates with the spine, through this study." title="Know how the brain communicates with the spine, through this study."><figcaption>Know how the brain communicates with the spine, through this study.</figcaption></figure><p>This study sheds light on the nervous system's physical layout and how the brain communicates with the spinal cord, enhancing our understanding of motor function.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Muscle movement occurs through brain signals sent to motor neurons, often via spinal interneurons.</li><li>Researchers at St. Jude Children's Research Hospital created a whole-brain atlas to illustrate direct brain inputs to V1 interneurons, essential for movement.</li><li>The atlas provides a basis for deeper insights into neural communication and the nervous system's organization.</li><li>Inhibiting a modified rabies virus helped trace neuronal circuits linking the brain to the spinal cord.</li><li>The research emphasizes the importance of understanding how different brain regions influence motor neuron activity.</li></ul><blockquote>“Defining the cellular targets of descending motor systems is fundamental to understanding neural control of movement and behavior.” - Jay Bikoff, PhD</blockquote><p>The findings from this study will serve as a valuable resource for future research in the field of neurobiology, ultimately improving our grasp on movement control.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/brain-map-clarifies-neuronal-connectivity-behind-motor-function-study-101735115296226.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/brain-map-clarifies-neuronal-connectivity-behind-motor-function-study-101735115296226.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:34:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Healthy Kidney Signs: 4 Expert-Backed Tips from a Nephrologist to Manage Chronic Kidney Disease - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Healthy Kidney Signs: 4 Expert-Backed Tips from a Nephrologist to Manage Chronic Kidney Disease</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p><figure><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Healthy-Kidney-Signs-4-Expert-Backed-Tips-from-a-Nephrologist-to-Manage-Chronic-Kidney-Disease.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="Healthy Kidney Signs: 4 Expert-Backed Tips from a Nephrologist to Manage Chronic Kidney Disease" width="900" height="375"><figcaption>Healthy Kidney Signs: 4 Expert-Backed Tips from a Nephrologist to Manage Chronic Kidney Disease</figcaption></figure><p>Chronic Kidney Disease (CKD) is a serious health issue affecting millions globally. The article provides four expert-backed tips for managing and maintaining kidney health effectively.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Manage Blood Pressure: Keep your blood pressure below 140/90 mm Hg through a low sodium diet, quitting smoking, moderating alcohol intake, and regular exercise.</li><li>Eat a Healthy Diet: Focus on fruits, vegetables, whole grains, lean proteins, and limit unhealthy fats and sugars.</li><li>Stay Active: Aim for at least 30 minutes of physical activity most days.</li><li>Manage Blood Sugar: Maintain healthy blood sugar levels if diabetic and consult your doctor before taking OTC medications that may harm kidneys.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes:</h2><blockquote>“By following these simple tips, you can improve your kidney health and overall quality of life.”</blockquote><p>This article emphasizes the importance of proactive management of CKD to prevent progression and enhance quality of life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/healthy-kidney-signs-4-expert-backed-tips-from-a-nephrologist-to-manage-chronic-kidney-disease-1166585/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/healthy-kidney-signs-4-expert-backed-tips-from-a-nephrologist-to-manage-chronic-kidney-disease-1166585/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Health News Live December 25, 2024 : Is your daily cup of coffee a boon in disguise? Study says it can lower this risk - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPd2J4RDBFdHh4VDhUUkd4bHVhbHZaNmZ0d2JzNFZpVE1pZllWekVrUkNzbzJ0MEtyaWo2QW52Z2cwNE1Sb2J6UjQ4d1ZZVDhsU3Jfa0tfNWwyRmpkcXBvcVA1TWRkN1N2MlhjNFlSd2toZUFKSDJMZkVUcHRVbTJIWFBrNDB1YmttVEpSOGdVdGFnOVJaU2VOZFAtbnhXNDBBclluZWxsMkJsZF9NZVZnVmhn0gG3AUFVX3lxTE5WWFpwcHk1Mzh6WTZoVFd1blZWR1JUamVsVlJtT0FSTk5ILWFJb1dVcTc2OWxLWVhfVnlZT3dmQ2ctSXRzaTc0Y2pnZGlGbjdXb05FNDdyLUk1VF91RVNJdTBKU1VtSUl6Ym1uXzkxTTUwVXluSW9vQzJOYUhDMEYwc2lYcHpxcGp2WnRjc3pKcXF3VndtNlF0RDdONTJ5bmMxTURVM2toam1tN1R4cEk2eG5ZcWk1MA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPd2J4RDBFdHh4VDhUUkd4bHVhbHZaNmZ0d2JzNFZpVE1pZllWekVrUkNzbzJ0MEtyaWo2QW52Z2cwNE1Sb2J6UjQ4d1ZZVDhsU3Jfa0tfNWwyRmpkcXBvcVA1TWRkN1N2MlhjNFlSd2toZUFKSDJMZkVUcHRVbTJIWFBrNDB1YmttVEpSOGdVdGFnOVJaU2VOZFAtbnhXNDBBclluZWxsMkJsZF9NZVZnVmhn0gG3AUFVX3lxTE5WWFpwcHk1Mzh6WTZoVFd1blZWR1JUamVsVlJtT0FSTk5ILWFJb1dVcTc2OWxLWVhfVnlZT3dmQ2ctSXRzaTc0Y2pnZGlGbjdXb05FNDdyLUk1VF91RVNJdTBKU1VtSUl6Ym1uXzkxTTUwVXluSW9vQzJOYUhDMEYwc2lYcHpxcGp2WnRjc3pKcXF3VndtNlF0RDdONTJ5bmMxTURVM2toam1tN1R4cEk2eG5ZcWk1MA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:12:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is your daily cup of coffee a boon in disguise? Study says it can lower this risk - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is Your Daily Cup of Coffee a Boon in Disguise? Study Says It Can Lower Head and Neck Cancer Risk</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/coffee_1735112070586_1735112070868.jpg" alt="Coffee can help in protecting us from one of the most common types of cancers. (Pexels)" title="Coffee can help in protecting us from one of the most common types of cancers. (Pexels)"><figcaption>Coffee can help in protecting us from one of the most common types of cancers. (Pexels)</figcaption></figure><p>A recent study suggests that drinking more than four cups of coffee daily may lower the risk of head and neck cancer by at least 17%. The research was led by Yuan-Chin Amy Lee, PhD, from the University of Utah School of Medicine.</p><ul><li>The study involved data from 9,548 head and neck cancer patients and 15,783 control subjects.</li><li>Heavy coffee drinkers had a 30% lower risk of oral cavity cancer and a 22% lower risk of throat cancer.</li><li>Even decaffeinated coffee drinkers observed a 25% lower risk of oral cavity cancer.</li><li>Tea drinkers also showed a 29% lower risk of hypopharyngeal cancer.</li></ul><blockquote>“While there has been prior research on coffee and tea consumption and reduced risk of cancer, this study highlighted their varying effects with different sub-sites of head and neck cancer.” – Yuan-Chin Amy Lee, PhD</blockquote><p>This study opens a new understanding of the protective effects of coffee and tea against certain cancers, urging further research in this vital area.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/is-your-daily-cup-of-coffee-a-boon-in-disguise-study-says-it-can-lower-this-risk-101735111989809.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/is-your-daily-cup-of-coffee-a-boon-in-disguise-study-says-it-can-lower-this-risk-101735111989809.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:12:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rise in Number of Bowel Cancer Patients Under Age 50 - SBS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxQQ2RYdmZLN0RIcHZldUU5OE1Hc1AtUmdLQ2pkNDJDUWZlaUhfeWZub0xJQ19JRTdHNzlMdDVGVEdIbktWdzhKNGlJWEZwRFNqM2JzUGhlVFE1Q0pvR01OQmdNQWhVOWFHVHFqUE11MVE2LUd3ZzlLZnhTQlZCOGptazQtbFlXYWpyVDdGcUp1Znpib1NKRWIyZnp0TmcwTlJZbVgzdUxrUGEzeHd2MG5NOHd5UTZwZTN5VnhMeXJ2bG9uZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxQQ2RYdmZLN0RIcHZldUU5OE1Hc1AtUmdLQ2pkNDJDUWZlaUhfeWZub0xJQ19JRTdHNzlMdDVGVEdIbktWdzhKNGlJWEZwRFNqM2JzUGhlVFE1Q0pvR01OQmdNQWhVOWFHVHFqUE11MVE2LUd3ZzlLZnhTQlZCOGptazQtbFlXYWpyVDdGcUp1Znpib1NKRWIyZnp0TmcwTlJZbVgzdUxrUGEzeHd2MG5NOHd5UTZwZTN5VnhMeXJ2bG9uZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 07:36:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honey Singh’s battle with bipolar disorder: How to spot symptoms, get the right therapy and sleep well - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Honey Singh’s battle with bipolar disorder: How to spot symptoms, get the right therapy and sleep well</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/honey-singh-1.jpg?w=640" alt="Honey Singh, Bipolar Disorder" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>People with bipolar disorder often have irregular biological clocks, leading to erratic sleep-wake cycles. Lack of sleep can trigger manic episodes. (File Image)</figcaption><p>Rapper Honey Singh recently opened up about his struggles with bipolar disorder, which impacted his music career. After a long journey, he was diagnosed with the condition that was often misattributed to mood swings.</p><ul><li>Challenges in diagnosing bipolar disorder often lead to misconceptions about mood swings being caused by work pressure.</li><li>Symptoms include severe mood swings, impulsive behavior, and paranoid thoughts.</li><li>Genetic factors play a considerable role in the onset of bipolar disorder.</li><li>Effective treatment involves mood stabilizers, antipsychotics, and Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT).</li><li>Peer support and monitoring apps have proven beneficial in managing the disorder.</li></ul><blockquote>“Alok reported a significant reduction in the frequency and intensity of mood swings after treatment.”</blockquote><p>Recognizing the symptoms and seeking appropriate help can significantly improve the quality of life for those affected by bipolar disorder.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/honey-singhs-battle-with-bipolar-disorder-9743632/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/honey-singhs-battle-with-bipolar-disorder-9743632/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 07:28:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[17 causes of pelvic pain in women - Health shots]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxQRHhlLXVZVFRuUWlJVGdTeGhENzdLVEswa1lRUWVSZzV1WllXQVJ5Vm5BNFhzQlpxWDRmWmlBMUVMYVNGY3c4NUI1a2JHV0JNY3MxbjdsV3k3V2dtTTBmMlA3Y05YeWJHanRlWlpWYU9DZzNGSU1vd1JWWFlaeDNqMkI5aTE3SVBJ0gGMAUFVX3lxTE8zOG8wSndBZHhNbFgwTndUR25ISVlETXVPYzRzVEJHY1lqbFl5WnlySGN5Mk5wY3R6TkVlcEI5MmxNenUzb0pVS2hqYW1NXzd3QUgwOFhLR25PZDdwUWhOQU9FNXFrT2RUQlhxRzM1REpkaXo3OW9PN3hGNUhrcVczbGtIYlJpSWFUVkVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxQRHhlLXVZVFRuUWlJVGdTeGhENzdLVEswa1lRUWVSZzV1WllXQVJ5Vm5BNFhzQlpxWDRmWmlBMUVMYVNGY3c4NUI1a2JHV0JNY3MxbjdsV3k3V2dtTTBmMlA3Y05YeWJHanRlWlpWYU9DZzNGSU1vd1JWWFlaeDNqMkI5aTE3SVBJ0gGMAUFVX3lxTE8zOG8wSndBZHhNbFgwTndUR25ISVlETXVPYzRzVEJHY1lqbFl5WnlySGN5Mk5wY3R6TkVlcEI5MmxNenUzb0pVS2hqYW1NXzd3QUgwOFhLR25PZDdwUWhOQU9FNXFrT2RUQlhxRzM1REpkaXo3OW9PN3hGNUhrcVczbGtIYlJpSWFUVkVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 07:23:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fastest individual to recite all elements of the periodic table in reverse order - India Book of Records]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOcVVKOU5RaHZ2UDZHN25sQ1JPbFZSUmZTNkhZSzU5dGxLZExnUDhGUjEzNGFLOHkxVVcxYTdKcGtLY0EyUG83OEdoaFE2VzE5UnhERnRlWm5QSDk4cEY2MzNSNkNkU2tPVkZvaGtWSFYya0liempJaGc1QnNIYkZ6S1Y0X1J5RUYwUUU5V3MteGVFeEpCSUh0UG9uUXhkSGhvbXVCZWFTc3V0YWIyTmMtVA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOcVVKOU5RaHZ2UDZHN25sQ1JPbFZSUmZTNkhZSzU5dGxLZExnUDhGUjEzNGFLOHkxVVcxYTdKcGtLY0EyUG83OEdoaFE2VzE5UnhERnRlWm5QSDk4cEY2MzNSNkNkU2tPVkZvaGtWSFYya0liempJaGc1QnNIYkZ6S1Y0X1J5RUYwUUU5V3MteGVFeEpCSUh0UG9uUXhkSGhvbXVCZWFTc3V0YWIyTmMtVA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 06:44:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hidden dangers of tea bags revealed: Scientists warn of health risks posed by huge amounts of microplastics in them - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hidden dangers of tea bags revealed: Scientists warn of health risks posed by huge amounts of microplastics in them</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 25, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/two-tea-bags-glass-tea-marble_114579-58331_1735106260262_1735106268025.jpg" alt="Commercial tea bags release millions of microplastics when in use. (Representative pic: Freepik)" title="Commercial tea bags release millions of microplastics when in use. (Representative pic: Freepik)">
<figcaption>Commercial tea bags release millions of microplastics when in use. (Representative pic: Freepik)</figcaption>
<p>A new study reveals that tea bags release billions of microplastics into hot water, raising health concerns as these particles can be absorbed into the human body. Conducted by researchers at the Autonomous University of Barcelona, the findings highlight significant risks associated with consuming tea made from commercially available tea bags.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Tea bags release millions to billions of plastic particles per infusion.</li>
  <li>Polypropylene bags can release approximately 1.2 billion particles per drop.</li>
  <li>Microplastics can enter human cells and potentially disrupt cellular functions.</li>
  <li>The study emphasizes the pervasive nature of microplastic exposure in everyday life.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We are exposed everywhere to micro-nano plastics... Something as simple as preparing a cup of tea is enough to ingest millions of nanoparticles or nanoplastics." - Ricardo Marcos Dauder</blockquote>
<p>This research underscores the importance of reevaluating the safety of commonly used tea bags and raises awareness about microplastic consumption in beverages.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/hidden-dangers-of-tea-bags-revealed-scientists-warn-of-health-risks-posed-by-huge-amounts-of-microplastics-in-them-101735105997964.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/hidden-dangers-of-tea-bags-revealed-scientists-warn-of-health-risks-posed-by-huge-amounts-of-microplastics-in-them-101735105997964.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 06:40:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 fruits you must eat with their skin on - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNcHU5bk8xM2dBWnZ6dTZzWFpjRW9scTExdTg0Q3h3dEZwZWVweGNidDFCQ2pYSkxUbGdUb3J6bDNBLThndDU5dTZZNy1rTUpDUzhrSGMtT2xBa0tmdjVCQXZ3elhCWGV6VnhaUnVKbEZmNHJoV2dfdm4yYVREUmdaMnFTcWQ0SFYtM3l5TVNIdDEzVjhjNWN4V0JtckNrcTlSU01hZW94Qk15aXYyN2dzb3VxOHFJeF8zMGdESFVfcXYwenYxZUZvUFFhQnhMX1VIR2oxSkFHSdIB1wFBVV95cUxNcHU5bk8xM2dBWnZ6dTZzWFpjRW9scTExdTg0Q3h3dEZwZWVweGNidDFCQ2pYSkxUbGdUb3J6bDNBLThndDU5dTZZNy1rTUpDUzhrSGMtT2xBa0tmdjVCQXZ3elhCWGV6VnhaUnVKbEZmNHJoV2dfdm4yYVREUmdaMnFTcWQ0SFYtM3l5TVNIdDEzVjhjNWN4V0JtckNrcTlSU01hZW94Qk15aXYyN2dzb3VxOHFJeF8zMGdESFVfcXYwenYxZUZvUFFhQnhMX1VIR2oxSkFHSQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNcHU5bk8xM2dBWnZ6dTZzWFpjRW9scTExdTg0Q3h3dEZwZWVweGNidDFCQ2pYSkxUbGdUb3J6bDNBLThndDU5dTZZNy1rTUpDUzhrSGMtT2xBa0tmdjVCQXZ3elhCWGV6VnhaUnVKbEZmNHJoV2dfdm4yYVREUmdaMnFTcWQ0SFYtM3l5TVNIdDEzVjhjNWN4V0JtckNrcTlSU01hZW94Qk15aXYyN2dzb3VxOHFJeF8zMGdESFVfcXYwenYxZUZvUFFhQnhMX1VIR2oxSkFHSdIB1wFBVV95cUxNcHU5bk8xM2dBWnZ6dTZzWFpjRW9scTExdTg0Q3h3dEZwZWVweGNidDFCQ2pYSkxUbGdUb3J6bDNBLThndDU5dTZZNy1rTUpDUzhrSGMtT2xBa0tmdjVCQXZ3elhCWGV6VnhaUnVKbEZmNHJoV2dfdm4yYVREUmdaMnFTcWQ0SFYtM3l5TVNIdDEzVjhjNWN4V0JtckNrcTlSU01hZW94Qk15aXYyN2dzb3VxOHFJeF8zMGdESFVfcXYwenYxZUZvUFFhQnhMX1VIR2oxSkFHSQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How healthy are protein bars and other 'high-protein' foods, really? - Medical News Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why Not All 'High-Protein' Food Products Are Healthy Choices</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Medical News Today</p><img src="https://media.post.rvohealth.io/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2024/12/cyclist-protein-bar-1296x728-header-1024x575.jpg" alt="close-up of cyclist eating protein bar"><figcaption>Are ‘high-protein’ food items, like protein bars, really all that healthy? A study from Spain casts doubt over their nutritive value. Image credit: Westend61/Getty Images.</figcaption><p>The article explores the findings of a study that indicates processed foods labeled as high in protein may not be as healthy as they seem, often containing excessive fat, sugar, and sodium.</p><ul><li>Processed high-protein foods are gaining popularity.</li><li>A study reveals many such foods can contain high levels of unhealthy ingredients.</li><li>Healthier protein options are available with professional guidance.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Potential clinical implications would be ensuring proper education regarding nutrition choices, [and people] choosing to carefully evaluate foods based on the whole nutrition label/facts instead of just relying on the package claims.”</p></blockquote><p>In conclusion, while protein is essential for health, consumers should be cautious and informed when choosing protein-rich products, opting for whole foods where possible.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/why-not-all-high-protein-food-products-are-good-for-you</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/why-not-all-high-protein-food-products-are-good-for-you</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 06:18:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists develop scan that unravels secrets of lung function By IANS - Investing.com India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxNaWlFUTEwNDZvRFRLVEU5Vy11RkdZQVkzWnZ0bk9uWU9sbW5MNGk1cm9qeUx4OTIyam05RTJ5MTk5TUVyRGEwRDI0c0Uyb2xqMTVpY3pXN0RLai03Tmd1WmZqSTdXYjZDME9oZTdON09UeXlzbWlCSHFsMDJtWTVjRlNMXzVQVVRHUnJPdXpTaGVWdDlkSllXd3ZObVZ2YVBLVWdfVV90bnMtQTNyT0dPSHI4MA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxNaWlFUTEwNDZvRFRLVEU5Vy11RkdZQVkzWnZ0bk9uWU9sbW5MNGk1cm9qeUx4OTIyam05RTJ5MTk5TUVyRGEwRDI0c0Uyb2xqMTVpY3pXN0RLai03Tmd1WmZqSTdXYjZDME9oZTdON09UeXlzbWlCSHFsMDJtWTVjRlNMXzVQVVRHUnJPdXpTaGVWdDlkSllXd3ZObVZ2YVBLVWdfVV90bnMtQTNyT0dPSHI4MA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 05:58:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>