<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:26:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:26:01 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why plant-based milks may not be healthy - Lokmat Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNNUpTN3A4Ylp6YnQwdXYxbzZTTVNsRWpOanU0YUpWc093NXVRRmhFZ2hsWUJvUFBPcjRRc1o2dEdyS1ZEeVRBNGtMRW9yWnRFNkNHZWFWZ2JMa0RLd2xmTGpiR2l1NV9aVlp6Z3BCMjdqVW5uZDltSkZvM1RyYW9OQ2pB0gGHAUFVX3lxTE9UUmxneWdIMVBzUXp0eDBkcGV5NGRJUklNNGRXZzV6R3V4eEpJdUhuOG1PdmNGS3dqTGFBY2FKWmlncldGMXVNTi12WW1zTDFXQ056NXc2dE5VQ3JUNk4xZW5WWFJ1eFNxeEEzSjlMRVp5WlE5VlgtWGpmT3d4cF9qUVZFeWRDVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNNUpTN3A4Ylp6YnQwdXYxbzZTTVNsRWpOanU0YUpWc093NXVRRmhFZ2hsWUJvUFBPcjRRc1o2dEdyS1ZEeVRBNGtMRW9yWnRFNkNHZWFWZ2JMa0RLd2xmTGpiR2l1NV9aVlp6Z3BCMjdqVW5uZDltSkZvM1RyYW9OQ2pB0gGHAUFVX3lxTE9UUmxneWdIMVBzUXp0eDBkcGV5NGRJUklNNGRXZzV6R3V4eEpJdUhuOG1PdmNGS3dqTGFBY2FKWmlncldGMXVNTi12WW1zTDFXQ056NXc2dE5VQ3JUNk4xZW5WWFJ1eFNxeEEzSjlMRVp5WlE5VlgtWGpmT3d4cF9qUVZFeWRDVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:54:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Northern Coalfields Limited (NCL) launches ‘CHARAK’- “Community Health - NewsRiveting]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxPY190dm52clowQnBRNmlDQjZaZnhTdjRmaGtLQjJ5dl9ISVZ6SmNYenRiMlh4Mk5VU3pHMkJFalR0eFh2UHhmUl9sLWFxQjF2SDJhcnhYM3RpLUlVTnd3NHp5TVJWeHNpWFI5UkQ1Ykp5QzRrMjdXeWRyek1NU1JKM0R0TFJLNE5tZkRYVjhZMnU2bmZu?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxPY190dm52clowQnBRNmlDQjZaZnhTdjRmaGtLQjJ5dl9ISVZ6SmNYenRiMlh4Mk5VU3pHMkJFalR0eFh2UHhmUl9sLWFxQjF2SDJhcnhYM3RpLUlVTnd3NHp5TVJWeHNpWFI5UkQ1Ykp5QzRrMjdXeWRyek1NU1JKM0R0TFJLNE5tZkRYVjhZMnU2bmZu?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:31:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to treat eczema in winter to prevent a flare-up - Health shots]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxOMVJJWUpITUdqNDFlUnc1VnNXbDlrQVY1X1p0cUIyQlZhR2JHRGRTeGFCTmdXYXFVVWR4dTZlX3lkdEtEVWxoaFQyaXFjSUtnQ19tNzFTckFPYWpNZDNmRlRoX28wR2lLSDNkQnI2ZVBObkhZaXhKSnRMSmJDbE5GStIBhAFBVV95cUxQVnNFNVhGTVpvSDF0Q0pWQVV4X0VlTkZ2ZHBnNUlteERpa1NOcnVZZEl4MGdlOHMtNVU3TFY1RmlYc2dKS3lGRktfSU5GdTZ1Zzg0TVdwTHF3UVFNQUVBTW9rX1B5bWFrRHl3M3gzS2FuUzJlc3JfWlVSeGFfVmN2RUlaQ1A?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxOMVJJWUpITUdqNDFlUnc1VnNXbDlrQVY1X1p0cUIyQlZhR2JHRGRTeGFCTmdXYXFVVWR4dTZlX3lkdEtEVWxoaFQyaXFjSUtnQ19tNzFTckFPYWpNZDNmRlRoX28wR2lLSDNkQnI2ZVBObkhZaXhKSnRMSmJDbE5GStIBhAFBVV95cUxQVnNFNVhGTVpvSDF0Q0pWQVV4X0VlTkZ2ZHBnNUlteERpa1NOcnVZZEl4MGdlOHMtNVU3TFY1RmlYc2dKS3lGRktfSU5GdTZ1Zzg0TVdwTHF3UVFNQUVBTW9rX1B5bWFrRHl3M3gzS2FuUzJlc3JfWlVSeGFfVmN2RUlaQ1A?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:30:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paracetamol poses gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, and renal risks for seniors: Study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/paracetamol-poses-gastrointestinal-cardiovascular-and-renal-risks-for-seniors-study/articleshow/116337547.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/paracetamol-poses-gastrointestinal-cardiovascular-and-renal-risks-for-seniors-study/articleshow/116337547.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tripura’s treasure: Fermented bamboo shoot emerges as a natural fat-fighter - EastMojo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tripura’s treasure: Fermented bamboo shoot emerges as a natural fat-fighter</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Guwahati</p>
<p>Researchers from the Institute of Advanced Study in Science and Technology (IASST) have highlighted the anti-obesity potential of <em>Melye-amiley</em>, a fermented bamboo shoot from Tripura, showing its ability to promote fat browning and combat obesity.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The study, published in <em>Food Frontiers</em>, found that the water extract of <em>Melye-amiley</em> activates the AMPK pathway, promoting fat breakdown.</li>
    <li>This bamboo shoot variety is part of a traditional preparation method that involves fermentation by lactic acid bacteria, enhancing its health benefits.</li>
    <li>Key genes linked to fat metabolism were upregulated when fat cells were exposed to the extract.</li>
    <li>The study also notes the presence of bioactive metabolites in the extract that may contribute to its anti-obesity effects.</li>
    <li>Researchers emphasize the need for further studies to confirm these results in animal and human trials.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“With rising obesity rates worldwide, there is a growing interest in natural dietary interventions that can support weight management.” – Dr. Mojibur R. Khan</blockquote>
<p>The findings suggest that traditional foods like <em>Melye-amiley</em> not only serve as sustenance but may also offer therapeutic benefits, thus paving the way for future research and potential development of nutraceutical products.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eastmojo.com/tripura/2024/12/15/tripuras-treasure-fermented-bamboo-shoot-emerges-as-a-natural-fat-fighter/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eastmojo.com/tripura/2024/12/15/tripuras-treasure-fermented-bamboo-shoot-emerges-as-a-natural-fat-fighter/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lifestyle News Live Today December 15, 2024: Do you drink raw milk? Study reveals flu virus can survive for days, raising health and safety concerns - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lifestyle News Live Today December 15, 2024: Want to lose 10 kg in 8 weeks? Nutritionist shares 7-day vegetarian diet plan to help you reach your weight loss goals</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/diet_1734263299527_1734263299690.jpg" alt="Latest news on December 15, 2024: Sticking to the diet plan requires discipline." title="Latest news on December 15, 2024: Sticking to the diet plan requires discipline." width="360" height="202" loading="lazy" decoding="async">
<figcaption>Latest news on December 15, 2024: Sticking to the diet plan requires discipline.</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses a comprehensive 7-day vegetarian diet plan shared by a nutritionist, aimed at helping individuals lose 10 kg in 8 weeks, along with current updates in lifestyle news.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The vegetarian diet includes detoxifying water and suggestions for managing mid-morning cravings.</li>
    <li>Other lifestyle updates include health-related news, fashion trends, and seasonal events.</li>
    <li>There is a variety of articles aimed at healthy living, diet, and mental health trends for the year.</li>
    <li>Read more detailed advice and tips on lifestyle improvement through various articles linked in the updates.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Nutritionist shared detailed vegetarian diet plan that involves everything, from detoxifying water to mid-morning cravings.”</blockquote>
<p>This summary encapsulates the focus on health and wellness through informed dietary choices and highlights the importance of sticking to a diet plan for effective weight loss.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/latest-lifestyle-today-live-updates-december-15-2024-101734229810733.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/latest-lifestyle-today-live-updates-december-15-2024-101734229810733.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:27:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Understanding The Connection Between Quality Sleep And Stroke Risk - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Understanding The Connection Between Quality Sleep And Stroke Risk</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p>
<img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/sleep-problems-stroke-risk.webp?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="Understanding The Connection Between Quality Sleep And Stroke Risk" width="900" height="375">
<figcaption>The Link Between Sleep and Stroke Risk</figcaption>
<p>Recent studies highlight the importance of sleep in reducing the risk of stroke, urging both doctors and patients to consider sleep quality and disorders in stroke prevention strategies.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Stroke risk is prevalent globally, with WHO estimating one in four individuals will experience a stroke in their lifetime.</li>
    <li>Traditional risk factors include hypertension, diabetes, and lifestyle issues such as obesity.</li>
    <li>New research indicates sleep quality and disorders significantly influence stroke risk, along with duration.</li>
    <li>Too little sleep (under six hours) and excessive sleep (over nine hours) are both linked to an increased risk of stroke.</li>
    <li>Obstructive Sleep Apnea (OSA) is a critical risk factor, increasing the likelihood of stroke two to three times.</li>
    <li>Insomnia and Restless Leg Syndrome (RLS) contribute to poorer sleep quality and higher stroke risk.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “Each apnea episode results in a brief drop in blood oxygen levels, causing blood pressure to spike.”
</blockquote>
<p>Overall, prioritizing quality sleep can play a vital role in stroke prevention strategies and improving brain health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/the-link-between-sleep-and-stroke-risk-1162589/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/the-link-between-sleep-and-stroke-risk-1162589/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Does Winter Worsen Asthma Symptoms—And How Can You Fight Back? - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why Does Winter Worsen Asthma Symptoms—And How Can You Fight Back?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116337184,thumbsize-1152510,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116337184.jpg" alt="Image - Canva" title="Image - Canva">
<figcaption>Image - Canva</figcaption>
<p>Asthma sufferers often find winter to be particularly challenging due to cold, dry air and indoor allergens, leading to increased symptoms and flare-ups. This article explores the reasons behind these worsened conditions and offers management strategies.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Cold air can irritate airways and increase mucus production.</li>
    <li>Indoor allergens such as dust mites, mold spores, and pet dander peak during colder months as people stay indoors.</li>
    <li>Respiratory infections, including flu and colds, are more common in winter and can trigger asthma episodes.</li>
    <li>Medications for cold and flu can sometimes worsen asthma symptoms.</li>
    <li>Staying hydrated, practicing good hygiene, and dressing warmly can help manage asthma in winter.</li>
    <li>It's important to have a flu vaccine and carry an inhaler, especially for outdoor activities.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “Viral diseases such as the flu and the common cold rise in the winter and are a primary trigger for many individuals with asthma.” - Dr. Sushrut Ganpule
</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, managing asthma during winter requires a combination of lifestyle adjustments, awareness of triggers, and proactive care, such as regular communication with a healthcare provider.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/health/why-does-winter-worsen-asthma-symptomsand-how-can-you-fight-back-article-116337172</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/health/why-does-winter-worsen-asthma-symptomsand-how-can-you-fight-back-article-116337172</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why cholesterol level rises during winter season - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-cholesterol-level-rises-during-winter-season/articleshow/116330667.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-cholesterol-level-rises-during-winter-season/articleshow/116330667.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How intermittent fasting could lead to hair loss - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How intermittent fasting could lead to hair loss</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Cell Press</p>
<p>Kilos are not the only thing that intermittent fasting will help you shed. A new study shows that the wildly popular weight-loss method could also inhibit hair growth.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Intermittent fasting is a time-restricted diet where participants consume calories in an 8-12 hour window.</li>
    <li>Benefits include weight loss, increased insulin sensitivity, and improved diabetes control.</li>
    <li>A 2023 survey reported that over 12% of respondents in the US are practicing intermittent fasting.</li>
    <li>Research linked intermittent fasting to a 91% higher risk of death from cardiovascular disease.</li>
    <li>Disruptions in sleep cycles and gastric issues are also associated with intermittent fasting.</li>
    <li>A recent study shows a link between intermittent fasting and hair loss by inhibiting hair follicle regeneration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Commonly used intermittent fasting regimens inhibit hair follicle regeneration by selectively inducing apoptosis [programmed cell death] in activated hair follicle stem cells (HFSCs)…”</blockquote>
<p>Researchers found that mice on intermittent fasting exhibited slower hair regeneration, and similar effects were observed in a small human trial, albeit likely less severe in humans.</p>
<p>The study suggests that hair growth inhibition occurs because HFSCs cannot handle the oxidative stress from switching energy sources during fasting.</p>
<blockquote>“During fasting, adipose tissue starts to release free fatty acids...but these stem cells don’t have the right machinery to use them,” - Bing Zhang, senior author and stem cell biologist.</blockquote>
<p>Further research is needed to understand the effects of intermittent fasting on hair loss across different individuals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-health/intermittent-fasting-hair-loss-9725849/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-health/intermittent-fasting-hair-loss-9725849/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:20:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poliovirus found in wastewater in Spain, Germany and Poland: All you need to know - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Poliovirus found in wastewater in Spain, Germany and Poland: All you need to know</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 15 December 2024, 08:59 IST</p>
<p><strong>By:</strong> Mariachiara Di Cesare, Francis Hassard for The Conversation</p>
<p>Recent detections of poliovirus in wastewater across Spain, Germany, and Poland raise concerns for public health, despite no confirmed infections reported. This serves as a reminder of the importance of vaccination efforts to prevent potential outbreaks.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Polio is a highly contagious disease that can lead to paralysis and death.</li>
    <li>Since 1988, global poliovirus cases have decreased by over 99%, with Pakistan and Afghanistan remaining endemic.</li>
    <li>Detection of the virus in wastewater is a warning of possible vaccination coverage gaps.</li>
    <li>Wastewater surveillance provides crucial insights for early disease detection, particularly in under-immunised populations.</li>
    <li>In 2023, Europe achieved polio immunisation coverage of about 95% for one-year-olds, but gaps remain.</li>
    <li>Reports indicate that 30% of countries have vaccination coverage below 80%.</li>
    <li>The COVID-19 pandemic has disrupted vaccination programs, impacting public health efforts against polio.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Wastewater-based surveillance provides public health authorities with another weapon in the fight against infectious diseases.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the detection of poliovirus in wastewater emphasizes the need for continuous vaccination efforts and surveillance to ensure public health safety and prevent the resurgence of this dangerous disease.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/health/poliovirus-found-in-wastewater-in-spain-germany-and-poland-all-you-need-to-know-3318420</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/health/poliovirus-found-in-wastewater-in-spain-germany-and-poland-all-you-need-to-know-3318420</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 08:59:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Achieves Milestone in Malaria Control with 69% Drop in Cases and Deaths: WHO Report - Pratidin Time]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Achieves Milestone in Malaria Control with 69% Drop in Cases and Deaths: WHO Report</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Publive</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://img-cdn.thepublive.com/fit-in/1280x960/filters:format(webp)/pratidin/media/media_files/2024/12/15/Ihm6uRQCDzcpHpM3FewH.jpg" alt="new pt mosquito">
    <figcaption>India Achieves Milestone in Malaria Control with 69% Drop in Cases and Deaths: WHO Report</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>India has made significant strides in combating malaria, achieving a 69% reduction in both cases and deaths, according to the latest World Malaria Report released by the WHO.</p>
<ul>
    <li>India exited the high burden high incidence (HBHI) group in 2024.</li>
    <li>From 2017 to 2023, malaria cases decreased from 64 lakh to 20 lakh (69% reduction).</li>
    <li>Malaria deaths dropped from 11,100 to 3,500 (68% decrease).</li>
    <li>India accounts for half of the malaria cases in Southeast Asia.</li>
    <li>Between 2000 and 2023, malaria cases reduced by 82.4%.</li>
    <li>Indoor Residual Spraying (IRS) coverage decreased in 2023, protecting 30 lakh fewer people.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The WHO report recognized India’s efforts, highlighting the crucial role of community health workers, particularly women, in reaching remote populations and significantly lowering malaria cases.”</blockquote>
<p>Despite the progress made in malaria control, the report warns that the global malaria target for 2030 is off track, urging for more investments and actions in high-burden countries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pratidintime.com/health/india-achieves-milestone-in-malaria-control-with-69-drop-in-cases-and-deaths-who-report-8441747</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pratidintime.com/health/india-achieves-milestone-in-malaria-control-with-69-drop-in-cases-and-deaths-who-report-8441747</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 08:30:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Health News Live December 15, 2024 : Ultimate fat burning guide to help you achieve healthy weight loss fast: Nutritionist shares top 8 recommendations - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPelFOUkFOYWJHMG95UDk3bXlGSUQ0WkVtZDBJYUhsUTluNHFOT0p2OEt6LWFWSnpXejdYQ1Zuck5fWEhoLWpjb0hPeGptcHlvSnExOTgyWjFYLWJabHdCRDRPblZTdWZ2b1B6eTUtLUE1UDBJZ3hETzB6cUhFVGlEWllRbV9waTMtM3lCME5SQWVTWTZVODloeG5rQkRWZXo5TUI4OXhTeURGMTR5WTh1S09n0gG3AUFVX3lxTE9nbmJ3RnBRQUw5ZDIza29iVVRScFdRdklBbmZVS3Z1X29yblF0Tm4xQVVwUmJURlNEMlpYWWRZend2TmRMUDIyY3JiUC1PMW5xV29ENG10eG9tUF96M3Z2bGFaU2xqQm0yR0ZVZU5Obm1RVkZkR0JjcmlVdWN1X2FMMzNoNTY5dXNoNVU5dDJxTXUyTWtkU0Q1VW50V2dyOGxVZ1ZWcVAxRjZ6YzlpOTF1SnM4d0xmcw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPelFOUkFOYWJHMG95UDk3bXlGSUQ0WkVtZDBJYUhsUTluNHFOT0p2OEt6LWFWSnpXejdYQ1Zuck5fWEhoLWpjb0hPeGptcHlvSnExOTgyWjFYLWJabHdCRDRPblZTdWZ2b1B6eTUtLUE1UDBJZ3hETzB6cUhFVGlEWllRbV9waTMtM3lCME5SQWVTWTZVODloeG5rQkRWZXo5TUI4OXhTeURGMTR5WTh1S09n0gG3AUFVX3lxTE9nbmJ3RnBRQUw5ZDIza29iVVRScFdRdklBbmZVS3Z1X29yblF0Tm4xQVVwUmJURlNEMlpYWWRZend2TmRMUDIyY3JiUC1PMW5xV29ENG10eG9tUF96M3Z2bGFaU2xqQm0yR0ZVZU5Obm1RVkZkR0JjcmlVdWN1X2FMMzNoNTY5dXNoNVU5dDJxTXUyTWtkU0Q1VW50V2dyOGxVZ1ZWcVAxRjZ6YzlpOTF1SnM4d0xmcw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:47:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ultimate fat burning guide to help you achieve healthy weight loss fast: Nutritionist shares top 8 recommendations - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ultimate Fat Burning Guide to Help You Achieve Healthy Weight Loss Fast: Nutritionist Shares Top 8 Recommendations</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/weight_loss_1734248328109_1734248336905.jpg" alt="Nutritionist's recommendations for weight loss">
    <figcaption>A nutritionist listed her '8 recommendations to lose weight and end this year strong'. Here's what she said. (Freepik)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Nutritionist and lifestyle coach Raksha Lulla has shared a video outlining eight easy and sustainable habits for weight loss that can help individuals burn calories and achieve their health goals without feeling restricted.</p>
<ul>
    <li><strong>1. Eat till spaciousness:</strong> Stop when your stomach feels light and not heavy.</li>
    <li><strong>2. Drink water from a glass:</strong> Stay hydrated without waiting to feel thirsty.</li>
    <li><strong>3. Take magnesium glycinate:</strong> A nightly supplement that supports vitamin levels with a doctor's guidance.</li>
    <li><strong>4. Add ghee to carbohydrates:</strong> Enhances fullness while moderating glycemic index.</li>
    <li><strong>5. Walk for no reason:</strong> Engage in leisurely walking without specific goals.</li>
    <li><strong>6. Add seasonal vegetables:</strong> Incorporate nutrient-rich vegetables for balanced nutrition.</li>
    <li><strong>7. Strength train at least once a week:</strong> Focus on full-body exercises without explosive movements.</li>
    <li><strong>8. Practice 4-7-8 breathing:</strong> Use this technique to center yourself each morning.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “This is the ultimate fat-burning guide that will make you the version of yourself – achieve a healthy weight loss and keep it off too!” - Raksha Lulla
</blockquote>
<p>This comprehensive guide emphasizes that weight loss should be sustainable and enjoyable, not a chore.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/ultimate-fat-burning-guide-to-help-you-achieve-a-healthy-weight-loss-fast-nutritionist-8-recommendations-ghee-roti-rice-101734247845846-amp.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/ultimate-fat-burning-guide-to-help-you-achieve-a-healthy-weight-loss-fast-nutritionist-8-recommendations-ghee-roti-rice-101734247845846-amp.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Polio Resurgence Alert: Wastewater Surveillance as a Critical Defense - Devdiscourse]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPWnBJUHlRTDdwd3lQM2IzeGlKNnpKZGVGajJiQXRGb0s0MElsTHRzOEU3Qy1FZ19BYzg0dllpejhybGZRU1AzTFBET1RRSVQyTWNnRzRqd3BFLTUxb3BzMDdvZlgzRnRiQVJrV21HUElMelFsQ25lWkxKWnk5YWROZ3R5OXZxNXV3X1B6MmhUb0Z2aU16T0xHSUFPOGhaTnp2QmtSOGZnT0t0U0dmaTd0OS1UVkRna2FSWlJhedIBwgFBVV95cUxOeDRkWDZSX3pIandqMEtCU2NtYWtKb3pqazM0bDJzeFFMN2xScmd6T2h1S1IyWUZRcW9rMWxFd2xpTDRaRnE5LThKTVl1Rm1vYkhWVnNUSkZTa044NGhYWXRUdjQwNXNQcWVfVEVNMTVBRjFQQmRrNXNJMjJoQzUtUEtNUjVZQkNYYnR0MnphMEktQmN1dm85a2NxT1UzRHQwXy1UTnBXN3g0bVJWd0FHLWxqeWxUTk8zMmFWYjREaHktdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPWnBJUHlRTDdwd3lQM2IzeGlKNnpKZGVGajJiQXRGb0s0MElsTHRzOEU3Qy1FZ19BYzg0dllpejhybGZRU1AzTFBET1RRSVQyTWNnRzRqd3BFLTUxb3BzMDdvZlgzRnRiQVJrV21HUElMelFsQ25lWkxKWnk5YWROZ3R5OXZxNXV3X1B6MmhUb0Z2aU16T0xHSUFPOGhaTnp2QmtSOGZnT0t0U0dmaTd0OS1UVkRna2FSWlJhedIBwgFBVV95cUxOeDRkWDZSX3pIandqMEtCU2NtYWtKb3pqazM0bDJzeFFMN2xScmd6T2h1S1IyWUZRcW9rMWxFd2xpTDRaRnE5LThKTVl1Rm1vYkhWVnNUSkZTa044NGhYWXRUdjQwNXNQcWVfVEVNMTVBRjFQQmRrNXNJMjJoQzUtUEtNUjVZQkNYYnR0MnphMEktQmN1dm85a2NxT1UzRHQwXy1UTnBXN3g0bVJWd0FHLWxqeWxUTk8zMmFWYjREaHktdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:13:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can drinking coffee boost longevity? - Medical News Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Coffee May Help Prolong Lifespan by Almost 2 Years, on Average</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Medical News Today</p>
<img src="https://media.post.rvohealth.io/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2024/12/coffee-armchair-1296x728-header-1024x575.jpg" alt="photo of coffee cup on the arm of a dark armchair repeated three times">
<figcaption>Drinking coffee is linked to a longer, healthier life, according to mounting evidence. Image credit: Polina Kovalova/Stocksy.</figcaption>
<p>A new review study suggests that regular coffee consumption may increase a person's lifespan by an average of 1.8 healthy years, reinforcing the beverage's positive health effects.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Coffee is one of the most popular beverages worldwide, with around 2 million cups consumed daily.</li>
    <li>A recent review from the University of Coimbra highlights coffee's potential health benefits.</li>
    <li>The study, funded by the Institute for Scientific Information on Coffee, analyzed over 50 studies on coffee consumption.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>“Moderate intake of coffee was found to decrease the incidence of several chronic diseases.” – Rodrigo Cunha, PhD.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, regular coffee consumption is associated with healthier aging; however, it is essential to consider individual health needs and consumption patterns.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/coffee-may-help-prolong-lifespan-by-almost-2-years-on-average</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/coffee-may-help-prolong-lifespan-by-almost-2-years-on-average</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:42:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Craving Sweets? Try Saumya Tandon's Healthy Sweet Potato Halwa Recipe For A Guilt-Free Indulgence - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Craving Sweets? Try Saumya Tandon's Healthy Sweet Potato Halwa Recipe For A Guilt-Free Indulgence</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Saumya Tandon revealed that she quit sugar and its substitutes four years ago." title="Saumya Tandon revealed that she quit sugar and its substitutes four years ago.">
    <figcaption>Saumya Tandon revealed that she quit sugar and its substitutes four years ago.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Saumya Tandon shared a healthy recipe for sweet potato halwa that eschews sugar and its substitutes, promoting guilt-free indulgence.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Saumya Tandon has been sugar-free for four years, including honey and jaggery.</li>
    <li>She discusses her lifestyle changes and shares a sweet potato halwa recipe in her recent Instagram video.</li>
    <li>The recipe includes healthy ingredients like ghee and milk, focusing on natural sweetness.</li>
    <li>Users can prepare the dish easily with simple steps provided in the article.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>“I gave up sugar/all sugar substitutes, honey and jaggery 4 years ago. I only eat fruits and dry fruits and desserts made of them. It’s a game changer. Try!”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Saumya Tandon's journey towards a sugar-free diet inspires many to explore healthier dessert options without compromising on taste.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/food-craving-sweets-try-saumya-tandons-healthy-sweet-potato-halwa-recipe-for-a-guilt-free-indulgence-9156782.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/food-craving-sweets-try-saumya-tandons-healthy-sweet-potato-halwa-recipe-for-a-guilt-free-indulgence-9156782.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:16:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paracetamol linked to side effects in digestive tract, heart, kidneys: Study - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/paracetamol-linked-to-side-effects-in-digestive-tract-heart-kidneys-study-12890128.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/paracetamol-linked-to-side-effects-in-digestive-tract-heart-kidneys-study-12890128.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:08:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 5 immunity-boosting drinks for winter - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top 5 immunity-boosting drinks for winter</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/13/900x1600/drinksiiimunity_1734085732542_1734085748019.jpg" alt="Top immunity-boosting drinks" />
<figcaption>Top immunity-boosting drinks for winter</figcaption>
<p>This article presents five delicious beverages aimed at enhancing immunity during the winter season, highlighting their health benefits and ingredients.</p>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Turmeric Golden Milk:</strong> A warming blend of milk with turmeric, black pepper, and honey rich in antioxidants and anti-inflammatory properties.</li>
    <li><strong>Ginger Lemon Tea:</strong> A zesty mix of ginger, lemon, and honey offering a high dose of vitamin C, perfect for soothing sore throats.</li>
    <li><strong>Tulsi and Peppermint Tea:</strong> A calming infusion that combines tulsi and peppermint to boost immunity and alleviate nasal congestion.</li>
    <li><strong>Spiced Apple Cider:</strong> A festive drink made from simmered apple juice with cinnamon, cloves, and star anise, packed with antioxidants.</li>
    <li><strong>Amla and Ginger Juice:</strong> A refreshing juice made from fresh amla and ginger, rich in vitamin C, helping to strengthen immunity and detoxify the body.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"High in vitamin C, amla juice strengthens immunity and detoxifies the body." - Hindustan Times</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, integrating these immunity-boosting drinks into your winter routine can help maintain health and wellness during the colder months.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/lifestyle/top-5-immunity-boosting-drinks-for-winter-101734085144156.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/lifestyle/top-5-immunity-boosting-drinks-for-winter-101734085144156.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:18:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Alia Bhatt to Deepika Padukone: 5 celebrity skincare routines you can follow - Health shots]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>From Alia Bhatt to Deepika Padukone: 5 celebrity skincare routines you can follow</h1>
<p><strong>Published On: </strong> 15 Dec 2024, 10:30 am IST</p>
<figure id="attachment_95545" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-95545">
    <img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" data-src="https://images.healthshots.com/healthshots/en/uploads/2023/11/28083904/vitamin-K-for-skin.jpg" alt="Woman with glowing skin" width="1600" height="900">
    <figcaption id="caption-attachment-95545">Know the benefits of a skincare routine to get glowing skin. Image courtesy: Adobe Stock</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Discover the secrets to radiant skin with these celebrity-inspired morning skincare routines. Know how to protect your skin like a star.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Alia Bhatt emphasizes gentle cleansing, toning, hydration, and sunscreen to achieve glowing skin.</li>
    <li>Kriti Sanon starts her routine with ice water to reduce puffiness, followed by cleansing and hydrating products.</li>
    <li>Deepika Padukone shares her moisturizing and sun protection techniques to maintain her skin’s health.</li>
    <li>Madhuri Dixit uses mild cleansers and natural toners to refresh her skin and always applies sunscreen.</li>
    <li>Kiara Advani follows a simple but effective regimen prioritizing gentle cleansing, hydration, and sun protection.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"These skincare routines contain simple ideas that everyone can follow in their everyday practice." - Article Summary</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, following the simple yet effective skincare routines of these celebrities can help achieve healthy, glowing skin. Remember, a blend of proper skincare, hydration, and sun protection is key.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthshots.com/beauty/skin-care/deepika-padukone-to-alia-bhatt-5-celebrity-approved-skincare-routines/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthshots.com/beauty/skin-care/deepika-padukone-to-alia-bhatt-5-celebrity-approved-skincare-routines/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:00:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rising incidence of early-onset bowel cancer: a global concern - News Karnataka]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://newskarnataka.com/health/rising-incidence-of-early-onset-bowel-cancer-a-global-concern/15122024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://newskarnataka.com/health/rising-incidence-of-early-onset-bowel-cancer-a-global-concern/15122024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:58:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shielding seniors: Combating influenza and air pollution for better health - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/shielding-seniors-combating-influenza-and-air-pollution-for-better-health/articleshow/116331608.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/shielding-seniors-combating-influenza-and-air-pollution-for-better-health/articleshow/116331608.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flu virus remains infectious in refrigerated raw milk: Study - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxOVklfNXdHS0FHVEI1WUl0VkJZaXNIUGpkWGFmdy1Xc2ozVTkwNEdEOEliZ2hUT2pWOXpDc2thbjhsR0NPWk44WUtzTHNjX2FuU1JTRTVHd1VPb1JONm5KNVpTT2hyOG8yaU9VS3FnOE5lWjVXVjVlRWRnRWVMdWRKcUh4TWpDYzh1c0FfcXpGaFVfenUydUItWGdPd2d3ZUszY2xvUDRmLS01ZXBRTU5hb2tHM094YUROdjc3N3VaWlgwLTJfUEHSAcsBQVVfeXFMTy1VelFwVnFteTBqX29Eb1NPQzl6aEZtaXItZ1Bqc1FvU2tGX2xNYk4xV09sbllCazQzNy1Rc19qYTA2NjZWdjRtM1ZpUUZNNEJnZG04VlU3ZHRCQlQzTUZoYzYwUUVkeGFyOWNoaWw2THYxLVE4YWZrejliRlZ4NlJnMjhmU2hQOVJvd3ZWMWs0V0MzaVRQR2F4N09wNW1mMllBUkY3OXlOSktfR292Z3dRYWpEc2Fyb1FEN3k4SHRtb1ZMc3hNZEltZXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxOVklfNXdHS0FHVEI1WUl0VkJZaXNIUGpkWGFmdy1Xc2ozVTkwNEdEOEliZ2hUT2pWOXpDc2thbjhsR0NPWk44WUtzTHNjX2FuU1JTRTVHd1VPb1JONm5KNVpTT2hyOG8yaU9VS3FnOE5lWjVXVjVlRWRnRWVMdWRKcUh4TWpDYzh1c0FfcXpGaFVfenUydUItWGdPd2d3ZUszY2xvUDRmLS01ZXBRTU5hb2tHM094YUROdjc3N3VaWlgwLTJfUEHSAcsBQVVfeXFMTy1VelFwVnFteTBqX29Eb1NPQzl6aEZtaXItZ1Bqc1FvU2tGX2xNYk4xV09sbllCazQzNy1Rc19qYTA2NjZWdjRtM1ZpUUZNNEJnZG04VlU3ZHRCQlQzTUZoYzYwUUVkeGFyOWNoaWw2THYxLVE4YWZrejliRlZ4NlJnMjhmU2hQOVJvd3ZWMWs0V0MzaVRQR2F4N09wNW1mMllBUkY3OXlOSktfR292Z3dRYWpEc2Fyb1FEN3k4SHRtb1ZMc3hNZEltZXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:23:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winter foods to boost your health and keep cold away - The Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOamJ4cEFRSGo5WmFxUWNvX0gyTDZkeUNFaG94aTlJcHVVV0VTQ1VsY2otbWdsSDZlcTFzRmRzS3JMQWdGeXdPSWtGcDQ2cGIwSUdPQkZLYnRIV1hyV1BlU1ZxSlktQzJtYnM2aEdrZU5JbWdQTjU0ODEyV0tfZ0F3Y1lwYUF6VTVzM1FvN0FVbjFSbWdPQ3VFU0RxOTIwN0ZT0gGmAUFVX3lxTFB4NGRwRkdsTEZLVU0tS0o2Z3hmeEg1NS1pQTN1NFJVZ2xQVW5nQkJLTnN1b2tKQU9laXhZLWlOOUF1STlpeTNzT0xSb011NXR6QktvOFdtTTd0eVFHWVhMbEc5TkVOSG9uOHRUZDBnOE9BU014ckJzV3NkNmwxdlRna0p3OHN0MkRQRGdWUTF5aW9yeUZqUFhyN0Y1YWg4ZHZYYzNqbEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOamJ4cEFRSGo5WmFxUWNvX0gyTDZkeUNFaG94aTlJcHVVV0VTQ1VsY2otbWdsSDZlcTFzRmRzS3JMQWdGeXdPSWtGcDQ2cGIwSUdPQkZLYnRIV1hyV1BlU1ZxSlktQzJtYnM2aEdrZU5JbWdQTjU0ODEyV0tfZ0F3Y1lwYUF6VTVzM1FvN0FVbjFSbWdPQ3VFU0RxOTIwN0ZT0gGmAUFVX3lxTFB4NGRwRkdsTEZLVU0tS0o2Z3hmeEg1NS1pQTN1NFJVZ2xQVW5nQkJLTnN1b2tKQU9laXhZLWlOOUF1STlpeTNzT0xSb011NXR6QktvOFdtTTd0eVFHWVhMbEc5TkVOSG9uOHRUZDBnOE9BU014ckJzV3NkNmwxdlRna0p3OHN0MkRQRGdWUTF5aW9yeUZqUFhyN0Y1YWg4ZHZYYzNqbEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 03:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Essential Health Tests Every Woman Should Take During Menopause to Protect Bone Health - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Essential Health Tests Every Woman Should Take During Menopause to Protect Bone Health</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Zee News</p>
<p>Menopause is a critical phase for women that comes with health challenges, particularly affecting bone health. Regular screenings and specific tests are essential to understand and mitigate these risks.</p>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Calcium and Vitamin D Levels:</strong> Essential for maintaining bone density; Vitamin D aids calcium absorption.</li>
    <li><strong>Bone Mineral Density (BMD) Test:</strong> Measures mineral density in bones to assess strength and fracture risk. Important for osteoporosis monitoring.</li>
    <li><strong>Hormone Level Testing:</strong> Evaluates estrogen and parathyroid hormone levels to understand bone health and osteoporosis risk.</li>
    <li><strong>Thyroid Function Tests:</strong> Monitors thyroid hormones that affect bone metabolism and density, especially in cases of hyperthyroidism.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "According to the National Osteoporosis Foundation, approximately 1 in 2 women over the age of 50 will experience a fracture due to osteoporosis."
</blockquote>
<p>In addition to these tests, it's crucial for women to assess lifestyle factors such as diet, exercise, and smoking that impact bone health. Regular check-ups can greatly assist in navigating menopause effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/health/the-essential-health-tests-every-woman-should-take-during-menopause-to-protect-bone-health-2831848</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/health/the-essential-health-tests-every-woman-should-take-during-menopause-to-protect-bone-health-2831848</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 02:41:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study warns: Ultra-processed foods may accelerate biological age - The Hans India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQSVgwS2NIb0tXS0FJR2QySmwyai1Sam1DYlJzcEVBOUdYQ0p2eUtZUEE1QURYS0tFRnpRaWdXYlpvRDhpakxSNVB3bWNiS3BKVHhoMURXM0I1aUd5ekNMQWxhZkl5Z0xZS3lIT3lwcXFPUzJPS05KYXllaS1wWHdJYXhJalpsMjlPTWhLekYwUHUyX2taWFByOF9NRDNNenhWWm02YmE1Z3ZrT2lGNHRBSDJLRjdwTG91QWNfdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQSVgwS2NIb0tXS0FJR2QySmwyai1Sam1DYlJzcEVBOUdYQ0p2eUtZUEE1QURYS0tFRnpRaWdXYlpvRDhpakxSNVB3bWNiS3BKVHhoMURXM0I1aUd5ekNMQWxhZkl5Z0xZS3lIT3lwcXFPUzJPS05KYXllaS1wWHdJYXhJalpsMjlPTWhLekYwUHUyX2taWFByOF9NRDNNenhWWm02YmE1Z3ZrT2lGNHRBSDJLRjdwTG91QWNfdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 02:30:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 healthy superfood recipes for your kid visual story - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-healthy-superfood-recipes-for-your-kid-visual-story-11733998226601.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-healthy-superfood-recipes-for-your-kid-visual-story-11733998226601.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:10:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taming the Silent Killer: India’s remarkable achievements towards controlling High bp - The Sunday Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQajVUTmNZOTlpTkU0d2gtVlN4bGNLQThMVFBqa0x3OFc4eS1YbXo2eTR2d3lIOFI0SWxlcU05RnhkZnROZE1wMW5hUkpPX1d0dVQ4bUdWMVlFb3BTZHhDLWVxV1RTTkZ2cUV6Y0NGN2Rfc2k5STBvR0tqcmRkdXdUcTQwOUliVHFqS2UybXIxX1Q5RjkxX2lhN2tnNFdabkdmUVY0bkZOSm0yTmhqSFkySUg1U2JOekhqeWhIUWRQMnk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQajVUTmNZOTlpTkU0d2gtVlN4bGNLQThMVFBqa0x3OFc4eS1YbXo2eTR2d3lIOFI0SWxlcU05RnhkZnROZE1wMW5hUkpPX1d0dVQ4bUdWMVlFb3BTZHhDLWVxV1RTTkZ2cUV6Y0NGN2Rfc2k5STBvR0tqcmRkdXdUcTQwOUliVHFqS2UybXIxX1Q5RjkxX2lhN2tnNFdabkdmUVY0bkZOSm0yTmhqSFkySUg1U2JOekhqeWhIUWRQMnk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 23:56:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mysterious illness in Congo: WHO investigates malaria link - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 23:31:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study Reveals Major Drawback to The Health Benefits of Fasting - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Study Reveals Major Drawback to The Health Benefits of Fasting</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> March 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Science Alert</p>

<figure>
    <img src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/12/person_waiting_to_eat.jpg" alt="woman looking at her watch before eating" loading="lazy">
    <figcaption>Calorie restriction can come with a range of benefits. A new study finds how long it takes for changes to occur inside your body. (nensuria/Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The article discusses a recent study revealing that fasting may not yield health benefits in shorter or intermittent fasts, emphasizing the need for more extended fasting periods to observe positive changes in the body.</p>

<ul>
    <li>The study indicates that more than three days of fasting is required for significant molecular changes in the body.</li>
    <li>Health experts stress that fasting should be done under medical supervision, especially for certain demographics.</li>
    <li>About a third of the proteins in the study participants showed significant systemic changes after a week of water-only fasting.</li>
    <li>Fasting is linked to potential improvements in conditions like rheumatoid arthritis and cardiovascular health after three days.</li>
    <li>Research highlights the risks associated with prolonged fasting, including dehydration and starvation impacts.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
    "Our results provide evidence for the health benefits of fasting beyond weight loss, but these were only visible after three days of total caloric restriction – later than we previously thought." – Claudia Langenberg, Queen Mary University of London
</blockquote>

<p>The findings underscore the complexity of fasting's effects on health and suggest that more research is needed to safely harness its benefits without the risks associated with prolonged calorie deprivation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/study-reveals-major-drawback-to-the-health-benefits-of-fasting</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/study-reveals-major-drawback-to-the-health-benefits-of-fasting</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 22:17:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>