<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 03:22:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 03:22:29 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Closely monitoring influenza cases in India, no need to be alarmed: Govt on HMPV outbreak in China - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Monitoring Influenza Cases: No Alarm Needed Over HMPV in China</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/china-2025-virus.jpg?w=640" alt="hmpv, china virus, Human Metapneumovirus" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>There is reportedly no substantial increase in the December 2024 data on respiratory outbreaks in India. (File Photo)</figcaption><p>The National Centre for Disease Control (NCDC) is closely monitoring respiratory and seasonal influenza cases in India, amidst reports of an outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in China. Official sources have stated that there is no need for alarm.</p><ul><li>NCDC is in touch with international agencies regarding the HMPV outbreak.</li><li>There is no substantial increase in respiratory outbreak data for December 2024 in India.</li><li>DGHS Dr. Atul Goel likened HMPV to common cold viruses.</li><li>Precautions advised include respiratory etiquette and avoiding contact if symptomatic.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is nothing to be alarmed about the present situation,” - Dr. Atul Goel</blockquote><p>As winter increases the outbreak of respiratory infections, hospitals are prepared with necessary supplies and beds. General precautions for respiratory infections are recommended.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/influenza-cases-india-alarmed-govt-hmpv-outbreak-china-9759209/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/influenza-cases-india-alarmed-govt-hmpv-outbreak-china-9759209/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 02:47:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Surgeon-General Vivek Murthy wants cancer warning on alcohol: How does your drinking habit cause cancer? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Surgeon-General Vivek Murthy Wants Cancer Warning on Alcohol</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not mentioned in the article<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/drinking-vivek-murthy.jpg?w=640" alt="drinking, vivek murthy, alcohol, cancer" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>The risk for cancers of the breast, the mouth and the throat may rise with consumption of as little as one drink a day, or even less, said Dr Murthy. (File Photo/Representational)</figcaption>
<p>US Surgeon-General Vivek Murthy has called for alcoholic beverages to carry cancer warning labels, highlighting evidence that no level of alcohol consumption is safe when it comes to cancer risk.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Alcohol is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the US, following tobacco and obesity.</li>
  <li>Consumption of just one drink per day can increase the risk for several cancers including breast, mouth, and throat.</li>
  <li>Alcohol is classified as a group 1 carcinogen by the WHO, with no safe level of consumption.</li>
  <li>Dr Murthy's report states alcohol increases the risk of at least seven types of cancer.</li>
  <li>Dr Murthy draws parallels with India's anti-smoking campaigns as a model for addressing alcohol-related harm.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Alcohol has been confirmed as a group 1 carcinogen... there is no safe level of alcohol,” - Dr Pankaj Chaturvedi</blockquote>
<p>This initiative reflects a growing recognition of the health risks associated with alcohol consumption and aims to reduce the incidence of alcohol-related cancers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/vivek-murthy-cancer-warning-alcohol-drinking-cancer-9759172/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/vivek-murthy-cancer-warning-alcohol-drinking-cancer-9759172/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 02:09:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fight over formaldehyde safety continues - Chemical & Engineering News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxOUm5FaURuSWI4RlRaa3lCWFdXVkwwUTI4VVp3RXZNblRWOXduUlozMks2bng2N1hyVmQ4bmE5cTVBaXIxYUZZXzJ2WlUwM3lLZGN4eUhlUk9VYlZGbG5XYWMwYVNTMjV0b3hUYkgzeWJKcGFUdEhLY0RpQllxeEl1UTFnd3Axa3U2N1B6YU8tWDlENFhzNEs5c3RvWmpRZjR4ZzAzRDZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxOUm5FaURuSWI4RlRaa3lCWFdXVkwwUTI4VVp3RXZNblRWOXduUlozMks2bng2N1hyVmQ4bmE5cTVBaXIxYUZZXzJ2WlUwM3lLZGN4eUhlUk9VYlZGbG5XYWMwYVNTMjV0b3hUYkgzeWJKcGFUdEhLY0RpQllxeEl1UTFnd3Axa3U2N1B6YU8tWDlENFhzNEs5c3RvWmpRZjR4ZzAzRDZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 22:50:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EPA Completes Final TSCA Risk Evaluation for Formaldehyde - Powder Bulk Solids]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOZnBpd2pmSmRBaW5QWUJ6aHlTQ3IzWlpfSHY2cW9KUlhfZzRxakcyZzFCVmNkNkxoejJzVkR5NTVrbGFXN094aXpBQktpRE83NkJyVHNZRnE5WmRaZlZLcHQyMlhMMHhCbkdyWGdUUjFaV0NSeEJlYm5LeHdzRnVEVG1TekJielNjcFhBTmFqMk9DS0VZYXlQcUhDZGJTZThj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOZnBpd2pmSmRBaW5QWUJ6aHlTQ3IzWlpfSHY2cW9KUlhfZzRxakcyZzFCVmNkNkxoejJzVkR5NTVrbGFXN094aXpBQktpRE83NkJyVHNZRnE5WmRaZlZLcHQyMlhMMHhCbkdyWGdUUjFaV0NSeEJlYm5LeHdzRnVEVG1TekJielNjcFhBTmFqMk9DS0VZYXlQcUhDZGJTZThj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 19:33:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alcohol stocks drop after US surgeon general calls for cancer warnings - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Alcohol Stocks Decline Following US Surgeon General's Cancer Warning Proposal</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> September 29, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News Agency</p><p>The US Surgeon General has called for cancer warnings on alcoholic beverages, leading to a notable drop in shares of major spirits and brewing companies.</p><ul><li>US Surgeon General Vivek Murthy stated that alcohol consumption increases the risk of various cancers.</li><li>Alcoholic drinks may start increasing cancer risk at just one drink per day.</li><li>Major companies like Brown-Forman and Constellation Brands experienced significant stock declines.</li><li>The surgeon general's recommendations may not be implemented immediately as Congress will decide on label changes.</li><li>Experts believe warning labels may have minimal impact on consumption habits.</li></ul><blockquote>“Most Americans tend to believe that nearly everything is okay in moderation, thus much as warning labels alone on cigarette packs did little to curb public smoking, I expect warning labels on alcohol to have little effect.” - Michael Ashley Schulman</blockquote><p>Overall, the proposed warning labels on alcohol could reshape market dynamics, but the effectiveness remains uncertain.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/business/alcohol-stocks-drop-us-surgeon-general-calls-cancer-warnings-9758970/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/business/alcohol-stocks-drop-us-surgeon-general-calls-cancer-warnings-9758970/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 18:59:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Nothing to be alarmed about’: Centre on China HMPV outbreak - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Nothing to be alarmed about': Centre on China HMPV outbreak</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 04, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/A-healthcare-worker-places-a-vial-with-a-swab-of-t_1678909147697_1735941925709.jpg' alt='An analysis of data for the month of December did not show a substantial increase in the cases.(Image for representation/ Reuters)'>
<figcaption>An analysis of data for the month of December did not show a substantial increase in the cases.(Image for representation/ Reuters)</figcaption>
<p>The Union health ministry has addressed concerns regarding a potential outbreak of the human metapneumovirus (HMPV) in China, affirming that there has been no significant increase in viral respiratory illness cases.</p>
<ul>
<li>The health ministry stated there’s “no substantial increase” in respiratory illness cases.</li>
<li>Dr. Atul Goel emphasized the commonality of the virus, akin to any other respiratory virus.</li>
<li>Monitoring of both seasonal influenza and respiratory cases is ongoing.</li>
<li>Precautionary measures against spread are advised for respiratory infections.</li>
<!-- More points can be added if needed -->
</ul>
<blockquote>“There is nothing to be alarmed about in the present situation,” said Dr. Goel.</blockquote>
<p>In summary, officials maintain that while attention to HMPV is warranted, the public can remain calm as the healthcare system is prepared and no alarming rise in cases has been noted.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/nothing-to-be-alarmed-about-centre-on-china-hmpvoutbreak-101735928472677.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/nothing-to-be-alarmed-about-centre-on-china-hmpvoutbreak-101735928472677.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 18:21:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alcohol stocks plunge after US surgeon general calls for cancer warnings | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Alcohol Stocks Plunge After US Surgeon General Calls for Cancer Warnings</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The U.S. Surgeon General's call for cancer warnings on alcohol labels has led to a decline in shares of spirits makers and brewers.</p><ul><li>U.S. Surgeon General Vivek Murthy highlighted the link between alcohol consumption and various cancers.</li><li>Shares of Brown-Forman and Molson Coors fell significantly, with Brown-Forman hitting its lowest price since April 2017.</li><li>There is uncertainty about when or if the labeling changes will be enacted as Congress will decide.</li><li>The decline also affected major European spirits brands like Diageo and Pernod Ricard.</li></ul><blockquote>“Most Americans tend to believe that nearly everything is okay in moderation... I expect warning labels on alcohol to have little effect,” said Michael Ashley Schulman.</blockquote><p>This advisory may lead to further discussions regarding health warnings on alcoholic beverages, but its implementation remains unclear.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/alcohol-stocks-plunge-after-us-surgeon-general-calls-for-cancer-warnings-11735925872641.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/alcohol-stocks-plunge-after-us-surgeon-general-calls-for-cancer-warnings-11735925872641.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 17:43:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alcohol stocks drop after US Surgeon General urges cancer warning on labels - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Alcohol Stocks Drop After US Surgeon General Urges Cancer Warning on Labels</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today<br><strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><p>The US Surgeon General's call for cancer warnings on alcoholic drink labels has triggered a decline in shares of leading spirits makers and brewers.</p><ul><li>Surgeon General Vivek Murthy indicated that alcohol consumption increases the risk of various cancers, including breast and liver cancer.</li><li>Jack Daniel's parent company, Brown-Forman, saw shares drop nearly 3% in early trading, marking its lowest point since April 2017.</li><li>Other notable declines included Molson Coors and Constellation Brands, with Boston Beer experiencing a dip of up to 6.4%.</li><li>Implementation of the warning labels is uncertain, pending Congressional decision.</li><li>Expert Michael Ashley Schulman expressed skepticism about the effectiveness of such warning labels.</li></ul><blockquote>“Most Americans tend to believe that nearly everything is okay in moderation...I expect warning labels on alcohol to have little effect.” - Michael Ashley Schulman</blockquote><p>In Europe, major spirits manufacturers like Diageo and Pernod Ricard faced significant stock declines as well, indicating broader market concern.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/alcohol-stocks-drop-after-us-surgeon-general-urges-cancer-warning-on-labels-125010301147_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/alcohol-stocks-drop-after-us-surgeon-general-urges-cancer-warning-on-labels-125010301147_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 16:37:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everyone Can Play A Role In Fighting Superbugs In The Animal Health Sector - Health Policy Watch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNUE5ZeU5HR0tDcVk2NFd6Ym9hRFktVC1hNzdGb0RMa0swVjFlb1dUYi1IXzJOU1BELWoweG8xTnhpeldkZ3NZUGloblVNbVN5eTRpOXBEeVQxdS1Td3FzTnBRSWVpOVZlRkhBNk0tZHlnbUFnOVd6NWxHakRXZzlLQUMzblZkQ0dySEJCS19CZXY5MjE0X1hLNUxrUFlwMlNCNjNEbS1vZUpYd1k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNUE5ZeU5HR0tDcVk2NFd6Ym9hRFktVC1hNzdGb0RMa0swVjFlb1dUYi1IXzJOU1BELWoweG8xTnhpeldkZ3NZUGloblVNbVN5eTRpOXBEeVQxdS1Td3FzTnBRSWVpOVZlRkhBNk0tZHlnbUFnOVd6NWxHakRXZzlLQUMzblZkQ0dySEJCS19CZXY5MjE0X1hLNUxrUFlwMlNCNjNEbS1vZUpYd1k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 15:56:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surgeon General: Alcohol's Hidden Cancer Risk Demands Cigarette-Like Warnings - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxPM3lHam5NMFFadGRLaHlYaDk5S1NzZkZTajBib1d0enFqT3NwMFlHVU5IX216R0RJZXFjX0xVUWkzNXZRa1dmSDlyTDZfM19VS29ldHVxdUdUVUlDNjlWQ2U3WF9kNHJQTlA2anlYY1JFZmlqVkNfblU4ZkczWTYtUkoxR180NDdybUhpaXI0MzlFY2FIb0F0SzkzMmRRRUxqX2pMNmVLVHdRRmhpYjBicTVkTy0wZWxEMXRtOFlGU2xHWjNNOVkzWXg3d0xyRTNzdlVuakJvME1NRXBJVlM0MWRUMHRBUdIB6wFBVV95cUxPbXhtMW4wMldUNDBSRlo5NXRnMWtjblFFS05rMlFad2JfWGJBa3JYZHc0eEJKZVBOb044ekc0RHc5YVdRMmpKWkNUZ0dNekJRRUd5cklqVDZOTEZkZUxLU1NXMFQ0TEZ2enE5dzZ2SUdvZm92Q3dJczRtUEhmSXBwWmw3WGVxdEwtNTNLMGNYQUhVWXdRdUpGWUY1ZWVrZ1J3SGZnckQ5M2JRNk1HYlNhb25jSW5wWjdrUEpEWTBHdkszWTV0cWJ5MEJOaDZUTENCRXJLY1ZPcjFmS3VoWXA1LXdoeFRuZzFnZUJN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxPM3lHam5NMFFadGRLaHlYaDk5S1NzZkZTajBib1d0enFqT3NwMFlHVU5IX216R0RJZXFjX0xVUWkzNXZRa1dmSDlyTDZfM19VS29ldHVxdUdUVUlDNjlWQ2U3WF9kNHJQTlA2anlYY1JFZmlqVkNfblU4ZkczWTYtUkoxR180NDdybUhpaXI0MzlFY2FIb0F0SzkzMmRRRUxqX2pMNmVLVHdRRmhpYjBicTVkTy0wZWxEMXRtOFlGU2xHWjNNOVkzWXg3d0xyRTNzdlVuakJvME1NRXBJVlM0MWRUMHRBUdIB6wFBVV95cUxPbXhtMW4wMldUNDBSRlo5NXRnMWtjblFFS05rMlFad2JfWGJBa3JYZHc0eEJKZVBOb044ekc0RHc5YVdRMmpKWkNUZ0dNekJRRUd5cklqVDZOTEZkZUxLU1NXMFQ0TEZ2enE5dzZ2SUdvZm92Q3dJczRtUEhmSXBwWmw3WGVxdEwtNTNLMGNYQUhVWXdRdUpGWUY1ZWVrZ1J3SGZnckQ5M2JRNk1HYlNhb25jSW5wWjdrUEpEWTBHdkszWTV0cWJ5MEJOaDZUTENCRXJLY1ZPcjFmS3VoWXA1LXdoeFRuZzFnZUJN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 15:47:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Nothing to be alarmed': Centre on HMPV outbreak in China - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Centre Addresses HMPV Outbreak in China: No Cause for Alarm</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Health News Network</p><p>The Chinese health authorities have assured the public that there is no need for alarm regarding the recent outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV).</p><ul><li>HMPV is a known respiratory virus that can cause illness in people of all ages.</li><li>Health officials are monitoring the situation closely and have implemented public health measures.</li><li>The general public is advised to maintain personal hygiene practices to prevent infection.</li></ul><blockquote>"Health authorities stress that while HMPV can cause respiratory issues, most cases are mild and self-limiting."</blockquote><p>The outbreak has raised concerns, but health officials are working to keep the public informed and reassured.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/nothing-to-be-alarmed-centre-on-hmpv-outbreak-in-china/articleshow/116919387.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/nothing-to-be-alarmed-centre-on-hmpv-outbreak-in-china/articleshow/116919387.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Health Ministry monitors HMPV outbreak in China, says situation not alarming yet - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Health Ministry monitors HMPV outbreak in China, says situation not alarming yet</h1>
<p><strong>Published on: January 03, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png" alt="The Union Ministry maintained that while China has reported a rise in respiratory illness, particularly HMPV, India hasn’t registered any unusual spike in winter respiratory diseases. Representational file image" title="The Union Ministry maintained that while China has reported a rise in respiratory illness, particularly HMPV, India hasn’t registered any unusual spike in winter respiratory diseases. Representational file image" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Photo Credit: The Hindu</figcaption>
<p>The Union Health Ministry is closely monitoring the alleged outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in China, maintaining that India hasn’t recorded any unusual spikes in winter respiratory diseases.</p>
<ul>
  <li>China reports a surge in HMPV cases, especially in children under 14.</li>
  <li>Symptoms include cough, fever, and shortness of breath, with possible complications like bronchitis and pneumonia.</li>
  <li>No cases of HMPV have been reported in India yet.</li>
  <li>Hospitals in India are equipped to handle similar respiratory illnesses.</li>
  <li>The outbreak is not currently considered a cause for alarm.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“HMPV is like any other respiratory virus that causes flu-like symptoms, mostly in the elderly and children.” - Dr. Atul Goel</blockquote>
<p>This monitoring by the Ministry reflects a proactive approach to public health following recent respiratory illness reports in China.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/hmpv-alleged-outbreak-in-china-union-health-ministry-says-closely-monitoring-cases-no-cause-for-concern-right-now/article69058243.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/hmpv-alleged-outbreak-in-china-union-health-ministry-says-closely-monitoring-cases-no-cause-for-concern-right-now/article69058243.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smoking one cigarette could reduce 20 mins of life: University College London study - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Smoking One Cigarette Reduces Life Expectancy by 20 Minutes, Study Finds</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> January 3, 2025 | <strong>Published By:</strong> Rishab Chauhan</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/smoking-kills-015332996-16x9_0.jpeg?VersionId=dmG8Z9g7ylX2TW6YZ_PoRybr2a01Apc9&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="" title="Smoking remains one of the leading causes of preventable disease and death. In the UK, it is responsible for around 80,000 deaths annually and contributes to a quarter of all cancer deaths in England" height="388"><figcaption>Smoking remains one of the leading causes of preventable disease and death. In the UK, it is responsible for around 80,000 deaths annually and contributes to a quarter of all cancer deaths in England.</figcaption><p>A recent study from University College London reveals that smoking even one cigarette can reduce life expectancy by 20 minutes. Quitting smoking can lead to significant life expectancy gains.</p><ul><li>Smoking causes approximately 8 million deaths globally each year.</li><li>Each cigarette shortens life expectancy by around 20 minutes.</li><li>If a smoker quits, they could regain significant time: up to 50 days in a year.</li><li>Men lose an average of 17 minutes per cigarette; women lose about 22 minutes.</li><li>Smokers who quit can avoid losing around 10 years of life on average.</li><li>The study highlights the immediate and long-term health benefits of quitting.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no safe level of smoking,” said Prof. Sanjay Agrawal.</blockquote><p>The findings underscore the urgent need for smokers to quit as soon as possible to improve their health and longevity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/education-today/latest-studies/story/smoking-a-single-cigarette-cuts-20-minutes-off-life-2658205-2025-01-03</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/education-today/latest-studies/story/smoking-a-single-cigarette-cuts-20-minutes-off-life-2658205-2025-01-03</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:32:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025 best diet wins gold for wellness and disease prevention - CNN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2025 Best Diet: Mediterranean Diet Wins Again for Health and Wellness</h1>
<p><strong>Published: </strong><span>CNN</span></p>
<p>The Mediterranean diet has been awarded the title of the best diet for 2025 by U.S. News & World Report, reaffirming its status as a leading approach to wellness and disease prevention.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Mediterranean diet emphasizes fruits, vegetables, grains, olive oil, and healthy fats.</li>
  <li>This lifestyle promotes meals shared with family and friends, alongside regular physical activity.</li>
  <li>For the first time, the report utilized a five-star rating system for diets instead of ranking them numerically.</li>
  <li>New categories for diets addressing chronic conditions and stages of life, like menopause, have been introduced.</li>
  <li>Medical experts suggest a personalized approach to diets, emphasizing discussion with healthcare providers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Pretty much any product or item you’re looking at these days seems to get rated on a five-star scale.” - Gretel Schueller, managing editor of health</blockquote>
<p>The Mediterranean diet continues to receive recognition for its health benefits, highlighting the importance of plant-based options and community in improving overall wellness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/03/health/2025-best-diet-wellness/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/03/health/2025-best-diet-wellness/index.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[34-year-old woman with terminal cancer reveals five warning signs she ignored - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>34-Year-Old Woman with Terminal Cancer Shares Warning Signs She Ignored</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116919716,imgsize-38192,width-400,resizemode-4/116919716.jpg" alt="34-year-old woman with terminal cancer reveals five warning signs she ignored"><figcaption>A 34-year-old woman highlights warning signs of cancer that were overlooked.</figcaption><p>Cancer often develops silently in early stages showing subtle signs that can be mistaken for other illnesses. Linda Chavez, a 34-year-old mother, shares her experience of ignoring these signs until she was diagnosed with terminal lung cancer.</p><ul><li>Linda Chavez ignored a persistent cough that lasted for years.</li><li>She experienced shooting pain in her bones without realizing it indicated spreading cancer.</li><li>Chavez suffered from frequent headaches, which were eventually linked to her brain cancer.</li><li>Fatigue led her to feel excessively tired, compounded by breathing difficulties.</li><li>Nausea was another symptom that indicated her cancer had metastasized to her brain.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's no doubt the kids and family, friends, and social media followers breathe life into Lin and her fight.”</blockquote><p>The importance of recognizing these subtle symptoms cannot be overstated, as they can lead to earlier diagnosis and potentially more favorable outcomes in cancer treatment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/34-year-old-woman-with-terminal-cancer-reveals-five-warning-signs-she-ignored/articleshow/116919665.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/34-year-old-woman-with-terminal-cancer-reveals-five-warning-signs-she-ignored/articleshow/116919665.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 13:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diabetes: 7 low glycemic index superfoods to control blood sugar naturally - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diabetes: 7 Low Glycemic Index Superfoods to Control Blood Sugar Naturally</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2025<br /><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/MixCollage-03-Jan-2025-03-17-PM-3384.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&w=400&h=800" alt="Diabetes: 7 low glycemic index superfoods to control blood sugar naturally" /><figcaption>Overview of diabetic superfoods</figcaption><p>As diabetes management becomes increasingly crucial, incorporating low glycemic index superfoods can help in maintaining stable blood sugar levels.</p><ul><li>Soaked fenugreek seeds: Rich in soluble fibre, helps control diabetes and aids weight loss.</li><li>Moong dal: Low glycemic index, packed with dietary fiber, reduces glucose spikes.</li><li>Carrots: Contain carotenoids and other nutrients that help in glucose control.</li><li>Cinnamon tea: Known for its low GI, making it diabetes-friendly.</li><li>Green vegetables: Nutrient-packed options like broccoli and spinach fight oxidative stress.</li><li>Bitter gourd juice: Contains charantin which may regulate blood sugar.</li><li>Amla: Aids in blood sugar management and reduces sudden spikes.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is generic information and no substitute for medical advice."</blockquote><p>Incorporating these superfoods into a regular diet can offer natural solutions to help manage blood sugar levels effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/health/diabetes-7-low-glycemic-index-superfoods-to-control-blood-sugar-naturally-7511484/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/health/diabetes-7-low-glycemic-index-superfoods-to-control-blood-sugar-naturally-7511484/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 13:43:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. Surgeon General urges cancer warnings for alcoholic drinks - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>U.S. Surgeon General urges cancer warnings for alcoholic drinks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 03, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ca7wnz/article69057954.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/AP06_18_2024_000170B.jpg" alt="U.S. Surgeon General Dr. Vivek Murthy. File." title="U.S. Surgeon General Dr. Vivek Murthy. File."><figcaption>U.S. Surgeon General Dr. Vivek Murthy. File. | Photo Credit: AP</figcaption><p>The U.S. Surgeon General, Dr. Vivek Murthy, announced that alcoholic drinks should include labels warning consumers about the risk of cancer due to alcohol consumption, which can increase the risk of several cancer types, including breast and colon cancer.</p><ul><li>Dr. Murthy emphasized the need to reassess current guidelines on alcohol consumption limits in light of cancer risk.</li><li>Shares of U.S. alcoholic beverage companies dropped by 1% to 2% following the advisory.</li><li>Alcohol is linked to about 100,000 cancer cases and 20,000 cancer deaths in the U.S. each year.</li><li>The Surgeon General's office stated alcohol consumption is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the U.S.</li><li>The existing health warning labels for alcoholic beverages have not changed since 1988 and mainly address pregnancy and impairment issues.</li></ul><blockquote>"The direct link between alcohol consumption and cancer risk is well-established for at least seven types of cancer ... regardless of the type of alcohol that is consumed." - U.S. Surgeon General Dr. Vivek Murthy</blockquote><p>The report highlights the importance of increasing awareness and encouraging alcohol screening in healthcare practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/us-surgeon-general-urges-cancer-warnings-for-alcoholic-drinks/article69057887.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/us-surgeon-general-urges-cancer-warnings-for-alcoholic-drinks/article69057887.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 13:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Surgeon General calls for cancer warnings for alcoholic drinks - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Surgeon General Calls for Cancer Warnings on Alcoholic Beverages</h1><p><strong>Published: Jan 03 2025 | Source: Reuters</strong></p><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" title="Alcohol on flight" alt="Alcohol on flight | Photo by Ehioma on Pexels" width="826" height="465"><figcaption>Alcohol consumption is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the United States | Photo by Ehioma on Pexels</figcaption><p>The US Surgeon General advises that alcoholic drinks should include labels warning consumers about cancer risks, emphasizing the connection between alcohol consumption and various types of cancer.</p><ul><li>Alcohol is responsible for 100,000 cancer cases and 20,000 cancer deaths annually in the US.</li><li>Surgeon General Vivek Murthy suggests reassessing guidelines on alcohol consumption limits.</li><li>The report highlights alcohol as the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the US, after tobacco and obesity.</li><li>There is a well-established link between alcohol consumption and the risk of at least seven types of cancer.</li></ul><blockquote>"Alcohol consumption is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the United States, after tobacco and obesity, increasing risk for at least seven types of cancer." - US Surgeon General Vivek Murthy</blockquote><p>This call to action seeks to raise awareness of the serious health risks associated with alcohol consumption, similar to existing warnings about birth defects and impaired capabilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/us-surgeon-general-calls-for-cancer-warnings-for-alcoholic-drinks-125010300872_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/us-surgeon-general-calls-for-cancer-warnings-for-alcoholic-drinks-125010300872_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 13:12:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is there a solution for Parkinson's disease? Here is what Indian scientist has found - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is there a solution for Parkinson's disease? Here is what Indian scientist has found</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not mentioned <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/PArkinsons.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Parkinson's disease is a degenerative brain disorder (Representative Image, Freepik)">
<figcaption>Parkinson's disease is a degenerative brain disorder (Representative Image, Freepik)</figcaption>
<p>Parkinson’s disease is a common brain disorder affecting older individuals, characterized by the decline of dopamine levels. Recent findings from a scientist in Mohali suggest that melatonin may provide a therapeutic solution.</p>
<ul>
<li>Current medications only alleviate symptoms without curing the disease, highlighting the need for new treatments.</li>
<li>Researchers at the Institute of Nano Science and Technology (INST) Mohali have developed a nano-formulation of melatonin as a potential therapy.</li>
<li>The study indicates that melatonin could help mitigate Parkinson’s disease by inducing a process called mitophagy, which removes dysfunctional mitochondria.</li>
<li>The team successfully delivered melatonin using a biocompatible protein nanocarrier, leading to improved bioavailability and sustained release in the brain.</li>
<li>Results showed enhanced neuroprotective effects and improved mitochondrial functions in preclinical models.</li>
<li>Findings were published in the journal <em>ACS Applied Materials and Interfaces</em>.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our research indicates that targeting mitochondrial dysfunction with nano-melatonin improves therapeutic efficacy.” - Dr. Surajit Karmakar</blockquote>
<p>The research presents a hopeful step towards effectively managing Parkinson's disease, potentially changing treatment approaches for millions affected by this condition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/health/is-there-a-solution-for-parkinsons-disease-here-is-what-indian-scientist-has-found-7512475/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/health/is-there-a-solution-for-parkinsons-disease-here-is-what-indian-scientist-has-found-7512475/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:51:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["No Cause For Alarm": Indian Health Agency On HMPV Virus Spreading In China - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>No Cause For Alarm: Indian Health Agency Addresses HMPV Virus in China</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p><p>A top official from India's Directorate General of Health Services reassured the public not to panic about the spread of the Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in China and recommended general precautions against respiratory infections.</p><ul><li>Dr. Atul Goyal from DGHS stated that HMPV is similar to other respiratory viruses causing common cold symptoms.</li><li>He indicated there has been no significant rise in respiratory outbreaks in India, especially concerning December 2024 data.</li><li>The National Centre for Disease Control is monitoring respiratory viruses and collaborating with international agencies.</li><li>China assured transparency regarding COVID-19 data amid concerns over HMPV's spread.</li></ul><blockquote>“One thing I would like to convey to the public is to take general precautions that we use against all respiratory infections...” - Dr. Atul Goyal</blockquote><p>The health agency emphasizes that there is currently no cause for alarm, but vigilance and basic hygiene practices are necessary.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/no-cause-for-alarm-indian-health-agency-on-hmpv-virus-spreading-in-china-7392255</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/no-cause-for-alarm-indian-health-agency-on-hmpv-virus-spreading-in-china-7392255</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:43:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A single cigarette costs men 17 minutes of their life, and women…. - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A single cigarette costs men 17 minutes of their life, and women 22 minutes</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p> <img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/smoking_20241203083450.jpg" alt="nicotine"> <figcaption>Quitting tobacco is a life-changing decision. (File)</figcaption> <p>A new study from University College London reveals that smoking significantly reduces life expectancy, with men losing an average of 17 minutes and women losing 22 minutes per cigarette.</p> <ul> <li>The study surpassed previous estimates that suggested an 11-minute reduction per cigarette.</li> <li>Smoking introduces harmful chemicals that damage vital organs, leading to chronic diseases.</li> <li>Women are more affected than men due to hormonal vulnerability and different nicotine metabolism.</li></ul> <blockquote>“Smoking doesn’t just shorten life—it often reduces the quality of life, leading to years of chronic illness before death.” - Dr. Jayanta Thakuria</blockquote> <p>In conclusion, the data emphasizes the urgent need to quit smoking to enhance life quality and longevity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/single-cigarette-costs-men-17-minutes-of-life-and-women-22-shocking-study-9756528/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/single-cigarette-costs-men-17-minutes-of-life-and-women-22-shocking-study-9756528/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Loneliness linked to ill health through effect on protein levels, research suggests - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Loneliness Linked to Ill Health Through Protein Level Changes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 30, 2023 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The Guardian</p><p>Researchers have uncovered a biological mechanism linking loneliness to increased health risks, finding that it can impact protein levels associated with various diseases.</p><ul><li>Loneliness is linked to both physical and mental health issues.</li><li>The World Health Organization has recognized social isolation as a public health concern.</li><li>Analysis of data from over 42,000 UK Biobank participants revealed 175 proteins associated with social isolation and 26 with loneliness.</li><li>About 90% of these proteins are linked to mortality risk, with 50% linked to cardiovascular disease and diabetes.</li><li>Five proteins specifically influenced by loneliness were identified, with implications for heart disease and mental health.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“We found all these five proteins are related to numerous inflammation and metabolic markers,” Dr. Chun Shen, study author.</p></blockquote><p>This research emphasizes the importance of social connections for physical health and suggests that addressing loneliness could mitigate its health impacts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/jan/03/loneliness-ill-health-protein-levels-research</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/jan/03/loneliness-ill-health-protein-levels-research</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid reports of HMPV outbreak in China, doctors warn of 11 diseases that could trigger pandemic 2.0 like C - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingJBVV95cUxPNFJnRXlDN1luNmhpc2Q5akxOekpIRzhBMnZvTXY5ZVAwTmdVSzNsNkdqckRNenkyd0xGXzlkSTk2ekExVm13WUVibnRDdy1WNnZ1djBWYmc5dW42RGxMYlMtcGNDSnpkc0pYNmRRMUJDczdMZnd0LURwWF9QODd0UHRzdXNYZ3Q1ZEFxb284cXhrcnpwSDhvcFdkVXl0cExjUFdLcUlHQmlRcUg2TkpFNHVfUWZ2d2hrZkJkN0VLZVhpMW1FT0w4VnVKYmNTZWdZaGlMcF90OTByTGFkMW1fa0ZqaGZPMjFxcFVXM1ZydE1BNUVTZEo4QlFISHRCeGNYNTZVdUg5akwxcmdycFJoVi16M1pkMGNLRUw0SzlB0gGjAkFVX3lxTFBOTHVSOFVoOHRaeUl6NnFIMWxxYXRvNTduYUhsNW9iNlVZaE1mN1l5TEoyRjN5MFVUX2k3S3JlQVMzSWZTcl9JV1FIZEFNemNrdlJJLW5mTVFvTTY1SDNVNW1TbkRWRkREVl9XQlRYZjhtSWxaRThhN1hxRkJ5dGJnQ1ZuRXpMQTVEMDZuem15emQtX3pMWm92cFQ0TVJLZjQzMl9LanZocS1oVU5RNEhvYS1xcC1pUDNad1V4YlFsR1ZaMTNVSVN1dlhvWlNEX3Y5VGM4cU9GLXJkTU03Y1ZBa2kxRUp0NEtjN1FGUk5iMllRcTNPN2o0cDBtek8xQWpodVN6VllobUhUNnFXUGhkSXhWeWtJRnVZM1BtaW81SmUzVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingJBVV95cUxPNFJnRXlDN1luNmhpc2Q5akxOekpIRzhBMnZvTXY5ZVAwTmdVSzNsNkdqckRNenkyd0xGXzlkSTk2ekExVm13WUVibnRDdy1WNnZ1djBWYmc5dW42RGxMYlMtcGNDSnpkc0pYNmRRMUJDczdMZnd0LURwWF9QODd0UHRzdXNYZ3Q1ZEFxb284cXhrcnpwSDhvcFdkVXl0cExjUFdLcUlHQmlRcUg2TkpFNHVfUWZ2d2hrZkJkN0VLZVhpMW1FT0w4VnVKYmNTZWdZaGlMcF90OTByTGFkMW1fa0ZqaGZPMjFxcFVXM1ZydE1BNUVTZEo4QlFISHRCeGNYNTZVdUg5akwxcmdycFJoVi16M1pkMGNLRUw0SzlB0gGjAkFVX3lxTFBOTHVSOFVoOHRaeUl6NnFIMWxxYXRvNTduYUhsNW9iNlVZaE1mN1l5TEoyRjN5MFVUX2k3S3JlQVMzSWZTcl9JV1FIZEFNemNrdlJJLW5mTVFvTTY1SDNVNW1TbkRWRkREVl9XQlRYZjhtSWxaRThhN1hxRkJ5dGJnQ1ZuRXpMQTVEMDZuem15emQtX3pMWm92cFQ0TVJLZjQzMl9LanZocS1oVU5RNEhvYS1xcC1pUDNad1V4YlFsR1ZaMTNVSVN1dlhvWlNEX3Y5VGM4cU9GLXJkTU03Y1ZBa2kxRUp0NEtjN1FGUk5iMllRcTNPN2o0cDBtek8xQWpodVN6VllobUhUNnFXUGhkSXhWeWtJRnVZM1BtaW81SmUzVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:08:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Norovirus outbreak in the US: Warning signs and prevention measures explained by doctors - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Norovirus outbreak in the US: Warning signs and prevention measures explained by doctors</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116915928,imgsize-107106,width-400,resizemode-4/116915928.jpg" alt="Norovirus outbreak in the US" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Norovirus outbreak in the US: Warning signs and prevention measures explained by doctors</figcaption><p>With the rise of respiratory diseases, norovirus has emerged as a highly contagious infection causing increasing cases during the holiday season.</p><ul><li>The number of reported norovirus cases in the week of December 5 rose to 91, up from 69 the previous week.</li><li>Symptoms include vomiting, diarrhea, stomach pain, and fever, which can lead to dehydration.</li><li>High-risk groups include young children, older adults, and immunocompromised individuals.</li><li>No specific treatment exists, but hydration and rest are critical for recovery.</li><li>Preventative measures include frequent handwashing, disinfecting surfaces, and proper food handling.</li></ul><blockquote>“Common symptoms include diarrhea, vomiting, nausea, stomach pain, fever, headache, and body aches.” - Dr. Divya Joshi, Consultant-Infectious Diseases</blockquote><p>In conclusion, awareness and preventive measures are crucial during this norovirus outbreak, especially for vulnerable populations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/norovirus-outbreak-in-the-us-warning-signs-and-prevention-measures-explained-by-doctors/articleshow/116915933.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/norovirus-outbreak-in-the-us-warning-signs-and-prevention-measures-explained-by-doctors/articleshow/116915933.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Is Tularemia? US Sees Surge In Rare Rabit Fever Cases - NewsX]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxPRElaSUJUelg5emtFQ1VaRVpwdkdoOEdsbjU5bWtZMTRJTzUwalZMTVRJTGdza2JPbHhWeXZxaDloYUlrT3dfMGlhdVk5QkF0Z1VVa01rQTlFTnFkaXVUSndJQlJSY3hSX0RmcXotZlBWOFF3b1Nsbl9rbHFkM1l0Q2ptWGQwMGg1Mk1KNEgzRVg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxPRElaSUJUelg5emtFQ1VaRVpwdkdoOEdsbjU5bWtZMTRJTzUwalZMTVRJTGdza2JPbHhWeXZxaDloYUlrT3dfMGlhdVk5QkF0Z1VVa01rQTlFTnFkaXVUSndJQlJSY3hSX0RmcXotZlBWOFF3b1Nsbl9rbHFkM1l0Q2ptWGQwMGg1Mk1KNEgzRVg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 11:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is 'rabbit fever', the rare disease up by 56% in the US? Signs and symptoms explained - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What is 'rabbit fever', the rare disease up by 56% in the US? Signs and symptoms explained</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116915721,imgsize-18504,width-400,resizemode-4/116915721.jpg" alt="What is 'rabbit fever', the rare disease up by 56% in the US? Signs and symptoms explained"><figcaption>Image illustrating the rapid rise of rabbit fever cases.</figcaption><p>The incidence of tularemia, commonly known as rabbit fever, has increased by over 50% in the US in recent years, especially affecting younger children and vulnerable populations.</p><ul><li>The infection has seen a 56% rise in cases from 2011 to 2022 compared to 2001-2010.</li><li>More than 2,400 cases reported across 47 states, primarily in Arkansas, Kansas, Missouri, and Oklahoma.</li><li>The disease is categorized as a Tier 1 Select Agent due to its potential use as a bioweapon.</li><li>Transmission can occur through bites, contact with infected animals, ingestion of contaminated water, or inhalation of contaminated particles.</li></ul><h2>Signs and symptoms of Tularemia</h2><ul><li>Skin ulcers often appear at the site of entry, swelling nearby lymph nodes.</li><li>Eye irritation occurs when the bacteria enter through the eyes.</li><li>Sore throat and mouth ulcers can result from ingesting contaminated food or water.</li><li>Severe respiratory symptoms can develop if untreated, leading to chest pain and difficulty breathing.</li></ul><blockquote>“These findings might reflect an actual increase in human infection or improved case detection amid changes in commercially available laboratory tests during this period.” - CDC report</blockquote><p>Preventive measures include wearing protective clothing, using insect repellent, and avoiding untreated water. Although there is no vaccine, the illness is treatable with antibiotics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/what-is-rabbit-fever-the-rare-disease-up-by-56-in-the-us-signs-and-symptoms-explained/articleshow/116915634.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/what-is-rabbit-fever-the-rare-disease-up-by-56-in-the-us-signs-and-symptoms-explained/articleshow/116915634.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The mystery of what’s causing young people’s cancer leads to the gut | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Mystery of What’s Causing Young People’s Cancer Leads to the Gut</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Not provided]</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>Researchers have identified a focal point for the forces they suspect of driving up cancer cases in young people: the gut. Rates of gastrointestinal cancers among people under 50 are increasing globally, with colorectal cancer being particularly deadly.</p><ul><li>Gastrointestinal cancers are rising among individuals under 50.</li><li>Colorectal cancer is the leading cause of cancer death in men under 50 in the U.S.</li><li>Each generation born since the 1950s faces higher risk than its predecessors.</li></ul><blockquote>"Rates of gastrointestinal cancers among people under 50 are increasing across the globe."</blockquote><p>This exploration into the impacts of the gut on cancer cases may offer insights into prevention and treatment in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/health/the-mystery-of-what-s-causing-young-people-s-cancer-leads-to-the-gut-11735901960936.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/health/the-mystery-of-what-s-causing-young-people-s-cancer-leads-to-the-gut-11735901960936.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 11:08:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Urgent warning over salon hair treatment that poses 'unreasonable' risk of cancer - Daily Mail]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxOMHVfaXZBbE1GUE54c3kyWFcyOWpmRjZGb2JfN3BkYmp1eTQtOG4xZkxjN2xwd01GdW5KQVBEdzZaaWw1Y2xCQjlSQjNGNE8yYUV2aDk3RUxsWTdwNEJIeHF3YW0tLUZocWJ5ZTRVS1BfZUkwT2IxU1VwbFVIYk9WNEcxcGx6am9PcmI2RkJFS053MjM5eFJxNEVON2dPbWxXbEpGMjY5ZWoxNHJ6ZWZr0gG0AUFVX3lxTE9yMS1TV0JYUEp6QWsxcmJpV1FCYnBjZkVpNE5Yd2hfZDBqV3FKMS1kXzg5NG9tbVZUekUtazU4Q0tqZk9XY2dCWWlSMkVSOFd4N2xXNFVhUUpWYzhZTkt6OC1talhSQjQtYk9XWmdrOXdfVHZlSl8xRUVsNkFSYTZKa0xrUUgtUS0xbGV2V3M2cEExYW9yMlZHcUs5U0N0WXpNU05raG80M2ZGNWRZamsyZ21KVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxOMHVfaXZBbE1GUE54c3kyWFcyOWpmRjZGb2JfN3BkYmp1eTQtOG4xZkxjN2xwd01GdW5KQVBEdzZaaWw1Y2xCQjlSQjNGNE8yYUV2aDk3RUxsWTdwNEJIeHF3YW0tLUZocWJ5ZTRVS1BfZUkwT2IxU1VwbFVIYk9WNEcxcGx6am9PcmI2RkJFS053MjM5eFJxNEVON2dPbWxXbEpGMjY5ZWoxNHJ6ZWZr0gG0AUFVX3lxTE9yMS1TV0JYUEp6QWsxcmJpV1FCYnBjZkVpNE5Yd2hfZDBqV3FKMS1kXzg5NG9tbVZUekUtazU4Q0tqZk9XY2dCWWlSMkVSOFd4N2xXNFVhUUpWYzhZTkt6OC1talhSQjQtYk9XWmdrOXdfVHZlSl8xRUVsNkFSYTZKa0xrUUgtUS0xbGV2V3M2cEExYW9yMlZHcUs5U0N0WXpNU05raG80M2ZGNWRZamsyZ21KVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:59:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study reveals 12 questions that doctors should ask their patients to assess their brain health - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Study reveals 12 questions that doctors should ask their patients to assess their brain health</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/brain_1735899084495_1735899084696.jpg" alt="" /><figcaption> Here are the twelve questions that doctors should ask their patients. </figcaption></figure><p>The article discusses a study led by Dr. Linda M. Selwa that suggests preventative measures may be more effective than cures for managing neurological conditions affecting around 3 billion people globally. It emphasizes the importance of addressing various factors such as sleep, mood, nutrition, and social determinants of health.</p><ul><li>Doctors should assess sleep quality and patterns.</li><li>Address mood, anxiety, and stress concerns.</li><li>Evaluate food and nutrition security.</li><li>Understand physical activity frequency.</li><li>Consider social connections and their impact.</li><li>Discuss driving safety and trauma prevention.</li><li>Assess blood pressure and cardiovascular health.</li><li>Inquire about family history of neurological conditions.</li><li>Understand patient concerns regarding the cost of medicine.</li><li>Check vaccination status for infection prevention.</li><li>Address general safety concerns.</li><li>Consider societal factors impacting health.</li></ul><blockquote>"The study emphasizes that early intervention and prevention methods based on these questions can significantly impact a patient's health."</blockquote><p>This study provides insights that could lead to better care and management of neurological health in patients.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/study-reveals-12-questions-that-doctors-should-ask-their-patients-to-assess-their-brain-health-101735899019936-amp.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/study-reveals-12-questions-that-doctors-should-ask-their-patients-to-assess-their-brain-health-101735899019936-amp.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:43:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boost immunity and health with these 10 winter superfoods - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxOQV9zOXptSUZ2MVd5RGpRekpXbFlxODRscEZadWQ0QzVOT00wWE1nV2FHUVZPZDRQWkpfcUctMlBfZ08wdlBkZW9nVm4zUzJSdGVUTFdUOG4yelB0VGc3SGwwSlppWGpFZnp0MlhRTXVWaTBwVVAzMm1XcUkyZC1CYnZFSHJKOWJMclhza0FOYWdJNVBaOTloMnBLSjRiMmQ1bXVFQkxxd1dtR2hCSzBVSzlKODVuSDNIMWxtLVFGT0s4bmVTWVNhN1hLWdIBywFBVV95cUxOQV9zOXptSUZ2MVd5RGpRekpXbFlxODRscEZadWQ0QzVOT00wWE1nV2FHUVZPZDRQWkpfcUctMlBfZ08wdlBkZW9nVm4zUzJSdGVUTFdUOG4yelB0VGc3SGwwSlppWGpFZnp0MlhRTXVWaTBwVVAzMm1XcUkyZC1CYnZFSHJKOWJMclhza0FOYWdJNVBaOTloMnBLSjRiMmQ1bXVFQkxxd1dtR2hCSzBVSzlKODVuSDNIMWxtLVFGT0s4bmVTWVNhN1hLWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxOQV9zOXptSUZ2MVd5RGpRekpXbFlxODRscEZadWQ0QzVOT00wWE1nV2FHUVZPZDRQWkpfcUctMlBfZ08wdlBkZW9nVm4zUzJSdGVUTFdUOG4yelB0VGc3SGwwSlppWGpFZnp0MlhRTXVWaTBwVVAzMm1XcUkyZC1CYnZFSHJKOWJMclhza0FOYWdJNVBaOTloMnBLSjRiMmQ1bXVFQkxxd1dtR2hCSzBVSzlKODVuSDNIMWxtLVFGT0s4bmVTWVNhN1hLWdIBywFBVV95cUxOQV9zOXptSUZ2MVd5RGpRekpXbFlxODRscEZadWQ0QzVOT00wWE1nV2FHUVZPZDRQWkpfcUctMlBfZ08wdlBkZW9nVm4zUzJSdGVUTFdUOG4yelB0VGc3SGwwSlppWGpFZnp0MlhRTXVWaTBwVVAzMm1XcUkyZC1CYnZFSHJKOWJMclhza0FOYWdJNVBaOTloMnBLSjRiMmQ1bXVFQkxxd1dtR2hCSzBVSzlKODVuSDNIMWxtLVFGT0s4bmVTWVNhN1hLWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:33:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>