<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 23:23:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 23:23:36 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can’t find time to workout? 5 ways to move more and get slim - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can’t find time to workout? 5 ways to move more and get slim</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article discusses practical tips for individuals struggling to find time for formal workouts, offering simple ways to incorporate movement into their daily routines.</p><ul><li>Take the stairs instead of the elevator.</li><li>Walk during phone calls to keep active.</li><li>Engage in light exercises while watching TV.</li><li>Opt for standing desks when possible.</li><li>Incorporate walking meetings instead of sitting in a conference room.</li></ul><blockquote>“The key is consistency and finding small opportunities to move throughout the day.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, even small changes in daily routines can lead to better health and weight management without the need for structured exercise sessions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/weight-loss/cant-find-time-to-workout-5-ways-to-move-more-and-get-slim/articleshow/116345436.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/weight-loss/cant-find-time-to-workout-5-ways-to-move-more-and-get-slim/articleshow/116345436.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Chocolate May Reduce Diabetes Risk, Study Finds - THE INDIAN AWAAZ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxPQ01RbEpldWlYaXRjVUxwZ3pWam55VzNwZ0hiMHZ5SlFPNG5kMmJ4T2ZmdGViX3REbG14ODNfN0FzYXE4eHNNWHAtR1F1TXRIczhJdm1uOU1MNkJvLW9UblNGRUlGQmVyUWhZNHRSemZPenBSQW1YMjBIVHZLTWVmbHN0bC10UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxPQ01RbEpldWlYaXRjVUxwZ3pWam55VzNwZ0hiMHZ5SlFPNG5kMmJ4T2ZmdGViX3REbG14ODNfN0FzYXE4eHNNWHAtR1F1TXRIczhJdm1uOU1MNkJvLW9UblNGRUlGQmVyUWhZNHRSemZPenBSQW1YMjBIVHZLTWVmbHN0bC10UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 19:49:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 magnesium-rich foods to ward off winter blues - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/7-magnesium-rich-foods-to-ward-off-winter-blues/articleshow/116343628.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/7-magnesium-rich-foods-to-ward-off-winter-blues/articleshow/116343628.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yoga proven to prevent diabetes: RSSDI study released by Union Minister Jitendra Singh - Healthcare Radius]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthcareradius.in/awareness-and-promotion/yoga-proven-to-prevent-diabetes-rssdi-study-released-by-union-minister-jitendra-singh</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcareradius.in/awareness-and-promotion/yoga-proven-to-prevent-diabetes-rssdi-study-released-by-union-minister-jitendra-singh</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alarming Mutation in H5N1 Virus Raises Pandemic Red Flags - SciTechDaily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/alarming-mutation-in-h5n1-virus-raises-pandemic-red-flags/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scitechdaily.com/alarming-mutation-in-h5n1-virus-raises-pandemic-red-flags/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 16:56:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru Sees Increase In Flu-Like Symptoms, Respiratory Infections, Tips To Stay Safe - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru Sees Increase In Flu-Like Symptoms, Respiratory Infections, Tips To Stay Safe</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116342627,thumbsize-39030,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116342627.jpg" alt="Bengaluru Sees Increase In Flu-Like Symptoms, Respiratory Infections, Tips To Stay Safe" title="Bengaluru Sees Increase In Flu-Like Symptoms, Respiratory Infections, Tips To Stay Safe"><figcaption>Bengaluru Sees Increase In Flu-Like Symptoms, Respiratory Infections, Tips To Stay Safe (Image Credits: iStock)</figcaption><p>Bengaluru is witnessing a surge in flu-like symptoms and respiratory infections due to seasonal changes. Health experts cite cooler temperatures and increased indoor activity as contributing factors.</p><ul><li>The winter weather has led to an increase in illnesses such as seasonal flu, viral bronchitis, and respiratory allergies.</li><li>Dust, mould, and indoor pollutants are exacerbating respiratory symptoms.</li><li>Health experts recommend various precautions to stay safe this winter.</li><li>Maintain proper ventilation and clean air filters to ensure good indoor air quality.</li></ul><blockquote>"Good indoor air quality is crucial for respiratory health."</blockquote><p>By following simple tips, residents can lessen their risk of illness during this time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/health/bengaluru-sees-increase-in-flu-like-symptoms-respiratory-infections-tips-to-stay-safe-article-116342635</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/health/bengaluru-sees-increase-in-flu-like-symptoms-respiratory-infections-tips-to-stay-safe-article-116342635</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 16:40:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Are plant-based milk truly healthy or overhyped? - Mathrubhumi English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Are Plant-Based Milks Truly Healthy or Overhyped?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p>
<figure><img src="/image/contentid/policy:1.10167214:1734277482/plant-based-milk.jpg?$p=35e33af&amp;q=0.8" alt="plant milk"><figcaption>Representational image | photo:Canva</figcaption></figure>
<p>New research suggests that popular plant-based milk alternatives such as oat, almond, and soy milk may lack essential nutritional components compared to cow’s milk. The University of Copenhagen study indicates that processing methods can compromise protein quality and create potentially harmful compounds.</p>
<ul>
<li>The popularity of plant-based milks has increased, but they may be nutritionally inadequate compared to cow's milk.</li>
<li>Extensive processing, including ultra-high temperature treatments, diminishes protein quality and reduces essential amino acids.</li>
<li>Researchers found harmful compounds like acrylamide in certain plant-based beverages, raising potential health risks over time.</li>
<li>Despite being eco-friendly options, these drinks may not offer the same benefits as cow's milk.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Plant-based drinks cannot replace cow’s milk in terms of proper nutrition,” said Professor Marianne Nissen Lund.</blockquote>
<p>The findings highlight a need for consumers to be cautious about the nutritional value of plant-based milks and seek alternatives that can meet dietary needs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://english.mathrubhumi.com/lifestyle/food/are-plant-based-milk-healthy-option-compared-to-cow-milk-1.10167213</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://english.mathrubhumi.com/lifestyle/food/are-plant-based-milk-healthy-option-compared-to-cow-milk-1.10167213</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:48:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Timely surgical intervention at Kalaburagi hospital saves kidney cancer patient - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/timely-surgical-intervention-at-kalaburagi-hospital-saves-kidney-cancer-patient/article68988926.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/timely-surgical-intervention-at-kalaburagi-hospital-saves-kidney-cancer-patient/article68988926.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HPV Vaccination: A Crucial Cancer Prevention Step for Boys and Girls - PUNE.NEWS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://pune.news/health/hpv-vaccination-a-crucial-cancer-prevention-step-for-boys-and-girls-278579/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pune.news/health/hpv-vaccination-a-crucial-cancer-prevention-step-for-boys-and-girls-278579/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:42:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[High Cholesterol Causes: 5 Risk Factors of Excessive LDL Plaque Formation In Heart Arteries - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>High Cholesterol Causes: 5 Risk Factors of Excessive LDL Plaque Formation In Heart Arteries</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p><figure><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/High-Cholesterol-Causes-5-Risk-Factors-of-Excessive-LDL-Plaque-Formation-In-Heart-Arteries.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="High Cholesterol Causes: 5 Risk Factors of Excessive LDL Plaque Formation In Heart Arteries"><figcaption>High Cholesterol Causes: 5 Risk Factors of Excessive LDL Plaque Formation In Heart Arteries</figcaption></figure><p>The article discusses high cholesterol, particularly high levels of low-density lipoprotein (LDL), which is a significant risk for cardiovascular health. It outlines the top five risk factors contributing to LDL plaque formation in heart arteries.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Unhealthy Diet: Diets high in saturated and trans fats can raise LDL levels.</li><li>Not Exercising Regularly: Sedentary lifestyle increases cholesterol levels.</li><li>Excessive Weight or Obesity: Obesity correlates with high LDL and lower HDL cholesterol levels.</li><li>Genetic Contribution: Familial hypercholesterolemia influences cholesterol levels from a young age.</li><li>Excessive Smoking: Smoking contributes to high cholesterol and reduces HDL.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes</h2><blockquote>“Regular check-ups and blood tests are essential for monitoring cholesterol.”</blockquote><p>Taking control of risk factors can help manage cholesterol and improve heart health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/high-cholesterol-causes-5-risk-factors-of-excessive-ldl-plaque-formation-in-heart-arteries-1162892/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/high-cholesterol-causes-5-risk-factors-of-excessive-ldl-plaque-formation-in-heart-arteries-1162892/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Keeping bones healthy in winter: How to maintain bone health during cold months - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Keeping Bones Healthy in Winter: How to Maintain Bone Health During Cold Months</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Health News</p><p>This article discusses the importance of maintaining bone health during the colder months, providing practical tips and recommendations.</p><ul><li>Emphasizes the impact of cold weather on bone health.</li><li>Recommends activities to keep bones strong and healthy.</li><li>Highlights dietary considerations for bone density.</li></ul><blockquote>“Winter can be tough on our bones, but with the right care, we can keep them healthy.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, maintaining bone health in winter is crucial, and by following these tips, individuals can ensure their bones remain strong.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/keeping-bones-healthy-in-winter-how-to-maintain-bone-health-during-cold-months/articleshow/116340522.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/keeping-bones-healthy-in-winter-how-to-maintain-bone-health-during-cold-months/articleshow/116340522.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Are plant-based milks really healthy? Study finds out - mid-day.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQOE8wYVlsVFB6YTVSUng2UndGTHRuS2VFZWFtRzdFRm9NU0tTemRBSHllRHRUVHZKSUdvQmh5dEhOSkJQYlVBV3M4bjFnR2Y1UTlmQVFyQ0FRMDBIdmpNX3lKbG94Qm5DTklUdGotMTJ1TjltZE5xMlpUTkdvN3JzemRfbEFlbXpJN0JmQ0wwb05GZ0ppU3B5c2JwTzN0Sm9JdWpReVNpN0Mwd3kwWGkxY2pYN1U2aTdBcF80MUczQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQOE8wYVlsVFB6YTVSUng2UndGTHRuS2VFZWFtRzdFRm9NU0tTemRBSHllRHRUVHZKSUdvQmh5dEhOSkJQYlVBV3M4bjFnR2Y1UTlmQVFyQ0FRMDBIdmpNX3lKbG94Qm5DTklUdGotMTJ1TjltZE5xMlpUTkdvN3JzemRfbEFlbXpJN0JmQ0wwb05GZ0ppU3B5c2JwTzN0Sm9JdWpReVNpN0Mwd3kwWGkxY2pYN1U2aTdBcF80MUczQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flu Virus Found To Survive In Refrigerated Raw Milk: Study - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Flu Virus Found To Survive In Refrigerated Raw Milk: Study</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Sunday, December 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Free Press Journal</p><img src="https://media.assettype.com/freepressjournal/2024-12-15/idoeilvg/Aanchal-29.png" alt="Flu Virus Study Image"><figcaption>Research highlights risks of avian influenza transmission through raw milk.</figcaption><p>The study conducted by Stanford University reveals that the influenza virus can remain infectious in refrigerated raw milk for up to five days. This raises concerns about the potential health risks associated with raw milk consumption.</p><ul><li>The flu virus H1N1 PR8 remained infectious in raw milk at refrigeration temperatures.</li><li>More than 14 million Americans consume raw milk annually despite health risks from pathogens.</li><li>The FDA links raw milk to over 200 outbreaks of serious illnesses.</li><li>Pasteurization is effective in destroying infectious influenza but not all viral RNA.</li><li>Flu viruses infect over 40 million people in the U.S. each year, causing significant health issues.</li><li>Bird flu detection in cattle raises further concerns about transmission through dairy products.</li></ul><blockquote>"The persistence of infectious influenza virus in raw milk for days raises concerns about potential transmission pathways." - Mengyang Zhang</blockquote><p>The findings stress the importance of pasteurization and monitoring systems to manage food safety, especially amid ongoing bird flu outbreaks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/lifestyle/flu-virus-found-to-survive-in-refrigerated-raw-milk-study</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/lifestyle/flu-virus-found-to-survive-in-refrigerated-raw-milk-study</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poliovirus found in wastewater in Spain, Germany and Poland — what you need to know - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Poliovirus found in wastewater in Spain, Germany and Poland — what you need to know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/ai-2-1.jpg" alt="poliovirus"><figcaption>More is needed to safeguard immunisation programmes and prevent undoing decades of progress. (Source: Freepik)</figcaption><p>In recent months, traces of poliovirus have been found in wastewater in Germany, Spain, and Poland, signaling potential risks for public health and raising alarms for vaccination coverage across Europe.</p><ul><li>The WHO initiated a global effort to eradicate polio in 1988, achieving a 99% reduction in cases.</li><li>Polio is a highly contagious disease that can lead to paralysis and death, primarily spread through the faecal-oral route.</li><li>Despite significant gains in eradication, two countries, Pakistan and Afghanistan, remain endemic.</li><li>Detection of poliovirus in wastewater can warn healthcare systems of potential outbreaks.</li><li>Vaccine-derived poliovirus strains can revert to virulent forms if circulation occurs among under-immunised populations.</li></ul><blockquote>“The alert triggered by wastewater surveillance systems in Spain, Poland and Germany highlights how wastewater-based surveillance provides public health authorities with another weapon in the fight against infectious diseases.”</blockquote><p>The findings underscore the importance of monitoring vaccination coverage and enhancing public health responses to prevent polio's resurgence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/poliovirus-found-in-wastewater-in-spain-germany-and-poland-9725932/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/poliovirus-found-in-wastewater-in-spain-germany-and-poland-9725932/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:30:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Are Plant-Based Milks As Healthy As They Seem? Study Reveals Concerns Over Protein Quality And Potential Health Risks - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Are Plant-Based Milks As Healthy As They Seem? Study Reveals Concerns Over Protein Quality And Potential Health Risks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Zee News</p><p>Recent research indicates that popular plant-based milks like oat, almond, and soy may not provide the same nutritional benefits as cow's milk, raising concerns about protein quality and potential health risks due to processing methods.</p><ul><li>The study from the University of Copenhagen indicates that extensive processing may reduce protein quality in plant-based milks.</li><li>Plant-based milks typically contain less protein compared to cow's milk and may lose essential amino acids during ultra-high temperature (UHT) treatment.</li><li>Acrylamide, a known carcinogen, was found at low levels in some almond and oat-based drinks, leading to potential health risks over time.</li></ul><blockquote>“Plant-based drinks cannot replace cow’s milk in terms of proper nutrition.” - Professor Marianne Nissen Lund</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while plant-based milks are popular for their environmental benefits, their nutritional adequacy compared to traditional dairy remains in question.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/health/are-plant-based-milks-as-healthy-as-they-seem-study-reveals-concerns-over-protein-quality-and-potential-health-risks-2832062</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/health/are-plant-based-milks-as-healthy-as-they-seem-study-reveals-concerns-over-protein-quality-and-potential-health-risks-2832062</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:29:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bhabi Ji Ghar Par Hai Actress Saumya Tandon Reveals Life-Changing Benefits Of Quitting Sugar: Shares A Healthy Sweet Potato Halwa Recipe - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxPd2lZSklvZTlsdUl4R0tEbmdERG55Z1JJS1ZNQTBWcUdWbkNGQUwzalhWeVJvNjlYRnBVY1JqLWFfOTd5MDhVX3dIb0pEWHdramFfRFlYaTdta3RKbkZiallsVzFzQTNBdmx4Qm0zTFpRZEwyUnNTeFA0cmdaRGl2V0hiOEkyekZaYkEwNUUzMV9KUzVlRFR6dXFrOHNJMV9venEwM1VSdVBMaGFzUWkwa0ZfOHVMbjJCRlBqN0JLM3RpRzZsS19uTTVzQ3kzbk5LV3VlSno2N0tNNVlVdUtoN2Q3cDVEQmJtYmfSAe8BQVVfeXFMUDJUOGh3QmtZeVN4aFVLcElDUmpuRXlkNVVxSGV5dWJ4N1JqZmZ4bVZTZERrZXVEOGdhWHNJWXE0SVZNOHhCckdWTk1IbzhzNmM0N1pNZzkzMXl0M29fWVZoR3Z4Ull5YmVUdVNPN2hUU3Zub1RzS3dfWU85a0pTVVFfbnRwRFI4V2c0TnEtVlFsdnNYbXo0alhDd1NVbnktcXg0RDRUTm9nNUwxdFZuMnBIQkdMcHBkX2Z5ZmdhMnVsNzBlVHNuNGRXV2Jyb3M1UUZyUHFJbWNNNGJ3VDhIRXVSb01oM18yYVNLWlMyWjA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxPd2lZSklvZTlsdUl4R0tEbmdERG55Z1JJS1ZNQTBWcUdWbkNGQUwzalhWeVJvNjlYRnBVY1JqLWFfOTd5MDhVX3dIb0pEWHdramFfRFlYaTdta3RKbkZiallsVzFzQTNBdmx4Qm0zTFpRZEwyUnNTeFA0cmdaRGl2V0hiOEkyekZaYkEwNUUzMV9KUzVlRFR6dXFrOHNJMV9venEwM1VSdVBMaGFzUWkwa0ZfOHVMbjJCRlBqN0JLM3RpRzZsS19uTTVzQ3kzbk5LV3VlSno2N0tNNVlVdUtoN2Q3cDVEQmJtYmfSAe8BQVVfeXFMUDJUOGh3QmtZeVN4aFVLcElDUmpuRXlkNVVxSGV5dWJ4N1JqZmZ4bVZTZERrZXVEOGdhWHNJWXE0SVZNOHhCckdWTk1IbzhzNmM0N1pNZzkzMXl0M29fWVZoR3Z4Ull5YmVUdVNPN2hUU3Zub1RzS3dfWU85a0pTVVFfbnRwRFI4V2c0TnEtVlFsdnNYbXo0alhDd1NVbnktcXg0RDRUTm9nNUwxdFZuMnBIQkdMcHBkX2Z5ZmdhMnVsNzBlVHNuNGRXV2Jyb3M1UUZyUHFJbWNNNGJ3VDhIRXVSb01oM18yYVNLWlMyWjA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:13:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Feeling lonely? Study says loneliness increases your risk of developing dementia by 31% - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Feeling lonely? Study says loneliness increases your risk of developing dementia by 31%</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Dec 15, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/loneliness_1734266877386_1734266877631.jpg" alt="Loneliness deteriorates brain health.(Shutterstock)" />
<figcaption>Loneliness deteriorates brain health.(Shutterstock)</figcaption>
<p>A groundbreaking study published in Nature Mental Health finds that loneliness increases the risk of developing dementia by 31%. It emphasizes the severe impact of loneliness on brain health.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study analyzed data from 608,561 individuals worldwide.</li>
  <li>Loneliness was shown to be a crucial risk factor for dementia, comparable to smoking and lack of exercise.</li>
  <li>Researchers noted loneliness leads to cognitive decline and is linked to Alzheimer’s disease and vascular dementia.</li>
  <li>Lack of mental stimulation and chronic stress due to loneliness contribute to the risk of dementia.</li>
  <li>Loneliness can also lead to mild cognitive problems, indicating early effects before dementia onset.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is groundbreaking, as the risk factor of loneliness is similar to other commonly known risk factors for dementia.”</blockquote>
<p>This study highlights the urgent need for addressing loneliness as a public health issue, especially in light of its long-term implications for cognitive health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/feeling-lonely-study-says-loneliness-increases-your-risk-of-developing-dementia-by-31-101734266773856.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/feeling-lonely-study-says-loneliness-increases-your-risk-of-developing-dementia-by-31-101734266773856.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:05:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World can expect another zoonotic pandemic: Ex-WHO Director - Yes Punjab]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>World Can Expect Another Zoonotic Pandemic, Warns Ex-WHO Director</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Yes Punjab News</p><p>The world can anticipate another pandemic due to virus spillover from animals, according to Mario C.B. Raviglione, former Director of the WHO's Global TB Programme.</p><ul><li>Raviglione emphasizes the interconnectedness of the world as a key factor for rapid disease spread.</li><li>He states that many emerging diseases are zoonotic, with potential for new pathogens to emerge from animal species.</li><li>Recent diseases such as COVID-19, Ebola, and mPox highlight the risks associated with zoonotic diseases.</li><li>Preparedness for such pandemics is critically low among countries, leading to potential implications for global health.</li><li>Raviglione suggests the creation of preparedness hubs to enhance early detection and response capabilities.</li></ul><blockquote>“Preparedness implies that you need to have the support of laboratories, the support of pharma and biochemical, or the biochemical sector to rapidly develop the test...” - Mario C.B. Raviglione</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Raviglione calls for increased investment in pandemic preparedness to prevent disastrous outbreaks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://yespunjab.com/world-can-expect-another-zoonotic-pandemic-ex-who-director/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://yespunjab.com/world-can-expect-another-zoonotic-pandemic-ex-who-director/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:00:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doctor who diagnosed his own Alzheimer’s advises to NEVER ignore these warning signs - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/doctor-who-diagnosed-his-own-alzheimers-advises-to-never-ignore-these-warning-signs/articleshow/116260867.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/doctor-who-diagnosed-his-own-alzheimers-advises-to-never-ignore-these-warning-signs/articleshow/116260867.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does reduced water intake during winter increase the risk of kidney stones? Doctor explains - Indiatimes.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Does Reduced Water Intake During Winter Increase the Risk of Kidney Stones? Doctor Explains</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Indiatimes</p><p>As winter approaches, reduced water intake alongside increased consumption of hot drinks may lead to dehydration and an increased risk of kidney stones, according to Dr. Uday Dipakrao Gajare, Consultant Nephrologist.</p><img src="https://im.indiatimes.in/content/2023/Oct/big-test-min_6528266ce9a76.jpeg?w=32&amp;h=32&amp;cc=1&amp;webp=1&amp;q=75" alt="Water Intake and Kidney Stones"/><figcaption>Water Intake and Kidney Stones</figcaption><h2>Introduction</h2><p>Water is crucial for health, but in winter, people tend to drink less, which can lead to health issues, including dehydration and kidney stones.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Men should drink at least 3.1 liters of water daily, while women should consume 2.1 liters.</li><li>Reduced thirst in winter can increase the risk of kidney stones due to concentrated urine.</li><li>Kidney stones are major health problems characterized by hard deposits in the kidney.</li><li>Maintaining adequate hydration and diet is essential to prevent kidney stones.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes</h2><blockquote>“Hydration and salt intake play major roles in their formation.” - Dr. Uday Dipakrao Gajare</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>To prevent kidney stones in winter, it is essential to maintain hydration, reduce salt, and consume a balanced diet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatimes.com/health/does-reduced-water-intake-during-winter-increase-the-risk-of-kidney-stones-doctor-explains-648417.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatimes.com/health/does-reduced-water-intake-during-winter-increase-the-risk-of-kidney-stones-doctor-explains-648417.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:53:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can Omega-3 supplements slow prostate cancer? Research suggests so - Mathrubhumi English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can Omega-3 supplements slow prostate cancer? Research suggests so</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Mathrubhumi</p>
<img src="/image/contentid/policy:1.10166873:1734266286/omega3-cancer.jpg?$p=6f71f1b&amp;q=0.8" alt="omega 3">
<figcaption>Representational Image | photo: Canva</figcaption>
<p>A new study indicates that a diet low in omega-6 and high in omega-3 fatty acids may significantly slow the growth of prostate cancer cells in men with early-stage disease. Conducted by UCLA Health Sciences, the research highlights the importance of dietary adjustments in managing cancer growth.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study involved 100 men with low-risk prostate cancer who chose active surveillance.</li>
  <li>Participants were split into two groups: one followed an omega-3 rich diet with supplements; the other continued their normal diet.</li>
  <li>The omega-3 group showed a 15% decrease in the Ki-67 index, a measure of cancer cell proliferation.</li>
  <li>The control group experienced a 24% increase in the Ki-67 index.</li>
  <li>Dr. William Aronson emphasized that dietary changes might help delay the need for aggressive treatments.</li>
  <li>Further research is necessary to confirm these findings and their potential long-term benefits.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Dietary changes may help slow cancer growth, potentially delaying or even preventing the need for more aggressive treatments.” - Dr. William Aronson</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this study suggests that simple dietary adjustments could have significant implications for prostate cancer management, but further research is needed to verify these results over time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://english.mathrubhumi.com/lifestyle/health/low-omega-3-fish-oil-diet-slow-prostate-cancer-growth-1.10166838</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://english.mathrubhumi.com/lifestyle/health/low-omega-3-fish-oil-diet-slow-prostate-cancer-growth-1.10166838</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tired of Sleepless Nights? 7 Essential Sleep Hygiene Tips That Boosted Sleep Quality in 2024 - iDiva.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Essential Sleep Hygiene Tips for Better Sleep in 2024</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> iDiva</p><p>Sleep hygiene is crucial for maintaining mental and physical health, especially amidst our busy lives and constant distractions from gadgets. In 2024, improved sleep hygiene has helped many achieve better rest.</p><h2>7 Game-changing sleep hygiene habits that improved rest in 2024</h2><ul><li>Stick to a sleep-only zone to associate your bed with sleep.</li><li>Ditch late-night coffee to avoid caffeine’s stimulating effects.</li><li>Incorporate exercise into your routine to regulate sleep patterns.</li><li>Manage stress through meditation or using a weighted blanket.</li><li>Avoid heavy meals before bed to prevent sleep disturbances.</li><li>Establish a calming bedtime routine to ease into sleep.</li><li>Unplug from devices to minimize blue light exposure before sleeping.</li></ul><p>By incorporating these tips, individuals can improve their sleep quality significantly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.idiva.com/health-wellness/well-being/helpful-sleep-hygiene-tips-to-improve-sleep-quality-in-2024/18088164</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.idiva.com/health-wellness/well-being/helpful-sleep-hygiene-tips-to-improve-sleep-quality-in-2024/18088164</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:37:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Everyday Food that help to reduce anxiety and stress visual story - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxOWVBGMlU5OXUwV2xjVFFOV1pFMjdDenRqQ0g1Q0tUNDRXdXZDdGZTN3dDRkRsYVhtSUhBYWVYZTE0c2pqME5tcUlZX0VDRjNWUWUxRVhKZS1ES0thcGRtU3dTYk80Z0JCb2FPLUxYY0d2MEhTelRiaG5PRzdlelFjUDAyeTlFbFVSVFNYd1RrSF9jdlV4b01MQXl2NEtQY1hMQ2pmNUw1aDFTYjhnZ3RibGUtYmtoWnNNTmVralpMdGxhd9IBwgFBVV95cUxOWVBGMlU5OXUwV2xjVFFOV1pFMjdDenRqQ0g1Q0tUNDRXdXZDdGZTN3dDRkRsYVhtSUhBYWVYZTE0c2pqME5tcUlZX0VDRjNWUWUxRVhKZS1ES0thcGRtU3dTYk80Z0JCb2FPLUxYY0d2MEhTelRiaG5PRzdlelFjUDAyeTlFbFVSVFNYd1RrSF9jdlV4b01MQXl2NEtQY1hMQ2pmNUw1aDFTYjhnZ3RibGUtYmtoWnNNTmVralpMdGxhdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxOWVBGMlU5OXUwV2xjVFFOV1pFMjdDenRqQ0g1Q0tUNDRXdXZDdGZTN3dDRkRsYVhtSUhBYWVYZTE0c2pqME5tcUlZX0VDRjNWUWUxRVhKZS1ES0thcGRtU3dTYk80Z0JCb2FPLUxYY0d2MEhTelRiaG5PRzdlelFjUDAyeTlFbFVSVFNYd1RrSF9jdlV4b01MQXl2NEtQY1hMQ2pmNUw1aDFTYjhnZ3RibGUtYmtoWnNNTmVralpMdGxhd9IBwgFBVV95cUxOWVBGMlU5OXUwV2xjVFFOV1pFMjdDenRqQ0g1Q0tUNDRXdXZDdGZTN3dDRkRsYVhtSUhBYWVYZTE0c2pqME5tcUlZX0VDRjNWUWUxRVhKZS1ES0thcGRtU3dTYk80Z0JCb2FPLUxYY0d2MEhTelRiaG5PRzdlelFjUDAyeTlFbFVSVFNYd1RrSF9jdlV4b01MQXl2NEtQY1hMQ2pmNUw1aDFTYjhnZ3RibGUtYmtoWnNNTmVralpMdGxhdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:35:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is a 6-minute walking test (know what it can predict)? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/fitness/what-is-a-6-minute-walking-test-know-what-it-can-predict/articleshow/116337014.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/fitness/what-is-a-6-minute-walking-test-know-what-it-can-predict/articleshow/116337014.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paracetamol poses gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, and renal risks for seniors: Study - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:27:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can Ozempic cause sudden vision loss? A study uncovers the link - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/can-ozempic-cause-sudden-vision-loss-a-study-uncovers-the-link/articleshow/116339266.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/can-ozempic-cause-sudden-vision-loss-a-study-uncovers-the-link/articleshow/116339266.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Low-Calorie, High-Protein Diet helps Reduce Anxiety and Depression Symptoms in 15 Days: Study - Pune Pulse]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxNWTdOcTMzcFh3V2hSVFhVNFI0Q1ZmQmZJQXVpdjBRaHQ2emJNeUZHMlVSLUl5enpsR3c2a25HeUd2VlMxTFh6ekZYZFM3UEFFM1ZNWDRHSXJSVlJETURUOXNvUUp6QUZXSVpheDFvR1MteTRkX2FIZ2xLZGNLZ3FjWDN6b3dObHlnRkNiOGVUUC04U01YdC1fajQ0d0MxdWxFUEhILWV3aFBNVS1nU0RKTE9RN2tFSGVuUXpYMg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxNWTdOcTMzcFh3V2hSVFhVNFI0Q1ZmQmZJQXVpdjBRaHQ2emJNeUZHMlVSLUl5enpsR3c2a25HeUd2VlMxTFh6ekZYZFM3UEFFM1ZNWDRHSXJSVlJETURUOXNvUUp6QUZXSVpheDFvR1MteTRkX2FIZ2xLZGNLZ3FjWDN6b3dObHlnRkNiOGVUUC04U01YdC1fajQ0d0MxdWxFUEhILWV3aFBNVS1nU0RKTE9RN2tFSGVuUXpYMg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:18:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can Dark Chocolate Help Prevent Diabetes Risk? Here’s What Science Says - NewsX]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxQNHdfVW93NmlFc0E2clNCXzI4Zi1QbjFXeEFqcW5Fem40dEhnU1VBLVZIb3ZxTUw4RDlNZTd3VDJPX0pxTXlKajJTQTdSaG9HV0VlU0RFNzZXc2RJZGRYVzNfY3R4ck4zTzR1Ty00VHBQMFVMcmVpbHZSRXlCQ2tTbmJxVXpzQUE4OHhqWjlMVVhPRF9XbW5DckFjVHZMVHYt?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxQNHdfVW93NmlFc0E2clNCXzI4Zi1QbjFXeEFqcW5Fem40dEhnU1VBLVZIb3ZxTUw4RDlNZTd3VDJPX0pxTXlKajJTQTdSaG9HV0VlU0RFNzZXc2RJZGRYVzNfY3R4ck4zTzR1Ty00VHBQMFVMcmVpbHZSRXlCQ2tTbmJxVXpzQUE4OHhqWjlMVVhPRF9XbW5DckFjVHZMVHYt?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to treat eczema in winter to prevent a flare-up - Health shots]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxOMVJJWUpITUdqNDFlUnc1VnNXbDlrQVY1X1p0cUIyQlZhR2JHRGRTeGFCTmdXYXFVVWR4dTZlX3lkdEtEVWxoaFQyaXFjSUtnQ19tNzFTckFPYWpNZDNmRlRoX28wR2lLSDNkQnI2ZVBObkhZaXhKSnRMSmJDbE5GStIBhAFBVV95cUxQVnNFNVhGTVpvSDF0Q0pWQVV4X0VlTkZ2ZHBnNUlteERpa1NOcnVZZEl4MGdlOHMtNVU3TFY1RmlYc2dKS3lGRktfSU5GdTZ1Zzg0TVdwTHF3UVFNQUVBTW9rX1B5bWFrRHl3M3gzS2FuUzJlc3JfWlVSeGFfVmN2RUlaQ1A?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxOMVJJWUpITUdqNDFlUnc1VnNXbDlrQVY1X1p0cUIyQlZhR2JHRGRTeGFCTmdXYXFVVWR4dTZlX3lkdEtEVWxoaFQyaXFjSUtnQ19tNzFTckFPYWpNZDNmRlRoX28wR2lLSDNkQnI2ZVBObkhZaXhKSnRMSmJDbE5GStIBhAFBVV95cUxQVnNFNVhGTVpvSDF0Q0pWQVV4X0VlTkZ2ZHBnNUlteERpa1NOcnVZZEl4MGdlOHMtNVU3TFY1RmlYc2dKS3lGRktfSU5GdTZ1Zzg0TVdwTHF3UVFNQUVBTW9rX1B5bWFrRHl3M3gzS2FuUzJlc3JfWlVSeGFfVmN2RUlaQ1A?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:30:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paracetamol poses gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, and renal risks for seniors: Study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Paracetamol poses gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, and renal risks for seniors: Study</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified, <strong>Source: </strong>University of Nottingham</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116337532,imgsize-787125,width-400,resizemode-4/116337532.jpg" alt="Paracetamol poses gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, and renal risks for seniors: Study" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Paracetamol poses gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, and renal risks for seniors: Study</figcaption>
<p>Paracetamol, a common over-the-counter medication, poses significant risks to seniors, as revealed by a new study from the University of Nottingham.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study found increased risks of gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, and renal complications in people aged 65 and over using paracetamol.</li>
  <li>Data from 180,483 participants were analyzed, focusing on individuals aged 65 and older who had been prescribed paracetamol repeatedly.</li>
  <li>Findings indicated associations between paracetamol use and peptic ulcers, heart failure, hypertension, and chronic kidney disease.</li>
  <li>Prolonged use of paracetamol can lead to liver toxicity, particularly in seniors.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Due to its perceived safety, paracetamol has long been recommended as the first line drug treatment for osteoarthritis by many treatment guidelines..." - Professor Weiya Zhang</blockquote>
<p>The study calls for caution regarding the use of paracetamol among elderly patients, highlighting the need for alternative pain management strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/paracetamol-poses-gastrointestinal-cardiovascular-and-renal-risks-for-seniors-study/articleshow/116337547.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/paracetamol-poses-gastrointestinal-cardiovascular-and-renal-risks-for-seniors-study/articleshow/116337547.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>