<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 03:37:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 03:37:54 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia has developed its own cancer vaccine, to be distributed free of charge: News agency - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia has developed its own cancer vaccine, to be distributed free of charge</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> News agency</p>
<p>Russia has made significant progress in cancer treatment by developing a vaccine that will be made available to the public at no cost.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The vaccine aims to improve cancer treatment outcomes in the Russian population.</li>
  <li>Distribution will focus on accessibility for all citizens regardless of financial status.</li>
  <li>The initiative reflects Russia's commitment to addressing public health challenges.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This vaccine will mark a turning point in our fight against cancer," said a health official.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this development may pave the way for greater advancements in cancer research and treatment accessibility.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/russia-has-developed-its-own-cancer-vaccine-to-be-distributed-free-of-charge-news-agency/articleshow/116417627.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/russia-has-developed-its-own-cancer-vaccine-to-be-distributed-free-of-charge-news-agency/articleshow/116417627.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 02:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Health News Live December 18, 2024 : Yoga trends 2024: Desk yoga to eco-friendly practices, know the trends that ruled this year - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yoga trends 2024: Desk yoga to eco-friendly practices, know the trends that ruled this year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/10/550x309/yoga_1733829997350_1733829997660.jpg" alt="Latest news on December 18, 2024: “Yoga in 2024 was more dynamic than ever, blending tradition with innovation to meet the needs of a fast-paced, wellness-focused world," said yoga trainer Tanya Khanna." loading="lazy" decoding="async"><figcaption>“Yoga in 2024 was more dynamic than ever, blending tradition with innovation to meet the needs of a fast-paced, wellness-focused world,” said yoga trainer Tanya Khanna.</figcaption><p>This article discusses the major yoga trends that took center stage in 2024, focusing on how yoga has evolved to meet contemporary wellness needs.</p><ul><li>Yoga enhances the connection between body and mind.</li><li>Desk yoga has gained popularity as a practical solution for office workers.</li><li>Eco-friendly practices within yoga are becoming more prevalent.</li></ul><blockquote>“Yoga in 2024 was more dynamic than ever, blending tradition with innovation to meet the needs of a fast-paced, wellness-focused world,” said yoga trainer Tanya Khanna.</blockquote><p>The trends highlighted suggest a shift towards practices that integrate well-being into daily routines and embrace sustainability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/healthnewsliveupdatestoday-december-18-2024-101734489027754.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/healthnewsliveupdatestoday-december-18-2024-101734489027754.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 02:30:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Six reasons to start chewing guava leaves every day - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Six Reasons to Start Chewing Guava Leaves Every Day</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/heart.jpg" alt="Guava leaves can lower bad cholesterol (LDL) while raising good cholesterol (HDL), thus promoting cardiovascular health and reducing heart disease risks." decoding="async" width="1600" height="1066"><figcaption>Guava leaves can lower bad cholesterol (LDL) while raising good cholesterol (HDL), thus promoting cardiovascular health and reducing heart disease risks. (Source: Freepik)</figcaption><p>Guava leaves are a nutritious powerhouse, known for their antioxidants, vitamins, and anti-inflammatory properties. They have traditionally been used for health benefits and are gaining popularity as a natural remedy.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Rich source of vitamins, especially vitamin C and B, beneficial to immune and cognitive health.</li><li>Contains important minerals like calcium, potassium, magnesium, and iron for bone and cardiovascular health.</li><li>Antioxidants like quercetin help mitigate oxidative stress and inflammation.</li><li>Daily consumption aids digestion, balances blood glucose, strengthens the immune system, lowers bad cholesterol, reduces cancer risk, and alleviates menstrual cramps.</li></ul><blockquote>“Chewing guava leaves daily can provide numerous health benefits due to their rich nutrient profile.” - Kanikka Malhotra, Consultant Dietician</blockquote><p>Integrating guava leaves into your diet can enhance overall well-being, but moderation is key.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/food-wine/six-reasons-to-start-chewing-guava-leaves-every-day-9707833/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/food-wine/six-reasons-to-start-chewing-guava-leaves-every-day-9707833/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 02:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 2024 Wellness Trends With Real Staying Power - Oprah Mag]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The 2024 Wellness Trends With Real Staying Power</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Oprah Daily</p><img src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/rover/profile_photos/4df46b4c-35d5-459e-bbb9-50134ebd9dc6_1660158553.file?fill=1:1&resize=120:*" alt="Headshot of Cassie Hurwitz" title="Headshot of Cassie Hurwitz"><figcaption>Headshot of Cassie Hurwitz</figcaption><p>This article discusses the emerging wellness trends for 2024 that show promise for longevity and practical health benefits.</p><ul><li><strong>Trend #1: Vagus Nerve Stimulation</strong> - Connecting the brain and gut, vagus nerve stimulation could help with inflammation and chronic conditions.</li><li><strong>Trend #2: Home Diagnostic Tests</strong> - DIY health tests empower individuals to address their healthcare needs from home.</li><li><strong>Trend #3: Gua Sha</strong> - A facial technique that promotes circulation and can relieve tension and inflammation.</li><li><strong>Trend #4: Magnesium</strong> - This essential mineral aids relaxation and can help with various health issues, especially in women.</li><li><strong>Trend #5: Sleep Divorces</strong> - Couples are finding that sleeping apart can improve their relationships.</li></ul><blockquote>“More and more couples are saying see ya! at bedtime. And guess what? It works.”</blockquote><p>These trends reflect a shift towards more personalized and practical approaches to health and wellness, focusing on sustainability and long-term lifestyle adjustments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oprahdaily.com/life/health/a63162501/2024-wellness-trends/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oprahdaily.com/life/health/a63162501/2024-wellness-trends/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 21:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Men With History of Cannabis Use Have Less Cognitive Decline From Early Adulthood to Late Midlife - Pharmacy Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Men With History of Cannabis Use Have Less Cognitive Decline From Early Adulthood to Late Midlife</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024; <strong>Source:</strong> Brain and Behavior</p><img src="https://cdn.sanity.io/images/0vv8moc6/pharmacytimes/dc4bba9196876e6d03850d883f608779b399edfb-5742x3828.jpg?fit=crop&amp;auto=format" alt="Cannabis plant" title="Cannabis plant -- Image credit: cendeced | stock.adobe.com"><figcaption>Image credit: cendeced | stock.adobe.com</figcaption><p>This study investigates the relationship between cannabis use and cognitive decline among a male population, finding that those with a history of cannabis use exhibit less cognitive decline as they age compared to nonusers.</p><ul><li>The study utilized data from the Danish Aging and Cognition (DanACo) cohort involving 5162 men.</li><li>Findings suggest cannabis users experienced less cognitive decline, averaging 1.3 to 1.5 IQ points less than nonusers.</li><li>Approximately 39.3% of participants reported using cannabis at least once.</li><li>No significant relationship was found between the age of initiation of cannabis use and cognitive decline.</li><li>The study's limitations include a low participation rate (14.3%), which may affect the generalizability of the results.</li></ul><blockquote>"Cannabis users had a slightly higher average IQ at conscription, while nonusers experienced a mean cognitive decline of about 6.8 IQ points."</blockquote><p>The study provides insight into the long-term effects of cannabis use on cognitive decline, highlighting the need for further research, especially among diverse populations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pharmacytimes.com/view/men-with-history-of-cannabis-use-have-less-cognitive-decline-from-early-adulthood-to-late-midlife</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pharmacytimes.com/view/men-with-history-of-cannabis-use-have-less-cognitive-decline-from-early-adulthood-to-late-midlife</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 19:45:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TB still persists in J&K - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib0FVX3lxTFB2ek9zZEVZYXM5VHpjZmtGem9iODZHMmZBNDNmUnlzaGdKVk80YVE3RXd0U1d6V0pjcjYyR1lDTWFHTERsS1NINHR2Ty1LaFNFb0NSZGk4MVNGLXJKSUhuTGI1LUNNUnd3b2Y5TDlYZ9IBe0FVX3lxTE5OYzYzOThiMVZuOVlnbzFnYXU4YmhsemxOWWJjaFJqZlhCTDF1blN1ZmZFLTN0WFFob2FrUGlvbERsc1FFbnBuV0dCNFlIVGdiRVc3by1xdzNOVVAwVlYyaTlBa0ZWUGl5eGNSdUNyX1RzclBsVlN4Q0owOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib0FVX3lxTFB2ek9zZEVZYXM5VHpjZmtGem9iODZHMmZBNDNmUnlzaGdKVk80YVE3RXd0U1d6V0pjcjYyR1lDTWFHTERsS1NINHR2Ty1LaFNFb0NSZGk4MVNGLXJKSUhuTGI1LUNNUnd3b2Y5TDlYZ9IBe0FVX3lxTE5OYzYzOThiMVZuOVlnbzFnYXU4YmhsemxOWWJjaFJqZlhCTDF1blN1ZmZFLTN0WFFob2FrUGlvbERsc1FFbnBuV0dCNFlIVGdiRVc3by1xdzNOVVAwVlYyaTlBa0ZWUGl5eGNSdUNyX1RzclBsVlN4Q0owOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 19:30:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avian flu reported in 108 countries across five continents, says UN health agency - University of Nebraska Medical Center]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxNVURDLVhvN0JETEdlaFFIMlVCajBXNFI1bXoxd0FGcy1vVkJWMnRiVmNSdnhwQXhqVlBKd01DRkh5Z19KTE9jcE9hZkg5NVJfVHlTbGNtZTctMmdSSUZhYXFaUUhtRGdZYmxNbHNjamMxcDB3R3JxdGNCSmwxdlVtYkp5Rk45TFctWERqZHVRZmVLUWY1NnhiZWx5RFhjNENHSXlnbVNjUnkzVHVNaG1hcGwybURyenVsUFoyUW5XcWJTVmxILXEySVVjc2Y2UWpPeHFaekFXNnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxNVURDLVhvN0JETEdlaFFIMlVCajBXNFI1bXoxd0FGcy1vVkJWMnRiVmNSdnhwQXhqVlBKd01DRkh5Z19KTE9jcE9hZkg5NVJfVHlTbGNtZTctMmdSSUZhYXFaUUhtRGdZYmxNbHNjamMxcDB3R3JxdGNCSmwxdlVtYkp5Rk45TFctWERqZHVRZmVLUWY1NnhiZWx5RFhjNENHSXlnbVNjUnkzVHVNaG1hcGwybURyenVsUFoyUW5XcWJTVmxILXEySVVjc2Y2UWpPeHFaekFXNnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 19:28:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What To Do Under Pressure In The Cold - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What To Do Under Pressure In The Cold</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In cold-pressure situations, it is crucial to remain calm and implement practical strategies to manage the environment and personal safety effectively.</p><ul><li>Recognize signs of freezing temperatures and potential hazards.</li><li>Prioritize layered clothing to maintain warmth.</li><li>Stay hydrated and nourished even in low temperatures.</li><li>Understand basic survival mechanisms in cold conditions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Remaining calm is key to making the right decisions under pressure.”</blockquote><p>Preparation and knowledge of one’s environment can greatly enhance safety during cold weather challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/what-to-do-under-pressure-in-the-cold/articleshow/116409881.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/what-to-do-under-pressure-in-the-cold/articleshow/116409881.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avian flu reported in 108 countries across five continents, says UN health agency - UN News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Avian flu reported in 108 countries across five continents, says UN health agency</h1>
<p><strong>Date: 17 December 2024</strong><br><strong>Source: UN Health Agency</strong></p>
<p>Avian influenza has caused the deaths of more than 300 million birds worldwide and is increasingly crossing species barriers, according to UN health officers.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Dr. Madhur Dhingra of FAO warns the virus has infected over 500 bird species and at least 70 mammalian species.</li>
  <li>Avian influenza poses a serious threat to food and nutrition security in regions reliant on poultry.</li>
  <li>In 2024, 76 infections of H5 avian influenza in humans were reported, primarily among farm workers.</li>
  <li>Countries with reported cases include the US, Australia, Canada, China, Cambodia, and Vietnam.</li>
  <li>The risk of human-to-human transmission seems low, but precautions are necessary for those in close contact with infected animals.</li>
  <li>UN experts stress the importance of a One Health approach to manage avian influenza risks effectively.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We must remember, however, that this can change quickly as the virus is evolving.” - Dr. Maria Van Kerkhove, WHO</blockquote>
<p>This crisis underscores significant public health and agricultural challenges globally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.un.org/en/story/2024/12/1158286</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.un.org/en/story/2024/12/1158286</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:33:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Taxi and ambulance drivers less likely to die from Alzheimer's disease’ - The Week]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Taxi and Ambulance Drivers Have Lower Alzheimer's Disease Death Rates, Study Finds</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> British Medical Journal</p><p>A recent study has uncovered a surprising link between certain professions and a reduced risk of Alzheimer's disease. Researchers analysing death data from the US National Vital Statistics System found that taxi and ambulance drivers had the lowest proportion of deaths due to Alzheimer's disease compared to all other occupations.</p><img src='[Image URL]' alt='Taxi and ambulance drivers' /><figcaption>Taxi and ambulance drivers</figcaption><p>The study, published in the British Medical Journal, examined death data from nearly nine million adults across 443 different occupations. Among taxi drivers, only 1% (171 out of 16,658) died from Alzheimer's disease, while 0.74% (10 out of 1,348) of ambulance drivers succumbed to the disease. In contrast, approximately 4% of the general population had Alzheimer's disease listed as a cause of death.</p><ul><li>The frequent spatial and navigational processing in the jobs may provide a protective effect against Alzheimer's disease.</li><li>This finding is backed by previous studies on enhanced hippocampal function in taxi drivers.</li></ul><blockquote>“In an analysis of nearly all death certificates in the United States, taxi drivers and ambulance drivers, whose jobs require frequent spatial and navigational processing, were found to be the occupations with the two lowest risk-adjusted percentages of deaths due to Alzheimer's disease,” the authors wrote.</blockquote><p>While the study's findings are intriguing, researchers caution that no cause-and-effect conclusions can be drawn due to the observational nature of the study. Further research is necessary to determine whether the cognitive demands of these professions can prevent or reduce the risk of Alzheimer's disease.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theweek.in/news/health/2024/12/17/taxi-and-ambulance-drivers-less-likely-to-die-from-alzheimers-disease.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theweek.in/news/health/2024/12/17/taxi-and-ambulance-drivers-less-likely-to-die-from-alzheimers-disease.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:21:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New injectable variant of HIV-preventing drug in ‘poorest’ countries soon, claims health official - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Injectable HIV-Preventing Drug Aimed at World's Poorest Countries</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/_785cf906-10a4-11e8-8db2-4ddb0f8cfdad_1734452971825.jpg" alt="Lenacapavir, already approved for use in the United States, costs around $42,250 for the first year of therapy. (Representative image)(Shutterstock)" title="Lenacapavir, already approved for use in the United States, costs around $42,250 for the first year of therapy. (Representative image)(Shutterstock)"> <figcaption>Lenacapavir, already approved for use in the United States, costs around $42,250 for the first year of therapy. (Representative image)(Shutterstock)</figcaption> <p>A new variant of Lenacapavir, a drug used to treat multi-resistant HIV, could be available for use in the world’s poorest countries by the end of 2025 or early 2026. The new formulation comes with a year-long active potency and could play a preventive role in defense against HIV.</p> <ul> <li>Gilead Sciences is seeking FDA and WHO approval for global rollout.</li> <li>The Global Fund aims to partner with PEPFAR to enable affordable access to the drug.</li> <li>Gilead is working to manufacture cheaper versions of Lenacapavir in 120 countries.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“We don't want low and low-middle income countries to wait, to be at the back of the line when these approvals come in.” - Hui Yang, Global Fund</blockquote> <p>This new injectable drug could significantly improve access to HIV prevention methods in underprivileged regions, benefiting millions at risk of infection.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/new-injectable-variant-of-hiv-preventing-drug-in-poorest-countries-soon-claims-health-official-101734451480196.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/new-injectable-variant-of-hiv-preventing-drug-in-poorest-countries-soon-claims-health-official-101734451480196.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 16:39:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['There is hope': GRAND Mental Health sharing resources to help with seasonal depression - 2 News Oklahoma KJRH Tulsa]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘There is hope’: GRAND Mental Health sharing resources to help with seasonal depression</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Tulsa World</p><p>The holiday season can bring joy but also seasonal depression for many. Resources are available from GRAND Mental Health to assist those in need.</p><ul><li>Seasonal Affective Disorder (SAD) affects many individuals, with symptoms including low mood and changes in sleep patterns.</li><li>In Oklahoma, 160,000 adults lack mental health assistance.</li><li>Financial stress and grief are common triggers for SAD.</li><li>GRAND Mental Health offers a 24/7 mobile crisis team and urgent recovery centers for support.</li></ul><blockquote>“Again, you don’t have to do this alone. There is hope, and there is healing, so reach out for help.” - Kim Hill-Crowell</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.kjrh.com/news/local-news/there-is-hope-grand-mental-health-sharing-resources-to-help-with-seasonal-depression</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.kjrh.com/news/local-news/there-is-hope-grand-mental-health-sharing-resources-to-help-with-seasonal-depression</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 16:15:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Treatment Insights and Evolving Care Options in Vitiligo - Dermatology Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Treatment Insights and Evolving Care Options in Vitiligo</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Dermatology Times</p>
<img src="https://cdn.sanity.io/images/0vv8moc6/dermatologytimes/5d308c4d3e80a44e65d14de34b590adfd08709e0-4096x2160.png?fit=crop&amp;auto=format" alt="Dermatology Insights">
<figcaption>Innovations in vitiligo treatment options.</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the complexities of vitiligo care and the potential of innovative topical therapies as highlighted by experts during a recent conference.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Individualized treatment approaches for pediatric vitiligo emphasized.</li>
  <li>Innovative therapies such as topical ruxolitinib show promising results.</li>
  <li>Importance of patient and family education on the condition discussed.</li>
  <li>Advancements in JAK inhibition and their implications noted.</li>
  <li>Emotional support is crucial for managing vitiligo's impact on self-esteem.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We want to explain [to parents] that we continue to have evolution in the field of interventions, which will give both a positive perspective towards management and treatment.” - Lawrence Eichenfield, MD</blockquote>
<p>The evolving landscape includes new therapies that offer hope for improved outcomes in patients with vitiligo, particularly children and adolescents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dermatologytimes.com/view/treatment-insights-and-evolving-care-options-in-vitiligo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dermatologytimes.com/view/treatment-insights-and-evolving-care-options-in-vitiligo</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 16:10:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[REACH demonstrates model for care, support of migrant persons with TB - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>REACH demonstrates model for care, support of migrant persons with TB</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>REACH, a not-for-profit organisation, has demonstrated a comprehensive model to provide tailored care for migrant people with tuberculosis (MPwTB) in Tamil Nadu.</p><img src="path-to-image.jpg" alt="Image description" /><figcaption>Illustration of REACH's TB care initiative.</figcaption><p>The initiative includes screening, care packages, and community outreach aimed at improving diagnosis and treatment adherence among migrants.</p><ul><li>11,564 people with TB screened, 36.6% identified as migrants.</li><li>Launch of the ‘ARISE’ project for community-based TB and health risk sensitisation.</li><li>Challenges faced by migrants include stigma and delayed diagnosis.</li><li>Success rate of TB treatment reached 91% through follow-ups.</li><li>Recommendations for enhancing TB services tailored to migrants, including multilingual support and community health worker training.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is important to understand that migrants are not a homogenous group.” - Ramya Ananthakrishnan, REACH’s director</blockquote><p>This project highlights the need for focused healthcare solutions for vulnerable migrant populations to improve TB care and outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/chennai/reach-demonstrates-model-for-care-support-of-migrant-persons-with-tb/article68996222.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/chennai/reach-demonstrates-model-for-care-support-of-migrant-persons-with-tb/article68996222.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diarrhea-causing superbug is on the loose; stirs up trouble in Los Angeles - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diarrhea-causing superbug is on the loose; stirs up trouble in Los Angeles</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116407118,imgsize-61314,width-400,resizemode-4/116407118.jpg" alt="Diarrhea-causing superbug is on the loose; stirs up trouble in Los Angeles" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Diarrhea-causing superbug is on the loose</figcaption><p>A dangerous diarrhea-causing superbug is spreading fast and stirring up trouble in Los Angeles. Researchers have identified a new strain of Shigella bacteria resistant to most antibiotics.</p><ul><li>UCLA scientists tracked an unusual cluster of Shigella cases from 2023 to 2024, revealing the presence of an extensively drug-resistant (XDR) strain.</li><li>This discovery has been tagged as ‘alarming’ due to the potential for widespread transmission.</li><li>Symptoms of Shigella infection can lead to severe diarrhea, especially in vulnerable populations like young children and the elderly.</li><li>The superbug poses a growing public health concern, with CDC reporting a rise in cases involving XDR strains.</li></ul><blockquote>“The discovery of a novel XDR S. sonnei actively spreading in Los Angeles is alarming.” - UCLA Researchers</blockquote><p>The emergence of XDR Shigella complicates treatment, with a significant public health threat acknowledged by health officials. The continuous spread necessitates immediate attention in monitoring and managing infections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/diarrhea-causing-superbug-is-on-the-loose-stirs-up-trouble-in-los-angeles/articleshow/116407144.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/diarrhea-causing-superbug-is-on-the-loose-stirs-up-trouble-in-los-angeles/articleshow/116407144.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Researchers say drinking coffee could help you live two years longer - Women's Health UK]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Drinking Coffee Could Help You Live Almost Two Years Longer, Says New Study</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Women's Health Magazine</p><p>Could your morning cup of <a href='https://www.womenshealthmag.com/uk/food/a62542977/caffeinated-coffee-tea-heart-disease-risk-study/' target='_blank'>coffee</a> help you live longer? New research suggests yes.</p><img src='path_to_image.jpg' alt='Coffee' /><figcaption>Drinking coffee is associated with increased longevity.</figcaption><p>The analysis conducted by researchers at the University of Coimbra examined over 50 studies on coffee consumption and lifespan.</p><ul><li>Regular coffee drinkers may add an average of 1.8 years of healthy living.</li><li>Coffee intake reduces major causes of mortality such as cardiovascular diseases and cancer.</li><li>Social interaction while drinking coffee can also promote longevity.</li></ul><blockquote>‘Coffee does contain polyphenols that have been associated with a decreased risk of adverse health conditions,’ says registered dietitian Jessica Cording.</blockquote><p>The study indicates that moderate coffee consumption may offer health benefits and promote a longer life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.womenshealthmag.com/uk/food/a63213215/coffee-live-longer-study/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.womenshealthmag.com/uk/food/a63213215/coffee-live-longer-study/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:32:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't replace home-cooked meals with ready-to-eat foods. Here's why - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Don't replace home-cooked meals with ready-to-eat foods. Here's why</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Firstpost</p><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/12/ready-to-eat-pixabay-2024-12-7300ff13eb287566a92ccb545321156a.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Don't replace home-cooked meals with ready-to-eat foods. Here's why"><figcaption>A recent study has revealed that while ready to eat snacks may meet basic nutrition claims, their ingredients are dominated by carbohydrates and fats, raising red flags for long-term health.</figcaption><p>The increasing consumption of convenience foods in India poses serious health concerns, as a recent study shows that these products are generally high in carbohydrates and fats but low in nutritional value.</p><ul><li>The demand for convenience foods in India has surged, with revenue projected to grow significantly.</li><li>A study analyzing over 400 popular items found over 70% of their energy comes from carbohydrates.</li><li>High sodium and trans fat levels were noted, particularly in soup mixes.</li><li>Discrepancies were found in product claims versus actual ingredients.</li><li>Low-GI foods are scarce, impacting diabetes management among a large population.</li></ul><blockquote>“Preferably avoid processed foods as much as possible,” Dr. RM Anjana advised.</blockquote><p>Consumers are urged to read labels carefully and be cautious about convenience foods due to potential health risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/health/dont-replace-home-cooked-meals-with-ready-to-eat-foods-heres-why-13845303.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/health/dont-replace-home-cooked-meals-with-ready-to-eat-foods-heres-why-13845303.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:31:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New research reveals how the body clock regulates inflammation - Medical Xpress]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPYWxrczYydVVKT0tQdFhzbExHTVNIWHRuYzlhZWhKSVFTZjdiN1JsTElkRnYzcXNNYzBobFdlME02bTZkampfQWNqVlR4X0hEUXg3Z1pib05admlEMjJpaXlfMkVLZVd2TkNyYm1xZlZfQWkxT1lwMGVyZUt3anBnYQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPYWxrczYydVVKT0tQdFhzbExHTVNIWHRuYzlhZWhKSVFTZjdiN1JsTElkRnYzcXNNYzBobFdlME02bTZkampfQWNqVlR4X0hEUXg3Z1pib05admlEMjJpaXlfMkVLZVd2TkNyYm1xZlZfQWkxT1lwMGVyZUt3anBnYQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:22:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Role Does Regenerative Medicine Play In The Management Of Type 1 And Type 2 Diabetes? - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What Role Does Regenerative Medicine Play In The Management Of Type 1 And Type 2 Diabetes?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/regenerative-medicine-for-diabetes-1.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="What Role Does Regenerative Medicine Play In The Management Of Type 1 And Type 2 Diabetes?" width="900" height="375">
  <figcaption>Lately, there has been a growing interest towards regenerative medicine, which focuses on restoring lost normal activities by replacing or repairing damaged cells, tissues, or organs. (Photo: Freepik)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Regenerative medicine holds significant promise for the treatment of type 1 and type 2 diabetes through innovative therapies, potentially reshaping diabetes management.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Diabetes is classified into type 1 (autoimmune destruction of insulin-producing cells) and type 2 (insulin resistance).</li>
  <li>Dr. Pradeep Mahajan discusses promising new therapies like stem cell transplantation and gene therapy.</li>
  <li>Complications from unmanaged diabetes can include heart disease, kidney damage, and more.</li>
  <li>Regenerative techniques could help replace damaged cells and enhance the body's healing process.</li>
  <li>Current research focuses on regenerating insulin-producing cells and improving insulin action.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Maintaining a good glucose level in the blood is critical...regenerative medicine...focuses on restoring lost normal activities." - Dr. Pradeep Mahajan</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, regenerative medicine is paving the way for future diabetes treatments, with the potential to transform management practices for both type 1 and type 2 diabetes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/what-role-does-regenerative-medicine-play-in-the-management-of-type-1-and-type-2-diabetes-1163749/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/what-role-does-regenerative-medicine-play-in-the-management-of-type-1-and-type-2-diabetes-1163749/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bavarian Nordic partners to boost mpox vaccine production - The Pharma Letter]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bavarian Nordic partners to boost mpox vaccine production</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Pharmaletter</p><img src="https://cdn.thepharmaletter.com/convert/files/2024/06/cdcb9a70-2252-11ef-ad1f-e33a28dd5e74-vaccine.jpg/r%5Bwidth%5D=320/cdcb9a70-2252-11ef-ad1f-e33a28dd5e74-vaccine.webp" alt="" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Bavarian Nordic's mpox vaccine Jynneos</figcaption><p>Bavarian Nordic consolidates its partnership with India's Serum Institute to enhance the production of the mpox vaccine Jynneos, facilitating local manufacturing and addressing global vaccine accessibility.</p><ul><li>Bavarian Nordic has signed a licensing and manufacturing agreement with Serum Institute of India.</li><li>The deal follows a profit-sharing model without upfront payments, allowing SII to produce and distribute the vaccine in India.</li><li>It boosts global capacity amidst the push for equitable vaccine access.</li><li>Both parties will conduct a technology transfer for the vaccine's manufacturing process.</li><li>SII will manage regulatory approvals in India.</li></ul><blockquote><strong>“The agreement enables local manufacturing and distribution in India under a profit-sharing model.”</strong></blockquote><p>This partnership is pivotal in increasing vaccine availability in light of ongoing health challenges and reflects the commitment to equitable distribution of healthcare solutions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thepharmaletter.com/biotechnology/bavarian-nordic-partners-to-boost-mpox-vaccine-production</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thepharmaletter.com/biotechnology/bavarian-nordic-partners-to-boost-mpox-vaccine-production</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:14:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How bat poop turned deadly for two men growing marijuana - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How bat poop turned deadly for two men growing marijuana</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown<br><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>Two marijuana growers faced severe health consequences due to exposure to bat droppings, which can harbor dangerous pathogens.</p><ul><li>The incident highlights the often-overlooked health risks associated with animal waste.</li><li>Authorities are warning individuals involved in similar activities to take precautions.</li><li>This is a rare case, emphasizing the unexpected dangers in seemingly ordinary settings.</li></ul><blockquote>“The health risks of animal waste should not be underestimated.”</blockquote><p>This incident serves as a grave reminder of the potential hazards in commercial agriculture, particularly those involving wildlife.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/how-bat-poop-turned-deadly-for-two-men-growing-marijuana/articleshow/116406298.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/how-bat-poop-turned-deadly-for-two-men-growing-marijuana/articleshow/116406298.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Worried About Osteoporosis? 4 Ways to Help Prevent the Disease - Yale Medicine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Worried About Osteoporosis? 4 Ways to Help Prevent the Disease</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Yale Medicine</p><p>Osteoporosis is a serious condition that mainly affects older women by weakening their bones. This article discusses key steps to prevent osteoporosis or lessen its effects.</p><ul><li>Osteoporosis affects an estimated 10 million Americans, with women making up 80% of those affected.</li><li>Proper nutrition, including calcium and vitamin D, is critical for bone health.</li><li>Weight-bearing exercises can strengthen bones and reduce the risk of fractures.</li><li>Fall prevention strategies are essential to avoid injuries related to osteoporosis.</li></ul><blockquote>“The big picture is that the benefits of these medications outweigh the risks, and their use merits a serious discussion between the patient and the provider.” - Dr. Clemens Bergwitz</blockquote><p>Preventing osteoporosis involves a combination of lifestyle changes and, if necessary, medication. Regular check-ups and bone density tests can help monitor bone health over time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.yalemedicine.org/news/osteoporosis-prevention</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yalemedicine.org/news/osteoporosis-prevention</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:53:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clearing up a foggy memory - Harvard Health]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTE1icmRzQ0pYbDhjSVhIdk5yWi0zdjRoYzlaMkJZRExsN2o5aEpMRWpUb1hBVFRNNjJibXBLd1lrU2VlMVptd1RqcmdaSFVDR2Z4Yzl6anFwWEFUWFNpQzVvclk5RExrVEFrYWNIeGR1cWY4cmdFRzVtS2FxTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTE1icmRzQ0pYbDhjSVhIdk5yWi0zdjRoYzlaMkJZRExsN2o5aEpMRWpUb1hBVFRNNjJibXBLd1lrU2VlMVptd1RqcmdaSFVDR2Z4Yzl6anFwWEFUWFNpQzVvclk5RExrVEFrYWNIeGR1cWY4cmdFRzVtS2FxTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:53:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Higher Ambient Levels of Air Pollutants Linked to Increased VTE Risk - Pulmonology Advisor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Higher Ambient Levels of Air Pollutants Linked to Increased VTE Risk</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 12, 2023 | Source: HealthDay News</strong></p>
<img width="100" height="100" src="https://www.pulmonologyadvisor.com/wp-content/themes/hm-advisor-child/assets/svg/key-point_icon.svg">
<figcaption>Higher ambient levels of air pollutants are associated with increased risk for venous thromboembolism.</figcaption>
<p>The study indicates that chronic exposure to air pollution significantly elevates the risk of developing venous thromboembolism (VTE).</p>
<ul>
  <li>The research involved 6,651 participants from the Multi-Ethnic Study of Atherosclerosis.</li>
  <li>Participants were studied over a median follow-up of 16.7 years, during which 248 VTE events occurred.</li>
  <li>Hazard ratios for VTE were reported as 1.39 for PM<sub>2.5</sub>, 2.74 for NO<sub>2</sub>, and 2.21 for NO<sub>x</sub>.</li>
  <li>The study highlights that higher levels of specific air pollutants correlate with increased VTE risk.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Chronic exposure to air pollution...adds to mounting evidence that air pollution adversely impacts health.”</blockquote>
<p>This research emphasizes the health risks associated with air pollution and reinforces the need for public health measures to reduce pollution levels.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pulmonologyadvisor.com/news/higher-ambient-levels-of-air-pollutants-linked-to-increased-vte-risk/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pulmonologyadvisor.com/news/higher-ambient-levels-of-air-pollutants-linked-to-increased-vte-risk/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reduced Postpartum Depression and Anxiety Symptoms are Linked to Exercise - The Cardiology Advisor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Reduced Postpartum Depression and Anxiety Symptoms are Linked to Exercise</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> British Journal of Sports Medicine</p><p>A minimum of 80 minutes per week of moderate intensity exercise can lead to moderate reductions in severity of postpartum depressive symptoms, according to new research.</p><ul><li>The study included 35 studies with 4072 participants, focusing on postpartum individuals.</li><li>Exercisers showed a 40% lower odds of developing postpartum depression compared to non-exercisers.</li><li>Benefits were greater when exercise started within 12 weeks postpartum.</li><li>Results indicate a dose-response effect: more exercise correlates with greater reduction in depressive symptoms.</li></ul><blockquote>“There appears to be a dose-response effect of this benefit: a greater exercise volume was associated with a greater reduction in the severity of depressive symptoms,” the study authors noted.</blockquote><p>The research highlights the importance of early exercise interventions in reducing postpartum depression and anxiety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thecardiologyadvisor.com/news/does-exercise-help-anxiety-and-depression-in-postpartum-individuals-research-points-to-yes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thecardiologyadvisor.com/news/does-exercise-help-anxiety-and-depression-in-postpartum-individuals-research-points-to-yes/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A US farm breeds pigs for human kidney transplants - Yahoo! Voices]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidkFVX3lxTE9xM0dwSGN4Um9WZXlVQjUwMm84MXpQMzI5LXFxVGwybG93VnJSQ1NRM0FVcDhKZVNBN2IxRG0xVG9faW5SbnhPSEZhelFTNWRkT0MtRVIwc2pLcWFQR3ZEQzdlSlY4R0dDRkcxdk05MnVNMTdLU0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidkFVX3lxTE9xM0dwSGN4Um9WZXlVQjUwMm84MXpQMzI5LXFxVGwybG93VnJSQ1NRM0FVcDhKZVNBN2IxRG0xVG9faW5SbnhPSEZhelFTNWRkT0MtRVIwc2pLcWFQR3ZEQzdlSlY4R0dDRkcxdk05MnVNMTdLU0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doctors raise concern over rising lung cancers among non-smokers in India - DTNEXT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Doctors raise concern over rising lung cancers among non-smokers in India</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Monday</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> IANS</p>
<p>Lung cancer, traditionally affecting smokers, is increasingly seen in non-smokers in India, raising concerns among health experts, particularly due to rising air pollution.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Recent research indicates that most lung cancer patients in India are non-smokers.</li>
    <li>Lung cancer is occurring approximately 10 years earlier in India than in Western countries.</li>
    <li>There is a worrying trend of younger individuals, especially women, being diagnosed with lung cancer.</li>
    <li>Key risk factors include air pollution, radon exposure, and indoor cooking fumes.</li>
    <li>India reports around 75,000 new lung cancer cases annually, often diagnosed at advanced stages.</li>
    <li>Advancements in treatment options include minimally invasive surgical techniques and targeted therapies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“India's lung cancer demographic presents a unique and concerning picture...” - Dr. Prasad Adusumilli</blockquote>
<p>This rising trend in lung cancer among non-smokers requires urgent attention to address environmental and lifestyle risk factors, alongside advancements in treatment to improve patient outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dtnext.in/lifestyle/wellbeing/doctors-raise-concern-over-rising-lung-cancers-among-non-smokers-in-india-815644</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dtnext.in/lifestyle/wellbeing/doctors-raise-concern-over-rising-lung-cancers-among-non-smokers-in-india-815644</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:25:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New HIV prevention drug could reach poorest countries by 2025, says health official - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/new-hiv-prevention-drug-could-reach-poorest-countries-by-2025-says-health-2024-12-17/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/new-hiv-prevention-drug-could-reach-poorest-countries-by-2025-says-health-2024-12-17/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:15:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bird Flu Threat: Is the Next Human Pandemic Coming? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxQODFUNXdXZ2tDNWJHSktqMnRRVVJqNzVCczhzbTJrcU53ME9wbnBEem9FNGR6aDZLUVZYaXJjeTMyMHB2cEtFdTZCdHRjWW5OUTl0OFJvZ3hSeWxnN2p3OE9HQ2tqTlNnTGtydkxzRDg3X2p6Yml4QU5IU1pRM2FrRWcxZGFIUTlzVmh1OUxqZmlLUEJaUkdwTmZKWlQyUVZObWdFTEtoZkpENDBwQjctU3BUQU9QYVZkVk95N1ZlaWNFVmvSAcgBQVVfeXFMT1ZSOERaaHR5UGtvRi1tYUVXYXE1NVF5WlR2WW1odFI5YTNDWEdpYlNYZDVuVkxCTlZLVnpzaUNDMDJtS1oxbzNvTGxuWDdGX1U4RGpMYk1KNXJiQVVNRzFTalJlYW9YTFBVTGI5RElweFdMejJOV1R4UVBNWnBEV2VhQ2o5MEFYOTIxd0pOQ3NLVk5QREJEU1g2akpRbUNhS3FkWU1LWHBWemU2MXBPNVlhTWhjcVRQWHMzTV8yUzh5R005S3NYQUM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxQODFUNXdXZ2tDNWJHSktqMnRRVVJqNzVCczhzbTJrcU53ME9wbnBEem9FNGR6aDZLUVZYaXJjeTMyMHB2cEtFdTZCdHRjWW5OUTl0OFJvZ3hSeWxnN2p3OE9HQ2tqTlNnTGtydkxzRDg3X2p6Yml4QU5IU1pRM2FrRWcxZGFIUTlzVmh1OUxqZmlLUEJaUkdwTmZKWlQyUVZObWdFTEtoZkpENDBwQjctU3BUQU9QYVZkVk95N1ZlaWNFVmvSAcgBQVVfeXFMT1ZSOERaaHR5UGtvRi1tYUVXYXE1NVF5WlR2WW1odFI5YTNDWEdpYlNYZDVuVkxCTlZLVnpzaUNDMDJtS1oxbzNvTGxuWDdGX1U4RGpMYk1KNXJiQVVNRzFTalJlYW9YTFBVTGI5RElweFdMejJOV1R4UVBNWnBEV2VhQ2o5MEFYOTIxd0pOQ3NLVk5QREJEU1g2akpRbUNhS3FkWU1LWHBWemU2MXBPNVlhTWhjcVRQWHMzTV8yUzh5R005S3NYQUM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:09:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024's Most Popular Healthy Foods To Start Your Day With - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNa2lZWDZpY3dJdmRTVUFmUmtpZElKaDF2a3VRZDVQZFhIcnpnaGZnNFFZaUduVDFTVEo5TWhnVUYzNGtpZkpCd0tTNjZtVldYdThOMHhiVFRUY2p1NXppaE4yazR6VlpES1dubU9FY2hCYXZyS2JUWFpnLUNSd2J2bnp2dVpUY1ZUZ3lQTnlfdXlBMEh5RVHSAZ4BQVVfeXFMUHJQajh2OGx3WEd4MlVNUVhJdk1rUkxicmdHWG0zOWhJVHNHSm90dHBIRFhwQk9NZGUxcldPZlN1NEJYZ3hmMmszUnBrZ3RpRlVtYjdlWlRVa09sSlRFa24wTUtwQ1k2VEVQUDJkZi1uQWZYdHh3NkxncDA2b2JHcHRPdmduZ3V5clZ4NlBSeXFrdWVwNWlqSF9WUTRFcmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNa2lZWDZpY3dJdmRTVUFmUmtpZElKaDF2a3VRZDVQZFhIcnpnaGZnNFFZaUduVDFTVEo5TWhnVUYzNGtpZkpCd0tTNjZtVldYdThOMHhiVFRUY2p1NXppaE4yazR6VlpES1dubU9FY2hCYXZyS2JUWFpnLUNSd2J2bnp2dVpUY1ZUZ3lQTnlfdXlBMEh5RVHSAZ4BQVVfeXFMUHJQajh2OGx3WEd4MlVNUVhJdk1rUkxicmdHWG0zOWhJVHNHSm90dHBIRFhwQk9NZGUxcldPZlN1NEJYZ3hmMmszUnBrZ3RpRlVtYjdlWlRVa09sSlRFa24wTUtwQ1k2VEVQUDJkZi1uQWZYdHh3NkxncDA2b2JHcHRPdmduZ3V5clZ4NlBSeXFrdWVwNWlqSF9WUTRFcmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:07:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>