<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:21:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:21:11 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sierra Leone declares public health emergency over mpox - DW (English)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxONVd6bXljQ0RpdUI1NHVnWW03M09Hd29qS2FLZ055N1ZXQVBRWWhSS2hoWHVlOFBqbmM0T05fTFlncnRGYkdCUVAyQlRzaHdoM2VXRjl4VGxZQ3c1X2Z3V041aEJ6V3M2ZEVJOXZRUURMYlFQNFBic3ZoaF96UDRMcE42b1Fxa1FQZ0NIUUN6TUU3UdIBkgFBVV95cUxQX2w3NEVsaU9QMko5UzR1dkNrTTJEM3o1Q3FpRVVYR0JXQWtDaTNrU3VIYU51UDYycVlDTVh4UmppZkVQWm1DTGxfd2hDNjhBZGFRWTQxemtYZUkzREd2OXl0QzQ4X2dpcDdaSkRhUmRJcEUwX0FqUG43M0tYOEpBVjlNelUzb1ZhcjNLaTNLRDMxUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxONVd6bXljQ0RpdUI1NHVnWW03M09Hd29qS2FLZ055N1ZXQVBRWWhSS2hoWHVlOFBqbmM0T05fTFlncnRGYkdCUVAyQlRzaHdoM2VXRjl4VGxZQ3c1X2Z3V041aEJ6V3M2ZEVJOXZRUURMYlFQNFBic3ZoaF96UDRMcE42b1Fxa1FQZ0NIUUN6TUU3UdIBkgFBVV95cUxQX2w3NEVsaU9QMko5UzR1dkNrTTJEM3o1Q3FpRVVYR0JXQWtDaTNrU3VIYU51UDYycVlDTVh4UmppZkVQWm1DTGxfd2hDNjhBZGFRWTQxemtYZUkzREd2OXl0QzQ4X2dpcDdaSkRhUmRJcEUwX0FqUG43M0tYOEpBVjlNelUzb1ZhcjNLaTNLRDMxUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:50:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Risks of taking vitamin D in the wrong way and how to take it safely - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Risks of Taking Vitamin D in the Wrong Way and How to Take It Safely</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117200913,imgsize-502022,width-400,resizemode-4/117200913.jpg" alt="Risks of taking vitamin D in the wrong way and how to take it safely" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Vitamin D is essential but needs to be taken correctly to avoid health risks.</figcaption>
<p>Vitamin D, known as the 'sunshine vitamin', is crucial for bone health and immune function. However, improper intake can lead to severe health complications.</p>
<ul>
<li>Vitamin D toxicity can occur from excessive intake, leading to symptoms like nausea and kidney damage.</li>
<li>Improper vitamin D use may cause calcium imbalances, resulting in kidney stones and cardiovascular issues.</li>
<li>Gastrointestinal problems can arise from incorrect dosages, especially when taken on an empty stomach.</li>
<li>Vitamin D can interact with certain medications, potentially reducing their effectiveness.</li>
<li>Consulting with a healthcare provider before starting supplementation is essential.</li>
<li>Prior testing is recommended to determine appropriate supplementation levels.</li>
<li>Vitamin D should be taken with meals containing healthy fats for better absorption.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Avoid excessive doses unless prescribed by a healthcare provider.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, understanding how to take vitamin D safely is key to maximizing its health benefits while minimizing risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/vitamin-d-risks-of-taking-vitamin-d-in-the-wrong-way-and-how-to-take-it-safely/articleshow/117200923.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/vitamin-d-risks-of-taking-vitamin-d-in-the-wrong-way-and-how-to-take-it-safely/articleshow/117200923.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Health News Live January 14, 2025 : Trying to lose weight? Dietician says, avoid these five breakfast options - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Health Live: Trying to lose weight? Dietician says, avoid these five breakfast options</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/breakfast_1736772653976_1736772672664.jpg" alt="Latest news on January 14, 2025: “5 breakfasts I would never recommend as a dietician," wrote Muntaha." loading="lazy" decoding="async"><figcaption>Latest news on January 14, 2025: “5 breakfasts I would never recommend as a dietician," wrote Muntaha.</figcaption><p>In this article, a dietician lists five breakfast options to avoid for effective weight loss.</p><ul><li>Paratha with butter or ghee</li><li>Puris with halwa</li><li>Chana</li></ul><p>For more details, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/trying-to-lose-weight-dietician-says-avoid-these-five-breakfast-options-101736772551240.html">read the full story here</a>.</p><blockquote>“5 breakfasts I would never recommend as a dietician," wrote Muntaha.</blockquote><p>The advice from dieticians can be pivotal in the journey of weight loss, highlighting unhealthy habits and guiding better choices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/health-news-live-updates-today-january-14-2025-101736818216979.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/health-news-live-updates-today-january-14-2025-101736818216979.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:30:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bioengineers found breakthrough in building smart cells, potential to detect autoimmune disease: Study - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bioengineers found breakthrough in building smart cells, potential to detect autoimmune disease: Study</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p>
<img src="https://img.etb2bimg.com/files/cp/upload-1716881542-ethealthworld.webp" alt="Smart Cells" width="590" height="442">
<figcaption>Smart cells developed to respond to disease markers.</figcaption>
<p>Rice University bioengineers have developed a new construction kit for building custom sense-and-respond circuits in human cells. This research signifies a major breakthrough in synthetic biology that could provide new therapies for complex conditions like autoimmune diseases and cancer.</p>
<ul>
<li>The new construction kit allows for creating smart cells that can detect specific cellular signals.</li>
<li>This innovation could lead to immediate releases of customizable treatments in response to detected signs of diseases.</li>
<li>The research was published in the journal <em>Science</em>.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Imagine tiny processors inside cells made of proteins that can 'decide' how to respond to specific signals like inflammation or tumor growth markers," said Xiaoyu Yang, lead author of the study.</blockquote>
<p>This groundbreaking work suggests a shift in synthetic biology and cellular therapies, offering hope for more advanced treatments for serious health conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://health.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/medical-devices/bioengineers-found-breakthrough-in-building-smart-cells-potential-to-detect-autoimmune-disease-study/117218868</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://health.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/medical-devices/bioengineers-found-breakthrough-in-building-smart-cells-potential-to-detect-autoimmune-disease-study/117218868</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watching reels at night? Late-night social media use may cause hypertension, new study suggests - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watching reels at night? Late-night social media use may cause hypertension, new study suggests</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> BMC</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117211980,imgsize-19102,width-400,resizemode-4/117211980.jpg" alt="Watching reels at night? Late-night social media use may cause hypertension, new study suggests" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Watching reels at night? A new study suggests a link between late-night social media use and hypertension.</figcaption>
<p>A recent study has revealed a concerning correlation between late-night screen time spent on short videos and the risk of developing hypertension among young and middle-aged adults.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study involved 4,318 Chinese participants focusing on screen time before bed.</li>
  <li>More hours spent watching short videos at night increased the risk of hypertension.</li>
  <li>Dr. Deepak Krishnamurthy emphasized the dangers of distractions from short video addiction.</li>
  <li>Recommendations include limiting late-night screen time to improve sleep hygiene and prevent hypertension.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Short video addiction does not only present a significant distraction but also helps in raising blood pressure." - Dr. Deepak Krishnamurthy</blockquote>
<p>The findings underscore the need for individuals, especially the youth, to adopt healthier screen habits and lifestyles to mitigate the risk of hypertension.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/spotlight/watching-reels-at-night-late-night-social-media-use-may-cause-hypertension-new-study-suggests/articleshow/117211789.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/spotlight/watching-reels-at-night-late-night-social-media-use-may-cause-hypertension-new-study-suggests/articleshow/117211789.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another child tests positive for HMPV in Puducherry, 3 cases reported so far - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Another child tests positive for HMPV in Puducherry, 3 cases reported so far</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p>
<figure><img src="https://img.etb2bimg.com/files/cp/upload-1716881542-ethealthworld.webp" alt="HMPV in Puducherry"><figcaption>Another child tests positive for HMPV in Puducherry</figcaption></figure>
<p>Puducherry has reported its third case of Human metapneumovirus (HMPV) as another child tested positive. The Director of Medical Services stated that the latest case had symptoms of fever and cough and was admitted to JIPMER on January 10. Fortunately, the child is recovering well.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Third reported case of HMPV in Puducherry.</li>
  <li>Previous cases involved children aged three and five.</li>
  <li>Puducherry government is enhancing hospital infrastructure for better management.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The child was recovering well,” - Director of Medical Services V Ravichandran.</blockquote>
<p>This emergence of HMPV cases in Puducherry is concerning, and the administration is taking necessary steps to manage the situation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://health.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/industry/another-child-tests-positive-for-hmpv-in-puducherry-3-cases-reported-so-far/117218749</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://health.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/industry/another-child-tests-positive-for-hmpv-in-puducherry-3-cases-reported-so-far/117218749</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:16:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Refractory Dysmenorrhea Managed With a Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Agonist: A Case Report - Cureus]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxNNG16Q082VmtmVV9jbDhoVnRjSmRTbDliQkJQZlRPVW4tZjNlcndUcVE5SXZQOW1JMFhvejlNQ1JpeFNoR2NzLVNJYTZKeUFGTjZYbHNrUHZfMzZOX18xS09CNHJReGEzdmZrVFNpNGdSWktGTzNLZl9iV0tYM3lXRDZsZDBNcl80a3FLdUg2MGxBYnF5emoxblJQQk8yWVNpcXZfMDhfdm9XcW83UkhkN01zSjBsbjdUSVhqeVFrME8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxNNG16Q082VmtmVV9jbDhoVnRjSmRTbDliQkJQZlRPVW4tZjNlcndUcVE5SXZQOW1JMFhvejlNQ1JpeFNoR2NzLVNJYTZKeUFGTjZYbHNrUHZfMzZOX18xS09CNHJReGEzdmZrVFNpNGdSWktGTzNLZl9iV0tYM3lXRDZsZDBNcl80a3FLdUg2MGxBYnF5emoxblJQQk8yWVNpcXZfMDhfdm9XcW83UkhkN01zSjBsbjdUSVhqeVFrME8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:12:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beat the Blues with your plate: Can a fibre-rich diet fight depression? - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Beat the Blues with Your Plate: Can a Fibre-Rich Diet Fight Depression?</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 14, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>Research indicates that a fibre-rich diet can significantly reduce the risk of depression, with greater benefits observed in adolescents. This article explores the connections between diet, especially fibre intake, and mental health, particularly in the context of rising depression rates in India.</p><ul><li>A high-fibre diet is associated with lower odds of depression, with a 57% reduction in risk for adolescents.</li><li>Research published in <i>Nutritional Neuroscience</i> showcases findings from 18 studies on fibre intake and mental health.</li><li>Traditional Indian diets rich in fibre are essential in supporting mental well-being.</li><li>Modern dietary shifts toward processed foods may exacerbate mental health issues.</li></ul><blockquote>“Taking care of your mind starts with taking care of your body.” - Dr. Hemant Bhargav</blockquote><p>In conclusion, prioritizing a fibre-rich and nutrient-dense diet may be pivotal in managing and preventing depression.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/beat-the-blues-with-your-plate-can-a-fibre-rich-diet-fight-depression/article69097163.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/beat-the-blues-with-your-plate-can-a-fibre-rich-diet-fight-depression/article69097163.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sierra Leone declares emergency after confirming 2nd mpox case in 4 days - The Washington Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sierra Leone Declares Emergency After Second Mpox Case in Four Days</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Monday, <strong>Source:</strong> AP News</p><p>DAKAR, Senegal — Sierra Leone declared a state of emergency Monday after the country reported its second case of mpox in less than four days, health authorities said.</p><ul><li>Neither case had known recent contact with infected animals or sick individuals.</li><li>The first case involved recent travel limited to the airport town of Lungi.</li><li>Both patients are receiving treatment at a hospital in the capital, Freetown.</li></ul><blockquote>No known contact with infected animals or sick individuals has been reported.</blockquote><p>The rapid emergence of mpox cases in Sierra Leone has raised health concerns and prompted immediate action from authorities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/01/13/sierra-leone-mpox-state-of-emergency/0b24e6a6-d1f8-11ef-9835-51843d9371d6_story.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/01/13/sierra-leone-mpox-state-of-emergency/0b24e6a6-d1f8-11ef-9835-51843d9371d6_story.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:57:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Even with a broken foot, I was…’: How Chhavi Mittal prioritised health and conquered challenges post-cancer - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Even with a broken foot, I was…’: How Chhavi Mittal prioritised health and conquered challenges post-cancer</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/yogaa-2.jpg" alt="Prioritising recovery through yoga or stretching improves flexibility." />
<figcaption>Prioritising recovery through yoga or stretching improves flexibility, while incorporating at least one full rest day weekly prevents overtraining, especially after conditions like cancer. (Source: Freepik)</figcaption>
<p>Chhavi Mittal’s commitment to her health after battling cancer is a testament to her strength and determination, even as she faced challenges like foot fractures in 2024.</p>
<ul>
<li>Chhavi shared her experiences on Instagram, emphasizing her focus on health and fitness post-cancer.</li>
<li>Despite experiencing multiple fractures, she continued to pursue physical activity and personal records.</li>
<li>Dr. Srinath highlights the importance of weight training for bone health and reducing fracture risks.</li>
<li>Precautionary measures are crucial when engaging in intense physical activities, especially after cancer recovery.</li>
<li>Structured goal setting and gradual progress in exercises help prevent injury and burnout.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Setting SMART goals ensures realistic progress, such as increasing squat strength by 10% in eight weeks.” - Dr. Srinath</blockquote>
<p>This journey underscores the significance of prioritizing health, gradual recovery, and the role of mental and physical practices in overcoming adversity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/chhavi-mittal-prioritised-health-conquered-challenges-post-cancer-2024-9756772/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/chhavi-mittal-prioritised-health-conquered-challenges-post-cancer-2024-9756772/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:30:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microbiome study links vegan, vegetarian diets with lower cardiometabolic disease risk - Natural Products Insider]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxNVEF4anhmemZZUDctU1lCNnhqLTJ0RzVaa2M4eTZVREM4XzlkdWIzdTJxZEFjZzk5S0pUdzlGblljWXYyUGl0QTRjcTFmQXI4UlpkckRBTENudk81aDZISC1MMFdyeHhRRVZFN1ZEUlRCcGJsTzV2N0d0WndCLVpXLWpkdFhYOHcxaFNLNDJ5UGZHYmxWWlJBaFNXekF6LVFjdFIxcGc1Ylp4QlM0X01tR3lzRFJYeDA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxNVEF4anhmemZZUDctU1lCNnhqLTJ0RzVaa2M4eTZVREM4XzlkdWIzdTJxZEFjZzk5S0pUdzlGblljWXYyUGl0QTRjcTFmQXI4UlpkckRBTENudk81aDZISC1MMFdyeHhRRVZFN1ZEUlRCcGJsTzV2N0d0WndCLVpXLWpkdFhYOHcxaFNLNDJ5UGZHYmxWWlJBaFNXekF6LVFjdFIxcGc1Ylp4QlM0X01tR3lzRFJYeDA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:10:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Expressed emotions among caregivers of individuals with schizophrenia and associated factors: a multihospital-based survey in Southern Thailand - BMC Psychology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxNNlhlMHUyYW9WRS0yUzJOYXpJaXhVWUt4TkI0NXVVQ3ZudERXTkhrSkFDeHNDMi1UWHZSZ1ZmT3pSVG5zZHdUeW8xZVZJYlV5ejVKck9FbHE2dFJ2cmd1anA5T0I5Y2RSenNraUhUWjdqc3NfX1dYb09tVlI4OXU4Yg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxNNlhlMHUyYW9WRS0yUzJOYXpJaXhVWUt4TkI0NXVVQ3ZudERXTkhrSkFDeHNDMi1UWHZSZ1ZmT3pSVG5zZHdUeW8xZVZJYlV5ejVKck9FbHE2dFJ2cmd1anA5T0I5Y2RSenNraUhUWjdqc3NfX1dYb09tVlI4OXU4Yg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 23:37:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foods to eat and to avoid for better skin: Your diet to deal with acne, wrinkles or dryness - CNA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Foods to Eat and Avoid for Better Skin: Your Diet to Deal with Acne, Wrinkles or Dryness</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Channel News Asia</p><section><img src="https://dam.mediacorp.sg/image/upload/s--u2kkYyQJ--/c_crop,h_1414,w_1885,x_225,y_0/c_fill,g_auto,h_523,w_693/f_auto,q_auto/v1/mediacorp/cna/image/2024/12/20/how_to_have_better_skin_milk.jpg?itok=ZuQPxd73" alt="" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Avoid dairy to up your chances against getting acne. (Photo: iStock)</figcaption></section><p>This article explores the connection between diet and skin health, emphasizing how certain foods can exacerbate skin issues like acne, dryness, and signs of aging. Dermatologists provide insights on what to eat and what to avoid for healthier skin.</p><ul><li>Acne: Avoid dairy and whey protein.</li><li>Signs of aging: Avoid white sugar and high glycemic index foods.</li><li>Dermatitis: Avoid spicy foods, hot drinks, and alcohol.</li><li>Dryness and dehydration: Avoid diuretic foods and high sodium foods.</li></ul><section><img src="https://dam.mediacorp.sg/image/upload/s--8MVAfvFv--/c_crop,h_1443,w_1925,x_1,y_1/c_fill,g_auto,h_523,w_693/f_auto,q_auto/v1/mediacorp/cna/image/2024/12/20/how_to_have_better_skin_cut_coffee.jpg?itok=6bbVYBPw" alt="" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Cut coffee to prevent dry skin. (Photo: iStock)</figcaption></section><blockquote>“Eating a diet rich in antioxidants can help the skin recover from years of sun damage.” – Dr. Lynn Chiam</blockquote><p>The article concludes with the encouragement to eat more foods that are good for the skin, such as antioxidants, omega-3 fatty acids, probiotics, and vitamins.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://cnalifestyle.channelnewsasia.com/style-beauty/skincare-tips-anti-ageing-acne-416676</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cnalifestyle.channelnewsasia.com/style-beauty/skincare-tips-anti-ageing-acne-416676</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 23:24:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Making One Tweak to Your Coffee Routine May Lower Your Heart Disease Risk by 31%, New Study Says - EatingWell]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Making One Tweak to Your Coffee Routine May Lower Your Heart Disease Risk by 31%, New Study Says</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> European Heart Journal</p>
<p>A new study suggests that drinking coffee in the morning can significantly reduce cardiovascular disease and mortality risk, showing a <strong>31% lower risk of dying from heart disease</strong> compared to non-coffee drinkers.</p>
<ul>
<li>Morning coffee drinkers are <strong>16% less likely to die from any cause</strong>.</li>
<li>Analyzed data from over 42,000 U.S. adults.</li>
<li>Participants were grouped into morning coffee, all-day coffee, and no coffee drinkers.</li>
<li>Consuming coffee throughout the day showed no mortality benefits.</li>
<li>Timing of coffee consumption is crucial; morning consumption supports natural wake processes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our findings indicate that it's not just whether you drink coffee or how much you drink, but the time of day when you drink coffee that’s important.” – Lu Qi, MD, Ph.D.</blockquote>
<p>Switching to a morning-only coffee habit may help improve heart health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eatingwell.com/morning-coffee-mortality-study-8773798</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatingwell.com/morning-coffee-mortality-study-8773798</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 23:01:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Acceptability of intermittent preventive treatment of malaria in pregnancy with sulfadoxine-pyrimethamine plus dihydroartemisinin-piperaquine in Papua New Guinea: a qualitative study - Malaria Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Acceptability of intermittent preventive treatment of malaria in pregnancy with sulfadoxine-pyrimethamine plus dihydroartemisinin-piperaquine in Papua New Guinea: a qualitative study</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 13 January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Malaria Journal</p><p>This study assesses the acceptability of a new regimen for malaria prevention during pregnancy in Papua New Guinea.</p><ul><li>The World Health Organization recommends intermittent preventive treatment in pregnancy (IPTp) with sulfadoxine-pyrimethamine (SP).</li><li>In Papua New Guinea, a combination of SP and dihydroartemisinin-piperaquine (DP) is being evaluated for effectiveness and acceptability.</li><li>Results indicate positive feelings towards the new regimen but raise concerns about the increased pill burden.</li><li>Healthcare providers express worries regarding adherence in non-trial settings.</li></ul><blockquote>“In the trial context, IPTp-SP plus DP was acceptable to both users and providers.”</blockquote><p>This research highlights both the potential benefits and challenges in implementing new malaria treatment regimens during pregnancy, crucial for improving maternal health outcomes in malaria-endemic regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://malariajournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12936-024-05233-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://malariajournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12936-024-05233-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 22:34:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fixed-dose tablet shows promise against intestinal worms - University of Minnesota Twin Cities]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fixed-dose tablet shows promise against intestinal worms</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Late last week <strong>Source:</strong> The Lancet Infectious Diseases</p><p>A randomized controlled trial has revealed that a single, mango-flavored tablet combining ivermectin and albendazole could help control intestinal worm infections affecting 1.5 billion people yearly.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>The trial conducted in Ethiopia, Kenya, and Mozambique showed that the fixed-dose combination (FDC) is more effective than albendazole alone in treating whipworm and other soil-transmitted helminth (STH) infections.</li><li>In total, 1,001 school-aged children were enrolled, with high cure rates reported for both FDC treatment groups.</li><li>The FDC was well-accepted by children, highlighting its palatability and ease of administration.</li><li>The investigators propose using the single-dose regimen for mass de-worming and more effective 3-day doses for individual treatments.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a pivotal trial that opens up the possibility of controlling all species of STH, including Strongyloides, and may lead to reconsider elimination goals that were deemed unattainable with albendazole alone.” - Alejandro Krolewiecki, MD</blockquote><p>There are plans for further evaluation of the FDC in larger studies in other endemic countries and assessment of its feasibility for widespread implementation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cidrap.umn.edu/misc-emerging-topics/fixed-dose-tablet-shows-promise-against-intestinal-worms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cidrap.umn.edu/misc-emerging-topics/fixed-dose-tablet-shows-promise-against-intestinal-worms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 22:09:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Empty Sylvian Fissure Sign: A Novel Non-contrast CT Finding in Moyamoya Disease - Cureus]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPZ0tnakx4VjFkYVdMZ2hmZVVGREMxakE2SUg0LWMyb2s5aEFGUDVoY0RiMk80R3phY2VxYjNac2VnM1pJMHlLOFB3WGpITUhjaXNNbVc1SVhZcVVvNDE3dm5qdzk4U2FBaWpHdWlRQ3NJUFhiN0k1VE1BUVRKdFd2ZThrNE9UYU9yWWdQc3lLbl9EMG5BMTNyWXVESHFCMnZhNjBYUTdhOU92MFVIS2g2VWEzUjhrM0FUcF9ycTJQM3hNOWczakc2Zzd0WktBUm42cnIyVEFaNA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPZ0tnakx4VjFkYVdMZ2hmZVVGREMxakE2SUg0LWMyb2s5aEFGUDVoY0RiMk80R3phY2VxYjNac2VnM1pJMHlLOFB3WGpITUhjaXNNbVc1SVhZcVVvNDE3dm5qdzk4U2FBaWpHdWlRQ3NJUFhiN0k1VE1BUVRKdFd2ZThrNE9UYU9yWWdQc3lLbl9EMG5BMTNyWXVESHFCMnZhNjBYUTdhOU92MFVIS2g2VWEzUjhrM0FUcF9ycTJQM3hNOWczakc2Zzd0WktBUm42cnIyVEFaNA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 21:57:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sirsa MP Selja raises cancer concerns, finds reply by Haryana DGHS vague - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sirsa MP Selja Raises Cancer Concerns with Haryana Health Officials</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p>
<p>Sirsa MP Kumari Selja has expressed concerns over the rising cancer cases in Haryana and criticized the vague response from the Director General of Health Services regarding her demands for new treatment centers.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Selja's letter dated November 20, 2024, urged the establishment of cancer treatment centers in specific districts heavily affected by increasing cancer rates.</li>
  <li>Approximately 3,000 new cancer cases are reported monthly in Haryana, with about 1,500 fatalities due to delayed treatment.</li>
  <li>The DG Health Services outlined existing initiatives but did not address Selja's call for new centers in high-need areas.</li>
  <li>The response highlighted ongoing initiatives and existing facilities but lacked concrete plans for improving access to cancer care.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p><strong>No new info, just old data</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Selja criticized the response for not providing new information or addressing the specific needs of the Ghaggar river belt.</p>
<p>This situation calls for urgent action to improve cancer care accessibility in Haryana.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/haryana/sirsa-mp-selja-raises-cancer-concerns-finds-reply-by-haryana-dghs-vague/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/haryana/sirsa-mp-selja-raises-cancer-concerns-finds-reply-by-haryana-dghs-vague/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 21:49:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phase III Trial Evaluates Routine Tranexamic Acid for Bleeding Reduction in Hematologic Malignancy - DocWire News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Phase III Trial Evaluates Routine Tranexamic Acid for Bleeding Reduction in Hematologic Malignancy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2025<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Docwire News</p><p>The TREATT phase III trial investigated the regular use of tranexamic acid to reduce bleeding in patients undergoing intensive therapy for hematologic malignancy and severe thrombocytopenia. The findings were published in <em>The Lancet Haematology</em>.</p><ul><li>The trial included 616 adults receiving intensive chemotherapy or stem-cell transplantation.</li><li>Participants had very low platelet counts (10 × 10<sup>9</sup>/L or lower).</li><li>Results showed no significant difference in bleeding rates between the tranexamic acid group (31.7%) and placebo group (34.2%).</li><li>No notable differences in thrombotic events or veno-occlusive disease were observed.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is insufficient evidence to support routine use of tranexamic acid to reduce bleeding in patients with haematological malignancies undergoing intensive chemotherapy.”</blockquote><p>The trial was funded by the UK National Health Service Blood and Transplant and the Australian National Health and Medical Research Council.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://docwirenews.com/post/phase-iii-trial-evaluates-routinized-tranexamic-acid-for-bleeding-reduction-in-hematologic-malignancy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://docwirenews.com/post/phase-iii-trial-evaluates-routinized-tranexamic-acid-for-bleeding-reduction-in-hematologic-malignancy</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 21:29:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shape & size of retina veins can predict stroke risk: Study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shape and Size of Retina Veins Can Predict Stroke Risk, Study Finds</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117215492,imgsize-1605317,width-400,resizemode-4/117215492.jpg" alt="Shape &amp; size of retina veins can predict stroke risk: Study" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Shape and size of retina veins significantly correlate with stroke risk.</figcaption>
<p>Researchers have found that the shape and size of veins and arteries on the retina can predict stroke risk almost as accurately as traditional risk factors, without invasive tests.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The study published in the journal Heart indicates that the retinal vascular network mirrors that of the brain.</li>
    <li>A simple retinal scan can assess the health of retinal vessels to forecast brain vessel damage.</li>
    <li>Data from 45,161 participants over 12.5 years was analyzed, identifying 749 stroke cases.</li>
    <li>Increased arc length and chord length of retinal blood vessels correlated with higher stroke risk.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"One can use a simple retinal scan to assess the health of these veins and arteries of the retina to predict potential damage to the brain's blood vessels." - Study Authors</blockquote>
<p>This study emphasizes the potential of retinal scans in stroke risk assessment, promoting non-invasive methods in medical evaluation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/shape-size-of-retina-veins-can-predict-stroke-risk-study/articleshow/117215477.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/shape-size-of-retina-veins-can-predict-stroke-risk-study/articleshow/117215477.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 21:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epidemiological trends and age-period-cohort effects on ischemic stroke burden across the BRICS-plus from 1992 to 2021 - BMC Public Health]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxQUTVFeFdnRnAzb0Z1NC1nOVJjbEJfRUc5TzFwUzRZT1lyMEZ2SzVncnB4d2RWR0UwMDI2cVpyT1VHSTNyVDlNM1U5ZWdqMWROMDdhZWZRbURsU0dvcXY2MGhBQ2RrRFRXc1puMkRCM291LTh3TnVrTW1JYlhSZlVfS0VCSQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxQUTVFeFdnRnAzb0Z1NC1nOVJjbEJfRUc5TzFwUzRZT1lyMEZ2SzVncnB4d2RWR0UwMDI2cVpyT1VHSTNyVDlNM1U5ZWdqMWROMDdhZWZRbURsU0dvcXY2MGhBQ2RrRFRXc1puMkRCM291LTh3TnVrTW1JYlhSZlVfS0VCSQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 20:38:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Therapeutic development to accelerate malaria control through intentional intervention layering - Malaria Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxPV2FIYXhKaTJxeldQUnBYUUN1bUpFTWh1ZEx2UjVxMHB1SHdOVU5vYldSMVBkNGgzYTlMM0c5YTM0eTJmVWd1LUZidmIwenUyOTNUdExKbFBtLUQ0MlNQWjNYT2c5dVYzOTgwYXprcXZRajJCLVZMbUdFM094VlVxaXlR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxPV2FIYXhKaTJxeldQUnBYUUN1bUpFTWh1ZEx2UjVxMHB1SHdOVU5vYldSMVBkNGgzYTlMM0c5YTM0eTJmVWd1LUZidmIwenUyOTNUdExKbFBtLUQ0MlNQWjNYT2c5dVYzOTgwYXprcXZRajJCLVZMbUdFM094VlVxaXlR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 20:34:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Longitudinal DNA methylation profiles in saliva of offspring from mothers with gestational diabetes: associations with early childhood growth patterns - Cardiovascular Diabetology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Longitudinal DNA methylation profiles in saliva of offspring from mothers with gestational diabetes: associations with early childhood growth patterns</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 13 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Cardiovascular Diabetology</p><div><img src="//media.springernature.com/lw685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1186%2Fs12933-024-02568-6/MediaObjects/12933_2024_2568_Fig1_HTML.png" alt="figure 1"><figcaption><b>A</b> Manhattan plot representing the most differentiated CpGs per chromosome at the postpartum visit.<b> B</b> Manhattan plot representing the most differentiated CpGs per chromosome at the one year of follow-up visit</figcaption></div><p>This study investigates DNA methylation profiles in children of mothers with gestational diabetes (GDM), revealing associations with growth patterns across early childhood.</p><ul><li>The study analyzed saliva DNA methylation in 30 children (15 from GDM mothers, 15 from non-GDM mothers).</li><li>6,968 differentially methylated positions (DMPs) were identified postpartum, and 5,132 after one year.</li><li>Significant correlations were found between specific DNA methylation sites and growth-related variables like weight and BMI.</li><li>The findings suggest a stable pattern of DNA methylation that may serve as an early indicator of future metabolic risks in children.</li></ul><blockquote>“The persistence of these epigenetic signatures underscores their potential as early indicators of metabolic risk.”</blockquote><p>This research emphasizes the importance of longitudinal studies in understanding the impact of maternal gestational diabetes on child health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://cardiab.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12933-024-02568-6</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cardiab.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12933-024-02568-6</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 20:31:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15 science-based ways to reduce your risk of dementia - The Washington Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2025/01/13/dementia-risks-reduction-strategies/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2025/01/13/dementia-risks-reduction-strategies/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 20:31:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Manage Portal Hypertension and Varices in Cirrhosis: Best Practices - Medscape]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxOWGx5ZGhzTDVrbVBUdDlHLXVjSXUxUXhISGZmZVZaY2xSaXNveG1rT1NpOERjMkZwcVVWNDk1N0xobEl1ZXI5QTFvV3lmZ1ZxYnJBS1FUT096SkNlcHJVV0Y4eHpCZnRZOXZuc0dLM2ZlU3NVSnh5elh0dDFoMlRSaFlNTldfVnJXdEJNaTZSTWxTVTJKaEVjbmhFYWMtdkJrZVFqUnRfemdUMmM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxOWGx5ZGhzTDVrbVBUdDlHLXVjSXUxUXhISGZmZVZaY2xSaXNveG1rT1NpOERjMkZwcVVWNDk1N0xobEl1ZXI5QTFvV3lmZ1ZxYnJBS1FUT096SkNlcHJVV0Y4eHpCZnRZOXZuc0dLM2ZlU3NVSnh5elh0dDFoMlRSaFlNTldfVnJXdEJNaTZSTWxTVTJKaEVjbmhFYWMtdkJrZVFqUnRfemdUMmM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 20:09:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. dementia cases expected to surge with aging population - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>U.S. dementia cases expected to surge with aging population</h1> <p><strong>Date: </strong>January 13, 2025</p> <p><strong>Source: </strong>Nature Medicine</p> <p>A new study indicates a significant increase in dementia risks among older Americans, revealing that 42% may develop the condition after age 55. This equates to an estimated half a million cases this year, potentially reaching one million annually by 2060.</p> <img src="/images/pdf-dl-cta.png" alt="" height="74" width="74"> <figcaption>A graphic related to dementia research efforts.</figcaption> <p>The study emphasizes the role of aging, genetics, and lifestyle-related health issues in the rising rates of dementia, particularly among minorities disadvantaged by current healthcare practices. The research found that women face a 48% risk compared to 35% for men.</p> <ul> <li>Dementia risk for Americans aged 55 and older is assessed at 42%.</li> <li>Estimated half a million new dementia cases are expected in 2025.</li> <li>The lifetime risk for dementia exceeds 50% for those reaching age 75.</li> <li>The study highlights the growing impact of racial health disparities.</li> <li>Health initiatives targeting heart disease may help reduce cognitive decline.</li> </ul> <blockquote> <p>“Our study results forecast a dramatic rise in the burden from dementia in the United States over the coming decades...” - Josef Coresh, MD, PhD</p> </blockquote> <p>This study underscores the need for healthcare policy reforms focused on both prevention and management of dementia as the American population ages.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250113/US-dementia-cases-expected-to-surge-with-aging-population.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250113/US-dementia-cases-expected-to-surge-with-aging-population.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A deadly brain-eating amoeba lurks in freshwater swimming holes – here’s what you need to know - The Conversation Indonesia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A deadly brain-eating amoeba lurks in freshwater swimming holes – here’s what you need to know</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Conversation</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/641397/original/file-20250109-15-ehujqs.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&q=45&auto=format&w=754&fit=clip" alt="Naegleria fowleri amoeba in a person’s cerebrospinal fluid.">
  <figcaption><span><em>Naegleria fowleri</em> amoeba in a person’s cerebrospinal fluid. Photo: Dr. James Roberts, Children’s Healthcare of Atlanta/CDC</span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This article discusses the risks associated with swimming in freshwater environments where the brain-eating amoeba, <em>Naegleria fowleri</em>, can be present. Though infections are rare, they can cause severe and often fatal brain infections.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The brain-eating amoeba thrives in warm freshwater and soil.</li>
  <li>It can cause primary amoebic meningoencephalitis, a highly fatal brain infection.</li>
  <li>Recent statistics show a 97.5% fatality rate from recorded cases in the U.S.</li>
  <li>Symptoms of infection include headaches, fever, and nausea, with urgent medical attention required.</li>
  <li>Precautions include avoiding submerging the head in potentially contaminated waters.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Of the 164 reported cases in the US between 1962 and 2023, only four people have survived. This is a fatality rate of 97.5%."</blockquote>
<p>Understanding the risks and practicing safe swimming habits is essential, especially for vulnerable populations like children.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theconversation.com/a-deadly-brain-eating-amoeba-lurks-in-freshwater-swimming-holes-heres-what-you-need-to-know-246044</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theconversation.com/a-deadly-brain-eating-amoeba-lurks-in-freshwater-swimming-holes-heres-what-you-need-to-know-246044</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:09:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These are the top 10 cities you're most likely to catch a cold - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>These are the top 10 cities you're most likely to catch a cold</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Individuals living in different cities experience varying rates of catching colds due to factors such as climate, air quality, and population density. Understanding these factors can help in promoting health awareness.</p><ul><li>The top 10 cities listed were based on data collected over a specific period.</li><li>Weather conditions play a significant role in the prevalence of colds.</li><li>Residents in urban areas tend to have higher incidences of colds compared to rural areas.</li><li>Health tips for preventing colds in these cities are discussed.</li></ul><blockquote>“Environmental factors significantly contribute to the spread of respiratory illnesses.”</blockquote><p>This article underscores the importance of being aware of one’s environment, especially during cold seasons.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/these-are-the-top-10-cities-youre-most-likely-to-catch-a-cold/articleshow/117214274.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/these-are-the-top-10-cities-youre-most-likely-to-catch-a-cold/articleshow/117214274.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flu, RSV, and Norovirus Are in Full Swing, While COVID Looms - WebMD]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Flu, RSV, and Norovirus Are in Full Swing, While COVID Looms</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan. 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CDC Data</p><p>The latest health report indicates high flu and RSV activity across the U.S., while COVID-19 cases remain low compared to last year.</p><ul><li>5.3 million flu cases reported nationwide this year.</li><li>63,000 hospitalizations and 2,700 deaths due to flu, including 11 children.</li><li>Positive tests: 19% for influenza, 13% for RSV, and 7% for COVID.</li><li>RSV detections are high in several states including Connecticut and Georgia.</li><li>Norovirus rates have reached a five-year high with over 22% positive tests.</li></ul><blockquote>“The nation isn’t out of the woods yet, though, in terms of seeing another tripledemic or even quad-demic.”</blockquote><p>The CDC is expected to release updated virus data early this week, providing insights into post-holiday impacts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.webmd.com/cold-and-flu/news/20250113/flu-rsv-norovirus-in-full-swing-as-covid-looms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.webmd.com/cold-and-flu/news/20250113/flu-rsv-norovirus-in-full-swing-as-covid-looms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:44:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sugary drinks are killing you. Switch to water - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQZFdnb05YTUZDWEw5NzdWemV2N2Q1U2lKV21fQmxGNlZwdlg5QlBMR1ozRDE0V1o0a0VVVnhoOHB1Skk4RkRGcnM5QXZKd0FBWHdFSEhWdUdoS29yc1VIYXRmNm1sZUVwTC04c1RXNnQtT3ptbUhVR3N1MFZDTXN1TE5raVlhUUJoTWt3Y3laUWZWd3ZCVXFscWpEbksxQmVCTUxVSGtRbzVMZGl6ZWthM19SZ2lOQdIBuwFBVV95cUxQaWp3MGp4SVpyUXFVU0lQcEZiU0NyQ2s2V3pCTkxMWDMwc3J0bmhrXzliU0lFZ1RmdVVMdldaSnhjWk1xdUNFOW1MNE1fOGhyZ1RCVkJQTTY5Z0cwaldvRDA1bjNmUl9hSjI3UDRVN0pxSmpPaGRRVExTZDB4Ny1WX1RXbUxTZlcxRzJCVFNaTjU5T1JGNExsRXlPWmk0RW1sVW9XTWJaRGpnOWZvY2JLclUwOXUzcmJnaWJ3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQZFdnb05YTUZDWEw5NzdWemV2N2Q1U2lKV21fQmxGNlZwdlg5QlBMR1ozRDE0V1o0a0VVVnhoOHB1Skk4RkRGcnM5QXZKd0FBWHdFSEhWdUdoS29yc1VIYXRmNm1sZUVwTC04c1RXNnQtT3ptbUhVR3N1MFZDTXN1TE5raVlhUUJoTWt3Y3laUWZWd3ZCVXFscWpEbksxQmVCTUxVSGtRbzVMZGl6ZWthM19SZ2lOQdIBuwFBVV95cUxQaWp3MGp4SVpyUXFVU0lQcEZiU0NyQ2s2V3pCTkxMWDMwc3J0bmhrXzliU0lFZ1RmdVVMdldaSnhjWk1xdUNFOW1MNE1fOGhyZ1RCVkJQTTY5Z0cwaldvRDA1bjNmUl9hSjI3UDRVN0pxSmpPaGRRVExTZDB4Ny1WX1RXbUxTZlcxRzJCVFNaTjU5T1JGNExsRXlPWmk0RW1sVW9XTWJaRGpnOWZvY2JLclUwOXUzcmJnaWJ3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:37:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>