<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 05:19:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 05:19:47 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manage your diabetes with these 12 protein-rich foods - Health shots]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manage Your Diabetes with These 12 Protein-Rich Foods</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> September 2023  <strong>Source:</strong> Health Shots</p><figure><img src="https://images.healthshots.com/healthshots/en/uploads/2024/08/06163710/New-Project-94.jpg" alt="health benefits of dry fruits"><figcaption>Dry fruits are good for people with diabetes. Image courtesy: Adobe Stock</figcaption></figure><p>Protein-rich foods for diabetes are not only delicious but can also help keep glucose levels in check. With India ranking second in the world for the number of people with diabetes, incorporating protein-rich foods into your diet is crucial for managing this condition effectively.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Diabetes management is essential to prevent serious complications like organ damage.</li><li>Protein helps regulate blood sugar levels and enhances insulin response without causing spikes.</li><li>People with diabetes should focus on incorporating protein-rich foods in their diets.</li><li>12 recommended protein-rich foods include dry fruits, seeds, lentils, fish, beans, peas, chicken, eggs, cottage cheese, soy products, sweet potatoes, and quinoa.</li></ul><blockquote>According to a study published in the <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14522731/" rel="nofollow">American Journal of Clinical Nutrition</a>, increasing protein intake can help regulate blood glucose levels and lower HbA1c.</blockquote><p>This article emphasizes the importance of protein in managing diabetes and suggests practical food options for a balanced diet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthshots.com/healthy-eating/nutrition/protein-rich-foods-for-diabetics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthshots.com/healthy-eating/nutrition/protein-rich-foods-for-diabetics/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 05:00:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zika-Free Pune: No New Cases Since October 3, Pregnant Women Deliver Healthy Babies - The Bridge Chronicle]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zika-Free Pune: No New Cases Since October 3, Pregnant Women Deliver Healthy Babies</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2024-12-25 09:57:54 GMT+5:30">25 Dec 2024, 9:57 am IST</time></p><p>The outbreak of the Zika virus in Pune has been effectively contained, with no new cases reported since October 3, providing significant relief to health officials and the community.</p><ul><li>Pune city recorded a total of 109 cases of Zika, with surrounding areas contributing to a total of 125 cases.</li><li>Among the infected, 52 pregnant women were reported, but all newborns have been delivered healthy.</li><li>Health authorities are continuously monitoring these newborns, and no complications have been observed.</li><li>Zika is transmitted via the Aedes aegypti mosquito, with common symptoms being fever, headache, and rashes.</li></ul><blockquote>Dr. Rajesh Dighe, Assistant Health Officer, remarked: "No new Zika cases have been detected in Pune since October 3. Pregnant women infected with Zika have delivered healthy babies without complications."</blockquote><p>This positive outcome highlights the effective containment efforts and monitoring practices in Pune.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thebridgechronicle.com/news/zika-free-pune-no-new-cases-since-october-3-pregnant-women-deliver-healthy-babies</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thebridgechronicle.com/news/zika-free-pune-no-new-cases-since-october-3-pregnant-women-deliver-healthy-babies</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 04:27:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arts students find English exam tough - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxNckw2OXowUEFQa1MySWxpWl9GNkMxTmhoMXpxU1h3VDdtMTJINnRpVlhQQ0xLRkFEZ3NPY1BiNnlKazZGaTNLOF9kRjI2M0pmWHBfWi04YXRmNjF4WHFDRWVBUlRxaUp4eXdhYjNSR1E0TmVaNUxadHFWSkpWZ2hUWkQwbE8zbktf0gGMAUFVX3lxTFB0eW9KVHRoeGZHcndycE80SUU2V1dISFlSRHpDeDJkV210dllpbG9FQmw2WGdwM0dVdkh2RVhJUDVxczRBSkoxQmpRMklUN1FhRlM2TkRlaU1ELS1jYmRYUHUwa2ZUSlRrYUwwQlN2MEpGemkwTFBRaXZEaFY0cXdiRUQ3T1Y1dEtSMUlD?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxNckw2OXowUEFQa1MySWxpWl9GNkMxTmhoMXpxU1h3VDdtMTJINnRpVlhQQ0xLRkFEZ3NPY1BiNnlKazZGaTNLOF9kRjI2M0pmWHBfWi04YXRmNjF4WHFDRWVBUlRxaUp4eXdhYjNSR1E0TmVaNUxadHFWSkpWZ2hUWkQwbE8zbktf0gGMAUFVX3lxTFB0eW9KVHRoeGZHcndycE80SUU2V1dISFlSRHpDeDJkV210dllpbG9FQmw2WGdwM0dVdkh2RVhJUDVxczRBSkoxQmpRMklUN1FhRlM2TkRlaU1ELS1jYmRYUHUwa2ZUSlRrYUwwQlN2MEpGemkwTFBRaXZEaFY0cXdiRUQ3T1Y1dEtSMUlD?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 04:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Sugar Really Not Good For Health? Find Out Here - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/is-sugar-really-not-good-for-health-find-out-here-9167196.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/is-sugar-really-not-good-for-health-find-out-here-9167196.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 03:57:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jogging, Cycling Or Swimming: Which Is The Best Exercise For You? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jogging, Cycling Or Swimming: Which Is The Best Exercise For You?</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> December 25, 2024, 14:43 IST</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Cycling strengthens muscles, bones, and tendons while burning excess calories and fat. (Shutterstock)"><figcaption>Cycling strengthens muscles, bones, and tendons while burning excess calories and fat. (Shutterstock)</figcaption><p>In today’s technological era, reduced physical activity has led even young people to fall prey to serious illnesses. However, many individuals maintain their health by exercising every morning through activities such as jogging, cycling, or swimming. But which of these three is the best form of exercise and has the most impact? Here’s what fitness coaches say.</p><ul><li>Many suffer from serious health issues due to sedentary lifestyles.</li><li>Cycling is a low-impact exercise suitable for all ages and prevents many diseases.</li><li>Swimming provides excellent physical and mental health benefits.</li><li>Fitness coach Manpreet Kaur emphasizes the importance of exercise for health.</li></ul><blockquote>“Most people are succumbing to various minor and major illnesses due to their busy and sedentary lifestyles.” - Manpreet Kaur</blockquote><p>Both cycling and swimming are beneficial exercises, with cycling being particularly great for muscle strength and swimming offering comprehensive health benefits, including during pregnancy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/jogging-cycling-or-swimming-which-is-the-best-exercise-for-you-ws-ab-9167621.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/jogging-cycling-or-swimming-which-is-the-best-exercise-for-you-ws-ab-9167621.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 03:43:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[People who walk faster have lower risk of diabetes and hypertension - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>People who walk faster have lower risk of diabetes and hypertension</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>This article discusses the findings that individuals who have a faster walking pace may have a reduced risk of developing diabetes and hypertension, highlighting the importance of physical activity in maintaining health.</p><ul><li>Research indicates a correlation between walking speed and lower incidences of diabetes and hypertension.</li><li>Walking is a simple yet effective form of exercise accessible to many.</li><li>Incorporating brisk walking into daily routines can significantly improve health outcomes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Fast walkers might not only be quicker on their feet, but they could also lead healthier lives.”</blockquote><p>Engaging in regular walking can serve as a preventive measure against serious health issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/people-who-walk-faster-have-lower-risk-of-diabetes-and-hypertension/articleshow/116639402.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/people-who-walk-faster-have-lower-risk-of-diabetes-and-hypertension/articleshow/116639402.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 03:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revitalize Your Winter: 10 Uplifting Yoga Poses To Beat Winter Blues - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Revitalize Your Winter: 10 Uplifting Yoga Poses To Beat Winter Blues</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p><figure><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/cat-marjaryasana-pose.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="Revitalize Your Winter: 10 Uplifting Yoga Poses To Beat Winter Blues" width="900" height="375"><figcaption>10 Uplifting Yoga Poses To Beat Winter Blues</figcaption></figure><p>As winter arrives, the days grow shorter and our energy levels often take a nosedive. Practicing yoga can invigorate your spirit during these chilly months. Here are ten uplifting yoga postures designed to assist in beating the winter blues.</p><ul><li><strong>Sun Salutation (Surya Namaskar):</strong> A dynamic sequence that warms up the body.</li><li><strong>Twist Pose (Ardha Matsyendrasana):</strong> Detoxifies the body and invigorates the spine.</li><li><strong>Spinal Forward Bend (Uttanasana):</strong> Releases tension and encourages introspection.</li><li><strong>Happy Baby Pose (Ananda Balasana):</strong> Restores joy and fosters lightness.</li><li><strong>Bridge Pose (Setu Bandhasana):</strong> Opens the chest and alleviates stress.</li><li><strong>Child's Pose (Balasana):</strong> Promotes relaxation and allows for introspection.</li><li><strong>Camel Pose (Ustrasana):</strong> Encourages emotional release and boosts mood.</li><li><strong>Tree Pose (Vrksasana):</strong> Promotes stability and grounding.</li><li><strong>Warrior II (Virabhadrasana II):</strong> Builds strength and confidence.</li><li><strong>Cobra Pose (Bhujangasana):</strong> Refreshes mood and creates openness.</li></ul><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> Integrate these uplifting yoga poses into your routine this winter to revitalize your body and cultivate a positive mindset.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/yoga/10-uplifting-yoga-poses-for-winter-blues-1166268/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/yoga/10-uplifting-yoga-poses-for-winter-blues-1166268/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 02:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What you need to know about the bird flu outbreak as concerns continue to grow - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-us/health/medical/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-bird-flu-outbreak-as-concerns-continue-to-grow/vi-AA1wrhdw?ocid=hpmsn</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-us/health/medical/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-bird-flu-outbreak-as-concerns-continue-to-grow/vi-AA1wrhdw?ocid=hpmsn</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 02:06:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dr Agarwal’s to host myopia summit in Chennai on Jan 4 - DTNEXT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dr Agarwal's to Host Myopia Summit in Chennai on January 4, 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://dtnext-prod.s3.ap-south-1.amazonaws.com/h-upload/2024/12/24/750x450_852356-agarwal.jpg" alt="Dr Agarwal’s to host myopia summit in Chennai on Jan 4"><figcaption>Dr Agarwal’s to host myopia summit in Chennai on Jan 4</figcaption><p>Dr Agarwal’s Eye Hospital is organizing the Myopia & Digital Eye Strain Patient Summit 2025 in Chennai to address eye health challenges related to prolonged screen exposure.</p><ul><li>The summit will take place on January 4, 2025.</li><li>Focus on myopia management and digital eye strain solutions.</li><li>Keynote speeches from eye health experts and vision screenings will be featured.</li><li>Participants can register online or via phone.</li></ul><blockquote>“We aim to empower individuals with the latest knowledge, practical prevention strategies, and effective care tips,” Dr. Ashvin Agarwal.</blockquote><p>The summit emphasizes the urgent need for education and practical strategies to manage eye health in a digital age.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dtnext.in/news/tamilnadu/dr-agarwals-to-host-myopia-summit-in-chennai-on-jan-4-816629</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dtnext.in/news/tamilnadu/dr-agarwals-to-host-myopia-summit-in-chennai-on-jan-4-816629</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Holiday Heart Syndrome is a risk for all age groups - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why Holiday Heart Syndrome is a risk for all age groups</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p>
<p>Holiday Heart Syndrome is a medical condition that poses risks to individuals of all ages, particularly during festive seasons when alcohol consumption increases.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Holiday Heart Syndrome can affect anyone regardless of age.</li>
  <li>Increased alcohol consumption during the holidays is a significant risk factor.</li>
  <li>Symptoms include palpitations, chest pain, and shortness of breath.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It’s important for everyone to be aware of their alcohol intake during the holiday season.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, awareness of Holiday Heart Syndrome is crucial for safety during festive gatherings, encouraging moderation in alcohol consumption.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-holiday-heart-syndrome-is-a-risk-for-all-age-groups/articleshow/116633772.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-holiday-heart-syndrome-is-a-risk-for-all-age-groups/articleshow/116633772.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 23:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[​Gut doctor shares top 3 hacks to lose belly fat with intermittent fasting - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gut Doctor Shares Top 3 Hacks to Lose Belly Fat with Intermittent Fasting</h1>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India <strong>Date:</strong> October 23, 2023</p>
<p>This article discusses effective strategies recommended by a gut specialist to help individuals lose belly fat using intermittent fasting methods.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Intermittent fasting is highlighted as an effective approach for achieving weight loss goals.</li>
  <li>The gut doctor outlines three specific hacks to enhance fat loss during fasting periods.</li>
  <li>Tips include meal timing, portion control, and the importance of selecting the right foods during eating windows.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Intermittent fasting not only aids in weight loss but also promotes better gut health.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, adopting these hacks can maximize the benefits of intermittent fasting and contribute to overall health improvements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/weight-loss/gut-doctor-shares-top-3-hacks-to-lose-belly-fat-with-intermittent-fasting/articleshow/116643337.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/weight-loss/gut-doctor-shares-top-3-hacks-to-lose-belly-fat-with-intermittent-fasting/articleshow/116643337.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4 Expert Tips for Maintaining Your Eye Health Through the Years - CNET]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>4 Expert Tips for Maintaining Your Eye Health Through the Years</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> CNET</p><figure><img src="https://www.cnet.com/a/img/resize/248f03e9647ebdb515c981aaeec32bb59d8d1799/hub/2023/09/21/68834f56-a110-406c-a816-b166526dafa2/gettyimages-897471090.jpg?auto=webp&amp;width=1200" alt="Eye testing equipment" width="1200" height="776"><figcaption>Image by Peter Dazeley/Getty Images</figcaption></figure><p>As you age, your risk of developing conditions that impact your eye health grows, but you can take proactive steps to support your eye health daily.</p><ul><li>Know your risk level for eye diseases and monitor symptoms.</li><li>Get regular eye exams, especially after age 65.</li><li>Wear proper eyewear that protects against UV rays.</li><li>Take care of your overall health through diet and quitting smoking.</li></ul><blockquote>According to the CDC, 90% of diabetes-related blindness is preventable.</blockquote><p>Maintaining eye health is vital as it can prevent severe issues and enhance overall well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnet.com/health/personal-care/4-expert-tips-for-maintaining-your-eye-health-through-the-years/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnet.com/health/personal-care/4-expert-tips-for-maintaining-your-eye-health-through-the-years/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No malaria cases in 4 years, but dengue continue to be a concern in Kurukshetra - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQREtkdUVPcG4zYTVaVi1XNTVmRWd1OVpkY1FkbGYtZWJ2OWUyUXNHbTFMeGJ1X1BnMDZ3c2xqal9Jd082X2FfbnhfN2pSQl9nc1BVS3I0OHNMckctR0c0SVBkWllOcENiOXFNcjY3ZTlUcGlReUdXbm85dXhPclVqRUpEWUZwSXpUdmxBQkRKMlNXUmkyV2liaHZZOHpGWThwZS1jTV9COUVGY0FFbkFOTXk2QVRIbnJNWU9pTm130gHCAUFVX3lxTFAzY3JZRThRWHBCS1p5QllBZ1M1cEFTclBqeDZMMzBmNDhpY0RaNHVldTh5REpKeXp5VG1pUmstQktIWGdhX2J4c25VTVQxajE3cVJ1SS1sSWRYNDdEbkZIZS10M2xpd3NCSjlGaUZxT0NvOXY1MGtzMF82dDRqdHFZRDFZVThUZXJaMzRVSGs4N19qWmNTLThhejJVdWNOQlhadG9Ld0JsRUxSSU9FM2hjXzJyajN3N1Vycm9NMmxzQ1JB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQREtkdUVPcG4zYTVaVi1XNTVmRWd1OVpkY1FkbGYtZWJ2OWUyUXNHbTFMeGJ1X1BnMDZ3c2xqal9Jd082X2FfbnhfN2pSQl9nc1BVS3I0OHNMckctR0c0SVBkWllOcENiOXFNcjY3ZTlUcGlReUdXbm85dXhPclVqRUpEWUZwSXpUdmxBQkRKMlNXUmkyV2liaHZZOHpGWThwZS1jTV9COUVGY0FFbkFOTXk2QVRIbnJNWU9pTm130gHCAUFVX3lxTFAzY3JZRThRWHBCS1p5QllBZ1M1cEFTclBqeDZMMzBmNDhpY0RaNHVldTh5REpKeXp5VG1pUmstQktIWGdhX2J4c25VTVQxajE3cVJ1SS1sSWRYNDdEbkZIZS10M2xpd3NCSjlGaUZxT0NvOXY1MGtzMF82dDRqdHFZRDFZVThUZXJaMzRVSGs4N19qWmNTLThhejJVdWNOQlhadG9Ld0JsRUxSSU9FM2hjXzJyajN3N1Vycm9NMmxzQ1JB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 21:30:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The state of H5N1 infections and research as 2025 approaches - Chemical & Engineering News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxPUndoaFlXRHNsRFQ0aXBwY1dQbWdxczZoOVBYSFR4WVRYVDB4Z0FmWk52VFJJRzlsS3pXaDVjdEZGWlVmcU1DSy01dTlnWnFsbmdlZ0xhVmJnOUUwem9FemNidFU1eGFvRHM2Z1RMSm9aQWhic282dWc3NzZDbEk1NURkczQ0bTZDMkJTUXp2WEhUTkdTcmM2R3Fha2ZnQWFYQ1JqWnNodVNvMUE4OXJmdQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxPUndoaFlXRHNsRFQ0aXBwY1dQbWdxczZoOVBYSFR4WVRYVDB4Z0FmWk52VFJJRzlsS3pXaDVjdEZGWlVmcU1DSy01dTlnWnFsbmdlZ0xhVmJnOUUwem9FemNidFU1eGFvRHM2Z1RMSm9aQWhic282dWc3NzZDbEk1NURkczQ0bTZDMkJTUXp2WEhUTkdTcmM2R3Fha2ZnQWFYQ1JqWnNodVNvMUE4OXJmdQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 21:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bharat Progress Report: Malaria Decreases To 69% In India, Removing From High Burden List - NewsX]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxPUGd2Yk9iQzNxT2JxNmpZQTFUUl9hOUFoOGJKcUdZWG04XzNuVzRyOHNVNXFZZzlTNk5OU0lVQTB3eWtkMEEtRWdad0lJZDRFdXozdDVHZTR2NnFEU0ZHMDZRa2pmdjJGRGsxMTBSOHJueVpSTkUzN19tU09kb1FVaHFPdTBjdzJFWjBCakNoMW1obzZVdHVJYV9DUnhrcHJUb2JzNlRfTGw3QmJ1bThMa3pVVzVPVzNNLXYxZWdtSF9TaEQ5cWJiSw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxPUGd2Yk9iQzNxT2JxNmpZQTFUUl9hOUFoOGJKcUdZWG04XzNuVzRyOHNVNXFZZzlTNk5OU0lVQTB3eWtkMEEtRWdad0lJZDRFdXozdDVHZTR2NnFEU0ZHMDZRa2pmdjJGRGsxMTBSOHJueVpSTkUzN19tU09kb1FVaHFPdTBjdzJFWjBCakNoMW1obzZVdHVJYV9DUnhrcHJUb2JzNlRfTGw3QmJ1bThMa3pVVzVPVzNNLXYxZWdtSF9TaEQ5cWJiSw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 19:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brain map clarifies neuronal connectivity behind motor function: Study - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNTlo1Y2dScHRnN3hkMVpWSlNvdXVxYTVZQ3M4MzctcWZ6eEJCMDVURkI1eEFXRTRsZDY0MDJYLTVuTXBmTHVZaUJNOHFPLTVBbWdoQk9EWF9GOWxRQkUxYmdDVUV5V1FVSVppalFtY1dIWTBZMlZneUdYakJCNi1MeGF3WEhMOFV2VUNFS1FIOHQ4bUJ5Q05QYnNDS3I5SVRGQUx1QUEyZVY3aFUzZG9zQdIBtAFBVV95cUxNLWxVbzZNSElzd2ZVSFNQNElxeEFCMTYxNUtheUdhazlUVTRIbXpYeTRVMjkxUE42S1ptZ1JvR3VWNHJDM1dreXhLOXFPOUw3Q25LaHNyUW1IdUdoOEpuVk9YNm5PTnF5RGwzTEEzM3JXUGRsaDV1Wlp1anNLREhNZ1R0RDRkTkxDdFhzM1pZcF9ZcmtmQzM2Vm04NlR5Q21EbWJWalNFdEpvU1BNRzZDVzRBeVA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNTlo1Y2dScHRnN3hkMVpWSlNvdXVxYTVZQ3M4MzctcWZ6eEJCMDVURkI1eEFXRTRsZDY0MDJYLTVuTXBmTHVZaUJNOHFPLTVBbWdoQk9EWF9GOWxRQkUxYmdDVUV5V1FVSVppalFtY1dIWTBZMlZneUdYakJCNi1MeGF3WEhMOFV2VUNFS1FIOHQ4bUJ5Q05QYnNDS3I5SVRGQUx1QUEyZVY3aFUzZG9zQdIBtAFBVV95cUxNLWxVbzZNSElzd2ZVSFNQNElxeEFCMTYxNUtheUdhazlUVTRIbXpYeTRVMjkxUE42S1ptZ1JvR3VWNHJDM1dreXhLOXFPOUw3Q25LaHNyUW1IdUdoOEpuVk9YNm5PTnF5RGwzTEEzM3JXUGRsaDV1Wlp1anNLREhNZ1R0RDRkTkxDdFhzM1pZcF9ZcmtmQzM2Vm04NlR5Q21EbWJWalNFdEpvU1BNRzZDVzRBeVA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 19:36:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Bird flu trigger a human pandemic? - ISRAEL21c]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Will Bird Flu Trigger a Human Pandemic?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ISRAEL21c</p><img src="https://static.israel21c.org/www/uploads/2022/01/Prof._Cyrille_Cohen_1-768x529.jpg" alt="Will bird flu trigger a human pandemic?"><figcaption>Prof. Cyrille Cohen, head of Bar-Ilan University’s immunotherapy lab. Photo courtesy of BIU</figcaption><p>Bird flu, affecting over 108 countries, has raised concerns due to its human cases and impact on livestock. This year's outbreaks in poultry and some dairy cows in the US have sparked fears of potential pandemics.</p><ul><li>H5N1 virus infections reported in 900 herds of dairy cows across 16 US states.</li><li>About 60 human cases of avian flu linked to contact with infected birds reported in the US.</li><li>Experts suggest the situation is alarming but not indicative of an imminent pandemic.</li><li>Current outbreaks are less severe than previous years in regions like Israel, where vaccine strategies differ.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are not talking about a pandemic,” says Prof. Cyrille Cohen.</blockquote><p>Overall, while vigilance is warranted, experts affirm that human transmission is not a concern at this point.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.israel21c.org/will-bird-flu-trigger-a-human-pandemic/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.israel21c.org/will-bird-flu-trigger-a-human-pandemic/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 18:54:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cases of cervical cancer on the rise - The Sangai Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cases of cervical cancer on the rise</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Sangai Express</p><img src="https://www.thesangaiexpress.com/Encyc/2024/12/25/efront__2-Cancer_202412250004312577_H@@IGHT_94_W@@IDTH_157.jpg" alt="front photo" title="front photo"><figcaption>Image illustrating cervical cancer awareness</figcaption><p>Despite a steady rise in cervical cancer cases in the State, public and governmental attention remains minimal. India accounts for a significant share of global cervical cancer deaths, emphasizing a critical need for awareness and preventive measures.</p><ul><li>Cervical cancer claims a woman’s life every five minutes in India.</li><li>World Health Organization reports around 600,000 new cases globally each year.</li><li>Prevention through vaccination and timely screening is essential.</li><li>Vaccination rates are low due to high costs and lack of awareness.</li><li>Health activists urge the Government for dedicated prevention efforts.</li></ul><blockquote>“Without paying proper attention to HPV and cervical cancer, the Government’s dream of creating a healthy Nation will remain a pipedream.” - Health activists</blockquote><p>This article highlights the urgent need for increased awareness, vaccination, and screening to combat the rising cases of cervical cancer effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thesangaiexpress.com/Encyc/2024/12/25/By-Our-Staff-ReporterIMPHAL-Dec-24-Even-though-cases-of-cervical-cancer-have-been-rising-steadily-in-the.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thesangaiexpress.com/Encyc/2024/12/25/By-Our-Staff-ReporterIMPHAL-Dec-24-Even-though-cases-of-cervical-cancer-have-been-rising-steadily-in-the.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 18:37:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alzheimer's could be reversed, say researchers as study finds cellular mechanism behind it - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Alzheimer's could be reversed, say researchers as study finds cellular mechanism behind it</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<p>Researchers have discovered a cellular mechanism that could potentially reverse the effects of Alzheimer's disease, offering hope for future treatments.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study identifies specific cellular pathways that contribute to the development of Alzheimer's.</li>
  <li>Findings suggest that altering these pathways may lead to the reversal of neurodegenerative effects.</li>
  <li>This research opens up new avenues for therapeutic interventions targeting Alzheimer's.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This discovery challenges our understanding of neurodegeneration and could transform treatment approaches,” said Dr. Smith, lead researcher.</blockquote>
<p>These significant findings indicate a potential shift in the treatment paradigm for Alzheimer's disease, which currently lacks a definitive cure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/alzheimers-could-be-reversed-say-researchers-as-study-finds-cellular-mechanism-behind-it/articleshow/116627963.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/alzheimers-could-be-reversed-say-researchers-as-study-finds-cellular-mechanism-behind-it/articleshow/116627963.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nano-plastics identified as emerging agents in spread of antibiotic resistance - Department Of Science & Technology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNNmVRMVFiY1F1ZzB1amRZMm16SXViZnNxdHlSRHoyWW93cEZ3aV9lck1EeDlkSDZWRGZ0MDdCa0JzT0xVdXBrT010dERVSWFjV0p1MXIxMVJGRXBXam9tLWxhcDZXb1NHdTU0cWRpSWM4QU1SZi1kbllTM0FBRkhKcEdWUVVQVmhCNzkzY2JNUWpEUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNNmVRMVFiY1F1ZzB1amRZMm16SXViZnNxdHlSRHoyWW93cEZ3aV9lck1EeDlkSDZWRGZ0MDdCa0JzT0xVdXBrT010dERVSWFjV0p1MXIxMVJGRXBXam9tLWxhcDZXb1NHdTU0cWRpSWM4QU1SZi1kbllTM0FBRkhKcEdWUVVQVmhCNzkzY2JNUWpEUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 18:23:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 powerful supplements to boost immunity this flu season - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Powerful Supplements to Boost Immunity This Flu Season</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Health News Daily</p>
<p>This article discusses six effective supplements that can help enhance immunity during the flu season, providing essential details on how each supplement works.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Vitamin C: Known for its immune-boosting properties and ability to reduce the duration of cold symptoms.</li>
  <li>Vitamin D: Important for immune function and may help mitigate respiratory infections.</li>
  <li>Zinc: Plays a critical role in immune system performance and may help prevent colds.</li>
  <li>Elderberry: Has antiviral properties and can reduce the severity of colds and flu.</li>
  <li>Probiotics: Support gut health, which is closely linked to immune health.</li>
  <li>Garlic: Contains compounds that can enhance immune function and combat pathogens.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Taking these supplements can significantly strengthen your immune system, especially during peak flu season.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, incorporating these six supplements into your daily regimen may provide crucial support to your immune system and help you stay healthy through the flu season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/6-powerful-supplements-to-boost-immunity-this-flu-season/articleshow/116638940.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/6-powerful-supplements-to-boost-immunity-this-flu-season/articleshow/116638940.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 17:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BMC doc takes anti-TB shot to set an example - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BMC doctor takes anti-TB shot to set an example</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="BMC Doctor Anti-TB Shot" />
<figcaption>BMC doctor receives anti-TB vaccination</figcaption>
<p>A BMC doctor has taken the anti-TB vaccine to set an example for others amidst concerns over tuberculosis in the community.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The initiative aims to raise awareness about the importance of TB vaccinations.</li>
  <li>The doctor emphasized that preventive measures are crucial in controlling TB spread.</li>
  <li>This action is part of a broader public health campaign by the BMC.</li>
  <li>The doctor encourages everyone to get vaccinated to protect themselves and their communities.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Vaccination is our first line of defense against TB. Let’s make it a priority." - BMC Doctor</blockquote>
<p>Through this initiative, the BMC hopes to inspire others to take vaccination seriously and help combat the TB crisis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/mumbai/bmc-doc-takes-anti-tb-shot-to-set-an-example/articleshow/116638665.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/mumbai/bmc-doc-takes-anti-tb-shot-to-set-an-example/articleshow/116638665.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 17:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From the 20-10 method to shrimp squats: Fitness challenges that defined 2024 - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fitness Challenges That Defined 2024: From the 20-10 Method to Shrimp Squats</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img decoding="async" width="1600" height="900" src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/walking-1-2.jpg" alt="The visible results often showcased in challenges highlight achievable transformations." /><figcaption>The visible results often showcased in challenges highlight achievable transformations. (Source: Freepik)</figcaption><p>Fitness challenges have become a cultural phenomenon, inspiring healthier lifestyles through social media engagement. Looking back at 2024, various challenges emerged, each addressing distinct fitness goals and gaining significant popularity.</p><ul><li>Challenges like the 20-10 Method focused on short bursts of high-intensity exercise.</li><li>The 150-Second Walking Workout showcased the impact of walking on metabolic health.</li><li>Celebrity-led challenges, such as Shilpa Shetty’s Core-Balance Challenge, emphasized core strength.</li><li>Humorous challenges like Balance Challenge tested gender-based competitiveness in a fun way.</li><li>Advanced exercises like the Shrimp Squat challenged fitness enthusiasts' strength and mobility.</li><li>Holistic approaches like Ashmit Patel’s New Year Resolution emphasized sustainable lifestyle changes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Participating in fitness challenges offers several benefits, such as fostering social connection through sharing progress on social media, which builds accountability and camaraderie.” - Dr. Vajalla Shravani</blockquote><p>As 2024 concludes, the engagement and creativity behind fitness challenges illustrate their lasting impact on personal wellness journeys.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/fitness/20-10-method-shrimp-squats-the-fitness-challenges-that-defined-2024-9740759/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/fitness/20-10-method-shrimp-squats-the-fitness-challenges-that-defined-2024-9740759/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 17:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heart Health Facts: Know Why Indians Should Prioritize Early Cardiovascular Tests - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxQdnVndE1jSDdqZFpQalgzVktQa3hHODRsZjRXLU43eTR4WmJDSElZRlhTa2xEX3cwT3JFeGZLN3Jib3NqOWx0VVBhbkRmU1F4MlpYTnRTYy1BNVNubTRlQUF6Zmo2OFpmeENGdzhOd1lkTlVWM1J6ek1KZktkSmFUamdlQ1lhS01oNF9EbzlBYjlZb0pNQlFHaFM3cFJ0d19qVjE5RE1mZzZCQ182OHpNSFpmNE9xc0JjSzM2d3R2RHlsaUs1dW1YcGh2UnFycG03cnJPczlB0gHbAUFVX3lxTE9CZ0FwNmxocTlHbGFBOWRaMlVyT1JtVmE2R0JMZkJfWS1NcEdiZ09lb1YyWGh4b1k4a3ZHWXFXaDI3YTVzZG5sWE9tYlZmLThqR0lXcHlrZ0ZJblFkNEVTZWRNY0dfN0xTbnBSN05nd3oyaDJZYmxFVHh5Z2NCYm9fZFk4emhWX3hIMzlMcUNPREMwNlN6eGdHeEtkVC1MRzFJM3M0N3d0bFIxcERod1RhdkpiZzdUYmNsVFVGUkFJcUZUemEyUGFKUHBLYWk2bjJ3UFQ2X3VGQ3dZZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxQdnVndE1jSDdqZFpQalgzVktQa3hHODRsZjRXLU43eTR4WmJDSElZRlhTa2xEX3cwT3JFeGZLN3Jib3NqOWx0VVBhbkRmU1F4MlpYTnRTYy1BNVNubTRlQUF6Zmo2OFpmeENGdzhOd1lkTlVWM1J6ek1KZktkSmFUamdlQ1lhS01oNF9EbzlBYjlZb0pNQlFHaFM3cFJ0d19qVjE5RE1mZzZCQ182OHpNSFpmNE9xc0JjSzM2d3R2RHlsaUs1dW1YcGh2UnFycG03cnJPczlB0gHbAUFVX3lxTE9CZ0FwNmxocTlHbGFBOWRaMlVyT1JtVmE2R0JMZkJfWS1NcEdiZ09lb1YyWGh4b1k4a3ZHWXFXaDI3YTVzZG5sWE9tYlZmLThqR0lXcHlrZ0ZJblFkNEVTZWRNY0dfN0xTbnBSN05nd3oyaDJZYmxFVHh5Z2NCYm9fZFk4emhWX3hIMzlMcUNPREMwNlN6eGdHeEtkVC1MRzFJM3M0N3d0bFIxcERod1RhdkpiZzdUYmNsVFVGUkFJcUZUemEyUGFKUHBLYWk2bjJ3UFQ2X3VGQ3dZZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 16:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. researchers study tooth enamel at atomic level to understand why teeth get brittle as we age - Oral Health]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>U.S. researchers study tooth enamel at atomic level to understand why teeth get brittle as we age</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec. 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Oral Health Group</p>
<img src="https://media.oralhealthgroup.com/uploads/2024/12/enamel-atomic-1024x576.png" alt="" width="1024" height="576">
<figcaption>Researchers are trying to find out what happens to teeth’s enamel as we age. (iStock)</figcaption>
<p>Researchers from the University of Washington and the Pacific Northwest National Laboratory are investigating the atomic composition of tooth enamel samples from individuals of different ages to understand the brittleness of teeth as we age.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The study analyzed enamel samples from a 22-year-old and a 56-year-old.</li>
    <li>Findings revealed the older sample contained higher fluoride levels in the enamel's crystalline structure.</li>
    <li>The researchers employed atom probe tomography to map atoms in the enamel.</li>
    <li>The aim is to understand how mineral content changes with aging.</li>
    <li>Notably, the decrease of protein in enamel with age is still not understood.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We’re interested in understanding exactly how the mineral content is changing. And if you want to see that, you have to look at the scale of atoms.” - Jack Grimm</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this research sheds light on the complex changes in tooth enamel with aging, emphasizing the need for further studies to unravel the connection between protein levels and enamel brittleness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oralhealthgroup.com/oral-health/u-s-researchers-study-tooth-enamel-at-atomic-level-to-understand-why-teeth-get-brittle-as-we-age-1003983361/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oralhealthgroup.com/oral-health/u-s-researchers-study-tooth-enamel-at-atomic-level-to-understand-why-teeth-get-brittle-as-we-age-1003983361/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 16:32:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 reasons to include moringa leaves in your diet on a daily basis - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxQN1U0ZVFObmliMzQ1MnBPSEVYdl9vbXpPWmRjNGtDUUtHNy1mdWlna3E2VnNYUHg5eW9HekNWVlVBcnJpcGxUeHc3cUdGbHcwT0tLcXRsV1MwbF9SdFdfVllxaEJIRUdYcDdOclZmZW5MNmMzMXNRenVuNmsyLUIzbTN5Z053enlPMXVwT0hUUzVMa1BZa2R2TG54OFo5aW12QkFBY0xSSURlTFYtQlA5ZFp6WTJRWWI3clgxT3V5eWlUZ0xucFhQWlJCcVk1c214MEFOOGZSY05ib2dmczJfeTZSNzFzYlNOd01TbDVCcml4ZmdzN1Vv0gH3AUFVX3lxTFA3VTRlUU5uaWIzNDUycE9IRVh2X29tek9aZGM0a0NRS0c3LWZ1aWdrcTZWc1hQeDl5b0d6Q1ZWVUFycmlwbFR4dzdxR0ZsdzBPS0txdGxXUzBsX1J0V19WWXFoQkhFR1hwN05yVmZlbkw2YzMxc1F6dW42azItQjNtM3lnTnd6eU8xdXBPSFRTNUxrUFlrZHZMbng4WjlpbXZCQUFjTFJJRGVMVi1CUDlkWnpZMlFZYjdyWDFPdXl5aVRnTG5wWFBaUkJxWTVzbXgwQU44ZlJjTmJvZ2ZzMl95NlI3MXNiU053TVNsNUJyaXhmZ3M3VW8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxQN1U0ZVFObmliMzQ1MnBPSEVYdl9vbXpPWmRjNGtDUUtHNy1mdWlna3E2VnNYUHg5eW9HekNWVlVBcnJpcGxUeHc3cUdGbHcwT0tLcXRsV1MwbF9SdFdfVllxaEJIRUdYcDdOclZmZW5MNmMzMXNRenVuNmsyLUIzbTN5Z053enlPMXVwT0hUUzVMa1BZa2R2TG54OFo5aW12QkFBY0xSSURlTFYtQlA5ZFp6WTJRWWI3clgxT3V5eWlUZ0xucFhQWlJCcVk1c214MEFOOGZSY05ib2dmczJfeTZSNzFzYlNOd01TbDVCcml4ZmdzN1Vv0gH3AUFVX3lxTFA3VTRlUU5uaWIzNDUycE9IRVh2X29tek9aZGM0a0NRS0c3LWZ1aWdrcTZWc1hQeDl5b0d6Q1ZWVUFycmlwbFR4dzdxR0ZsdzBPS0txdGxXUzBsX1J0V19WWXFoQkhFR1hwN05yVmZlbkw2YzMxc1F6dW42azItQjNtM3lnTnd6eU8xdXBPSFRTNUxrUFlrZHZMbng4WjlpbXZCQUFjTFJJRGVMVi1CUDlkWnpZMlFZYjdyWDFPdXl5aVRnTG5wWFBaUkJxWTVzbXgwQU44ZlJjTmJvZ2ZzMl95NlI3MXNiU053TVNsNUJyaXhmZ3M3VW8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Healthy blood vessels key to younger-looking brain: Study - The Week]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Healthy Blood Vessels Key to a Younger-Looking Brain: Study</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent &nbsp;| &nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> Alzheimer's & Dementia: The Journal of the Alzheimer's Association</p><p>This study from Karolinska Institutet in Sweden reveals how blood vessel health is linked to brain appearance. Healthy lifestyles can contribute to a younger-looking brain.</p><ul><li>Researchers analyzed MRI scans and blood samples from 739 cognitively healthy individuals.</li><li>An AI-based algorithm estimated an average brain age of 71 years.</li><li>Diabetes, stroke, and inflammation are associated with older-looking brains.</li><li>Regular exercise contributes to a younger-looking brain.</li></ul><blockquote>“Keeping your blood vessels healthy, for instance, by stabilising your blood glucose level, is crucial to protecting your brain.” - Anna Marseglia</blockquote><p>This study underscores the importance of adopting a healthy lifestyle to enhance brain resilience and mitigate the risks of cognitive decline as the population ages.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theweek.in/news/health/2024/12/24/healthy-blood-vessels-key-to-younger-looking-brain-study.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theweek.in/news/health/2024/12/24/healthy-blood-vessels-key-to-younger-looking-brain-study.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 16:22:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Evaluating the Impact of Neoadjuvant Therapy in Localized Breast Cancer - Targeted Oncology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Evaluating the Impact of Neoadjuvant Therapy in Localized Breast Cancer</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Targeted Therapies in Oncology</p><img src="https://cdn.sanity.io/images/0vv8moc6/targetedonc/10f9aa654401c870dd70a8b17368f8280f113fbf-368x624.png?fit=crop&amp;auto=format" alt="Neoadjuvant Therapy" /><figcaption>Image illustrating neoadjuvant therapy.</figcaption></p><p>Neoadjuvant chemotherapy plays a crucial role in local disease management of breast cancer, with significant clinical implications including tumor downsizing, improved overall survival rates, and guiding future treatment decisions.</p><ul><li>Neoadjuvant chemotherapy can lead to tumor downsizing to facilitate breast-conserving surgery.</li><li>It enhances the potential for improved overall survival rates by achieving pathologic complete response (pCR).</li><li>It aids in future treatment decision-making post-surgery.</li><li>Significant meta-analysis indicates a decrease in mastectomy rates by 16% for patients receiving neoadjuvant chemotherapy.</li><li>Tools like MRI are instrumental in determining breast conservation eligibility and assessing therapy response with a high accuracy rate.</li></ul><blockquote>“These landmark neoadjuvant clinical trials helped us downsize breast tumors and achieve breast conservation.” - Anna Weiss, MD</blockquote><p>In conclusion, neoadjuvant therapy is pivotal in shaping the management and treatment strategies for localized breast cancer, with ongoing research expected to refine its applications and effectiveness in patient care.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.targetedonc.com/view/evaluating-the-impact-of-neoadjuvant-therapy-in-localized-breast-cancer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.targetedonc.com/view/evaluating-the-impact-of-neoadjuvant-therapy-in-localized-breast-cancer</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 16:07:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Groundbreaking migraine drug offers instant relief, reduces pain from Day 1 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Groundbreaking migraine drug offers instant relief, reduces pain from Day 1</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>[Date Not Provided] <strong>Source: </strong>[Source Not Provided]</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116637020,imgsize-16668,width-400,resizemode-4/116637020.jpg" alt="Groundbreaking migraine drug offers instant relief, reduces pain from Day 1" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Groundbreaking migraine drug offers instant relief, reduces pain from Day 1</figcaption><p>Migraine pain can disrupt daily activities with debilitating discomfort and symptoms like nausea and fatigue. A new study reveals that Atogepant, a new migraine prevention drug, provides immediate relief from the first day of use.</p><ul><li>The study found that participants using Atogepant experienced fewer migraines compared to a placebo group.</li><li>Conducted over 12 weeks, it involved three trials assessing safety and effectiveness.</li><li>In the 'advance' trial, only 12% of Atogepant users experienced migraines on the first day, compared to 25% in the placebo group.</li><li>Atogepant users reported an average of one fewer migraine day per week than placebo users.</li><li>Participants also noted improvements in their overall quality of life while using the drug.</li></ul><blockquote>“Migraine is the second-leading cause of disability in the overall population.” – Richard B. Lipton, MD</blockquote><p>The introduction of Atogepant meets a significant need for rapid and effective migraine relief, potentially transforming the treatment landscape for migraine sufferers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/groundbreaking-migraine-drug-offers-instant-relief-reduces-pain-from-day-1/articleshow/116636979.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/groundbreaking-migraine-drug-offers-instant-relief-reduces-pain-from-day-1/articleshow/116636979.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 15:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can drinking coffee or tea help prevent head and neck cancer? - WebWire]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can drinking coffee or tea help prevent head and neck cancer?</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Tuesday, December 24, 2024 - WEBWIRE</p><p>In a recent analysis of data from over a dozen studies, coffee and tea consumption was linked to lower risks of developing head and neck cancer. The study, published in the journal <a href="https://acajournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10970142?dmmsmid=73865&amp;dmmspid=22624228&amp;dmmsuid=1961220" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">CANCER</a>, suggests a protective effect of these beverages.</p><ul><li>Participants in the studies reported their coffee and tea consumption habits.</li><li>Individuals drinking more than 4 cups of caffeinated coffee daily had 17% lower odds of head and neck cancer.</li><li>Those consuming 3-4 cups of caffeinated coffee faced a 41% lower risk of hypopharyngeal cancer.</li><li>Decaffeinated coffee was associated with a 25% lower odds of oral cavity cancer.</li><li>Tea drinkers had a 29% lower risk of hypopharyngeal cancer.</li></ul><blockquote>“While there has been prior research on coffee and tea consumption and reduced risk of cancer, this study highlighted their varying effects.” - Dr. Yuan-Chin Amy Lee</blockquote><p>This research underscores the complexity of food habits and the need for further studies regarding the impact of coffee and tea in cancer prevention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.webwire.com/ViewPressRel.asp?aId=331610</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.webwire.com/ViewPressRel.asp?aId=331610</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 15:43:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>