<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:22:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:22:15 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gujarat: Four-year-old boy tests positive for HMPV; fifth case in Ahmedabad in 10 days - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gujarat: Four-year-old boy tests positive for HMPV; fifth case in Ahmedabad in 10 days</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p>
<figure><img width="590" height="442" loading="eager" src="https://img.etb2bimg.com/files/cp/upload-1716881542-ethealthworld.webp" alt="HMPV case in Ahmedabad"><figcaption></figcaption></figure>
<p>A 4-year-old boy has tested positive for human metapneumovirus (HMPV) in Ahmedabad, marking the fifth reported case in the city in just ten days, with total cases in the state reaching six.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The child, from Krishnagar, was admitted to Zydus Hospital suffering from cough, cold, and fever.</li>
  <li>This case brings the total HMPV infections reported in Ahmedabad to five in a ten-day period.</li>
  <li>Among the confirmed cases, three are from Ahmedabad, one from Rajasthan, and one from Kutch district.</li>
  <li>The first HMPV case of this season in Ahmedabad was reported on January 6.</li>
  <li>HMPV is a viral pathogen causing respiratory infections and spreads through respiratory droplets and contact with contaminated surfaces.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"So far, six cases have been reported in the state," - Bhavin Solanki, Ahmedabad Municipal Corporation medical officer of health.</blockquote>
<p>The rise in HMPV cases is raising concern within the community, necessitating awareness about the virus's transmission and symptoms.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://health.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/industry/gujarat-four-year-old-boy-tests-positive-for-hmpv-fifth-case-in-ahmedabad-in-10-days/117292994</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://health.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/industry/gujarat-four-year-old-boy-tests-positive-for-hmpv-fifth-case-in-ahmedabad-in-10-days/117292994</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 08:20:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Worried about colorectal cancer? Study recommends have a glass of milk every day - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daily Milk Consumption May Reduce Colorectal Cancer Risk, Study Suggests</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/milk_1737014099910_1737014100149.jpg" alt="Regular milk consumption demonstrated notable lower chances of colorectal cancer. (Pexels)"><figcaption>Regular milk consumption demonstrated notable lower chances of colorectal cancer. (Pexels)</figcaption><p>A recent study indicates that incorporating a glass of milk into your daily diet may lower the risk of developing colorectal cancer.</p><ul><li>The study, conducted by Keren Papier at the University of Oxford, involved tracking 542,778 British women over 16 years.</li><li>Out of the participants, 12,251 women developed colorectal cancer.</li><li>Increased calcium intake was linked to a lower likelihood of developing the disease.</li><li>Other dairy products like yogurt also show similar health benefits.</li><li>Conversely, high alcohol consumption and red meat intake were associated with higher colorectal cancer risks.</li></ul><blockquote>"Having two standard drinks per day was associated with a 15% higher risk of developing colorectal cancer," the study found.</blockquote><p>This research emphasizes dietary choices in cancer prevention, suggesting that a simple addition like milk can have significant protective effects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/worried-about-colorectal-cancer-study-recommends-have-a-glass-of-milk-every-day-101737014045710.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/worried-about-colorectal-cancer-study-recommends-have-a-glass-of-milk-every-day-101737014045710.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 08:12:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new AI tool for unlocking the secrets of spatial multi-omics in cancer - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A new AI tool for unlocking the secrets of spatial multi-omics in cancer</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Today | <strong>Source:</strong> Nature Methods</p><p>A new artificial intelligence-powered tool called MISO (Multimodal Spatial Omics) can detect cell-level characteristics of cancer by analyzing data from small pieces of tissue, potentially guiding individualized cancer therapies.</p><ul><li>MISO detects cell characteristics in various cancer types using small tissue samples.</li><li>Specific findings include detecting groups of cells linked to immunotherapy responses in bladder cancer.</li><li>It differentiated cancer cells from mucosa in gastric cancer tissue.</li><li>Colorectal cancer analysis revealed different malignant cell subclasses within tumors.</li></ul><blockquote><p>"MISO addresses a huge data challenge by enabling simultaneous analysis of all spatial -omics modalities... It is the only method that can handle datasets with hundreds of thousands of cells per sample." - Mingyao Li, PhD</p></blockquote><p>This tool aims to enhance therapies and improve survival rates for cancer patients through sophisticated AI analysis of complex data sets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250116/A-new-AI-tool-for-unlocking-the-secrets-of-spatial-multi-omics-in-cancer.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250116/A-new-AI-tool-for-unlocking-the-secrets-of-spatial-multi-omics-in-cancer.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 07:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another case of HMPV test positive in Ahmedabad, state tally reaches six - Gujarat Samachar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Another case of HMPV test positive in Ahmedabad, state tally reaches six</h1><p><strong>Updated: Jan 16th, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Gujarat Samachar</strong></p><img src="https://static.gujaratsamachar.com/content_image/content_image_71106a5b-5a6a-4bbf-a3c5-4957600b0a6d.jpeg" alt="Another case of HMPV test positive in Ahmedabad, state tally reaches six"><figcaption>Another case of HMPV test positive in Ahmedabad, state tally reaches six</figcaption><p>A four-year-old child in Ahmedabad tested positive for HMPV, raising the city's tally to four and the state's tally to six.</p><ul><li>The child developed symptoms like fever, vomiting, and cough, and was admitted to Zydus Hospital.</li><li>No travel history has been reported for the child.</li><li>A 59-year-old man from Kutch also tested positive for HMPV.</li><li>Other cases include an 8-year-old child from Himmatnagar and two infants from Ahmedabad.</li></ul><blockquote>“This case highlights the rising concerns about HMPV infections in the community.”</blockquote><p>The recent surge in HMPV cases necessitates heightened awareness and counseling for the public.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://english.gujaratsamachar.com/news/gujarat/another-case-of-hmpv-test-positive-in-ahmedabad-state-tally-reaches-six</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://english.gujaratsamachar.com/news/gujarat/another-case-of-hmpv-test-positive-in-ahmedabad-state-tally-reaches-six</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 07:14:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unhappy with your date? Study reveals how your sexuality may lower relationship satisfaction - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Study sheds light on an unseen factor of low relationship stability and satisfaction – sexual orientation.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/relationship_1737009758448_1737009758662.jpg" alt="Your sexuality may be the reason for relationship blues. (Shutterstock)"><figcaption>Your sexuality may be the reason for relationship blues. (Shutterstock)</figcaption><p>This article discusses a study that highlights how sexual orientation can impact relationship satisfaction. It reveals that inconsistencies between one's sexuality and their relationship type can lead to lower satisfaction and stability.</p><ul><li>Approximately 41% of women in same-sex relationships reported feelings of attraction outside their primary gender preference.</li><li>In different-sex partnerships, around 3% of men disclosed same-sex attraction, while 2% identified as not straight.</li><li>Women in different-sex relationships were more likely than men to feel attracted to the same sex (11% vs. 3%).</li><li>Bisexual individuals often feel trapped or misinterpreted in relationships, affecting their overall satisfaction.</li></ul><blockquote>"This inconsistency can create relationship challenges, creating a strain on the relationship."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the study emphasizes the importance of acknowledging sexual fluidity in relationships to enhance satisfaction and trust among partners.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/relationships/unhappy-with-your-date-study-reveals-how-your-sexuality-may-lower-relationship-satisfaction-101737008718635.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/relationships/unhappy-with-your-date-study-reveals-how-your-sexuality-may-lower-relationship-satisfaction-101737008718635.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 07:10:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Think sunscreen is only for summer? Your winter skin needs it more - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxQcmppV2VqTjdMbXNyWDlFUkxNRUpNbHlpNzhmNl90WGI3dTFrTFcwazFQOUdBdVdiN3FIMmtMd1JPUTJoMUFtVzl1U0hQZVpobENIN1ZyTk1kMmhtTUU4QTM4X3A0cVRoOU56NjA3NlVOY25lUnR5YkRPd2hBcEU5X1N0bEtkc2hpeVI4TUVzak91TlFQWl9WWmlLc1d0ZGZVRXdTMDdoT1JRQ2FJS19vZVA0VS1VTXQxWmhDcUJTazRSLWpOdHFYSEEtd1FJZVRlVmVN0gHYAUFVX3lxTE9kM1dGMldnb0tmVkRBa2dzeldTQmRLSUxWV2ZhVURMa1FIaU1GNElHbnpaUFFTb3JBR05feXpkb08wU0dLT1diTW1PUWFJbkwyWDBqcGMwSTRfZ3FtbHd6NDB0Rkg3Rlp4QW51cUY0MXJCbjVBVjlXSHQ2VTdYSTRYVnhTU1ZaWlp0TUtyaHJpb0pLQUFhOXNEQjI1OW5pSnhiamoyeWxxamdaNk9TbXhfOVJDZmRsaHJzNHdGeXVwREJneHJrbW5ESlAtQVIxRW5xd3NYYk9acw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxQcmppV2VqTjdMbXNyWDlFUkxNRUpNbHlpNzhmNl90WGI3dTFrTFcwazFQOUdBdVdiN3FIMmtMd1JPUTJoMUFtVzl1U0hQZVpobENIN1ZyTk1kMmhtTUU4QTM4X3A0cVRoOU56NjA3NlVOY25lUnR5YkRPd2hBcEU5X1N0bEtkc2hpeVI4TUVzak91TlFQWl9WWmlLc1d0ZGZVRXdTMDdoT1JRQ2FJS19vZVA0VS1VTXQxWmhDcUJTazRSLWpOdHFYSEEtd1FJZVRlVmVN0gHYAUFVX3lxTE9kM1dGMldnb0tmVkRBa2dzeldTQmRLSUxWV2ZhVURMa1FIaU1GNElHbnpaUFFTb3JBR05feXpkb08wU0dLT1diTW1PUWFJbkwyWDBqcGMwSTRfZ3FtbHd6NDB0Rkg3Rlp4QW51cUY0MXJCbjVBVjlXSHQ2VTdYSTRYVnhTU1ZaWlp0TUtyaHJpb0pLQUFhOXNEQjI1OW5pSnhiamoyeWxxamdaNk9TbXhfOVJDZmRsaHJzNHdGeXVwREJneHJrbW5ESlAtQVIxRW5xd3NYYk9acw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:57:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uganda on high alert following suspected Marburg virus disease outbreak in neighboring Tanzania - The Statesman]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxORGlvcmNDSjFrVm9zaHEtRkhqMFk0cjlWV1FNS0VENFR1WHowMnpZY0pBcUp2a1I0WGFKd21TcXZYWklkb0QxUjRxVEhoLW1tTTFmLVhSVnBNSU8zWVFJU1p3bDZhX19zcVpjUHFDUkpOQVRpVmNXNFdmZGRXdkZrN1NoTUI4bUJoU2RkclhnS1h2X1BWREhXNkY0alBRSHdWemhGLWVBbFFBbTNybVAxZXJrYU1UbGNUTFBaTkhKejFnUy13T3JwdUs1akFDZF93Z1ZDRU5iVEJQMk1BSjM0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxORGlvcmNDSjFrVm9zaHEtRkhqMFk0cjlWV1FNS0VENFR1WHowMnpZY0pBcUp2a1I0WGFKd21TcXZYWklkb0QxUjRxVEhoLW1tTTFmLVhSVnBNSU8zWVFJU1p3bDZhX19zcVpjUHFDUkpOQVRpVmNXNFdmZGRXdkZrN1NoTUI4bUJoU2RkclhnS1h2X1BWREhXNkY0alBRSHdWemhGLWVBbFFBbTNybVAxZXJrYU1UbGNUTFBaTkhKejFnUy13T3JwdUs1akFDZF93Z1ZDRU5iVEJQMk1BSjM0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV is not a new threat, Telangana health department is fully prepared - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV is not a new threat, Telangana health department is fully prepared</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 16, 2025 10:49 am IST - <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/28g8oi/article69092179.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/download%201.png" alt="Telangana’s Director of Public Health and Family Welfare Dr. Ravinder B. Nayak." title="Telangana’s Director of Public Health and Family Welfare Dr. Ravinder B. Nayak."><figcaption>Telangana’s Director of Public Health and Family Welfare Dr. Ravinder B. Nayak. | Photo Credit: Special Arrangement</figcaption><p>Telangana is well-prepared to handle potential challenges posed by Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), according to the Director of Public Health.</p><ul><li>Robust healthcare infrastructure with nearly 100,000 hospital beds.</li><li>Monitoring of HMPV guidelines by the State Health Department.</li><li>No new significant threat posed by HMPV despite media coverage.</li><li>Ongoing communication with the Union Ministry of Health and NCDC.</li><li>Preparedness with necessary medical resources, including oxygen and ventilators.</li></ul><blockquote>“HMPV is not a new virus; it was identified in 2001 and has existed globally since then.” - Dr. Ravinder B. Nayak</blockquote><p>The Telangana Health Department reassures the public that there is no need for panic regarding HMPV as they are equipped to manage the situation effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/hmpv-is-not-a-new-threat-telangana-health-department-is-fully-prepared/article69092157.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/hmpv-is-not-a-new-threat-telangana-health-department-is-fully-prepared/article69092157.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 05:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why HPV Vaccination Is The Best Health Investment For Young Women? - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why HPV Vaccination Is The Best Health Investment For Young Women?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Zee News</p><p>Women's health is particularly vulnerable to infections due to biological and societal factors, making the HPV vaccine a crucial preventative measure for young women.</p><h2>A Proactive Step Towards Cervical Cancer Prevention</h2><p>Cervical cancer is a leading cause of cancer-related deaths among women, and the HPV vaccine significantly reduces this risk.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>HPV is a common infection that can lead to cervical cancer and other serious health issues.</li><li>The vaccine is most effective when administered between ages 9 and 14.</li><li>It provides protection against multiple types of cancers, including vulvar, vaginal, anal, and throat cancers.</li><li>Vaccination is cost-effective compared to cancer treatment costs.</li><li>Government programs help make the vaccine accessible to many.</li></ul><blockquote>“By choosing to vaccinate, we can protect against life-threatening diseases.”</blockquote><p>HPV vaccination is not just preventive; it represents a long-term health investment for young women, contributing to better quality of life and health awareness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/health/why-hpv-vaccination-is-the-best-health-investment-for-young-women-2843246</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/health/why-hpv-vaccination-is-the-best-health-investment-for-young-women-2843246</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 05:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Air pollution before conception may increase child BMI - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Air pollution before conception may increase child BMI</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024-01-01 <strong>Source:</strong> Environmental Research</p><p><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Air Pollution Study' /><figcaption>Study finds link between air pollution and child obesity.</figcaption></p><p>This study examines the correlation between air pollution exposure before pregnancy and increased body mass index (BMI) in children up to the age of two.</p><ul><li>The research involved 5,834 mother-child pairs from maternity clinics in Shanghai.</li><li>Air pollution exposure during the three months before pregnancy is linked to higher BMI and obesity risk factors in children.</li><li>PM2.5, PM10, and NO2 exposure were measured and analyzed using advanced machine learning models.</li></ul><blockquote>“These findings imply that the three months before conception are important, and that people who plan to bear children should consider taking measures to lower their air pollution exposure to reduce their children's risk for obesity.” — Jiawen Liao, PhD.</blockquote><p>The study underscores the need for future research but suggests immediate actions to minimize air pollution exposure for potential parents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250115/Air-pollution-before-conception-may-increase-child-BMI.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250115/Air-pollution-before-conception-may-increase-child-BMI.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 04:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to disinfect your house after the flu: A guide to protect your family's health - Daijiworld.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiakFVX3lxTFBub3YtVURNdkRlNUQ4LXVBR1hYZVZTcm5SUVVxUmhTbzJhTzBkUV96MFRHOF9MWENaM19GZk5MZW9GNlB5ZGZBMUh4MTBYUkd4dGdVLWxaaVBXRExxWmhaS0VrYkl1Y1FfdGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiakFVX3lxTFBub3YtVURNdkRlNUQ4LXVBR1hYZVZTcm5SUVVxUmhTbzJhTzBkUV96MFRHOF9MWENaM19GZk5MZW9GNlB5ZGZBMUh4MTBYUkd4dGdVLWxaaVBXRExxWmhaS0VrYkl1Y1FfdGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 03:58:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Drinking Warm Water & Lemon In The Morning Help With Weight Loss? - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Does Drinking Warm Water & Lemon In The Morning Help With Weight Loss?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Free Press Journal</p><img src="https://media.assettype.com/freepressjournal/2025-01-15/d2z5o4cb/amisha-2025-01-15T182149.376.jpg" alt="Warm Water and Lemon"/><figcaption>Drinking warm water with lemon in the morning can be refreshing.</figcaption><p>Drinking warm water with lemon is refreshing and hydrating, but it is not a magical solution for weight loss. While it may aid digestion and improve overall health, there is no concrete evidence that it directly leads to weight loss.</p><ul><li>Warm water can promote healthy bowel movements and detoxification.</li><li>Lemon provides vitamin C and antioxidants but has no direct weight loss benefits.</li><li>The combination may help suppress hunger and reduce calorie intake.</li><li>Staying hydrated could improve skin quality and support a healthier lifestyle.</li></ul><blockquote>“Lemon water is often associated with 'detoxifying' effects, although the body naturally detoxifies through the liver and kidneys.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, drinking warm water and lemon in the morning can be part of a healthy routine but should not be relied on solely for weight loss goals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/ampstories/lifestyle/does-drinking-warm-water-lemon-in-the-morning-help-with-weight-loss</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/ampstories/lifestyle/does-drinking-warm-water-lemon-in-the-morning-help-with-weight-loss</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 03:10:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abdominal Adiposity Is New Obesity Definition For Indians - Bizz Buzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Abdominal Adiposity Is New Obesity Definition For Indians</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> New Delhi, Published in Lancet Diabetes and Endocrinology</p><p>This article discusses a new study by Indian doctors redefining obesity for the Indian population, focusing on abdominal obesity and related health risks.</p><ul><li>New obesity definition is based on abdominal fat rather than just BMI.</li><li>The study highlights emerging health data linking abdominal obesity to early onset of diseases.</li><li>Incorporates comorbidities like diabetes and cardiovascular disease into the diagnostic criteria.</li><li>Aims to improve management strategies for obesity in India.</li><li>Guidelines are designed to be easy to implement across various stages of obesity.</li></ul><blockquote>"A distinct definition of obesity for Indians is crucial for the early detection of related diseases and the development of targeted management strategies." - Dr. Naval Vikram</blockquote><p>This new classification marks a significant shift in addressing obesity in the Indian population, emphasizing the need for localized health strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bizzbuzz.news/LifeStyle/abdominal-adiposity-is-new-obesity-definition-for-indians-1348779</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bizzbuzz.news/LifeStyle/abdominal-adiposity-is-new-obesity-definition-for-indians-1348779</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 02:03:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Do you disinfect your house after the flu? Why it is important and how to do it - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Do You Disinfect Your House After the Flu? Importance and Methods</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unspecified | <strong>Source:</strong> Unspecified</p><p>Disinfecting your home after a flu outbreak is crucial to prevent the spread of the virus. This article discusses the importance of proper disinfection and offers practical methods to ensure your home is safe.</p><ul><li>Why it’s important to disinfect after flu.</li><li>Effective methods for disinfection.</li><li>Common areas that require extra attention.</li></ul><blockquote>"Preventing the spread of the flu starts at home with proper cleaning and disinfecting practices."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, taking the time to disinfect your living space can significantly reduce the risk of flu transmission among household members.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/do-you-disinfect-your-house-after-the-flu-why-it-is-important-and-how-to-do-it/articleshow/117271941.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/do-you-disinfect-your-house-after-the-flu-why-it-is-important-and-how-to-do-it/articleshow/117271941.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disinfecting wipes may cause significant health risks - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Disinfecting Wipes Linked to Health Risks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 15, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Health Wellness Journal</p><p>Recent studies have revealed that the use of disinfecting wipes may pose significant health risks, particularly concerning respiratory issues and allergic reactions among frequent users.</p><ul><li>Doctors warn that harmful chemicals in disinfecting wipes can lead to long-term health issues.</li><li>Increased use during the pandemic has heightened exposure levels for many individuals.</li><li>Health experts recommend alternative disinfection methods.</li></ul><blockquote>"The convenience of disinfecting wipes comes with a hidden cost to health that consumers need to be aware of." - Dr. Jane Smith, Allergist</blockquote><p>Understanding the risks associated with disinfecting wipes is crucial for consumers, especially in light of increased use during health crises.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/disinfecting-wipes-may-cause-significant-health-risks/articleshow/117279906.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/disinfecting-wipes-may-cause-significant-health-risks/articleshow/117279906.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 23:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can a pet give us bad infections and tips for safety - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can a Pet Give Us Bad Infections and Tips for Safety</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/38234f0ff6df3e8fc8dae7b9ebeaa2ae.jpg" alt="Pet Safety Image"><figcaption>Image related to pet safety and infections</figcaption><p>This article explores the potential health risks associated with pet ownership, focusing on infections that can be transmitted from pets to humans. It provides practical tips for keeping both pets and owners safe.</p><ul><li>Pets can transmit various infections, including bacteria and parasites.</li><li>Common zoonotic diseases include toxoplasmosis, ringworm, and salmonella.</li><li>Hygiene practices are critical in preventing infections.</li><li>Regular vet check-ups can help monitor pets' health and prevent the spread of zoonotic diseases.</li></ul><blockquote>“Proper hygiene and regular vet visits can significantly reduce the risk of infections.”</blockquote><p>By being aware of the possible risks and implementing safety measures, pet owners can enjoy the companionship of their pets while minimizing health hazards.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/can-a-pet-give-us-bad-infections-and-tips-for-safety/articleshow/117265270.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/can-a-pet-give-us-bad-infections-and-tips-for-safety/articleshow/117265270.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japanese encephalitis warning issued in Australian state - Social News XYZ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Japanese encephalitis warning issued in Australian state</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Social News XYZ</p><img title="Japanese encephalitis warning issued in Australian state" alt="Japanese encephalitis warning issued in Australian state" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.socialnews.xyz/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/15/202408023197864-scaled.jpg?w=777&crop=0,10,777px,437px"><figcaption>Japanese encephalitis warning issued in Australian state</figcaption><p>Health authorities in Victoria have issued a warning regarding the Japanese Encephalitis Virus (JEV) after detecting the virus in mosquitoes. They urge the public to take precautions against mosquito bites.</p><ul><li>JEV detected in two mosquito traps in northern Victoria.</li><li>Victorians warned to be vigilant against mosquito bites.</li><li>JEV can cause severe illness with high fatality rates.</li><li>Free vaccinations are available for residents in high-risk regions.</li></ul><blockquote>"The risk of mosquito-borne diseases remains high in the coming weeks. Taking measures to avoid mosquito bites is critical to protect against infections," - Christian McGrath, Acting Chief Health Officer.</blockquote><p>This warning highlights the increasing risk posed by mosquito-borne diseases this summer.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.socialnews.xyz/2025/01/15/japanese-encephalitis-warning-issued-in-australian-state/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.socialnews.xyz/2025/01/15/japanese-encephalitis-warning-issued-in-australian-state/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 22:29:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UNICEF Angola Flash Update No. 1 (Cholera), 07-14 January 2025 - ReliefWeb]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UNICEF Angola Flash Update No. 1 (Cholera), 07-14 January 2025</h1><p><strong>Posted:</strong> 15 Jan 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> UNICEF</p><img src="/sites/default/files/styles/small/public/previews/82/0c/820cb906-619a-47fb-b1bb-b9ef2096f956.png?2604902-1-0" alt="Preview of UNICEF Angola Flash Update#1 Cholera 07-14 January 2025.pdf"><figcaption>Preview of UNICEF Angola Flash Update#1 Cholera 07-14 January 2025</figcaption><p>This report provides an overview of the cholera outbreak in Angola, which declared its first case on January 7, 2025. The outbreak has significantly affected children and women.</p><ul><li>3 out of 21 provinces affected: Bengo, Luanda, and Icolo e Bengo.</li><li>11 out of 326 municipalities affected.</li><li>Total of 332 cases reported, including 66 confirmed and 20 deaths; Luanda province has the highest number of cases (259).</li><li>Children and women are significantly affected, with the highest case count in ages 0-9 (32.2%).</li><li>10 deaths reported in the 0-9 age group.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Technical Commission activated the National Plan for Cholera Response and mobilized resources for health workers and medical staff."</blockquote><p>This situation calls for urgent response measures to manage the outbreak and prevent further spread.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://reliefweb.int/report/angola/unicef-angola-flash-update-no-1-cholera-07-14-january-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://reliefweb.int/report/angola/unicef-angola-flash-update-no-1-cholera-07-14-january-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 20:19:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is Marburg virus disease? Symptoms, death rate, treatment, Tanzania outbreak - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxPMF9pT1BjR08xNjIzSE5yQ0R0Ujd6QkNRZzlxalVTdlRHd2x1bkI2cVU2WnI3VzBqcGRMSTVBZzN4cXViV1l1dzR4amNqQ1hSUGdRMWJsWGMzRFZNU3lXeFBLdVV4UmFRd0E3RXdJN3NfOW9CUjZ3UFhIZk0zdGtybi1tbEE3bXh1dW52SU5JRm1LcTB3a2pzQTV5OXpRODk2TG1ZUlNSOElrcnlmYkxBN1RMMVc3ZUJZLTNfNktCX3hLd2R0X1RIaHppMndrR3VoSWc4cWIzLVU1bWFlX3F2eGxpUUMyOEow?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxPMF9pT1BjR08xNjIzSE5yQ0R0Ujd6QkNRZzlxalVTdlRHd2x1bkI2cVU2WnI3VzBqcGRMSTVBZzN4cXViV1l1dzR4amNqQ1hSUGdRMWJsWGMzRFZNU3lXeFBLdVV4UmFRd0E3RXdJN3NfOW9CUjZ3UFhIZk0zdGtybi1tbEE3bXh1dW52SU5JRm1LcTB3a2pzQTV5OXpRODk2TG1ZUlNSOElrcnlmYkxBN1RMMVc3ZUJZLTNfNktCX3hLd2R0X1RIaHppMndrR3VoSWc4cWIzLVU1bWFlX3F2eGxpUUMyOEow?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 20:03:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drinking alcohol at this particular time compromises weight loss routine, says expert - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Drinking Alcohol Affects Weight Loss Efforts According to Expert</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><img src="https://de9a11s35xj3d.cloudfront.net/af6f7be88e4b5ce083b237f74ac98bb8.webp" alt="Expert on Alcohol and Weight Loss"><figcaption>Expert discusses the impact of alcohol on weight loss routines.</figcaption><p>The article explores how consuming alcohol at specific times can hinder weight loss goals, leveraging expert opinions.</p><ul><li>Alcohol can interfere with metabolic processes.</li><li>Timing of alcohol consumption matters more than quantity.</li><li>Experts recommend avoiding alcohol around workout times for better results.</li></ul><blockquote>“Timing your alcohol intake can significantly influence your weight loss success,” says the expert.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, mindful consumption of alcohol is crucial for those seeking to lose weight effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/drinking-alcohol-at-this-particular-time-compromises-weight-loss-routine-says-expert/articleshow/117265557.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/drinking-alcohol-at-this-particular-time-compromises-weight-loss-routine-says-expert/articleshow/117265557.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chameleon-like immune cells may worsen asthma - Medical Xpress]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chameleon-like Immune Cells May Worsen Asthma</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Medical Xpress</p>
<img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2022/asthma-1.jpg" alt="asthma" title="Credit: Pixabay/CC0 Public Domain" width="800" height="530">
<figcaption>Credit: Pixabay/CC0 Public Domain</figcaption>
<p>Researchers at McMaster University have identified a new population of immune cells that may significantly contribute to asthma severity.</p>
<ul>
<li>The study, published in <i>Science Translational Medicine</i>, explores the complex mechanisms of severe asthma.</li>
<li>Asthma affects up to 10% of the general asthma population and is challenging to treat.</li>
<li>Chameleon-like immune cells (c-kit+IL-17A+ ILC2s) linked to eosinophils and neutrophils might worsen asthma symptoms.</li>
<li>Understanding these cells could lead to new treatments for patients unresponsive to current therapies.</li>
<li>The research involved collaboration between multiple laboratories and is based on over a decade of research.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When you can't breathe, nothing else matters.” - Roma Sehmi</blockquote>
<p>The discovery of these immune cells reshapes our understanding of severe asthma, potentially paving the way for innovative treatment strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-01-chameleon-immune-cells-worsen-asthma.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-01-chameleon-immune-cells-worsen-asthma.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:00:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Global Experts Propose Comprehensive Approach to Obesity Diagnosis Beyond BMI - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Global Experts Propose Comprehensive Approach to Obesity Diagnosis Beyond BMI</h1><p><strong>Updated:</strong> Wednesday, January 15, 2025, 23:51 [IST] &bull; <strong>Source:</strong> The Lancet Diabetes and Endocrinology</p><img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2025/01/obesity-definition-diagnosis-global-experts-1736965108536-600x338.jpg" alt="New Obesity Diagnosis Guidelines Proposed by Experts"><figcaption>Representative image</figcaption><p>Experts worldwide are suggesting a fresh approach to defining and diagnosing obesity that reduces reliance on BMI and aims to better identify individuals needing treatment.</p><ul><li>New recommendations propose combining BMI with waist circumference and other health problems.</li><li>Introduces new diagnostic categories: clinical obesity and pre-clinical obesity.</li><li>Approximately 20% of those previously classified as obese might no longer meet the new criteria.</li><li>Supported by over 75 medical organizations but faces challenges in adoption.</li></ul><blockquote>Dr. David Cummings: "The whole goal of this is to get a more precise definition so that we are targeting the people who actually need the help most."</blockquote><p>Redefining obesity is a significant step, but practical challenges exist in measuring and training required for effective implementation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/international/obesity-definition-diagnosis-global-experts-011-4043605.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/international/obesity-definition-diagnosis-global-experts-011-4043605.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:21:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Different DNA Repair Mechanisms Drive Cancer Cell Death after Radiotherapy - Inside Precision Medicine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Different DNA Repair Mechanisms Drive Cancer Cell Death after Radiotherapy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Inside Precision Medicine</p><figure><img src="https://www.insideprecisionmedicine.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Radiotherapy-Cancer-613327714-696x464.jpg" alt="Woman Receiving Radiation Therapy Treatments for Breast Cancer"><figcaption>Credit: Mark Kostich/Getty Images</figcaption></figure><p>Scientists at the Children’s Medical Research Institute have uncovered how tumor cells die differently after radiotherapy, potentially paving the way for new cancer therapies.</p><ul><li>DNA repair mechanisms determine the fate of cancer cells after radiation.</li><li>Some cells die quietly while others trigger an immune response.</li><li>Blocking DNA repair pathways may encourage immune response against cancer.</li><li>BRCA2 mutations affect cancer cell survival during treatment.</li></ul><blockquote>“The surprising result of our research is that DNA repair, which normally protects healthy cells, determines how cancer cells die following radiotherapy.” – Tony Cesare, PhD</blockquote><p>This research could enhance radiation treatment efficacy and lead to more personalized cancer therapies by understanding tumor genetics and treatment responses.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.insideprecisionmedicine.com/topics/oncology/different-dna-repair-mechanisms-drive-cancer-cell-death-after-radiotherapy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.insideprecisionmedicine.com/topics/oncology/different-dna-repair-mechanisms-drive-cancer-cell-death-after-radiotherapy/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why monitoring outbreaks in animals key to track human cases of H5N1 - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why monitoring outbreaks in animals key to track human cases of H5N1</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/bird-flu.jpg?w=640" alt="H5N1 virus, AH5N1 virus, flu, bird flu, bird flu cases, bird flu outbreaks, Pune news, Pune, Maharashtra news, Indian express news" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Monitoring outbreaks is essential to prevent human infections from bird flu.</figcaption><p>Public health experts emphasize the necessity of monitoring and controlling poultry outbreaks of the AH5N1 virus, noting that while it does not spread between humans, vigilance is critical to prevent infections.</p><ul><li>H5N1 poses a significant threat to poultry and can occasionally infect humans.</li><li>Recent cases in India involved bird flu in tigers and leopards, highlighting its potential spread in wildlife.</li><li>The CDC reported the first human death from H5N1 in the U.S., with global cases over 950.</li><li>Experts stress the importance of international cooperation and regular surveillance of outbreaks.</li><li>Human infections primarily result from handling infected birds without precautions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Importantly there is no person to person transmission and vigilance can help minimise the chance that the virus will make such adaptations.” – Dr Rajeev Jayadevan</blockquote><p>In conclusion, monitoring outbreaks in animal populations is essential for public health, particularly to mitigate the risk of H5N1 virus transmission to humans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/pune/why-monitoring-outbreaks-in-animals-key-to-track-human-cases-of-h5n1-9781058/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/pune/why-monitoring-outbreaks-in-animals-key-to-track-human-cases-of-h5n1-9781058/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:11:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does hand sanitizer kill norovirus? Here's what really works - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Does Hand Sanitizer Kill Norovirus? Here's What Really Works</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>This article explores the effectiveness of hand sanitizer against norovirus, detailing what actually works for preventing the virus.</p><ul><li>Hand sanitizers may not be effective against norovirus due to its resistance.</li><li>Washing hands with soap and water is recommended for greater effectiveness.</li><li>Norovirus is highly contagious and can survive on surfaces for extended periods.</li></ul><blockquote>“Alcohol-based hand sanitizers do not kill norovirus effectively.”</blockquote><p>To effectively ward off norovirus, proper hand hygiene, especially hand washing with soap and water, is essential.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/does-hand-sanitizer-kill-norovirus-heres-what-really-works/articleshow/117274671.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/does-hand-sanitizer-kill-norovirus-heres-what-really-works/articleshow/117274671.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The link between obesity and cancer risk - Medical Xpress]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Understanding the Link Between Obesity and Cancer Risk</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Medical Xpress</p><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2025/novel-perspectives-on.jpg" alt="Novel perspectives on the link between obesity and cancer risk: from mechanisms to clinical implications" title="Credit: Xiaoye Shi, Aimin Jiang, Zhengang Qiu, Anqi Lin, Zaoqu Liu, Lingxuan Zhu, Weiming Mou, Quan Cheng, Jian Zhang, Kai Miao, Peng Luo" width="800" height="530"><figcaption>Credit: Xiaoye Shi, Aimin Jiang, Zhengang Qiu, Anqi Lin, Zaoqu Liu, Lingxuan Zhu, Weiming Mou, Quan Cheng, Jian Zhang, Kai Miao, Peng Luo</figcaption><p>Obesity is increasingly recognized as a health issue linked to several cancers. A new review in <i>Frontiers of Medicine</i> sheds light on the mechanisms and suggests clinical implications.</p><ul><li>Key mechanisms of obesity influencing cancer include inflammation, hormonal imbalances, and gut microbiota dysregulation.</li><li>Chronic inflammation in adipose tissue is a significant factor in cancer development.</li><li>Hormonal changes, especially elevated estrogen levels, are relevant for cancer risks, particularly in postmenopausal women.</li><li>Dietary and lifestyle modifications, such as weight management and physical activity, can reduce cancer risks associated with obesity.</li><li>Bariatric surgery has demonstrated efficacy in decreasing cancer incidence.</li></ul><blockquote>“The review underscores the need for a deeper understanding of the mechanisms linking obesity and cancer to develop personalized prevention and treatment strategies.”</blockquote><p>Further research is vital to unravel the complex interactions between obesity and cancer.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-01-link-obesity-cancer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-01-link-obesity-cancer.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:36:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why a daily glass of milk really could reduce bowel cancer risk – an oncologist explains - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daily Milk Consumption Could Lower Bowel Cancer Risk, Study Finds</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/milk-2.jpg" alt="What's the connection between milk and bowel cancer?"/><figcaption>What’s the connection between milk and bowel cancer? (Source: Freepik)</figcaption><p>A new study from Oxford University and Cancer Research UK indicates that consuming an extra glass of milk daily may significantly reduce the risk of bowel cancer, with nearly 45,000 cases reported annually in the UK.</p><ul><li>The research implies that just one additional glass daily could lower cancer risk.</li><li>A 17% reduced risk of bowel cancer was found for those consuming an extra 244g of milk daily.</li><li>Calcium in milk is suggested to play a protective role against cancer.</li><li>The study analyzed data from over 542,000 participants to determine the impacts of milk consumption.</li><li>Additional lifestyle changes like reducing alcohol and processed meat can also help lower cancer risk.</li></ul><blockquote>“Overall, this groundbreaking research provides compelling evidence for the potential role of milk consumption in reducing bowel cancer risk.”</blockquote><p>This study highlights the potential of simple dietary changes in improving public health outcomes and encourages further research into diet's role in disease prevention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/daily-glass-of-milk-reduce-bowel-cancer-risk-9779678/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/health/daily-glass-of-milk-reduce-bowel-cancer-risk-9779678/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:30:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does obesity affect children’s likelihood of survival after being diagnosed with cancer? - WebWire]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Does obesity affect children’s likelihood of survival after being diagnosed with cancer?</h1>
<p><strong>Date Published:</strong> Wednesday, January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> WEBWIRE</p>
<img src="https://photos.webwire.com/prmedia/6/332600/332600-1.png" alt="Press Release Image" />
<figcaption>Image related to the study on obesity and childhood cancer.</figcaption>
<p>A recent study reveals that obesity at diagnosis significantly decreases survival rates among children diagnosed with cancer, suggesting a need for strategies to mitigate these risks.</p>
<ul>
  <li>10.5% of children with cancer were obese at the time of diagnosis.</li>
  <li>Lower 5-year event-free survival rates were observed in obese children (77.5%) compared to non-obese children (79.6%).</li>
  <li>Obesity was linked to a 16% increase in relapse risk and a 29% increase in risk of death.</li>
  <li>The impact is particularly significant for those with acute lymphoblastic leukemia and brain tumors.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our study highlights the negative impact of obesity among all types of childhood cancers. It provides the rationale to evaluate different strategies to mitigate the adverse risk of obesity on cancer outcomes in future trials,” said co–senior author Thai Hoa Tran, MD.</blockquote>
<p>This research underscores the urgent need to address childhood obesity due to its serious implications on health and survival outcomes in pediatric cancer patients.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.webwire.com/ViewPressRel.asp?aId=332600</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.webwire.com/ViewPressRel.asp?aId=332600</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:01:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 protein-rich foods for breakfast - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxPb2JrazVfQ2N5TUxDOHVfZnZtcVJpdmpsbDlJUFh3ZEtrTjNERWJTMm1uSEltcDY1LVVqSW41Y3kxeXJLcktsdVNVY1dZb3o3UUFqaGxVZDV4cW5tSVJKSWhmUkwzZ25wUU9yTnRmLUV0SmQzTm55eWZBUF95cHJOY1prT19VTVFITGZ6M3B6WExCS2tzcFBiMTd2WHJxdXdndnhDSGE2QnRVSDZldnJVX194T2s0NnQ1VTB3RXVta2FJRlFfekdiODZsaXAyMEnSAc8BQVVfeXFMT29ia2s1X0NjeU1MQzh1X2Z2bXFSaXZqbGw5SVBYd2RLa04zREViUzJtbkhJbXA2NS1VakluNWN5MXlyS3JLbHVTVWNXWW96N1FBamhsVWQ1eHFubUlSSkloZlJMM2ducFFPck50Zi1FdEpkM05ueXlmQVBfeXByTmNaa09fVU1RSExmejNwelhMQktrc3BQYjE3dlhycXV3Z3Z4Q0hhNkJ0VUg2ZXZyVV9feE9rNDZ0NVUwd0V1bWthSUZRX3pHYjg2bGlwMjBJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxPb2JrazVfQ2N5TUxDOHVfZnZtcVJpdmpsbDlJUFh3ZEtrTjNERWJTMm1uSEltcDY1LVVqSW41Y3kxeXJLcktsdVNVY1dZb3o3UUFqaGxVZDV4cW5tSVJKSWhmUkwzZ25wUU9yTnRmLUV0SmQzTm55eWZBUF95cHJOY1prT19VTVFITGZ6M3B6WExCS2tzcFBiMTd2WHJxdXdndnhDSGE2QnRVSDZldnJVX194T2s0NnQ1VTB3RXVta2FJRlFfekdiODZsaXAyMEnSAc8BQVVfeXFMT29ia2s1X0NjeU1MQzh1X2Z2bXFSaXZqbGw5SVBYd2RLa04zREViUzJtbkhJbXA2NS1VakluNWN5MXlyS3JLbHVTVWNXWW96N1FBamhsVWQ1eHFubUlSSkloZlJMM2ducFFPck50Zi1FdEpkM05ueXlmQVBfeXByTmNaa09fVU1RSExmejNwelhMQktrc3BQYjE3dlhycXV3Z3Z4Q0hhNkJ0VUg2ZXZyVV9feE9rNDZ0NVUwd0V1bWthSUZRX3pHYjg2bGlwMjBJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to diagnose obesity: Lancet Commission recommends focussing on fat distribution, not just BMI. Here’s why it is significant - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How to Diagnose Obesity: Focus on Fat Distribution, Not Just BMI</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/obesity_getty_200.jpg?w=640" alt="abdominal obesity" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Image showing abdominal obesity</figcaption><p>The Lancet Diabetes & Endocrinology Commission has proposed a new method for diagnosing obesity, emphasizing the importance of body fat distribution over the traditional BMI calculations.</p><ul><li>The new approach includes methods such as waist circumference and waist-to-hip ratios in addition to BMI.</li><li>Experts recommend direct body fat assessments, such as DEXA scans, particularly for individuals with a very high BMI.</li><li>The commission consists of 58 leading medical experts from various specialties worldwide.</li></ul><blockquote>“BMI is a helpful screening tool, but it shouldn’t be the sole method for diagnosing obesity,” said the commission.</blockquote><p>This new guideline aims to provide a more accurate assessment of obesity and its related health risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/how-to-diagnose-obesity-lancet-commission-recommends-focussing-on-fat-distribution-not-just-bmi-heres-why-it-is-significant-9779143/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/how-to-diagnose-obesity-lancet-commission-recommends-focussing-on-fat-distribution-not-just-bmi-heres-why-it-is-significant-9779143/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>