<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 22:17:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 22:17:19 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Health Rounds: New method may eliminate need for cold storage of drugs, vaccines - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Health Rounds: New method may eliminate need for cold storage of drugs, vaccines</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 17 | <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><p>A new storage technique can keep protein-based drugs and vaccines stable without refrigeration, potentially saving billions and increasing accessibility in resource-limited areas.</p><ul><li>The technique utilizes a perfluorocarbon oil storage solution and surfactant to coat drug molecules.</li><li>It maintains stability at temperatures up to 212 degrees Fahrenheit (100°C).</li><li>This innovation could allow distribution in places without reliable refrigeration, including combat zones.</li></ul><blockquote>“Over 80% of biologic drugs and 90% of vaccines require temperature-controlled conditions” - Scott Medina, study leader at Pennsylvania State University.</blockquote><p>The new method promises significant cost savings and wider access to life-saving medications, particularly in challenging environments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/health-rounds-new-method-may-eliminate-need-cold-storage-drugs-vaccines-2025-01-17/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/health-rounds-new-method-may-eliminate-need-cold-storage-drugs-vaccines-2025-01-17/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 20:52:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roll out and prospects of the malaria vaccine R21/Matrix-M - PLOS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Rollout and Future of the Malaria Vaccine R21/Matrix-M</h1><p><strong>Published: </strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source: </strong> PLoS Medicine</p><p>In 2025, the malaria vaccine R21/Matrix-M, developed as an improvement over RTS,S, received licensing from WHO. This article explores the implications of its rollout amid the ongoing global malaria burden.</p><ul><li>R21/Matrix-M is a new malaria vaccine licensed and WHO-prequalified within 6 years since its first description in 2017.</li><li>It offers a 78% efficacy against uncomplicated malaria in children aged 5 to 17 months from clinical trials.</li><li>The vaccine aims to expand protection beyond just young children, including older children and adults at risk of malaria.</li><li>Production challenges remain, although plans to increase manufacturing capacity have been established.</li><li>Strategies involving mass vaccination along with drug administration could significantly reduce malaria transmission.</li></ul><blockquote>“After decades of waiting, 2 malaria vaccines are now registered and licensed, adding a promising tool for the control and ultimately the elimination of malaria.”</blockquote><p>The progress of R21/Matrix-M is vital in combating the increasing global malaria burden and calls for innovative distribution strategies to maximize its impact.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1004515</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1004515</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 20:12:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RKMH revises blood processing charge - The Arunachal Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RKMH revises blood processing charge</h1><p><strong>Date: 17 Jan | Source: ITANAGAR</strong></p><p>The Ramakrishna Mission Hospital (RKMH) has cut the processing charge for blood from Rs 500/unit to Rs 400/unit effective from 10 January, following recommendations from the State Blood Transfusion Council (SBTC).</p><ul><li>The reduced charge pertains to the cost of testing blood for various infections, not the blood itself.</li><li>RKMH, a private charitable institute, requires these charges to sustain its transfusion facilities.</li><li>The SBTC warns against the sale or purchase of blood, highlighting it as a crime and urging vigilance against professional blood donation.</li><li>Government blood centers in Arunachal Pradesh provide blood free of cost subject to availability.</li></ul><blockquote>“Blood donation for any pecuniary advantage is a crime and the public in general is advised to keep a vigil...”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the move by RKMH aims to promote voluntary blood donation while ensuring the sustainability of testing facilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://arunachaltimes.in/index.php/2025/01/18/rkmh-revises-blood-processing-charge/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arunachaltimes.in/index.php/2025/01/18/rkmh-revises-blood-processing-charge/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drink Tea Every Day? Science Says It May Help You Age Slower - Woman's World]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Drinking Tea Every Day May Slow Aging, Study Reveals</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Woman's World</p>
<figure><img src="https://www.womansworld.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/drinking-tea-everyday-tea-leaves.jpg?w=1024&amp;quality=86&amp;strip=all" alt="Black Tea Leaves on Spoon" width="1024" height="576"><figcaption>Savany</figcaption></figure>
<p>A recent study suggests that consuming tea daily can slow down biological aging. This study, published in <i>The Lancet Regional Health</i>, involved over 13,000 participants from the UK and China.</p>
<ul>
<li>The study finds that three cups of tea a day are optimal for slowing biological aging.</li>
<li>Significant differences were noted in participants who shifted from nondrinking to tea-drinking.</li>
<li>Polyphenols in tea are highlighted for their health benefits, including anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects.</li>
<li>Tea consumption may help protect against age-related diseases.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Tea contains a variety of bioactive substances, especially polyphenols... which may delay the aging process,” the authors stated.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, making tea a daily habit could offer significant health benefits and potentially extend lifespan by slowing aging processes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.womansworld.com/wellness/drinking-tea-every-day-may-slow-aging-study-reveals</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.womansworld.com/wellness/drinking-tea-every-day-may-slow-aging-study-reveals</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:45:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experts call for urgent action against viral hepatitis - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Experts call for urgent action against viral hepatitis</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 &nbsp; <strong>Source: </strong>Health News</p><p>This article highlights the growing urgency for action against viral hepatitis as health experts emphasize the need for increased awareness, vaccination, and treatment accessibility.</p><ul><li>Viral hepatitis is a significant public health issue affecting millions worldwide.</li><li>Experts are calling for better vaccination programs and public education campaigns.</li><li>Access to treatment remains a critical barrier in many regions.</li><li>The World Health Organization has set goals to eliminate viral hepatitis by 2030.</li></ul><blockquote>“Without immediate and coordinated action, we risk falling further behind in the fight against viral hepatitis,” said a health expert.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, addressing viral hepatitis urgently could prevent millions of infections and improve global health outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/chennai/experts-call-for-urgent-action-against-viral-hepatitis/articleshow/117341181.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/chennai/experts-call-for-urgent-action-against-viral-hepatitis/articleshow/117341181.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minimally Invasive Approach Versus Traditional Approach for Treating Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis - Cureus]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogJBVV95cUxNODFyTU5uaW43TENOZ25MOW5icUlaUXI4NnI1alkyc1BlZHpqWi1kRFFiMUpVNF9vd1k3NFotSHdURHh1NThQQ3JqNGRhSkhpS0hYXzM5T1l4cmZ2TXR5ZTVVVC0tbTNnLTBjQjdHcEFNOWZRdXRQNGJOZUxKT054LV9iRzdpR2hXelVIZ1JwN0pmaEZWM09PTVBkcFdTaUJrYjYxbV9reklBb0NRVXJOQVZIM0ItWE5NWFo3UDBOaE82QlBmWFZ4WU5Gck1jelpJMW5sdzlQZGRrNGk2eElVWjVhdE5TMUt0Nmw1MFRvV3JxTnJoSjVvYldxVENJUnRza3BYQ1ZtbEJXVi16ODRnVDZGMmlTMEdpbWZSWTJNWHJhdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogJBVV95cUxNODFyTU5uaW43TENOZ25MOW5icUlaUXI4NnI1alkyc1BlZHpqWi1kRFFiMUpVNF9vd1k3NFotSHdURHh1NThQQ3JqNGRhSkhpS0hYXzM5T1l4cmZ2TXR5ZTVVVC0tbTNnLTBjQjdHcEFNOWZRdXRQNGJOZUxKT054LV9iRzdpR2hXelVIZ1JwN0pmaEZWM09PTVBkcFdTaUJrYjYxbV9reklBb0NRVXJOQVZIM0ItWE5NWFo3UDBOaE82QlBmWFZ4WU5Gck1jelpJMW5sdzlQZGRrNGk2eElVWjVhdE5TMUt0Nmw1MFRvV3JxTnJoSjVvYldxVENJUnRza3BYQ1ZtbEJXVi16ODRnVDZGMmlTMEdpbWZSWTJNWHJhdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:38:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A nap can boost your cognition, here’s how - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A Nap Can Boost Your Cognition, Here’s How</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Date not provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117340710,imgsize-33292,width-400,resizemode-4/117340710.jpg" alt="A nap can boost your cognition, here’s how" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>A nap can enhance cognitive function.</figcaption><p>In a fast-paced world, sleep often takes a back seat. However, even a short nap can significantly boost cognitive function and mood. Various studies support the positive effects of napping on memory and brain health.</p><ul><li>A 2022 study found that a brief nap can improve memory to a degree similar to a full night's sleep.</li><li>A 2024 meta-analysis linked prolonged daytime napping with increased health risks, but napping under 30 minutes avoids these risks.</li><li>A 2023 study indicates napping may slow brain shrinkage associated with aging.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our findings suggest that, for some people, short daytime naps may be a part of the puzzle that could help preserve the health of the brain as we get older.” - Dr. Victoria Garfield</blockquote><p>To maximize cognitive benefits while minimizing risks, naps should ideally last 20-30 minutes, taken in the afternoon, in a quiet environment, and can even be paired with a cup of coffee before sleeping for an added boost of alertness upon waking.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/a-nap-can-boost-your-cognition-heres-how/articleshow/117340710.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/a-nap-can-boost-your-cognition-heres-how/articleshow/117340710.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With successful trials, CDRI a step closer to antimalarial vaccine - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>With successful trials, CDRI a step closer to antimalarial vaccine</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> <a href='https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/'>Times of India</a></p>
<img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='CDRI Antimalarial Vaccine Trials' />
<figcaption>CDRI's promising antimalarial vaccine trials.</figcaption>
<p>The Central Drug Research Institute (CDRI) has reported successful trials of its antimalarial vaccine, promising a significant advancement in combating malaria.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The vaccine has shown efficacy in preclinical trials.</li>
  <li>CDRI aims to address increasing malaria resistance to existing treatments.</li>
  <li>The new vaccine presents hope for effective malaria prevention strategies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This development could revolutionize our approach to malaria prevention," said a CDRI spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>The progress made by CDRI in developing an antimalarial vaccine represents a hopeful step toward controlling malaria worldwide.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/with-successful-trials-cdri-a-step-closer-to-antimalarial-vaccine/articleshow/117341077.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/with-successful-trials-cdri-a-step-closer-to-antimalarial-vaccine/articleshow/117341077.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI-driven technique analyses heart cells inner electrical signals from outside: Study - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxNUnA4TkE2NmhSMXRSRmt0VGtETmcxVER1SWt3ak1ZZ3JNSFlZa2xReVN2b2RQc0FmbDVoUWV2VDI0T3FBdzMzTENNZUQ0VlZ3YWRlakpNQTJXZWlqRDZWd0ZFajlCVTdzUkxUWUQ2U1ZmWEVyRmRGTEl4TDA1ZWx2TEwzZ0QwOEt2ZTQtWjkwTThrZjJ1bzJySlFGNEx1d0hTcnJZd3FWX1JxSUppa3lmbzRCWlpCOUhxM2dHbk5WQlVBNkYw0gHIAUFVX3lxTE9IMTZsdXhuQ0ZMRW45dzRCdHhDUGczWDliZml0dDNveEFzT3hueGYwcENrczZHaXZDOXZORE1jOWk5WWFVRVNfYmtfQUNxUUVHT0h4OHljVEFxWXp2N0ZQU3BFZXFuSGZId2JzX2trQlUzbVNMelA3SGZ4bXpreG1hYzVNcXFkaEowbVVKMnAwdEpKX01SUWN2Q29UaFhlMFVwTVVDRTIybkRPU2w3Yi15S2h1cGVWc0tYM1ljUlFCQnVqcWFLaFo1?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxNUnA4TkE2NmhSMXRSRmt0VGtETmcxVER1SWt3ak1ZZ3JNSFlZa2xReVN2b2RQc0FmbDVoUWV2VDI0T3FBdzMzTENNZUQ0VlZ3YWRlakpNQTJXZWlqRDZWd0ZFajlCVTdzUkxUWUQ2U1ZmWEVyRmRGTEl4TDA1ZWx2TEwzZ0QwOEt2ZTQtWjkwTThrZjJ1bzJySlFGNEx1d0hTcnJZd3FWX1JxSUppa3lmbzRCWlpCOUhxM2dHbk5WQlVBNkYw0gHIAUFVX3lxTE9IMTZsdXhuQ0ZMRW45dzRCdHhDUGczWDliZml0dDNveEFzT3hueGYwcENrczZHaXZDOXZORE1jOWk5WWFVRVNfYmtfQUNxUUVHT0h4OHljVEFxWXp2N0ZQU3BFZXFuSGZId2JzX2trQlUzbVNMelA3SGZ4bXpreG1hYzVNcXFkaEowbVVKMnAwdEpKX01SUWN2Q29UaFhlMFVwTVVDRTIybkRPU2w3Yi15S2h1cGVWc0tYM1ljUlFCQnVqcWFLaFo1?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:33:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drop in episiotomy not tied to increase in obstetric anal sphincter injury for most women - Medical Xpress]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Drop in Episiotomy Not Linked to Increased Injuries in Most Women</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> HealthDay</p><figure><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2025/drop-in-episiotomy-not.jpg" alt="Drop in episiotomy not tied to increase in obstetric anal sphincter injury for most women" width="800" height="530"></figure><figcaption>Drop in episiotomy not tied to increase in obstetric anal sphincter injury for most women</figcaption><p>A significant reduction in the prevalence of episiotomy in France from 2010 to 2021 has not been followed by an overall increase in obstetric anal sphincter injury (OASI), according to a study published in <i>PLOS Medicine</i>.</p><ul><li>The prevalence of episiotomy decreased from 25.8% in 2010 to 8.3% in 2021.</li><li>The overall prevalence of OASI remained statistically insignificant between 0.7% in 2010 and 1.0% in 2021.</li><li>Only nulliparous women with a term cephalic singleton undergoing spatula delivery saw a significant increase in OASI prevalence.</li></ul><blockquote>"Our results and recent literature suggest that there is a need to reconsider indications of restrictive episiotomy policies for instrumental deliveries in nulliparous women."</blockquote><p>This study suggests that a declining use of episiotomy does not lead to increased risks of specific injuries, indicating potential changes in surgical practices could be warranted.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-01-episiotomy-obstetric-anal-sphincter-injury.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-01-episiotomy-obstetric-anal-sphincter-injury.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists develop ‘smart’ wearable device that mimics human pain response - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists develop ‘smart’ wearable device that mimics human pain response</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023, <strong>Source: </strong>Health Wellness Journal</p><p>This article discusses a breakthrough in wearable technology that enables devices to replicate the human pain response, potentially revolutionizing pain management.</p><ul><li>The wearable device is designed to monitor and respond to pain stimuli.</li><li>It employs advanced sensors for real-time feedback.</li><li>Researchers believe this technology could enhance pain relief methods.</li><li>The development may lead to personalized pain management solutions.</li></ul><blockquote>“This device could change how we approach pain management in daily health.”</blockquote><p>The development of this smart wearable device could significantly impact how individuals experience and manage pain, paving the way for future innovations in healthcare technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/scientists-develop-smart-wearable-device-that-mimics-human-pain-response/articleshow/117340237.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/scientists-develop-smart-wearable-device-that-mimics-human-pain-response/articleshow/117340237.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka reports two cases of monkey fever, aims for zero deaths this year - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka Reports Two Cases of Monkey Fever, Aims for Zero Deaths This Year</h1><p><strong>Published: 17 January 2025, 18:00 IST</strong></p><p>Bengaluru: Within the first fortnight of the New Year, Karnataka has reported two positive cases of the Kyasanur Forest Disease (KFD), also known as monkey fever. The state health department has vowed to work towards ensuring there are zero deaths due to KFD this year.</p><ul><li>The patients are Kushal (63) from Basavani village, Shivamogga, and Sathish (24) from Kadabagere, Chikkamagaluru.</li><li>Kushal has been discharged, while Sathish is recovering in a private hospital in Manipal.</li><li>The state reported 14 deaths and 303 confirmed cases of KFD in 2024.</li><li>The health department is coordinating with the forest department to reduce KFD's spread.</li></ul><blockquote>“We do not want any KFD-related deaths this year. Our prevention and surveillance systems this time are more robust than last year so we are aiming at zero deaths,” said a senior official privy to the discussions.</blockquote><p>The tick-borne viral disease is endemic to the forested districts along the Western Ghats in Karnataka. The state is also tracking the progress of a new vaccine for KFD.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/karnataka-reports-two-cases-of-monkey-fever-aims-for-zero-deaths-this-year-3361171</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/karnataka-reports-two-cases-of-monkey-fever-aims-for-zero-deaths-this-year-3361171</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:00:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Immune system changes linked to schizophrenia: Study - Nagaland Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Immune system changes linked to schizophrenia: Study</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A, <strong>Source:</strong> Nagaland Post</p><p>This article discusses a study by Singaporean researchers that links immune system changes to schizophrenia and highlights potential treatment resistance in patients.</p><ul><li>The immune system dysregulation may contribute to the development of schizophrenia.</li><li>Schizophrenia affects around 24 million people globally, with 1 in 116 individuals in Singapore.</li><li>About one-third of patients diagnosed with schizophrenia do not respond to standard antipsychotic treatments.</li><li>The research could help identify patients likely to be treatment-resistant and lead to earlier, more targeted interventions.</li><li>The study involved analyzing blood samples from 196 participants, including 147 individuals diagnosed with schizophrenia.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our goal was to identify immune cell changes that could potentially be used to predict treatment resistance, allowing for earlier and more targeted interventions...” - Dr. Li Yanhui</blockquote><p>The findings from this study could have significant implications for improving treatment outcomes for individuals with schizophrenia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://nagalandpost.com/index.php/2025/01/17/immune-system-changes-linked-to-schizophrenia-study/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nagalandpost.com/index.php/2025/01/17/immune-system-changes-linked-to-schizophrenia-study/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 17:55:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How denoising algorithms can improve MRI image quality - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How Denoising Algorithms Can Improve MRI Image Quality</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Bruker BioSpin</p>
<img alt="Smart Noise Reduction using different neuronal networks" src="https://d2jx2rerrg6sh3.cloudfront.net/images/appnotes/ImageForAppNote_5493_17344169043432423.png" width="700" height="317">
<figcaption>Smart Noise Reduction using different neuronal networks</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the importance of denoising algorithms in improving the quality of MRI images, detailing the challenges faced due to noise and showcasing a new method called Smart Noise Reduction.</p>
<ul>
  <li>MRI provides multiparametric information noninvasively, requiring high spatial resolution.</li>
  <li>Thermal noise impacts image quality; denoising algorithms are essential for clarity.</li>
  <li>Bruker's Smart Noise Reduction utilizes convolutional neural networks for noise removal.</li>
  <li>Performance evaluation of the denoising approach indicates improvements in image quality and preservation of essential details.</li>
  <li>Denoising methods allow for faster imaging and better resolution in MRI scans.</li>
  <li>Key figures show the effects of various denoising levels on image quality.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Smart Noise Reduction allows for enhanced imaging with significant reductions in acquisition time, improving research throughput.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, denoising algorithms like Bruker's Smart Noise Reduction offer significant advancements in MRI imaging by enhancing quality, reducing noise, and facilitating faster data acquisition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/whitepaper/20250117/How-denoising-algorithms-can-improve-MRI-image-quality.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/whitepaper/20250117/How-denoising-algorithms-can-improve-MRI-image-quality.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 17:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IBAT inhibitors have potential to boost life quality for patients: Study - Liver Disease News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IBAT Inhibitors Could Enhance Quality of Life for Alagille Syndrome Patients</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Liver Disease News</p><img src="https://liverdiseasenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Untitled_Artwork3-150x0-c-default.png" alt="Main banner for Jay Sandstrom's column, 'Be Rare with Finn.'"><figcaption>Main banner for Jay Sandstrom's column, 'Be Rare with Finn.'</figcaption><p>The article discusses the potential of new treatments for Alagille syndrome, particularly IBAT inhibitors like Livmarli and Bylvay, to improve patient quality of life and reduce the need for liver transplants.</p><ul><li>IBAT inhibitors may alleviate symptoms and healthcare costs for Alagille syndrome patients.</li><li>The review involved 119 studies illustrating the high burden of Alagille syndrome on patients and caregivers.</li><li>Previous off-label treatments were less effective and could cause intolerable side effects.</li><li>Emerging clinical data show promising results in reducing symptoms, improving life quality, and potentially delaying liver transplants.</li></ul><blockquote>“Based on their disease-modifying potential and ability to transform the lives of patients with ALGS through amelioration of cholestatic-related symptoms along with improvement in HRQoL, IBAT inhibitors are the new standard of care for long-term treatment of patients with ALGS,” researchers concluded.</blockquote><p>The integration of IBAT inhibitors into standard care could significantly enhance the outlook for those affected by Alagille syndrome.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://liverdiseasenews.com/news/ibat-inhibitors-potential-boost-life-quality-patients-study/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://liverdiseasenews.com/news/ibat-inhibitors-potential-boost-life-quality-patients-study/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 17:24:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Treating Alzheimer's: Scientists investigate potential of xenon gas - Medical News Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Xenon Gas Shows Promise as Potential Treatment for Alzheimer's</h1>
<p><strong>Published on: Date Unknown, Source: Medical News Today</strong></p>
<img src="https://media.post.rvohealth.io/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/01/Oxygen-mask-hospital-1296x728-header-1024x575.jpg" alt="An oxygen mask on a surface at a hospital">
<figcaption>Scientists are investigating xenon gas as a potential treatment for Alzheimer’s. Westend61/Getty Images</figcaption>
<p>Researchers are exploring xenon gas as a potential new therapy for Alzheimer's disease, finding that it can suppress neuroinflammation and reduce brain shrinkage in a mouse model, paving the way for clinical trials in humans.</p>
<ul>
<li>Researchers are actively seeking effective treatments for Alzheimer's, which is becoming increasingly common.</li>
<li>Current medications primarily address symptoms rather than the disease itself, although some newer treatments target brain lesions.</li>
<li>Xenon gas has been identified as a promising avenue for treatment.</li>
<li>In studies using mouse models, xenon inhalation exhibited neuroprotective benefits.</li>
<li>A clinical trial for human participants is set to begin soon.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>“The results are intriguing... it is quite expensive and there would be a challenge understanding how to deliver it to a large patient group.”</p>
<p>— Anton Porsteinsson, MD</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The researchers' findings suggest that xenon inhalation could modify microglial activity and reduce neurodegeneration associated with Alzheimer's. Although this study is preliminary, the implications for future research and treatment options are optimistic.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/could-xenon-gas-protect-against-alzheimers-mountain-climbing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/could-xenon-gas-protect-against-alzheimers-mountain-climbing</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 17:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brazil's Chikungunya Outbreak Continues in 2025 - Vax-Before-Travel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Brazil's Chikungunya Outbreak Continues in 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Vax-Before-Travel</p>
<p>The Chikungunya virus outbreaks in Brazil, first reported in 2014, persist into 2025, with the highest risk regions identified as São Paulo and Rio de Janeiro. Recent data shows alarming infection numbers and increased mortality rates.</p>
<ul>
  <li>523 confirmed Chikungunya cases in Brazil during the first two weeks of 2025.</li>
  <li>Over 420,139 chikungunya cases and 236 related deaths recorded in 2024.</li>
  <li>The states most affected by CHIKV include Pernambuco, São Paulo, and Paraíba.</li>
  <li>A recent epidemic in Minas Gerais reported a mortality rate of 35.1 per 100,000 inhabitants.</li>
  <li>Travel-related chikungunya cases in the U.S. included 173 confirmed cases in 2024.</li>
  <li>The U.S. CDC suggests considering Chikungunya vaccination for travelers to Brazil.</li>
  <li>One approved vaccine exists, with multiple candidates in late-stage clinical research, including VLP vaccines showing promising results.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The government of São Paulo has introduced an Urban Arbovirus Contingency Plan for 2025/2026 to combat future outbreaks.”</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing outbreak underscores the need for public health measures and traveler precautions as Brazil navigates these health challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.vax-before-travel.com/brazils-chikungunya-outbreak-continues-2025-2025-01-17</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vax-before-travel.com/brazils-chikungunya-outbreak-continues-2025-2025-01-17</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 17:12:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JNCASR scientists develop device that senses strain - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JNCASR Scientists Create Innovative Device for Strain Sensing and Pain Mimicking</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 17, 2025 10:41 pm IST</p><p>This new device developed by scientists at JNCASR senses strain and mimics pain perception, paving the way for advanced smart wearable systems.</p><h4>Nociceptors that detect pain</h4><p>Using a silver wire network on stretchable material, the device recreates pain-like responses and adapts to stress over time.</p><ul><li>The device operates on neuromorphic principles inspired by human pain perception.</li><li>It integrates sensing and adaptive response in a flexible unit.</li><li>This technology aims to enhance health monitoring systems for stress detection.</li></ul><blockquote>The device mimics memory and adaptation, resembling how our bodies adapt to repeated pain over time.</blockquote><p>The innovation from JNCASR bridges the gap between human sensory experiences and technology, promising advancements in medical applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/jncasr-scientists-develop-device-that-senses-strain/article69109117.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/jncasr-scientists-develop-device-that-senses-strain/article69109117.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 17:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coffee in the morning is best for heart health, says study: Can this routine work for you? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Coffee in the morning is best for heart health, says study: Can this routine work for you?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/coffee_f24cc3.jpg?w=640" alt="coffee, heart health, morning coffee," width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>150 ml of brewed coffee contains 70-80 mg caffeine, while instant (decaffeinated or filtered) coffee contains 50-65 mg caffeine. (Credit: pexels.com)</figcaption>
<p>Your cup of coffee could be more beneficial for your body in the morning than later in the day. A US study found that a shot of morning coffee, rather than the all-day-anytime-cup pattern, was significantly associated with lower risks of cardiovascular diseases and all-cause mortality.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Morning coffee drinkers were found to be 16% less likely to die from any cause and 31% less likely to die from cardiovascular disease compared to non-coffee drinkers.</li>
  <li>Dr. Komal Shah explains that consuming caffeine later can disrupt sleep patterns, leading to health risks like cardiovascular disease.</li>
  <li>Caffeine overconsumption can result in higher blood pressure and arrhythmias.</li>
  <li>The Indian Council of Medical Research recommends limiting caffeine intake to below 300 mg a day.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These findings suggest that morning coffee consumption may have beneficial effects on cardiovascular health at the population level.”</blockquote>
<p>Moderate coffee consumption, particularly in the morning, can have various health benefits, while excessive sugar in coffee can negate these benefits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/coffee-morning-best-heart-health-study-routine-work-9783367/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/coffee-morning-best-heart-health-study-routine-work-9783367/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 16:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 signs our body is not getting enough protein - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxPMXZqREdYV1owNUZsN3lwc3VmZENTZG16WERQcTkxZXY4eXRmYlhTQWNMUlRGaUlvYU84eVIwTnVUVFE2bllOd2FVY1JfVDlMZDZEVUItYWczMEIzcHRpVUFHS0pzdDJ3OE5nR1A4LUhLOWF2Nl91bmlzZlZIMy00T1BQUEhGVktlZjJtVTBXbm9URXNfRmVsd0xtX2JrclB2ZU12WWJJUS1IUHdOWldDX1k3MTJQcnBQUkxuazI2ZFdEbjRvcnJuek5fc29nZVhwMENBcDRiQUFoT1FKSEHSAd4BQVVfeXFMTzF2akRHWFdaMDVGbDd5cHN1ZmRDU2RtelhEUHE5MWV2OHl0ZmJYU0FjTFJURmlJb2FPOHlSME51VFRRNm5ZTndhVWNSX1Q5TGQ2RFVCLWFnMzBCM3B0aVVBR0tKc3QydzhOZ0dQOC1ISzlhdjZfdW5pc2ZWSDMtNE9QUFBIRlZLZWYybVUwV25vVEVzX0ZlbHdMbV9ia3JQdmVNdlliSVEtSFB3TlpXQ19ZNzEyUHJwUFJMbmsyNmRXRG40b3JybnpOX3NvZ2VYcDBDQXA0YkFBaE9RSkhB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxPMXZqREdYV1owNUZsN3lwc3VmZENTZG16WERQcTkxZXY4eXRmYlhTQWNMUlRGaUlvYU84eVIwTnVUVFE2bllOd2FVY1JfVDlMZDZEVUItYWczMEIzcHRpVUFHS0pzdDJ3OE5nR1A4LUhLOWF2Nl91bmlzZlZIMy00T1BQUEhGVktlZjJtVTBXbm9URXNfRmVsd0xtX2JrclB2ZU12WWJJUS1IUHdOWldDX1k3MTJQcnBQUkxuazI2ZFdEbjRvcnJuek5fc29nZVhwMENBcDRiQUFoT1FKSEHSAd4BQVVfeXFMTzF2akRHWFdaMDVGbDd5cHN1ZmRDU2RtelhEUHE5MWV2OHl0ZmJYU0FjTFJURmlJb2FPOHlSME51VFRRNm5ZTndhVWNSX1Q5TGQ2RFVCLWFnMzBCM3B0aVVBR0tKc3QydzhOZ0dQOC1ISzlhdjZfdW5pc2ZWSDMtNE9QUFBIRlZLZWYybVUwV25vVEVzX0ZlbHdMbV9ia3JQdmVNdlliSVEtSFB3TlpXQ19ZNzEyUHJwUFJMbmsyNmRXRG40b3JybnpOX3NvZ2VYcDBDQXA0YkFBaE9RSkhB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Research questions ‘iron deficiency’ as key cause of anaemia in India - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Research questions ‘iron deficiency’ as key cause of anaemia in India</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> January 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/d7yyqg/article69110239.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_BL0710_Pulse_regulat_2_1_4TDDRPMB.jpg" alt="Representative image">
<figcaption>Representative image | Photo Credit: Getty Images</figcaption>
<p>A recent study suggests that the traditional belief that iron deficiency is the primary cause of anaemia in India may be outdated, highlighting alternative factors such as Vitamin B12 deficiency and air pollution. The findings call for a review of public health policies regarding anaemia.</p>
<ul>
<li>The study was published in the European Journal of Clinical Nutrition.</li>
<li>Anaemia affects 34.9% of the population tested, but only 9% had iron-deficiency anaemia.</li>
<li>Prevalence of anaemia in women of reproductive age increased from 53.2% to 57.2% as per the latest National Family Health Survey.</li>
<li>Other causes of anaemia include deficiencies in nutrients like B12 or folate and environmental factors such as pollution.</li>
<li>The study indicates the need for diversified dietary policies and holistic approaches, rather than focusing solely on iron supplementation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The key is to diversify diets. We have to intervene with ensuring more fruits, milk and vegetables are made available to a wider population which will improve absorption of essential nutrients.” - Dr. Anura Kurpad</blockquote>
<p>The findings of this study advocate for more comprehensive public health strategies to combat anaemia in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/research-questions-iron-deficiency-as-key-cause-of-anaemia-in-india/article69109969.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/research-questions-iron-deficiency-as-key-cause-of-anaemia-in-india/article69109969.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 16:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heart patients should avoid extreme temperatures because... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Heart Patients Should Avoid Extreme Temperatures</h1>
<p><strong>Published Date:</strong> Wednesday, January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> IANS</p>
<img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Mediterranean-Diet-51.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Heart patients should avoid extreme temperatures">
<figcaption>Photo related to heart health</figcaption>
<p>Experts advise that individuals with cardiovascular diseases or risk factors should stay away from extreme temperatures to prevent health complications.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Extreme cold or heat can disrupt cardiovascular functions.</li>
    <li>Fluctuations in temperature can lead to spikes in blood pressure.</li>
    <li>About 3.5 crore devotees participated in the Maha Kumbh event under harsh conditions.</li>
    <li>Notable increases in heart attack rates during winter attributed to temperature changes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Exposure to extreme cold can affect the heart, the brain and other vital organs.”</blockquote>
<p>This increased awareness and caution regarding temperature impacts can help prevent serious cardiovascular events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/health/heart-patients-should-avoid-extreme-temperatures-because-7546863/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/health/heart-patients-should-avoid-extreme-temperatures-because-7546863/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 16:13:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uganda receives 2,000 doses of monkeypox vaccines from Africa CDC - Daijiworld.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZEFVX3lxTE5rYlpfOFFGeW10TEpOX1l3R2xwMTVfM0d6cWRRUjJoTkpPdm9kcm5CYmthdUM0Z2ltV0ZBNnhldW80NXIwTkVtanlVQ2RzaHRWaGxJMlY1ZzRPRWNZWkItUnRTb0Q?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZEFVX3lxTE5rYlpfOFFGeW10TEpOX1l3R2xwMTVfM0d6cWRRUjJoTkpPdm9kcm5CYmthdUM0Z2ltV0ZBNnhldW80NXIwTkVtanlVQ2RzaHRWaGxJMlY1ZzRPRWNZWkItUnRTb0Q?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 16:11:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prevalence of asymptomatic Leishmania donovani infection and associated factors in Ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis - BMC Infectious Diseases]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prevalence of Asymptomatic Leishmania donovani Infection and Associated Factors in Ethiopia: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 17 January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> BMC Infectious Diseases</p><h2>Introduction</h2><p>Visceral leishmaniasis is endemic in Ethiopia and caused by <i>Leishmania donovani</i>. This systematic review explores the prevalence of asymptomatic infections, which can complicate control efforts.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>A total of 1,288 articles were identified; 11 studies met inclusion criteria.</li><li>The overall pooled estimate of asymptomatic <i>L. donovani</i> infection in Ethiopia was 9.0%.</li><li>Significant risk factors for asymptomatic infection include close contact with domestic animals and being male.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics</h2><blockquote>The overall pooled estimate in the Amhara region was 9.0% (95% CI: 8.0-11.0%).</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>This study highlights the need for regular screening in populations at risk to aid in controlling and managing visceral leishmaniasis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bmcinfectdis.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12879-024-10275-6</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bmcinfectdis.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12879-024-10275-6</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[To lower blood pressure, even five minutes of exercise helps - Harvard Health]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPWm5ESHZNVVBqZkVCRUZpUmt0ZUpONzdrWjZETTA4Yk92V05TSm5BcmVRMnNmX050Q0RnejFQNnFWWlBLdmZNS1F0bzBfall3Q0QtbWFlUTUwanhMUkFINGxQb1dEVXNpUTZFb3NlZTBXZ1dxTHZtSGlwYlIxX0ZpR290bkZ5Z3c1ajh4NHVyb0JjMFhZOHM3bDFoLUtMeFZVNmswRldR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPWm5ESHZNVVBqZkVCRUZpUmt0ZUpONzdrWjZETTA4Yk92V05TSm5BcmVRMnNmX050Q0RnejFQNnFWWlBLdmZNS1F0bzBfall3Q0QtbWFlUTUwanhMUkFINGxQb1dEVXNpUTZFb3NlZTBXZ1dxTHZtSGlwYlIxX0ZpR290bkZ5Z3c1ajh4NHVyb0JjMFhZOHM3bDFoLUtMeFZVNmswRldR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:20:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New clues about "broken heart" syndrome - Harvard Health]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxOa0V0MU1MYVg3Nmh4dlpnMzVPNW5fM3ZTdjdRR2lkdFhtV0ROaU9tN0g2Q0pKdjVnajRmMUZKRTc2RERJRVAweGdNaEZjRG1hN05RemhTV3FJT3JSLVM4N01lMnp5Y1ptVVdEaW5zTWFYWklKQzlfSHg3Qk92MU9rUzhKZmExZi15?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxOa0V0MU1MYVg3Nmh4dlpnMzVPNW5fM3ZTdjdRR2lkdFhtV0ROaU9tN0g2Q0pKdjVnajRmMUZKRTc2RERJRVAweGdNaEZjRG1hN05RemhTV3FJT3JSLVM4N01lMnp5Y1ptVVdEaW5zTWFYWklKQzlfSHg3Qk92MU9rUzhKZmExZi15?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Woxsen University Researchers alongside US Scientist, develop AI-Based Prediction Model to Detect Obesity Risk - India Education Diary]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indiaeducationdiary.in/woxsen-university-researchers-alongside-us-scientist-develop-ai-based-prediction-model-to-detect-obesity-risk/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiaeducationdiary.in/woxsen-university-researchers-alongside-us-scientist-develop-ai-based-prediction-model-to-detect-obesity-risk/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:07:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases rise in India, decline in China: Expert answers 10 top questions about human metapneumovirus - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/health/health-news/hmpv-cases-rise-in-india-decline-in-china-expert-answers-top-10-questions-about-human-metapneumovirus/ar-AA1xnmMZ</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/health/health-news/hmpv-cases-rise-in-india-decline-in-china-expert-answers-top-10-questions-about-human-metapneumovirus/ar-AA1xnmMZ</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:31:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Surprising Benefits of Having Black Coffee In The Morning - HerZindagi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPT0hyWnh0X3l2ZGU0MlB4NkRPOW9jS0RGZzhUOVZoLUdudXVEZHoyTTFRLWl6NE1GWWFXbWFjUUFHX25KcFU4Qko5empobEpQZDNwby1XZ2JnSkRXOF96d21XQ3dULWxEdVB5dUlYQ3VSajl3UnNmcS0zbWdISmJKRlYwLVRnbzlwZUhWeTZUeExxbnYyZkp3dUdMUW1PdDFuMndDYnlVQUZ3NDM5bFpRSGRR0gGyAUFVX3lxTE9PSHJaeHRfeXZkZTQyUHg2RE85b2NLREZnOFQ5VmgtR251dURkejJNMVEtaXo0TUZZYVdtYWNRQUdfbkpwVThCSjl6amhsSlBkM3BvLVdnYmdKRFc4X3p3bVdDd1QtbER1UHl1SVhDdVJqOXdSc2ZxLTNtZ0hKYkpGVjAtVGdvOXBlSFZ5NlR4THFudjJmSnd1R0xRbU90MW4yd0NieVVBRnc0MzlsWlFIZFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPT0hyWnh0X3l2ZGU0MlB4NkRPOW9jS0RGZzhUOVZoLUdudXVEZHoyTTFRLWl6NE1GWWFXbWFjUUFHX25KcFU4Qko5empobEpQZDNwby1XZ2JnSkRXOF96d21XQ3dULWxEdVB5dUlYQ3VSajl3UnNmcS0zbWdISmJKRlYwLVRnbzlwZUhWeTZUeExxbnYyZkp3dUdMUW1PdDFuMndDYnlVQUZ3NDM5bFpRSGRR0gGyAUFVX3lxTE9PSHJaeHRfeXZkZTQyUHg2RE85b2NLREZnOFQ5VmgtR251dURkejJNMVEtaXo0TUZZYVdtYWNRQUdfbkpwVThCSjl6amhsSlBkM3BvLVdnYmdKRFc4X3p3bVdDd1QtbER1UHl1SVhDdVJqOXdSc2ZxLTNtZ0hKYkpGVjAtVGdvOXBlSFZ5NlR4THFudjJmSnd1R0xRbU90MW4yd0NieVVBRnc0MzlsWlFIZFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cancer rate sees an alarming rise in young females; Know the most common cancers in women - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cancer rate sees an alarming rise in young females; Know the most common cancers in women</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>The article discusses the troubling increase in cancer rates among young females, highlighting the most common types of cancers affecting women today.</p><ul><li>Recent statistics show a significant rise in cancer diagnoses among young females.</li><li>The increase is attributed to various factors including lifestyle changes and environmental influences.</li><li>Common cancers among young women include breast cancer, cervical cancer, and melanoma.</li><li>Early detection strategies and awareness campaigns are being emphasized to combat this trend.</li></ul><blockquote>"We need to raise awareness about the importance of regular check-ups and screenings for young women." - [Health Expert]</blockquote><p>This alarming trend calls for immediate attention and proactive measures in healthcare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/cancer-rate-sees-an-alarming-rise-in-young-females-know-the-most-common-cancers-in-women/articleshow/117336445.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/cancer-rate-sees-an-alarming-rise-in-young-females-know-the-most-common-cancers-in-women/articleshow/117336445.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>