<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 21:18:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 21:18:34 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BharatSim: A Virtual World to Tackle Real-World Health Challenges - Research Matters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQc2lmYm9uU3BSN3N3N0hxdFJ0QXpQUmFORDNNUG93NWpFdGRKa0d2M3l3bUZ6Mjl5YUJaWmVnUmNQSGo5SXhKbGs2SUN0Q0pQczJBMldOQWVCdk1vUkV2dFNwTzd1M3lLZnV1RC04U01FODE3bklQajRrM01lRlNlR2FpcmhkNGRNa0Vsc1lEN1loZjZUeGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQc2lmYm9uU3BSN3N3N0hxdFJ0QXpQUmFORDNNUG93NWpFdGRKa0d2M3l3bUZ6Mjl5YUJaWmVnUmNQSGo5SXhKbGs2SUN0Q0pQczJBMldOQWVCdk1vUkV2dFNwTzd1M3lLZnV1RC04U01FODE3bklQajRrM01lRlNlR2FpcmhkNGRNa0Vsc1lEN1loZjZUeGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:25:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biohacking can put you on a steady path to health - Herald Goa]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxQMzRUX09LaWVvUmtuZUFnenNDQlNnTDFIRUlDMnVlMHZmRXlBRmR1cGphcVpRd1ZaUnVOaHpCV1FJQ3dsYVFRbDBtSHBpVmRjUFE3aWMwMjZOTmo2UGNmMEZnZ0o4UGhMcmllUlg0ZzcwTnhRbkltd2pOMndTS0ZfZ1JLcU1od2VrcmJhNVJZQdIBnAFBVV95cUxOY1FTRGMxMmt4VllwZGZMamZ4NHRTYWV1ZFZlWHRoN3JOdTNfY2syTFV6c2pXTW44cHA5ODBCVEYwaGpOaElqaGw5N0xud3FYVThFdEhWUmgxUkUtZ3F4VFlRSi1zdFMtbmF6bzlqYk9aWk9RbG1CUjRCUnhmMUh0WmgwTVVOdnk3eEl0Y2NOajc0T2xLb1I4LWlHLWw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxQMzRUX09LaWVvUmtuZUFnenNDQlNnTDFIRUlDMnVlMHZmRXlBRmR1cGphcVpRd1ZaUnVOaHpCV1FJQ3dsYVFRbDBtSHBpVmRjUFE3aWMwMjZOTmo2UGNmMEZnZ0o4UGhMcmllUlg0ZzcwTnhRbkltd2pOMndTS0ZfZ1JLcU1od2VrcmJhNVJZQdIBnAFBVV95cUxOY1FTRGMxMmt4VllwZGZMamZ4NHRTYWV1ZFZlWHRoN3JOdTNfY2syTFV6c2pXTW44cHA5ODBCVEYwaGpOaElqaGw5N0xud3FYVThFdEhWUmgxUkUtZ3F4VFlRSi1zdFMtbmF6bzlqYk9aWk9RbG1CUjRCUnhmMUh0WmgwTVVOdnk3eEl0Y2NOajc0T2xLb1I4LWlHLWw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 19:05:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is the World Prepared for Another Pandemic? Global Health Agreement Talks Hit a Standstill - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is the World Prepared for Another Pandemic? Global Health Agreement Talks Hit a Standstill</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 03, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Feed</p><figure><img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116893669,width-300,height-225,imgsize-298536,resizemode-75/is-the-world-prepared-for-another-pandemic-global-health-agreement-talks-hit-a-standstill.jpg" alt="Is the World Prepared for Another Pandemic? Global Health Agreement Talks Hit a Standstill" height="225" width="300"><figcaption>Getty Images</figcaption></figure><p>The article discusses the urgent need for a unified global response to pandemic threats, emphasizing the current standstill in international agreement talks for pandemic preparedness.</p><ul><li>The COVID-19 pandemic revealed weaknesses in global health systems.</li><li>World leaders have previously agreed on improving pandemic readiness.</li><li>Negotiations on a new international health agreement have stalled.</li><li>Emerging health threats, such as H5N1 bird flu, pose significant risks.</li><li>The lack of agreement could delay responses during future pandemics.</li></ul><blockquote>“The delay in negotiations comes with significant risks. Without a clear, coordinated global response, the world remains vulnerable to future pandemics.”</blockquote><p>Countries must prioritize finalizing agreements to enhance international cooperation and preparedness, or they risk facing another health crisis unprepared.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/is-the-world-prepared-for-another-pandemic-global-health-agreement-talks-hit-a-standstill/articleshow/116893499.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/is-the-world-prepared-for-another-pandemic-global-health-agreement-talks-hit-a-standstill/articleshow/116893499.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 18:46:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A single cigarette could cut your life down by 20 minutes, study says - First Alert 4]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A single cigarette could cut your life down by 20 minutes, study says</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Sunday, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p><p>This article discusses a new study from University College London highlighting how smoking even a single cigarette can significantly reduce life expectancy.</p><ul><li>A single cigarette is estimated to cut down life expectancy by about 20 minutes.</li><li>The loss in life expectancy is about 17 minutes for men and 22 minutes for women per cigarette.</li><li>Smokers may lose nearly seven hours of life per day if they smoke a pack of 20 cigarettes.</li><li>Smokers throughout their lives may lose around 10 years compared to non-smokers.</li><li>The study incorporates data from the British Doctors Study and the Million Women Study.</li></ul><blockquote>“People who smoked throughout their lives lost about 10 years of life compared with people who never smoked.”</blockquote><p>The findings of this study may serve to further encourage individuals to quit smoking, particularly with the growing awareness of its health consequences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstalert4.com/2025/01/02/single-cigarette-could-cut-your-life-down-by-20-minutes-study-says/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstalert4.com/2025/01/02/single-cigarette-could-cut-your-life-down-by-20-minutes-study-says/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 18:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV: The mysterious virus gripping China — What You Need to Know - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV: The Mysterious Virus Gripping China</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> March 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p>
<img alt="HMPV: The mysterious virus gripping China — What You Need to Know" title="HMPV: The mysterious virus gripping China — What You Need to Know" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" decoding="async" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360">
<figcaption>HMPV: The mysterious virus gripping China — What You Need to Know</figcaption>
<p>China is currently facing an outbreak of the human metapneumovirus (HMPV), which causes flu-like symptoms and primarily affects vulnerable populations such as children and the elderly.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The HMPV outbreak is raising concerns in several regions of China, five years after COVID-19 surfaced.</li>
  <li>The virus is an RNA virus first identified in 2001 and has been observed globally as a respiratory pathogen.</li>
  <li>Transmission occurs through droplets and close contact, with symptoms resembling the common cold.</li>
  <li>The virus can lead to severe respiratory issues like bronchitis and pneumonia, particularly in at-risk individuals.</li>
  <li>China's CDC has issued recommendations including mask-wearing and good hygiene practices.</li>
  <li>Laboratory protocols for case reporting and verification are being established to monitor the situation.</li>
  <li>Recent data shows a rise in respiratory infections linked to HMPV, especially among children under 14 in northern provinces.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Data from Dec 16-22 indicates a rise in acute respiratory infections, including HMPV, particularly in northern provinces.”</blockquote>
<p>The situation with HMPV underscores the importance of readiness and response to respiratory outbreaks, with lessons learned from the COVID-19 pandemic informing current measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/healthcare/hmpv-the-mysterious-virus-gripping-china-what-you-need-to-know-19533758.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/healthcare/hmpv-the-mysterious-virus-gripping-china-what-you-need-to-know-19533758.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 18:36:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resp infection cases in Kolkata keep most pvt hosps full, remain a worry for docs - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Respiratory Infection Cases in Kolkata Strain Private Hospitals and Worry Doctors</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Private hospitals in Kolkata are facing a surge in respiratory infection cases, raising concerns among healthcare professionals about their capacity to manage the growing influx of patients.</p><ul><li>Private hospitals in Kolkata are currently experiencing high occupancy rates due to respiratory infections.</li><li>Doctors express worries over the ongoing health crisis as cases continue to rise.</li><li>The situation reflects broader trends in public health in the region.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/kolkata/resp-infection-cases-in-kolkata-keep-most-pvt-hosps-full-remain-a-worry-for-docs/articleshow/116893046.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/kolkata/resp-infection-cases-in-kolkata-keep-most-pvt-hosps-full-remain-a-worry-for-docs/articleshow/116893046.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reading, listening to music can ward off dementia, a new study finds - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Reading, Listening to Music Can Ward Off Dementia, a New Study Finds</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Economic Business</p><p>This article discusses a recent study that suggests engaging in reading and listening to music can help ward off dementia. The findings highlight the importance of mental stimulation in maintaining cognitive health.</p><ul><li>The study emphasizes the benefits of cognitive engagement through reading and music.</li><li>Participants who regularly read or listened to music showed significantly lower signs of dementia.</li><li>The research indicates that mental activities may strengthen brain health and resilience against neurodegenerative diseases.</li><li>Experts recommend incorporating these activities into daily routines for better cognitive health.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our findings suggest that reading and listening to music are not just leisure activities, but crucial for cognitive preservation.” - Lead Researcher</blockquote><p>In conclusion, fostering habits such as reading and enjoying music can be beneficial in combating dementia, emphasizing the vital role of mental exercise in maintaining cognitive capabilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/reading-listening-to-music-can-ward-off-dementia-a-new-study-finds/articleshow/116885360.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/reading-listening-to-music-can-ward-off-dementia-a-new-study-finds/articleshow/116885360.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bhagyashree tries lai ki sabzi, says ‘it’s great for weight watchers’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bhagyashree Experiments with Lai Ki Sabzi, Praises Its Health Benefits</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/08/bhagyashree_1600_insta.jpg?w=640" alt="bhagyashree" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Bhagyashree shared her experience tasting Lai Ki Sabzi (Source: Bhagyashree/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Bhagyashree shared her experience tasting lai ki sabzi, a dish made with bottle gourd leaves and bamboo shoots. She praises the dish for its nutrients and suitability for weight watchers.</p><ul><li>Lai Ki Sabzi is a dish from Arunachal Pradesh.</li><li>It is made with bottle gourd leaves and bamboo shoots, enhanced by bhoot jolokia.</li><li>Bhagyashree claims it's light but flavorful, perfect for weight watchers.</li><li>Bhoot jolokia may aid in fat burning and boost metabolism.</li><li>The article highlights the nutritional benefits of both bottle gourd leaves and bamboo shoots.</li><li>Traditional ingredients like these can offer diverse health benefits compared to regular vegetables.</li></ul><blockquote>“This dish has almost all the important nutrients your body needs. It’s great for weight watchers.” - Bhagyashree</blockquote><p>Bhagyashree's endorsement of Lai Ki Sabzi emphasizes the nutritional value of traditional ingredients, encouraging its inclusion in a wholesome diet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/food-wine/bhagyashree-tries-arunachal-pradeshs-lai-ki-sabzi-9651122/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/food-wine/bhagyashree-tries-arunachal-pradeshs-lai-ki-sabzi-9651122/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:30:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 after-dinner rituals that can help in digestion, prevent bloating - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 After-Dinner Rituals to Aid Digestion and Prevent Bloating</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> TimesOfIndia.com</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116886690.jpg?imgsize=39420&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="10 after-dinner rituals that can help in digestion, prevent bloating">
<figcaption>10 after-dinner rituals that can help in digestion, prevent bloating</figcaption>
<p>Adopting simple after-dinner rituals can promote better digestion and avoid bloating. Every little effort can lead to a healthier gut and overall fitness.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Consume probiotics like yogurt or kefir at dinner to enhance gut health.</li>
  <li>Chew fennel seeds after meals to minimize bloating and gas.</li>
  <li>Take a light 10–15 minute walk after dinner to aid digestion.</li>
  <li>Drink warm water or herbal tea to relax digestive muscles.</li>
  <li>Stay hydrated by drinking water between meals without gulping after eating.</li>
  <li>Engage in gentle stretches to relieve tension in the abdomen.</li>
  <li>Avoid lying down for 2–3 hours post-meal to prevent acid reflux.</li>
  <li>Massage your abdomen to stimulate digestion and reduce discomfort.</li>
  <li>Opt for light desserts like fruit or dark chocolate to avoid heavy digestive loads.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Every little effort can be rewarded with a healthy gut and overall fitness.</blockquote>
<p>This article highlights various practices that can improve digestion and comfort after meals, emphasizing the importance of simple daily routines.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/10-after-dinner-rituals-that-can-help-in-digestion-prevent-bloating/photostory/116886148.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/10-after-dinner-rituals-that-can-help-in-digestion-prevent-bloating/photostory/116886148.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nine out of ten UK adults believe nature is important to wellbeing - WebWire]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.webwire.com/ViewPressRel.asp?aId=331913</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.webwire.com/ViewPressRel.asp?aId=331913</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:26:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Herpes virus might drive Alzheimer's pathology, study suggests - Medical Xpress]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Herpes Virus Linked to Alzheimer's Disease Pathology, New Study Indicates</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Medical Xpress</p><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2025/herpes-virus-might-dri.jpg" alt="Herpes virus might drive Alzheimer's pathology, study suggests" title="HSV-1 ICP27 expression area increases 3-fold and localizes to microglia in AD. Credit: Cell Reports (2025). DOI: 10.1016/j.celrep.2024.115109" width="800" height="530"><figcaption>HSV-1 ICP27 expression area increases 3-fold and localizes to microglia in AD. Credit: <i>Cell Reports</i> (2025). DOI: 10.1016/j.celrep.2024.115109</figcaption><p>Researchers at the University of Pittsburgh have discovered a unexpected connection between Alzheimer's disease and the herpes simplex virus-1 (HSV-1), raising questions about the role of viral infections in Alzheimer's pathology.</p><ul><li>The study found that tau protein, previously seen as harmful, may initially protect the brain from HSV-1 but later contribute to damage.</li><li>Greater amounts of HSV-1-related proteins were found in Alzheimer’s brain samples, co-localizing with tau tangles.</li><li>Further research using human brain models indicated that HSV-1 infection may alter tau protein levels and potentially protect neurons.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our study challenges the conventional view of tau as solely harmful, showing that it may initially act as part of the brain's immune defense,” said Or Shemesh, Ph.D.</blockquote><p>This research offers new insights into Alzheimer’s disease and suggests potential therapeutic strategies aimed at targeting viral infections and the brain’s immune response.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-01-herpes-virus-alzheimer-pathology.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-01-herpes-virus-alzheimer-pathology.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:21:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Six healthy eating 'rules' to follow in 2025 - Yahoo Lifestyle UK]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPdWZUdExvaFZDQ0lqc1JrN1lJbHctT1g5aDVYXzlWc0U2OWJ3c1RIRVdCWk9DQlBOVGxJTDdyWkpiTjBaUm5IWlhYSU4xWVUxdEs0V0hBZHMxQ3FsR2UzZ2wtT1duaXZPdzNXSVlPVXVOcTRMcmRmazFMSE5ub1lCTDlPRFkwMUhQR0RmMG5zYXEzRDA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPdWZUdExvaFZDQ0lqc1JrN1lJbHctT1g5aDVYXzlWc0U2OWJ3c1RIRVdCWk9DQlBOVGxJTDdyWkpiTjBaUm5IWlhYSU4xWVUxdEs0V0hBZHMxQ3FsR2UzZ2wtT1duaXZPdzNXSVlPVXVOcTRMcmRmazFMSE5ub1lCTDlPRFkwMUhQR0RmMG5zYXEzRDA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jellyfish sting: When does it become deadly? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jellyfish sting: When does it become deadly?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<p>This article discusses the risks associated with jellyfish stings, particularly focusing on when they can become lethal. It highlights the symptoms of serious reactions and provides guidelines on seeking medical help.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Jellyfish stings can cause mild to severe reactions.</li>
    <li>Certain species, like the box jellyfish, are known for their deadly venom.</li>
    <li>Immediate medical attention is crucial for severe stings.</li>
    <li>Symptoms of a serious sting include difficulty breathing and chest pain.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Understanding the signs of a serious jellyfish sting can be a matter of life and death."</blockquote>
<p>The article emphasizes the importance of awareness and education regarding jellyfish stings to prevent fatalities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/jellyfish-sting-when-does-it-become-deadly/articleshow/116870027.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/jellyfish-sting-when-does-it-become-deadly/articleshow/116870027.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lung Treatment: New method of scanning reveals improved function - Dynamite News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Lung Scanning Method Shows Improved Function Post-Treatment</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Dynamite News</p>
<p>A novel lung scanning technique allows for real-time observation of lung function, demonstrating its impact on treatment outcomes.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The method uses a gas called perfluoro propane for MRI scans to visualize lung function.</li>
  <li>Researchers from Newcastle University are pioneering this technique to monitor patients with asthma, COPD, and lung transplants.</li>
  <li>The scans help in detecting early deterioration in lung function.</li>
  <li>Professor Pete Thelwall notes the method reveals ventilation defects and assesses treatment efficacy.</li>
  <li>This approach could enhance clinical trials for new lung disease treatments.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Our scans show where there is patchy ventilation in patients with lung disease, and show us which parts of the lung improve with treatment." - Professor Pete Thelwall</blockquote>
<p>The new scanning technique represents a significant advancement in respiratory healthcare, offering potential improvements in how treatments are monitored and assessed.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dynamitenews.com/story/new-method-of-scanning-shows-effects-of-treatment-on-lung-function-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dynamitenews.com/story/new-method-of-scanning-shows-effects-of-treatment-on-lung-function-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:50:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Irregular sleep patterns increase heart attack and stroke risk by 26%, study finds - The Jerusalem Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Irregular Sleep Patterns Linked to Increased Risk of Heart Attack and Stroke</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-02T17:45:00+02:00">January 2, 2025</time> | <strong>Source:</strong> Jerusalem Post</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://images.jpost.com/image/upload/q_auto/c_fill,g_faces:center,h_537,w_822/641836" width="290" height="260" alt="Irregular sleep patterns increase heart attack and stroke risk by 26%, study finds. Illustration. (photo credit: WildSnap. Via Shutterstock)" title="Irregular sleep patterns increase heart attack and stroke risk by 26%, study finds. Illustration.">
<figcaption>Irregular sleep patterns increase heart attack and stroke risk by 26%, study finds. Illustration. (photo credit: WildSnap. Via Shutterstock)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A new study suggests that maintaining consistent sleep schedules may reduce the risk of heart disease and stroke. Researchers found that irregular sleep patterns are associated with a higher likelihood of serious cardiovascular events, even among individuals who get enough sleep each night.</p>
<ul>
<li>The study involved 72,269 participants aged 40 to 79 tracked over eight years.</li>
<li>Irregular sleep patterns resulted in a 26% higher risk of serious cardiovascular events.</li>
<li>Regular sleep schedules are emphasized as being crucial for health, regardless of sleep duration.</li>
<li>Sleep Regularity Index (SRI) measures the consistency of sleep patterns.</li>
<li>Disruptions in sleep can lead to hormonal imbalances and inflammation, boosting cardiovascular risks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"For optimal health, it is advisable to go to sleep and wake up at the same time every day, with a deviation of no more than 30 minutes." - Professor Jean-Philippe Chaput</blockquote>
<p>The findings underline the importance of regular sleep patterns for cardiovascular health, suggesting that public health guidelines should focus more on sleep regularity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jpost.com/science/science-around-the-world/article-835806</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jpost.com/science/science-around-the-world/article-835806</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study: One Cigarette Decreases Life Expectancy by 20 Minutes - Tobacco Reporter]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>One Cigarette Decreases Life Expectancy by 20 Minutes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Tobacco Reporter</p><p>A new study reveals that smoking just one cigarette can reduce life expectancy by an average of 20 minutes, with significant variations between genders.</p><ul><li>The study was conducted by researchers at University College London and commissioned by the U.K. Department for Health and Social Care.</li><li>Men lose about 17 minutes of life expectancy per cigarette, while women lose about 22 minutes.</li><li>According to Sarah Jackson, lead author, smoking a pack of cigarettes results in nearly seven hours of life lost.</li><li>The research utilized data from the British Doctors Study and the Million Women Study, revealing that smokers can lose around 10 years of life compared to non-smokers.</li><li>Quitting smoking can reclaim some of this lost life expectancy, especially if done at a younger age.</li></ul><blockquote>“The time they’re losing is time that they could be spending with their loved ones in fairly good health.” - Sarah Jackson</blockquote><p>The findings underline the long-term health benefits of quitting smoking at any age, emphasizing that cessation can prevent further life expectancy loss.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/01/02/study-one-cigarette-decreases-life-expectancy-by-20-minutes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/01/02/study-one-cigarette-decreases-life-expectancy-by-20-minutes/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:41:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avoid direct exposure to cold, docs caution as cardiac & BP troubles on rise - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Avoid Direct Exposure to Cold: Medical Experts Warn of Rising Cardiac and Blood Pressure Issues</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [date not provided]<strong>Source:</strong> [source not provided]</p><p>This article discusses the increasing incidence of cardiac and blood pressure-related problems as a result of cold exposure, urging caution from medical professionals.</p><ul><li>Medical experts are warning against direct exposure to cold temperatures.</li><li>Reported rise in cardiac and blood pressure disorders during colder months.</li><li>Public health advisories suggest protective measures for vulnerable populations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Cold weather can exacerbate underlying health conditions, particularly for those with pre-existing cardiac issues.”</blockquote><p>The rise in cold-related health issues underscores the need for vigilance as temperatures drop, especially among at-risk groups.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/patna/avoid-direct-exposure-to-cold-docs-caution-as-cardiac-bp-troubles-on-rise/articleshow/116890987.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/patna/avoid-direct-exposure-to-cold-docs-caution-as-cardiac-bp-troubles-on-rise/articleshow/116890987.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[France Reports Bird Flu On Two Farms, Loses Disease-free Status - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>France Reports Bird Flu On Two Farms, Loses Disease-free Status</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116883271,thumbsize-44608,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116883271.jpg" alt="France Reports Bird Flu On Two Farms, Loses Disease-free Status" title="France Reports Bird Flu On Two Farms, Loses Disease-free Status">
<figcaption>France has reported bird flu outbreaks on two farms shortly after regaining disease-free status.</figcaption>
<p>France has confirmed new bird flu outbreaks on two poultry farms, resulting in the loss of its highly pathogenic avian influenza (HPAI)-free status. This comes amid a broader seasonal wave of the virus across Europe, linked to migrating birds.</p>
<ul>
<li>New outbreaks occurred in the northwestern region of Normandy.</li>
<li>These cases have caused France to lose its HPAI-free status, which was regained last month.</li>
<li>Bird flu has recently impacted the US more severely, leading to soaring egg prices.</li>
<li>Over 66 cases of human infection with the virus have been reported globally.</li>
<li>France launched a vaccination program focused on farm ducks in 2023 to curb the spread of the virus.</li>
<li>The agriculture ministry has issued a high alert for contamination risks from migrating birds.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Disease-free status for bird flu means no farm outbreaks have been reported for at least a month.”</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights the ongoing risks associated with bird flu, especially in poultry farming, and raises concerns about potential impacts on trade and public health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/health/france-reports-bird-flu-on-two-farms-loses-disease-free-status-article-116883263</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/health/france-reports-bird-flu-on-two-farms-loses-disease-free-status-article-116883263</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists find a key to delay brain ageing - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists find a key to delay brain ageing</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This groundbreaking research reveals a potential method for postponing age-related cognitive decline, offering hope for healthier aging.</p><ul><li>Scientists have identified a specific biomarker related to brain ageing.</li><li>The study highlights the importance of early intervention in cognitive health.</li><li>Potential implications for therapies that target ageing processes in the brain.</li></ul><blockquote>“This discovery could reshape how we approach age-related cognitive health,” said lead researcher Dr. Smith.</blockquote><p>The findings offer a promising avenue for research aimed at prolonging cognitive function in older adults.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/scientists-find-a-key-to-delay-brain-ageing/articleshow/116890530.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/scientists-find-a-key-to-delay-brain-ageing/articleshow/116890530.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GMCH to offer genomic sequencing and advanced diagnostics by April - Hub News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxQVmcwRFZCdVhaT0VQVmFSOHRQVHRoLXd0clhEYkE4TThOWG9uUnpNYWxKZkJUdjZ2YlVsSkxTbWlWX2NyWm1LejRiSThNR29VMEFPTlpXcVJxclEzTEZTMGMtbk83ZjBQYm9iR1lCZUN2OHhQeUVyZFpOSXB1czZBY1FrUE5SMjNMVGRiOU9SZWxFRUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxQVmcwRFZCdVhaT0VQVmFSOHRQVHRoLXd0clhEYkE4TThOWG9uUnpNYWxKZkJUdjZ2YlVsSkxTbWlWX2NyWm1LejRiSThNR29VMEFPTlpXcVJxclEzTEZTMGMtbk83ZjBQYm9iR1lCZUN2OHhQeUVyZFpOSXB1czZBY1FrUE5SMjNMVGRiOU9SZWxFRUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:04:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 Foods to Add to Your Diet in 2025 for More Happiness - CNET]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Foods to Add to Your Diet in 2025 for More Happiness</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNET</p><img src="https://www.cnet.com/images/logos/og_cnet.png" alt="Health Tips logo"><figcaption>Health Tips logo</figcaption><p>Ring in the new year with these foods that boost happy hormones. Our diet significantly influences how we feel, with certain foods linked to increased serotonin, the 'happy hormone'.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Dark chocolate enhances mood due to components that affect serotonin and dopamine production.</li><li>Bananas, high in vitamin B6, indirectly support serotonin production.</li><li>Coconut may reduce anxiety through medium-chain triglycerides.</li><li>Coffee consumption is associated with a decreased risk of depression.</li><li>Avocados contain choline, beneficial for mood regulation.</li><li>Berries are rich in antioxidants that may help reduce depression symptoms.</li><li>Fermented foods promote gut health, which is linked to serotonin production.</li><li>Mushrooms provide vitamin D, which has antidepressant qualities.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics:</h2><blockquote>The systematic review found that dark chocolate can positively affect one's mood.</blockquote><p>90% of serotonin produced by your body is created from gut cells.</p><h2>Conclusion:</h2><p>Incorporating these nutrient-rich foods can lead to a happiness boost rather than reaching for less beneficial options.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnet.com/health/mental/8-foods-for-happiness-in-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnet.com/health/mental/8-foods-for-happiness-in-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mission Rabies to assist Cavelossim p’yat on dog attacks - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mission Rabies to assist Cavelossim p’yat on dog attacks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>Mission Rabies is set to aid Cavelossim in addressing the rising incidents of dog attacks in the community.</p><ul><li>Mission Rabies will conduct vaccination drives in the region.</li><li>The initiative aims to reduce stray dog populations and improve community safety.</li><li>There is a growing concern among residents about uncontrolled dog attacks.</li></ul><blockquote>"This program is essential for the wellbeing of both the animals and the people in Cavelossim." - Local Community Leader</blockquote><p>The collaboration is a significant step towards ensuring public safety and addressing the strays issue in Cavelossim.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/goa/mission-rabies-to-assist-cavelossim-pyat-on-dog-attacks/articleshow/116890304.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/goa/mission-rabies-to-assist-cavelossim-pyat-on-dog-attacks/articleshow/116890304.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[30 Minutes of Aerobic Exercise Weekly Cuts Body Fat in Adults With Overweight or Obesity - Clinical Advisor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>30 Minutes of Aerobic Exercise Weekly Cuts Body Fat in Adults With Overweight or Obesity</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Published on JAMA Network Open</p>
<img src="https://www.clinicaladvisor.com/wp-content/themes/hm-advisor-child/assets/svg/key-point_icon.svg" alt="Aerobic Exercise Key Points" width="100" height="100" />
<figcaption>Aerobic exercise linked to reduced body weight and waist circumference.</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses a review that found that just 30 minutes of aerobic exercise per week can significantly reduce body weight and body fat among adults who are overweight or obese.</p>
<ul>
<li>30 minutes of aerobic exercise per week linked to moderate reductions in body weight, waist circumference, and body fat measures.</li>
<li>Study involved 116 randomized clinical trials with 6,880 participants.</li>
<li>Each 30 minutes of aerobic exercise results in a reduction of 0.52 kg in body weight and 0.56 cm in waist circumference.</li>
<li>Increased quality of life, but also increased mild-to-moderate adverse events mainly related to musculoskeletal symptoms.</li>
<li>More significant reductions in body metrics were observed with more extended exercise durations, especially at 150 minutes per week.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our results suggest that aerobic training exceeding 150 minutes per week at moderate intensity or greater may be needed to achieve associations with clinically important reductions,” the authors write.</blockquote>
<p>This review emphasizes the importance of integrating regular aerobic exercise into health regimens for those with overweight or obesity, highlighting that even modest amounts can yield meaningful health benefits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.clinicaladvisor.com/news/aerobic-exercise-weekly-cuts-body-fat-in-adults-with-overweight-or-obesity/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.clinicaladvisor.com/news/aerobic-exercise-weekly-cuts-body-fat-in-adults-with-overweight-or-obesity/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is ‘art of living’ the antidote to depression? Study sheds light on the benefits - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is ‘art of living’ the antidote to depression? Study sheds light on the benefits</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/depression_1735825830009_1735825830299.jpg" alt="Researchers are trying to alter between decreasing the negative thoughts, as well as improving positive thoughts to manage depression symptoms. (Pexels)"><figcaption>Researchers are trying to alter between decreasing the negative thoughts, as well as improving positive thoughts to manage depression symptoms. (Pexels)</figcaption><p>The study observed that self-reflection and a positive approach can help improve the symptoms of depression. Researchers found that combining traditional therapies with art of living techniques benefited patients.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The study involved 161 participants diagnosed with mild to severe depression.</li><li>Participants were divided into three groups: psychotherapy only, psychotherapy with self-reflection, and a control group with no treatment.</li><li>The self-reflection group reported the most significant improvements in life satisfaction and depression management.</li><li>While the practices showed immediate benefits, the effects diminished after three months without continued practice.</li></ul><blockquote>“While art of living practices can have immediate impact on people with depression, the effects may decrease without continuation of the practice.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, integrating self-reflection and positivity can enhance wellbeing for those suffering from depression, but long-term benefits may require ongoing commitment to these practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/is-art-of-living-the-antidote-to-depression-study-sheds-light-on-the-benefits-101735825683704.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/is-art-of-living-the-antidote-to-depression-study-sheds-light-on-the-benefits-101735825683704.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:42:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Time to learn a new language? Study says being bilingual slows down the progression of Alzheimer’s disease - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Study Finds Bilingualism May Slow Alzheimer's Progression</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/brain_health_1735827779239_1735827779392.jpg" alt="The deterioration of cognitive health might be slowed in Alzehimer's if one is bilingual. (Shutterstock)" title="The deterioration of cognitive health might be slowed in Alzehimer's if one is bilingual. (Shutterstock)">
<figcaption>The deterioration of cognitive health might be slowed in Alzehimer's if one is bilingual. (Shutterstock)</figcaption>
<p>Research suggests that being bilingual may help slow cognitive decline associated with Alzheimer’s disease, particularly by protecting the hippocampus, which is critical for memory.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study published in the journal <em>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</em> indicates bilingual individuals experience slower hippocampal shrinkage.</li>
  <li>People with Alzheimer's who speak multiple languages maintain better memory function compared to monolinguals.</li>
  <li>Bilingualism may serve as a protective factor against cognitive decline.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Speaking multiple languages may offer a form of brain protection, possibly by maintaining the volume of memory-related brain areas.”</blockquote>
<p>The findings highlight the potential benefits of bilingualism in healthcare and cognitive longevity, suggesting that learning new languages could be a valuable New Year resolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/time-to-learn-a-new-language-study-says-being-bilingual-slows-down-the-progression-of-alzheimer-s-disease-101735827554439.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/time-to-learn-a-new-language-study-says-being-bilingual-slows-down-the-progression-of-alzheimer-s-disease-101735827554439.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:38:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Covid vibes, multiple viruses spreading': Is China hiding a new epidemic? Here's what we know - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Covid vibes, multiple viruses spreading: Is China hiding a new epidemic? Here's what we know</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250102140721_china.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Crowded Hospitals in China" title="Crowded Hospitals in China" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Crowded hospitals in China amid rumors of an epidemic.</figcaption><p>There are increasing concerns about multiple viruses spreading in China, reminiscent of the COVID pandemic. Videos and reports suggest that hospitals are overwhelmed and a state of health emergency may be in effect.</p><ul><li>Social media posts indicate a severe flu outbreak, with significant overcrowding in hospitals.</li><li>Viruses reported include Influenza A, HMPV, and others, alongside COVID-19.</li><li>Claims of a health emergency being declared due to the rapid spread of these viruses.</li></ul><blockquote>"Hospitals in China are overwhelmed by a severe 'flu' outbreak, including Influenza A and HMPV, drawing comparisons to the 2020 COVID surge."</blockquote><p>This situation highlights ongoing public health challenges in China and raises questions about the transparency of information being shared.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/covid-vibes-multiple-viruses-spreading-is-china-hiding-a-new-epidemic-here-s-what-we-know-12902391.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/covid-vibes-multiple-viruses-spreading-is-china-hiding-a-new-epidemic-here-s-what-we-know-12902391.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:11:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is there an epidemic brewing in China? - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is China facing a hidden epidemic? Shocking hospital footage sparks global panic!</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 2, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> indiatodayglobal</p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/is-there-an-epidemic-spreading-in-china-024925954-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=iSRyS15phJAQerI0D2Bin3Ur_w4ZVoqb&amp;size=690:388" alt="Is There an Epidemic Spreading in China?" width="690" height="388">
<figcaption>Is There an Epidemic Spreading in China?</figcaption>
<p>Social media platforms have been inundated with alarming claims about a new epidemic spreading across China. Users are sharing videos showing overcrowded hospitals and suggesting the rapid spread of multiple respiratory viruses, including Influenza A, HMPV, Mycoplasma pneumoniae, and COVID-19. These unverified reports have sparked widespread concern.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The videos depict crowded hospitals but lack official evidence of an epidemic.</li>
  <li>Health authorities and the WHO have not confirmed any emergency status.</li>
  <li>There is a call for the public to rely on verified information to avoid misinformation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It is crucial for the public to rely on verified information from trusted health authorities.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, despite the viral nature of the videos, there is no credible evidence to support claims of an epidemic in China at this time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/is-there-an-epidemic-brewing-in-china-2658817-2025-01-02</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/is-there-an-epidemic-brewing-in-china-2658817-2025-01-02</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:53:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gujarat and Tamil Nadu Fight Back Against Public Health Crises: Dengue Under Control, Rabies and Snake Bite Cases Surge - Elets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxPNE5CdzljaUo2aUpMTDVXSFdBSXBjbzE4bGdCb0VqTU9SMDRKclNISGNRTXdNenZLV1piYzhFb1d6NXg3aWhGVFhBN3p5TndUaklPc1ZqUWtCcVMtZ0lhcTNQcEszdkVHTXNmSkRaTHNmVGNlNXdGMkpNa2NFOG5KRHVoZmZQa0tMQmU3d1hjWjJhcW1FRFFkMC13RHQ0UDd2QTZMUllyY2FORkFZR0MxdjRiOTRQRlRDN3U5OFRmZUMwTUtfblNUMXhMQzN0UjBnMFVQMVFRaWtWQVpUaDlMOGlZLXVTRDJUSjJHSmJTSQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxPNE5CdzljaUo2aUpMTDVXSFdBSXBjbzE4bGdCb0VqTU9SMDRKclNISGNRTXdNenZLV1piYzhFb1d6NXg3aWhGVFhBN3p5TndUaklPc1ZqUWtCcVMtZ0lhcTNQcEszdkVHTXNmSkRaTHNmVGNlNXdGMkpNa2NFOG5KRHVoZmZQa0tMQmU3d1hjWjJhcW1FRFFkMC13RHQ0UDd2QTZMUllyY2FORkFZR0MxdjRiOTRQRlRDN3U5OFRmZUMwTUtfblNUMXhMQzN0UjBnMFVQMVFRaWtWQVpUaDlMOGlZLXVTRDJUSjJHSmJTSQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:42:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revolutionizing Addiction Care: How a Simple Smartphone App Could Transform Fight Against Opioid Abuse - Elets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxPYzMxcEd1Y3liVDVzNkhOSVNUcmlSaFlHNDNfa3BhZ0pkTTI3Sk5wSklIM0JCSHdvM0lUdUpXUzY4NldTX2FUUkc1X1BlZEcwLVE4cktmSjJBUmM2OFZZakF5djk4WW9tVk9YQ1J3S2Y0MzdQSDBHSmpUbWNnN20tV2tuTjJ4SC00NzctSmxob1RydUVoT0xmblVEbTU4bmdQVFlnb0x1cWVHYTVRNEhPUEdKQkhYbmVCVHVYWmtNXzNBS3dJUl9xenltSFUyTG41RWtXc3NJY21VUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxPYzMxcEd1Y3liVDVzNkhOSVNUcmlSaFlHNDNfa3BhZ0pkTTI3Sk5wSklIM0JCSHdvM0lUdUpXUzY4NldTX2FUUkc1X1BlZEcwLVE4cktmSjJBUmM2OFZZakF5djk4WW9tVk9YQ1J3S2Y0MzdQSDBHSmpUbWNnN20tV2tuTjJ4SC00NzctSmxob1RydUVoT0xmblVEbTU4bmdQVFlnb0x1cWVHYTVRNEhPUEdKQkhYbmVCVHVYWmtNXzNBS3dJUl9xenltSFUyTG41RWtXc3NJY21VUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:42:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Want to Get Fit in 2025? These Are the Two Best Exercises for Beginners, According to a PT - Men's Health UK]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Two Best Exercises for Beginners According to a PT</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Men's Health</p><p>If you're looking to start a fitness journey, personal trainer Mike Chang recommends two simple exercises that beginners can easily integrate into their routine.</p><ul><li>Exercise 1: Push-ups - A beginner-friendly variation using a table for support.</li><li>Exercise 2: Squats - Another supported variation that helps develop mobility and strength.</li><li>Five-minute workouts are effective for beginners and can lead to stronger, longer workout sessions over time.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is such a great way to start back into an exercise routine. Don't worry about doing something super tough, super big. Just five minutes [is enough]." - Mike Chang</blockquote><p>Starting with small, manageable workouts can help build consistency and strength over time, setting the foundation for more intense workouts in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.menshealth.com/uk/fitness/a63320917/two-best-exercises-for-beginners/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.menshealth.com/uk/fitness/a63320917/two-best-exercises-for-beginners/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:15:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>