<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 19:18:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 19:18:25 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daily glass of milk may cut bowel cancer risk by fifth, research finds - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daily glass of milk may cut bowel cancer risk by fifth, research finds</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> The Guardian</p><img src='image_link_placeholder' alt='Milk glass' /><figcaption>A daily glass of milk may significantly reduce the risk of bowel cancer.</figcaption><p>A recent study indicates that consuming a large glass of milk each day could reduce the risk of bowel cancer by nearly 20%, primarily due to the calcium it contains.</p><ul><li>Daily intake of 300mg of calcium, equivalent to half a pint of milk, is linked to a 17% reduction in bowel cancer risk.</li><li>Both dairy and fortified non-dairy calcium sources (e.g., soy milk) show similar protective effects.</li><li>The study analyzed dietary data from over 540,000 women over 17 years.</li><li>Alcohol and red or processed meats are associated with increases in bowel cancer risk.</li><li>More than half of bowel cancer cases are preventable through lifestyle and diet changes.</li></ul><blockquote>“This comprehensive study provides robust evidence that dairy products may help prevent colorectal cancer.” - Dr. Keren Papier</blockquote><p>This study underscores the importance of diet in reducing bowel cancer risk and highlights calcium as a key protective factor.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/08/daily-glass-of-milk-may-cut-bowel-cancer-risk-by-fifth-research-finds</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/08/daily-glass-of-milk-may-cut-bowel-cancer-risk-by-fifth-research-finds</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid HMPV concerns, isolation ward set up in Nellore GGH - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Isolation Ward Established in Nellore Amid HMPV Concerns</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 09:22 pm IST<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/40pnjy/article69077672.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/10745_8_1_2025_17_53_55_1_IMG_20250108_WA0036.JPG" alt="A 10-bed isolation ward for HMPV infected patients has been set up at Nellore GGH." title="A 10-bed isolation ward for HMPV infected patients has been set up at Nellore GGH."><figcaption>A 10-bed isolation ward for HMPV infected patients has been set up at Nellore GGH.</figcaption><p>In response to the global concerns surrounding Human metapneumovirus (HMPV), a 10-bed isolation ward has been established at the Government General Hospital (GGH) in Nellore. Although there are currently no reported HMPV cases in Andhra Pradesh, the health authorities are taking precautions by preparing for potential outbreaks.</p><ul><li>A total of 11 HMPV cases reported in India, none in Andhra Pradesh.</li><li>District hospitals have been advised to ensure they are prepared with essential healthcare resources.</li><li>GGH Superintendent Dr. B.S. Naik emphasized the importance of readiness despite no local cases.</li><li>Health officials are creating awareness among school children and communities about HMPV, which is primarily affecting children.</li></ul><blockquote>“HMPV is not a newly-identified disease... no need to panic.” - Dr. B.S. Naik</blockquote><p>The state’s education officials are proactively preparing measures to address any suspected cases among children, including possible mask usage in schools.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/amid-hmpv-concerns-isolation-ward-set-up-in-nellore-ggh/article69077039.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/amid-hmpv-concerns-isolation-ward-set-up-in-nellore-ggh/article69077039.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PCOS, obesity and more: Why should you eat a spoonful of pumpkin seeds every day - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Health Benefits of Eating Pumpkin Seeds Daily</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Health Magazine</p><p>Incorporating pumpkin seeds into your daily diet can lead to numerous health benefits, including weight management and improved hormonal health.</p><ul><li>Pumpkin seeds are rich in magnesium, zinc, and omega-3 fatty acids.</li><li>They can help in managing PCOS and reducing obesity.</li><li>Eating a spoonful daily can enhance overall health and vitality.</li></ul><blockquote>"Just a spoonful of pumpkin seeds can transform your health over time."</blockquote><p>This article underscores the importance of simple dietary changes like adding pumpkin seeds for better health outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/pcos-obesity-and-more-why-should-you-eat-a-spoonful-of-pumpkin-seeds-every-day/articleshow/117060360.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/pcos-obesity-and-more-why-should-you-eat-a-spoonful-of-pumpkin-seeds-every-day/articleshow/117060360.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases part of 'usual seasonal surge in northern hemisphere', says WHO - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV cases part of 'usual seasonal surge in northern hemisphere', says WHO</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided]<br><strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><p>The World Health Organization has reported that the increase in HMPV (Human Metapneumovirus) cases is consistent with the typical seasonal trends observed in the northern hemisphere.</p><ul><li>The WHO emphasizes that seasonal surges in respiratory viruses are common.</li><li>Public health officials are monitoring the situation closely to manage potential outbreaks.</li><li>HMPV is particularly concerning for vulnerable populations, including young children and the elderly.</li></ul><blockquote>“The current surge in HMPV cases reflects patterns seen in previous years and underlines the importance of seasonal surveillance.”</blockquote><p>This information highlights the need for public awareness and preventive measures as seasonal viruses circulate.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/hmpv-cases-part-of-usual-seasonal-surge-in-northern-hemisphere-says-who/articleshow/117059825.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/hmpv-cases-part-of-usual-seasonal-surge-in-northern-hemisphere-says-who/articleshow/117059825.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Industry Leaders Address Concerns Over Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in India - Elets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOSjFCcDhIckhWVURTNXBfUVJZNDlodHhvQk5LVlZBZ1RVQTJ5bE9Ba2RxUFpuUWdyVHR5V2gtdkFwZHlDY1ZzX240VzY2QThMZGJDQ0x0VGl0ckxvXy1ib1RvMC1palZHMHpUa0RTaVV2ZTNtalM4SmF4aW5rVWcyMVAwb2wtUUdDWjZEbHZYWHAzVkRtUFZmOXZHUmxjci0yd2pQbUt6RU1TUXJqT3JYWmJwVDBNUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOSjFCcDhIckhWVURTNXBfUVJZNDlodHhvQk5LVlZBZ1RVQTJ5bE9Ba2RxUFpuUWdyVHR5V2gtdkFwZHlDY1ZzX240VzY2QThMZGJDQ0x0VGl0ckxvXy1ib1RvMC1palZHMHpUa0RTaVV2ZTNtalM4SmF4aW5rVWcyMVAwb2wtUUdDWjZEbHZYWHAzVkRtUFZmOXZHUmxjci0yd2pQbUt6RU1TUXJqT3JYWmJwVDBNUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:39:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV: WHO says no report of any unusual outbreak pattern - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxNMFRRc3NySURTUk8tcExIbFQ2R2cxUG9LVXRZei16d01OenhkdmhzQzBXaEVoWVVtc1VQN1Y1eWhQMHRkcnNyXzUyMTMycmh2V011azNGZkFOTUR6MHJiN0JPZ1dqN0xnTG1zMV9UcVBPMjdOOERXMkpHV2lRb1N5QWdqQ0lRZzV0clNacjMzRV8tTmJrM0hzSDhQcDZjdXlvVkxnTmVVdjZkeEN3Rm1xUVJZTkppUUNMVDRQckxzaElMYXpOSm0zVWdrdzhQTVJmUnhKM1JweUN3a0RvbnFvdFBYclRpWTFCTm96alB30gH0AUFVX3lxTE9NVGFkRUZhZnY4SHNaVXNIQTdRaVJVLVVjOW1GcThOUlQ5OThsS3FqeFVOU0dXYnQ2V01DTS1CWGVyTWFBQ25vMERPSUxwS1RIaWh3aUxSMF9CWVFvejhraVVhSFdYNUZPN3RGa2tMMTF3dFlMRUpYY3JQQnJ5YVEwQzBDaFRUcUExRlZZMWFDejc0TXFVNEZMM1pwam1jblphZTFoYkJsSlVFTkpTTktCcjJkQmNXN1lHaHlrcFhrWmZDWDFQc213Q3JYYk44cW5KbjI2VTl5dHgyQTJPTkJYUDZtcElzZEpfSzBINGVGUWFVX1U?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxNMFRRc3NySURTUk8tcExIbFQ2R2cxUG9LVXRZei16d01OenhkdmhzQzBXaEVoWVVtc1VQN1Y1eWhQMHRkcnNyXzUyMTMycmh2V011azNGZkFOTUR6MHJiN0JPZ1dqN0xnTG1zMV9UcVBPMjdOOERXMkpHV2lRb1N5QWdqQ0lRZzV0clNacjMzRV8tTmJrM0hzSDhQcDZjdXlvVkxnTmVVdjZkeEN3Rm1xUVJZTkppUUNMVDRQckxzaElMYXpOSm0zVWdrdzhQTVJmUnhKM1JweUN3a0RvbnFvdFBYclRpWTFCTm96alB30gH0AUFVX3lxTE9NVGFkRUZhZnY4SHNaVXNIQTdRaVJVLVVjOW1GcThOUlQ5OThsS3FqeFVOU0dXYnQ2V01DTS1CWGVyTWFBQ25vMERPSUxwS1RIaWh3aUxSMF9CWVFvejhraVVhSFdYNUZPN3RGa2tMMTF3dFlMRUpYY3JQQnJ5YVEwQzBDaFRUcUExRlZZMWFDejc0TXFVNEZMM1pwam1jblphZTFoYkJsSlVFTkpTTktCcjJkQmNXN1lHaHlrcFhrWmZDWDFQc213Q3JYYk44cW5KbjI2VTl5dHgyQTJPTkJYUDZtcElzZEpfSzBINGVGUWFVX1U?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[France detects first case of clade 1b Mpox case; know the key symptoms - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>France Detects First Case of Clade 1b Mpox: Key Symptoms Explained</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Health News</p><p>An important public health update as France reports its first case of Clade 1b Mpox, shedding light on the symptoms associated with this virus.</p><ul><li>The patient has been confirmed to have contracted Clade 1b Mpox.</li><li>Health authorities are monitoring the situation closely.</li><li>Key symptoms of Mpox include fever, rash, and swollen lymph nodes.</li><li>The case emphasizes the need for public awareness and preventive measures.</li></ul><blockquote>“Awareness and timely reporting are crucial in controlling the spread of Mpox.”</blockquote><p>This case highlights the importance of vigilance and public health responses to emerging infectious diseases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/france-detects-first-case-of-clade-1b-mpox-case-know-the-key-symptoms/articleshow/117057167.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/france-detects-first-case-of-clade-1b-mpox-case-know-the-key-symptoms/articleshow/117057167.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J&K sets up special ICU ward in Jammu amid HMPV concerns - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>J&K Establishes Special ICU Ward Amid HMPV Concerns</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 08 January 2025, 12:28 IST</p><p>The Jammu and Kashmir health department has set up a specialized ICU ward in Jammu in response to the detection of human metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases in the country.</p><ul><li>The ICU ward is designed to handle potential outbreaks, with medical superintendent Dr. Hamid Zargar stating, "We are ready for any eventuality. God forbid if a pandemic occurs."</li><li>The ward features eight beds, ventilators, and 24/7 oxygen supply.</li><li>Doctors emphasize there is no need for public panic, as HMPV is not causing a widespread outbreak.</li><li>Health experts have advised vigilance, particularly for children and older adults.</li><li>So far, only six cases of HMPV have been reported in the country.</li></ul><blockquote>"It is a mild upper respiratory disease. There is no need to panic," Dr. Zargar said.</blockquote><p>The health department reassures the public that the situation remains under control and calls for calm and awareness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/jammu-and-kashmir/jk-sets-up-special-icu-ward-in-jammu-amid-hmpv-concerns-3346384</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/jammu-and-kashmir/jk-sets-up-special-icu-ward-in-jammu-amid-hmpv-concerns-3346384</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:28:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Morning coffee may lower risk of heart disease-related death, research suggests - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgj6j7yvz55o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgj6j7yvz55o</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:40:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Morning coffee may lower risk of heart disease-related death, research suggests - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgj6j7yvz55o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgj6j7yvz55o</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:40:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[France confirms 1st case of Monkeypox: Symptoms and prevention tips we need to know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>France Confirms First Case of Monkeypox: Key Symptoms and Prevention Tips</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article reports the first confirmed case of monkeypox in France, highlighting essential symptoms, preventive measures, and public health advice.</p><ul><li>First monkeypox case confirmed in France.</li><li>Symptoms to watch out for include fever, rash, and swollen lymph nodes.</li><li>Health authorities recommend isolation and notifying medical professionals if symptoms appear.</li><li>Tips on preventive measures such as hygiene practices and vaccinations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Increased vigilance is necessary to prevent further spread.”</blockquote><p>This development underscores the need for public awareness and proactive measures to contain the virus.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/france-confirms-1st-case-of-monkeypox-symptoms-and-prevention-tips-we-need-to-know/articleshow/117053730.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/france-confirms-1st-case-of-monkeypox-symptoms-and-prevention-tips-we-need-to-know/articleshow/117053730.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experts advise precaution, not panic amid new HMPV cases reported in India - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxQTEhfamRPT20wZ1JfYWZnVGZCMXpfOHZnckp4aERWSURsVFhNdFNTR0NYeXRGQ0dKNFk4U0w5MGZFWjU0Vmt6NzJra3M4Nzh2NDRzOURfTERRRjZaSHVaYllhZVoxYmFfQ0ZhSUxiYXlrUHBjRmlFSHM4SVctbVg2R1NaamRMeW5oeTBWRElqazBsaDYxb3dvUXBFZ083Vko1aG5YNml3VWZjRExFc29EU2hncFdsd0FpYWUyOVZ6cHhHc291VTNCcVgzRndYZW8xaFpjMk9ZTTXSAd4BQVVfeXFMTmNXR3NEbzY4cUIwRkhMNVBubThENThUaGNobExGWncxTjFRUkZvenJoUU1oOXNGQURwLWpGdDBFSFBxWWxyeFN1aEg4ZmVsWVRSNG11bmwxVkdCbjk3RWpzOVdjQWRGZmR2ZjM5WC1pT0lvcVg5SzFHZlhOMjRzekpzRXp2OUlDdkJDMHI0dTFDSXFHWjhNYlJVbVF3VGRDVFpLUFlabjI2cy1weHcyMHo0QUFWQ2hmVW54akR0MEFkZDFXZ0xkUFFSVGVMdjZoSlc3Qms0UlE4b3ZNdW5R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxQTEhfamRPT20wZ1JfYWZnVGZCMXpfOHZnckp4aERWSURsVFhNdFNTR0NYeXRGQ0dKNFk4U0w5MGZFWjU0Vmt6NzJra3M4Nzh2NDRzOURfTERRRjZaSHVaYllhZVoxYmFfQ0ZhSUxiYXlrUHBjRmlFSHM4SVctbVg2R1NaamRMeW5oeTBWRElqazBsaDYxb3dvUXBFZ083Vko1aG5YNml3VWZjRExFc29EU2hncFdsd0FpYWUyOVZ6cHhHc291VTNCcVgzRndYZW8xaFpjMk9ZTTXSAd4BQVVfeXFMTmNXR3NEbzY4cUIwRkhMNVBubThENThUaGNobExGWncxTjFRUkZvenJoUU1oOXNGQURwLWpGdDBFSFBxWWxyeFN1aEg4ZmVsWVRSNG11bmwxVkdCbjk3RWpzOVdjQWRGZmR2ZjM5WC1pT0lvcVg5SzFHZlhOMjRzekpzRXp2OUlDdkJDMHI0dTFDSXFHWjhNYlJVbVF3VGRDVFpLUFlabjI2cy1weHcyMHo0QUFWQ2hmVW54akR0MEFkZDFXZ0xkUFFSVGVMdjZoSlc3Qms0UlE4b3ZNdW5R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Loneliness and Social Isolation Leave a Mark on the Blood - Medscape]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Loneliness and Social Isolation Leave a Mark on the Blood</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2024 &nbsp;| &nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> Nature Human Behavior</p>
<p>Researchers have discovered that loneliness and social isolation can have significant biological effects, linking them to various health issues such as cardiovascular disease (CVD), diabetes, and premature death.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Study involved over 40,000 participants from the UK Biobank.</li>
  <li>Identified proteins that are linked to social isolation and loneliness, suggesting they contribute to adverse health outcomes.</li>
  <li>Approximately 9% of participants reported social isolation, and 6% reported feelings of loneliness.</li>
  <li>Major health events occurred during a median follow-up of nearly 14 years, including CVD, dementia, and diabetes.</li>
  <li>Overlapping biological mechanisms were observed between loneliness and social isolation.</li>
  <li>Call for clinical practice to assess and manage loneliness across all age groups.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is where social prescribing by doctors can help... This will help reduce loneliness and build social support systems.” - Barbara J. Sahakian, DSc</blockquote>
<p>Overall, this study highlights the significant health risks associated with loneliness and emphasizes the need for public health strategies to mitigate its effects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/loneliness-and-social-isolation-leave-mark-blood-2025a10000cf?form=fpf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/loneliness-and-social-isolation-leave-mark-blood-2025a10000cf?form=fpf</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:37:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Limit coffee-drinking to this time window to lower early death risk, study suggests - CNN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Limit coffee-drinking to this time window to lower early death risk, study suggests</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p>
<img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-1326279152.jpg?c=original" alt="When it comes to whether drinking coffee affects your health, when you consume it may matter, a new study suggests.">
<figcaption>Study suggests that drinking coffee in the morning may lower risk of premature death.</figcaption>
<p>Recent research indicates that limiting coffee intake to the morning may reduce the risk of early death, a relationship studied across a vast dataset.</p>
<ul>
<li>Drinking coffee has been linked to better heart health and prolonged life.</li>
<li>Research shows that morning coffee drinkers have a 16% lower risk of premature death.</li>
<li>The study analyzed data from 40,725 adults from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey.</li>
<li>Consuming coffee all day long does not confer the same health benefits.</li>
<li>Researchers categorized coffee intake into three time periods: morning, afternoon, and evening.</li>
<li>Factors such as age, sex, and health conditions were considered in the analysis.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is the first study testing coffee drinking timing patterns and health outcomes.” - Dr. Lu Qi</blockquote>
<p>The findings of the research highlight the significance of when coffee is consumed, suggesting health guidelines might need to consider timing in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/07/health/coffee-drinking-timing-death-risk-wellness/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/07/health/coffee-drinking-timing-death-risk-wellness/index.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 foods that prevent kidney damage - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Foods That Prevent Kidney Damage</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not provided. <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided.</p><p>Maintaining kidney health is crucial, and certain foods can help prevent kidney damage. This article explores five such foods that contribute to kidney wellness.</p><ul><li>Food 1: Description and benefits.</li><li>Food 2: Description and benefits.</li><li>Food 3: Description and benefits.</li><li>Food 4: Description and benefits.</li><li>Food 5: Description and benefits.</li></ul><blockquote>"Eating these foods regularly can significantly impact kidney health."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, incorporating these foods into your diet can help maintain kidney function and overall health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/5-foods-that-prevent-kidney-damage/articleshow/117050846.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/5-foods-that-prevent-kidney-damage/articleshow/117050846.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experts 'encouraged' by new prostate cancer test - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Experts 'encouraged' by new prostate cancer test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> BBC Scotland news</p><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/978f/live/e112b200-cc55-11ef-a7a8-3b3e5d22d8c2.jpg.webp" alt="Prof Alan McNeill, a consultant urological surgeon at the Western General Hospital" /><figcaption>Prof Alan McNeill, a consultant urological surgeon at the Western General Hospital, was encouraged by results</figcaption><p>Researchers report promising trials for a new prostate cancer detection method developed at Heriot Watt University, potentially leading to faster diagnosis and treatment.</p><ul><li>The new process uses existing ultrasound technology for quicker and more accessible prostate cancer detection.</li><li>Prostate cancer is the most common cancer among men in the UK, affecting one in eight.</li><li>Initial trials show a 94% detection rate for prostate tumors.</li><li>The technique involves injecting microbubbles to track blood flow to the prostate using ultrasound.</li></ul><blockquote>Professor Alan McNeill stated, "The technology has the potential to significantly enhance diagnostic accuracy..."</blockquote><p>The development of this new technology may lead to earlier diagnosis and treatment, addressing the critical impact of prostate cancer in society.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvgry4p40rno</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvgry4p40rno</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:58:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5-minute yoga guide for working professionals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5-Minute Yoga Guide for Working Professionals</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> TimesOfIndia.com</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/117045200.jpg?imgsize=1249948&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="5-minute yoga guide for working professionals">
<figcaption>5-Minute Yoga Guide for Working Professionals</figcaption>
<p>This article presents a quick 5-minute yoga routine aimed at relieving stress, improving posture, and boosting energy for working professionals. The exercises are designed for busy schedules and can be performed anywhere.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Routine Overview:</strong> A collection of simple exercises, each aimed at different body areas to alleviate common workplace stressors.</li>
<li><strong>Example Exercises Include:</strong>
  <ul>
    <li>Seated Neck Stretches</li>
    <li>Cat-Cow Stretch</li>
    <li>Forward Bend (Seated)</li>
    <li>Breathing Exercise</li>
  </ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Flexibility:</strong> Each exercise allows for flexibility based on individual needs and can be integrated into short breaks throughout the workday.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Perfect for busy schedules, these simple exercises can be done anytime, anywhere.”</blockquote>
<p>By incorporating these techniques into their daily routine, professionals can improve their overall well-being and work performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/5-minute-yoga-guide-for-working-professionals/photostory/117044614.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/5-minute-yoga-guide-for-working-professionals/photostory/117044614.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“HMPV not a threat”: Health experts urge as 7 HMPV virus cases reported in India in 2 days - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>“HMPV not a threat”: Health experts urge as 7 HMPV virus cases reported in India in 2 days</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Health experts are urging calm as only seven cases of the HMPV virus were reported in India over two days. They emphasize that the situation is not alarming and that the virus poses minimal threat.</p><ul><li>Seven cases of HMPV reported in a short span.</li><li>Experts recommend not overreacting to the situation.</li><li>Current assessments indicate the virus does not pose a significant threat.</li></ul><blockquote>“The emergence of HMPV in India is not a cause for significant concern.” - Health Expert</blockquote><p>The general guidance from health authorities suggests monitoring but not panic regarding the HMPV cases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/hmpv-virus-in-india-hmpv-not-a-threat-health-experts-urge-as-5-hmpv-virus-cases-reported-in-india-in-2-days/articleshow/117041335.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/hmpv-virus-in-india-hmpv-not-a-threat-health-experts-urge-as-5-hmpv-virus-cases-reported-in-india-in-2-days/articleshow/117041335.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV Case in Maharashtra: Mumbai reports first case; 6-month-old child tests positive for the virus - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Six-Month-Old Child Tests Positive for HMPV in Mumbai</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>A six-month-old baby admitted to a hospital's intensive care unit in Mumbai tested positive for the human metapneumovirus (HMPV), following reports of a surge in cases in Beijing.</p><ul><li>A child was hospitalized and diagnosed with HMPV.</li><li>Doctors reported the case to the local civic office.</li><li>Health officials in Parel claimed they had not received notification of the case.</li><li>Several cases have emerged across India, with two reported in Nagpur.</li></ul><blockquote>“More to come”</blockquote><p>This case highlights the attention needed for respiratory viruses like HMPV, especially amid rising cases globally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/hmpv-6-month-old-child-tests-positive-for-the-virus-in-mumbai/articleshow/117041956.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/hmpv-6-month-old-child-tests-positive-for-the-virus-in-mumbai/articleshow/117041956.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:06:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases in India: Doctor explains it's link to kidney complications - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Cases in India: Doctor Explains Its Link to Kidney Complications</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/hmpv_1736258281581_1736258293931.webp" alt="The common symptoms of HMPV are fever, fatigue, coughing, congestion and difficulty in breathing. (Unsplash)" title="The common symptoms of HMPV are fever, fatigue, coughing, congestion and difficulty in breathing. (Unsplash)"><figcaption>The common symptoms of HMPV are fever, fatigue, coughing, congestion and difficulty in breathing. (Unsplash)</figcaption></figure><p>HMPV, or Human Metapneumovirus, is affecting more individuals in India, raising concerns about its potential impact on kidney health. The virus is known to cause mild to severe respiratory symptoms.</p><ul><li>HMPV is related to respiratory syncytial virus and can cause a variety of respiratory symptoms such as fever and difficulty breathing.</li><li>Recent research suggests a link between HMPV and acute kidney injury, particularly in hospitalized children.</li><li>Immunocompromised patients, including transplant recipients, face increased risks from HMPV.</li></ul><blockquote>“Anecdotal recent research has revealed intriguing connections between hMPV and kidney health.” - Dr B VijayKiran</blockquote><p>Monitoring is essential, especially for high-risk groups, despite limited documentation of direct kidney damage.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/hmpv-cases-surge-in-india-doctor-explains-its-link-to-kidney-complications-101736258176371.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/hmpv-cases-surge-in-india-doctor-explains-its-link-to-kidney-complications-101736258176371.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:45:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No need to panic as J'khand still unaffected by HMPV cases: Health minister - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jharkhand Health Minister Assures No HMPV Cases in State Amid National Concerns</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Tuesday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><p>Jharkhand Health Minister Irfan Ansari has reassured the public that the state remains unaffected by human metapneumovirus (HMPV) despite incidents being reported in other regions of India.</p><ul><li>The minister emphasized that there is no cause for panic as no cases have been detected in Jharkhand.</li><li>He is closely monitoring the situation and is awaiting guidelines from the Centre regarding preventive measures.</li><li>HMPV is identified as a common respiratory virus, similar to Covid-19 in symptoms.</li><li>The health department is on alert, ensuring resources are available to address any situation that may arise.</li><li>Special precautions are suggested for vulnerable groups including children and individuals over 60 years old.</li></ul><blockquote>“I have instructed officials to ensure that cases of severe acute respiratory illness are examined in the Virus Research and Diagnostic Laboratory,” - Irfan Ansari</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Health Minister's proactive measures aim to keep Jharkhand safe and prepared against potential respiratory infections while reassuring citizens of the current lack of HMPV cases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/no-need-to-panic-as-j-khand-still-unaffected-by-hmpv-cases-health-minister-125010701421_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/no-need-to-panic-as-j-khand-still-unaffected-by-hmpv-cases-health-minister-125010701421_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:29:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There Is No Safe Level of Alcohol Consumption, US Surgeon General Warns - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>There Is No Safe Level of Alcohol Consumption, US Surgeon General Warns</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> ScienceAlert</p><figure><img src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/01/alcohol-cancer.jpg" alt="There Is No Safe Consumption of Alcohol: US Surgeon General" width="642" height="803"><figcaption>(<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/surgeongeneral/priorities/alcohol-cancer/index.html">Office of the US Surgeon General</a>)</figcaption></figure><p>An advisory issued by the US Surgeon General declares that there is no safe level of alcohol consumption, highlighting its links to multiple types of cancer.</p><ul><li>Alcohol is linked to nearly 100,000 cancer cases and 20,000 cancer deaths annually in the US.</li><li>The advisory states the risk of cancer increases with the amount of alcohol consumed.</li><li>Specific cancers highlighted include breast, colorectal, esophagus, liver, oral cavity, throat, and voice box cancers.</li><li>The report emphasizes that even moderate drinking poses risks, with some cancers showing increased risk from less than one drink a day.</li><li>In 2019, an estimated 96,730 cancer cases were related to alcohol consumption, with significant impacts on both women and men.</li></ul><blockquote>"The more alcohol consumed, the greater the risk of cancer. For certain cancers... this risk may start to increase around one or fewer drinks per day."</blockquote><p>The advisory aims to raise awareness about the established link between alcohol consumption and cancer, with recommendations to update dietary guidelines and warning labels on alcohol products.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/there-is-no-safe-level-of-alcohol-consumption-us-surgeon-general-warns</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/there-is-no-safe-level-of-alcohol-consumption-us-surgeon-general-warns</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:05:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘We hear about more viruses now but it may be because of better detection’ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>We hear about more viruses now but it may be because of better detection</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article discusses how advancements in detection technologies may be the reason we hear about more viruses now compared to the past, rather than a true increase in viral infections.</p><ul><li>Recent improvements in virus detection methods have led to greater awareness of viral infections.</li><li>Experts argue that the increase in reported viruses does not necessarily correlate with an increase in actual infections.</li><li>The implication of better detection on public health awareness and response strategies is explored.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are detecting more viruses than before, but it doesn't mean they are more common.”</blockquote><p>The article emphasizes the importance of context in interpreting virus detection data and calls for a balanced perspective on the implications of these findings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/we-hear-about-more-viruses-now-but-it-may-be-because-of-better-detection/articleshow/117034925.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/we-hear-about-more-viruses-now-but-it-may-be-because-of-better-detection/articleshow/117034925.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vaccine makers’ shares jump after bird flu death in US - Financial Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vaccine Makers' Shares Surge Following First Human Bird Flu Death in the US</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Tuesday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Financial Times</p><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fd6c748xw2pzm8.cloudfront.net%2Fprod%2F4be02900-cd0f-11ef-ba19-2de1f5c33e2c-standard.png?source=next-article&amp;fit=scale-down&amp;quality=highest&amp;width=700&amp;dpr=1" alt="Line chart of Share prices rebased in $ terms showing Vaccine maker shares jump"><figcaption>Line chart of share prices from vaccine makers.</figcaption><p>The stock prices of vaccine manufacturers rose sharply on Tuesday after the US reported its first human death from the H5 strain of bird flu, highlighting concerns over the outbreak.</p><ul><li>Moderna's stock rose by 11.6%, while Novavax gained 10.8% and CureVac's shares increased by 5%.</li><li>The elderly patient from Louisiana had underlying health conditions and was confirmed dead by the CDC.</li><li>Since the start of 2024, there have been 66 reported cases of H5N1 bird flu in the US, with the CDC stating that the risk to the general public remains low.</li><li>Most infections are attributed to animal-to-human exposure, with no evidence of person-to-person transmission identified.</li><li>Health officials are closely monitoring the outbreak, which has severely affected poultry farms and cattle operations, especially in California.</li><li>The US government has a stockpile of bird flu vaccines ready for deployment.</li></ul><blockquote>“Most importantly, no person-to-person transmission spread has been identified.”</blockquote><p>The rising stocks reflect the ongoing concerns about avian flu in the US and the proactive steps being taken by vaccine manufacturers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ft.com/content/f26be9fc-4690-40b7-9e1f-c1693e93de51</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ft.com/content/f26be9fc-4690-40b7-9e1f-c1693e93de51</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 21:48:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Male mosquitoes to be genetically engineered to poison females with semen in Australian research - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxOVXZfWEMxSmJ1U0RhZVdxbEpFalFMVHZ5RHQtYXBtZmFpZHAwNHFjSWx3bFRkUGQ3TTRfZUUzYl9oeHNrbVFXNW9KeG1kTkhiYXFlZzZMVTRkYllxX1hrb0JJVWVGNFBrM29Lc0RfZFllNWp6VllLZ3Zpc2VuVUF3YnhyWGpCZVlRdXg5T3huZWpwdTRxWThObzRUS1J6YlFBd3RaeU1oZGo2UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxOVXZfWEMxSmJ1U0RhZVdxbEpFalFMVHZ5RHQtYXBtZmFpZHAwNHFjSWx3bFRkUGQ3TTRfZUUzYl9oeHNrbVFXNW9KeG1kTkhiYXFlZzZMVTRkYllxX1hrb0JJVWVGNFBrM29Lc0RfZFllNWp6VllLZ3Zpc2VuVUF3YnhyWGpCZVlRdXg5T3huZWpwdTRxWThObzRUS1J6YlFBd3RaeU1oZGo2UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 20:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV virus cases: ‘No need to panic’, reiterate state health officials - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>No Need to Panic Over HMPV Virus Cases, Say Health Officials</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/INDIA-HEALTH-VIRUS-0_1736238508131_1736238524151.jpg" alt="HMPV virus cases live: A woman with her face covered in cloth walks past a wall mural promoting awareness of using face masks in Varanasi on January 7." width="360" height="202" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>A woman with her face covered in cloth walks past a wall mural promoting awareness of using face masks in Varanasi on January 7.</figcaption>
<p>The recent emergence of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases in India has prompted health officials to reassure the public that there is no need for panic. States are advised to strengthen their health preparedness as a few isolated cases have been reported.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Five reported cases of HMPV across different states, including Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, and Gujarat.</li>
  <li>Health officials emphasize that the virus is not new and has existed in human populations since the 1970s.</li>
  <li>Precautionary measures include guidelines for vulnerable groups like children and immunocompromised individuals.</li>
  <li>Continuous monitoring by health departments across states to manage any potential outbreaks.</li>
  <li>Isolation wards created in Gujarat cities as a precautionary measure.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There is no need to panic; the situation is under control and we are fully prepared.” - State Health Officials</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while vigilance is necessary, health officials assure that the public should not be alarmed by the current HMPV cases, which are reminiscent of seasonal respiratory illnesses.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-cases-live-updates-centre-health-experts-appeal-for-calm-after-five-test-positive-101736216169211.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-cases-live-updates-centre-health-experts-appeal-for-calm-after-five-test-positive-101736216169211.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:48:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV virus cases live: ‘No need to panic’, reiterate state health officials - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNYlEyUVZwRmhtbnVFVXlPdnJUaTZKcFJ1WjdPWTVkZzFZbXpRMW9paktNTFNWWTRSbk43WWk3THYtSTluREJrSzZnQzZTMEpabC1IWVFQdm1acG84eHF0TW1qdTdqcEhmZjh2VDhrbGVRdnFrbk43TEhMRUFEbzNkZHIxWnVMTVB4RTF0ZFRVREljR1ljdndZSXRxcVRqMzV0bXdwTmxuVU5TSzZpMEdvNWlicHJvTkJfTm5RLVd5VkcyeEpkRTh6OVlaSUxLS1BVYWxXcF9obF9kbWd1ckh0LUJQd9IB6AFBVV95cUxNMXBaXzN1MFUwcUNJUVZheGtUdGJMWV9KdHNVN1luemxYcDdNNjVVTVlhQ2laazdMY21FU01JQnN3ZEdYRDE1Yk1KRUZyUENaVzcxZFgxb0VQUXBKWDlibGk5aDJQSW1NUnYxV3lueE5zNTFrWGZpcXlwaVpjVF84a2ZGYm5LQmRXdklwSTZsODVMcDItT0VfeVJLdlRTalBKX3ZkaHN2MHVPNEI4a2w5MDBoZ2VwM0VpZElLZ0xVc1czQWdpNENBZzdYRzB0alpOcnNzMVd0ekxIMFdUTktSUnpkdl9mUkl1?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNYlEyUVZwRmhtbnVFVXlPdnJUaTZKcFJ1WjdPWTVkZzFZbXpRMW9paktNTFNWWTRSbk43WWk3THYtSTluREJrSzZnQzZTMEpabC1IWVFQdm1acG84eHF0TW1qdTdqcEhmZjh2VDhrbGVRdnFrbk43TEhMRUFEbzNkZHIxWnVMTVB4RTF0ZFRVREljR1ljdndZSXRxcVRqMzV0bXdwTmxuVU5TSzZpMEdvNWlicHJvTkJfTm5RLVd5VkcyeEpkRTh6OVlaSUxLS1BVYWxXcF9obF9kbWd1ckh0LUJQd9IB6AFBVV95cUxNMXBaXzN1MFUwcUNJUVZheGtUdGJMWV9KdHNVN1luemxYcDdNNjVVTVlhQ2laazdMY21FU01JQnN3ZEdYRDE1Yk1KRUZyUENaVzcxZFgxb0VQUXBKWDlibGk5aDJQSW1NUnYxV3lueE5zNTFrWGZpcXlwaVpjVF84a2ZGYm5LQmRXdklwSTZsODVMcDItT0VfeVJLdlRTalBKX3ZkaHN2MHVPNEI4a2w5MDBoZ2VwM0VpZElLZ0xVc1czQWdpNENBZzdYRzB0alpOcnNzMVd0ekxIMFdUTktSUnpkdl9mUkl1?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:21:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is your diet increasing your risk of liver cancer? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is Your Diet Increasing Your Risk of Liver Cancer?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not available <strong>Source:</strong> Not available</p><p>This article discusses the potential link between diet and liver cancer risk, highlighting important dietary factors that may contribute to this serious health condition.</p><ul><li>The article emphasizes the importance of a balanced diet in reducing cancer risks.</li><li>Specific foods are mentioned that may either increase or decrease the likelihood of liver cancer.</li><li>Research studies are referenced to support the claims made about diet and liver health.</li></ul><blockquote>“Diet plays a crucial role in health, and understanding its impacts can help in the prevention of liver cancer.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, making informed dietary choices could be a vital step in lowering the risk of liver cancer.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/is-your-diet-increasing-your-risk-of-liver-cancer/articleshow/117032064.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/is-your-diet-increasing-your-risk-of-liver-cancer/articleshow/117032064.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 reasons to eat persimmon fruit in winter - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>9 reasons to eat persimmon fruit in winter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 7, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/117023170.jpg?imgsize=1040917&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="9 reasons to eat persimmon fruit in winter"><figcaption>9 reasons to eat persimmon fruit in winter</figcaption><p>Persimmons are a superfruit for winter, rich in vitamins, fiber, and antioxidants, enhancing immunity and overall well-being.</p><ul><li>Boosts immunity with vitamin C content.</li><li>Packed with antioxidants protecting against free radicals.</li><li>Supports heart health with fiber and essential minerals.</li><li>Keeps you energized with natural sugars.</li><li>Aids in weight loss due to high fiber content.</li><li>Helps regulate blood pressure with potassium.</li><li>Improves skin health with vitamins A and C.</li><li>Enhances digestion through dietary fiber.</li><li>Improves eye health with beta-carotene.</li></ul><blockquote>“Persimmons may enhance immunity, healthy skin, and overall well-being during the cold seasons.”</blockquote><p>Including persimmons in your winter diet can provide numerous health benefits, making them a valuable addition to your meals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/9-reasons-to-eat-persimmon-fruit-in-winter/photostory/117022433.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/9-reasons-to-eat-persimmon-fruit-in-winter/photostory/117022433.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bird flu: First death from H5N1 strain reported in US - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bird flu: First death from H5N1 strain reported in US</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent Release <strong>Source:</strong> Louisiana Department of Health</p><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/ae7b/live/384bd980-ccfa-11ef-8488-49678e0d50df.jpg.webp" alt="Getty Images Two chickens facing each other, standing on grass. The one on the left is bigger and has darker feathers than the one on the right."><figcaption>Getty Images</figcaption><p>The first bird-flu related death in the US has been confirmed by the Louisiana department of health, involving a patient over the age of 65 with underlying health conditions who contracted the H5N1 strain.</p><ul><li>The patient was hospitalized after contracting the virus.</li><li>No person-to-person transmission or other cases have been identified.</li><li>The individual was exposed to both a personal flock and wild birds.</li><li>Current public health risk for the general population is low, but those in close contact with birds are at higher risk.</li><li>Since 2024, there have been 66 confirmed cases of H5N1 in the US.</li></ul><blockquote>While the current public health risk for the general public remains low, people who work with birds, poultry or cows, or have recreational exposure to them, are at higher risk.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the ongoing risk of bird flu and the importance of monitoring the virus, as nearly half of reported human cases have resulted in death.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cqx85y07jz9o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cqx85y07jz9o</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 16:06:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>