<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 20:21:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 20:21:08 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Strict isolation, proper documentation': Delhi health officials issue advisory to tackle HMPV outbreak - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Issues Advisory to Combat HMPV Outbreak</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>The Delhi health officials have released a new advisory aimed at tackling the outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) which has been affecting multiple individuals.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Health authorities emphasize strict isolation protocols for those infected.</li>
  <li>Proper documentation and reporting of HMPV cases are mandated.</li>
  <li>The advisory aims to prevent further spread of the virus.</li>
  <li>Officials recommend public awareness campaigns to educate citizens on symptoms and prevention methods.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Timely isolation and thorough documentation can significantly curb the outbreak.” - Delhi Health Official</blockquote>
<p>This advisory is a proactive measure to ensure public health safety amid growing concerns regarding the HMPV virus.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/strict-isolation-proper-documentation-delhi-health-officials-issues-advisory-to-tackle-hmpv-outbreak/articleshow/116970919.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/strict-isolation-proper-documentation-delhi-health-officials-issues-advisory-to-tackle-hmpv-outbreak/articleshow/116970919.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 17:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Strict isolation, proper documentation': Delhi health officials issues advisory to tackle HMPV outbreak - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Health Officials Issue Advisory to Tackle HMPV Outbreak</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 20, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="HMPV outbreak image"><figcaption>Delhi's health response to HMPV.</figcaption><p>Health officials in Delhi have issued a new advisory to combat the recent outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), urging strict isolation and proper documentation of cases to curb the spread.</p><ul><li>HMPV poses a significant risk especially to infants and elderly individuals.</li><li>Health officials recommend enhanced surveillance and early reporting of symptoms.</li><li>Public awareness campaigns will be launched to educate citizens about HMPV.</li><li>The advisory includes guidelines for patients, healthcare providers, and emergency services.</li></ul><blockquote>“Prompt reporting and isolation are crucial in managing this outbreak,” advised a senior health official.</blockquote><p>The swift response aims to mitigate the impact of HMPV in the capital, ensuring community health safeguards are prioritized.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/strict-isolation-proper-documentation-delhi-health-officials-issues-advisory-to-tackle-hmpv-outbreak/articleshow/116970919.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/strict-isolation-proper-documentation-delhi-health-officials-issues-advisory-to-tackle-hmpv-outbreak/articleshow/116970919.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 17:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quarantine animals infected by bird flu, Centre tells States after tiger, leopard deaths in Nagpur - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Quarantine animals infected by bird flu, Centre tells States after tiger, leopard deaths in Nagpur</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/c3hd93/article69065776.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/11073_3_7_2024_23_22_17_5_4TVAL9_SPOTLIGHT.JPG" alt="Image for representation" title="Image for representation"><figcaption>Image for representation. | Photo Credit: The Hindu</figcaption><p>With the first case of avian influenza reported in Maharashtra, the Union Animal Husbandry Ministry is urging states to quarantine infected cats to prevent disease transmission.</p><ul><li>Three tigers and one leopard died from H5N1 virus at a Nagpur rescue centre.</li><li>Union Animal Husbandry Commissioner confirmed it as the first reported case of bird flu in animals in India.</li><li>The ministry is investigating potential causes, including chicken meat consumption.</li><li>A biosecurity protocol has been established for affected establishments.</li><li>Zoo staff must be equipped with personal protective equipment and follow health monitoring.</li></ul><blockquote>“The situation demands urgent attention to mitigate risks to both animal and human health.”</blockquote><p>The outbreak of bird flu in animals poses a significant risk and warrants immediate measures to ensure the safety of both wildlife and human populations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/quarantine-animals-infected-by-bird-flu-centre-tells-states-after-tiger-leopard-deaths-in-nagpur/article69065397.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/quarantine-animals-infected-by-bird-flu-centre-tells-states-after-tiger-leopard-deaths-in-nagpur/article69065397.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 17:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viral footage from China raises red flags: Could HMPV be spreading to India? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Viral Footage from China Raises Concerns About HMPV Spread to India</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>China is seeing a rise in cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), prompting increased screening measures. Despite alarming social media reports, health authorities reassure the public that there is no cause for alarm.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>HMPV is a respiratory virus causing mild cold-like symptoms but can be severe in vulnerable populations.</li><li>Chinese health officials report rising cases, particularly among children in northern regions.</li><li>No cases of HMPV have been reported in India thus far.</li><li>Health authorities in India are monitoring the situation and stress that there is no alarm.</li></ul><blockquote>“Metapneumovirus is like any other respiratory virus that causes the common cold,” – Dr. Atul Goel, Director-General of Health Services in India.</blockquote><p>Overall, while the rise of cases in China has raised concerns, health officials in both China and India are working to reassure the public and maintain preparedness as HMPV is typically seasonal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/new-updates/viral-footage-from-china-raises-red-flags-could-hmpv-be-spreading-to-india/articleshow/116969179.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/new-updates/viral-footage-from-china-raises-red-flags-could-hmpv-be-spreading-to-india/articleshow/116969179.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:38:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The happiness diet: Foods that boost your mood this winter - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Happiness Diet: Foods That Boost Your Mood This Winter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>As winter approaches, many people experience mood changes. This article explores various foods that can enhance mood and provide emotional support during the winter months.</p><ul><li>Introduction of foods that increase serotonin levels.</li><li>Recommendation of omega-3 fatty acid-rich foods.</li><li>Importance of vitamins and minerals in diet for mental health.</li><li>Suggestions for incorporating these foods into daily meals.</li></ul><blockquote>"Eating the right foods can significantly impact your mood and well-being during the colder months."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, adjusting your diet by including mood-boosting foods can lead to a better winter experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/the-happiness-diet-foods-that-boost-your-mood-this-winter/articleshow/116968098.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/the-happiness-diet-foods-that-boost-your-mood-this-winter/articleshow/116968098.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There are no HMPV cases in Andhra Pradesh, says Director of Public Health - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>No HMPV Cases in Andhra Pradesh, Says Public Health Director</h1><p><strong>Published on January 05, 2025 by IST</strong></p><p>Dr. K. Padmavathi, Director of Public Health, confirmed that there are currently no Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases in Andhra Pradesh and advised against panic over its spread.</p><ul><li>The virus spreads similarly to Coronavirus, primarily affecting children, the elderly, and those with low immunity.</li><li>Symptoms resemble a common cold and may include cough, runny nose, and respiratory issues.</li><li>Precautions similar to those during COVID-19 are recommended, including self-isolation for symptomatic individuals.</li><li>There is no specific antiviral treatment currently available for HMPV.</li></ul><blockquote>“The virus spreads through droplets expelled by coughing or sneezing, close contact, handshakes, and touching surfaces.” - Dr. K. Padmavathi</blockquote><p>Supportive care is important for those affected as government hospitals are prepared to treat those severely impacted.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/there-are-no-hmpv-cases-in-andhra-pradesh-says-director-of-public-health/article69064929.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/there-are-no-hmpv-cases-in-andhra-pradesh-says-director-of-public-health/article69064929.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After China, HMPV cases now rise in Malaysia; public asked to remain vigilant | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After China, HMPV cases now rise in Malaysia; public asked to remain vigilant</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Malaysia has seen a significant rise in human metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases, urging the public to remain vigilant.</p><ul><li>327 HMPV cases reported in 2024, a 45% increase from 2023.</li><li>Authorities stress the importance of sanitary practices such as hand washing and wearing masks.</li><li>China has also experienced a surge in respiratory illnesses, but officials describe it as a seasonal occurrence.</li><li>Indian health authorities are monitoring the situation without alarm.</li><li>HMPV is a common respiratory virus, generally causing mild flu-like symptoms in specific age groups.</li></ul><blockquote>“Metapneumovirus is like any other respiratory virus that causes common cold, and in very old and very young it could cause flu-like symptoms.”</blockquote><p>Authorities recommend that the public stay informed while noting that seasonal spikes in respiratory infections are expected.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/after-china-hmpv-cases-now-rise-in-malaysia-public-asked-to-remain-vigilant-11736085898495.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/after-china-hmpv-cases-now-rise-in-malaysia-public-asked-to-remain-vigilant-11736085898495.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why do women binge drink when estrogen surges? Study explains - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why do women binge drink when estrogen surges? Study explains</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article explores the phenomenon of binge drinking among women during periods of estrogen surges, revealing key insights and findings from recent studies on the subject.</p><ul><li>The study examines hormonal effects on women's drinking behaviors.</li><li>Research highlights the connection between estrogen levels and increased alcohol consumption.</li><li>Experts discuss implications for health and social norms regarding women's drinking habits.</li></ul><blockquote>"Understanding these hormonal influences can lead to better health strategies for women."</blockquote><p>This study sheds light on a crucial aspect of women's health, emphasizing the need for awareness and tailored approaches in tackling binge drinking in women.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-do-women-binge-drink-when-estrogen-surges-study-explains/articleshow/116967047.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-do-women-binge-drink-when-estrogen-surges-study-explains/articleshow/116967047.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Even small amounts of alcohol can cause cancer, bottles should have warning: US Surgeon General - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Surgeon General Calls for Cancer Warning Labels on Alcoholic Beverages</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/USA-HEALTH-ALCOHOL-POLITICS-1_1736081540893_1736081735750.JPG" alt="Vivek Murthy said that alcohol is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the US.(Reuters File)" title="Vivek Murthy said that alcohol is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the US.(Reuters File)">
  <figcaption>Vivek Murthy said that alcohol is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the US.(Reuters File)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The US Surgeon General, Dr. Vivek Murthy, has recommended that alcoholic beverages carry warning labels due to their link to cancer, highlighting the risks even from moderate drinking.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The advisory emphasizes that alcohol is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the US.</li>
  <li>Approximately 20,000 cancer-related deaths annually are attributed to alcohol, with 17% from those who drink within recommended limits.</li>
  <li>Less than half of Americans are aware of the alcohol-cancer connection.</li>
  <li>Alcohol consumption is linked to at least seven types of cancer.</li>
  <li>The call for warning labels has received mixed reactions from health organizations and industry representatives.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“What we know with a high degree of confidence is that there is a causal link between alcohol and cancer risk. The data has been building for some time and getting stronger and stronger.” - Dr. Vivek Murthy</blockquote>
<p>The Surgeon General's advisory on warning labels seeks to enhance public awareness about the health risks associated with alcohol, targeting a product widely consumed in the US.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/even-small-amounts-of-alcohol-can-cause-cancer-bottles-should-have-warning-us-surgeon-general-vivek-murthy-101736081334080.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/even-small-amounts-of-alcohol-can-cause-cancer-bottles-should-have-warning-us-surgeon-general-vivek-murthy-101736081334080.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 12:59:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tiruchi Corporation ramps up mosquito control measures to prevent spread of dengue and other fever cases - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tiruchi Corporation ramps up mosquito control measures to prevent spread of dengue and other fever cases</h1><p><strong>Published on: January 05, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/cities/Tiruchirapalli/r4fu40/article69064673.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/1736079740782.jpg" alt="A sanitation worker sprays mosquito repentant on a storm water drain on Moolaikollai Street in Tiruchi." title="A sanitation worker sprays mosquito repentant on a storm water drain on Moolaikollai Street in Tiruchi."><figcaption>A sanitation worker sprays mosquito repentant on a storm water drain on Moolaikollai Street in Tiruchi. | Photo Credit: SPECIAL ARRANGEMENT</figcaption><p>Tiruchi Corporation has initiated a special drive to prevent dengue and fever cases following the monsoon season in the city.</p><ul><li>A special team of 50 sanitation workers is engaged in spraying insecticides to control mosquito breeding.</li><li>Innovative methods such as 'oil balls' are being utilized to suffocate mosquito larvae in stagnant water.</li><li>Anti-mosquito fogging is being conducted throughout all 65 wards in the city.</li><li>Multiple fever camps are operational to track and manage fever cases across the urban health centres.</li></ul><blockquote>“The ongoing anti-dengue drive will gradually be intensified,” said M. Vijay Chandran, City Health Officer.</blockquote><p>Currently, Tiruchi has not experienced a surge in fever cases, indicating the effectiveness of the current measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Tiruchirapalli/tiruchi-corporation-ramps-up-mosquito-control-measures-to-prevent-spread-of-dengue-and-other-fever-cases/article69064711.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Tiruchirapalli/tiruchi-corporation-ramps-up-mosquito-control-measures-to-prevent-spread-of-dengue-and-other-fever-cases/article69064711.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 12:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adequate calcium intake, exercise crucial for young adults to prevent osteoporosis, say experts - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Experts Stress Importance of Calcium and Exercise for Young Adults to Prevent Osteoporosis</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 05, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/mpr62n/article69064769.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_Germany_Daily_Life_2_1_I0DEJP03.jpg" alt="The session was part of the ‘Healthy India, Happy India’ initiative aimed at promoting health and wellness nationwide." />
<figcaption>The session was part of the ‘Healthy India, Happy India’ initiative aimed at promoting health and wellness nationwide. | Photo Credit: AP</figcaption>
<p>The recent webinar on osteoporosis highlighted the critical role of adequate calcium intake and regular exercise in preventing bone loss among young adults.</p>
<ul>
<li>Experts emphasized the need for adequate calcium intake and regular physical activity to prevent osteoporosis.</li>
<li>The session was organized by Naruvi Hospitals and <i>The Hindu</i> as part of the 'Healthy India, Happy India' initiative.</li>
<li>Key speakers included endocrinologists from Naruvi Hospitals and Sri Ramachandra Institute.</li>
<li>Osteoporosis increases fracture risk significantly; it is crucial for young adults to build strong bones.</li>
<li>Common risk factors include low body weight, smoking, excessive alcohol consumption, and low physical activity.</li>
<li>Young adults should prioritize dairy intake and outdoor activities for bone health.</li>
<li>Hormone therapy options were discussed for menopausal women concerning osteoporosis treatment.</li>
<li>The webinar is available for viewing on YouTube.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Unfortunately, modern lifestyles, with academic pressures and increased screen time, often limit calcium intake and physical activity, making supplements necessary in some cases.” - Dr. Seshadri</blockquote>
<p>The importance of proactive measures in young adulthood to prevent osteoporosis was underscored as a critical health issue.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/adequate-calcium-intake-and-exercise-crucial-for-young-adults-to-prevent-osteoporosis-say-experts/article69064347.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/health/adequate-calcium-intake-and-exercise-crucial-for-young-adults-to-prevent-osteoporosis-say-experts/article69064347.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 12:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyderabad’s famous doctor says HMPV is not a novel virus, eases fears about China outbreak - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hyderabad Doctor Addresses HMPV Concerns Amid China Outbreak</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Chronicle</p><p>In the context of rising concerns over a Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) outbreak in China, Dr. Ranga Reddy Burri reassures that HMPV is not a novel virus and emphasizes its typical mild impact.</p><ul><li>HMPV primarily leads to flu-like symptoms lasting 2-5 days.</li><li>It can cause severe respiratory illness in vulnerable populations.</li><li>No cases of HMPV reported in India thus far.</li><li>Many circulating reports are sensationalized and lack a scientific basis.</li><li>Healthcare professionals are equipped to manage HMPV cases.</li></ul><blockquote>“Most cases of HMPV are mild, but the virus can cause severe respiratory illness.” - Dr. Ranga Reddy Burri</blockquote><p>Dr. Burri, the president of the Infection Control Academy of India, is an experienced physician known for his involvement in healthcare education and management.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/hyderabads-famous-doctor-says-hmpv-is-not-a-novel-virus-eases-fears-about-china-outbreak/articleshow/116965998.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/hyderabads-famous-doctor-says-hmpv-is-not-a-novel-virus-eases-fears-about-china-outbreak/articleshow/116965998.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 12:44:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[H5N1 Kills 3 Tigers, 1 Leopard at Nagpur Animal Rescue Centre. Bird Flu Red Alert Across Maharashtra Zoos - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQLXhBSF9CVEkyTVZGajJWYU01SUZKckJTQWstSDJBSnM3RGRlenRTemdFV3hlMzZLcGhJaG1IQi1JTW1PemZDclJoM2w4MUstV2FwbEdHOGkteHBQVjNtTHFfQWpOWW1iamVFYzR3WDVjN2p3Tkt5RXlGLVBDdE9OTGN4YnZxUU1QWVdXZ2JlUHFrNmJ4bm9wUlV1WVdCR3Vha3lGWGxB0gGrAUFVX3lxTE44VXVYQnNZd3l2NnpsQTU0eGktbXpyR01nTzlPazdOTDRkOFZ4VWVWbXJEZTVCOVRBNy1IeTNmNzByZDEzT0F3VjloWTlrMHRHQ0hhTHJCS2hscTN6cGJvd1lHT2JYSGtlazFGRkdodHNYQU5PQ2FrMnpkaUhlV2NnSmdIWDdWbDlJNlEwaWNUNmtGbjhLb3Q4VlpfLTdlUVpkdVE3SmUxQnF1bw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQLXhBSF9CVEkyTVZGajJWYU01SUZKckJTQWstSDJBSnM3RGRlenRTemdFV3hlMzZLcGhJaG1IQi1JTW1PemZDclJoM2w4MUstV2FwbEdHOGkteHBQVjNtTHFfQWpOWW1iamVFYzR3WDVjN2p3Tkt5RXlGLVBDdE9OTGN4YnZxUU1QWVdXZ2JlUHFrNmJ4bm9wUlV1WVdCR3Vha3lGWGxB0gGrAUFVX3lxTE44VXVYQnNZd3l2NnpsQTU0eGktbXpyR01nTzlPazdOTDRkOFZ4VWVWbXJEZTVCOVRBNy1IeTNmNzByZDEzT0F3VjloWTlrMHRHQ0hhTHJCS2hscTN6cGJvd1lHT2JYSGtlazFGRkdodHNYQU5PQ2FrMnpkaUhlV2NnSmdIWDdWbDlJNlEwaWNUNmtGbjhLb3Q4VlpfLTdlUVpkdVE3SmUxQnF1bw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 11:36:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['A lot of flu out there': Winter wave of respiratory illnesses spark concern across the US; here's what t - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘A lot of flu out there’: Winter wave of respiratory illnesses spark concern across the US; here's what to know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>As respiratory illnesses surge across the United States, health officials are expressing concern over increased flu cases and other respiratory viruses this winter season, emphasizing the importance of vaccination and public health measures.</p><ul><li>Significant rise in flu cases reported nationwide.</li><li>Health officials urge vaccination as the best defense.</li><li>A mix of flu, RSV, and COVID-19 cases observed.</li><li>Emergency rooms experiencing increased patient load.</li><li>Vulnerable populations, including the elderly and young children, are at greater risk.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are seeing a lot of flu out there,” said a health official, emphasizing the need for vaccinations.</blockquote><p>The combined strain of multiple respiratory illnesses highlights the critical need for preventative measures this winter. Health officials remind the public to stay informed and protect vulnerable populations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/a-lot-of-flu-out-there-winter-wave-of-respiratory-illnesses-spark-concern-across-the-us-heres-what-to-know/articleshow/116964535.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/a-lot-of-flu-out-there-winter-wave-of-respiratory-illnesses-spark-concern-across-the-us-heres-what-to-know/articleshow/116964535.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Healthcare research links loneliness to morbidity and mortality - The Week]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Healthcare research links loneliness to morbidity and mortality</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> University of Cambridge, Fudan University</p>
<p>This article discusses a study published in the journal <i>Nature Human Behaviour</i> indicating a correlation between loneliness and increased morbidity and mortality, emphasizing its significance as a public health concern.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study analyzed data from over 40,000 participants, identifying genetic correlations between loneliness, depression, and social isolation.</li>
  <li>Loneliness can significantly affect mental and physical health, impacting sleep, cognition, and cardiovascular health.</li>
  <li>The World Health Organization estimates that 1 in 4 older adults experience social isolation.</li>
  <li>Loneliness is comparable to well-known health risk factors like smoking and obesity regarding its impact on mortality.</li>
  <li>Experts urge for improved psychosocial support and mental health awareness.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Loneliness has been negatively associated with multiple health outcomes, including mental and physical health, sleep, cognition and cardiovascular health.” - Researchers from <i>Psychiatry Research</i></blockquote>
<p>This research highlights the urgent need to address loneliness as a growing public health issue, particularly amid the UN Decade of Healthy Ageing (2021-2030).</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theweek.in/news/health/2025/01/05/healthcare-research-links-loneliness-to-morbidity-and-mortality.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theweek.in/news/health/2025/01/05/healthcare-research-links-loneliness-to-morbidity-and-mortality.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 11:00:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Surgeon General calls for cancer warnings on alcohol - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Surgeon General Calls for Cancer Warnings on Alcohol</h1><p><strong>Published: 05 January 2025, Source: Bloomberg News</strong></p><p>Alcoholic drinks like beer and wine should carry warnings about their links to cancer, according to US Surgeon General Vivek Murthy, who highlights a significant lack of public awareness regarding the health risks associated with alcohol consumption.</p><ul><li>Alcohol causes approximately 100,000 cancer cases and 20,000 related deaths annually in the US.</li><li>Less than half of Americans recognize that alcohol increases cancer risk.</li><li>An advisory from the Surgeon General calls for updated warning labels on alcoholic beverages.</li><li>Alcohol is a major risk factor for at least seven types of cancer.</li><li>The American Medical Association supports the advisory, stating it will improve health awareness.</li></ul><blockquote>“Alcohol consumption at any level... is a modifiable risk factor for cancer.” - Bruce Scott, AMA President</blockquote><p>The Surgeon General's advisory aims to bolster public awareness of alcohol-related health risks and advocate for changes in labeling to reflect these dangers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/us-surgeon-general-calls-for-cancer-warnings-on-alcohol-3342139</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/us-surgeon-general-calls-for-cancer-warnings-on-alcohol-3342139</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 09:48:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leopard, three tigers die of Avian flu in Maharashtra’s Gorewada Rescue Centre - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Leopard, three tigers die of Avian flu in Maharashtra’s Gorewada Rescue Centre</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> January 05, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><p>Four animals, including three tigers and a leopard, have died due to H5N1 Avian Influenza at the Gorewada Rescue Centre in Nagpur, Maharashtra. A red alert has been issued by the Government of India to prepare zoos across the state for potential outbreaks.</p><img src='image_url_placeholder' alt='Gorewada Rescue Centre' /><figcaption>Image of Gorewada Rescue Centre</figcaption><p>This tragic event has triggered enhanced bio-security measures to prevent further infections among animals and protect staff.</p><ul><li>Three tigers and one leopard died from H5N1 Avian Influenza.</li><li>Red alert issued by the Government of India for preparedness in all zoos.</li><li>Veterinarians released a detailed protocol to prevent bird access to animal enclosures.</li><li>Symptoms observed in animals included limping, diarrhoea, and fever.</li><li>Advisories aim to minimize AI transmission risk and ensure rapid containment.</li></ul><blockquote>“H5N1 is a lethal virus but other variants may not be this lethal, and animals can be saved on timely treatment,” - Shatanik Bhagwat, Divisional Manager, Gorewada Project.</blockquote><p>The ongoing situation stresses the need for vigilance and safety protocols in wildlife facilities to combat the spread of Avian Influenza.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/energy-and-environment/leopard-three-tigers-die-of-avian-flu-in-maharashtras-gorewada-rescue-centre/article69064307.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/energy-and-environment/leopard-three-tigers-die-of-avian-flu-in-maharashtras-gorewada-rescue-centre/article69064307.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 09:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kesar Doodh Benefits: 8 reasons to consume saffron milk for health and vitality - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kesar Doodh Benefits: 8 reasons to consume saffron milk for health and vitality</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 5, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116962766.jpg?imgsize=1124327&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="Kesar Doodh Benefits" />
<figcaption>Kesar Doodh Benefits: An elixir for health</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the numerous health benefits of saffron milk, also known as kesar doodh, highlighting its rich nutrient profile and antioxidant properties. Here are eight compelling reasons to include saffron milk in your daily routine:</p>
<ul>
<li>Boosts immunity through antioxidants.</li>
<li>Enhances mood and relieves stress.</li>
<li>Improves digestion and gut health.</li>
<li>Promotes glowing skin.</li>
<li>Strengthens bones due to calcium content.</li>
<li>Supports respiratory health.</li>
<li>Improves heart health by regulating blood pressure.</li>
<li>Enhances memory and cognitive function.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Saffron is known as the 'golden spice' and is historically valued for its health benefits. It is combined with warm milk to create a soothing and nutritious drink."</blockquote>
<p>The inclusion of saffron milk in one's diet can leverage its multiple health benefits and promote overall vitality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/kesar-doodh-benefits-8-reasons-to-consume-saffron-milk-for-health-and-vitality/photostory/116962749.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/kesar-doodh-benefits-8-reasons-to-consume-saffron-milk-for-health-and-vitality/photostory/116962749.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 08:50:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV Virus: How deadly is this virus? China's Center for Disease Control and Prevention sheds light on fat - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Virus: How deadly is this virus?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent report<br><strong>Source:</strong> China's Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</p>
<p>Amid rising worries following recent reports of an outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in China, China's Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has explained the fatality rate caused by the virus.</p>
<ul>
  <li>HMPV primarily affects children, immunocompromised individuals, and the elderly.</li>
  <li>The virus often results in cold-like symptoms but can lead to more severe conditions like bronchitis and pneumonia.</li>
  <li>Approximately 1% of acute lower respiratory infection-related deaths in children under five are attributed to HMPV.</li>
  <li>Currently, there is no vaccine or effective treatment for HMPV; care focuses on symptom relief.</li>
  <li>Health officials have reassured the public about preparedness for respiratory infections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"There is nothing to be alarmed about the present situation, urging people to take general precautions." - Dr. Atul Goel</blockquote>
<p>Overall, while a seasonal increase in respiratory pathogens is expected, this year's intensity of respiratory infectious diseases in China is lower than last year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/global-trends/hmpv-virus-how-deadly-is-this-virus-chinas-center-for-disease-control-and-prevention-sheds-light-on-fatality-rate/articleshow/116960604.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/global-trends/hmpv-virus-how-deadly-is-this-virus-chinas-center-for-disease-control-and-prevention-sheds-light-on-fatality-rate/articleshow/116960604.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:28:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 signs of overtraining and how to recover - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Signs of Overtraining and How to Recover</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2025/01/05/900x1600/pexels-cesar-galeao-1673528-3289711_1736065575624_1736065587336.jpg" alt="Signs of Overtraining"><figcaption>Signs of Overtraining</figcaption><p>Overtraining can significantly impact both physical performance and mental health. Recognizing the signs early is essential for effective recovery and maintaining a balanced fitness routine.</p><ul><li><strong>Persistent Fatigue:</strong> Constant exhaustion despite adequate rest.</li><li><strong>Decreased Performance:</strong> Noticeable decline in workout performance or strength.</li><li><strong>Increased Injury Risk:</strong> Frequent injuries or prolonged muscle soreness.</li><li><strong>Mood Changes:</strong> Irritability, anxiety, or lack of motivation.</li><li><strong>Sleep Disturbances:</strong> Struggling with insomnia or poor sleep quality.</li></ul><blockquote>Engage in stress-relief activities and establish a calming bedtime routine to enhance overall well-being.</blockquote><p>Addressing these signs promptly can help maintain health and optimize performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-signs-of-overtraining-and-how-to-recover-visual-story-11736065329129.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-signs-of-overtraining-and-how-to-recover-visual-story-11736065329129.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 06:57:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Covid-like outbreak in China, Indian Health experts say ‘HMPV has been observed in India multiple times....’ | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Observed in India Amid Outbreak Concerns in China</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 4, 2023 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Business Today</p>
<p>As concerns rise over a Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) outbreak in China, Indian health experts clarify that HMPV has been present in India multiple times, particularly in winter, and is typically mild.</p>
<ul>
<li>HMPV is a common respiratory virus, similar to influenza, observed particularly during winter.</li>
<li>Dr. Suresh Gupta from Sir Ganga Ram Hospital emphasized that most cases are mild and self-limiting.</li>
<li>India's Health Ministry is increasing laboratory testing for HMPV and monitoring trends throughout the year.</li>
<li>The Telangana government has issued precautionary measures including hand hygiene and social distancing.</li>
<li>Kerala Health Minister reassures that there is no need for panic despite news of viral outbreaks in China.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Most cases present with symptoms such as cold, cough, and fever, which are self-limiting and manageable at home." - Dr. Suresh Gupta</blockquote>
<p>The current focus on HMPV in India highlights the need for vigilance amidst global health concerns, albeit with reassurance of the virus's mild nature based on past observations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/health/amid-covid-like-outbreak-in-china-indian-health-experts-say-hmpv-has-been-observed-in-india-multiple-times-11736055173466.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/health/amid-covid-like-outbreak-in-china-indian-health-experts-say-hmpv-has-been-observed-in-india-multiple-times-11736055173466.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 06:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Gurgaon to Freeze at 3°C: Top Cardiologist Shares 7 Safety Tips To Prevent Heart Attacks And Winter Stroke - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Gurgaon to Freeze at 3°C: Is Your Heart Ready for the Cold Wave? 7 Safety Tips To Prevent Heart Attacks.</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Lorem Ipsum, <strong>Source: </strong>The Health Site</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Delhi-Gurgaon-to-Freeze-at-3%C2%B0C-How-to-Prevent-Winter-Heart-Attacks.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="Delhi, Gurgaon to Freeze at 3°C: Top Cardiologist Shares 7 Safety Tips To Prevent Heart Attacks And Winter Stroke" width="900" height="375">
  <figcaption>Delhi, Gurgaon to Freeze at 3°C: Is Your Heart Ready for the Cold Wave? 7 Safety Tips To Prevent Heart Attacks</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Several regions in northern India are grappling with a sharp decline in temperatures, with the Delhi-Gurgaon region expected to plunge to 3°C next week. This cold wave poses serious health risks to the heart, increasing the likelihood of heart attacks and winter strokes.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Cover your body with warm clothes to protect against cold waves.</li>
  <li>Maintain a balanced diet focused on heart-friendly foods.</li>
  <li>Stay active indoors to keep warm.</li>
  <li>Stay hydrated, prioritizing warm beverages.</li>
  <li>Manage stress and ensure adequate sleep.</li>
  <li>Monitor health parameters like blood pressure and cholesterol.</li>
  <li>Avoid smoking and excessive alcohol consumption.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>“Take care of your heart, and don't let the frost catch you off guard. Stay warm, stay safe, and prioritize your health during this chilling season.”</p></blockquote>
<p>By following these safety tips, individuals can minimize their risk of heart-related issues this winter as temperatures drop.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/delhi-gurgaon-to-freeze-at-3c-top-cardiologist-shares-7-safety-tips-to-prevent-heart-attacks-and-winter-stroke-1170057/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/delhi-gurgaon-to-freeze-at-3c-top-cardiologist-shares-7-safety-tips-to-prevent-heart-attacks-and-winter-stroke-1170057/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 06:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV outbreak in China: Telangana health department issues dos & don’ts - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Outbreak in China: Telangana Health Department Issues Guidelines</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>In light of the recent HMPV outbreak in China, the Telangana health department has issued dos and don’ts to safeguard public health and prevent the spread of the virus.</p>
<ul>
<li>The health department emphasizes personal hygiene and regular handwashing.</li>
<li>Individuals are advised to avoid close contact with infected persons.</li>
<li>Symptoms to watch for include cough, fever, and breathing difficulties.</li>
<li>Public health campaigns will be initiated to raise awareness about HMPV.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It is crucial to follow health advisories to prevent contagion,” a health official stated.</blockquote>
<p>The Telangana health department's proactive measures aim to mitigate risk and ensure community safety during this outbreak.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/hyderabad/hmpv-outbreak-in-china-telangana-health-department-issues-dos-donts/articleshow/116958054.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/hyderabad/hmpv-outbreak-in-china-telangana-health-department-issues-dos-donts/articleshow/116958054.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV outbreak in China: Is it a new virus? How is it similar to Covid-19? Is there any vaccine? What we know so far | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV outbreak in China: Is it a new virus? How is it similar to Covid-19? Is there any vaccine? What we know so far</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>An outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in China has raised global alarm, prompting several countries, including India, to closely monitor the situation. This article delves into what HMPV is, its similarities to COVID-19, and the current understanding of its spread and impact.</p><h2>What is Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV)?</h2><p>HMPV is a respiratory virus that commonly causes infections, especially during winter and spring months.</p><h2>Is HMPV similar to COVID-19 virus?</h2><ul><li>Both cause respiratory diseases, particularly affecting vulnerable groups.</li><li>Symptoms like cough, fever, and nasal congestion are common to both.</li><li>Transmission occurs via respiratory secretions and contaminated surfaces.</li><li>HMPV follows seasonal patterns similar to COVID-19.</li></ul><h2>Is there a vaccine to prevent HMPV spread?</h2><p>Currently, no vaccine exists for HMPV, and antiviral treatments are not recommended. General preventive measures are advised.</p><h2>HMPV outbreak: Should India be worried?</h2><p>Health officials in India insist there is no need for alarm despite the outbreak, urging the public to follow safety precautions.</p><blockquote>“We have analysed the data of the respiratory outbreaks within the country, there is no such substantial increase in 2024 data.” — Dr. Atul Goel</blockquote><p>Experts warn that if the outbreak is not managed swiftly, it could put a strain on healthcare systems.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/hmpv-outbreak-in-china-is-it-a-new-virus-how-is-it-similar-to-covid-19-is-there-any-vaccine-what-we-know-so-far-11736044379099.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/hmpv-outbreak-in-china-is-it-a-new-virus-how-is-it-similar-to-covid-19-is-there-any-vaccine-what-we-know-so-far-11736044379099.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 02:40:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 signs of magnesium deficiency - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Signs of Magnesium Deficiency</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p>
<img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2025/01/05/900x1600/Magnesium_Deficiency_1736057309409_1736057309589.jpeg" alt="MAGNESIUM DEFICIENCY" />
<figcaption>Magnesium Deficiency</figcaption>
<p>Magnesium is essential for bone strength, heart health, and muscle function. Magnesium deficiency can lead to osteoporosis, diabetes, migraines, and heart issues.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Muscle Cramps and Twitches:</strong> Low magnesium causes muscle cramps and twitches by disrupting electrolyte balance and nerve signal transmission.</li>
<li><strong>Weakness and Fatigue:</strong> Fatigue and muscle weakness are common symptoms of low magnesium, which is essential for energy metabolism.</li>
<li><strong>Sleep Disorders:</strong> Low magnesium can lead to sleep difficulties causing unhealthy sleep and fatigue.</li>
<li><strong>Numbness:</strong> Numbness in legs and hands can signal nerve issues from low magnesium.</li>
<li><strong>Migraines:</strong> Low magnesium relates to migraines, causing symptoms like nausea and vomiting.</li>
<li><strong>Irregular Heartbeat:</strong> Low magnesium increases ventricle contractions and irregular heartbeats.</li>
<li><strong>High Blood Pressure:</strong> Low magnesium can cause high blood pressure and increase heart disease risk.</li>
</ul>
<p>This article highlights the various signs of magnesium deficiency and emphasizes the importance of magnesium in overall health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/7-signs-of-magnesium-deficiency-visual-story-11736055781898.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/7-signs-of-magnesium-deficiency-visual-story-11736055781898.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 02:34:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mask Wearing Strict Screening Compulsory In Kerala Telangana As HMPV Virus Spreads Rapidly In China - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Strict Mask Wearing and Screening Implemented in Kerala and Telangana Due to Rapid Spread of HMPV Virus in China</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> TheHealthSite</p>
<img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Mask-Wearing-Strict-Screening-Compulsory-In-Kerala-Telangana-As-HMPV-Virus-Spreads-Rapidly-In-China.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="Mask Wearing, Strict Screening Compulsory In Kerala, Telangana As HMPV Virus Spreads Rapidly In China">
<figcaption>Mask Wearing, Strict Screening Compulsory In Kerala, Telangana As HMPV Virus Spreads Rapidly In China</figcaption>
<p>The Kerala and Telangana governments have issued guidelines to prevent the spread of HMPV virus, which causes serious respiratory illnesses, following reports of a rapid outbreak in China.</p>
<ul>
<li>A new virus, HMPV, is spreading in China, causing pneumonia-like symptoms.</li>
<li>The virus predominantly affects children under 14 and the elderly.</li>
<li>Kerala Health Minister has advised mask-wearing and caution but reassured there is no immediate panic.</li>
<li>Precautionary measures include isolation, hydration, and avoiding crowds.</li>
<li>Reports suggest the increase in hospital cases in China is due to HMPV, COVID-19 variants, and Influenza A.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Children should not be sent to school during illness. Those with respiratory symptoms should definitely wear weak masks." - Kerala Health Minister Veena George</blockquote>
<p>This response from the governments reflects proactive measures in the face of potential public health concerns, urging citizens to remain vigilant and informed.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/mask-wearing-strict-screening-compulsory-in-kerala-telangana-as-hmpv-virus-spreads-rapidly-in-china-1170024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/mask-wearing-strict-screening-compulsory-in-kerala-telangana-as-hmpv-virus-spreads-rapidly-in-china-1170024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 02:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can chronic illnesses be prevented in 2025? Five doctors from across the country give you 25 pro tips - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Five Doctors Reveal 25 Pro Tips to Prevent Chronic Illnesses by 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/chronic-illness.jpg?w=640" alt="chronic illness" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>One can prevent chronic illnesses by following diet, exercising regularly, limiting usage of mobile phones, and doing medical checkups.</figcaption><p>This article provides insights from five medical professionals offering practical tips for preventing chronic illnesses as we approach 2025. Emphasizing routines, mental health, and regular check-ups, the tips aim to optimize health and well-being.</p><ul><li>Dr. Vijay Natarajan suggests creating 'me' time for mental health.</li><li>Set timers to encourage regular movement.</li><li>Check Vitamin D levels regularly to maintain overall health.</li><li>Focus on mental health as part of a holistic approach.</li><li>Ensure cardiac fitness with proper testing before starting fitness plans.</li></ul><blockquote>“Neglecting mental health can worsen health conditions.” - Dr. Vijay Natarajan</blockquote><p>Overall, these tips highlight the importance of incorporating healthy habits into daily life, stressing that personal time and self-care are critical components in chronic illness prevention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/chronic-illness-doctors-9760546/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/chronic-illness-doctors-9760546/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 02:13:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Even before US alcohol warning, younger Americans were turning to mocktails - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Even before US alcohol warning, younger Americans were turning to mocktails</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>The U.S. Surgeon General's warning of an increased risk of cancer from drinking alcohol may resonate with younger Americans, who have recently favored mocktails and juices over alcoholic drinks.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The youngest adults have been drinking less alcohol over the last decade.</li>
  <li>In 2023, 49.6% of Americans aged 18-25 reported consuming alcohol in the past month, down from 59.6% in 2013.</li>
  <li>Non-alcoholic beverage platforms like The Zero Proof are experiencing increased demand.</li>
  <li>Public health organizations are shifting focus to alcohol consumption following tobacco control successes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I found mocktails to be a good way to get antioxidants while incorporating anti-inflammatory foods into my diet.” – Amy Hudson</blockquote>
<p>With public awareness around alcohol's risks growing, it is uncertain how effective Surgeon General Vivek Murthy's proposal for updated warning labels will be in changing drinking behaviors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/world-news/even-before-us-alcohol-warning-younger-americans-were-turning-to-mocktails/articleshow/116956047.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/world-news/even-before-us-alcohol-warning-younger-americans-were-turning-to-mocktails/articleshow/116956047.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 01:23:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Loneliness: The 21st century pandemic - The Sunday Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxQOWFWTnRpXzZKejZKOEpYaWYtQmh6ODBLY3l3dGZoZmFVdmFCYUlsbUhFcTIzVEQ4M3N1NFZBUzc5ZXZfelI0eGg1a0lMYkZYUC1BZ2gtR09DN29yQkZoQ1BRTXZtYVYtOXl5NTR2V3I5Sk1YZ2JhdFVJVmVVakM0YllB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxQOWFWTnRpXzZKejZKOEpYaWYtQmh6ODBLY3l3dGZoZmFVdmFCYUlsbUhFcTIzVEQ4M3N1NFZBUzc5ZXZfelI0eGg1a0lMYkZYUC1BZ2gtR09DN29yQkZoQ1BRTXZtYVYtOXl5NTR2V3I5Sk1YZ2JhdFVJVmVVakM0YllB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 22:35:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winter wellness simplified: How to consume dry fruits - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxNcEFsQkduOTdEdmoySGxWYlA0aExIZTZJQVJnUmhlclZvWkxJOV9RdUpfWEhucUFkQVA2VUdHd0xoaF85alpLeW5uUlBhcHN4QnNDbG02ZXVwd0JMLVZ0RlFaUHN0Q25jVW9aQkR1YklMQ3FzcDBfaFJENEZvU1BGSGZMd2VhSEtNNzJPcXlxY19kUWd0OWd1dVpoWWNJS2ta0gGnAUFVX3lxTE9IYjZnbmNKcmRDSmpqb3puUkdhbFMzQTVFY3MzdFFZQW9SanhhMDdlYmlRcGUxZVM1UV85WV96ZHBPMVpXZzIxYThPZUd3WXk2X0RiV0lOWTAxNlJaLWxIS0dGMHFrOXZTQ04wNWF1bHRzQ05Lb0Zvb2ljSTdTRU8xMTZIV0NmQWxMVEpGZEFhSWNva2lBa283bDdMVllBamZfM003dXc4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxNcEFsQkduOTdEdmoySGxWYlA0aExIZTZJQVJnUmhlclZvWkxJOV9RdUpfWEhucUFkQVA2VUdHd0xoaF85alpLeW5uUlBhcHN4QnNDbG02ZXVwd0JMLVZ0RlFaUHN0Q25jVW9aQkR1YklMQ3FzcDBfaFJENEZvU1BGSGZMd2VhSEtNNzJPcXlxY19kUWd0OWd1dVpoWWNJS2ta0gGnAUFVX3lxTE9IYjZnbmNKcmRDSmpqb3puUkdhbFMzQTVFY3MzdFFZQW9SanhhMDdlYmlRcGUxZVM1UV85WV96ZHBPMVpXZzIxYThPZUd3WXk2X0RiV0lOWTAxNlJaLWxIS0dGMHFrOXZTQ04wNWF1bHRzQ05Lb0Zvb2ljSTdTRU8xMTZIV0NmQWxMVEpGZEFhSWNva2lBa283bDdMVllBamZfM003dXc4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 20:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>