<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:22:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:22:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Severe case of bird flu in the U.S.: Here are symptoms, treatment, precautions, vaccines and all the details you need to know - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogJBVV95cUxNWWdrREM1bE9CdWh0QS15ZWlyM0swMlJxN29zYllXVFpnMTdyNU9wcVF5T3ZWbnIwbzFwT1N0N2pBeEZjV2lycmxLa2hPYlRqZjN3Ry1nWmZjNG1idmpTSVZSNjhJWUhyVWROVlhYb3NQVFJaX3QtS1pSeTBGV0xNWWNJWklhUmZ4bTBnbkpxczNVdXdfbUp4cHRPSEpmSkNlWHA0MVpXb0haUUNKQUM5YnNRX1NvVnVkeUFDRkxfNWJrN1g5Z3EtZFJSUGxsdjRTWUF1eTRmQVM0M2JpXzB1eDh0RWR1SHQ3M0dIamVmUGJvWnI3RVhTMG9Ga3VKQS1JcTlUNldHdm1rYV93Z25WQUFwTzEwdFdvTWsyN3dMcUk4dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogJBVV95cUxNWWdrREM1bE9CdWh0QS15ZWlyM0swMlJxN29zYllXVFpnMTdyNU9wcVF5T3ZWbnIwbzFwT1N0N2pBeEZjV2lycmxLa2hPYlRqZjN3Ry1nWmZjNG1idmpTSVZSNjhJWUhyVWROVlhYb3NQVFJaX3QtS1pSeTBGV0xNWWNJWklhUmZ4bTBnbkpxczNVdXdfbUp4cHRPSEpmSkNlWHA0MVpXb0haUUNKQUM5YnNRX1NvVnVkeUFDRkxfNWJrN1g5Z3EtZFJSUGxsdjRTWUF1eTRmQVM0M2JpXzB1eDh0RWR1SHQ3M0dIamVmUGJvWnI3RVhTMG9Ga3VKQS1JcTlUNldHdm1rYV93Z25WQUFwTzEwdFdvTWsyN3dMcUk4dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 20:08:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Noida, Gzb see rise in diabetes, cardiac & respiratory cases amid cold & pollution - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rise in Diabetes, Cardiac and Respiratory Cases in Noida and Ghaziabad Due to Cold and Pollution</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 10, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Health concerns" width="600" height="400"><figcaption>Health concerns in Noida and Ghaziabad due to environmental factors.</figcaption><p>The recent increase in diabetes, cardiac, and respiratory cases in Noida and Ghaziabad is being attributed to the ongoing cold weather and rising pollution levels.</p><ul><li>Both cities have reported an alarming rise in health conditions linked to air quality.</li><li>Health officials recommend measures to combat pollution and improve public health.</li><li>Local hospitals are experiencing a surge in admissions for related ailments.</li></ul><blockquote>"We have seen a notable uptick in patients suffering from chronic conditions exacerbated by poor air quality," said a local health official.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, urgent action is needed to address the health crisis stemming from pollution and cold temperatures in these regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/noida/noida-gzb-see-rise-in-diabetes-cardiac-respiratory-cases-amid-cold-pollution/articleshow/116482284.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/noida/noida-gzb-see-rise-in-diabetes-cardiac-respiratory-cases-amid-cold-pollution/articleshow/116482284.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 19:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flu Vaccine Response Boosted by Coupling Antigens from Multiple Subtypes - Genetic Engineering & Biotechnology News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Flu Vaccine Response Boosted by Coupling Antigens from Multiple Subtypes</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here]</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p>
<p>A recent study by Stanford Medicine scientists reveals that individual genetic makeup significantly influences immune responses to the seasonal influenza vaccine. Their findings suggest a novel vaccine platform improves protection against various influenza subtypes.</p>
<ul>
<li>Host genetics play a stronger role than prior exposure in flu vaccine responses.</li>
<li>The study introduces a new vaccine platform tested in animal models and human organoids.</li>
<li>Current flu vaccines show efficacy ranging from 20% to 80% due to subtype bias.</li>
<li>The compound vaccine design could enhance the immune response to all strains.</li>
<li>Concerns exist about avian flu and its potential pandemic threat.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Overcoming subtype bias this way can lead to a much more effective influenza vaccine.” – Mark Davis, PhD</blockquote>
<p>This research not only provides insights into enhancing flu vaccines but also presents a viable methodology for developing vaccines for other pathogens.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.genengnews.com/topics/infectious-diseases/flu-vaccine-response-boosted-by-coupling-antigens-from-multiple-subtypes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.genengnews.com/topics/infectious-diseases/flu-vaccine-response-boosted-by-coupling-antigens-from-multiple-subtypes/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 19:00:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Understanding the mechanisms behind alcohol-associated liver disease - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Understanding Alcohol-Associated Liver Disease: Mechanisms and Future Directions</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> eGastroenterology</p><p>This review provides an analysis of the mechanisms behind alcohol-associated liver disease (ALD), emphasizing its global impact and the urgent need for effective treatments.</p><ul><li>The review summarizes cellular, molecular, and systemic processes involved in ALD.</li><li>It highlights alcohol metabolism's effect on liver function, particularly oxidative stress and inflammation.</li><li>Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are discussed as key players in intercellular communication and potential biomarkers.</li><li>The gut-liver axis's role in ALD development is explained, focusing on gut dysbiosis and inflammatory pathways.</li><li>Cytokines' dual role in promoting or counteracting inflammation in ALD is explored for potential therapeutic strategies.</li></ul><blockquote>"This review is a testament to the progress made in understanding ALD," said Dr. Hui Gao, the first author. "It highlights not only the complexity of the disease but also the opportunities for intervention through targeted therapies."</blockquote><p>This comprehensive synthesis aims to guide future research and therapeutic developments in tackling ALD.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20241219/Understanding-the-mechanisms-behind-alcohol-associated-liver-disease.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/news/20241219/Understanding-the-mechanisms-behind-alcohol-associated-liver-disease.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top executives reflect on 2024’s biggest surprises, part one - Mobihealth News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mobihealthnews.com/news/executives-reflect-2024-s-biggest-surprises-part-one</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mobihealthnews.com/news/executives-reflect-2024-s-biggest-surprises-part-one</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:30:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New report shows Commonwealth countries making progress against global uptick of malaria burden - Commonwealth]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Commonwealth Countries Make Significant Progress in Combating Malaria</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Commonwealth Secretariat</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://production-new-commonwealth-files.s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/styles/banner/public/2024-12/world-malaria-report-image.png?VersionId=BtUXzOb6lxhlN1gY0Jg11Iba8b7e4WIt&amp;h=d320664f&amp;itok=YLRM9P4I" width="1600" height="1050" alt="Malaria report vaccine">
<figcaption>Image depicting malaria report efforts.</figcaption>
<p>The World Malaria Report 2024 reveals significant advancements by Commonwealth countries in reducing malaria cases, signaling effective interventions despite a global rise in instances. Belize has been malaria-free for two consecutive years, while several African nations have also shown decreased incidence rates.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Belize certified malaria-free for the second year.</li>
  <li>India exited the high-burden group by achieving significant reductions in malaria rates.</li>
  <li>Global reports indicate nearly 1 in 10 children die from malaria each year.</li>
  <li>Commonwealth leaders reaffirmed their commitment to eliminate malaria by 2030.</li>
  <li>Notable milestones achieved include new vaccine introductions and health initiatives.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p>"Malaria is a disease that affects a diverse range of people but takes a disproportionate toll on the poorest, least educated, and most disenfranchised people in the world." - Dr. Astrid Bonfield, CEO of Malaria No More UK</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This article underscores the ongoing commitment and efforts that Commonwealth countries are making towards achieving a malaria-free world, highlighting both successes and the challenges that remain.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thecommonwealth.org/news/new-report-shows-commonwealth-countries-making-progress-against-global-uptick-malaria-burden</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thecommonwealth.org/news/new-report-shows-commonwealth-countries-making-progress-against-global-uptick-malaria-burden</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:47:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[​Kalonji oil benefits: 8 health benefits of using black seed oil - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxPdlZicUdTYTJiZlhONmwyUllCRFQycW9YQjc5ZTU1RmRrT2ZKVl95UVNZWGV4WUxJeXdPSEEtWXJLdHVMVFRkM0p3ZGl2OVp5Um4xUnRFalRucHpqUm9mUFF0RUdfLU9qcHFkVURsR0tfMi1xNTU3UU9ka1QzczB6RjhmRDRxVV9Da3hRY2VVa2J1Z1NJaHFYQ0NVRDU1MEpJQWcybTkxMFgwNzVyZ1RHUzVZZGpfenZsdmpTUFdkRmp2aDMxMk9vZl8tMlRZakJBYkljN2JBaWVrTldjV0dWX1c5aDNzcE8tNkhJTThXTlZWTXPSAfMBQVVfeXFMT3ZWYnFHU2EyYmZYTjZsMlJZQkRUMnFvWEI3OWU1NUZka09mSlZfeVFTWVhleFlMSXl3T0hBLVlyS3R1TFRUZDNKd2RpdjlaeVJuMVJ0RWpUbnB6alJvZlBRdEVHXy1PanBxZFVEbEdLXzItcTU1N1FPZGtUM3MwekY4ZkQ0cVVfQ2t4UWNlVWtidWdTSWhxWENDVUQ1NTBKSUFnMm05MTBYMDc1cmdUR1M1WWRqX3p2bHZqU1BXZEZqdmgzMTJPb2ZfLTJUWWpCQWJJYzdiQWlla05XY1dHVl9XOWgzc3BPLTZISU04V05WVk1z?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxPdlZicUdTYTJiZlhONmwyUllCRFQycW9YQjc5ZTU1RmRrT2ZKVl95UVNZWGV4WUxJeXdPSEEtWXJLdHVMVFRkM0p3ZGl2OVp5Um4xUnRFalRucHpqUm9mUFF0RUdfLU9qcHFkVURsR0tfMi1xNTU3UU9ka1QzczB6RjhmRDRxVV9Da3hRY2VVa2J1Z1NJaHFYQ0NVRDU1MEpJQWcybTkxMFgwNzVyZ1RHUzVZZGpfenZsdmpTUFdkRmp2aDMxMk9vZl8tMlRZakJBYkljN2JBaWVrTldjV0dWX1c5aDNzcE8tNkhJTThXTlZWTXPSAfMBQVVfeXFMT3ZWYnFHU2EyYmZYTjZsMlJZQkRUMnFvWEI3OWU1NUZka09mSlZfeVFTWVhleFlMSXl3T0hBLVlyS3R1TFRUZDNKd2RpdjlaeVJuMVJ0RWpUbnB6alJvZlBRdEVHXy1PanBxZFVEbEdLXzItcTU1N1FPZGtUM3MwekY4ZkQ0cVVfQ2t4UWNlVWtidWdTSWhxWENDVUQ1NTBKSUFnMm05MTBYMDc1cmdUR1M1WWRqX3p2bHZqU1BXZEZqdmgzMTJPb2ZfLTJUWWpCQWJJYzdiQWlla05XY1dHVl9XOWgzc3BPLTZISU04V05WVk1z?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Even inside holiday desserts, can apples help keep the doctor away? - Seattle PI]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.seattlepi.com/news/article/even-inside-holiday-desserts-can-apples-help-19990513.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.seattlepi.com/news/article/even-inside-holiday-desserts-can-apples-help-19990513.php</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:07:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Even inside holiday desserts, can apples help keep the doctor away? - American Heart Association News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPbzNWTUZXVXJfM09mWE43MHotcFJxQ2lzbk84T0llTGpMUVVUN2MxQ2Jmc3dJbGozbzFOb0VkVTBjekFrNzNrOE5GdTVMeUd2MWFuTklGeVJ3a19KU28wY0tSS0ozT0RYZWwxVnNrVUxvU2FMNjVJcEV5R01lV2dLay12SDR5andUeXg1VmFDdmtXYzRXVTkxN0RrN0NtLWVsVHB4eTlRMjdvQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPbzNWTUZXVXJfM09mWE43MHotcFJxQ2lzbk84T0llTGpMUVVUN2MxQ2Jmc3dJbGozbzFOb0VkVTBjekFrNzNrOE5GdTVMeUd2MWFuTklGeVJ3a19KU28wY0tSS0ozT0RYZWwxVnNrVUxvU2FMNjVJcEV5R01lV2dLay12SDR5andUeXg1VmFDdmtXYzRXVTkxN0RrN0NtLWVsVHB4eTlRMjdvQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:48:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Long-term assessment of Helicobacter pylori cagA EPIYA motif changes and pathology outcomes in gastric biopsies of dyspeptic patients: 10-year follow-up - BMC Gastroenterology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Long-term Assessment of Helicobacter pylori cagA EPIYA Motif Changes and Pathology Outcomes in Dyspeptic Patients: A 10-Year Follow-Up Study</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 19 December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> BMC Gastroenterology</p><p>This study investigates the long-term genetic changes in the cagA EPIYA motifs of Helicobacter pylori and their association with gastric pathology over a decade, focusing on factors like smoking and gender.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>The study included 100 H. pylori-positive patients with dyspeptic symptoms.</li><li>90% of primary samples and 91% of secondary samples were cagA positive.</li><li>52% of patients exhibited notable changes in cagA motif patterns.</li><li>Significant correlations were found between changes in pathology outcomes and gender (p=0.01) as well as smoking (p=0.00).</li></ul><blockquote>“The study highlights substantial heterogeneity in the cagA EPIYA motif patterns in long-term H. pylori colonization and notes an inverse relationship between pathology outcomes and smoking.”</blockquote><p>This research underlines the importance of monitoring genetic variations in H. pylori strains, which can have implications for understanding disease progression and treatment strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bmcgastroenterol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12876-024-03516-0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bmcgastroenterol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12876-024-03516-0</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:44:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US confirms first-ever 'severe' human bird flu; California declares emergency - NewsBytes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Declares Emergency as US Reports First Severe Human Bird Flu Case</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> NewsBytes</p><figure><img alt="US confirms first-ever 'severe' human bird flu; California declares emergency" title="US confirms first-ever 'severe' human bird flu; California declares emergency" src="https://i.cdn.newsbytesapp.com/images/29030161734594246.jpg"><figcaption>61 people have been infected with bird flu in the US</figcaption></figure><p>California Governor Gavin Newsom has declared a state of emergency as bird flu spreads rapidly among dairy cattle. The outbreak has made California the nation's hotspot for cattle infections.</p><ul><li>Over 300 dairy herds in California have tested positive for bird flu in the last month.</li><li>The first severe human case of bird flu in the US was reported in Louisiana, with a resident hospitalized after exposure.</li><li>A total of 61 people have been infected with bird flu in the US, with indications of undercounting.</li><li>A teenager in British Columbia was hospitalized with the D1.1 strain, but the source of infection remains unclear.</li></ul><blockquote>Dr. Demetre Daskalakis stated, "Infections without a clear source of exposure do occur," emphasizing a lack of evidence for human-to-human transmission.</blockquote><p>The declaration is a proactive measure to provide government agencies with necessary resources to address the outbreak and its potential health implications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/world/us-reports-first-human-bird-flu-case-california-declares-emergency/story</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/world/us-reports-first-human-bird-flu-case-california-declares-emergency/story</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:07:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tamil Nadu sought adding mumps vaccine in UIP - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tamil Nadu Advocates for Mumps Vaccine Inclusion in Universal Immunisation Programme</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 19, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Tamil Nadu Journal of Public Health and Medical Research</p>
<p>Tamil Nadu has requested the Government of India to include the mumps vaccine in the Universal Immunisation Programme (UIP) in response to a rising number of mumps cases. The move aims to improve public health and control disease spread.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Tamil Nadu records approximately 150 to 200 mumps cases monthly.</li>
    <li>The Directorate of Public Health has advised the inclusion of MMR vaccine in routine immunisation.</li>
    <li>Current UIP covers 11 vaccines against 12 diseases for children and pregnant women.</li>
    <li>The cases of mumps have shown a significant increase, especially in 2023-24, with over 1,000 reported cases.</li>
    <li>The largest percentage of cases occurred in children aged six to nine and less than five years.</li>
    <li>Experts warn of potential complications in adults and support the policy decision to include mumps in UIP.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In view of the growing evidence of complications due to shift in the age group, it is advisable to include mumps in the UIP.” - Dr. T. S. Selvavinayagam</blockquote>
<p>The request from Tamil Nadu aims to enhance vaccination efforts for mumps to prevent possible outbreaks and complications, emphasizing the importance of government support for implementation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/chennai/tamil-nadu-sought-adding-mumps-vaccine-in-uip/article69005062.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/chennai/tamil-nadu-sought-adding-mumps-vaccine-in-uip/article69005062.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smoke and Mirrors: The Myth of Healthy Vaping - University of Utah Health Care]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Smoke and Mirrors: The Myth of Healthy Vaping</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: Not specified</strong> | <strong>Source: Not specified</strong></p>
<p>Vaping is often perceived as a healthier alternative to smoking, but recent insights reveal significant oral health risks associated with it.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Inhaling chemicals in e-cigarettes can lead to gum disease and tooth decay.</li>
  <li>Nicotine is the major factor contributing to these health issues, similar to traditional cigarettes.</li>
  <li>Long-term nicotine exposure may increase the risk of heart disease.</li>
  <li>Narrowing of blood vessels due to nicotine reduces blood flow, hindering healing after oral injuries or surgeries.</li>
  <li>Despite widespread use, long-term research on vaping's health effects is still lacking.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“You lose bone faster if you’re vaping, just like you would with tobacco.” - David Okano, DDS</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while vaping is often viewed as less harmful, the evidence suggests it poses significant risks, particularly to oral health. Caution is advised until more comprehensive research is conducted.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://healthcare.utah.edu/healthfeed/2024/12/smoke-and-mirrors-myth-of-healthy-vaping</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://healthcare.utah.edu/healthfeed/2024/12/smoke-and-mirrors-myth-of-healthy-vaping</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:31:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“These filoviruses are always re-emerging” say East African scientists working on vaccine for Sudan Ebola strain - Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxOSUZTUWxlbGNLNkVoUk8yM2Fua1lnVWk5QTA5c2NnalhYRzA2SGJIVXhvUjFzT25fSTl3elJXdk93U2N6RlhoN090Y1JYc3lqXzdUMEN6c2lXSVA2VjNiNjkxSERlM1A3d2ItZTJjWjB4MVBZOUF5RVNDNkJBV3BQLWhfRERsZlNUSk1UaTcza3NoaXNiQ3BfUU1PSzJBYmxhekpCZjFkYnR0anFvN09DRk1uNW0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxOSUZTUWxlbGNLNkVoUk8yM2Fua1lnVWk5QTA5c2NnalhYRzA2SGJIVXhvUjFzT25fSTl3elJXdk93U2N6RlhoN090Y1JYc3lqXzdUMEN6c2lXSVA2VjNiNjkxSERlM1A3d2ItZTJjWjB4MVBZOUF5RVNDNkJBV3BQLWhfRERsZlNUSk1UaTcza3NoaXNiQ3BfUU1PSzJBYmxhekpCZjFkYnR0anFvN09DRk1uNW0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:28:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[User’s Guide to Essential TNM - International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTkFVX3lxTFBDODIwaHZVVHlUZUhzYVdxcEtpWDVvT3hyWkhCdnNJSmtxS256TzJIallDUi1YS3R2OGR4czlJVGJpTFY5QWh4Tmpqanlkdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTkFVX3lxTFBDODIwaHZVVHlUZUhzYVdxcEtpWDVvT3hyWkhCdnNJSmtxS256TzJIallDUi1YS3R2OGR4czlJVGJpTFY5QWh4Tmpqanlkdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:12:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Self-reported walking speed can predict metabolic disease risk - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Self-reported walking speed can predict metabolic disease risk</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Scientific Reports</p>
<p>Walking speed is regarded as a crucial health indicator, often termed the "sixth vital sign." A recent study in Japan revealed that individuals with a self-reported fast walking speed have a significantly lower risk of metabolic diseases, even when dealing with obesity.</p>
<ol>
  <li>The study, led by Prof. Kojiro Ishii, ties subjective walking speed to lower odds of hypertension, diabetes, and dyslipidemia.</li>
  <li>Data was collected from 8,578 participants identified as obese, with findings suggesting 30% lower risk of diabetes for faster walkers.</li>
  <li>The research emphasizes the potential of using simple self-assessment tools in public health screenings.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote><p>"Promoting a faster walking pace may be a helpful individual behavior to help prevent metabolic diseases, particularly in individuals with obesity," notes Dr. Ishii.</p></blockquote>
<p>The findings suggest that subjective assessments could enhance metabolic disease screenings and provide critical health insights. Future research should be conducted to test these findings longitudinally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20241219/Self-reported-walking-speed-can-predict-metabolic-disease-risk.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/news/20241219/Self-reported-walking-speed-can-predict-metabolic-disease-risk.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WHO launches new collaborating centre to advance research on public health and social measures during health emergencies - World Health Organization]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxPSGViOUtOdEhqWWVaX1huZktxRFFSTC1BZ2tPb0pJQ19tLUV0Q2ZQT1MtcU5yblVtOUk5S3RMbnlKeWFwNUtyNnpNNGVHX092dzhoSjVCSVlpdFFCZzZwbTdKejQ3X3luSGdqZm1pOTRKU3ItRW5Va1JqRFVSRVZjOWd4NmF5clVUV3llVU94T3BxcUhTV2x0ZXhNYUszTlR4anZSdjZld0NxOUUzbWxUMkVFeU5SQ3Jlbkxnci10TF9XOFppa08ta1pZcmptSTVqVFBBaWp1cFplVE1NU0x0YUlaZ3YxeERBMW9tc29YVmIxUWs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxPSGViOUtOdEhqWWVaX1huZktxRFFSTC1BZ2tPb0pJQ19tLUV0Q2ZQT1MtcU5yblVtOUk5S3RMbnlKeWFwNUtyNnpNNGVHX092dzhoSjVCSVlpdFFCZzZwbTdKejQ3X3luSGdqZm1pOTRKU3ItRW5Va1JqRFVSRVZjOWd4NmF5clVUV3llVU94T3BxcUhTV2x0ZXhNYUszTlR4anZSdjZld0NxOUUzbWxUMkVFeU5SQ3Jlbkxnci10TF9XOFppa08ta1pZcmptSTVqVFBBaWp1cFplVE1NU0x0YUlaZ3YxeERBMW9tc29YVmIxUWs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:43:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Effect of transcutaneous electro-stimulation in postoperative rehabilitation pain treatment in thoracic surgery: a randomized clinical trial - Trials Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Effect of transcutaneous electro-stimulation in postoperative rehabilitation pain treatment in thoracic surgery: a randomized clinical trial</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 19 December 2024<br/><strong>Source:</strong> <i>Trials</i>, Volume 25, Article number: 839</p><img src="//media.springernature.com/lw685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1186%2Fs13063-024-08613-9/MediaObjects/13063_2024_8613_Fig1_HTML.png" alt="Figure 1" loading="lazy" width="685" height="474"><figcaption>Diagram of the intervention process developed</figcaption><p>Chest pain post-thoracic surgery is challenging to manage, often leading to complications. This study evaluates transcutaneous electrical stimulation (TENS) as part of the rehabilitation protocol for patients after thoracotomy.</p><ul><li>A randomized clinical trial with 109 participants divided into three groups: experimental, control, and placebo.</li><li>Results indicate significant improvement in pain control and spirometry outcomes in the TENS group compared to control and placebo.</li><li>Effects measured using McGill test for pain assessment and spirometry for lung function.</li></ul><blockquote>“The use of TENS leads to an improvement in pain control and spirometry values in patients after thoracic surgery.”</blockquote><p>This study highlights TENS's potential role in enhancing postoperative recovery and suggests it may reduce reliance on analgesics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://trialsjournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13063-024-08613-9</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://trialsjournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13063-024-08613-9</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:34:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia claims it developed first cancer vaccine in big breakthrough, says 'will distribute for free' - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia Claims Breakthrough in Cancer Vaccine Development, Promises Free Distribution</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/cancer-vaccine-1734608833.webp" alt="Russia claims it developed first cancer vaccine in big breakthrough" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>Russia claims it developed the first cancer vaccine in a big breakthrough.</figcaption>
<p>Russia has announced the development of a cancer vaccine claimed to prevent all types of tumors, proving successful in pre-clinical trials. The initiative aims to enhance the immune system's ability to combat cancer cells effectively.</p>
<ul>
<li>The vaccine reportedly boosts the immune system to destroy potential cancer cells before they develop.</li>
<li>Russian President Vladimir Putin discusses the progress in creating this vaccine and related immunomodulatory drugs.</li>
<li>Indian oncologists express caution, noting the vaccine is still in pre-clinical stages and requires further testing.</li>
<li>The technology employs mRNA to target cancer cells, triggering the immune response to eliminate them.</li>
<li>The vaccine is intended for treatment rather than prevention; conventional preventive vaccines against cancer-causing infections are already available.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"If Russia's claim is linked to reality, then it can prove to be a milestone in the history of cancer," said Dr. Shyam Agarwal, Chairman of the Cancer Department at Sir Ganga Ram Hospital.</blockquote>
<p>As Russia prepares to distribute this vaccine for free, the global medical community awaits more detailed human trial data to understand its efficacy and potential impact on cancer treatment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/health/russia-claims-it-developed-first-cancer-vaccine-in-big-breakthrough-says-will-distribute-for-free-2024-12-19-967045</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/health/russia-claims-it-developed-first-cancer-vaccine-in-big-breakthrough-says-will-distribute-for-free-2024-12-19-967045</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:19:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Polio Resurgence In Spain, Germany, and Poland; Virus Detected In Wastewater - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Poliovirus Resurgence In Spain, Germany, and Poland; Nations To Ramp Up Vaccination And Surveillance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p><figure><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Polio-News.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="Poliovirus Resurgence In Spain, Germany, and Poland; Nations To Ramp Up Vaccination And Surveillance" width="900" height="375"><figcaption>Polio Resurgence In Spain, Germany, and Poland; Virus Detected In Wastewater</figcaption></figure><p>Three countries in Europe, Germany, Spain, and Poland, have reported the presence of poliovirus in wastewater, raising concerns over a potential resurgence of the disease.</p><ul><li><strong>Polio Virus Detection Timeline</strong>: The VDPV2 was first detected in Spain in mid-September, followed by detections in Poland on November 18 and in multiple cities in Germany throughout November and early December.</li><li><strong>Public Health Response</strong>: The ECDC and WHO are urging countries to maintain high vaccination rates and enhance surveillance to prevent a possible outbreak.</li></ul><blockquote>“Although cases have significantly decreased, recent wastewater monitoring serves as a concerning reminder of the ongoing risks.”</blockquote><p>Finding the poliovirus in wastewater highlights the need for vigilance in vaccination and public health measures to combat potential outbreaks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/polio-resurgence-in-spain-germany-and-poland-virus-detected-in-wastewater-1164628/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/polio-resurgence-in-spain-germany-and-poland-virus-detected-in-wastewater-1164628/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What are the effects of sex and gender on outcomes after kidney transplantation? - Cochrane]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxOTDYtMk94RU5rQVZaenZ6amQ1OW9zZXhYZVNNbU83OHlZYkFaLXRjSzBvenM1bWJYNDJlQ1FxOEpUSUJMMENJazBpZW9nMmVNSGNtaERSZUxVTGVqNld6ZUNVVUM5aUdLVEJGSjVQNE91Ynh5bldFaFVudC1NYUFwQ1NmYnBjYlVOdG1hQ2JJNTNjOFoyZDZIUmgtRlV2bE9RZkxOOEdJWmlUZWhMSlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxOTDYtMk94RU5rQVZaenZ6amQ1OW9zZXhYZVNNbU83OHlZYkFaLXRjSzBvenM1bWJYNDJlQ1FxOEpUSUJMMENJazBpZW9nMmVNSGNtaERSZUxVTGVqNld6ZUNVVUM5aUdLVEJGSjVQNE91Ynh5bldFaFVudC1NYUFwQ1NmYnBjYlVOdG1hQ2JJNTNjOFoyZDZIUmgtRlV2bE9RZkxOOEdJWmlUZWhMSlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:14:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experience the Incredible Benefits of Black Garlic for Heart Health & Immunity - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPYXE3TlNnN0VOVXAtbnQ5RDgzcS12d3owT25ZdFU4SnJCQXVpWW40TzdxSDkzNWxZWk5abHNSazdQZlllZUxLSm5kN19xdFVUSzhKdFpZeE4xTkVFVzZiTlpJTmpfQjR6ZnBWZ0xndkRJaTJGcTZsVU1lMjc3UHFPdVVFa1lhV0p5V0VOTmlOZER1Z2lUU3VKWXN0SVllR2dIWnBHamRhd3JfNnFGaDlLbjVn0gG6AUFVX3lxTE4xWUd6d0t0c05UMm9pNTZCN3Y0UEFUZm5teVhNZ0stNGU1Ql9vYzQyOFB0VGZFQUhLdGpjTGRNQlVnS3lpc01hcy1GSk9kWWJ5cGtVVnQxY0dYdlJGYzdxakJTeTdUd0hwMUljd1FMbmhOVmhiekoxTU9XcVBIM0VxUXdEZDFSY3FLdFJRUE1aV29odmNwbkhiMlJIaTFiYjJWc2wtQUR3anBibHhkX0t6ZVBjeHJoa1YxQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPYXE3TlNnN0VOVXAtbnQ5RDgzcS12d3owT25ZdFU4SnJCQXVpWW40TzdxSDkzNWxZWk5abHNSazdQZlllZUxLSm5kN19xdFVUSzhKdFpZeE4xTkVFVzZiTlpJTmpfQjR6ZnBWZ0xndkRJaTJGcTZsVU1lMjc3UHFPdVVFa1lhV0p5V0VOTmlOZER1Z2lUU3VKWXN0SVllR2dIWnBHamRhd3JfNnFGaDlLbjVn0gG6AUFVX3lxTE4xWUd6d0t0c05UMm9pNTZCN3Y0UEFUZm5teVhNZ0stNGU1Ql9vYzQyOFB0VGZFQUhLdGpjTGRNQlVnS3lpc01hcy1GSk9kWWJ5cGtVVnQxY0dYdlJGYzdxakJTeTdUd0hwMUljd1FMbmhOVmhiekoxTU9XcVBIM0VxUXdEZDFSY3FLdFJRUE1aV29odmNwbkhiMlJIaTFiYjJWc2wtQUR3anBibHhkX0t6ZVBjeHJoa1YxQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:07:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can infectious bird flu linger in refrigerated raw milk? Here’s what the study reveals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can infectious bird flu linger in refrigerated raw milk? Here’s what the study reveals</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>This article explores the potential for bird flu viruses to survive in refrigerated raw milk, highlighting recent research findings that shed light on this concerning issue.</p><ul><li>Research indicates that avian influenza can survive in refrigerated conditions.</li><li>Raw milk may serve as a medium for the transmission of infectious bird flu.</li><li>Investigation aimed at understanding the implications for food safety and public health.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Understanding the survival of bird flu in dairy products is crucial for preventing outbreaks.”</p></blockquote><p>The findings underscore the importance of monitoring food products and enhancing safety protocols to prevent potential health risks associated with raw milk consumption.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/can-infectious-bird-flu-linger-in-refrigerated-raw-milk-heres-what-the-study-reveals/articleshow/116470140.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/can-infectious-bird-flu-linger-in-refrigerated-raw-milk-heres-what-the-study-reveals/articleshow/116470140.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The risks of late-night sugar: Weight gain, sleep loss, and more - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Risks of Late-Night Sugar: Weight Gain, Sleep Loss, and More</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://indianexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1_bda8f0.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="1280">
<figcaption>An image illustrating the impacts of late-night sugar consumption.</figcaption>
<p>Consuming sugar late at night can lead to various health issues including weight gain, poor sleep, and metabolic disruptions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Late-night sugar intake causes blood sugar spikes and crashes that disturb sleep quality.</li>
  <li>The body focuses on glucose metabolism instead of essential recovery processes like hormonal balance.</li>
  <li>Sugar consumption at night can lower insulin sensitivity, leading to fat storage and weight gain.</li>
  <li>Increased consumption of sugar at night can raise cortisol levels and decrease melatonin, affecting sleep.</li>
  <li>Frequent late-night sugar intake can escalate the risk of sleep disorders, including insomnia and sleep apnoea.</li>
  <li>Sugar can worsen insulin sensitivity in diabetics, increasing risks for serious complications.</li>
  <li>Late-night sugar consumption is linked with heightened risks of type 2 diabetes and heart disease.</li>
  <li>Adopting healthier alternatives and mindful eating can help manage late-night cravings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Emphasize balanced meals, healthy options like fruit or dark chocolate, and mindful eating to control late-night cravings."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, being mindful of sugar consumption at night is vital for maintaining overall health and well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/web-stories/wellness/the-risks-of-late-night-sugar-weight-gain-sleep-loss-and-more/9732469/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/web-stories/wellness/the-risks-of-late-night-sugar-weight-gain-sleep-loss-and-more/9732469/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:45:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1st malaria vaccine shows promise against rising cases: Report - Ten News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxOMUtMOUhNQ1lmdUJtRjlGa1k5MzJZeTl2bEE0d3hDWXVfMndjU254eElrSmR3ZlJucjBUMW52VXo4N2YwV1psYzFHT0RJbmpyc3hPY2ZncDBEajBFMFR6TTRGM3Q3endGbk13TG9JbzRPd0pqR05BZWU4SEpMR1VsY0Z1U2tEeVFy?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxOMUtMOUhNQ1lmdUJtRjlGa1k5MzJZeTl2bEE0d3hDWXVfMndjU254eElrSmR3ZlJucjBUMW52VXo4N2YwV1psYzFHT0RJbmpyc3hPY2ZncDBEajBFMFR6TTRGM3Q3endGbk13TG9JbzRPd0pqR05BZWU4SEpMR1VsY0Z1U2tEeVFy?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:35:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[United States confirms first ‘severe’ case of H5N1 avian flu from backyard poultry - Down To Earth Magazine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Severe Case of H5N1 Avian Flu in the US Linked to Backyard Poultry</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)</p><p>A patient from Louisiana has been hospitalized after being diagnosed with a ‘severe’ case of avian influenza A (H5N1), marking the first report of such a case in the United States traced to exposure from backyard poultry.</p><ul><li>Patient had exposure to sick and dead birds in backyard flocks.</li><li>Total of 61 human cases of H5N1 reported since April 2023, with most presenting mild symptoms.</li><li>Wisconsin reported a presumptive positive human case pending CDC confirmation.</li><li>Viral genome analysis shows the virus belongs to the D1.1 genotype, linked to recent cases in the US and Canada.</li><li>CDC notes that sporadic cases, while rare, can occur from multiple sources including backyard flocks.</li></ul><blockquote>“This case underscores that, in addition to affected commercial poultry and dairy operations, wild birds and backyard flocks also can be a source of exposure,” stated the CDC.</blockquote><p>The increase in H5N1 cases emphasizes the need for continued monitoring of avian influenza, particularly in connection to backyard poultry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/health/united-states-confirms-first-severe-case-of-h5n1-avian-flu-from-backyard-poultry</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.downtoearth.org.in/health/united-states-confirms-first-severe-case-of-h5n1-avian-flu-from-backyard-poultry</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:26:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Journal retracts COVID study in favour of using hydroxychloroquine - Euronews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxQbl9RanFnMC1YRTVRTU5rX1FqY3dJMVVBOXVLTldJbnppVjBxNGowZmdsVlJraHh2UE9wdFdCZzhLMFlLOVhkMDc4dmZYSkQ2aVZmZVFzaGFIRzhvbTJKWVBySzFmbnJ3WG9OZDM1a002eWo4SndaYnM4Vi11VVUzeV9Zck1lYk84aEkwczdnUFNNOXU0c2pCblkwb3ktZlNjQnViUl9XeW5EQ0p6a2JUVXdMR2JyQm40LWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxQbl9RanFnMC1YRTVRTU5rX1FqY3dJMVVBOXVLTldJbnppVjBxNGowZmdsVlJraHh2UE9wdFdCZzhLMFlLOVhkMDc4dmZYSkQ2aVZmZVFzaGFIRzhvbTJKWVBySzFmbnJ3WG9OZDM1a002eWo4SndaYnM4Vi11VVUzeV9Zck1lYk84aEkwczdnUFNNOXU0c2pCblkwb3ktZlNjQnViUl9XeW5EQ0p6a2JUVXdMR2JyQm40LWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:25:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. life spans rebound from pandemic lows, helped by drop in fatal overdoses - Medical Xpress]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2024-12-life-spans-rebound-pandemic-lows.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medicalxpress.com/news/2024-12-life-spans-rebound-pandemic-lows.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:20:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Gut to Brain: How a Common Virus May Trigger Alzheimer’s Disease - SciTechDaily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/from-gut-to-brain-how-a-common-virus-may-trigger-alzheimers-disease/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scitechdaily.com/from-gut-to-brain-how-a-common-virus-may-trigger-alzheimers-disease/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:00:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[France says bird flu-free after month without outbreaks - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxPZWJpUjJNTnBXVjhGZF92WUFvRUlqbUlKVm9ib0dhVkZ2UXFrV1F3anhWQ253T2FQWHljRllJM1l3MnN4RVhkZ2dkcE1rUWxFbmoyeXd0Z3pXLVpndDVfUGNVWHpucVhPN3plMzY2WW93bXAwTzJOUjF0bnkwY1l4Y2VFQlpmbEpSbXVXYmJ0MTNGREJSLThxYjcwTkxpZlVCSHo2bU55aTM3Z0RCd2FNQ0ktU05QYXRYR0lrVEcwODjSAcYBQVVfeXFMTnN5WldfcFltWEVsZ2hFZ2FrUmxjb0x0N055THhEMnR2am92ZGRKSjFJUzM4Ym4tZXlTUXBRcVA5cG1iMmpzaURndjVLVTNYdTJPUGlZY0NqOWFWRVFNV0xrTGlnajM4dHZVNVJ3RldVYWc2LWVzR2hnckprWnE5bHhhLVJ2WFZrRURvT1BCc3FlNHhndGluZlFSYUppZ01mU2ZHSnZHNFIzN3U0NVFpcWFwLWMyaVI3Y3NkRU9SODBCMXAtenpR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxPZWJpUjJNTnBXVjhGZF92WUFvRUlqbUlKVm9ib0dhVkZ2UXFrV1F3anhWQ253T2FQWHljRllJM1l3MnN4RVhkZ2dkcE1rUWxFbmoyeXd0Z3pXLVpndDVfUGNVWHpucVhPN3plMzY2WW93bXAwTzJOUjF0bnkwY1l4Y2VFQlpmbEpSbXVXYmJ0MTNGREJSLThxYjcwTkxpZlVCSHo2bU55aTM3Z0RCd2FNQ0ktU05QYXRYR0lrVEcwODjSAcYBQVVfeXFMTnN5WldfcFltWEVsZ2hFZ2FrUmxjb0x0N055THhEMnR2am92ZGRKSjFJUzM4Ym4tZXlTUXBRcVA5cG1iMmpzaURndjVLVTNYdTJPUGlZY0NqOWFWRVFNV0xrTGlnajM4dHZVNVJ3RldVYWc2LWVzR2hnckprWnE5bHhhLVJ2WFZrRURvT1BCc3FlNHhndGluZlFSYUppZ01mU2ZHSnZHNFIzN3U0NVFpcWFwLWMyaVI3Y3NkRU9SODBCMXAtenpR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:42:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>