<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:19:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:19:55 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Milestone: COVID-19 five years ago - World Health Organization]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Milestone: COVID-19 five years ago</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 31 December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> WHO Media Team</p>
<p>Five years ago on 31 December 2019, WHO’s Country Office in China picked up a media statement by the Wuhan Municipal Health Commission about 'viral pneumonia' cases in Wuhan, which led to the emergence of COVID-19 and its profound impact on global lives.</p>
<ul>
<li>WHO activated emergency systems on 1 January 2020 and informed the world on 4 January.</li>
<li>The first comprehensive guidance was published by WHO between 9-12 January 2020.</li>
<li>On 13 January, WHO collaborated with partners to develop the first SARS-CoV-2 laboratory test.</li>
<li>As we take this milestone moment, we honor those who suffered and died, and express gratitude to healthcare workers.</li>
<li>WHO continues to urge China to share data on COVID-19's origins, vital for future preparedness.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Is the world better prepared for the next pandemic than we were for COVID-19?” - Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus</blockquote>
<p>As we reflect on the past five years, we emphasize the lessons learned to build a healthier future and ensure better preparedness for potential pandemics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.who.int/news/item/30-12-2024-milestone-covid-19-five-years-ago</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.who.int/news/item/30-12-2024-milestone-covid-19-five-years-ago</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 16:35:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Artificial heart patients can regenerate heart muscles: Study - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxQYWRGVHFBNnBpTjRzN0J4OVJsd3p3bzI2OV9PUVZmeUpaSTJ6M0VPTHZzTDM0Q0pia3lqQkV2VTN0TDIwZGt5ekFUdHExNVY0UkxNaVBaMkhTTklhY3dKaVNScFVZOERvMjhYblBZSFJqNmRYV2ppQ0UtMDR1ZkhjZ1dLUG1oRkRqLTRYc0dRWDFKcEVuZ1pxZ293djdRSmF0YXlBStIBqAFBVV95cUxPTU14bmV5cmFRTU9uaHF2TG5BemVsUFlmVEc5MmJPRkVtWmMwMWZ6WF9XM0M2NGVzQjA3OGVzWDRhVFk2c1pGWDVkVkVYRGEwX0JfcEpTYlpVMURnaWY0R2NDVDBDaG13VHl4MzVzTktWblZ6Ykd0a3NGYUd6cm9LX2tPSWJPTEw1OEhqQm1XRlBFS20wT0x5QkNBMTFSYThHWWtKZGR6MVI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxQYWRGVHFBNnBpTjRzN0J4OVJsd3p3bzI2OV9PUVZmeUpaSTJ6M0VPTHZzTDM0Q0pia3lqQkV2VTN0TDIwZGt5ekFUdHExNVY0UkxNaVBaMkhTTklhY3dKaVNScFVZOERvMjhYblBZSFJqNmRYV2ppQ0UtMDR1ZkhjZ1dLUG1oRkRqLTRYc0dRWDFKcEVuZ1pxZ293djdRSmF0YXlBStIBqAFBVV95cUxPTU14bmV5cmFRTU9uaHF2TG5BemVsUFlmVEc5MmJPRkVtWmMwMWZ6WF9XM0M2NGVzQjA3OGVzWDRhVFk2c1pGWDVkVkVYRGEwX0JfcEpTYlpVMURnaWY0R2NDVDBDaG13VHl4MzVzTktWblZ6Ykd0a3NGYUd6cm9LX2tPSWJPTEw1OEhqQm1XRlBFS20wT0x5QkNBMTFSYThHWWtKZGR6MVI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:37:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mediterranean To DASH Diet: Top 7 Healthy Diets You Must Try In 2025 - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mediterranean To DASH Diet: Top 7 Healthy Diets You Must Try In 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2025 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116797660,thumbsize-96084,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116797660.jpg" alt="Mediterranean To DASH Diet: Top 7 Healthy Diets You Must Try In 2025" title="Mediterranean To DASH Diet: Top 7 Healthy Diets You Must Try In 2025">
<figcaption>Mediterranean To DASH Diet: Top 7 Healthy Diets You Must Try In 2025 (Image Credits: iStock)</figcaption>
<p>This article presents seven healthy diets that are popular and effective for 2025, providing insights into their benefits and expert recommendations.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Mediterranean Diet:</strong> Focuses on fresh produce, whole grains, and healthy fats. Supports heart health.</li>
<li><strong>Plant-Based Diet:</strong> Emphasizes vegetables and legumes. Linked to reduced risk of type 2 diabetes.</li>
<li><strong>Flexitarian Diet:</strong> A flexible mix of plant-based and occasional animal products. Sustainable and balanced.</li>
<li><strong>DASH Diet:</strong> Reduces high blood pressure through potassium-rich foods. Supported by research for heart health.</li>
<li><strong>Nordic Diet:</strong> Rich in whole grains and fatty fish. Promotes heart health and reduces inflammation.</li>
<li><strong>Intermittent Fasting (IF):</strong> Focuses on meal timing. Aids in weight management and metabolic health.</li>
<li><strong>Probiotic-Rich Diet:</strong> Includes foods like yogurt and kimchi. Supports gut health and immunity.</li>
</ul>
<p>To get started, choose a diet that fits your lifestyle, consult with a nutrition professional, make gradual changes, and stay consistent.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/health/diet/mediterranean-to-dash-diet-top-7-healthy-diets-you-must-try-in-2025-article-116797673</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/health/diet/mediterranean-to-dash-diet-top-7-healthy-diets-you-must-try-in-2025-article-116797673</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 crucial nutrients for optimal gut health - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/9-crucial-nutrients-for-optimal-gut-health/articleshow/116804555.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/9-crucial-nutrients-for-optimal-gut-health/articleshow/116804555.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smoking Each Cigarette Reduces Life Span By 20 Minutes, Women At Greater Risk, New Study Finds - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/health/smoking-each-cigarette-reduces-life-span-by-20-minutes-women-at-greater-risk-new-study-finds-1740780</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/health/smoking-each-cigarette-reduces-life-span-by-20-minutes-women-at-greater-risk-new-study-finds-1740780</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:01:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How can we manage stress from bossy bosses and deadlines? | Health Wealth, Ep 76 - India Today Podcast]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How can we manage stress from bossy bosses and deadlines? | Health Wealth, Ep 76</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Health Wealth</p><p>This episode discusses the rise of work-related stress in the 21st century, exploring whether we are solving these stressors or simply becoming more obsessed with them. Integrative lifestyle medicine expert Luke Coutinho shares actionable solutions to improve our ability to handle workplace challenges.</p><ul><li>Work-related stress may have increased due to modern demands.</li><li>Luke Coutinho's six pillars for wellness can mitigate stress.</li><li>Adjustments in diet, exercise, sleep, and emotional health are crucial.</li><li>Work should enhance, not govern, our happiness and peace of mind.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ensure work remains a part of life, not the governor of your happiness and peace of mind.”</blockquote><p>Tune in to gain insights into managing stress effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://podcasts.indiatoday.in/health/health-wealth/how-can-we-manage-stress-from-bossy-bosses-and-deadlines-health-wealth-ep-76-1146484-2024-12-30</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://podcasts.indiatoday.in/health/health-wealth/how-can-we-manage-stress-from-bossy-bosses-and-deadlines-health-wealth-ep-76-1146484-2024-12-30</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:29:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FDA approves lenacapavir for HIV treatment; Science journal hails it as 'breakthrough of the year' - The New Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FDA Approves Lenacapavir for HIV Treatment; Science Journal Hails it as 'Breakthrough of the Year'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 30 Dec 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> AP</p><img src='link_to_image' alt='Pharmacist holding a vial of lenacapavir'><figcaption>A pharmacist holds a vial of lenacapavir, the new HIV prevention injectable drug.</figcaption><p>The FDA has approved Lenacapavir, an injectable drug that protects against HIV for six months with each dose, which has been recognized by Science journal as a major breakthrough in combating the HIV/AIDS crisis.</p><ul><li>Lenacapavir provides long-term protection against HIV with biannual injections.</li><li>Science journal labeled it 'breakthrough of the year' for its efficacy in HIV prevention.</li><li>Clinical trials showed 100% efficacy among African adolescent girls and 99.9% among gender-diverse populations.</li><li>HOPE for reducing global HIV infections relies on access and demand for the drug.</li></ul><blockquote>"It has the potential if we can do it right, which means going big and getting it out there." - Linda-Gail Bekker, University of Cape Town</blockquote><p>Lenacapavir represents a significant advancement in HIV prevention, with the potential to transform public health efforts against the epidemic.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/lifestyle/health/2024/Dec/30/fda-approves-lenacapavir-for-hiv-treatment-science-journal-hails-it-as-breakthrough-of-the-year</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newindianexpress.com/lifestyle/health/2024/Dec/30/fda-approves-lenacapavir-for-hiv-treatment-science-journal-hails-it-as-breakthrough-of-the-year</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:49:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sick kids and cold season blues: Ultimate guide for parents to prevent dehydration in children - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Boosting Kids' Immunity: A Parent's Guide to Preventing Dehydration During Illness</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Published on HT Lifestyle</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/fever_child_1643355652919_1735562565898.jpg" alt="Boost your child's immunity this season with these simple hydration hacks.(Photo by Pixabay)" title="Boost your child's immunity this season with these simple hydration hacks.(Photo by Pixabay)">
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Seasonal changes often bring fluctuating weather conditions and an increased risk of illnesses in children, which can lead to dehydration and reduced energy levels.</p>
<ol>
  <li><strong>Dehydration and its impact on immunity:</strong> Pediatric expert Dr. NL Sridhar explains that dehydration can weaken children's immunity and leave them more vulnerable to infections.</li>
  <li><strong>How seasonal illnesses lead to dehydration:</strong> Fever, nausea, and vomiting are common in children during seasonal changes and can result in fluid, electrolyte, and energy deficits.</li>
  <li><strong>Highlighting the role of fluid, electrolyte, and energy (FEE) deficits in supporting recovery:</strong> Dr. NL Sridhar emphasizes the importance of replenishing fluids, electrolytes, and energy to counteract the effects of dehydration.</li>
  <li><strong>The Role of Electrolytes in Recovery:</strong> Electrolytes like sodium, potassium, and magnesium are vital for recovery during seasonal illnesses.</li>
  <li><strong>The Importance of Timely Intervention:</strong> Early identification and management of dehydration and energy deficits can significantly improve recovery in children.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote><strong>Notable Quote:</strong> "Ready-to-drink formulations with a scientifically balanced composition of electrolytes and energy are particularly beneficial as they ensure consistent quality and taste." - Dr. NL Sridhar</blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> Parents should remain vigilant for signs of dehydration and consult pediatricians for appropriate care, prioritizing hydration and addressing energy needs to help children navigate seasonal transitions with resilience and good health.</p>
<p><em>Disclaimer: The information provided in this article are scientific facts only and not a substitute for any professional advice. Please consult a doctor / nutritionist for more information on managing dehydration during infections.</em></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/sick-kids-and-cold-season-blues-ultimate-guide-for-parents-to-prevent-dehydration-in-children-101735561768620.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/sick-kids-and-cold-season-blues-ultimate-guide-for-parents-to-prevent-dehydration-in-children-101735561768620.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:43:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Female Sex Hormone Oestrogen Might Be The Reason Ladies Binge On Alcohol; Study Reveals - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Female Sex Hormone Oestrogen Might Be The Reason Ladies Binge On Alcohol; Study Reveals</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Weill Cornell Medicine</p><img src="https://media.assettype.com/freepressjournal/2024-12-30/8efw3y64/Amisha-2-2024-12-30T190749.946.jpg" alt="Oestrogen and Binge Drinking Study"><figcaption>Oestrogen's Role in Alcohol Consumption</figcaption><p>The study reveals that oestrogen regulates binge drinking in females, highlighting the increase in heavy alcohol consumption among women.</p><ul><li>The research indicates that circulating oestrogen levels affect binge drinking behaviors in females.</li><li>Women have increased their heavy alcohol consumption rates more than men in recent years.</li><li>High oestrogen levels can enhance alcohol's harmful effects.</li><li>The findings may inform new treatments for alcohol use disorder in women.</li></ul><blockquote>“When a female takes her first sip from the bottle containing alcohol, those neurons go crazy.” - Dr. Kristen Pleil</blockquote><p>Understanding the role of oestrogen in alcohol consumption may lead to significant health implications for women.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/lifestyle/female-sex-hormone-oestrogen-might-be-the-reason-ladies-binge-on-alcohol-study-reveals</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/lifestyle/female-sex-hormone-oestrogen-might-be-the-reason-ladies-binge-on-alcohol-study-reveals</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:42:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Needle-Free Shock Syringes for painless medical treatments - Research Matters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxNWnZhSmotaUl2N18taUdhV0M5UnBUNVY5RjV5SHhGdUFZanYzTHVaS3BNQWg2eTJEaF9wZkQ0ek5rSDVUVTVxcXBsUXljeEVCNk4zaHBsWklfWDlQM1Z4LW4zOFE5UmJqQVN2TTVpTVE1dUd1ZkF0NXRCRkg3MU5Eb0k3UUp5ME5mN2g1MUlDUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxNWnZhSmotaUl2N18taUdhV0M5UnBUNVY5RjV5SHhGdUFZanYzTHVaS3BNQWg2eTJEaF9wZkQ0ek5rSDVUVTVxcXBsUXljeEVCNk4zaHBsWklfWDlQM1Z4LW4zOFE5UmJqQVN2TTVpTVE1dUd1ZkF0NXRCRkg3MU5Eb0k3UUp5ME5mN2g1MUlDUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:41:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Your dog could have diabetes. Yes, you read that right - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Your Dog Could Have Diabetes: A Common Yet Often Unnoticed Condition</h1>
<p><strong>Published on Dec 31, 2023 - Source: India Today</strong></p>
<img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2024/12/dogs2itg-1735565018496-scaled_1200_675.jpg" alt="Dogs and cats with diabetes" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>The image shows dogs and cats, highlighting the importance of pet health awareness.</figcaption>
<p>Diabetes in pets, especially dogs and cats, is more common than many pet owners realize. While it's not as prevalent as in humans, it's a serious condition that requires proper management. Sadly, around 20% of pets with diabetes are euthanized within a year of diagnosis due to various factors, including lack of awareness and understanding of the condition.</p>
<ol>
<li>Glucose is the body's main energy source, regulated by insulin, a hormone produced by the pancreas.</li>
<li>In diabetic animals, low insulin levels cause high blood sugar. Middle-aged, obese, and unspayed female dogs are at higher risk.</li>
<li>There are two types of diabetes in pets: Type 1, which is common in dogs but rare in cats, and Type 2, which is the opposite.</li>
<li>Symptoms of diabetes in pets develop gradually but can worsen quickly if untreated. Key signs include increased thirst, urination, appetite, and weight loss.</li>
<li>Cats may develop a flat-footed stance, while dogs are prone to cataracts.</li>
<li>Management of diabetes in pets involves SGLT2 inhibitors for early stages and long-acting insulin injections for advanced cases, along with gradual weight loss and low-carb diets for cats.</li>
<li>Insulin therapy remains the cornerstone of treatment, despite the rarity of diabetes reversal in dogs.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>"Sadly, around 20% of pets with diabetes are euthanized within a year of diagnosis."</blockquote>
<p>Understanding and managing diabetes in pets is crucial for their well-being and longevity. Regular vet check-ups and proper diet management can significantly improve the quality of life for diabetic pets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/health/your-dog-cat-could-have-diabetes-yes-you-read-that-right-198596-30-12-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/health/your-dog-cat-could-have-diabetes-yes-you-read-that-right-198596-30-12-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:36:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study links social inequality to dementia-related changes in brain - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxOcndhSXRtZWk1OHNObDlGeTBiTjVtY2dSMHhxVFJXbXdQOFg4TnU1c2syd1NWQ05jU3AzcjJ2M18xaVZqUkRGaUI4SE1kbWFkR2xOcHYySXBQWmN4ZFdScXFSQzdhM051QVI1NmZGY3JGT0QyWklxbWVVeURyV2hyMHZoeng3bjNwYko5VHhlS1FHNFdvX21TZG1YRWt3OHA3cGx1MjFGOG92ZUpNR3IwRkRjeVRZRlVreDEwdTg2S2NNLXpWM3hQdHl0LUlMSnPSAdQBQVVfeXFMTV9SNEhxbEs2OHhLQ05BdU1rQ1RzTnVxVWo3M0dsZWE2SE0xQTgyY3NNdkNPcjYyUzQwVjNrcldORGF1NDZVU1ZISmI3MjhGQjYtcFYzOWh1Q1ZMemRjVGdMUTZZVHZVMHM2OGE3T3daLXNfSlNJME5PNzZtZGFqM3dzMlQxN2tZYWpvenJQWEFPSGZLT1dRSEZRZGdLVHA2QzZ6LTc2S2YwT3NYVDZQQzFLNWpvNlNQQ0FwM2NNVVQ1ZExfTGtrblFzYWhaWXo3QV9aNC0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxOcndhSXRtZWk1OHNObDlGeTBiTjVtY2dSMHhxVFJXbXdQOFg4TnU1c2syd1NWQ05jU3AzcjJ2M18xaVZqUkRGaUI4SE1kbWFkR2xOcHYySXBQWmN4ZFdScXFSQzdhM051QVI1NmZGY3JGT0QyWklxbWVVeURyV2hyMHZoeng3bjNwYko5VHhlS1FHNFdvX21TZG1YRWt3OHA3cGx1MjFGOG92ZUpNR3IwRkRjeVRZRlVreDEwdTg2S2NNLXpWM3hQdHl0LUlMSnPSAdQBQVVfeXFMTV9SNEhxbEs2OHhLQ05BdU1rQ1RzTnVxVWo3M0dsZWE2SE0xQTgyY3NNdkNPcjYyUzQwVjNrcldORGF1NDZVU1ZISmI3MjhGQjYtcFYzOWh1Q1ZMemRjVGdMUTZZVHZVMHM2OGE3T3daLXNfSlNJME5PNzZtZGFqM3dzMlQxN2tZYWpvenJQWEFPSGZLT1dRSEZRZGdLVHA2QzZ6LTc2S2YwT3NYVDZQQzFLNWpvNlNQQ0FwM2NNVVQ1ZExfTGtrblFzYWhaWXo3QV9aNC0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:31:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Each cigarette smoked steals 20 mins of life expectancy: UCL study - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Each Cigarette Smoked Steals 20 Minutes of Life Expectancy, Reveals UCL Study</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> University College London</p><p>A new research from University College London indicates that each cigarette smoked reduces life expectancy by an average of 20 minutes. The study also found that quitting smoking can significantly recover lost life.</p><ul><li>Every pack of 20 cigarettes smoked correlates with a loss of nearly seven hours of life.</li><li>Quitting smoking on New Year’s Day can reclaim an entire day of life by January 8.</li><li>By mid-February, individuals could recover one full week; by year-end, up to 50 days.</li><li>The UK government is implementing measures to phase out the sale of tobacco to individuals born after January 1, 2009.</li><li>A survey indicates that 53% of smokers plan to quit as part of their 2025 New Year resolutions.</li><li>Smoking is responsible for around 80,000 deaths annually in the UK.</li></ul><blockquote>“Stopping smoking is one of the best things you can do to improve your current and future health.” - Jeanelle de Gruchy, England’s Deputy Chief Medical Officer</blockquote><p>Quitting smoking greatly improves health almost immediately, with benefits such as easier breathing and increased energy levels observed within 72 hours.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/health/quitting-smoking-health-benefits-uk-tobacco-ban-124123000716_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/health/quitting-smoking-health-benefits-uk-tobacco-ban-124123000716_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:07:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Advantage Healthcare & Physiotherapy Expands Women’s Physiotherapy Services - GlobeNewswire]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Advantage Healthcare & Physiotherapy Expands Women’s Physiotherapy Services</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec. 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> GLOBE NEWSWIRE</p>
<img src="https://newsroom.submitmypressrelease.com/system/media_files/images/000/058/796/original_jpeg/unnamed.jpg" alt="Advantage Healthcare and Physiotherapy is a multidisciplinary clinic specialising in physiotherapy and allied health services.">
<figcaption>Advantage Healthcare and Physiotherapy is a multidisciplinary clinic specialising in physiotherapy and allied health services.</figcaption>
<p>Many women have suffered in silence regarding pelvic health issues, but increased awareness is leading to better access to specialized physiotherapy services targeted at these conditions.</p>
<ul>
<li>The clinic is expanding its team of women’s health physiotherapists to meet growing demand.</li>
<li>Specialists offer treatments for conditions including pelvic floor issues, pelvic pain, endometriosis, and urinary incontinence.</li>
<li>Pelvic floor exercises are an effective treatment for urinary incontinence, often recommended before more invasive procedures.</li>
<li>Additionally, the clinic offers pediatric physiotherapy to assist children with developmental challenges.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Helping children with disabilities is a fulfilling job,” said Jenny. “Helping make a difference in their lives and seeing the joy on their faces when they achieve what they previously couldn’t is amazing.”</blockquote>
<p>This expansion of services demonstrates a commitment to enhancing women's health and wellness in the community, addressing often overlooked issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2024/12/30/3002644/0/en/Advantage-Healthcare-Physiotherapy-Expands-Women-s-Physiotherapy-Services.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2024/12/30/3002644/0/en/Advantage-Healthcare-Physiotherapy-Expands-Women-s-Physiotherapy-Services.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As Heart Check-Ups See Big Jump In 2024, Here's How India Plans To Fight Cardiac Diseases - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/year-ender-2024-heart-health-fight-cardiac-diseases-awareness-big-jump-check-ups-india-9171979.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/year-ender-2024-heart-health-fight-cardiac-diseases-awareness-big-jump-check-ups-india-9171979.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IIT Bombay researchers develop needle-free ‘shock’ syringe - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IIT Bombay researchers develop needle-free ‘shock’ syringe</h1>
<p><strong>New Delhi:</strong> Researchers from IIT Bombay have developed a ‘shock’ syringe that delivers medication using shock waves, eliminating the need for needles.</p>
<img src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Syringe.jpg?w=802&amp;enlarge=true" alt="The shock syringes are painless. (Image Credit: kuniharu wakabayashi/DigitalVision/Getty Images)." />
<figcaption>The shock syringes are painless. (Image Credit: kuniharu wakabayashi/DigitalVision/Getty Images).</figcaption>
<p>The device uses a micro shock tube to create a rapid jet stream of liquid that penetrates the skin, allowing for painless drug delivery.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The shock syringe is longer than a regular ballpoint pen and uses pressurized nitrogen to deliver medication.</li>
  <li>Tests on lab rats showed results comparable to conventional syringes.</li>
  <li>Could facilitate quicker vaccination drives and alleviate fears associated with needles, especially for children.</li>
  <li>Less skin damage compared to traditional needle injections, reducing trauma from injections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The shock syringe is designed to deliver the medication rapidly,” - Priyanka Hankare, lead author of the research paper.</blockquote>
<p>This innovation highlights the potential to transform drug delivery methods, pending further research and regulatory approval.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/iit-bombay-researchers-develop-needle-free-shock-syringe-2785434</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/iit-bombay-researchers-develop-needle-free-shock-syringe-2785434</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:49:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Accuracy of ESAT6-CFP10 skin test compared with tuberculin skin test in a healthy population: a randomized, blind, parallel controlled phase III clinical study - BMC Infectious Diseases]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>EC Skin Test Accuracy and Booster Effect Factors</h1>
<p>This randomized, double-blind, parallel-controlled phase III clinical trial evaluated the accuracy of the ESAT6-CFP10 (EC) skin test compared to the tuberculin skin test (TB-PPD) and interferon-gamma release assay (T-SPOT) in a healthy population. The trial also determined factors influencing the booster effect of EC.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The trial was conducted at the Jiangsu Center for Disease Control and Prevention in China.</li>
  <li>Healthy participants aged 18-65 were enrolled and provided written informed consent.</li>
  <li>The experiment was divided into two stages, with the first stage involving all participants undergoing T-SPOT, TB-PPD, and EC tests. In the second stage, tri-negative participants (negative in all three tests) were randomly assigned to receive BCG or placebo vaccinations and underwent the tests again after 12 weeks.</li>
  <li>The primary endpoints were reactions at the injection sites and safety results within 48 hours after the skin tests, while the secondary endpoints were booster effects of skin tests.</li>
  <li>In the first stage, 1,564 participants were enrolled, and in the second stage, 585 tri-negative participants were randomly assigned to the BCG or placebo groups.</li>
  <li>The positivity rates and concordance of the three tests were calculated in both stages, and a logistic regression model was used to determine factors influencing the EC booster effect.</li>
  <li>Safety observations continued until the skin test results were available.</li>
</ul>
<div><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Article Image' width='685' height='450'></div>
<h2>Results</h2>
<ul>
  <li>The positivity rates of the T-SPOT, EC, and TB-PPD tests in the first stage were 18.89%, 10.37%, and 53.96%, respectively. The concordance between the EC and T-SPOT tests was 88.97% (kappa = 0.56), and that between the TB-PPD and T-SPOT tests was 58.19% (kappa = 0.20).</li>
  <li>In the second stage, the overall positivity rates of the T-SPOT, EC, and TB-PPD tests in the tri-negative participants were 5.47%, 8.84%, and 62.11%, respectively. The concordance between the EC and T-SPOT tests was 93.68% (kappa = 0.53), and that between the TB-PPD and T-SPOT tests was 43.37% (kappa = 0.06).</li>
  <li>The factors associated with the EC booster effect were age ≥ 60 years and retest positivity of the T-SPOT test.</li>
  <li>Adverse events occurred in 328 (20.97%) participants in the first stage, with most being local adverse reactions.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Discussion</h2>
<p>The EC skin test showed similar diagnostic performance to the T-SPOT test in the healthy population and was unaffected by BCG vaccination. The booster effects were more likely to occur in populations with retest positivity of the T-SPOT test or age ≥ 60 years.</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> BMC Infectious Diseases, Volume 24, Article number: 1479, 2024</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bmcinfectdis.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12879-024-10302-6</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bmcinfectdis.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12879-024-10302-6</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:40:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drinking coffee every day could have a big impact on your body, according to a new study - Marca.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daily Coffee Consumption Linked to Major Health Benefits</h1><p><strong>Published on Dec 30, 2024 in Marca</strong></p><img src="https://e00-marca.uecdn.es/assets/multimedia/imagenes/2024/12/30/17355576125109.jpg" alt="Coffee" width="360" height="240"><figcaption>Coffee</figcaption><p>Consuming a cup of coffee daily can have significant health impacts, according to a new study.</p><ol><li><strong>Cardiovascular benefits:</strong> Moderate coffee consumption reduces the risk of cardiovascular disease due to antioxidants like polyphenols that improve heart health and blood flow.</li><li><strong>Cognitive performance improvement:</strong> Coffee's caffeine can enhance alertness, concentration, and lower the risk of cognitive decline with age.</li><li><strong>Reducing chronic diseases risk:</strong> Daily coffee consumption is linked to a lower risk of type 2 diabetes and certain cancers due to its anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties.</li></ol>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.marca.com/en/lifestyle/fitness/2024/12/30/677292c7268e3e1a648b4575.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.marca.com/en/lifestyle/fitness/2024/12/30/677292c7268e3e1a648b4575.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surging oestrogen levels could drive women to ‘binge-drink’, mice study suggests - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxOck0xZjJLS2MtNEw0SWFhaGp1THh2X25OamJMWWJjc19RZVpZRGFpQkVYVUdNUDdWYjVjMkxCaFZVb3RCUGMyQkt6QUFTRTdGbmxDaEpJQTJJSTMtVXhfdTVDZEJMcUpvdjg3OVdLS2dwUVVnSEtaZnc4dVloNmJhQlZjMjA1cnFlZG1qc21vMkdZR0tPbFV0VzU2TkdvMHRHcXVhVUdMejY5bkRaemlGTUlZUVRReUtzRVRz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxOck0xZjJLS2MtNEw0SWFhaGp1THh2X25OamJMWWJjc19RZVpZRGFpQkVYVUdNUDdWYjVjMkxCaFZVb3RCUGMyQkt6QUFTRTdGbmxDaEpJQTJJSTMtVXhfdTVDZEJMcUpvdjg3OVdLS2dwUVVnSEtaZnc4dVloNmJhQlZjMjA1cnFlZG1qc21vMkdZR0tPbFV0VzU2TkdvMHRHcXVhVUdMejY5bkRaemlGTUlZUVRReUtzRVRz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:26:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Burnt your mouth? 5 home remedies to heal faster - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Home Remedies to Soothe a Burnt Mouth</h1><p><strong>Published: December 29, 2024 | Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/900x1600/mouth_burn29_1735464198204_1735464208419.jpg" alt="Burnt Mouth" width="720" height="1280"><figcaption>Image: Hindustan Times</figcaption><p>Burnt your mouth on hot food or drinks? Here are some quick and effective home remedies to heal your mouth burn and reduce pain.</p><ol><li>Cold water or ice cubes: Rinse your mouth with cold water or suck on ice cubes to reduce swelling and numb the pain immediately.</li><li>Dairy relief with yogurt or milk: Milk or yogurt cools the burning sensation and creates a protective layer to soothe irritation.</li><li>Honey's healing power: Honey, with its anti-inflammatory properties, helps reduce pain, prevent infection, and promotes faster healing.</li><li>Aloe vera gel for quick relief: Aloe vera’s cooling properties reduce inflammation and speed up healing when applied directly to the burn.</li><li>Saltwater rinse: A simple saltwater rinse cleanses the area and reduces the risk of infection. Rinse several times a day.</li></ol><p>Try these home remedies to find quick relief and speed up the healing process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/lifestyle/burnt-your-mouth-5-home-remedies-to-heal-faster-101735463347594.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/lifestyle/burnt-your-mouth-5-home-remedies-to-heal-faster-101735463347594.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists in Guwahati make breakthrough, fabricate Lysozyme bilayers at room temperature - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists in Guwahati make breakthrough, fabricate Lysozyme bilayers at room temperature</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> PIB press release</p><p>This research by scientists from the IASST in Guwahati demonstrates the fabrication of lysozyme bilayers at room temperature, mimicking natural protein adsorption processes.</p><ul><li>Researchers fabricated lysozyme bilayers on silicon surfaces at room temperature.</li><li>This breakthrough offers insights into ion-mediated protein interactions relevant to implants and biomaterials.</li><li>Lysozyme, found in various bodily fluids, is central to this study.</li><li>The research explains the stabilization mechanisms of lysozyme bilayers through various interactions.</li><li>The findings could enhance understanding of biological protein adsorption on medical devices.</li></ul><blockquote>“This research holds great significance for mimicking biological protein adsorption processes on implanted devices and biomaterials.”</blockquote><p>This study represents a significant advancement in biomaterial science, suggesting potential for improved outcomes in implant technologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/india/scientists-in-guwahati-make-breakthrough-fabricate-lysozyme-bilayers-at-room-temperature/2424907/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/india/scientists-in-guwahati-make-breakthrough-fabricate-lysozyme-bilayers-at-room-temperature/2424907/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:17:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Norovirus cases surge in US: What you need to know about the stomach flu? 10 points - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAJBVV95cUxNTldCNjZZWDhpcHNPQVFpbTFKdWIxUGdncG1Ta1Z2NndZTzhqN0pVeW9kY3Z6eXhUbklKVHZtbk91MEtfVTRPejV5Y2lCd056bUVLTm1NS0VSWVBLM3VXclZPdUhiaUVPcVJVVUNyS1ltb0dia21UM0lrRzMzN3diY01hZGlIaHQ4aV9WRHNwdzNyZHZ0U0gzNDNBMmYwdWRNT0RkamZfMnJIM0E3WVpLZVdBa2FzWDNqeTlSVVNQeHJzMHF1MHlhOVRra3VzdVpCZm5zRTZ2Xzcyb1U2aG1WaTRhejcwcTBIUjlOYWZFM3AxNDFCUnY0QTZzZzJyZlZ5RFRTN1hCVzRyMG11MFR3MjBkLTZEQkZSNmlQcU5PUXB3c0VVQlA2Ng?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAJBVV95cUxNTldCNjZZWDhpcHNPQVFpbTFKdWIxUGdncG1Ta1Z2NndZTzhqN0pVeW9kY3Z6eXhUbklKVHZtbk91MEtfVTRPejV5Y2lCd056bUVLTm1NS0VSWVBLM3VXclZPdUhiaUVPcVJVVUNyS1ltb0dia21UM0lrRzMzN3diY01hZGlIaHQ4aV9WRHNwdzNyZHZ0U0gzNDNBMmYwdWRNT0RkamZfMnJIM0E3WVpLZVdBa2FzWDNqeTlSVVNQeHJzMHF1MHlhOVRra3VzdVpCZm5zRTZ2Xzcyb1U2aG1WaTRhejcwcTBIUjlOYWZFM3AxNDFCUnY0QTZzZzJyZlZ5RFRTN1hCVzRyMG11MFR3MjBkLTZEQkZSNmlQcU5PUXB3c0VVQlA2Ng?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:16:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From smog to stroke: How does air quality affect cardiovascular health? - Passionate In Marketing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxPWmZNRW1mQjlwbU9oQkxOUzlXQkFWc0NKSGI5dEtLZmVkZzBDUnVGdjdoUTRQMVZZUmpFOExfMHp3WEg3Q1ZJU1dYNVFZUEtqQTNWLVRHZXpId1MyeHNGUGM4TTBSa2pydmJpczJlWGVtUWRvWFBFb01POE9tUTZSNkZZc01pcFFqdVIwd19KRVN2R1YwTXNuYzROUDVfY3ZmTFM2RWpQZUsyeXZD?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxPWmZNRW1mQjlwbU9oQkxOUzlXQkFWc0NKSGI5dEtLZmVkZzBDUnVGdjdoUTRQMVZZUmpFOExfMHp3WEg3Q1ZJU1dYNVFZUEtqQTNWLVRHZXpId1MyeHNGUGM4TTBSa2pydmJpczJlWGVtUWRvWFBFb01POE9tUTZSNkZZc01pcFFqdVIwd19KRVN2R1YwTXNuYzROUDVfY3ZmTFM2RWpQZUsyeXZD?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:11:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 ways to healthy bones for a smooth winter pregnancy - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Ways to Ensure Healthy Bones During Winter Pregnancy</h1><p><strong>Published On: </strong> Dec 30, 2024</p><p><strong>Published By: </strong> Shyam Balasubramanian</p><div><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/pregnancy-nutrition-303235348-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=z_HB1JGf9TVMQLiFsgTKs3bAyMzyRah5&amp;size=690:388" width="690" height="388" alt="" title="Representational image (Getty)"><figcaption>Representational image (Getty)</figcaption></div><p>Strong bones are essential for both the expectant mother and the developing baby, ensuring adequate calcium supply and a sturdy skeletal framework. Here are five ways to optimize bone health for winter pregnancy.</p><ul><li><strong>Calcium-rich foods:</strong> Include dairy products, leafy greens, and fortified foods to meet the 1,000 mg calcium requirement during pregnancy.</li><li><strong>Vitamin D:</strong> Aim for sunlight exposure and include fortified foods to aid calcium absorption.</li><li><strong>Low-impact, weight-bearing exercises:</strong> Engage in gentle activities like walking or swimming to maintain bone density.</li><li><strong>Hydration:</strong> Stay hydrated with water and herbal tea to support joint health and bone strength.</li><li><strong>Balanced diet:</strong> Prioritize magnesium and Vitamin K, and avoid smoking while limiting alcohol and caffeine intake.</li></ul><blockquote>Dr Asha Dalal, director at Sir H.N. Reliance Foundation Hospital, emphasizes the importance of a well-rounded nutritional strategy for bone health during pregnancy.</blockquote><p>Maintaining strong bones during pregnancy is crucial, especially in winter, to support both mother and child’s health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/india-today-insight/story/5-ways-to-healthy-bones-for-a-smooth-winter-pregnancy-2657322-2024-12-30</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/india-today-insight/story/5-ways-to-healthy-bones-for-a-smooth-winter-pregnancy-2657322-2024-12-30</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:34:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 magical benefits of Neem oil for the plants and garden - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxNYXVHU3ZhX0dkeGU0RVhiZERoT0FsbmR6azQ5SVZQTDNTS1BJSmFWNTRPUEo4LVJTellPb0NNcjJFdWQtNWNva0hvOFNKSFZ4RG9fU3hpNTA0TWR4amZKeC1ycGFVVWhscU5PX1gzU3JONDQtdEF6a0F3UlJSNFZFczFFeFBySW16MlczWE5iRjZONzZxMlpoZWJkZUZZd3Rrd04wUW95WVpFbml3T25JZGdfdmE4bGVIaGs5VDFNYlVUMEgyRmlHbHlpclZLZjNkSTJhaWw0ZGJ1eXN3eGhjSGZDNk5zalHSAecBQVVfeXFMTWF1R1N2YV9HZHhlNEVYYmREaE9BbG5kems0OUlWUEwzU0tQSUphVjU0T1BKOC1SU3pZT29DTXIyRXVkLTVjb2tIbzhTSkhWeERvX1N4aTUwNE1keGpmSngtcnBhVVVobHFOT19YM1NyTjQ0LXRBemtBd1JSUjRWRXMxRXhQckltejJXM1hOYkY2Tjc2cTJaaGViZGVGWXd0a3dOMFFveVlaRW5pd09uSWRnX3ZhOGxlSGhrOVQxTWJVVDBIMkZpR2x5aXJWS2YzZEkyYWlsNGRidXlzd3hoY0hmQzZOc2pR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxNYXVHU3ZhX0dkeGU0RVhiZERoT0FsbmR6azQ5SVZQTDNTS1BJSmFWNTRPUEo4LVJTellPb0NNcjJFdWQtNWNva0hvOFNKSFZ4RG9fU3hpNTA0TWR4amZKeC1ycGFVVWhscU5PX1gzU3JONDQtdEF6a0F3UlJSNFZFczFFeFBySW16MlczWE5iRjZONzZxMlpoZWJkZUZZd3Rrd04wUW95WVpFbml3T25JZGdfdmE4bGVIaGs5VDFNYlVUMEgyRmlHbHlpclZLZjNkSTJhaWw0ZGJ1eXN3eGhjSGZDNk5zalHSAecBQVVfeXFMTWF1R1N2YV9HZHhlNEVYYmREaE9BbG5kems0OUlWUEwzU0tQSUphVjU0T1BKOC1SU3pZT29DTXIyRXVkLTVjb2tIbzhTSkhWeERvX1N4aTUwNE1keGpmSngtcnBhVVVobHFOT19YM1NyTjQ0LXRBemtBd1JSUjRWRXMxRXhQckltejJXM1hOYkY2Tjc2cTJaaGViZGVGWXd0a3dOMFFveVlaRW5pd09uSWRnX3ZhOGxlSGhrOVQxTWJVVDBIMkZpR2x5aXJWS2YzZEkyYWlsNGRidXlzd3hoY0hmQzZOc2pR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New insights into prevalence and risk factors of anemia among women of reproductive age in China - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prevalence and Risk Factors of Anemia in Chinese Women of Reproductive Age</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024-12-18<br><strong>Source:</strong> <a href='https://doi.org/10.1007/s11684-024-1070-x'>Frontiers of Medicine</a></p>
<div><img src='https://d2jx2rerrg6sh3.cloudfront.net/image-handler/picture/2017/3/Obesity-Jakub_Cejpek_ead0fb8492f0437f96e9fd842630990c-620x480.jpg' alt='New insights into prevalence and risk factors of anemia among women of reproductive age in China' width='620' height='480' /></div>
<p>Anemia significantly impacts global public health, with over 571 million women at risk of adverse health outcomes due to iron deficiency and other causes. This nationwide, population-based study in China aims to estimate the prevalence of anemia among women of reproductive age, explore geographic variations, and investigate the association between anemia and metabolic factors, particularly overweight and obesity. The study utilizes data from the Meinian Healthcare Group system, providing insights into the epidemiological characteristics of anemia and contributing to the development of targeted intervention strategies.</p>
<ul><li>Between 2019 and 2021, the global prevalence of anemia in women showed a minimal decline, with the prevalence increasing from 28.5% in 2013 to 29.9% in 2019. Anemia results from multiple conditions, including nutrient deficiencies and chronic infections.</li><li>In China, the prevalence of anemia varies by demographic and geographic regions, with a rising risk observed since 2010. The study focuses on non-pregnant women aged 18-49, defining anemia as a hemoglobin concentration &lt;120.0 g/L, adjusted for altitude. The prevalence of anemia was categorized into mild, moderate, and severe, with 41.5% classified as moderate and worse.</li><li>Geographic variations in anemia prevalence are significant, with the highest prevalence in Xizang and the lowest in Guizhou. The study also finds a positive association between anemia and impaired kidney function and a history of cesarean delivery, while overweight and obesity are negatively associated with overall anemia but positively associated with moderate and worse anemia. The findings suggest that metabolic factors play a role in the prevalence of anemia, highlighting the need for comprehensive strategies that address both anemia and metabolic disorders.</li><li>Despite these limitations, the study provides robust estimates of anemia prevalence and underscores the importance of considering geographic and metabolic factors in anemia reduction strategies. The findings call for increased attention to anemia among women of reproductive age and suggest that managing metabolic risk factors could be crucial in reducing the burden of anemia.</li>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20241230/New-insights-into-prevalence-and-risk-factors-of-anemia-among-women-of-reproductive-age-in-China.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/news/20241230/New-insights-into-prevalence-and-risk-factors-of-anemia-among-women-of-reproductive-age-in-China.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Problem Peeing? 6 Things All Men Should Know About Enlarged Prostate - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Problem Peeing? 6 Things All Men Should Know About Enlarged Prostate</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/prostate-issues-men-1.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="Problem Peeing? 6 Things All Men Should Know About Enlarged Prostate" width="900" height="375">
  <figcaption>Prostate gland is present outside the bladder surrounding the urethra. When it begins to get enlarged, usually after 40, it can squeeze the urethra, making it difficult to pass urine. (Photo: Freepik)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>After the age of 40, men should be vigilant about their health, especially regarding urinary issues that could indicate an enlarged prostate, a common condition requiring medical attention.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Prostate enlargement can result in various urinary symptoms.</li>
  <li>Symptoms include poor urine stream, interrupted flow, and frequent urination.</li>
  <li>Diagnosis typically involves physical exams, blood tests, and PSA tests.</li>
  <li>Treatment options range from medications to surgery.</li>
  <li>Lifestyle changes, such as diet and exercise, can help manage symptoms.</li>
  <li>Immediate medical attention is required for severe or sudden symptoms.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"One should not hesitate to consult a urologist if he is experiencing symptoms of an enlarged prostate. Early diagnosis and treatment can significantly improve quality of life." - Dr. Amit Saple</blockquote>
<p>It is crucial for men over 40 to remain proactive about prostate health to prevent complications, including the potential for prostate cancer.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/problem-peeing-6-things-all-men-should-know-about-enlarged-prostate-1168208/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/diseases-conditions/problem-peeing-6-things-all-men-should-know-about-enlarged-prostate-1168208/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pune’s first robotic-assisted hip replacement improves recovery and mobility for patients - Healthcare Radius]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pune's First Robotic-Assisted Hip Replacement Surgery</h1>
<p><strong>Date: November 27, 2024<br>Source: Healthcare Radius</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.healthcareradius.in/cloud/2024/12/30/YQOee3KZ-Untitled-design-56-1200x675.jpg" alt="Dr. Abhijit Agashe" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Dr. Abhijit Agashe, Consultant Orthopedic and Joint Replacement Surgeon at Sahyadri Hospitals</figcaption>
<p>Pune's first robotic-assisted hip replacement surgery, using the direct anterior approach, was successfully completed at Sahyadri Hospitals. A 65-year-old patient diagnosed with hip avascular necrosis (AVN) underwent the procedure and was discharged with excellent post-operative progress.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The robotic system combined with the direct anterior approach provided unparalleled precision and safety.</li>
  <li>Patients experienced reduced pain, quicker recovery, and more natural movement post-surgery.</li>
  <li>Immediate postoperative mobility significantly improved the quality of life for patients with AVN hip.</li>
  <li>The robotic system enabled customized surgery plans tailored to each patient's specific anatomy.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Dr. Abhijit Agashe said, “This method has not only enhanced functional outcomes but has also allowed immediate postoperative mobility, significantly improving the quality of life for patients with AVN Hip.”</blockquote>
<p>This breakthrough in orthopedic surgery sets a new standard in the field, particularly beneficial for those suffering from hip problems.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.healthcareradius.in/features/surgery/punes-first-robotic-assisted-hip-replacement-sets-new-standard-in-orthopedic-surgery</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcareradius.in/features/surgery/punes-first-robotic-assisted-hip-replacement-sets-new-standard-in-orthopedic-surgery</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stigma around TB kills more women than men: Reliance Foundation Hospital study - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxPUTFleVgxc19FSkVjeUhNZUlVbl9fbldic00yNlFzUkxiLThKemxZVERyZ1E4OWlkQ0VmS294a1B4R2xpSW13VWs1TDFVMkdYTGU2RnVDU0NsTG8yQlRQQ2hkM1ZOdG9GbjE2M2xZZ1IwTi1idjFIMGI1OTRxdmlHZXk1YkdhWnVXZERQclY5bW13c2otS1lVR3hiVE9oa040ekZ6VHUweTR5M2FMN0d3R2ZkSHpGaTBhUmMxMUhPWEYxa2V6aXdHNlZSb3Y1aXQwUWZDMHREeWxmeWRVR2040gHkAUFVX3lxTE0tcldqc1RJMGFxYjE3RG1jWWhiTkduZVFwYldCT1pibnBneFdUcm9wdmVtVHVLR2hFOVRTeW00U3pMQmNrTE1VaHU0NDM2VVdrZXRKSXFPb08tRUdvUGlDRG9KSkYtSllaa0YzUkgxZE16N0VGSjFpUEc5LTN0T2VoRFJZU2FudEFBQzNPeFdHTllrSnhSdGVNOVN2R1VSaW5FelNmS3lJb3E0LVA3SFVhMk16VnQ4dHJidmlYUEc5M19hejItTTdLRkJkd1ZHXy1vVGE0ZkR6VzYzR2Q4dW5xMThxdQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxPUTFleVgxc19FSkVjeUhNZUlVbl9fbldic00yNlFzUkxiLThKemxZVERyZ1E4OWlkQ0VmS294a1B4R2xpSW13VWs1TDFVMkdYTGU2RnVDU0NsTG8yQlRQQ2hkM1ZOdG9GbjE2M2xZZ1IwTi1idjFIMGI1OTRxdmlHZXk1YkdhWnVXZERQclY5bW13c2otS1lVR3hiVE9oa040ekZ6VHUweTR5M2FMN0d3R2ZkSHpGaTBhUmMxMUhPWEYxa2V6aXdHNlZSb3Y1aXQwUWZDMHREeWxmeWRVR2040gHkAUFVX3lxTE0tcldqc1RJMGFxYjE3RG1jWWhiTkduZVFwYldCT1pibnBneFdUcm9wdmVtVHVLR2hFOVRTeW00U3pMQmNrTE1VaHU0NDM2VVdrZXRKSXFPb08tRUdvUGlDRG9KSkYtSllaa0YzUkgxZE16N0VGSjFpUEc5LTN0T2VoRFJZU2FudEFBQzNPeFdHTllrSnhSdGVNOVN2R1VSaW5FelNmS3lJb3E0LVA3SFVhMk16VnQ4dHJidmlYUEc5M19hejItTTdLRkJkd1ZHXy1vVGE0ZkR6VzYzR2Q4dW5xMThxdQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:38:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An exploration of healthcare professionals’ knowledge and perceived barriers about acute oxygen therapy: a survey in a tertiary care hospital, Sudan - BMC Medical Education]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-024-06533-5</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-024-06533-5</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:38:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>