<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:25:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:25:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases LIVE: ‘Virus not new, no need to panic’, says govt as #lockdown trends on X - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV cases LIVE: ‘Virus not new, no need to panic’, says govt as #lockdown trends on X</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/hmpv_virus_india__1736157385724_1736157385994.jpg" alt="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat." title="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.">
<figcaption>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</figcaption>
<p>The government reassured the public that HMPV is not a new virus after confirming three cases in India. Health experts emphasize there is no need to panic as the virus resembles a regular flu.</p>
<ul>
<li>Three cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) confirmed in India, two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</li>
<li>Cases detected in children; health officials stress that there is no cause for alarm.</li>
<li>Regular flu shots provide immunity; HMPV is not as transmissible as Covid-19.</li>
<li>Health ministry reports no unusual surge in related respiratory illnesses in the country.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“HMPV has been circulating for years and there is no reason to panic.” – Health Minister JP Nadda</blockquote>
<p>The health officials are actively monitoring the situation, ensuring preparedness to handle any potential increase in respiratory illnesses.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:53:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Global HMPV Tracker: Karnataka, Maharashtra, Delhi Issue Guidelines As 3 Cases Reported In India - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Global HMPV Tracker: Karnataka, Maharashtra, Delhi Issue Guidelines As 3 Cases Reported In India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>Three cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) were confirmed in India, marking the first reported instances of the virus in the country. The Union health ministry is monitoring the situation closely.</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/1c0t3qog_covid-india_625x300_27_December_22.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738"><figcaption>Image showing a health alert regarding respiratory viruses</figcaption><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Confirmed cases in Bengaluru and Ahmedabad.</li><li>Guidelines issued by Karnataka, Maharashtra, and Delhi governments.</li><li>Most of the Indian population is reportedly immune to HMPV.</li></ul><blockquote>“HMPV is not a new virus. It has been part of the circulating flu virus in India for long.” - Dr. Harshal R Salve</blockquote><p>The outbreak has prompted precautions similar to those taken during the COVID-19 pandemic, as health officials remain vigilant.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-hmpv-tracker-karnataka-maharashtra-issue-guidelines-amid-rising-cases-china-hmpv-virus-scare-bengaluru-virus-7409815</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-hmpv-tracker-karnataka-maharashtra-issue-guidelines-amid-rising-cases-china-hmpv-virus-scare-bengaluru-virus-7409815</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:26:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV virus cases LIVE: 3 cases in India; experts say virus old, ‘don’t unnecessarily panic' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: ‘Virus not new, no need to panic’, says govt as #lockdown trends on X</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/hmpv_virus_india__1736157385724_1736157385994.jpg" alt="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat." title="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat."><figcaption>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</figcaption></div><p>The Indian government confirmed three cases of the Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in children, urging the public not to panic as this virus has been known for years.</p><ul><li>Three cases of HMPV confirmed in India: two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</li><li>All cases detected in children without recent travel history.</li><li>Health minister reassures public about the virus being non-new and similar to flu.</li><li>Health experts highlight flu shots as a form of immunity against HMPV.</li><li>No immediate cause for alarm, according to health officials and experts.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no need to panic over HMPV as it is not a new pathogen and results in regular flu-like symptoms.” - Union Health Minister JP Nadda</blockquote><p>The government is taking measures to monitor the situation and ensure public safety. The public is encouraged to follow standard health precautions to prevent respiratory infections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:04:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV virus cases LIVE: 3 cases in India; Karnataka issues advisory titled ‘Do Not Panic’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: 3 cases in India; Karnataka issues advisory titled ‘Do Not Panic’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/hmpv_virus_india__1736157385724_1736157385994.jpg" alt="HMPV Virus confirmation in India" title="HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat."><figcaption>HMPV Virus Cases LIVE: India has confirmed three cases of HMPV so far - two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat.</figcaption><p>India has confirmed its first three cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), prompting health officials to reassure the public that the virus is akin to regular flu and not a new threat.</p><ul><li>Three cases of HMPV have been confirmed in India: two in Karnataka and one in Gujarat, all in children.</li><li>Health officials emphasize that HMPV is not a new pathogen, and flu and Covid vaccinations provide immunity.</li><li>The Karnataka government has issued an advisory titled 'Do Not Panic, Be Aware'.</li><li>Symptoms resemble those of the common cold, with serious cases leading to bronchitis or pneumonia.</li><li>Experts highlight the importance of routine surveillance and public awareness about HMPV.</li></ul><blockquote>“HMPV is an existing flu virus causing respiratory issues and is not a cause for panic,” said Karnataka Health Minister Dinesh Gundu Rao.</blockquote><p>This outbreak underscores the need for vigilance and proper health measures as health authorities monitor and respond to HMPV cases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-virus-cases-live-news-global-human-metapneumovirus-hmpv-tracker-government-guidelines-symptoms-latest-updates-today-101736152619898.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:55:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 longevity goals to set for a healthier, happier 2025 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Longevity Goals to Set for a Healthier, Happier 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116995092,imgsize-18438,width-400,resizemode-4/116995092.jpg" alt="7 longevity goals to set for a healthier, happier 2025" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>7 longevity goals to improve health and happiness in 2025.</figcaption><p>As the new year approaches, it's a great time to lay out wellness and happiness goals to make 2025 memorable. Focusing on longevity involves adding quality to your years, not just quantity.</p><ul><li>Walk 10,000 steps every day to stay fit and healthy.</li><li>Get proper sleep, aiming for 7 to 8 hours each night.</li><li>Try new hobbies to keep your brain engaged and active.</li><li>Drink plenty of water—8 liters a day is recommended.</li><li>Eat healthy food to maintain energy and productivity.</li><li>Socialize and connect with friends and communities.</li><li>Laugh regularly, as laughter is a great mood booster.</li></ul><blockquote>“Laughter is the best medicine.”</blockquote><p>By setting these goals, you can focus on both health and happiness, making the upcoming year one to cherish.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/7-longevity-goals-to-set-for-a-healthier-happier-2025/articleshow/116995069.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/7-longevity-goals-to-set-for-a-healthier-happier-2025/articleshow/116995069.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Global HMPV Tracker: Karnataka, Maharashtra, Delhi Issue Guidelines As Cases Rise - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Global HMPV Tracker: Karnataka, Maharashtra, Delhi Issue Guidelines As Cases Rise</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Recent</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Union Health Ministry</p><p>The article reports the first confirmed cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in India, with cases in Bengaluru and Ahmedabad. The Union health ministry is proactively monitoring the situation.</p><ul><li>Three cases of HMPV confirmed in India.</li><li>Affected infants are from Bengaluru and Ahmedabad, with no recent travel history.</li><li>Karnataka, Maharashtra, and Delhi governments have issued preparedness guidelines.</li><li>HMPV is a respiratory virus recognized worldwide, particularly affecting young children and those with weakened immune systems.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Indian Council of Medical Research (IMCR) will continue to track trends in HMPV circulation throughout the year.”</blockquote><p>The emergence of HMPV cases underscores the need for vigilant health measures and monitoring.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-hmpv-tracker-karnataka-maharashtra-issue-guidelines-amid-rising-cases-china-hmpv-virus-scare-bengaluru-virus-7409815</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-hmpv-tracker-karnataka-maharashtra-issue-guidelines-amid-rising-cases-china-hmpv-virus-scare-bengaluru-virus-7409815</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:00:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can antibiotics work against HMPV virus? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxNV3BrVl9lZmx4T0pOS2tya3UtSm1sQTFVN054Tk45UzM4dW1zMmZqZ2lPSmctc09IVWViVjIzS2dWTmgwdnBVRzVEM2lyTEVmd192OXBVeVh6LVhJM2hnM2dxZFpTUzJobWVkS1lOZVRwZmZDR0N0dXdRdHNJZHg5MlpmQUExd1YzNmJxZ2dfR1FsVURhWGl3UXgyWU5CS05tNnR6Yk5jQnJETDFZaGc3OGNiODdTYk9UVFNkQWo4UkNLVEpScm5MalhpZ1FsNXJMdXFTS3Fn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxNV3BrVl9lZmx4T0pOS2tya3UtSm1sQTFVN054Tk45UzM4dW1zMmZqZ2lPSmctc09IVWViVjIzS2dWTmgwdnBVRzVEM2lyTEVmd192OXBVeVh6LVhJM2hnM2dxZFpTUzJobWVkS1lOZVRwZmZDR0N0dXdRdHNJZHg5MlpmQUExd1YzNmJxZ2dfR1FsVURhWGl3UXgyWU5CS05tNnR6Yk5jQnJETDFZaGc3OGNiODdTYk9UVFNkQWo4UkNLVEpScm5MalhpZ1FsNXJMdXFTS3Fn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Long COVID Breakthrough: Spike Proteins Persist in Brain for Years - SciTechDaily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Long COVID Breakthrough: Spike Proteins Persist in Brain for Years</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 29 November 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Cell Host & Microbe</p><p>Researchers have discovered that the SARS-CoV-2 spike protein persists in the brain and skull bone marrow for years after infection, potentially leading to chronic inflammation and neurodegenerative diseases.</p><h4>Key Points:</h4><ul><li>The SARS-CoV-2 spike protein can linger in the brain’s protective layers and skull bone marrow for up to four years.</li><li>The spike protein's presence may lead to chronic inflammation and increased risk of neurodegenerative diseases.</li><li>mRNA vaccines significantly reduce spike protein levels in the brain.</li><li>The research employs a novel AI-powered imaging technique to visualize previously undetectable spike protein distributions.</li><li>Approximately 400 million individuals globally may carry significant amounts of spike protein caused by Long COVID.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is not just an individual health issue – it is a societal challenge.” – Prof. Ali Ertürk</blockquote><p>The findings open new avenues for diagnosing and treating long-term neurological effects of COVID-19 and suggest a need for further research and therapeutic interventions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/long-covid-breakthrough-spike-proteins-persist-in-brain-for-years/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scitechdaily.com/long-covid-breakthrough-spike-proteins-persist-in-brain-for-years/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 09:18:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases in India: After Bengaluru, Gujarat reports its first case; third nationwide - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gujarat Reports First Human Metapneumovirus Case in India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<div>
  <figure>
    <img height="225" width="300" alt="Covid pandemic hmpv virus surge china" src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116989099,width-300,height-225,imgsize-2683349,resizemode-75/covid-pandemic-hmpv-virus-surge-china.jpg">
    <figcaption>Gujarat reports its first HMPV case (Representational image)</figcaption>
  </figure>
</div>
<p>Gujarat has confirmed its first case of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), making it the third case in India. The Health Ministry reassures the public amidst rising respiratory illness concerns.</p>
<ul>
  <li>First HMPV case confirmed in Gujarat, two prior cases in Bengaluru.</li>
  <li>No need for public panic, robust surveillance systems in place.</li>
  <li>Kerala advises caution for vulnerable populations due to reports of an outbreak in China.</li>
  <li>ICMR assures no significant increase in related respiratory illnesses in India.</li>
  <li>Refresh on HMPV's global circulation and current cases in the country.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Health Minister Veena George emphasizes: "We should all pay attention to some things... There are no reports of any viruses likely to become a pandemic or spread quickly at this time."</blockquote>
<p>Authorities stress monitoring and caution, particularly for those most at risk, while ensuring the public remains informed and calm.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/hmpv-case-gujarat-first-human-metapneumovirus-case-bengaluru-gujarat-reports-its-first-case-third-in-india/articleshow/116989120.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/hmpv-case-gujarat-first-human-metapneumovirus-case-bengaluru-gujarat-reports-its-first-case-third-in-india/articleshow/116989120.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 08:42:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2 Babies Diagnosed With HMPV Virus In Bengaluru, No Travel History: Centre - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Two Babies Diagnosed With HMPV Virus In Bengaluru</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today <strong>Source:</strong> The Centre</p><p>The report highlights two cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in Bengaluru, marking the first occurrences in India. One of the infants has been discharged, while the other is still recovering.</p><ul><li>3-month-old and 8-month-old babies diagnosed with HMPV.</li><li>No recent travel history for affected families.</li><li>HMPV monitoring initiated by ICMR and related health bodies.</li><li>Health Ministry convened a meeting for preparedness against HMPV.</li><li>The virus can lead to mild respiratory symptoms but may cause serious complications.</li></ul><blockquote>“Both cases were identified through routine surveillance for multiple respiratory viral pathogens...” - Centre statement</blockquote><p>The monitoring of HMPV and respiratory viruses is crucial, especially in light of the increase in respiratory illnesses observed in other regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/3-month-old-and-8-month-old-babies-diagnosed-with-hmpv-in-bengaluru-7409670</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/3-month-old-and-8-month-old-babies-diagnosed-with-hmpv-in-bengaluru-7409670</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 06:11:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV virus in India: 8-month-old baby tests positive for HMPV in Bengaluru - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV in India: 8-month-old baby tests positive for HMPV in Bengaluru</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 06, 2025 11:23 am IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/djkwef/article69067139.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20250104237L.jpg" alt="A teacher of Gurukul School Of Art at Lalbaug in Mumbai makes a painting on the Human Meta-pneumo Virus (HMPV) outbreak in China, on January 4, 2024." title="A teacher of Gurukul School Of Art at Lalbaug in Mumbai makes a painting on the Human Meta-pneumo Virus (HMPV) outbreak in China, on January 4, 2024." /><figcaption>A teacher of Gurukul School Of Art at Lalbaug in Mumbai makes a painting on the Human Meta-pneumo Virus (HMPV) outbreak in China. Photo Credit: DEEPAK SALVI</figcaption><p>Karnataka has reported the first case of Human Meta-pneumo Virus (HMPV) with an eight-month-old baby testing positive at a private hospital in Bengaluru.</p><ul><li>The baby tested positive for HMPV and Human Rhinovirus/Enterovirus on January 3, according to tests from Baptist Hospital.</li><li>The sample has been sent to the National Institute of Virology for further confirmation.</li><li>Karnataka’s Principal Secretary stated that HMPV typically affects children under 11 and doesn't require immediate panic.</li><li>A meeting has been convened on January 6 to discuss the situation.</li></ul><blockquote>“This may not be the first case as monitoring was not being done earlier. However, there is no need to panic as HMPV is like any other respiratory virus, which causes common cold and flu-like symptoms.” - Harsh Gupta</blockquote><p>Authorities are monitoring the situation closely while encouraging public awareness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/bangalore/eight-month-old-baby-tests-positive-for-hmpv-in-bengaluru-private-hospital/article69067099.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/bangalore/eight-month-old-baby-tests-positive-for-hmpv-in-bengaluru-private-hospital/article69067099.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First HMPV cases in India: Two Bengaluru infants test positive - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First HMPV Cases in India: Two Bengaluru Infants Test Positive</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p>
<p>Two infants from Bengaluru have tested positive for Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), marking the first reported cases of this virus in India.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The infants were hospitalized with respiratory symptoms.</li>
  <li>Health experts are raising awareness about HMPV and its transmission methods.</li>
  <li>HMPV can lead to severe respiratory illnesses, particularly in young children and the elderly.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p>"HMPV is known to cause respiratory infections that can be serious, especially in vulnerable populations." - Health Official</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emergence of HMPV highlights the need for public vigilance and proper healthcare practices to manage respiratory diseases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/8-month-old-baby-tests-positive-for-hmpv-in-bengaluru/articleshow/116982378.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/8-month-old-baby-tests-positive-for-hmpv-in-bengaluru/articleshow/116982378.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8-month-old at Bengaluru hospital is first suspected HMPV case in India - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru Hospital Reports First Suspected Case of HMPV in India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 06, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/photo-1584036561566-baf8f5f1b144_1720449114783_1736137371745.jpg" alt="HMPV primarily affects children and is known to be present in about 0.7 per cent of flu cases globally.(Representational Image)" title="HMPV primarily affects children and is known to be present in about 0.7 per cent of flu cases globally.(Representational Image)"><figcaption>HMPV primarily affects children and is known to be present in about 0.7 per cent of flu cases globally.(Representational Image)</figcaption><p>An eight-month-old infant is suspected to have tested positive for Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) at a hospital in Bengaluru. The infant's family has no recent travel history and shows no concerning symptoms.</p><ul><li>The infant's sample was collected on January 2, 2025.</li><li>The state health department has not verified the results but trusts the private facility's testing accuracy.</li><li>HMPV is known to primarily affect children and is present in approximately 0.7% of global flu cases.</li><li>Health officials in Karnataka have stated they lack detailed information on the specific strain.</li><li>There are current concerns regarding HMPV's spread in China, but health authorities claim there is nothing to alarm about.</li></ul><blockquote>“We trust the accuracy of their testing procedures,” - health department official.</blockquote><p>This case marks a significant development in public health as the first suspected instance of HMPV in India, highlighting the need for awareness and monitoring of respiratory infections, especially with ongoing concerns about viral outbreaks globally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/bengaluru-news/8monthold-at-bengaluru-hospital-is-first-suspected-hmpv-case-in-india-101736136908266.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/bengaluru-news/8monthold-at-bengaluru-hospital-is-first-suspected-hmpv-case-in-india-101736136908266.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 04:41:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Early Morning Routine To Dinner, This Full-Day Meal Plan Will Keep You Healthy In Winter - NDTV Food]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Full-Day Meal Plan for Healthy Winter Eating</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Food</p><div><p>Winter poses health challenges such as dry skin and reduced immunity. Dietitian Manpreet Kalra shares a balanced meal plan focused on seasonal foods to maintain warmth and vitality during this season.</p></div><h2>Here's Ideal Full-Day Meal Plan For Winter, Suggested By Expert:</h2><ol><li><strong>Morning:</strong> Start with a cup of coriander seeds water for detoxification and improved digestion.</li><li><strong>Breakfast:</strong> Enjoy vegetable poha for energy and nourishment.</li><li><strong>Mid-Morning Snack:</strong> Drink black carrot kanji for gut health.</li><li><strong>Lunch:</strong> Have methi & bajra stuffed rotis with mint-coriander chutney for a wholesome meal.</li><li><strong>Post-Lunch:</strong> Sip fennel-ajwain water to aid digestion.</li><li><strong>Evening Snack:</strong> Green tea with roasted makhana for antioxidants and protein.</li><li><strong>Dinner:</strong> Conclude with broccoli & carrot soup for a light, nutritious end to the day.</li></ol><h3>Best Winter Picks for Specific Health Needs:</h3><ul><li>Thyroid Health: Kalonji and coriander seeds tea.</li><li>Diabetes: Methi and bajra-stuffed roti.</li><li>Gut Health: Black carrot kanji.</li><li>Skin Health: Red carrot salad.</li><li>Immunity: Fresh ginger and turmeric tea.</li><li>Hair Health: Aliv seeds ladoo.</li></ul><p>Dietitian Manpreet Kalra’s meal plan advocates a healthy, seasonal diet for overall well-being in winter.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://food.ndtv.com/health/from-early-morning-routine-to-dinner-this-full-day-meal-plan-will-keep-you-healthy-in-winter-7406812</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://food.ndtv.com/health/from-early-morning-routine-to-dinner-this-full-day-meal-plan-will-keep-you-healthy-in-winter-7406812</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 04:03:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What US Surgeon General says about drinking and cancer risk - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Surgeon General Warns About Alcohol and Cancer Risks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Last Week<br /><strong>Source:</strong> The New York Times</p><p>According to a new report by the US Surgeon General, alcohol is the third leading preventable cause of cancer in the United States, prompting a call for warning labels on alcoholic beverages similar to those on cigarettes.</p><ul><li>Alcohol use is linked to 100,000 cancer cases and 20,000 related deaths annually.</li><li>The report presents evidence that even moderate drinking can increase cancer risks for breast, mouth, and throat cancers.</li><li>Four mechanisms by which alcohol leads to cancer include DNA damage, oxidation and inflammation, increased carcinogen absorption from tobacco, and hormone production.</li><li>Types of cancers associated with alcohol use include breast, colon, esophagus, liver, mouth, throat, and larynx cancers.</li></ul><blockquote>“The risk for cancers of the breast, the mouth and the throat may rise with consumption of as little as one drink a day.” - Dr. Vivek Murthy</blockquote><p>The report details that the likelihood of developing an alcohol-related cancer increases with the amount consumed, emphasizing the importance of public awareness regarding alcohol and cancer risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-health/what-us-surgeon-general-says-about-drinking-and-cancer-risk-9761683/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-health/what-us-surgeon-general-says-about-drinking-and-cancer-risk-9761683/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 03:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After HMPV outbreak in China, Maharashtra intensifies surveillance for respiratory disease cases - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maharashtra Boosts Surveillance Following HMPV Outbreak in China</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 06, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/Necessary-precautions-are-being-implemented--and-c_1736103115159.jpeg" alt="Necessary precautions are being implemented, and citizens should not panic. As of now, no cases of HMPV have been reported in Maharashtra, said the officials. (REPRESENTATIVE PIC)" title="Necessary precautions are being implemented, and citizens should not panic. As of now, no cases of HMPV have been reported in Maharashtra, said the officials. (REPRESENTATIVE PIC)"><figcaption>Necessary precautions are being implemented, and citizens should not panic. As of now, no cases of HMPV have been reported in Maharashtra, said the officials. (REPRESENTATIVE PIC)</figcaption><p>Following the outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases in China, the health department in Maharashtra has heightened surveillance for respiratory infections. The director of health services has instructed officials to report severe acute respiratory infections (SARI) and influenza-like illnesses (ILI).</p><ul><li>No reported cases of HMPV in Maharashtra yet.</li><li>The HMPV is a common respiratory virus that primarily affects the upper respiratory tract.</li><li>Officials assure the public there is no need for alarm.</li><li>The situation in China corresponds to the seasonal flu pattern.</li><li>The government is in close watch and has requested updates from WHO regarding the situation in China.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no need for the citizens to panic and the officials are asked to submit reports of SARI and ILI cases,” Dr Nitin Ambadekar stated.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while there is an outbreak in China, Maharashtra is maintaining a proactive approach to ensure public safety, with no immediate threat present locally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/pune-news/after-hmpv-outbreak-in-china-maharashtra-intensifies-surveillance-for-respiratory-disease-cases-101736103129179.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/pune-news/after-hmpv-outbreak-in-china-maharashtra-intensifies-surveillance-for-respiratory-disease-cases-101736103129179.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 02:10:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi authorities issue guidelines to prevent HMPV breakout - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Authorities Issue Guidelines to Prevent HMPV Breakout</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Delhi Health Department</p><p>Delhi health authorities issued an advisory to prepare for potential health challenges related to the Human MetaPneumoVirus (HMPV) and other respiratory viruses.</p><ul><li>Dr. Vandana Bagga convened a meeting with medical officials to discuss respiratory illness preparedness.</li><li>Hospitals must report Influenza-like Illness (ILI) and Severe Acute Respiratory Infection (SARI) cases.</li><li>Strict isolation protocols and universal precautions for suspected cases are mandatory.</li><li>Proper documentation of SARI and lab-confirmed influenza cases is required.</li><li>Hospitals should ensure the availability of treatment supplies like paracetamol and oxygen.</li></ul><blockquote>Updates indicated no significant surge in respiratory illnesses as of January 2, 2025.</blockquote><p>The guidelines follow reports of increased respiratory illnesses in China and highlight the importance of preparedness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/delhi-authorities-issue-guidelines-to-prevent-hmpv-breakout/article69065898.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/delhi-authorities-issue-guidelines-to-prevent-hmpv-breakout/article69065898.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 23:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Discover Common Virus Could Be Causing a Type of Alzheimer's - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Discover Common Virus Could Be Causing a Type of Alzheimer's</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>2024-12-19 <strong>Source: </strong>Science Alert</p><figure id="attachment_147539" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-147539"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/12/readhead-microglia-banner.png" alt="" width="1200" height="675" loading="lazy"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-147539">The brain's immune cells, or microglia (light blue/purple), are shown interacting with amyloid plaques (red) – harmful protein clumps linked to Alzheimer's disease. The illustration highlights the microglia's role in monitoring brain health and clearing debris. (<a href="https://news.asu.edu/20241219-health-and-medicine-surprising-role-gut-infection-alzheimers-disease">Jason Drees/Arizona State University</a>)</figcaption></figure><p>Researchers have discovered a link between a chronic gut infection caused by a common virus and the development of Alzheimer's disease in some individuals.</p><ul><li>The study identifies cytomegalovirus (CMV) as a potential causal factor in Alzheimer’s disease, particularly in a specific subset of individuals.</li><li>By age 80, 90% of people will have antibodies for CMV, but only a small subset experiences chronic intestinal infection.</li><li>The active virus may travel up the gut-brain axis, aggravating the immune system and potentially leading to Alzheimer’s.</li><li>Researchers are exploring antiviral treatments to potentially prevent this subtype of Alzheimer’s.</li></ul><blockquote>"We think we found a biologically unique subtype of Alzheimer's that may affect 25 percent to 45 percent of people with this disease," said Ben Readhead, lead author from Arizona State University.</blockquote><p>This research highlights the need for further investigation into the relationship between chronic infections and neurodegenerative diseases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/scientists-discover-common-virus-could-be-causing-a-type-of-alzheimers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/scientists-discover-common-virus-could-be-causing-a-type-of-alzheimers</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 20:04:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surprising sign of Parkinson's disease that appears decades before onset of tremor - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Surprising Sign of Parkinson's Disease That Appears Decades Before Onset of Tremor</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This article discusses a surprising early indicator of Parkinson's disease that can manifest many years before traditional symptoms such as tremors. Researchers are exploring the implications of this finding for early diagnosis and treatment.</p><ul><li>Early signs of Parkinson's can appear decades before noticeable symptoms.</li><li>The research emphasizes the importance of early detection in managing the disease.</li><li>Potential for new screening methods based on the identified signs.</li></ul><blockquote>“Identifying these signs early could change the way we approach Parkinson's disease treatment.”</blockquote><p>This finding could lead to significant advancements in the early diagnosis of Parkinson's disease, potentially improving patient outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/surprising-sign-of-parkinsons-disease-that-appears-decades-before-onset-of-tremor/articleshow/116972356.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/surprising-sign-of-parkinsons-disease-that-appears-decades-before-onset-of-tremor/articleshow/116972356.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 18:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pupil Dynamics During Sleep Reveal Brain’s Memory-Saving Secrets - Neuroscience News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pupil Dynamics During Sleep Reveal Brain’s Memory-Saving Secrets</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 1, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Cornell University</p>
<img src="https://neurosciencenews.com/files/2025/01/pupil-size-sleep-memory-neurosicence.jpg" alt="This shows a woman sleeping." width="1200" height="800">
<figcaption>While the relationship between sleep and memory has been well established, the neural mechanisms that underpin their interplay remain murky. Credit: Neuroscience News</figcaption>
<p>Researchers at Cornell University have found that pupil size during non-REM sleep plays a crucial role in memory consolidation. This study demonstrates that contracted pupils correlate with the consolidation of new memories, while dilated pupils relate to the processing of older memories.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Pupil Size and Memory:</strong> Contracted pupils correlate with new memory consolidation, while dilated pupils process older memories.</li>
<li><strong>Memory Separation:</strong> The brain alternates between new and old knowledge during non-REM sleep to prevent interference.</li>
<li><strong>AI Applications:</strong> Insights into memory processing may help improve efficiency in artificial neural networks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The eyes may be the window to the soul, but the pupil is key to understanding how, and when, the brain forms strong, long-lasting memories, Cornell researchers have found.</blockquote>
<p>The findings offer potential for developing better memory enhancement techniques and deeper understanding of sleep's role in memory processing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://neurosciencenews.com/sleep-memory-pupil-size-28306/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://neurosciencenews.com/sleep-memory-pupil-size-28306/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 18:43:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Strict isolation, proper documentation': Delhi health officials issue advisory to tackle HMPV outbreak - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Issues Advisory to Combat HMPV Outbreak</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>The Delhi health officials have released a new advisory aimed at tackling the outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) which has been affecting multiple individuals.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Health authorities emphasize strict isolation protocols for those infected.</li>
  <li>Proper documentation and reporting of HMPV cases are mandated.</li>
  <li>The advisory aims to prevent further spread of the virus.</li>
  <li>Officials recommend public awareness campaigns to educate citizens on symptoms and prevention methods.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Timely isolation and thorough documentation can significantly curb the outbreak.” - Delhi Health Official</blockquote>
<p>This advisory is a proactive measure to ensure public health safety amid growing concerns regarding the HMPV virus.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/strict-isolation-proper-documentation-delhi-health-officials-issues-advisory-to-tackle-hmpv-outbreak/articleshow/116970919.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/strict-isolation-proper-documentation-delhi-health-officials-issues-advisory-to-tackle-hmpv-outbreak/articleshow/116970919.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 17:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Strict isolation, proper documentation': Delhi health officials issues advisory to tackle HMPV outbreak - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Health Officials Issue Advisory to Tackle HMPV Outbreak</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 20, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="HMPV outbreak image"><figcaption>Delhi's health response to HMPV.</figcaption><p>Health officials in Delhi have issued a new advisory to combat the recent outbreak of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), urging strict isolation and proper documentation of cases to curb the spread.</p><ul><li>HMPV poses a significant risk especially to infants and elderly individuals.</li><li>Health officials recommend enhanced surveillance and early reporting of symptoms.</li><li>Public awareness campaigns will be launched to educate citizens about HMPV.</li><li>The advisory includes guidelines for patients, healthcare providers, and emergency services.</li></ul><blockquote>“Prompt reporting and isolation are crucial in managing this outbreak,” advised a senior health official.</blockquote><p>The swift response aims to mitigate the impact of HMPV in the capital, ensuring community health safeguards are prioritized.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/strict-isolation-proper-documentation-delhi-health-officials-issues-advisory-to-tackle-hmpv-outbreak/articleshow/116970919.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/strict-isolation-proper-documentation-delhi-health-officials-issues-advisory-to-tackle-hmpv-outbreak/articleshow/116970919.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 17:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quarantine animals infected by bird flu, Centre tells States after tiger, leopard deaths in Nagpur - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Quarantine animals infected by bird flu, Centre tells States after tiger, leopard deaths in Nagpur</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/c3hd93/article69065776.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/11073_3_7_2024_23_22_17_5_4TVAL9_SPOTLIGHT.JPG" alt="Image for representation" title="Image for representation"><figcaption>Image for representation. | Photo Credit: The Hindu</figcaption><p>With the first case of avian influenza reported in Maharashtra, the Union Animal Husbandry Ministry is urging states to quarantine infected cats to prevent disease transmission.</p><ul><li>Three tigers and one leopard died from H5N1 virus at a Nagpur rescue centre.</li><li>Union Animal Husbandry Commissioner confirmed it as the first reported case of bird flu in animals in India.</li><li>The ministry is investigating potential causes, including chicken meat consumption.</li><li>A biosecurity protocol has been established for affected establishments.</li><li>Zoo staff must be equipped with personal protective equipment and follow health monitoring.</li></ul><blockquote>“The situation demands urgent attention to mitigate risks to both animal and human health.”</blockquote><p>The outbreak of bird flu in animals poses a significant risk and warrants immediate measures to ensure the safety of both wildlife and human populations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/quarantine-animals-infected-by-bird-flu-centre-tells-states-after-tiger-leopard-deaths-in-nagpur/article69065397.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/quarantine-animals-infected-by-bird-flu-centre-tells-states-after-tiger-leopard-deaths-in-nagpur/article69065397.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 17:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viral footage from China raises red flags: Could HMPV be spreading to India? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Viral Footage from China Raises Concerns About HMPV Spread to India</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>China is seeing a rise in cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV), prompting increased screening measures. Despite alarming social media reports, health authorities reassure the public that there is no cause for alarm.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>HMPV is a respiratory virus causing mild cold-like symptoms but can be severe in vulnerable populations.</li><li>Chinese health officials report rising cases, particularly among children in northern regions.</li><li>No cases of HMPV have been reported in India thus far.</li><li>Health authorities in India are monitoring the situation and stress that there is no alarm.</li></ul><blockquote>“Metapneumovirus is like any other respiratory virus that causes the common cold,” – Dr. Atul Goel, Director-General of Health Services in India.</blockquote><p>Overall, while the rise of cases in China has raised concerns, health officials in both China and India are working to reassure the public and maintain preparedness as HMPV is typically seasonal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/new-updates/viral-footage-from-china-raises-red-flags-could-hmpv-be-spreading-to-india/articleshow/116969179.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/new-updates/viral-footage-from-china-raises-red-flags-could-hmpv-be-spreading-to-india/articleshow/116969179.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:38:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Think You’re Healthy? Science Says This Is How You Should Measure It - Yahoo Life]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPcHZ5T2JPaGtoVFMtbko3SWNIR09jU0t0aEpuSS1wa1FJRWF4ZTlwdUJZeXhvSmJzM1FUV1E2VXhVVzhVSWIwS25sODR5VGlPSkNyWHNaZE9UTHlrR0UzQTFER2VQUG5pdDNSUk1MZlJ5d0xDTkFpbVZnZHJzcFNkeERBaVBEakxK?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPcHZ5T2JPaGtoVFMtbko3SWNIR09jU0t0aEpuSS1wa1FJRWF4ZTlwdUJZeXhvSmJzM1FUV1E2VXhVVzhVSWIwS25sODR5VGlPSkNyWHNaZE9UTHlrR0UzQTFER2VQUG5pdDNSUk1MZlJ5d0xDTkFpbVZnZHJzcFNkeERBaVBEakxK?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The happiness diet: Foods that boost your mood this winter - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Happiness Diet: Foods That Boost Your Mood This Winter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>As winter approaches, many people experience mood changes. This article explores various foods that can enhance mood and provide emotional support during the winter months.</p><ul><li>Introduction of foods that increase serotonin levels.</li><li>Recommendation of omega-3 fatty acid-rich foods.</li><li>Importance of vitamins and minerals in diet for mental health.</li><li>Suggestions for incorporating these foods into daily meals.</li></ul><blockquote>"Eating the right foods can significantly impact your mood and well-being during the colder months."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, adjusting your diet by including mood-boosting foods can lead to a better winter experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/the-happiness-diet-foods-that-boost-your-mood-this-winter/articleshow/116968098.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/the-happiness-diet-foods-that-boost-your-mood-this-winter/articleshow/116968098.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There are no HMPV cases in Andhra Pradesh, says Director of Public Health - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>No HMPV Cases in Andhra Pradesh, Says Public Health Director</h1><p><strong>Published on January 05, 2025 by IST</strong></p><p>Dr. K. Padmavathi, Director of Public Health, confirmed that there are currently no Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases in Andhra Pradesh and advised against panic over its spread.</p><ul><li>The virus spreads similarly to Coronavirus, primarily affecting children, the elderly, and those with low immunity.</li><li>Symptoms resemble a common cold and may include cough, runny nose, and respiratory issues.</li><li>Precautions similar to those during COVID-19 are recommended, including self-isolation for symptomatic individuals.</li><li>There is no specific antiviral treatment currently available for HMPV.</li></ul><blockquote>“The virus spreads through droplets expelled by coughing or sneezing, close contact, handshakes, and touching surfaces.” - Dr. K. Padmavathi</blockquote><p>Supportive care is important for those affected as government hospitals are prepared to treat those severely impacted.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/there-are-no-hmpv-cases-in-andhra-pradesh-says-director-of-public-health/article69064929.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/there-are-no-hmpv-cases-in-andhra-pradesh-says-director-of-public-health/article69064929.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is driving the winter flu crisis in England? - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What is driving the winter flu crisis in England?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2025<strong>Source:</strong> The Guardian</p><img src="https://www.example.com/image.jpg" alt="Flu patients in hospital"/><figcaption>Flu patients in hospital during the winter crisis.</figcaption><p>As flu hospital admissions quadruple in England, the UK faces significant pressures on its healthcare system, raising concerns about the ongoing winter flu crisis.</p><ul><li>Flu-related hospital admissions increased significantly compared to previous months.</li><li>Average daily flu patients in hospital reached 4,469 during the last week of December 2024.</li><li>The NHS faces a 'quad-demic', including flu, Covid, RSV, and norovirus pressures.</li><li>Older adults and those with underlying conditions are most affected by flu.</li><li>Flu vaccine uptake is low among younger at-risk groups, with 11 million individuals over 65 still at risk.</li></ul><blockquote>“The latest data suggest that the spread of flu in the 2024-25 season is likely to be at its peak around now.” - Sir Andrew Pollard</blockquote><p>The ongoing flu crisis highlights the urgent need for improved vaccination rates and public health measures to protect vulnerable populations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/jan/05/what-is-driving-the-winter-flu-crisis-in-england</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/jan/05/what-is-driving-the-winter-flu-crisis-in-england</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After China, HMPV cases now rise in Malaysia; public asked to remain vigilant | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After China, HMPV cases now rise in Malaysia; public asked to remain vigilant</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Malaysia has seen a significant rise in human metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases, urging the public to remain vigilant.</p><ul><li>327 HMPV cases reported in 2024, a 45% increase from 2023.</li><li>Authorities stress the importance of sanitary practices such as hand washing and wearing masks.</li><li>China has also experienced a surge in respiratory illnesses, but officials describe it as a seasonal occurrence.</li><li>Indian health authorities are monitoring the situation without alarm.</li><li>HMPV is a common respiratory virus, generally causing mild flu-like symptoms in specific age groups.</li></ul><blockquote>“Metapneumovirus is like any other respiratory virus that causes common cold, and in very old and very young it could cause flu-like symptoms.”</blockquote><p>Authorities recommend that the public stay informed while noting that seasonal spikes in respiratory infections are expected.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/after-china-hmpv-cases-now-rise-in-malaysia-public-asked-to-remain-vigilant-11736085898495.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/after-china-hmpv-cases-now-rise-in-malaysia-public-asked-to-remain-vigilant-11736085898495.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why do women binge drink when estrogen surges? Study explains - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why do women binge drink when estrogen surges? Study explains</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article explores the phenomenon of binge drinking among women during periods of estrogen surges, revealing key insights and findings from recent studies on the subject.</p><ul><li>The study examines hormonal effects on women's drinking behaviors.</li><li>Research highlights the connection between estrogen levels and increased alcohol consumption.</li><li>Experts discuss implications for health and social norms regarding women's drinking habits.</li></ul><blockquote>"Understanding these hormonal influences can lead to better health strategies for women."</blockquote><p>This study sheds light on a crucial aspect of women's health, emphasizing the need for awareness and tailored approaches in tackling binge drinking in women.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-do-women-binge-drink-when-estrogen-surges-study-explains/articleshow/116967047.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/why-do-women-binge-drink-when-estrogen-surges-study-explains/articleshow/116967047.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>