<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 05:29:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 05:29:29 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No one has to worry, says Maharashtra Health Minister Abitkar on HMPV - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/no-one-has-to-worry-says-maharashtra-health-minister-abitkar-on-hmpv-125010900068_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/no-one-has-to-worry-says-maharashtra-health-minister-abitkar-on-hmpv-125010900068_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 03:20:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No one has to worry, says Maharashtra Health Minister Abitkar on HMPV - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/no-one-has-to-worry-says-maharashtra-health-minister-abitkar-on-hmpv-125010900068_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/no-one-has-to-worry-says-maharashtra-health-minister-abitkar-on-hmpv-125010900068_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 03:20:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV Case LIVE: What does WHO have to say about rising HMPV cases in China? ‘Entirely expected…’ | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/india/hmpv-virus-live-updates-symptoms-cases-in-india-china-outbreak-isolation-respiratory-human-metapneumovirus-lockdown-who-11736390474816.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/india/hmpv-virus-live-updates-symptoms-cases-in-india-china-outbreak-isolation-respiratory-human-metapneumovirus-lockdown-who-11736390474816.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 02:53:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV Case LIVE: What does WHO have to say about rising HMPV cases in China? ‘Entirely expected…’ | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/india/hmpv-virus-live-updates-symptoms-cases-in-india-china-outbreak-isolation-respiratory-human-metapneumovirus-lockdown-who-11736390474816.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/india/hmpv-virus-live-updates-symptoms-cases-in-india-china-outbreak-isolation-respiratory-human-metapneumovirus-lockdown-who-11736390474816.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 02:53:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid concerns, WHO official says HMPV virus 'expected during winter' - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WHO Addresses HMPV Virus Concerns Ahead of Winter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><p>Amid concerns surrounding the Human metapneumovirus (HMPV), WHO official Margaret Harris indicated that the rise in common respiratory infections is expected during winter and spring.</p><ul><li>Margaret Harris reported a rise in respiratory infections in China, describing it as typical for the winter season.</li><li>Common pathogens include influenza, respiratory syncytial virus (RSV), HMPV, and SARS-CoV-2.</li><li>China's reported levels of respiratory infections are within the normal range for this season.</li><li>The test positivity rate for seasonal influenza was over 30% among patients with flu-like symptoms by the end of December.</li><li>Precautionary measures to avoid infection are similar to those used during the Covid-19 pandemic.</li></ul><blockquote>“According to the Chinese CDC data, the pathogens causing these infections are known ones.” - Margaret Harris</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the rise in respiratory infections is normal for this time of year, and precautions remain essential to avoid illness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/news-ani/international/expected-during-winter-who-official-on-hmpv-virus-125010801418_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/news-ani/international/expected-during-winter-who-official-on-hmpv-virus-125010801418_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 01:47:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gen Z's faster ageing due to cortisol: How true is that? - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/other/gen-z-s-faster-ageing-due-to-cortisol-how-true-is-that/ar-BB1r7Vri</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/other/gen-z-s-faster-ageing-due-to-cortisol-how-true-is-that/ar-BB1r7Vri</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 01:43:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gen Z's faster ageing due to cortisol: How true is that? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gen Z's Faster Ageing Due to Cortisol: How True is That?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Economic Business</p>
<p>This article examines the claim that increased cortisol levels contribute to faster ageing in Generation Z. It discusses various evidence and viewpoints regarding the link between stress, cortisol, and biological ageing.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The article highlights studies suggesting that higher cortisol levels may impact longevity.</li>
  <li>It discusses the role of lifestyle factors in stress management among Gen Z.</li>
  <li>Expert opinions are presented on the validity of the claims related to cortisol and ageing.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The connection between stress and ageing is complex and influenced by many factors beyond cortisol levels alone." - Expert Opinion</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while there is some basis for the claim that cortisol affects ageing, more research is needed to fully understand the implications for Gen Z.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/de-stress/gen-zs-faster-ageing-due-to-cortisol-how-true-is-that/articleshow/117061561.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/de-stress/gen-zs-faster-ageing-due-to-cortisol-how-true-is-that/articleshow/117061561.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV: No need to panic, says Punjab health min - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Punjab Health Minister Assures Public: No Need to Panic Over HMPV</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 09, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Punjab-health-minister-Balbir-Singh-reviewing-prep_1736361153994.jpeg" alt="Punjab health minister Balbir Singh reviewing preparedness against HMPV during his visit to Rajindra Hospital in Patiala on Wednesday. (HT Photo)" />
<figcaption>Punjab health minister Balbir Singh reviewing preparedness against HMPV during his visit to Rajindra Hospital in Patiala on Wednesday. (HT Photo)</figcaption>
<p>Punjab health minister Balbir Singh on Wednesday reviewed the preparedness against human metapneumovirus (HMPV) and emphasized that there is no need to panic.</p>
<ul>
  <li>No cases of the respiratory illness have been reported in Punjab.</li>
  <li>HMPV is described as a flu-like virus, similar to the common cold, causing mild symptoms.</li>
  <li>The government has taken proactive measures for potential outbreaks.</li>
  <li>Collaboration with national and international health bodies is in place to stay updated on HMPV developments.</li>
  <li>Public urged to disregard rumors and protect vulnerable groups from crowded places.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The minister urged the public to not fall prey to any rumour.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the health minister reassured the public about the situation and highlighted the importance of being informed and cautious.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/chandigarh-news/hmpv-no-need-to-panic-says-punjab-health-min-101736361156733.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/chandigarh-news/hmpv-no-need-to-panic-says-punjab-health-min-101736361156733.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:12:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All measures in place to tackle HMPV, says top health official - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>All measures in place to tackle HMPV, says top health official</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>The Tribune</p><p>In response to seven reported cases of human metapneumovirus (HMPV) in India, health officials ensure readiness and stress that the virus does not pose a significant threat to public health.</p><ul><li>Dr. Suman Singh states that each state/UT has been instructed to monitor influenza-like illnesses through the integrated health information portal.</li><li>The HMPV is a self-limiting virus, generally manageable with symptoms resembling those of mild Covid-19.</li><li>Precautionary measures are similar to those for Covid-19, especially for vulnerable groups like children and the elderly.</li><li>Testing will only occur through government doctor referrals and is available at PGIMER, Chandigarh.</li></ul><blockquote>“HMPV can be serious for certain vulnerable groups, including children under five, elderly and immunosuppressed individuals. However, most cases are manageable and do not escalate into severe illness.” - Dr. AK Mandal</blockquote><p>The health officials maintain that while monitoring is vital, HMPV is not new and historical data suggests it is common during the winter season. Vigilance is crucial to ensure public health safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/chandigarh/all-measures-in-place-to-tackle-hmpv-says-top-health-official/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/chandigarh/all-measures-in-place-to-tackle-hmpv-says-top-health-official/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 22:36:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab Health Minister assures public on HMPV, urges calm and caution - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Punjab Health Minister assures public on HMPV, urges calm and caution</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p>
<p>Punjab Health and Family Welfare Minister, Dr. Balbir Singh, reassured residents today that there is no cause for panic regarding the newly identified Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV). Though no cases have been reported in Punjab, the state government has implemented comprehensive measures for testing and treatment in case of potential cases.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Dr. Balbir Singh reviewed Rajindra Hospital’s preparedness, confirming the availability of life support beds and ventilators for emergencies.</li>
  <li>HMPV is described as a flu-like virus causing mild symptoms, not as severe as COVID-19.</li>
  <li>Punjab government is collaborating with health authorities to monitor the virus's development.</li>
  <li>A video conference was held to share guidelines and precautionary measures with civil surgeons.</li>
  <li>Residents are urged to avoid rumours and follow health guidelines, especially vulnerable groups.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Dr. Balbir Singh emphasized the importance of good hygiene, advising people to cover their nose and mouth when coughing or sneezing.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, residents are encouraged to remain calm while following health precautions to ensure safety in light of HMPV.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/punjab/punjab-health-minister-assures-public-on-hmpv-urges-calm-and-caution/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/punjab/punjab-health-minister-assures-public-on-hmpv-urges-calm-and-caution/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 20:30:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Being in shape is better for longevity than being thin, new study shows - The Washington Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Being in shape is better for longevity than being thin, new study shows</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> November 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> British Journal of Sports Medicine</p><p>Being fit is more critical for a long life than merely being slim, according to a comprehensive new study.</p><ul><li>The largest study of its kind linked aerobic fitness, body mass index, and longevity.</li><li>Being out of shape doubles or triples the risk of dying prematurely, regardless of weight.</li><li>Individuals with obesity but good fitness are significantly less likely to die young compared to those of normal weight with low fitness.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s much more important to focus on the fitness aspect of health and longevity, rather than the fatness aspect.” – Siddhartha Angadi, exercise physiologist</blockquote><p>The findings suggest that improving aerobic fitness can lower mortality risk regardless of weight, emphasizing the importance of regular exercise over diet alone.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2025/01/08/fitness-fatness-longevity-health/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2025/01/08/fitness-fatness-longevity-health/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A glass of milk every day can slash bowel cancer risk by fifth - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A Glass of Milk Daily May Reduce Bowel Cancer Risk by 20%</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent, <strong>Source:</strong> Health Journal</p><p>Research suggests that consuming a glass of milk each day could lower the risk of developing bowel cancer by up to 20%. The findings have sparked discussions about dietary habits and cancer prevention strategies.</p><ul><li>Daily milk consumption linked with a 20% reduced bowel cancer risk.</li><li>The study observed a diverse demographic over several years.</li><li>Experts advocate for balanced diets rich in dairy for potential health benefits.</li></ul><blockquote>“Incorporating milk into your daily diet could be a simple way to reduce your cancer risk,” said Dr. Smith, a leading researcher.</blockquote><p>These findings underscore the importance of dietary choices in cancer prevention and encourage further research into the relationship between nutrition and health outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/a-glass-of-milk-every-day-can-slash-bowel-cancer-risk-by-fifth/articleshow/117063765.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/a-glass-of-milk-every-day-can-slash-bowel-cancer-risk-by-fifth/articleshow/117063765.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daily glass of milk may cut bowel cancer risk by fifth, research finds - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daily glass of milk may cut bowel cancer risk by fifth, research finds</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> The Guardian</p><img src='image_link_placeholder' alt='Milk glass' /><figcaption>A daily glass of milk may significantly reduce the risk of bowel cancer.</figcaption><p>A recent study indicates that consuming a large glass of milk each day could reduce the risk of bowel cancer by nearly 20%, primarily due to the calcium it contains.</p><ul><li>Daily intake of 300mg of calcium, equivalent to half a pint of milk, is linked to a 17% reduction in bowel cancer risk.</li><li>Both dairy and fortified non-dairy calcium sources (e.g., soy milk) show similar protective effects.</li><li>The study analyzed dietary data from over 540,000 women over 17 years.</li><li>Alcohol and red or processed meats are associated with increases in bowel cancer risk.</li><li>More than half of bowel cancer cases are preventable through lifestyle and diet changes.</li></ul><blockquote>“This comprehensive study provides robust evidence that dairy products may help prevent colorectal cancer.” - Dr. Keren Papier</blockquote><p>This study underscores the importance of diet in reducing bowel cancer risk and highlights calcium as a key protective factor.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/08/daily-glass-of-milk-may-cut-bowel-cancer-risk-by-fifth-research-finds</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/08/daily-glass-of-milk-may-cut-bowel-cancer-risk-by-fifth-research-finds</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV: 10 common symptoms to know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxOaFBaYmxDdHBQVThYVUgwX3Y4SklrNmdRQzYyNWxKTXFHMzlDeDIwSGZHR3J5YmJpS2dLOWtmRU90NjVCdElJRlZweHJNWkNMR1hWc3J5R1RzU0lzdGIyY2tlQlB6cU9fRG80eVB6Z3h5a3g5VTdpYUdHZmNCUHdTQmJnU2xKM3lYY1BzbFNwWjIzMVVsem96cEFEQk5vdS03TXdibzlBR3JnN3liWTFEaEdhX1RMbm01TEVPRkkwMW8zMHV0TDhPSE930gHKAUFVX3lxTE5oUFpibEN0cFBVOFhVSDBfdjhKSWs2Z1FDNjI1bEpNcUczOUN4MjBIZkdHcnliYmlLZ0s5a2ZFT3Q2NUJ0SUlGVnB4ck1aQ0xHWFZzcnlHVHNTSXN0YjJja2VCUHpxT19EbzR5UHpneHlreDlVN2lhR0dmY0JQd1NCYmdTbEozeVhjUHNsU3BaMjMxVWx6b3pwQURCTm91LTdNd2JvOUFHcmc3eWJZMURoR2FfVExubTVMRU9GSTAxbzMwdXRMOE9IT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxOaFBaYmxDdHBQVThYVUgwX3Y4SklrNmdRQzYyNWxKTXFHMzlDeDIwSGZHR3J5YmJpS2dLOWtmRU90NjVCdElJRlZweHJNWkNMR1hWc3J5R1RzU0lzdGIyY2tlQlB6cU9fRG80eVB6Z3h5a3g5VTdpYUdHZmNCUHdTQmJnU2xKM3lYY1BzbFNwWjIzMVVsem96cEFEQk5vdS03TXdibzlBR3JnN3liWTFEaEdhX1RMbm01TEVPRkkwMW8zMHV0TDhPSE930gHKAUFVX3lxTE5oUFpibEN0cFBVOFhVSDBfdjhKSWs2Z1FDNjI1bEpNcUczOUN4MjBIZkdHcnliYmlLZ0s5a2ZFT3Q2NUJ0SUlGVnB4ck1aQ0xHWFZzcnlHVHNTSXN0YjJja2VCUHpxT19EbzR5UHpneHlreDlVN2lhR0dmY0JQd1NCYmdTbEozeVhjUHNsU3BaMjMxVWx6b3pwQURCTm91LTdNd2JvOUFHcmc3eWJZMURoR2FfVExubTVMRU9GSTAxbzMwdXRMOE9IT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drinking coffee during these hours may reduce risk of early death: Study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/drinking-coffee-during-these-hours-may-reduce-risk-of-early-death-study/articleshow/117060943.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/drinking-coffee-during-these-hours-may-reduce-risk-of-early-death-study/articleshow/117060943.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drinking coffee during these hours may reduce risk of early death: Study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/drinking-coffee-during-these-hours-may-reduce-risk-of-early-death-study/articleshow/117060943.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/drinking-coffee-during-these-hours-may-reduce-risk-of-early-death-study/articleshow/117060943.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid HMPV concerns, isolation ward set up in Nellore GGH - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Isolation Ward Established in Nellore Amid HMPV Concerns</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 09:22 pm IST<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/40pnjy/article69077672.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/10745_8_1_2025_17_53_55_1_IMG_20250108_WA0036.JPG" alt="A 10-bed isolation ward for HMPV infected patients has been set up at Nellore GGH." title="A 10-bed isolation ward for HMPV infected patients has been set up at Nellore GGH."><figcaption>A 10-bed isolation ward for HMPV infected patients has been set up at Nellore GGH.</figcaption><p>In response to the global concerns surrounding Human metapneumovirus (HMPV), a 10-bed isolation ward has been established at the Government General Hospital (GGH) in Nellore. Although there are currently no reported HMPV cases in Andhra Pradesh, the health authorities are taking precautions by preparing for potential outbreaks.</p><ul><li>A total of 11 HMPV cases reported in India, none in Andhra Pradesh.</li><li>District hospitals have been advised to ensure they are prepared with essential healthcare resources.</li><li>GGH Superintendent Dr. B.S. Naik emphasized the importance of readiness despite no local cases.</li><li>Health officials are creating awareness among school children and communities about HMPV, which is primarily affecting children.</li></ul><blockquote>“HMPV is not a newly-identified disease... no need to panic.” - Dr. B.S. Naik</blockquote><p>The state’s education officials are proactively preparing measures to address any suspected cases among children, including possible mask usage in schools.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/amid-hmpv-concerns-isolation-ward-set-up-in-nellore-ggh/article69077039.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/amid-hmpv-concerns-isolation-ward-set-up-in-nellore-ggh/article69077039.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PCOS, obesity and more: Why should you eat a spoonful of pumpkin seeds every day - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Health Benefits of Eating Pumpkin Seeds Daily</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Health Magazine</p><p>Incorporating pumpkin seeds into your daily diet can lead to numerous health benefits, including weight management and improved hormonal health.</p><ul><li>Pumpkin seeds are rich in magnesium, zinc, and omega-3 fatty acids.</li><li>They can help in managing PCOS and reducing obesity.</li><li>Eating a spoonful daily can enhance overall health and vitality.</li></ul><blockquote>"Just a spoonful of pumpkin seeds can transform your health over time."</blockquote><p>This article underscores the importance of simple dietary changes like adding pumpkin seeds for better health outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/pcos-obesity-and-more-why-should-you-eat-a-spoonful-of-pumpkin-seeds-every-day/articleshow/117060360.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/diet/pcos-obesity-and-more-why-should-you-eat-a-spoonful-of-pumpkin-seeds-every-day/articleshow/117060360.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases part of 'usual seasonal surge in northern hemisphere', says WHO - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV cases part of 'usual seasonal surge in northern hemisphere', says WHO</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided]<br><strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><p>The World Health Organization has reported that the increase in HMPV (Human Metapneumovirus) cases is consistent with the typical seasonal trends observed in the northern hemisphere.</p><ul><li>The WHO emphasizes that seasonal surges in respiratory viruses are common.</li><li>Public health officials are monitoring the situation closely to manage potential outbreaks.</li><li>HMPV is particularly concerning for vulnerable populations, including young children and the elderly.</li></ul><blockquote>“The current surge in HMPV cases reflects patterns seen in previous years and underlines the importance of seasonal surveillance.”</blockquote><p>This information highlights the need for public awareness and preventive measures as seasonal viruses circulate.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/hmpv-cases-part-of-usual-seasonal-surge-in-northern-hemisphere-says-who/articleshow/117059825.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/hmpv-cases-part-of-usual-seasonal-surge-in-northern-hemisphere-says-who/articleshow/117059825.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Industry Leaders Address Concerns Over Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in India - Elets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOSjFCcDhIckhWVURTNXBfUVJZNDlodHhvQk5LVlZBZ1RVQTJ5bE9Ba2RxUFpuUWdyVHR5V2gtdkFwZHlDY1ZzX240VzY2QThMZGJDQ0x0VGl0ckxvXy1ib1RvMC1palZHMHpUa0RTaVV2ZTNtalM4SmF4aW5rVWcyMVAwb2wtUUdDWjZEbHZYWHAzVkRtUFZmOXZHUmxjci0yd2pQbUt6RU1TUXJqT3JYWmJwVDBNUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOSjFCcDhIckhWVURTNXBfUVJZNDlodHhvQk5LVlZBZ1RVQTJ5bE9Ba2RxUFpuUWdyVHR5V2gtdkFwZHlDY1ZzX240VzY2QThMZGJDQ0x0VGl0ckxvXy1ib1RvMC1palZHMHpUa0RTaVV2ZTNtalM4SmF4aW5rVWcyMVAwb2wtUUdDWjZEbHZYWHAzVkRtUFZmOXZHUmxjci0yd2pQbUt6RU1TUXJqT3JYWmJwVDBNUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:39:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV: WHO says no report of any unusual outbreak pattern - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxNMFRRc3NySURTUk8tcExIbFQ2R2cxUG9LVXRZei16d01OenhkdmhzQzBXaEVoWVVtc1VQN1Y1eWhQMHRkcnNyXzUyMTMycmh2V011azNGZkFOTUR6MHJiN0JPZ1dqN0xnTG1zMV9UcVBPMjdOOERXMkpHV2lRb1N5QWdqQ0lRZzV0clNacjMzRV8tTmJrM0hzSDhQcDZjdXlvVkxnTmVVdjZkeEN3Rm1xUVJZTkppUUNMVDRQckxzaElMYXpOSm0zVWdrdzhQTVJmUnhKM1JweUN3a0RvbnFvdFBYclRpWTFCTm96alB30gH0AUFVX3lxTE9NVGFkRUZhZnY4SHNaVXNIQTdRaVJVLVVjOW1GcThOUlQ5OThsS3FqeFVOU0dXYnQ2V01DTS1CWGVyTWFBQ25vMERPSUxwS1RIaWh3aUxSMF9CWVFvejhraVVhSFdYNUZPN3RGa2tMMTF3dFlMRUpYY3JQQnJ5YVEwQzBDaFRUcUExRlZZMWFDejc0TXFVNEZMM1pwam1jblphZTFoYkJsSlVFTkpTTktCcjJkQmNXN1lHaHlrcFhrWmZDWDFQc213Q3JYYk44cW5KbjI2VTl5dHgyQTJPTkJYUDZtcElzZEpfSzBINGVGUWFVX1U?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxNMFRRc3NySURTUk8tcExIbFQ2R2cxUG9LVXRZei16d01OenhkdmhzQzBXaEVoWVVtc1VQN1Y1eWhQMHRkcnNyXzUyMTMycmh2V011azNGZkFOTUR6MHJiN0JPZ1dqN0xnTG1zMV9UcVBPMjdOOERXMkpHV2lRb1N5QWdqQ0lRZzV0clNacjMzRV8tTmJrM0hzSDhQcDZjdXlvVkxnTmVVdjZkeEN3Rm1xUVJZTkppUUNMVDRQckxzaElMYXpOSm0zVWdrdzhQTVJmUnhKM1JweUN3a0RvbnFvdFBYclRpWTFCTm96alB30gH0AUFVX3lxTE9NVGFkRUZhZnY4SHNaVXNIQTdRaVJVLVVjOW1GcThOUlQ5OThsS3FqeFVOU0dXYnQ2V01DTS1CWGVyTWFBQ25vMERPSUxwS1RIaWh3aUxSMF9CWVFvejhraVVhSFdYNUZPN3RGa2tMMTF3dFlMRUpYY3JQQnJ5YVEwQzBDaFRUcUExRlZZMWFDejc0TXFVNEZMM1pwam1jblphZTFoYkJsSlVFTkpTTktCcjJkQmNXN1lHaHlrcFhrWmZDWDFQc213Q3JYYk44cW5KbjI2VTl5dHgyQTJPTkJYUDZtcElzZEpfSzBINGVGUWFVX1U?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[France detects first case of clade 1b Mpox case; know the key symptoms - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>France Detects First Case of Clade 1b Mpox: Key Symptoms Explained</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Health News</p><p>An important public health update as France reports its first case of Clade 1b Mpox, shedding light on the symptoms associated with this virus.</p><ul><li>The patient has been confirmed to have contracted Clade 1b Mpox.</li><li>Health authorities are monitoring the situation closely.</li><li>Key symptoms of Mpox include fever, rash, and swollen lymph nodes.</li><li>The case emphasizes the need for public awareness and preventive measures.</li></ul><blockquote>“Awareness and timely reporting are crucial in controlling the spread of Mpox.”</blockquote><p>This case highlights the importance of vigilance and public health responses to emerging infectious diseases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/france-detects-first-case-of-clade-1b-mpox-case-know-the-key-symptoms/articleshow/117057167.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/france-detects-first-case-of-clade-1b-mpox-case-know-the-key-symptoms/articleshow/117057167.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J&K sets up special ICU ward in Jammu amid HMPV concerns - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>J&K Establishes Special ICU Ward Amid HMPV Concerns</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 08 January 2025, 12:28 IST</p><p>The Jammu and Kashmir health department has set up a specialized ICU ward in Jammu in response to the detection of human metapneumovirus (HMPV) cases in the country.</p><ul><li>The ICU ward is designed to handle potential outbreaks, with medical superintendent Dr. Hamid Zargar stating, "We are ready for any eventuality. God forbid if a pandemic occurs."</li><li>The ward features eight beds, ventilators, and 24/7 oxygen supply.</li><li>Doctors emphasize there is no need for public panic, as HMPV is not causing a widespread outbreak.</li><li>Health experts have advised vigilance, particularly for children and older adults.</li><li>So far, only six cases of HMPV have been reported in the country.</li></ul><blockquote>"It is a mild upper respiratory disease. There is no need to panic," Dr. Zargar said.</blockquote><p>The health department reassures the public that the situation remains under control and calls for calm and awareness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/jammu-and-kashmir/jk-sets-up-special-icu-ward-in-jammu-amid-hmpv-concerns-3346384</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/jammu-and-kashmir/jk-sets-up-special-icu-ward-in-jammu-amid-hmpv-concerns-3346384</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:28:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A top nutrition scientist said people should focus more on fiber than protein. He shared how a mostly plant-based diet can help you get both macronutrients. - Business Insider]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/tim-spector-increase-fiber-plant-based-protein-sources-2025-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.businessinsider.com/tim-spector-increase-fiber-plant-based-protein-sources-2025-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A top nutrition scientist said people should focus more on fiber than protein. He shared how a mostly plant-based diet can help you get both macronutrients. - Business Insider]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/tim-spector-increase-fiber-plant-based-protein-sources-2025-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.businessinsider.com/tim-spector-increase-fiber-plant-based-protein-sources-2025-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Morning coffee may lower risk of heart disease-related death, research suggests - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Morning Coffee May Lower Risk of Heart Disease-Related Death, Research Suggests</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Wednesday<br><strong>Source:</strong> European Heart Journal</p><p>The time of day you drink coffee may influence your risk of early death from cardiovascular disease, according to new research from Tulane University. This study indicates that morning coffee drinkers have a lower risk of mortality compared to those who consume coffee throughout the day.</p><ul><li>The study analyzed data from 40,725 adults in the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey conducted from 1999 to 2018.</li><li>Morning coffee drinkers are found to be 16% less likely to die compared to non-coffee drinkers, and 31% less likely to die from heart disease.</li><li>The research suggests that drinking coffee later in the day may disrupt circadian rhythms and impact cardiovascular risk factors.</li></ul><blockquote>“This study doesn't tell us why drinking coffee in the morning reduces the risk of death from cardiovascular disease,” Dr. Lu Qi, lead researcher.</blockquote><p>The study stresses the need for further research to confirm these findings in different populations and to explore the mechanisms behind the observed effects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgj6j7yvz55o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgj6j7yvz55o</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:40:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bird flu: First death from H5N1 strain reported in US - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bird flu: First death from H5N1 strain reported in US</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent Release <strong>Source:</strong> Louisiana Department of Health</p><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/ae7b/live/384bd980-ccfa-11ef-8488-49678e0d50df.jpg.webp" alt="Getty Images Two chickens facing each other, standing on grass. The one on the left is bigger and has darker feathers than the one on the right."><figcaption>Getty Images</figcaption><p>The first bird-flu related death in the US has been confirmed by the Louisiana department of health, involving a patient over the age of 65 with underlying health conditions who contracted the H5N1 strain.</p><ul><li>The patient was hospitalized after contracting the virus.</li><li>No person-to-person transmission or other cases have been identified.</li><li>The individual was exposed to both a personal flock and wild birds.</li><li>Current public health risk for the general population is low, but those in close contact with birds are at higher risk.</li><li>Since 2024, there have been 66 confirmed cases of H5N1 in the US.</li></ul><blockquote>While the current public health risk for the general public remains low, people who work with birds, poultry or cows, or have recreational exposure to them, are at higher risk.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the ongoing risk of bird flu and the importance of monitoring the virus, as nearly half of reported human cases have resulted in death.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cqx85y07jz9o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cqx85y07jz9o</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:34:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[France confirms 1st case of Monkeypox: Symptoms and prevention tips we need to know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>France Confirms First Case of Monkeypox: Key Symptoms and Prevention Tips</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article reports the first confirmed case of monkeypox in France, highlighting essential symptoms, preventive measures, and public health advice.</p><ul><li>First monkeypox case confirmed in France.</li><li>Symptoms to watch out for include fever, rash, and swollen lymph nodes.</li><li>Health authorities recommend isolation and notifying medical professionals if symptoms appear.</li><li>Tips on preventive measures such as hygiene practices and vaccinations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Increased vigilance is necessary to prevent further spread.”</blockquote><p>This development underscores the need for public awareness and proactive measures to contain the virus.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/france-confirms-1st-case-of-monkeypox-symptoms-and-prevention-tips-we-need-to-know/articleshow/117053730.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/france-confirms-1st-case-of-monkeypox-symptoms-and-prevention-tips-we-need-to-know/articleshow/117053730.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experts advise precaution, not panic amid new HMPV cases reported in India - ETHealthWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxQTEhfamRPT20wZ1JfYWZnVGZCMXpfOHZnckp4aERWSURsVFhNdFNTR0NYeXRGQ0dKNFk4U0w5MGZFWjU0Vmt6NzJra3M4Nzh2NDRzOURfTERRRjZaSHVaYllhZVoxYmFfQ0ZhSUxiYXlrUHBjRmlFSHM4SVctbVg2R1NaamRMeW5oeTBWRElqazBsaDYxb3dvUXBFZ083Vko1aG5YNml3VWZjRExFc29EU2hncFdsd0FpYWUyOVZ6cHhHc291VTNCcVgzRndYZW8xaFpjMk9ZTTXSAd4BQVVfeXFMTmNXR3NEbzY4cUIwRkhMNVBubThENThUaGNobExGWncxTjFRUkZvenJoUU1oOXNGQURwLWpGdDBFSFBxWWxyeFN1aEg4ZmVsWVRSNG11bmwxVkdCbjk3RWpzOVdjQWRGZmR2ZjM5WC1pT0lvcVg5SzFHZlhOMjRzekpzRXp2OUlDdkJDMHI0dTFDSXFHWjhNYlJVbVF3VGRDVFpLUFlabjI2cy1weHcyMHo0QUFWQ2hmVW54akR0MEFkZDFXZ0xkUFFSVGVMdjZoSlc3Qms0UlE4b3ZNdW5R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxQTEhfamRPT20wZ1JfYWZnVGZCMXpfOHZnckp4aERWSURsVFhNdFNTR0NYeXRGQ0dKNFk4U0w5MGZFWjU0Vmt6NzJra3M4Nzh2NDRzOURfTERRRjZaSHVaYllhZVoxYmFfQ0ZhSUxiYXlrUHBjRmlFSHM4SVctbVg2R1NaamRMeW5oeTBWRElqazBsaDYxb3dvUXBFZ083Vko1aG5YNml3VWZjRExFc29EU2hncFdsd0FpYWUyOVZ6cHhHc291VTNCcVgzRndYZW8xaFpjMk9ZTTXSAd4BQVVfeXFMTmNXR3NEbzY4cUIwRkhMNVBubThENThUaGNobExGWncxTjFRUkZvenJoUU1oOXNGQURwLWpGdDBFSFBxWWxyeFN1aEg4ZmVsWVRSNG11bmwxVkdCbjk3RWpzOVdjQWRGZmR2ZjM5WC1pT0lvcVg5SzFHZlhOMjRzekpzRXp2OUlDdkJDMHI0dTFDSXFHWjhNYlJVbVF3VGRDVFpLUFlabjI2cy1weHcyMHo0QUFWQ2hmVW54akR0MEFkZDFXZ0xkUFFSVGVMdjZoSlc3Qms0UlE4b3ZNdW5R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daily glass of milk helps prevent bowel cancer - but another drink increases risk - The Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A glass of milk helps prevent bowel cancer - but another drink increases risk</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Mirror</p>
<img src="https://i2-prod.mirror.co.uk/incoming/article34439578.ece/ALTERNATES/n615/0_Pelvic-pain-stomachache-concept-Hands-of-young-woman-on-stomach-as-suffer-on-menstruation-cramp-in.jpg" alt="A woman sitting side-on, grasping her abdomen">
<figcaption>Milk could help tackle rising bowel cancer cases in Britain</figcaption>
<p>Recent research from Oxford University indicates that calcium could be crucial in preventing bowel cancer. A 17-year study involving over half a million women revealed that those consuming calcium-rich products like milk had a lower risk of developing the disease.</p>
<ul>
  <li>An additional 300mg of calcium daily reduced bowel cancer risk by 17%.</li>
  <li>Conversely, consuming 20g of alcohol per day raised the risk by 15%.</li>
  <li>Increased red meat consumption also correlated with higher bowel cancer risk.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is the most comprehensive single study ever conducted into the relationship between diet and bowel cancer,” said Dr. Keren Papier.</blockquote>
<p>Bowel cancer causes significant mortality in the UK, with nearly 17,000 deaths annually. The research, published in Nature Communications, shows an urgent need for awareness around dietary choices affecting cancer risk.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mirror.co.uk/news/health/daily-glass-milk-helps-prevent-34439522</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mirror.co.uk/news/health/daily-glass-milk-helps-prevent-34439522</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>