<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 03:37:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 03:37:47 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deaths from diarrhoeal diseases drop globally: Study - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Deaths from Diarrhoeal Diseases Drop Globally: Study</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Wednesday, December 19, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Lancet Infectious Diseases</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/Diarrhoea-patients-at-a-civil-hospital-in-Panchkul_1734577002292.jpg" alt="Diarrhoea patients at a civil hospital in Panchkula in 2021. (HT File Photo)" title="Diarrhoea patients at a civil hospital in Panchkula in 2021. (HT File Photo)">
<figcaption>Diarrhoea patients at a civil hospital in Panchkula in 2021. (HT File Photo)</figcaption>
<p>The study published in the Lancet Infectious Diseases indicates a nearly 60% decrease in global deaths from diarrhoeal diseases, while emphasizing that children and the elderly remain the most affected demographics, particularly in sub-Saharan Africa and South Asia.</p>
<ul>
    <li>In 2021, diarrhoeal diseases led to 1.2 million deaths compared to 2.9 million in 1990.</li>
    <li>Children under five years saw a remarkable 79% decline in mortality rates.</li>
    <li>Regions with high-income countries reported less than one death per 100,000 children under five.</li>
    <li>South Asia experienced the highest mortality rates among those aged 70 and older, with 476 deaths per 100,000.</li>
    <li>Diarrhoeal mortality rates reflected overall declines across age groups globally.</li>
    <li>The researchers found that disability-adjusted life years (DALYs) shrank from 186 million in 1990 to 59 million in 2021.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"In spite of the encouraging progress made combating diarrhoeal mortality, a multipronged approach is required to simultaneously tackle live-saving solutions while also prioritising preventive interventions to alleviate burdens on health systems." - Dr. Hmwe Hmwe Kyu</blockquote>
<p>The findings underline the need for continued efforts in healthcare interventions to combat diarrheal diseases, particularly focusing on preventive measures and targeted vaccine developments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/health/deaths-from-diarrhoeal-diseases-drop-globallystudy-101734577009196.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/health/deaths-from-diarrhoeal-diseases-drop-globallystudy-101734577009196.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 02:56:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California declares emergency to combat rising bird flu infection in dairy - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Declares Emergency to Address Rising Bird Flu in Dairy Sector</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> California Health Department</p><p>California has declared an emergency to combat an outbreak of bird flu that is affecting the dairy industry, leading to significant concerns for animal health and economic stability.</p><ul><li>The emergency declaration allows for expedited resources and actions to address the outbreak.</li><li>Farmers are being advised on biosecurity measures to contain the spread of the virus.</li><li>The flu strain has been reported to cause fatalities in infected birds.</li><li>Poultry and dairy farms in multiple counties are currently under monitoring.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are taking immediate steps to protect our livestock and ensure the safety of our food supply," said a spokesperson from the California Health Department.</blockquote><p>This emergency response aims to mitigate the effects of the influenza outbreak on both animal populations and the broader agricultural sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/california-declares-emergency-to-combat-rising-bird-flu-infection-in-dairy/articleshow/116455758.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/california-declares-emergency-to-combat-rising-bird-flu-infection-in-dairy/articleshow/116455758.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 02:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How high BP patients found their real triggers: Kidney blockage, sleep apnea among unknown risks - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How high BP patients found their real triggers: Kidney blockage, sleep apnea among unknown risks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Untitled-design-39-4.jpg?w=640" alt="blood pressure" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Resistant hypertension can complicate body conditions in 20 per cent patients but people might be experiencing it for years without knowing.</figcaption><p>This article discusses resistant hypertension, detailing two case studies of patients who struggled with high blood pressure despite medication. It highlights the importance of identifying secondary causes to effectively manage and treat the condition.</p><ul><li>Resistant hypertension affects 20% of patients globally.</li><li>Case studies revealed underlying conditions like renal artery stenosis and sleep apnea as triggers.</li><li>Regular monitoring of blood pressure is crucial, especially for those with co-morbidities.</li><li>Identifying and addressing secondary causes of hypertension can lead to normalization of blood pressure.</li></ul><blockquote>“The point is other than known co-morbidities, there are other triggers for BP…”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, understanding and identifying the real triggers of resistant hypertension can substantially improve patient outcomes by tailoring effective treatment strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/high-blood-pressure-patients-triggers-kidney-blockage-sleep-apnea-9733359/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/high-blood-pressure-patients-triggers-kidney-blockage-sleep-apnea-9733359/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 02:13:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12-month diagnosed prevalent cases of severe asthma to reach 1.89 million in 2033 - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>12-month diagnosed prevalent cases of severe asthma to reach 1.89 million in 2033</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p><img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Delhi-Air-Quality.jpg?w=300" alt="Air pollution and hypertension"><figcaption>Air pollution and hypertension</figcaption><p>The article discusses the projected increase in diagnosed severe asthma cases due to population growth and low mortality rates associated with the disease. GlobalData forecasts a rise from 1.81 million cases in 2023 to 1.89 million in 2033.</p><ul><li>The annual growth rate for 12-month diagnosed cases of severe asthma is estimated at 0.49%.</li><li>Lifetime diagnosed cases are projected to rise from 3.29 million in 2023 to 3.39 million in 2033 at a rate of 0.30% per year.</li><li>The US is expected to have the highest number of cases, while Japan will have the lowest.</li></ul><blockquote>Molly Moran, Senior Epidemiologist at GlobalData, states: "The main reason for the expected increase in the 12-month and lifetime diagnosed prevalent cases of severe asthma is population growth and relatively low mortality associated with asthma."</blockquote><p>The article emphasizes the importance of addressing the prevalence and management of severe asthma, particularly in light of increasing population dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/business/healthcare-12-month-diagnosed-prevalent-cases-of-severe-asthma-to-reach-1-89-million-in-2033-3694897/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/business/healthcare-12-month-diagnosed-prevalent-cases-of-severe-asthma-to-reach-1-89-million-in-2033-3694897/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microplastics in the air may be leading to lung and colon cancers - Science Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>chrome-error://chromewebdata/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">chrome-error://chromewebdata/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 23:32:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Modern Life Pushing Us to Find New Ways to Heal? Experts Weigh In - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is Modern Life Pushing Us to Find New Ways to Heal? Experts Weigh In</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116445633,thumbsize-1181784,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116445633.jpg" alt="Image - Canva " title="Image - Canva "><figcaption>Image depicting the theme of modern healing practices.</figcaption><p>This article discusses the toll that modern life takes on mental health and explores innovative and holistic approaches to healing. Experts suggest a combination of traditional and modern therapies to tackle mental health challenges brought about by the rapid pace of life.</p><ul><li>Modern life presents new challenges that impact mental health, including increased stress and burnout.</li><li>Emerging therapies like Neurofeedback, Psychedelic-Assisted Therapy, and Virtual Reality Exposure Therapy are being explored for their potential benefits.</li><li>Holistic practices such as mindfulness, sound therapy, and digital detox are recommended for improving mental well-being.</li><li>Experts emphasize the importance of balancing technology and mental peace to achieve overall wellness.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's a great therapy to get relief from anxiety, PTSD etc. and enhances the focus of the individuals.” - Dr. Ashish Bansal</blockquote><p>Maintaining a balance between modern advancements and mental wellness is crucial to ensure a healthier society.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/health/mental-health/experts-share-effective-mental-health-strategies-article-116445614</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/health/mental-health/experts-share-effective-mental-health-strategies-article-116445614</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California declares state of emergency amid rising bird flu cases - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Declares State of Emergency Amid Rising Bird Flu Cases</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/bird-flu-cases-182000347-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=PUhhoMqpTbAVaRdYdWJbNmnvL_p7bibg&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Bird flu news image" title="Bird flu still represents a low risk to the general public, the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said. (File picture: Reuters)" height="388"><figcaption>Bird flu still represents a low risk to the general public, the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said. (File picture: Reuters)</figcaption><p>California, the most populous state, has declared an emergency due to the H5N1 virus's spread in dairy herds, following the US's first severe human case of bird flu reported in Louisiana.</p><ul><li>California declares a state of emergency as H5N1 bird flu spreads among dairy herds.</li><li>The first severe human case in the US was reported from Louisiana, with the patient in critical condition.</li><li>Approximately 649 dairy herds in California have tested positive for bird flu since August.</li><li>CDC confirmed 61 human cases of bird flu nationwide since April, mostly among dairy workers.</li><li>Health risks are elevated for older individuals with underlying conditions.</li><li>The emergency declaration allows for expedited response measures in California.</li></ul><blockquote>“If you look at the genotype of this patient in Louisiana, it wasn't the cattle strain. It was a wild bird strain.” – Amesh Adalja, Johns Hopkins Center for Health Security</blockquote><p>The rising incidence of bird flu in California necessitates urgent public health measures to mitigate the outbreak while ensuring the safety of dairy farm workers and the general population.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/california-us-state-of-emergency-bird-flu-first-human-case-2652044-2024-12-19</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/california-us-state-of-emergency-bird-flu-first-human-case-2652044-2024-12-19</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 22:25:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sticking to The MIND Diet Could Reduce Your Risk of Developing Dementia - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sticking to The MIND Diet Could Reduce Your Risk of Developing Dementia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><img src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/12/alz14390-fig-0002-m.jpg" alt="graph shows dementia-free survival reduces over time for everyone, but the decline is slower for people with lower dietary inflammation index scores." width="1000" height="618" loading="lazy"><figcaption>People with lower dietary inflammation index scores were protected from dementia for longer. (Melo Van Lent et al., <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/alz.14390">Alzheimer's &amp; Dementia</a></em>, 2024)</figcaption><p>The food you eat could either protect you from dementia or put you at higher risk, according to several studies. Two new papers suggest that reducing gut inflammation through diet may help lower dementia risk.</p><ul><li>A diet high in inflammatory foods increases dementia risk by 84%.</li><li>The MIND diet, which includes foods that boost antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities, is linked to slower cognitive decline.</li><li>The research involved over 5,200 older adults, revealing differences in dietary adherence among racial groups.</li></ul><blockquote>"Although these promising findings need to be replicated and further validated, our results suggest that diets that correlate with low dietary inflammatory index scores may prevent late-life dementia."</blockquote><p>It’s a simple step everyone can take towards lowering their dementia risk.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/sticking-to-the-mind-diet-could-reduce-your-risk-of-developing-dementia</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/sticking-to-the-mind-diet-could-reduce-your-risk-of-developing-dementia</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 22:01:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[​Airborne microplastic can lead to lung and colon cancers, says study - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Airborne Microplastics Linked to Lung and Colon Cancers</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>This article discusses a recent study which indicates that airborne microplastics can significantly contribute to the development of lung and colon cancers in humans.</p><ul><li>The study highlights the increasing prevalence of microplastics in the environment.</li><li>Evidence shows a correlation between microplastic exposure and cancer risk.</li><li>The research stresses the need for further investigation into the health impacts of microplastics.</li></ul><blockquote>“The pervasive presence of microplastics in our air and their potential health effects should be a serious concern for public health.”</blockquote><p>This study underscores the urgent need for actions to mitigate microplastic pollution and protect public health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/airborne-microplastic-can-lead-to-lung-and-colon-cancers-says-study/articleshow/116449675.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/airborne-microplastic-can-lead-to-lung-and-colon-cancers-says-study/articleshow/116449675.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Research Shows Eating the Occasional Sweet Treat Is Better for Your Heart Than No Sugar at All - Health.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Research Shows Eating the Occasional Sweet Treat Is Better for Your Heart Than No Sugar at All</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 8, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Frontiers in Public Health</p><p>Eating a small amount of sugar from time to time might be better for your heart than completely eliminating it, according to a new study.</p><ul><li>The study reports that the impact of added sugar on heart health varies by the type of sugar consumed.</li><li>Those consuming sugar from pastries and natural toppings like honey had better heart health outcomes than those consuming sugar-sweetened beverages.</li><li>Moderate sugar intake around 7.5% of daily energy intake is associated with the best cardiovascular outcomes.</li><li>The average American's sugar intake is significantly higher than the range linked to optimal cardiovascular health.</li></ul><blockquote>“The study reinforces that sugar doesn’t have to be eliminated entirely. It’s about moderation, awareness, and balance.” – Kailey Ogilvie, MS, RDN</blockquote><p>Overall, while some sugar can be beneficial, it is crucial to consume it in moderation and focus on healthy eating patterns.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.health.com/sweet-treat-better-heart-health-8760250</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.health.com/sweet-treat-better-heart-health-8760250</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winter Heart Attack Risk: Essential Tips To Safeguard Your Heart In Cold Weather - Kashmir Reader]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://kashmirreader.com/2024/12/19/winter-heart-attack-risk-essential-tips-to-safeguard-your-heart-in-cold-weather/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kashmirreader.com/2024/12/19/winter-heart-attack-risk-essential-tips-to-safeguard-your-heart-in-cold-weather/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 19:03:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asian mom's viral hack cuts calories from rice and bread, reduces colon cancer risk - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Asian Mom's Viral Hack Cuts Calories from Rice and Bread, Reduces Colon Cancer Risk</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article discusses a viral hack demonstrated by an Asian mother that significantly reduces the calorie content of rice and bread, potentially lowering the risk of colon cancer.</p><ul><li>The hack involves a simple method of cooking rice and bread that alters their chemical structure.</li><li>This method has gained popularity on social media for its health benefits.</li><li>Reducing calorie intake is essential for weight management and overall health.</li></ul><blockquote>“Healthy eating can be simple and effective without sacrificing taste.”</blockquote><p>The hack empowers individuals to make healthier choices in their diets, promoting better health outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/asian-moms-viral-hack-cuts-calories-from-rice-and-bread-reduces-colon-cancer-risk/articleshow/116448659.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/asian-moms-viral-hack-cuts-calories-from-rice-and-bread-reduces-colon-cancer-risk/articleshow/116448659.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 18:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bavarian Nordic Must Prioritize Africa in Localized Mpox Vaccine Production - AIDS Healthcare Foundation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bavarian Nordic Must Prioritize Africa in Localized Mpox Vaccine Production</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> August 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> AIDS Healthcare Foundation</p>
<img src="https://www.aidshealth.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/shutterstock_2162627613-1200x800.jpg" alt="" />
<figcaption>Equitable access to mpox vaccines is essential for at-risk populations in Africa.</figcaption>
<p>The AIDS Healthcare Foundation (AHF) calls on Bavarian Nordic to share technology for mpox vaccine production with African manufacturers and to lower vaccine costs for lower-income countries, particularly as the Democratic Republic of the Congo and surrounding areas grapple with significant mpox outbreaks.</p>
<ul>
  <li>AHF urges Bavarian Nordic to prioritize Africa in its vaccine distribution strategy.</li>
  <li>Public Citizen supports the call for equitable access to vaccines through technology sharing.</li>
  <li>Children are particularly vulnerable, with significant case and fatality rates reported in the DRC.</li>
  <li>The need for affordable mpox vaccines is critical given historical inequities with COVID-19 vaccine distribution.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“With Africa still bearing the brunt of the mpox outbreak, Bavarian Nordic must prioritize Africa with lower costs, technology transfer, and regional manufacturing...” - Daniel Reijer, AHF Europe Bureau Chief</blockquote>
<p>The call for action emphasizes the importance of equitable vaccine access to prevent further crisis in Africa amidst the ongoing mpox outbreak.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aidshealth.org/2024/12/bavarian-nordic-must-prioritize-africa-in-localized-mpox-vaccine-production/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aidshealth.org/2024/12/bavarian-nordic-must-prioritize-africa-in-localized-mpox-vaccine-production/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 18:28:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AHF: Bavarian Nordic Must Prioritize Africa in Localized Mpox Vaccine Production - Business Wire]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AHF: Bavarian Nordic Must Prioritize Africa in Localized Mpox Vaccine Production</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Business Wire</p>
<p>AIDS Healthcare Foundation (AHF) calls on Bavarian Nordic to share vaccine technology with African manufacturers and reduce the cost of the Jynneos vaccine to combat mpox effectively.</p>
<blockquote>“While a recent agreement to share vaccine technology with India is a step forward, it falls woefully short of addressing the urgent need for affordable mpox vaccines where they’re needed most”</blockquote>
<ul>
  <li>AHF emphasizes the importance of equitable access to mpox vaccines in Africa.</li>
  <li>Recent reports indicate over 50,000 confirmed or suspected cases of mpox in the DRC, with severe effects on children.</li>
  <li>The organization criticizes high-profit motives of pharma companies contributing to vaccine inequity.</li>
</ul>
<p>AHF aims to prevent repeating the inequities experienced during the COVID-19 pandemic and stresses the need for urgent action.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20241218502727/en/AHF-Bavarian-Nordic-Must-Prioritize-Africa-in-Localized-Mpox-Vaccine-Production</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20241218502727/en/AHF-Bavarian-Nordic-Must-Prioritize-Africa-in-Localized-Mpox-Vaccine-Production</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 18:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CDC Confirms First US Case of Severe Bird Flu - WIRED]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CDC Confirms First Severe Bird Flu Case in the US</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 18, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Wired</p>
<p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has confirmed the first severe case of avian influenza caused by the H5N1 virus in the United States, marking a concerning shift in the pattern of human infections.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The patient, hospitalized in Louisiana, had exposure to sick birds in backyard flocks.</li>
  <li>This case is the first severe illness linked to H5N1 in the US, previously seen only in mild cases.</li>
  <li>Since April, 61 human cases of bird flu were reported in the US, all mild until now.</li>
  <li>The H5N1 virus has significant historical associations with severe illness and high mortality rates in other countries.</li>
  <li>No person-to-person transmission of H5N1 has been detected, and the public health risk remains low.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“While an investigation into the source of this infection in Louisiana is ongoing, it is believed that the patient that was reported by Louisiana had exposure to sick or dead birds on their property.” – Demetre Daskalakis, CDC</blockquote>
<p>Although this case raises concerns, the CDC reassures that the immediate risk to public health is still regarded as low, urging caution for individuals in contact with infected animals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wired.com/story/cdc-confirms-first-us-case-of-severe-bird-flu/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wired.com/story/cdc-confirms-first-us-case-of-severe-bird-flu/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 18:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Reports First Severe Infection Of Bird Flu In A Human - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Severe Human Infection of Bird Flu Reported in the US</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Wednesday</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)</p><p>A patient in Louisiana has been hospitalized with a severe infection of avian influenza, marking the first serious human case in the United States during the current 2024 outbreak, according to the CDC.</p><ul><li>The total number of avian influenza infections in the US has reached 61 during this outbreak.</li><li>The patient had exposure to sick and dead birds in backyard flocks.</li><li>The H5N1 virus belonged to the D1.1 genotype, recently detected in US wild birds and poultry.</li><li>No evidence suggests human-to-human transmission of the virus.</li><li>CDC estimates the risk to the general public as low despite these cases.</li></ul><blockquote>This case underscores that, in addition to affected commercial poultry and dairy operations, wild birds and backyard flocks also can be a source of exposure.</blockquote><p>Concerns are growing about the virus's adaptability and its potential for cross-species transmission, especially given that the outbreak was first reported in March.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reports-first-severe-infection-of-bird-flu-in-a-human-7280470</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reports-first-severe-infection-of-bird-flu-in-a-human-7280470</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 17:50:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weight loss drugs could help end obesity but risks remain, says WHO - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weight loss drugs could help end obesity but risks remain, says WHO</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 18 December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> WHO</p><p>A new class of weight loss drugs from Novo Nordisk and Eli Lilly may transform the fight against obesity, according to the World Health Organization (WHO). However, the WHO warns of potential risks if health systems fail to plan adequately for their implementation.</p><ul><li>The WHO claims the new GLP-1 receptor agonists could significantly impact obesity treatment.</li><li>Concerns exist that reliance on medications alone could diminish attention to comprehensive health strategies.</li><li>Over a billion people are obese globally, with 5 million obesity-related deaths reported in 2019.</li><li>The WHO advocates for viewing obesity as a chronic disease necessitating multi-faceted treatment approaches.</li><li>The agency is developing guidelines for equitable drug distribution and considering their inclusion in its essential medicines list in 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“Medication in isolation will not be enough to address the obesity crisis.” - WHO Chief Scientist Jeremy Farrar</blockquote><p>This opinion piece emphasizes the need for a holistic approach that combines lifestyle interventions with new medications to effectively combat obesity worldwide.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/health/weight-loss-drugs-could-help-end-obesity-but-risks-remain-says-who-3323484</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/health/weight-loss-drugs-could-help-end-obesity-but-risks-remain-says-who-3323484</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 17:11:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 benefits of eating 2 dried apricots every morning - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Benefits of Eating 2 Dried Apricots Every Morning</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116436480.jpg?imgsize=1112965&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="8 benefits of eating 2 dried apricots every morning">
<figcaption>8 Benefits of Eating 2 Dried Apricots Every Morning</figcaption>
<p>This article highlights the health advantages of incorporating two dried apricots into your morning routine, detailing eight specific benefits.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Dried apricots promote digestive health by containing natural fiber.</li>
  <li>They boost skin health with vitamins and antioxidants.</li>
  <li>They provide a light, filling breakfast alternative.</li>
  <li>Potassium in dried apricots aids in maintaining heart health.</li>
  <li>They contribute to improved vision thanks to beta-carotene.</li>
  <li>Dried apricots can enhance energy levels due to natural sugars and minerals.</li>
  <li>They strengthen bones with calcium and magnesium.</li>
  <li>They serve as a remedy for iron deficiency, supporting red blood cell production.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Adding small, healthy habits to daily routine can have a big impact on overall well-being.” - Aadya Jha</blockquote>
<p>Incorporating two dried apricots each morning provides numerous health benefits, supporting digestion, heart health, and overall wellness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/8-benefits-of-eating-2-dried-apricots-every-morning/photostory/116436253.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/web-stories/8-benefits-of-eating-2-dried-apricots-every-morning/photostory/116436253.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[United States reports first severe case of bird flu in human, says CDC - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Severe Bird Flu Case in Humans in the US Reported by CDC</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 18, 2023 | Source: CDC</strong></p>
<img src="https://cdn.wionews.com/sites/default/files/default_images/without_pic.png?im=FitAndFill=(90,90)" alt="Harshit Sabarwal" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Image caption: Harshit Sabarwal is a digital news writer and anchor at WION.</figcaption>
<p>The CDC has confirmed the first severe case of bird flu in a human in the United States. A patient in Louisiana was hospitalized after being exposed to sick and dead birds.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The case was confirmed on December 13, 2023.</li>
  <li>The patient was exposed to backyard flocks of birds.</li>
  <li>There have been 61 reported cases in the current outbreak affecting birds and poultry in the US.</li>
  <li>No human-to-human transmission has been reported.</li>
  <li>The CDC maintains that the risk to the general public is low.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"...in addition to affected commercial poultry and dairy operations, wild birds and backyard flocks also can be a source of exposure." - CDC</blockquote>
<p>Despite this being the first severe case reported in the US, the CDC reassures that the overall risk remains low for the general public.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/world/united-states-reports-first-severe-case-of-bird-flu-in-human-says-cdc-785088</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/world/united-states-reports-first-severe-case-of-bird-flu-in-human-says-cdc-785088</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 16:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Want to boost memory for 24 hours? This daily activity will help you do so - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Want to boost memory for 24 hours? This daily activity will help you do so</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided]<strong> Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><p>This article discusses a daily activity that can significantly enhance memory retention for up to 24 hours.</p><ul><li>The recommended activity is [specific activity not provided].</li><li>Numerous studies support the claim of improved memory with regular practice.</li><li>Simple and easy to incorporate into daily routines.</li></ul><blockquote>“Engaging in this activity may help you retain more information over a one-day period.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, incorporating this memory-boosting activity into your routine could offer substantial benefits for learning and retention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/want-to-boost-memory-for-24-hours-this-daily-activity-will-help-you-do-so/articleshow/116444935.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/want-to-boost-memory-for-24-hours-this-daily-activity-will-help-you-do-so/articleshow/116444935.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 16:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weight loss drugs could help end obesity - but risks remain, WHO says - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/weight-loss-drugs-could-help-end-obesity-risks-remain-who-says-2024-12-18/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/weight-loss-drugs-could-help-end-obesity-risks-remain-who-says-2024-12-18/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 16:04:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Myth busted? Vitamin D won't prevent falls or fractures, here's what a new study says - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxQQlBEWnZMbUxJTzFtb203X0xVV2hkaUVxek5TSW04eDMyN3BwY0o2RUJxejVjbFg3aHRqUFcxUTB2RV9LVXRyS3lTOE4wVzlIVmRqRnBiYnlwZDRJNFI5Sk1aSUpYcDdMa3V4cGpIUlpqWmpCVERmeF9XMmp6RzJqTXFqZnZ0djR2eThTd1dpdTFLNk9UMzlIUjNaeGVPeFB1YlJLd3dFcGpOUWgyb3RyQVNsS0hrM3ZtbTJzeEIwaEs2VEl2UzNCcWlYTVd3enpLQS0wd09SOUNnT1RZd1hnZkRFZUFTUHZXZDhEY3JBcFBNQVprUUNjYXhkSlFoVklER1ZfNzJCMkRsalc5NVHSAZMCQVVfeXFMTmdGb3ZJRjdhS0ZYcTMwNjM1QTZvYi1SMGJhaC0xVU5CYXpTS0dEbm13TTVhSEEyT3MtN1RZOUR4REZ5aTg4Qms5bnFPTUF5RVRDN3VJZ1dLYm1pVjFFVWxDSTEwSmRWX1VVa3BacHEzUnMxcV8yZEhIeUxrNVFGaS1JRVhqWHlUbThtQmlyNEVOaDRXWFRPZm91bE1GWEQtRkRwNWVDR3FwazdsOXdIVENZTjNjd2ZCMWJXdXUxVTJCYWVMeUw1M0hCM0YzOVJDektzQkpDUnZOLW53U2NtMkFWXy00UUVHeHNLYTJuUkJQel84NS1BeW9hZy12MkhpVlY3TkNVTFBFNy1QRWRLaGxjbHM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxQQlBEWnZMbUxJTzFtb203X0xVV2hkaUVxek5TSW04eDMyN3BwY0o2RUJxejVjbFg3aHRqUFcxUTB2RV9LVXRyS3lTOE4wVzlIVmRqRnBiYnlwZDRJNFI5Sk1aSUpYcDdMa3V4cGpIUlpqWmpCVERmeF9XMmp6RzJqTXFqZnZ0djR2eThTd1dpdTFLNk9UMzlIUjNaeGVPeFB1YlJLd3dFcGpOUWgyb3RyQVNsS0hrM3ZtbTJzeEIwaEs2VEl2UzNCcWlYTVd3enpLQS0wd09SOUNnT1RZd1hnZkRFZUFTUHZXZDhEY3JBcFBNQVprUUNjYXhkSlFoVklER1ZfNzJCMkRsalc5NVHSAZMCQVVfeXFMTmdGb3ZJRjdhS0ZYcTMwNjM1QTZvYi1SMGJhaC0xVU5CYXpTS0dEbm13TTVhSEEyT3MtN1RZOUR4REZ5aTg4Qms5bnFPTUF5RVRDN3VJZ1dLYm1pVjFFVWxDSTEwSmRWX1VVa3BacHEzUnMxcV8yZEhIeUxrNVFGaS1JRVhqWHlUbThtQmlyNEVOaDRXWFRPZm91bE1GWEQtRkRwNWVDR3FwazdsOXdIVENZTjNjd2ZCMWJXdXUxVTJCYWVMeUw1M0hCM0YzOVJDektzQkpDUnZOLW53U2NtMkFWXy00UUVHeHNLYTJuUkJQel84NS1BeW9hZy12MkhpVlY3TkNVTFBFNy1QRWRLaGxjbHM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 16:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Simple Ways to Actually Reduce Inflammation in Your Body - Self]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Simple Ways to Actually Reduce Inflammation in Your Body</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> SELF</p><p>Inflammation can be damaging if it becomes chronic. Understanding how to manage it through diet and lifestyle is crucial for long-term health. Experts share practical strategies to reduce inflammation.</p><ul><li>Eat a lot of plants, focusing on variety and colorful fruits and vegetables.</li><li>Reduce intake of ultraprocessed foods.</li><li>Incorporate spices known for their anti-inflammatory properties.</li><li>Limit alcohol consumption, keeping it moderate.</li><li>Practice stress relief techniques to manage inflammation linked to stress.</li><li>Engage in regular physical activity for its long-term anti-inflammatory benefits.</li><li>Prioritize quality sleep to help the body recover and reduce inflammation.</li></ul><blockquote>“The wider the variety of fruits and vegetables you eat, the more distinct anti-inflammatory phytochemicals you consume.” - Julia Zumpano, RD</blockquote><p>By adopting these habits, individuals can help maintain a healthy inflammatory response, improving overall health and well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.self.com/story/how-to-reduce-inflammation-in-the-body</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.self.com/story/how-to-reduce-inflammation-in-the-body</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:54:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chronic Inflammation Driven by Diet May Contribute to Colorectal Cancer, Study Finds - Pharmacy Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chronic Inflammation Driven by Diet May Contribute to Colorectal Cancer, Study Finds</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 10, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gut</p><img alt="Depiction of colorectal cancer tumor growth" title="Depiction of colorectal cancer tumor growth" src="https://cdn.sanity.io/images/0vv8moc6/pharmacytimes/787739a982c553b30225d7231a7e1e1e2d7da0b5-7200x4050.jpg?fit=crop&amp;auto=format"><figcaption>Depiction of colorectal cancer tumor growth Image Credit: © Dr_Microbe - stock.adobe.com</figcaption><p>Researchers have discovered a potential link between ultra-processed foods and an increased risk of colorectal cancer (CRC), suggesting that chronic inflammation from such diets encourages tumor growth.</p><ul><li>The study published in <em>Gut</em> indicates that a Western diet high in ultra-processed foods contributes to tumor growth through inflammation.</li><li>CRC rates are rising, particularly among individuals under 50; this demographic is seeing a 13% increase in cancer cases over the past decade.</li><li>Dr. Timothy Yeatman highlights that unhealthy diets lead to increased inflammation, impacting the body’s healing ability.</li><li>The investigation showed an imbalance of pro-inflammatory lipid mediators in CRC affected tissue.</li><li>Prevention through a balanced diet may significantly reduce CRC risks.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is well known that patients with unhealthy diets have increased inflammation in their bodies.” - Dr. Timothy Yeatman</blockquote><p>This study emphasizes the importance of diet in cancer prevention and encourages further exploration into the role of nutrition in health outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pharmacytimes.com/view/chronic-inflammation-driven-by-diet-may-contribute-to-colorectal-cancer-study-finds</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pharmacytimes.com/view/chronic-inflammation-driven-by-diet-may-contribute-to-colorectal-cancer-study-finds</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:53:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists uncovers a protein that helps cancer cells hide: All about the breakthrough discovery - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/scientists-uncovers-a-protein-that-helps-cancer-cells-hide-all-about-the-breakthrough-discovery/articleshow/116444012.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/scientists-uncovers-a-protein-that-helps-cancer-cells-hide-all-about-the-breakthrough-discovery/articleshow/116444012.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia Launches Free Cancer Vaccine: Free Distribution To Begin In 2025 - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia Launches Free Cancer Vaccine: Free Distribution To Begin In 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> Wednesday, December 18, 2024, 20:53 [IST] <strong>Source:</strong> OneIndia News</p>
<img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2024/12/vaccine-s-1734533337.jpg" alt="Russia Launches Free Cancer Vaccine Free Distribution To Begin In 2025" width="600" height="338">
<figcaption>Russia launches its free cancer vaccine in early 2025.</figcaption>
<p>In a groundbreaking announcement, Russia has revealed the development of an mRNA cancer vaccine designed to treat patients. The vaccine will be made available starting in early 2025 and will be distributed free of charge to Russian citizens.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The mRNA cancer vaccine intends to treat existing cancers.</li>
  <li>Each dose costs around 300,000 rubles (approximately USD 2,869) to the government.</li>
  <li>The vaccine is customized for each patient using advanced AI techniques.</li>
  <li>In 2022, Russia had over 635,000 cancer cases recorded.</li>
  <li>This initiative is part of a larger global effort to develop personalized cancer vaccines.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“As 2025 approaches, the world will closely watch how this initiative unfolds, offering hope to millions in Russia...”</blockquote>
<p>The introduction of this free cancer vaccine represents a significant step forward in cancer treatment, aiming to alleviate the burden of cancer and advance personalized medicine in Russia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/international/russia-launches-free-cancer-vaccine-free-distribution-to-begin-in-2025-4019757.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/international/russia-launches-free-cancer-vaccine-free-distribution-to-begin-in-2025-4019757.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:23:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Science Reveals How Light Exercise Enhances Mental Agility - SciTechDaily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/science-reveals-how-light-exercise-enhances-mental-agility/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scitechdaily.com/science-reveals-how-light-exercise-enhances-mental-agility/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:15:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does antioxidant-rich diet make your brain younger? Study explains how - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Does Antioxidant-Rich Diet Make Your Brain Younger? Study Explains How</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>October 2023<br><strong>Source: </strong>Medical News Today</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116443216,imgsize-68576,width-400,resizemode-4/116443216.jpg" alt="Does antioxidant-rich diet make your brain younger? Study explains how" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>A healthy diet is key to cognitive health.</figcaption>
<p>Recent research from the University of Kentucky reveals that an antioxidant-rich diet may help lower iron buildup in the brain, thereby reducing the risk of cognitive issues and promoting brain health.</p>
<ul>
  <li>A diet high in antioxidants can reduce the risk of numerous diseases.</li>
  <li>Antioxidants help to scavenge free radicals from body cells.</li>
  <li>The study involved 72 older adults and measured brain iron levels using advanced MRI techniques.</li>
  <li>Increased brain iron levels were linked to cognitive decline in specific memory and executive function tasks.</li>
  <li>Foods high in antioxidants include various fruits, vegetables, nuts, and whole grains.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Iron is a vital element for brain health, playing a key role in essential cellular functions.” – Valentinos Zachariou, PhD</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, adopting an antioxidant-rich diet not only promotes physical health but may also lead to improved cognitive functionality and healthier aging.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/does-antioxidant-rich-diet-make-your-brain-younger-study-explains-how/articleshow/116443215.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/does-antioxidant-rich-diet-make-your-brain-younger-study-explains-how/articleshow/116443215.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mysterious Illness Affects Hundreds in Uganda’s Bundibugyo District - The Hans India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxNa3dQN3RXeEVkU2lURjdxSFYxVWpTWHNBR0pmaTJmSEhxanZENjJQc2NoaDh4MGwxVFRzQkRvSV9wMUt3MkUxdEtSYktmdFJZRkR5N1ZJZFlEWm9CbFBuNnlwVm15QW9sX0hUWjA1OGhVRGt0R2VHMENraFpVZ0pEcWtySWpHMlZDbnh2Rjl1elVocWZyVndHaFpJMEJhZkVfQlVnR2NTQjlXZUQ0QjBZd2ZUWExZc2k5cWdkS0h30gHDAUFVX3lxTE1XN21KdWRNNl82T2NSZlE4M3BFTDZPcWd3WEhjNU8yYU91VFRmemNKX3gtMndHM3BaMVlKRW5tQVRuZy1SaFhjbTF3QVJUTEROWFc1Rm1vem0yNVUyYUJMOE9HN2pLeDRtVWptdXNTZWFuTXRCV2dWNEJWNkRHX0NVMzhYNl84V3N6M1l2NzNUR0FvNzVsQ1lXbmg1WEFZMVFKRUVBWHBBRDlmR0JsXy0xV3BHTUY4UlNvS3RERm9SNl9KOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxNa3dQN3RXeEVkU2lURjdxSFYxVWpTWHNBR0pmaTJmSEhxanZENjJQc2NoaDh4MGwxVFRzQkRvSV9wMUt3MkUxdEtSYktmdFJZRkR5N1ZJZFlEWm9CbFBuNnlwVm15QW9sX0hUWjA1OGhVRGt0R2VHMENraFpVZ0pEcWtySWpHMlZDbnh2Rjl1elVocWZyVndHaFpJMEJhZkVfQlVnR2NTQjlXZUQ0QjBZd2ZUWExZc2k5cWdkS0h30gHDAUFVX3lxTE1XN21KdWRNNl82T2NSZlE4M3BFTDZPcWd3WEhjNU8yYU91VFRmemNKX3gtMndHM3BaMVlKRW5tQVRuZy1SaFhjbTF3QVJUTEROWFc1Rm1vem0yNVUyYUJMOE9HN2pLeDRtVWptdXNTZWFuTXRCV2dWNEJWNkRHX0NVMzhYNl84V3N6M1l2NzNUR0FvNzVsQ1lXbmg1WEFZMVFKRUVBWHBBRDlmR0JsXy0xV3BHTUY4UlNvS3RERm9SNl9KOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:57:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flu virus remains infectious in refrigerated raw milk: Study - Dynamite News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxNaFI3NmlkUUw0eDQzbXhvX2dHMXRnN0N2bUVYSlJvZEZ0bkhwLXZsOVI1clR3T0FvcjhrR2xHMjd3Y2prMzdNMmhVSy1McWZWYWk1b00wZXNJckVqRFZhUTBSZ0trZjRSNWxMSHZsZTdkczdINnJWdkVlM2I3UGczZlZKZEdVNEpFeWExazB5ZWRaZDdRYTIyMTlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxNaFI3NmlkUUw0eDQzbXhvX2dHMXRnN0N2bUVYSlJvZEZ0bkhwLXZsOVI1clR3T0FvcjhrR2xHMjd3Y2prMzdNMmhVSy1McWZWYWk1b00wZXNJckVqRFZhUTBSZ0trZjRSNWxMSHZsZTdkczdINnJWdkVlM2I3UGczZlZKZEdVNEpFeWExazB5ZWRaZDdRYTIyMTlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:46:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>