<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Health Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 01:21:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Health.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 01:21:20 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Looking Back at 2024: The health trends that took centre stage - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Looking Back at 2024: The health trends that took centre stage</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><p>This article discusses the major health trends that emerged in 2024, covering topics from skincare advancements to the rise of weight loss drugs.</p><ul><li>Focus on wellness and self-care in skin treatments.</li><li>Increase in popularity of new weight loss medications.</li><li>Impact of technological advancements on personal health monitoring.</li></ul><blockquote>“Anonna Dutt and Rinku Ghosh join us as part of our year-end series to discuss these key trends.”</blockquote><p>The insights from this article highlight the evolving landscape of health and wellness trends in 2024, illustrating consumer priorities in maintaining health and beauty.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/audio/3-things/looking-back-at-2024-the-health-trends-that-took-centre-stage/9744543/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/audio/3-things/looking-back-at-2024-the-health-trends-that-took-centre-stage/9744543/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:53:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[​Pet food recalled after Washington County cat dies of bird flu - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pet Food Recalled After Bird Flu Claims Life of Cat in Washington County</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>Authorities have announced a recall of certain pet food products after a cat in Washington County died from bird flu, raising concerns about the safety of these products for pets.</p><ul><li>The affected pet food may contain ingredients sourced from birds that tested positive for the avian influenza virus.</li><li>Pet owners are advised to check their supplies and discontinue use of the recalled products immediately.</li><li>Symptoms of avian influenza can potentially affect domestic animals, making vigilance essential.</li></ul><blockquote>“This incident underscores the importance of proper food sourcing and monitoring animal health.”</blockquote><p>It is crucial for pet owners to remain informed about pet food recalls to ensure the safety and well-being of their pets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/pet-food-recalled-after-washington-county-cat-dies-of-bird-flu/articleshow/116663973.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/pet-food-recalled-after-washington-county-cat-dies-of-bird-flu/articleshow/116663973.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 22:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roundup: Bird flu tightens grip on California as human cases rise - Xinhua]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE1RSXF4a2xDQVlsUnZwUEFBekRFSm9qckg0RWpNWWxpaGljQlozT2FMRUVLTGJuRkxSX2RUVkpfSkFmckN5STJ5RHdrRzJHWjBzVXBaMjdXYnZJQlVEQ2t6T1JTcjBreXhhX2dNMzdtaEVXM19GLUh5Q1hhU1g?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE1RSXF4a2xDQVlsUnZwUEFBekRFSm9qckg0RWpNWWxpaGljQlozT2FMRUVLTGJuRkxSX2RUVkpfSkFmckN5STJ5RHdrRzJHWjBzVXBaMjdXYnZJQlVEQ2t6T1JTcjBreXhhX2dNMzdtaEVXM19GLUh5Q1hhU1g?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 20:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winter and the heart: Addressing the trend of increasing cardiac issues in winter - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Winter and the Heart: Addressing the Trend of Increasing Cardiac Issues in Winter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>This article discusses the rising incidence of cardiac problems during winter months, exploring the contributing factors and health implications for individuals in colder climates.</p><ul><li>Cardiac issues tend to increase during winter due to colder temperatures affecting blood circulation.</li><li>Factors such as holiday stress and changes in lifestyle during winter are highlighted as risk contributors.</li><li>Health experts emphasize the importance of self-care and awareness regarding heart health during this season.</li></ul><blockquote>“Understanding how winter impacts heart health can help individuals take proactive measures.”</blockquote><p>This article serves as a crucial reminder for individuals to be vigilant about their heart health during winter, as the trends indicate a need for increased awareness and care.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/winter-and-the-heart-addressing-the-trend-of-increasing-cardiac-issues-in-winter/articleshow/116662642.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/winter-and-the-heart-addressing-the-trend-of-increasing-cardiac-issues-in-winter/articleshow/116662642.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 20:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Role of Eye Care Professionals in Maintaining Vision Health - vivaglammagazine.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxOYmNpbGh6TjJzVWNUckU2dmlmdXdKZ2FmVVBQZS1nbzdYd0s4dUVBYjI0RHF3ZGl6M1ZoNDI2WDlLRTZNenhtMU91MktoR0lJNVU1T2J5dTBOSk5JaVkyYWxIMHBXQ0ZUVHo1MGx1U296cGp4aXpESkhjUUlZVmFKbVBTOEFtVXlFY3dZZmFYWlRsRWVRT0FvcA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxOYmNpbGh6TjJzVWNUckU2dmlmdXdKZ2FmVVBQZS1nbzdYd0s4dUVBYjI0RHF3ZGl6M1ZoNDI2WDlLRTZNenhtMU91MktoR0lJNVU1T2J5dTBOSk5JaVkyYWxIMHBXQ0ZUVHo1MGx1U296cGp4aXpESkhjUUlZVmFKbVBTOEFtVXlFY3dZZmFYWlRsRWVRT0FvcA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 20:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New method of scanning shows effects of treatment on lung function - ANI News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New method of scanning shows effects of treatment on lung function</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p>
<p>A novel way of scanning lungs can demonstrate the impact of treatment on lung function in real-time, benefiting patients with asthma, COPD, and lung transplants.</p>
<ul>
<li>The scanning technique allows doctors to observe changes in lung function and detect deterioration earlier.</li>
<li>Research led by Newcastle University uses perfluoro propane gas visible on MRI scans.</li>
<li>Scans show patchy ventilation and improvements in lung function with treatment.</li>
<li>Study results published in Radiology and JHLT Open validate the method's effectiveness.</li>
<li>Quantitative assessments can aid in clinical trials for new lung disease treatments.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our scans show where there is patchy ventilation in patients with lung disease, and show us which parts of the lung improve with treatment.” - Professor Pete Thelwall</blockquote>
<p>The new scanning method shows promise in enhancing understanding and treatment of lung conditions, potentially revolutionizing patient care in this field.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aninews.in/news/health/new-method-of-scanning-shows-effects-of-treatment-on-lung-function20241225234825/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aninews.in/news/health/new-method-of-scanning-shows-effects-of-treatment-on-lung-function20241225234825/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 18:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doctors stunned to find 27 contact lenses in woman's eye; here's how it happened - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Doctors Stunned to Find 27 Contact Lenses in Woman's Eye</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>A recent medical case has revealed a shocking discovery of 27 contact lenses lodged in a woman's eye, leaving doctors astonished. This incident raises significant awareness about the importance of proper eye care and hygiene.</p><ul><li>The woman had been experiencing discomfort in her eye for several weeks.</li><li>Upon examination, doctors found multiple lenses that had accumulated over time.</li><li>This case highlights the risks associated with wearing contact lenses beyond their intended use.</li></ul><blockquote>"It's essential to adhere to lens-wearing guidelines to avoid such complications." - Eye Specialist</blockquote><p>This remarkable case emphasizes the critical need for awareness and education surrounding contact lens usage.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/doctors-stunned-to-find-27-contact-lenses-in-womans-eye-heres-how-it-happened/articleshow/116661001.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/doctors-stunned-to-find-27-contact-lenses-in-womans-eye-heres-how-it-happened/articleshow/116661001.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 18:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists develop scan that unravels secrets of lung function - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Develop New Lung Scanning Method to Monitor Function and Treatment Effects</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p>
<p>A team of scientists has created a groundbreaking method for scanning lungs that reveals the effects of treatments in real-time, particularly useful for monitoring transplanted lungs.</p>
<img src='path_to_image.jpg' alt='Lung Scan Example'>
<figcaption>Example of a lung scan using the new method.</figcaption>
<p>This innovative scan visualizes air movement within the lungs for patients suffering from asthma, COPD, and those who have undergone lung transplants.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The method shows how air moves in and out of the lungs during breathing.</li>
  <li>Led by Newcastle University researchers, the study was published in Radiology and JHLT Open.</li>
  <li>Utilizes a safe gas (perfluoropropane) visible in MRI scans to analyze lung function.</li>
  <li>Can identify areas of patchy ventilation and gauge improvements from treatments such as salbutamol.</li>
  <li>May facilitate earlier intervention in lung transplant care and disease management.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We hope this new type of scan might allow us to see changes in the transplant lungs earlier and before signs of damage are present...” – Professor Andrew Fisher</blockquote>
<p>This scan technique has the potential to transform clinical evaluations of lung health and enhance treatment strategies in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/health/scientists-develop-scan-that-unravels-secrets-of-lung-function/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/health/scientists-develop-scan-that-unravels-secrets-of-lung-function/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 17:21:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India reports zero malaria cases in 122 districts in 2023: Centre - The New Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Reports Zero Malaria Cases in 122 Districts in 2023</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Union Health Ministry</p><p>India has marked a significant milestone in its fight against malaria, reporting zero cases in 122 districts in 2023, while also exiting the WHO's high burden to high impact group.</p><ul><li>Over 97% reduction in malaria cases since 1947.</li><li>Annual malaria cases dropped from 7.5 crore to 20 lakhs.</li><li>Malaria-related deaths decreased from 800,000 to just 83.</li><li>The National Framework for Malaria Elimination aims for a malaria-free India by 2030.</li><li>India's exit from the WHO's HBHI group marks a turning point in public health efforts.</li></ul><blockquote>“This historic achievement underscores India’s commitment to eliminating malaria and improving public health for its citizens,” said the ministry.</blockquote><p>The success in reducing malaria cases and deaths highlights India's robust public health strategies and community engagement in the fight against malaria.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/nation/2024/Dec/25/india-reports-zero-malaria-cases-in-122-districts-in-2023-centre</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newindianexpress.com/nation/2024/Dec/25/india-reports-zero-malaria-cases-in-122-districts-in-2023-centre</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:45:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Groundbreaking real-time lung scans to revolutionize respiratory health - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Groundbreaking Real-Time Lung Scans to Revolutionize Respiratory Health</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A &bull; <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<p>This article discusses a new technology in lung scanning that promises to significantly enhance respiratory health diagnostics.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The new lung scanning technology offers real-time analysis, enabling more accurate diagnoses.</li>
  <li>This advancement could lead to better management of respiratory conditions and improved patient outcomes.</li>
  <li>Researchers believe this innovation might change how respiratory diseases are treated in the future.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This technology represents a major leap forward in the early detection of respiratory issues.”</blockquote>
<p>The introduction of real-time scanning for lungs represents a significant advancement in medical technology that could transform treatment protocols for respiratory diseases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/groundbreaking-real-time-lung-scans-to-revolutionize-respiratory-health/articleshow/116659708.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/groundbreaking-real-time-lung-scans-to-revolutionize-respiratory-health/articleshow/116659708.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ways To Make A Healthy Fresh Start In New Year 2025 - Republic World]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxNTlNmTzFrcGhGeGpXXzVoTDdoZ2NES1ZWUDdiRVpLYXJMODh6Q256RjJ5cWJuWm5BSWh0U0dTd3pmWGVucDFzVGF0Z1I4SFNIMEhKanRVckVVRjJpdkdDLVNWM3JVY2xoWHd4eENWeTZhaC0walppNU9iU2FpYW4yRFZSODZXdmtxUklNZkY2eEl1NHZvdTJ5ZnlxSzVtcDVQblFOeVF30gGmAUFVX3lxTE1OU2ZPMWtwaEZ4aldfNWhMN2hnY0RLVlZQN2JFWkthckw4OHpDbnpGMnlxYm5abkFJaHRTR1N3emZYZW5wMXNUYXRnUjhIU0gwSEpqdFVyRVVGMml2R0MtU1YzclVjbGhYd3h4Q1Z5NmFoLTBqWmk1T2JTYWlhbjJEVlI4Nld2a3FSSU1mRjZ4SXU0dm91MnlmeXFLNW1wNVBuUU55UXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxNTlNmTzFrcGhGeGpXXzVoTDdoZ2NES1ZWUDdiRVpLYXJMODh6Q256RjJ5cWJuWm5BSWh0U0dTd3pmWGVucDFzVGF0Z1I4SFNIMEhKanRVckVVRjJpdkdDLVNWM3JVY2xoWHd4eENWeTZhaC0walppNU9iU2FpYW4yRFZSODZXdmtxUklNZkY2eEl1NHZvdTJ5ZnlxSzVtcDVQblFOeVF30gGmAUFVX3lxTE1OU2ZPMWtwaEZ4aldfNWhMN2hnY0RLVlZQN2JFWkthckw4OHpDbnpGMnlxYm5abkFJaHRTR1N3emZYZW5wMXNUYXRnUjhIU0gwSEpqdFVyRVVGMml2R0MtU1YzclVjbGhYd3h4Q1Z5NmFoLTBqWmk1T2JTYWlhbjJEVlI4Nld2a3FSSU1mRjZ4SXU0dm91MnlmeXFLNW1wNVBuUU55UXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:18:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Annual malaria cases at 2 mn in 2023, down 97% since 1947: Health ministry - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Annual malaria cases at 2 mn in 2023, down 97% since 1947: Health ministry</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> October 2023  <strong>Source:</strong> Ministry of Health and Family Welfare</p>
<p>India has made significant strides towards eradicating malaria, reducing annual cases to 2 million in 2023 from 7.5 crore in 1947, according to the latest report from the Health Ministry.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Cases have fallen from 11,69,261 in 2015 to 2,27,564 in 2023, and deaths reduced from 384 to just 83.</li>
  <li>24 states and UTs are categorized as having a low malaria burden (Category 1) by 2023.</li>
  <li>India exited from WHO's High Burden to High Impact group in 2024.</li>
  <li>Projects like Integrated Vector Management have successfully disrupted the transmission cycle.</li>
  <li>Community engagement and healthcare integration have strengthened malaria prevention efforts.</li>
  <li>India aims to eliminate malaria by 2030 with a significant focus on targeted interventions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"India’s commitment to capacity building and research has also been a cornerstone of its success." - Ministry of Health</blockquote>
<p>The substantial decrease in malaria cases over the decades showcases India's successful public health interventions and the determination to achieve a malaria-free status by 2030.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/annual-malaria-cases-at-2-mn-in-2023-down-97-since-1947-health-ministry-124122500665_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/annual-malaria-cases-at-2-mn-in-2023-down-97-since-1947-health-ministry-124122500665_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:02:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dinga Dinga Virus Raises Global Health Concerns in Uganda - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dinga Dinga Virus Raises Global Health Concerns in Uganda</h1>
<p><strong>Updated: Wednesday, December 25, 2024, 21:31 [IST]</strong></p>
<img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2024/12/dinga-dinga-virus-jpg-1735141964058_1735141965413-600x338.jpg" alt="Dinga Dinga Virus" width="600" height="338">
<figcaption>Dinga Dinga Virus</figcaption>
<p>A new virus, identified as 'Dinga Dinga,' has emerged in Uganda, raising alarms similar to those experienced during the coronavirus pandemic. Preliminary reports indicate it is particularly affecting women and teenage girls, with approximately 300 cases reported in the Bandibugyo district.</p>
<ul>
<li>The United Nations warns of a potential epidemic linked to the Dinga Dinga virus.</li>
<li>Symptoms include fever and uncontrollable shivering, with behavior reported to resemble dancing in affected individuals.</li>
<li>There is an ongoing investigation into the transmission modes and the development of a cure.</li>
<li>The outbreak in Uganda coincides with a viral outbreak in the Democratic Republic of Congo, further complicating health challenges in the region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The importance of international cooperation and preparedness in the face of such unpredictable health crises cannot be overstated.”</blockquote>
<p>Health authorities are urging people to seek medical attention if they exhibit symptoms and are emphasizing the infectious nature of this new virus.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/international/dinga-dinga-virus-raises-global-health-concerns-in-uganda-011-4025855.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/international/dinga-dinga-virus-raises-global-health-concerns-in-uganda-011-4025855.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:01:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three Red Flag Signs of Diabetes You May Spot During Christmas Celebration; Easy Ways to Slash the Risk - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Three Red Flag Signs of Diabetes You May Spot During Christmas Celebration; Easy Ways to Slash the Risk</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116659494,thumbsize-39496,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116659494.jpg" alt="Three Red Flag Signs of Diabetes You May Spot During Christmas Celebration" title="Three Red Flag Signs of Diabetes You May Spot During Christmas Celebration">
<figcaption>Three Red Flag Signs of Diabetes</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the risks of diabetes during the busy holiday season and highlights key symptoms to look for, along with tips for prevention.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Around 537 million people globally are living with diabetes.</li>
  <li>Christmas indulgence can cause blood sugar levels to rise.</li>
  <li>Three typical symptoms of diabetes are polydipsia (excessive thirst), polyuria (increased urination), and blurred vision.</li>
  <li>Preventive measures include maintaining a low-carb diet, exercising regularly, and staying hydrated.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Over the Christmas period there are lots of events during which people will overindulge.” - Dr. Adam Staten</blockquote>
<p>Overall, it’s crucial to monitor health especially during festive seasons when lifestyle changes can lead to health risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/health/three-red-flag-signs-of-diabetes-you-may-spot-during-christmas-celebration-easy-ways-to-slash-the-risk-article-116657649</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/health/three-red-flag-signs-of-diabetes-you-may-spot-during-christmas-celebration-easy-ways-to-slash-the-risk-article-116657649</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists develop scan that unravels secrets of lung function - Ahmedabad Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxObVI1MGV6blVlSGJBdjVRTnVpVVdTWVowZGhqd1ZYbWNVT3kzclFvRVZzR25lYm9EZzF4cl9NR29sTTFvUjJfczNpdmZmMUVlRm9HcndTOFVJU1pLdmVSNG4wNGxSNDNFUUx4NXkyNnNmWjVieEpPM2hsdHRZdGVBRTZ3ZlpES01kbjhUeE0zUEtjRHh3MDVzalcwWU1ZczBnaWhoeWpYWXM2ZHE5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxObVI1MGV6blVlSGJBdjVRTnVpVVdTWVowZGhqd1ZYbWNVT3kzclFvRVZzR25lYm9EZzF4cl9NR29sTTFvUjJfczNpdmZmMUVlRm9HcndTOFVJU1pLdmVSNG4wNGxSNDNFUUx4NXkyNnNmWjVieEpPM2hsdHRZdGVBRTZ3ZlpES01kbjhUeE0zUEtjRHh3MDVzalcwWU1ZczBnaWhoeWpYWXM2ZHE5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:08:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India poised to be malaria-free by 2030: Health ministry - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Poised to Achieve Malaria-Free Status by 2030</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/The-number-of-malaria-deaths-annually-in-India-has_1735139310412.jpg" alt="The number of malaria deaths annually in India has come down from 800,000 at the time of independence to 83 in 2023. (Representational image)" />
<figcaption>The number of malaria deaths annually in India has come down from 800,000 at the time of independence to 83 in 2023. (Representational image)</figcaption>
<p>India has made significant progress in reducing malaria cases over the past 75 years, with a goal to become malaria-free by 2030, according to the Union health ministry.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The number of malaria cases has decreased from 75 million at independence to 2 million in 2023.</li>
  <li>Annual malaria deaths have dropped from 800,000 to 83.</li>
  <li>122 districts reported no new malaria cases.</li>
  <li>India exited the WHO's High Burden to High Impact group in 2024.</li>
  <li>From 2015 to 2023, new malaria cases fell by 80%.</li>
  <li>24 states and UTs are in category 1, reporting less than 1 case per 1,000 population.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“India’s journey toward a malaria-free future is a story of remarkable transformation and progress.” - Union Health Ministry</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the health ministry emphasizes that India's proactive public health strategies have been crucial in combating malaria, paving the way for potential elimination by 2030.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-poised-to-be-malaria-free-by-2030-health-ministry-101735139318365.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-poised-to-be-malaria-free-by-2030-health-ministry-101735139318365.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:08:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Malaria cases, deaths drop significantly by 80 pc from 2015-2023: Centre By IANS - Investing.com India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQR296X2VCYllkR0JVZjZ3QU1JcUN5UGk2ZUZ1UnV0TXFDZ2h3bVJmNE44S1dqaDRnZDFEMzRtdVhMTkxvLVYtZ3pvVk9ld0M5N05YaDJ1eW1QTmxJSW1kNzRweU10M2ZQc0drRzEwUHBTWnBKZUJ0Tm12a19ZeE9YY0ozT01QOTJDQWZ4VEMxS3R2MlcweGlraTN1ZU1jX3NIbXZ3UWVCNFBzS3N3aFlLME5CQ3FTbU4zbU1LOQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQR296X2VCYllkR0JVZjZ3QU1JcUN5UGk2ZUZ1UnV0TXFDZ2h3bVJmNE44S1dqaDRnZDFEMzRtdVhMTkxvLVYtZ3pvVk9ld0M5N05YaDJ1eW1QTmxJSW1kNzRweU10M2ZQc0drRzEwUHBTWnBKZUJ0Tm12a19ZeE9YY0ozT01QOTJDQWZ4VEMxS3R2MlcweGlraTN1ZU1jX3NIbXZ3UWVCNFBzS3N3aFlLME5CQ3FTbU4zbU1LOQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:48:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Malaria cases, deaths drop significantly by 80 pc from 2015-2023: Centre - Sakshi Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Malaria cases, deaths drop significantly by 80 pc from 2015-2023: Centre</h1><p><strong>Date: 25 Dec, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Sakshi Post</strong></p><p>Malaria cases and deaths in India have significantly decreased by around 80% from 2015 to 2023, with the aim to achieve malaria-free status by 2030.</p><ul><li>Cases fell from 1,169,261 in 2015 to 227,564 in 2023.</li><li>Deaths dropped from 384 to just 83 during the same period.</li><li>Zero malaria cases reported in 122 districts in 2023.</li><li>India's malaria cases decreased by over 97% since independence in 1947.</li><li>India exited the WHO’s High Burden to High Impact group in 2024.</li><li>Intensified surveillance increased the Annual Blood Examination Rate from 9.58 in 2015 to 11.62 in 2023.</li><li>Integrated Vector Management strategies have effectively controlled mosquito populations.</li></ul><blockquote>“This success is further highlighted by India’s exit from the WHO’s High Burden to High Impact (HBHI) group in 2024, signifying a turning point in its fight against malaria.”</blockquote><p>India's significant achievements in reducing malaria reflect robust public health interventions and the goal of eradicating the disease by 2030.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://m.sakshipost.com/news/malaria-cases-deaths-drop-significantly-80-pc-2015-2023-centre-362100</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://m.sakshipost.com/news/malaria-cases-deaths-drop-significantly-80-pc-2015-2023-centre-362100</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:25:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Ingredients That Can Help Lower Sugar Spike During Christmas Festivities - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Ingredients That Can Help Lower Sugar Spike During Christmas Festivities</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p>
<img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Cinnamon-And-Ginger.webp?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=710&amp;h=467" alt="Cinnamon And Ginger">
<figcaption>Cinnamon And Ginger</figcaption>
<p>You can confidently navigate the holiday season without compromising your health by effortlessly incorporating these health-boosting ingredients into your festive meals.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cinnamon And Ginger:</strong> Regulate blood sugar levels while enhancing festive meals.</li>
<li><strong>Turmeric And Apple Cider Vinegar:</strong> Improve insulin sensitivity and reduce inflammation.</li>
<li><strong>Nuts And Legumes:</strong> Rich in healthy fats and fiber to stabilize blood sugar.</li>
<li><strong>Leafy Greens And Chia Seeds:</strong> Packed with nutrients that help slow digestion.</li>
<li><strong>Berries And Dark Chocolate:</strong> Source of antioxidants to control sugar spikes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Cinnamon and ginger are not just delicious additions to meals. They also regulate blood sugar levels.”</blockquote>
<p>These ingredients provide delicious and healthy options for your holiday meals, allowing you to enjoy the festivities without worrying about sugar spikes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/photo-gallery/ingredients-that-can-help-lower-sugar-spike-during-christmas-festivities-1166435/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/photo-gallery/ingredients-that-can-help-lower-sugar-spike-during-christmas-festivities-1166435/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:20:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parkinson’s patients have a surprising taste for mayonnaise and olive oil, study reveals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parkinson’s Patients Have a Surprising Taste for Mayonnaise and Olive Oil, Study Reveals</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This article discusses a study that uncovers surprising preferences in taste among Parkinson’s patients, highlighting their inclination towards mayonnaise and olive oil.</p><ul><li>Study reveals specific food preferences among Parkinson's patients.</li><li>Focus on the surprising popularity of mayonnaise and olive oil.</li><li>Potential implications for dietary recommendations for patients.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our findings can help improve the quality of life by tailoring dietary options to these patients.”</blockquote><p>This study sheds light on the nuanced dietary preferences of those with Parkinson’s, suggesting that understanding these tastes can optimize their nutrition and health outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/parkinsons-patients-have-a-surprising-taste-for-mayonnaise-and-olive-oil-study-reveals/articleshow/116656483.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/parkinsons-patients-have-a-surprising-taste-for-mayonnaise-and-olive-oil-study-reveals/articleshow/116656483.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mpox: Belgium Detects First Case Of Clade 1b Strain; WHO Tags It As 'Especially Concerning' - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mpox: Belgium Detects First Case Of Clade 1b Strain; WHO Tags It As 'Especially Concerning'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p><figure><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/mpox-virus-1.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=900" alt="Mpox: Belgium Detects First Case Of Clade 1b Strain; WHO Tags It As 'Especially Concerning'" width="900" height="375"><figcaption>Mpox: Belgium Detects First Case Of Clade 1b Strain; WHO Tags It As 'Especially Concerning'</figcaption></figure><p>Mpox continues to be a global concern with Belgium reporting its first case of the Clade 1b strain, marking it as the eighth non-African country to do so. The WHO has noted the rapid spread linked to sexual contact.</p><ul><li>Belgium reports first case of Clade 1b strain of mpox.</li><li>The strain is spreading faster through sexual contact, not animal to human transmission.</li><li>Other detected countries include Canada, Germany, Sweden, Thailand, the UK, and the US.</li><li>Initially emerged in the DRC, now spreading among young adults and potentially children.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is spreading among young adults via close physical contact, often sexual contact,” WHO stated.</blockquote><p>While mpox can be transmitted from animals, recent outbreaks suggest human-to-human contact is a major factor in its spread, particularly through sexual activities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/mpox-belgium-detects-first-case-of-clade-1b-strain-who-tags-it-as-especially-concerning-1166586/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/news/mpox-belgium-detects-first-case-of-clade-1b-strain-who-tags-it-as-especially-concerning-1166586/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brain chemicals work together in controlling eating, says study - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPdkh1Rm5ONGloRmVpdFVnd0hSN2NyOHRSVTc5amtNRE5QdjFiRVJyOWwyVkJtR1JrR1lkQ29YRFdCei1SRmx5c0xmSHBMeVI4ZDJ4MWRPZzVTT0k4dzJkT01LS3JDakNVUW1TQVR2TmJIZmlXT256UkY5bFlFaFlIOXBES1Ixa0FmMEtZdVh1QmdpWjQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPdkh1Rm5ONGloRmVpdFVnd0hSN2NyOHRSVTc5amtNRE5QdjFiRVJyOWwyVkJtR1JrR1lkQ29YRFdCei1SRmx5c0xmSHBMeVI4ZDJ4MWRPZzVTT0k4dzJkT01LS3JDakNVUW1TQVR2TmJIZmlXT256UkY5bFlFaFlIOXBES1Ixa0FmMEtZdVh1QmdpWjQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:31:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drinking tea and cancer can lower the risk of some cancers: Report - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/entertainment/lifestyle/news-drinking-tea-and-cancer-can-lower-the-risk-of-some-cancers-report-786742</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/entertainment/lifestyle/news-drinking-tea-and-cancer-can-lower-the-risk-of-some-cancers-report-786742</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Essential steps to combat antibiotic resistance - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Essential Steps to Combat Antibiotic Resistance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://indianexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1_83cd03.jpg" width="720" alt="" height="1280" layout="responsive"><figcaption>Image illustrating the campaign against antibiotic resistance.</figcaption><p>This article presents critical steps for individuals to take in order to combat the growing issue of antibiotic resistance. It emphasizes responsible antibiotic use and preventive measures to reduce infection rates.</p><ul><li>Only take antibiotics when prescribed by a healthcare professional and complete the full course of treatment.</li><li>Antibiotics are ineffective against viruses; avoid using them for viral infections such as the common cold or flu.</li><li>Good hygiene practices can help prevent infections, thereby reducing the need for antibiotics.</li><li>Stay up-to-date with vaccinations to prevent infections that may require antibiotic treatment.</li><li>Support food sources that minimize excessive antibiotic use in animal feed.</li><li>Fighting antibiotic resistance requires funding for international research and improved infection control measures.</li></ul><blockquote>"Fighting antibiotic resistance requires funding international programmes and research projects for improved infection control, antibiotic management, and the creation of novel therapies."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, responsible antibiotic use and preventive health measures are essential to combating antibiotic resistance, which poses a significant threat to public health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/web-stories/wellness/essential-steps-to-combat-antibiotic-resistance/9702341/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/web-stories/wellness/essential-steps-to-combat-antibiotic-resistance/9702341/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:15:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Healthy Holiday Eating Tips: 7 Ways To Enjoy Festive Meals While Making Healthier Choices - TheHealthSite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Healthy Holiday Eating Tips: 7 Ways To Enjoy Festive Meals While Making Healthier Choices</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> The Health Site</p><img src="https://st1.thehealthsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Healthy-Holiday-Eating-Tips-1.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=710&amp;h=467" alt="Health Holiday Eating Tips"><figcaption>Holiday Season Healthy Eating Tips</figcaption><p>The holiday season is all about indulging in your favourite festive foods while celebrating with friends and family. The key is to eat in moderation and stay healthy despite the variety of foods available.</p><ul><li>Focus on the social aspect of festive meals.</li><li>Plan ahead by consuming light, healthy snacks before big meals.</li><li>Prioritise whole, unprocessed foods.</li><li>Be mindful of portion sizes; use smaller plates.</li><li>Make healthier switches with ingredients.</li><li>Stay hydrated to control hunger.</li><li>Savour your food by eating slowly and mindfully.</li><li>Don't feel guilty about enjoying festive treats in moderation.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehealthsite.com/photo-gallery/healthy-holiday-eating-tips-7-ways-to-enjoy-festive-meals-while-making-healthier-choices-1166639/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehealthsite.com/photo-gallery/healthy-holiday-eating-tips-7-ways-to-enjoy-festive-meals-while-making-healthier-choices-1166639/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:43:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Homemade Ginger Cough Drops In 10 Mins - You Just Need 2 Ingredients - NDTV Food]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Homemade Ginger Cough Drops In 10 Mins - You Just Need 2 Ingredients</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Food</p><p>When the winter chill sets in and coughs and sore throats become an unwelcome companion, we often turn to store-bought remedies. But what if you could whip up a natural, chemical-free alternative right at home in just 10 minutes? Chef Neha Deepak Shah recently shared a simple recipe for homemade ginger cough drops on Instagram, and it's a game-changer.</p><img src='https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCyMtwxC6IJ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading' alt='Homemade Ginger Cough Drops'><figcaption>Homemade Ginger Cough Drops</figcaption><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Ingredients: 1 cup jaggery, 1/4 cup ginger juice.</li><li>Jaggery soothes throat irritation while ginger juice combats inflammation.</li><li>Cooking involves combining ingredients, heating, and testing for consistency.</li><li>Cough drops can be stored in an airtight container for weeks.</li></ul><blockquote>Chef Neha's special tip: Always use silicone or metal moulds to set the cough drops, as they withstand high heat.</blockquote><p>These ginger cough drops are a healthier alternative to store-bought options, being free from processed sugar and preservatives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://food.ndtv.com/food-drinks/homemade-ginger-cough-drops-in-10-mins-you-just-need-2-ingredients-7325277</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://food.ndtv.com/food-drinks/homemade-ginger-cough-drops-in-10-mins-you-just-need-2-ingredients-7325277</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:43:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blood sugar control is possible with diet, novel drugs and tech: What are takeaways from 2024? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Blood sugar control is possible with diet, novel drugs and tech: What are takeaways from 2024?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This year has witnessed transformative advancements in diabetes management, focusing on dietary habits and innovative technologies for better blood sugar control.</p><ul><li>Advancements in wearable devices allow real-time glucose monitoring.</li><li>Research on traditional diets shows potential benefits in managing diabetes risks.</li><li>New drug therapies aim to enhance insulin sensitivity.</li><li>Genetic studies may lead to personalized treatment plans for diabetes patients.</li><li>Mental health support is increasingly recognized for young Type 1 diabetes patients.</li><li>Urban lifestyle factors contribute to Type 2 diabetes prevalence, especially in India.</li><li>Innovations like closed-loop systems and smart insulin pumps are revolutionizing management of diabetes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Urbanization, sedentary habits, air pollution, stress, and unhealthy diets are key triggers for Type 2 diabetes spiralling in India.”</blockquote><p>Overall, 2024 signifies a pivotal year for diabetes management, combining dietary wisdom with modern technology to improve patient outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/blood-sugar-control-diet-novel-drugs-tech-takeaways-2024-9743834/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/health-wellness/blood-sugar-control-diet-novel-drugs-tech-takeaways-2024-9743834/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:39:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5-Minute Morning Yoga Routine To Calm The Mind - HerZindagi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5-Minute Morning Yoga Routine To Calm The Mind</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> HerZindagi</p><img src="https://images.herzindagi.info/webstories/37731/1-1735040007.webp" alt="Yoga Routine Image"><figcaption>Image Credit: canva</figcaption><p>Mornings can often feel rushed and chaotic, leaving little room to prepare your mind for the day ahead. Here is a five-minute morning yoga routine to calm your mind. Tap to read!</p><ul><li><h2>Padmasana</h2><p>Calms the mind and increases concentration.</p></li><li><h2>Halasana</h2><p>Increases blood circulation to the brain and activates brain function.</p></li><li><h2>Pranayama</h2><p>A breathing exercise that enhances mental clarity and reduces stress.</p></li><li><h2>Vrikshasana</h2><p>Improves mental stability and concentration.</p></li><li><h2>Surya Namaskar</h2><p>Improves posture, flexibility, and overall health.</p></li><li><h2>Tadasana</h2><p>Strengthens the nervous system and centers focus on awareness.</p></li></ul><blockquote>“This information has been taken from the famous YouTube channel beyoutifulliving. The channel has more than twelve thousand subscribers.”</blockquote><p>If you liked the story, then kindly share and spread the love. Follow HerZindagi for more updates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.herzindagi.com/web-stories/health/morning-yoga-routine-to-calm-the-mind-ws-37731</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.herzindagi.com/web-stories/health/morning-yoga-routine-to-calm-the-mind-ws-37731</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Long-Term Exposure to Air Pollution Linked to Blood Clots - Cancer Health Treatment News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Long-Term Exposure to Air Pollution Linked to Blood Clots</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> National Institutes of Health</p><img src='https://cdn.poz.com/153922_iStock-1141520118.jpg_ff3361e9-2aca-4d88-9e2d-0402f7704dc9.jpg' alt='Ecological catastrophy smokestacks billowing smoke'><figcaption>Ecological catastrophy smokestacks billowing smoke</figcaption><p>Air pollution has long been associated with inflammation and various diseases. A recent study reveals a significant link between long-term air pollution exposure and increased risks for blood clots.</p><ul><li>A study involving 6,651 U.S. adults over 17 years uncovered a correlation between air pollution and venous thromboembolism (VTE).</li><li>Approximately 3.7% of participants developed blood clots requiring hospital care.</li><li>Increased exposure to specific air pollutants was linked to a risk increase of 39% to over 200% for developing VTE.</li><li>VTE can have serious consequences, including complications and death.</li></ul><blockquote>“The likelihood of this outcome was linked to a risk increase based on long-term exposure to three different types of air pollutants.”</blockquote><p>This study highlights the importance of air quality and its implications for cardiovascular health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cancerhealth.com/article/longterm-exposure-air-pollution-linked-blood-clots</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cancerhealth.com/article/longterm-exposure-air-pollution-linked-blood-clots</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:58:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Long-Term Exposure to Air Pollution Linked to Blood Clots - POZ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQbEJlQUNFQWdLc1prUGN3blRiWFI0Sk1lQ0lDajRRNEdrSHl3UThyWUowb2U1N0ZRVlVoejJpRWFIdWllNnkxUGpFcXpRUkNVZlNvZW0wX0N0aVRhWVV6NnQyVktTeDdEX0luWkFQekllazBsUDZ2THRiQkU4MC1sZm1GcGE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQbEJlQUNFQWdLc1prUGN3blRiWFI0Sk1lQ0lDajRRNEdrSHl3UThyWUowb2U1N0ZRVlVoejJpRWFIdWllNnkxUGpFcXpRUkNVZlNvZW0wX0N0aVRhWVV6NnQyVktTeDdEX0luWkFQekllazBsUDZ2THRiQkU4MC1sZm1GcGE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:54:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>