<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 05:20:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 05:20:08 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Invitees list given by Shashi Tharoor': Hardeep Puri on 2009 dinner with George Soros - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Our recollections differ': Shashi Tharoor, Hardeep Puri in war of words over 2009 dinner with George Soros in US</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Shashi Tharoor and Hardeep Puri engage in a Twitter spat regarding the details of a 2009 dinner with George Soros, revealing differing accounts of the event.</p><ul><li>The disagreement arose over claims made by Tharoor regarding the attendees and context of the dinner.</li><li>Puri challenged Tharoor's recollection, emphasizing the differences in their accounts.</li><li>This altercation has drawn attention on social media, with both politicians having significant followings.</li></ul><blockquote>"Our recollections differ," Tharoor stated, highlighting the discrepancies.</blockquote><p>This public dispute reflects ongoing tensions between the two political figures and showcases how historical events can be interpreted differently based on personal perspectives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/invitees-list-given-by-shashi-tharoor-hardeep-puri-on-2009-dinner-with-george-soros/articleshow/116523193.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/invitees-list-given-by-shashi-tharoor-hardeep-puri-on-2009-dinner-with-george-soros/articleshow/116523193.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 03:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rainfall in Odisha to continue as well-marked low pressure over Bay of Bengal intensifies into depression - OTV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rainfall in Odisha to Continue as Well-Marked Low Pressure Intensifies</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Saturday, Source: Regional Meteorological Department</p><img src="https://odishatv.in/commondir/images/Whatsapp-Logo.png" alt=""/><figcaption>Latest news update delivered via WhatsApp</figcaption><p>The well-marked low-pressure area over the Bay of Bengal has intensified into a depression, resulting in expected rainfall across Odisha for the next 24 hours.</p><ul><li>Heavy rainfall is likely in coastal districts including Kendrapara, Jagatsinghpur, Ganjam, and Gajapati.</li><li>Light to moderate rainfall is forecast for several locations in Mayurbhanj, Keonjhar, Jajpur, and Dhenkanal.</li><li>After 24 hours, improvements in rainfall are expected, although cloudy skies and gusty winds will persist.</li><li>No significant change in temperature is anticipated over the next two days.</li></ul><blockquote>“Wind direction has changed to south-easterly and the winds are carrying a lot of moisture.” - Manorama Mohanty, IMD Bhubaneswar Director</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while the immediate forecast indicates continued rain, improvements are anticipated after a day or so, with less severe weather expected moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/rainfall-odisha-well-marked-low-pressure-bay-of-bengal-intensify-depression-251551</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/rainfall-odisha-well-marked-low-pressure-bay-of-bengal-intensify-depression-251551</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 03:11:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Man Stabbed To Death, Had Threatened Accused To Return Friend's Money - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Man Stabbed to Death Over Financial Dispute</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> NDTV, February 2024</p><img src='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/80ef0ba_delhi-police-generic_625x300_04_February_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400' alt='Delhi Man Stabbed To Death, Had Threatened Accused To Return Friend's Money'><figcaption>Delhi Man Stabbed To Death, Had Threatened Accused To Return Friend's Money</figcaption><p><strong>Introduction:</strong> A 26-year-old man was stabbed to death in Delhi's Narela area over an alleged financial dispute.</p><ol><li>The victim, Himanshu, was living with his friend, Sumit Kaushik.</li><li>The dispute involved a loan of ₹45,000 that the accused, Ravi, had borrowed from Sumit and failed to return.</li><li>Himanshu threatened Ravi's family over the unpaid debt.</li><li>Ravi and his accomplices later stabbed Himanshu to death.</li></ol><blockquote>Three people have been arrested in the case - Ravi (30), Sahil (24) and Ashish (26). The fourth accused, Akshay Khatri, is reportedly on the run.</blockquote><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The murder is linked to a financial dispute, and the police are investigating the case further.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/delhi-news/delhi-man-stabbed-to-death-had-threatened-accused-to-return-friends-money-7298519</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/delhi-news/delhi-man-stabbed-to-death-had-threatened-accused-to-return-friends-money-7298519</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 03:04:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fire breaks out at Salarpuria Sattva Knowledge City building in Hyderabad’s Madhapur - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fire Breaks Out at Salarpuria Sattva Knowledge City in Hyderabad</h1><p><strong>Date: December 21, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/u0ea7y/article69011780.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/554b18e6-2b74-4709-9777-5351dd984785.jpg" alt="Fire Breakout at Knowledge City" title="A fire broke out early Saturday morning in the amenities block of the Sattva Elixir building inside Knowledge City."/><figcaption>A fire broke out early Saturday morning in the amenities block of the Sattva Elixir building inside Knowledge City.</figcaption><p>On the morning of December 21, 2024, a fire broke out in the amenities block of Sattva Elixir building at Knowledge City, HITEC City, prompting a quick response from the Fire Services Department.</p><ul><li>The fire was reported at 6:12 a.m., leading to the mobilization of four firefighting vehicles.</li><li>The fire originated on the fourth floor and spread to the other floors, fortunately causing no injuries or casualties.</li><li>Sattva Group confirmed that operations at Knowledge City continued as usual and that the cause of the fire is still under investigation.</li></ul><blockquote>“We appreciate the swift and effective response of both our emergency team and the State Fire Department in managing the situation.”</blockquote><p>The fire was quickly detected and extinguished thanks to advanced safety systems and a well-trained emergency response team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Hyderabad/fire-breaks-out-at-salarpuria-sattva-knowledge-city-building-in-madhapur-hyderabad/article69011770.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Hyderabad/fire-breaks-out-at-salarpuria-sattva-knowledge-city-building-in-madhapur-hyderabad/article69011770.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 02:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Fire in software company near Hitec city in Hyderabad, efforts on to contain - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fire Breaks Out at Software Company Near Hitec City in Hyderabad</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 21 December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Telangana Today</p><figure><img src="https://media.telanganatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fire-2.jpg" alt="Watch: Fire in software company near Hitec city in Hyderabad, efforts on to contain"><figcaption>Fire broke out in a software company near Hitec City in Hyderabad</figcaption></figure><p>A fire broke out early Saturday morning at an IT company located in Madhapur, near Hitec City. The blaze rapidly spread through the building, causing thick smoke and panic among onlookers as fire tenders rushed to the scene.</p><ul><li>Fire started on the fifth floor of the Salarpuria Sattva Knowledge City building.</li><li>Thick smoke visible from a distance raised alarm among nearby residents.</li><li>Local police are assisting firefighters in managing the situation.</li><li>More details are expected to emerge soon.</li></ul><blockquote>The fire created a panic among the people.</blockquote><p>Efforts are ongoing to contain the fire, and the damage extent is yet to be assessed.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://telanganatoday.com/hyderabad-fire-in-software-company-near-hitec-city-efforts-on-to-contain</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://telanganatoday.com/hyderabad-fire-in-software-company-near-hitec-city-efforts-on-to-contain</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 02:02:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi's Kuwait visit from today, to interact with Indian diaspora, meet Emir | Details - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Narendra Modi's Kuwait visit from today, to interact with Indian diaspora, meet Emir | Details</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 21, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/Modi_1733067685535_1734743342663.jpg" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi.(PTI)" title="Prime Minister Narendra Modi.(PTI)"><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi.(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi is on a two-day visit to Kuwait, marking the first visit by an Indian premier in over four decades, aimed at enhancing India-Kuwait relations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>This visit is expected to “open a new chapter” in India-Kuwait relations.</li>
  <li>PM Modi will meet the Amir of Kuwait, Crown Prince, and Prime Minister.</li>
  <li>Key discussions will focus on trade, investment, energy, culture, and people-to-people contacts.</li>
  <li>He will also visit a labour camp and engage with the Indian diaspora at a community event.</li>
  <li>The visit aims to strengthen ties with the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It will not only consolidate the partnership in existing spheres but also unveil new avenues for future cooperation.” - Arun Kumar Chatterjee, Secretary (Overseas Indian Affairs)</blockquote>
<p>The visit underscores the importance of India-Kuwait relations, particularly in trade and energy sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modis-kuwait-visit-from-today-to-interact-with-indian-diaspora-meet-emir-details-101734742839486.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modis-kuwait-visit-from-today-to-interact-with-indian-diaspora-meet-emir-details-101734742839486.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 01:37:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chautala’s chequered journey: Five-time CM to Tihar’s oldest inmate - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chautala’s chequered journey: Five-time CM to Tihar’s oldest inmate</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p><p>Om Prakash Chautala, a five-time Chief Minister of Haryana, passed away at the age of 89. His life was marked by significant political achievements and controversies, including a long stint in Tihar Jail on corruption charges.</p><ul><li>Chautala served as Chief Minister multiple times between 1989 and 2005, influencing Jat politics in Haryana.</li><li>He was sentenced to jail for involvement in a teachers’ recruitment scam and a disproportionate assets case.</li><li>Despite his legal troubles, he passed his Class XII exam at the age of 82 while incarcerated.</li><li>His tenure saw notable events such as the 1990 Meham Assembly violence.</li><li>Chautala's legacy includes challenges with political alliances and the subsequent decline of INLD's power in Haryana.</li></ul><blockquote>“A film ‘Dasvi’ was made about Chautala's life, highlighting his educational achievements while in jail.”</blockquote><p>Chautala's complex journey reflects the turbulent political landscape of Haryana and the intertwining of personal achievements with public service.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/haryana/chautalas-chequered-journey-five-time-cm-to-tihars-oldest-inmate/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/haryana/chautalas-chequered-journey-five-time-cm-to-tihars-oldest-inmate/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:40:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court wants Dallewal shifted to hospital, asks Punjab to take call - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Calls for Hospital Transfer of Farmer Leader Dallewal</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p><p>The Supreme Court has ordered that farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal, currently on an indefinite fast, should be moved to a makeshift hospital near his protest site, leaving the decision in the hands of the Punjab Government.</p><ol><li>Dallewal has been fasting since November 26 to press for farmer demands.</li><li>The Punjab Government is responsible for Dallewal's health and must assess the need for hospital transfer.</li><li>A medical report is required by January 2, 2025, regarding Dallewal's health status.</li><li>Authorities have stated they are prepared to transfer him but will respect his consent due to health concerns.</li><li>The Supreme Court has previously reprimanded the Punjab Government for not performing adequate medical tests on Dallewal.</li><li>Current medical tests show Dallewal's condition is stable, but there are concerns about his health deteriorating.</li></ol><blockquote>“It is entirely the responsibility of the state of Punjab to ensure stable health conditions of Dallewal.”</blockquote><p>The Supreme Court's intervention underscores the importance of addressing health concerns amid ongoing protests, reflecting the delicate balance between civil rights and health safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/punjab/supreme-court-wants-dallewal-shifted-to-hospital-asks-punjab-to-take-call/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/punjab/supreme-court-wants-dallewal-shifted-to-hospital-asks-punjab-to-take-call/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:33:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crime Branch to investigate BJP’s FIR against Rahul, Congress complaint - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Crime Branch to Investigate BJP’s FIR Against Rahul Gandhi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img decoding="async" width="1600" height="900" src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Leader-of-Opposition-in-Lok-Sabha-Rahul-Gandhi-with-BJP-MP-Pratap-Chandra-Sarangi-who-was-injured-on-Thursday.-PTI.jpg" alt="Day-long faceoff: Two BJP MPs injured, police lodge FIR against Rahul"><figcaption>Leader of Opposition in Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi with BJP MP Pratap Chandra Sarangi who was injured on Thursday. (PTI)</figcaption><p>The Delhi Police has transferred the investigation of an FIR lodged against Rahul Gandhi following a scuffle in Parliament where two BJP MPs were injured, to the Crime Branch.</p><ul><li>The FIR against Gandhi is under sections concerning causing grievous hurt, use of criminal force, and intimidation.</li><li>The Congress party has also filed a complaint against BJP MPs regarding the incident.</li><li>Investigation will cover both complaints as the Crime Branch begins its inquiry.</li><li>The Congress has demanded the release of CCTV footage of the incident and reiterated calls for the resignation of Union Home Minister Amit Shah.</li></ul><blockquote>“In the history of democracy, this has happened for the first time.” - Pramod Tiwari</blockquote><p>The ongoing investigation highlights significant political tensions and divisions within parliament, as both parties trade accusations amid an increasingly contentious winter session.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/crime-branch-to-investigate-bjps-fir-against-rahul-congress-complaint-9736898/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/crime-branch-to-investigate-bjps-fir-against-rahul-congress-complaint-9736898/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 22:34:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Punjab Govt Would Be Responsible': Supreme Court's Direction On Farmer Leader Jagjit Dallewal's Health - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Directs Punjab Government to Ensure Farmer Leader Jagjit Dallewal's Health</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Jagjit Singh Dallewal had been protesting for farmers' rights for weeks now and his health has deteriorated sharply after his hunger strike. (PTI/File)" /><figcaption>Jagjit Singh Dallewal had been protesting for farmers' rights for weeks now and his health has deteriorated sharply after his hunger strike. (PTI/File)</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court has ordered the Punjab government to take immediate action to ensure the safety and health of farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal, who is on an indefinite hunger strike. His health has critically deteriorated recently.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court's directives come after Dallewal lost consciousness during his hunger strike.</li><li>The Punjab government is required to transfer him to a makeshift hospital for constant monitoring.</li><li>Dallewal has been on hunger strike for 24 days and his condition is described as critical.</li><li>Political leaders have urged the government to meet the farmers' demands to alleviate Dallewal's situation.</li></ul><blockquote>The court stated, "The Punjab government would be responsible for Dallewal’s health."</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the ongoing farmers' protests and their struggle for rights, particularly regarding the demands addressed to the Indian government.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/sc-directs-punjab-govt-to-ensure-fasting-farmer-leader-jagjit-singh-dallewals-safety-9162937.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/sc-directs-punjab-govt-to-ensure-fasting-farmer-leader-jagjit-singh-dallewals-safety-9162937.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 22:32:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi’s Kuwait trip to begin today with labour camp visit; to meet Emir - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi’s Kuwait trip to begin today with labour camp visit; to meet Emir</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 21-12-2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/modiji-2col.jpg?w=640" alt="Narendra Modi, PM modi visit to kuwait" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>PM Modi will review the entire spectrum of bilateral relations with Kuwait leadership.</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi is set to start his two-day visit to Kuwait, focusing on the Indian labour force and bilateral discussions on trade and investment.</p><ul><li>PM Modi will visit an Indian labour camp to express solidarity with Indian workers in Kuwait.</li><li>This is the first visit by an Indian Prime Minister to Kuwait in 43 years.</li><li>Meetings are scheduled with the Emir and Crown Prince of Kuwait for bilateral talks.</li><li>Arun Kumar Chatterjee emphasized the importance of the visit for Indian workers and diaspora.</li><li>Kuwait is a key trading partner for India, with significant investments and trade relations.</li></ul><blockquote>“This marks the first visit by an Indian Prime Minister to Kuwait in 43 years and therefore assumes considerable significance.” - Arun Kumar Chatterjee</blockquote><p>The visit highlights the long-standing ties between India and Kuwait, with potential for enhanced cooperation in multiple sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/pm-modis-kuwait-trip-to-begin-today-with-labour-camp-visit-to-meet-emir-9736972/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/pm-modis-kuwait-trip-to-begin-today-with-labour-camp-visit-to-meet-emir-9736972/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 21:50:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chaotic winter session ends: Lok Sabha worked for 57% of the time, Rajya Sabha for 43% - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chaotic winter session ends: Lok Sabha worked for 57% of the time, Rajya Sabha for 43%</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>The winter session of Parliament saw the Lok Sabha functioning for 57% of its scheduled time while the Rajya Sabha worked for only 43%, highlighting significant inefficiencies during the session.</p><ul><li>Lok Sabha had a productive engagement rate of 57%.</li><li>Rajya Sabha's productivity was notably lower at 43%.</li><li>Discussions were chaotic, reflecting poor legislative performance.</li></ul><blockquote>"The productivity of Parliament remains a matter of concern, with both houses struggling to meet their schedules effectively."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the winter session's outcomes reveal a pressing need for reforms to improve parliamentary efficiency and effectiveness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/chaotic-winter-session-ends-lok-sabha-worked-for-57-of-the-time-rajya-sabha-for-43/articleshow/116516764.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/chaotic-winter-session-ends-lok-sabha-worked-for-57-of-the-time-rajya-sabha-for-43/articleshow/116516764.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 21:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Temperatures dip below 0°C across Kashmir - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQZUVReUZaZXlQdDl4Y2lfOXZjeXZzNVlDZlNaaHgxWHhoaVd4bXp1LTB5YU05dzgtR2lKMFl6S1RBaFdRX0NRTU9nUzVqZXhKODloQU1sZ2tEYjdhc3g2eUtwc2tjck5kdjJ4cG55c3AwbWpaOWlUVGhOT0xvNGlnLTdQV0JBNVBBWlMyMlZn0gGSAUFVX3lxTE83ZHZCVG1lY1c3UlBITmZHQWt4WDRhRFo4UGVKOHYtUktWeVVpT0pUMENuZFpnUG1aLS12MThsaW11LWl4Yk5CUjRSdXVsVHl1bG1KQlhrSDlDeHdtejAzZ1dhR0RGUzRmY2x1QlQzdXVyUGtjQkg2UDYzcDVBUnp5WnlXVzVQV05BcXFhS3RQaTFR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQZUVReUZaZXlQdDl4Y2lfOXZjeXZzNVlDZlNaaHgxWHhoaVd4bXp1LTB5YU05dzgtR2lKMFl6S1RBaFdRX0NRTU9nUzVqZXhKODloQU1sZ2tEYjdhc3g2eUtwc2tjck5kdjJ4cG55c3AwbWpaOWlUVGhOT0xvNGlnLTdQV0JBNVBBWlMyMlZn0gGSAUFVX3lxTE83ZHZCVG1lY1c3UlBITmZHQWt4WDRhRFo4UGVKOHYtUktWeVVpT0pUMENuZFpnUG1aLS12MThsaW11LWl4Yk5CUjRSdXVsVHl1bG1KQlhrSDlDeHdtejAzZ1dhR0RGUzRmY2x1QlQzdXVyUGtjQkg2UDYzcDVBUnp5WnlXVzVQV05BcXFhS3RQaTFR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 19:42:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[39-member JPC to examine One Nation One Election bills formed - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>39-Member JPC to Examine One Nation One Election Bills Formed</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Friday, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/The-panel--earlier-planned-for-31-members--will-no_1734721049343.jpg" alt="The panel, earlier planned for 31 members, will now have 39 members after some smaller parties met Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla and demanded their inclusion in the important committee. (ANI PHOTO)" title="The panel, earlier planned for 31 members, will now have 39 members after some smaller parties met Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla and demanded their inclusion in the important committee. (ANI PHOTO)">
<figcaption>The panel, earlier planned for 31 members, will now have 39 members after some smaller parties met Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla and demanded their inclusion in the important committee. (ANI PHOTO)</figcaption>
<p>New Delhi: The Lok Sabha approved a 39-member joint parliamentary committee (JPC) to examine two significant bills aimed at implementing simultaneous state and national elections.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The committee's formation follows requests from smaller parties for representation.</li>
  <li>Parliamentary minister Kiren Rijiju stated that including prominent political parties was crucial.</li>
  <li>The JPC will consist of 27 Lok Sabha MPs and 12 Rajya Sabha members.</li>
  <li>The panel is expected to report by the last week of the 2025 budget session.</li>
  <li>Opposition parties have expressed concerns about the proposals impacting democratic accountability.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The government agreed that the matter is very important and it relates to the reformation of the election process of our country...” - Kiren Rijiju</blockquote>
<p>The establishment of the JPC reflects the government's commitment to reforming the electoral process, despite facing opposition. However, the passage of the bills may encounter challenges in the House.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/39member-jpc-to-examine-onop-bills-formed-101734721058736.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/39member-jpc-to-examine-onop-bills-formed-101734721058736.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:57:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OP Chautala: Jat strongman and five-time Haryana chief minister - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Om Prakash Chautala: A Political Legacy in Haryana</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 21, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Om-Prakash-Chautala--HT-File-_1734720509165_1734738938267.jpeg" alt="Om Prakash Chautala (HT File)" title="Om Prakash Chautala (HT File)">
<figcaption>Om Prakash Chautala (HT File)</figcaption>
<p>Om Prakash Chautala, the five-time Chief Minister of Haryana, passed away at the age of 89, leaving behind a significant political legacy marked by both achievements and controversies.</p>
<ul>
<li>Chautala served five terms as Chief Minister over a span of five decades.</li>
<li>His longest tenure lasted five years, from March 2, 2000, to February 5, 2005.</li>
<li>He was known for imposing unpopular taxes that contributed to Haryana’s financial health.</li>
<li>His career was marred by controversies, including criminal convictions and family disputes leading to a split in his political party.</li>
<li>Chautala's political influence diminished with the rise of the Jannayak Janta Party formed by his son and grandsons.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When it came to running the government, his abilities were second to none. No one could take him for a ride.” - Sampat Singh, former cabinet colleague.</blockquote>
<p>Chautala's legacy remains a complex tapestry of strong leadership intertwined with legal and political challenges, profoundly impacting Haryana's political landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/op-chautala-jat-strongman-and-five-time-haryana-chief-minister-101734720516539.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/op-chautala-jat-strongman-and-five-time-haryana-chief-minister-101734720516539.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:48:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Adjourned Sine Die, 'One Nation, One Election' Bills Referred to Joint Committee - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament Adjourned Sine Die, 'One Nation, One Election' Bills Referred to Joint Committee</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="View of the Lok Sabha during the Winter session of Parliament (Photo;PTI)">
<figcaption>View of the Lok Sabha during the Winter session of Parliament (Photo;PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Both Houses of the Parliament were adjourned sine die following Opposition protests over Union Home Minister Amit Shah’s remarks concerning BR Ambedkar. The 'One Nation, One Election' bills were also referred to a Joint Parliamentary Committee.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Lok Sabha adjourned indefinitely amid protests from the Opposition.</li>
  <li>The 'One Nation, One Election' bills were referred to a Joint Parliamentary Committee.</li>
  <li>The Speaker of Lok Sabha warned members against demonstrations in Parliament.</li>
  <li>The productivity of the Rajya Sabha session was noted to be only 40.03%.</li>
  <li>Discussions include the implications of simultaneous elections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“As Parliamentarians, we are drawing severe criticism from the people of India and rightfully so. These persistent disruptions are steadily eroding public trust in our democratic institutions.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the adjournment of Parliament reflects the ongoing tensions between the Government and the Opposition, particularly regarding significant policy proposals like 'One Nation, One Election' which are still under discussion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/parliament-winter-session-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-adjourned-nda-opposition-protest-ambedkar-row-bjp-mps-injured-9162588.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/parliament-winter-session-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-adjourned-nda-opposition-protest-ambedkar-row-bjp-mps-injured-9162588.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:44:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Om Prakash Chautala dies: Haryana government declares school holiday today - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Om Prakash Chautala dies: Haryana government declares school holiday today</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/op-chautala-1734714110.webp" alt="OP Chautala dies, Haryana government declares school holiday on December 21, om prakash chautala, ch" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>INLD chief and former Haryana Chief Minister Chaudhary Om Prakash Chautala.</figcaption><p>The government of Haryana has declared December 21 a school holiday in remembrance of former Chief Minister Om Prakash Chautala, who passed away on December 20.</p><ul><li>The Haryana government declared a three-day state mourning from December 20 to 22.</li><li>All state government functions will be cancelled during this mourning period.</li><li>A state funeral will be held for Chautala on December 21 at 3:00 PM in Teja Khera, Sirsa.</li><li>Chief Minister Nayab Singh Saini praised Chautala's contributions and leadership.</li></ul><blockquote>“With his demise, a chapter of Haryana politics has come to an end. His contribution to Haryana politics will always be remembered.” – CM Nayab Singh Saini</blockquote><p>Chautala's death is marked by tributes from political figures who recognized his influence in Haryana politics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/haryana/haryana-school-holiday-on-december-21-following-om-prakash-chautala-death-inld-chief-3-day-state-mourning-by-government-latest-updates-2024-12-20-967258</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/haryana/haryana-school-holiday-on-december-21-following-om-prakash-chautala-death-inld-chief-3-day-state-mourning-by-government-latest-updates-2024-12-20-967258</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:12:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Private Bus Destroyed In Jaipur Fire Did Not Have Permit: RTO - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxQWW5rZUpiZ1RJN1hUcGpUT1NsYkpSd2JtRWFqQVQ0bWJ6RVo5YXlTR09UWTZ1aXB0Nnp4OGRfOEhmUXp5dDU4SzJZR0UzZC13bXIzaTNmWHlqaUtpSjdudWNaX0twS2hqaVIycVNmU1hzV0ljQ0UtV0Jsb2VRNzVTSkU0WDR2RDBsb1dJNWM0UzN3Sng4RmhjWFJDX18zd1JnSHfSAaoBQVVfeXFMTTN3UEFpNEZ0UXcxMnd1R2RMcTJrZ2E4UEtBZVhRM3gyOEZkNjZtS0hjMmo1YkM2bDMtd3I1RDg3YkZTSFpRU29hYk9ERG1yWmZxTzJDampkUlp1SUNqck1hWjBHcktHUlZJRmhlYW9BRTQzc1VBVFpwN0VKcVhBWllxazBhNDJEeFlBRW8wYkFPUERhLWRMRG5qWGxGbEhBZnRCMDNwX3FGM2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxQWW5rZUpiZ1RJN1hUcGpUT1NsYkpSd2JtRWFqQVQ0bWJ6RVo5YXlTR09UWTZ1aXB0Nnp4OGRfOEhmUXp5dDU4SzJZR0UzZC13bXIzaTNmWHlqaUtpSjdudWNaX0twS2hqaVIycVNmU1hzV0ljQ0UtV0Jsb2VRNzVTSkU0WDR2RDBsb1dJNWM0UzN3Sng4RmhjWFJDX18zd1JnSHfSAaoBQVVfeXFMTTN3UEFpNEZ0UXcxMnd1R2RMcTJrZ2E4UEtBZVhRM3gyOEZkNjZtS0hjMmo1YkM2bDMtd3I1RDg3YkZTSFpRU29hYk9ERG1yWmZxTzJDampkUlp1SUNqck1hWjBHcktHUlZJRmhlYW9BRTQzc1VBVFpwN0VKcVhBWllxazBhNDJEeFlBRW8wYkFPUERhLWRMRG5qWGxGbEhBZnRCMDNwX3FGM2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:49:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Lodges Protest With Bangladesh Over 'Map' Post By Muhammad Yunus Aide - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxQX2V2bXA1VElCcXZIWkg0WnVrcmh1dlBUbEVGQ1JXU0xIR2p6WmtCeTVMODV2Q0ZyR0UwS0NYeGJmQ0t6Qlk1ZlFYN2FnNmRkZnBfTEd0bFVfOEhsVUtBX0s1ekh0NkVUdk5pbzFWYXF1VWVBMEd5UkExUjZNU1JGSUZ0WVBmQWd3ZVJYcnJaWkhtMHllYmJZVkRRdVpNV3lRanpsamlKTnI1ZjN2dHBRRTlPa9IBuwFBVV95cUxOLVZqMm5ZalNDR3VmcS13N2Y3Wk5CRks3M2ZDeGNwMXNWR05haC1ibGFlWFU3VGdqRUpDaTRQOXNjaVhLVEFqQXlaV0F0X0tDRjI0RXBRVG5DVldXM0pUTXl0Wjg4SGhKWTNhVDMyOXd6NHdiQ1hqYTM2SXJwTXI5QzBWOTNTNzIwQktXQ1RSTUNTQ3h3WjhRRXctMmNGUXhPYzc2SVBaMTNkaDhfUmgycEpaRXFKdU9jR2hZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxQX2V2bXA1VElCcXZIWkg0WnVrcmh1dlBUbEVGQ1JXU0xIR2p6WmtCeTVMODV2Q0ZyR0UwS0NYeGJmQ0t6Qlk1ZlFYN2FnNmRkZnBfTEd0bFVfOEhsVUtBX0s1ekh0NkVUdk5pbzFWYXF1VWVBMEd5UkExUjZNU1JGSUZ0WVBmQWd3ZVJYcnJaWkhtMHllYmJZVkRRdVpNV3lRanpsamlKTnI1ZjN2dHBRRTlPa9IBuwFBVV95cUxOLVZqMm5ZalNDR3VmcS13N2Y3Wk5CRks3M2ZDeGNwMXNWR05haC1ibGFlWFU3VGdqRUpDaTRQOXNjaVhLVEFqQXlaV0F0X0tDRjI0RXBRVG5DVldXM0pUTXl0Wjg4SGhKWTNhVDMyOXd6NHdiQ1hqYTM2SXJwTXI5QzBWOTNTNzIwQktXQ1RSTUNTQ3h3WjhRRXctMmNGUXhPYzc2SVBaMTNkaDhfUmgycEpaRXFKdU9jR2hZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:40:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ED files case against KTR for Formula-E irregularities, hours after Telangana HC relief - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Enforcement Directorate Files Money Laundering Case Against KTR Over Formula-E Irregularities</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 22, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/ktr_b151f9.jpg?w=640" alt="ktr ed case" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>BRS working president KTR. (Photo: KTR/ X)</figcaption><p>The Enforcement Directorate has filed a money laundering case against BRS leader K T Rama Rao in relation to alleged payment irregularities during the Formula-E race held in Hyderabad in February 2023.</p><ul><li>The ED registered the case following an FIR filed by Telangana Police’s anti-corruption bureau (ACB).</li><li>The case is linked to mismanagement of funds and payments authorized by KTR without cabinet clearance.</li><li>Former ACB, while investigating, discovered the alleged financial irregularities after an RBI fine of Rs 8 crore was imposed.</li><li>The Telangana High Court has granted temporary relief to KTR, preventing immediate arrest until December 30, 2023.</li></ul><blockquote>“The HMDA paid Rs 45 crore in two instalments to the foreign company, Formula-E Organisers, in violation of Reserve Bank of India guidelines.”</blockquote><p>This case highlights ongoing scrutiny over alleged corruption and financial mismanagement in the conduct of high-profile events in the state.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/ed-ktr-formula-irregularities-telangana-high-court-9736732/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/ed-ktr-formula-irregularities-telangana-high-court-9736732/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:25:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parents On Mumbai Ferry Wanted To Toss Children Into Sea. Rescuers Stopped Them - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parents On Mumbai Ferry Wanted To Toss Children Into Sea. Rescuers Stopped Them</h1><p><strong>Date: December 19, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: NDTV</strong></p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9i4sjb1o_mumbai-ferry-tragedy-pti-_625x300_19_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="Parents On Mumbai Ferry Wanted To Toss Children Into Sea. Rescuers Stopped Them"><figcaption>Rescuers coordinating efforts during the ferry accident.</figcaption><p>In a desperate situation aboard a sinking ferry near Mumbai, parents contemplated tossing their children into the sea. Rescuers from the CISF intervened, assuring the passengers that everyone would be saved.</p><ul><li>A Navy boat collided with the tourist ferry 'Neel Kamal', leading to the sinking.</li><li>CISF constable Amol Savant and his team reached the scene as first responders.</li><li>Approximately 14 fatalities were reported, but around 50-60 lives were salvaged.</li><li>Rescue operations involved trained marine commandos employing CPR and retrieval techniques.</li><li>International guests assisted in rescue efforts as well.</li></ul><blockquote>“I asked them not to panic and not attempt this. We took charge of the situation soon,” - Amol Savant, CISF constable.</blockquote><p>This incident showcases the swift actions of trained personnel that prevented further tragedy while highlighting the importance of courage and composure in emergencies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/parents-on-mumbai-ferry-planned-to-throw-their-kids-in-water-cisf-rescuers-7296161</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/parents-on-mumbai-ferry-planned-to-throw-their-kids-in-water-cisf-rescuers-7296161</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:15:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parents On Mumbai Ferry Planned To Throw Their Children In Water: Rescuers - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxPRWh0VmRZXzViR0ppcXhOVDhxbWN3QURJamloT0JqUVlLS0d2eGs3U3lIb1Nnb3drQlJpR2dOWTdZNG5hOGVYTEg3WUNQNzQ5VkFJNC0yckVSR2hpUlR1d3k5WU1aRWNMY0FUVjM5cmc3OUdPSkxxNENyZDFSRjBSRllDcTZhclo0Z21kY0F5WGdwQWUwUGJld0V6SjRUbmN2ZllGV183QjRSRU9CVkRuQXpud1g?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxPRWh0VmRZXzViR0ppcXhOVDhxbWN3QURJamloT0JqUVlLS0d2eGs3U3lIb1Nnb3drQlJpR2dOWTdZNG5hOGVYTEg3WUNQNzQ5VkFJNC0yckVSR2hpUlR1d3k5WU1aRWNMY0FUVjM5cmc3OUdPSkxxNENyZDFSRjBSRllDcTZhclo0Z21kY0F5WGdwQWUwUGJld0V6SjRUbmN2ZllGV183QjRSRU9CVkRuQXpud1g?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:15:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parents On Mumbai Ferry Planned To Throw Their Kids In Water: CISF Rescuers - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parents On Mumbai Ferry Planned To Throw Their Kids In Water: CISF Rescuers</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Parents On Mumbai Ferry Planned To Throw Their Kids In Water: CISF Rescuers" alt="Parents On Mumbai Ferry Planned To Throw Their Kids In Water: CISF Rescuers" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9i4sjb1o_mumbai-ferry-tragedy-pti-_625x300_19_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>Rescue operations following the tragic ferry accident.</figcaption><p>A tragic accident involving a tourist ferry off the coast of Mumbai led to a heroic rescue effort by CISF personnel, who intervened when parents considered throwing their children into the water in a desperate bid for survival.</p><ul><li>CISF constable Amol Savant and his team were the first responders to the sinking ferry.</li><li>The ferry, 'Neel Kamal', was struck by a Navy vessel, resulting in 14 fatalities.</li><li>First responders arrived quickly and managed to save around 50-60 people from the ferry.</li><li>Several rescued individuals required CPR due to near-drowning experiences.</li><li>Rescue operations were beyond the primary responsibility of the CISF, showcasing their commitment and professionalism.</li></ul><blockquote>“People were ready to throw their children in the ocean water thinking that they would be saved from the sinking ship.” - Amol Savant</blockquote><p>The courage and quick actions of the CISF personnel have been praised, and they are recommended for the 'Jeevan Raksha Padak' for their life-saving efforts during this tragic event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/parents-on-mumbai-ferry-planned-to-throw-their-kids-in-water-cisf-rescuers-7296161</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/parents-on-mumbai-ferry-planned-to-throw-their-kids-in-water-cisf-rescuers-7296161</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:15:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India distances itself from ‘six-point consensus’ in China readout on Doval-Wang talks - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/diplomacy/india-distances-itself-from-six-point-consensus-in-china-readout-on-doval-wang-talks/2413706/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/diplomacy/india-distances-itself-from-six-point-consensus-in-china-readout-on-doval-wang-talks/2413706/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:57:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allahabad High Court Stays Arrest Of Fact-Checker Mohammed Zubair - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPc1psWmtQTkthUTVZcHVwakl3SUh0RzgyamJhcExxeHJtUFZkdTNqajg1UEdHUVh1SFhsV3dBTXNZMW1hUUdJQ3MzbGVvYmd0dm91ODg4bGpjSndReEZtYmdoam0takp3MndfRmF1Q0pYdEs3RHdMem0wdk9faHV1d1paTF9rMU5tMUktWWN3d2N5ZVRtSlR3NElhX1k3b3dHZk8wQ3l3QlTSAbABQVVfeXFMT0pURlRQOGFzcHQtRDJtSjRwcllVemo1bGlVNGFIWWhnMGhsdFphci1obHlPbXphSEoyZ0p5cTFGSWlCTFQyTDJJby12dUxZM1ZDVVRaWTdwaTVkVFFUOUhXeUE4MS1kOEhfa2Nwbnh1LUdDRmxVbm1pcTA1dFpteXdpREJGeTVfcl9mZHFpdGl4ckVRUlpiaWhMUVFrSUl2amtsOXBacTZOcVVUZXJHbnE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPc1psWmtQTkthUTVZcHVwakl3SUh0RzgyamJhcExxeHJtUFZkdTNqajg1UEdHUVh1SFhsV3dBTXNZMW1hUUdJQ3MzbGVvYmd0dm91ODg4bGpjSndReEZtYmdoam0takp3MndfRmF1Q0pYdEs3RHdMem0wdk9faHV1d1paTF9rMU5tMUktWWN3d2N5ZVRtSlR3NElhX1k3b3dHZk8wQ3l3QlTSAbABQVVfeXFMT0pURlRQOGFzcHQtRDJtSjRwcllVemo1bGlVNGFIWWhnMGhsdFphci1obHlPbXphSEoyZ0p5cTFGSWlCTFQyTDJJby12dUxZM1ZDVVRaWTdwaTVkVFFUOUhXeUE4MS1kOEhfa2Nwbnh1LUdDRmxVbm1pcTA1dFpteXdpREJGeTVfcl9mZHFpdGl4ckVRUlpiaWhMUVFrSUl2amtsOXBacTZOcVVUZXJHbnE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:38:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YARD 12707 (SURAT) AND YARD 12651 (NILGIRI) DELIVERED TO INDIAN NAVY - PIB]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiY0FVX3lxTE1rc1RwMTJha2I2cm9tVlNSS0s4UjhoVThtTG16cE92bDNKOUFlclVPVGtxdlMxdHVmMkNiNVJCNi0zVG5TeGRUZWZMNWVON3FXdjZZZlI4YXhOaS11RG5FaEQ2MA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiY0FVX3lxTE1rc1RwMTJha2I2cm9tVlNSS0s4UjhoVThtTG16cE92bDNKOUFlclVPVGtxdlMxdHVmMkNiNVJCNi0zVG5TeGRUZWZMNWVON3FXdjZZZlI4YXhOaS11RG5FaEQ2MA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament scuffle: FIR against Rahul Gandhi transferred to Delhi Police Crime Branch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FIR Against Rahul Gandhi Over Parliament Scuffle Transferred to Crime Branch</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/New-Delhi--LoP-in-the-Lok-Sabha-Rahul-Gandhi-and-C_1734708475327_1734708511209.jpg" alt="LoP in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi and Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra take part in a protest.(PTI file photo)">
<figcaption>LoP in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi and Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra take part in a protest.(PTI file photo)</figcaption>
<p>The Delhi Police have transferred the FIR against Congress leader Rahul Gandhi to the Crime Branch following an alleged physical assault on BJP MPs during a recent scuffle in Parliament.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rahul Gandhi is accused of physically assaulting BJP MPs amid a scuffle during protests in Parliament.</li>
  <li>Two BJP MPs were hospitalized following injuries from the altercation.</li>
  <li>The FIR includes multiple serious sections, including causing grievous hurt and use of criminal force.</li>
  <li>Rahul Gandhi claims he was threatened and blocked from entering Parliament by BJP MPs.</li>
  <li>Congress filed a complaint alleging misconduct by BJP lawmakers towards their party leader Mallikarjun Kharge.</li>
  <li>Doctors reported that the injured MPs were in better condition after treatment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The entire country is seeing... They have registered multiple cases against Rahul. This shows their level of desperation.” - Priyanka Gandhi Vadra</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights ongoing tensions in Parliament, raising questions about the political climate and the actions of both major parties.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-scuffle-fir-against-rahul-gandhi-transferred-to-delhi-police-crime-branch-101734708256002.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-scuffle-fir-against-rahul-gandhi-transferred-to-delhi-police-crime-branch-101734708256002.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:29:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP MP PP Chaudhary to head 39-member Joint Parliamentary Committee on 'One Nation, One Election' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP MP PP Chaudhary to head 39-member Joint Parliamentary Committee on 'One Nation, One Election'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='BJP MP PP Chaudhary' /><figcaption>BJP MP PP Chaudhary appointed to lead the committee.</figcaption><p>The Indian government has appointed BJP MP PP Chaudhary as the chairman of a 39-member Joint Parliamentary Committee focused on the 'One Nation, One Election' proposal, aiming to synchronize state and national elections.<p><ul><li>The committee comprises representatives from various political parties.</li><li>Its primary objective is to explore the feasibility of conducting simultaneous elections across the country.</li><li>This initiative is seen as a significant reform in India's electoral system, potentially enhancing efficiency and governance.</li></ul><blockquote>"The implementation of this idea could transform the electoral landscape of India," said a government spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This appointment reflects the government's commitment to pursuing electoral reforms that resonate with citizens and could lead to substantial changes in the democratic process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/bjp-mp-pp-chaudhary-to-head-39-member-joint-parliamentary-committee-on-one-nation-one-election/articleshow/116509766.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/bjp-mp-pp-chaudhary-to-head-39-member-joint-parliamentary-committee-on-one-nation-one-election/articleshow/116509766.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Defence ministry orders 100 more K9 Vajra howitzers to boost Army’s artillery firepower - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Defence Ministry Orders 100 More K9 Vajra Howitzers to Boost Army's Artillery Firepower</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Friday</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> ThePrint</p><p>The Ministry of Defence (MoD) has signed a contract to procure 100 additional K9 VAJRA-T self-propelled artillery guns for the Indian Army at a cost of Rs 7,628.70 crore.</p><ul><li>The K9 Vajras are indigenous artillery guns manufactured by Larsen & Toubro (L&T).</li><li>This new order follows a previous order placed in 2017 and is part of the 'Make in India' initiative.</li><li>The guns are noted for their high mobility and effectiveness in diverse terrains, including high-altitude areas.</li><li>Deployment of these guns has been catalyzed by rising tensions at the Line of Actual Control with China.</li></ul><blockquote>“The procurement of K9 VAJRA-T will catalyse the artillery modernisation and enhance overall operational readiness of the Indian Army.” - Ministry of Defence</blockquote><p>This order for K9 Vajras is crucial for modernizing the Indian Army's artillery capabilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/defence/defence-ministry-orders-100-more-k9-vajra-howitzers-to-boost-armys-artillery-firepower/2413615/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/defence/defence-ministry-orders-100-more-k9-vajra-howitzers-to-boost-armys-artillery-firepower/2413615/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:56:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka HC Grants Interim Bail To BJP's CT Ravi Arrested For Allegedly Using Derogatory Words Against... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka HC Grants Interim Bail To BJP's CT Ravi Over Derogatory Remarks</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 20, 2023, Live Law</p><img src="https://www.livelaw.in/h-upload/2020/11/06/750x450_384285-ct-ravi.jpg" alt="Karnataka HC Grants Interim Bail To BJP's CT Ravi" title="Karnataka HC Grants Interim Bail To BJP's CT Ravi" /><figcaption>Image Source: Business Line</figcaption><p>The Karnataka High Court has granted interim bail to BJP legislator C T Ravi, who was arrested for allegedly using derogatory words against Congress legislator Laxmi Hebbalkar during a session in the State Council.</p><ul><li>The bail was granted by Justice M G Uma.</li><li>The court found that a prima facie case was made out for Ravi's release.</li><li>Ravi's arrest was contested due to alleged violations of his Fundamental Rights under Article 21 of the Constitution.</li><li>Both lawmakers involved are of opposing political parties, highlighting the unfortunate nature of the incident.</li><li>The police were criticized for not following proper arrest procedures.</li></ul><blockquote>“The police would not have apprehended him without following the procedure as contemplated under BNSS.”</blockquote><p>The court concluded that the conditions for interim bail were satisfied and directed Ravi's immediate release from custody.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/karnataka-high-court/karnataka-high-court-bail-bjp-leader-ct-ravi-derogatory-remarks-against-congress-leader-laxmi-hebbalkar-279067</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/karnataka-high-court/karnataka-high-court-bail-bjp-leader-ct-ravi-derogatory-remarks-against-congress-leader-laxmi-hebbalkar-279067</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:29:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>