<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:36:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:36:13 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Commissions Three Made-In-India Frontline Naval Combatants In Major Defence Boost - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-dedicate-three-naval-ships-to-nation-in-mumbai-ins-surat-nilgiri-vaghsheer-indian-navy-9189211.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-dedicate-three-naval-ships-to-nation-in-mumbai-ins-surat-nilgiri-vaghsheer-indian-navy-9189211.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:13:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[High-powered Enquiry Committee submits report on activities of organised terror groups which undermined security interests of India, U.S. - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>High-powered Enquiry Committee submits report on activities of organised terror groups which undermined security interests of India, U.S.</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/efvm4u/article65961736.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/IMG_21TH_FLAGS_6_1_L0839N29.jpg" alt="Committee report image" />
<figcaption>Committee report image illustrating the findings. Photo Credit: The Hindu</figcaption>
<p>A high-powered enquiry committee has submitted its findings regarding organised criminal groups and terrorist organisations that pose a threat to the security interests of both India and the U.S.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The investigation was prompted by allegations of a plot to assassinate Khalistani separatist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun by Indian agents.</li>
  <li>The committee has recommended legal action against an individual discovered during the enquiry.</li>
  <li>Cooperation from U.S. authorities was pivotal in the investigation.</li>
  <li>The MHA established the committee in November 2023 following intelligence from U.S. sources.</li>
  <li>The report suggests systemic improvements to enhance India's operational responses to threats.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Committee has further recommended functional improvements in systems and procedures as also initiation of steps that could strengthen India's response capability..."</blockquote>
<p>The report addresses critical security concerns and proposes measures to bolster operational strategies in counter-terrorism efforts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/high-powered-enquiry-committee-submits-report-on-activities-of-organised-terror-groups-which-undermined-security-interests-of-india-us/article69100465.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/high-powered-enquiry-committee-submits-report-on-activities-of-organised-terror-groups-which-undermined-security-interests-of-india-us/article69100465.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why India is reaching out to the Taliban now - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why India is Reaching Out to the Taliban Now</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> BBC News</p><figure><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/f988/live/49a55b20-d268-11ef-9dbb-9559c8b74d9b.jpg.webp" alt="MEA India Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri during a meeting with Acting Foreign Minister of Afghanistan Mawlawi Amir Khan Muttaqi, in Dubai"><figcaption>India's foreign secretary Vikram Misri met acting Afghan foreign minister Amir Khan Muttaqi in Dubai.</figcaption></figure><p>India's latest diplomatic outreach to Afghanistan's Taliban government signals a marked shift in how it sees the geopolitical reality in the region, following the Taliban's takeover of Kabul.</p><ul><li>The meeting last week was the highest level of engagement since Kabul's fall.</li><li>The Taliban expressed interest in strengthening ties with India, acknowledging it as a significant regional power.</li><li>Discussions focused on expanding trade and leveraging Iran's Chabahar port.</li><li>India has historically maintained extensive investments in Afghanistan exceeding $3 billion.</li><li>Experts highlight the complexity of engaging with a regime of a violent and brutal actor like the Taliban.</li></ul><blockquote>“The fact that this treatment is coming from India - a nation that never previously had friendly relations with the Taliban, makes this all the more significant.” - Michael Kugelman</blockquote><p>India's outreach reflects its strategic interests in countering Pakistan and enhancing connectivity with Central Asia through Afghanistan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp8ke9e27dxo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp8ke9e27dxo</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 10:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP takes ‘mental stability’ jibe at Rahul Gandhi over his ‘fighting Indian state’ remark - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxPTW5DRXFJemROaGR1cjVPR1owdlJwU3BkNW9odl9hWU5VUzNkeTZPNDFWb3JKR3FPcUR6VmdrZzA1N1VZLWt0OE1LVWJ1WUMzZjI2c1p1a1FFZ3pySmJHN0xrM1J3cHJ3QlJTM3FnUzJFSWsySUNVMm81bVVaeTB1dWtGVmdiMGtyZWNVV3gwTElmQ0p0ZkZZRUU5SVJnclNlQVF2R2RSdjV1cjh1aVNDczA0Tko3TGdfWXRPczd1Q1hMYXU5YTZ6R1RXbkZGUU83RExsYU10MjM3cE1fdTJJUTJ30gHnAUFVX3lxTFBpSFpCTlRrQnY3cU1SUktwSm42UVIzbHFaZEJRNXg2SUNrN2dhbFNFbWU0RGJuUGhXaWlKdDRBSU9hSzZteHpDbmVOTVVuNVc1aURnYmdaMVZHNWpBa05nb1J1UFhWMEEzcnZMWnQ5SDlDSkNiVUNpY0xoZDZfTE44QkF0MmtZRnpNdm5lbmtGd2YyRnhYRjhGMHQyc3F3QTRPQXZiZkNMVVN5UVVvS0o2NVl5YS05cV94SkttUTFPc2p1RXFfcHg4TV94R0R5Rjl6RDJ1Y09Fck95bld6WC1xR2haUFl1TQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxPTW5DRXFJemROaGR1cjVPR1owdlJwU3BkNW9odl9hWU5VUzNkeTZPNDFWb3JKR3FPcUR6VmdrZzA1N1VZLWt0OE1LVWJ1WUMzZjI2c1p1a1FFZ3pySmJHN0xrM1J3cHJ3QlJTM3FnUzJFSWsySUNVMm81bVVaeTB1dWtGVmdiMGtyZWNVV3gwTElmQ0p0ZkZZRUU5SVJnclNlQVF2R2RSdjV1cjh1aVNDczA0Tko3TGdfWXRPczd1Q1hMYXU5YTZ6R1RXbkZGUU83RExsYU10MjM3cE1fdTJJUTJ30gHnAUFVX3lxTFBpSFpCTlRrQnY3cU1SUktwSm42UVIzbHFaZEJRNXg2SUNrN2dhbFNFbWU0RGJuUGhXaWlKdDRBSU9hSzZteHpDbmVOTVVuNVc1aURnYmdaMVZHNWpBa05nb1J1UFhWMEEzcnZMWnQ5SDlDSkNiVUNpY0xoZDZfTE44QkF0MmtZRnpNdm5lbmtGd2YyRnhYRjhGMHQyc3F3QTRPQXZiZkNMVVN5UVVvS0o2NVl5YS05cV94SkttUTFPc2p1RXFfcHg4TV94R0R5Rjl6RDJ1Y09Fck95bld6WC1xR2haUFl1TQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:58:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Name It After Manmohan Singh': BJP Slams Congress Over Posters Outside New Headquarters - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Challenges Congress to Honor Manmohan Singh with New Headquarters Name</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Posters outside the Congress headquarters (Video screengrab/Social Media)"><figcaption>Posters outside the Congress headquarters (Video screengrab/Social Media)</figcaption></figure><p>In a controversial move, BJP leaders have criticized Congress for naming its new headquarters after Indira Gandhi instead of the former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, which has sparked a public call for honoring Singh's legacy.</p><ul><li>Posters outside the new Congress headquarters demand it be named 'Sardar Manmohan Singh Bhavan'.</li><li>BJP's Amit Malviya shared a video of the posters and criticized Congress for ignoring Singh's legacy.</li><li>Malviya pointed out that Rahul Gandhi's actions during Singh's mourning were disrespectful.</li><li>Manmohan Singh passed away at 92, and his legacy continues to be a point of political contention.</li></ul><blockquote>“Posters outside the new Congress headquarters call for it to be named Sardar Manmohan Singh Bhavan, as a tribute to the former Prime Minister.” - Amit Malviya</blockquote><p>The BJP's remarks highlight the ongoing political rivalry and the importance of honoring political legacies in contemporary India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/congress-headquarters-inauguration-bjp-calls-for-naming-after-manmohan-singh-sardar-manmohan-singh-bhavan-indira-bhawan-9189146.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/congress-headquarters-inauguration-bjp-calls-for-naming-after-manmohan-singh-sardar-manmohan-singh-bhavan-indira-bhawan-9189146.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:53:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP's Ramesh Bidhuri compares Delhi CM Atishi with deer: ‘Hirni Jaisi Ghoom Rahi’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP's Ramesh Bidhuri Compares Delhi CM Atishi with Deer: ‘Hirni Jaisi Ghoom Rahi’</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 03:19 PM IST <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Ramesh_Bidhuri_and_Atishi_1736932891000_1736932891405.jpg" alt="BJP's Ramesh Bidhuri is contesting against Delhi chief minister Atishi from Kalkaji." title="BJP's Ramesh Bidhuri is contesting against Delhi chief minister Atishi from Kalkaji." />
<figcaption>BJP's Ramesh Bidhuri is contesting against Delhi chief minister Atishi from Kalkaji.</figcaption>
<p>BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri has sparked controversy once again by comparing Delhi Chief Minister Atishi to a “deer” while criticizing her for not engaging with residents in her constituency.</p>
<ul>
<li>Bidhuri's comments come ahead of the Delhi assembly elections scheduled for February 5.</li>
<li>He accused Atishi of ignoring the public and only making appearances during election season, saying she roams the streets like a deer.</li>
<li>This is not the first time Bidhuri has made a controversial remark about Atishi.</li>
<li>Atishi responded emotionally to Bidhuri's comments, defending her father's legacy as a teacher and condemning the attacks on her character.</li>
<li>The Delhi BJP has called for political leaders to avoid personal attacks during campaigns.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I never thought that this country's politics could stoop so low,” - Atishi, responding to Bidhuri's remarks.</blockquote>
<p>The political climate is heated as the elections approach, with both parties engaging in a war of words.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/bjps-ramesh-bidhuri-compares-delhi-cm-atishi-with-deer-hirni-jaisi-ghoom-rahi-101736932900387.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/bjps-ramesh-bidhuri-compares-delhi-cm-atishi-with-deer-hirni-jaisi-ghoom-rahi-101736932900387.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:49:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta India apologises for CEO Mark Zuckerberg’s remark on 2024 elections, terms it “inadvertent error” - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meta India Apologizes for Zuckerberg's Comments on 2024 Elections</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/987114/article69100209.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/US_Media_Fact_Checking_Falters_38531.jpg" alt="Mark Zuckerberg, chief executive officer of Meta. File." title="Mark Zuckerberg, chief executive officer of Meta. File."><figcaption>Mark Zuckerberg, chief executive officer of Meta. File. | Photo Credit: AP</figcaption><p>Meta India has issued an apology following CEO Mark Zuckerberg's erroneous comments regarding the 2024 elections in India, which he made during a podcast, indicating the ruling government lost power.</p><ul><li>Meta's vice president, Shivnath Thukral, stated the comments were an "inadvertent error".</li><li>Several political figures, including BJP leader Nishikant Dubey, accepted the apology, emphasizing the strong support for Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</li><li>Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw criticized Zuckerberg's claims as misinformation.</li><li>India's 2024 elections saw over 640 million voters reaffirm their trust in the current government.</li></ul><blockquote>“A Meta India official has finally apologised for the mistake. This is a victory of the common citizens of India.” - Nishikant Dubey</blockquote><p>The apology marks the conclusion of a political controversy, with officials expressing the importance of maintaining accurate information from prominent organizations like Meta.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/meta-india-apologises-for-ceo-zuckerbergs-remark-on-india-elections-terms-it-inadvertent-error/article69100205.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/meta-india-apologises-for-ceo-zuckerbergs-remark-on-india-elections-terms-it-inadvertent-error/article69100205.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Inadvertent error': Meta India apologises for Mark Zuckerberg's remark on 2024 elections - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meta India Apologizes for Zuckerberg's Remarks on 2024 Elections</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Meta_Mark_Zuckerberg_1736936439207_1736936439499.jpg" alt="This photo illustration shows an image of Mark Zuckerberg, CEO of Meta, and a phone displaying the download page for the Facebook app. (AFP)" title="This photo illustration shows an image of Mark Zuckerberg, CEO of Meta, and a phone displaying the download page for the Facebook app. (AFP)"><figcaption>This photo illustration shows an image of Mark Zuckerberg, CEO of Meta, and a phone displaying the download page for the Facebook app. (AFP)</figcaption><p>Meta India has issued an apology for comments made by CEO Mark Zuckerberg regarding the 2024 elections in India, clarifying that the remark about the incumbent government losing due to its COVID-19 handling was an 'inadvertent error'.</p><ul><li>Mark Zuckerberg claimed that many incumbent governments lost elections worldwide, including India.</li><li>Meta India's vice president, Shivnath Thukral, emphasized India’s importance and issued the apology via a post on X.</li><li>BJP MP Nishikant Dubey criticized the misinformation and stated that Meta would be summoned by his committee.</li><li>Union minister Ashwini Vaishnaw countered Zuckerberg's statement, highlighting India's successful 2024 elections with over 640 million voters.</li></ul><blockquote>“The people of India reaffirmed their trust in the NDA led by PM Narendra Modi's leadership.” — Ashwini Vaishnaw</blockquote><p>This incident underscores the sensitivity surrounding misinformation and the significance of accurate statements by international figures regarding local democratic processes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/meta-india-apologises-for-mark-zuckerbergs-remark-on-lok-sabha-polls-india-remains-incredibly-important-101736930648753.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/meta-india-apologises-for-mark-zuckerbergs-remark-on-lok-sabha-polls-india-remains-incredibly-important-101736930648753.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:08:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi on Mohan Bhagwat’s ‘true independence’ remark: ‘It’s treason’ - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/its-treason-rahul-gandhi-on-mohan-bhagwats-true-independence-remark/article69100061.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/its-treason-rahul-gandhi-on-mohan-bhagwats-true-independence-remark/article69100061.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Political Updates | Congress' ugly truth exposed: Nadda slams Rahul's 'fight against Indian State' remark - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress' ugly truth exposed: Nadda slams Rahul's 'fight against Indian State' remark</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 15 January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> DH</p><p>Rahul Gandhi criticizes Mohan Bhagwat's remarks on India's independence, framing Congress's battle as against the BJP, RSS, and the Indian State.</p><ul><li>Mohan Bhagwat's statement about independence and Ram Mandir sparked controversy.</li><li>Rahul Gandhi labeled the comments as treasonous, claiming a fight against the BJP and the Indian State.</li><li>Sonia Gandhi inaugurated the Congress's new HQ amidst political tensions.</li><li>Kejriwal dismisses life threats, attributing his safety to divine protection.</li></ul><blockquote>Nadda calls out Congress, stating, "Hidden no more, Congress’ ugly truth now stands exposed by their own leader."</blockquote><p>The ongoing political conflict showcases deepening divides within Indian politics as leaders from both Congress and BJP intensify their rhetoric.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/india-political-news-live-updates-bjp-congress-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-arvind-kejriwal-atishi-delhi-assembly-elections-aap-amit-shah-mamata-banerjee-election-commission-2-3355783</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/india-political-news-live-updates-bjp-congress-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-arvind-kejriwal-atishi-delhi-assembly-elections-aap-amit-shah-mamata-banerjee-election-commission-2-3355783</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:34:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On Mumbai visit, PM Narendra Modi meets Mahayuti MLAs over lunch, months after Maharashtra election victory - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Narendra Modi Meets Mahayuti MLAs Over Lunch</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Modi_eknath_devendra_ajit_1736928146490_1736928147261.jpg" alt="PM Modi Luncheon with Mahayuti MLAs" title="PM Modi Luncheon with Mahayuti MLAs">
<figcaption>The Mahayuti parties won a whopping 230 out of 288 assembly seats in Maharashtra in the state polls held in November last year.(ANI File Photo)</figcaption>
<p>During his Mumbai visit, PM Narendra Modi held a luncheon with MLAs of the BJP-led Mahayuti coalition to celebrate their significant victory in the recent Maharashtra elections.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Modi met MLAs at the INS Angre Auditorium in Mumbai.</li>
  <li>The Mahayuti coalition won 230 out of 288 seats in the November assembly elections.</li>
  <li>Key attendees included Maharashtra chief minister Devendra Fadnavis and his deputies Eknath Shinde and Ajit Pawar.</li>
  <li>Modi also commissioned three new naval combatants on the same day, highlighting India's defense progress.</li>
  <li>He is scheduled to inaugurate an ISKCON temple later, emphasizing cultural promotion.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“India is swiftly progressing towards becoming the world's third-largest economy.” - PM Narendra Modi</blockquote>
<p>This event signifies the Mahayuti coalition's strong political position in Maharashtra and showcases PM Modi's continued efforts in bolstering defense and cultural initiatives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/on-mumbai-visit-pm-narendra-modi-meets-mahayuti-mlas-over-lunch-months-after-maharashtra-election-victory-101736927512633.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/on-mumbai-visit-pm-narendra-modi-meets-mahayuti-mlas-over-lunch-months-after-maharashtra-election-victory-101736927512633.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boby tenders unconditional apology, says he won't open his mouth again - Mathrubhumi English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Boby Chemmanur Apologizes to Court and Promises Silence</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Mathrubhumi</p>
<img src="/image/contentid/policy:1.10235056:1736424660/boby%203%20chemmannur.jpg?$p=9aaff8b&amp;q=0.8" alt="Boby Chemmanur">
<figcaption>Bobby Chemmanur | Photo: Mathrubhumi</figcaption>
<p>Boby Chemmanur, a controversial businessman, has issued an unconditional apology before the Kerala High Court after being directed to do so, assuring the court that he will not speak on the matter again.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Kerala High Court settled the case involving Chemmanur.</li>
  <li>Boby's advocate described his prior statements as a 'slip of the tongue'.</li>
  <li>The court warned Boby against acting like he had won an Olympic medal.</li>
  <li>Boby claimed he respects the court and was not trying to 'play games' with it.</li>
  <li>The court demanded an apology for what they termed 'unnecessary drama' regarding his bail release.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Anyone with a basic understanding of the judiciary would never think of playing games with the court." - Boby Chemmanur</blockquote>
<p>The situation highlighted the court's strong disapproval of Chemmanur's actions and the media attention surrounding his bail process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://english.mathrubhumi.com/news/kerala/businessman-boby-chemmanur-says-he-is-ready-to-apologise-for-his-unruly-behaviour-1.10255012</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://english.mathrubhumi.com/news/kerala/businessman-boby-chemmanur-says-he-is-ready-to-apologise-for-his-unruly-behaviour-1.10255012</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:28:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court refuses to quash FIR against BRS MLA KT Rama Rao in Formula E Race case - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/supreme-court-refuses-quash-fir-brs-mla-kt-rama-rao-formula-e-race-case</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/supreme-court-refuses-quash-fir-brs-mla-kt-rama-rao-formula-e-race-case</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:06:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court refuses to quash FIR against BRS MLA KT Rama Rao in Formula E Race case - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/supreme-court-refuses-quash-fir-brs-mla-kt-rama-rao-formula-e-race-case</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/supreme-court-refuses-quash-fir-brs-mla-kt-rama-rao-formula-e-race-case</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:06:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta apologises for Mark Zuckerberg's Indian elections remarks: ‘Inadvertent error’ - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meta Apologizes for Mark Zuckerberg's Indian Elections Remarks: ‘Inadvertent Error’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250111012557_meta.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Meta" title="Meta" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Image for Meta's Apology on Indian Elections Comments</figcaption><p>Meta India has issued an apology regarding comments made by Mark Zuckerberg about the Indian elections, calling them an “inadvertent error.”</p><ul><li>Meta's vice president, Shivnath Thukral, acknowledged the mistake in a post.</li><li>The apology follows remarks by Union minister Ashwini Vaishnaw, who labeled Zuckerberg's comments as “factually incorrect.”</li><li>India conducted its general elections in 2024, with over 640 million voters participating.</li></ul><blockquote>“We would like to apologise for this inadvertent error. India remains an incredibly important country for Meta.” - Shivnath Thukral</blockquote><p>Meta's acknowledgment of the error underlines the platform's commitment to accuracy and the significance of India in its operational strategy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/meta-apologises-for-mark-zuckerberg-s-indian-elections-remarks-inadvertent-error-12911178.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/meta-apologises-for-mark-zuckerberg-s-indian-elections-remarks-inadvertent-error-12911178.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:00:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court grants interim protection from arrest to ex-IAS trainee Puja Khedkar - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Grants Interim Protection from Arrest to Ex-IAS Trainee Puja Khedkar</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 15 Jan 2025, 7:45 am</p><figure><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justice BV Nagarathna and Justice Satish Chandra Sharma" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Justice BV Nagarathna and Justice Satish Chandra Sharma</figcaption></figure><p>The Supreme Court has ordered no coercive steps against Puja Khedkar, a former IAS trainee accused of fraudulently availing reservation benefits while sitting for the UPSC exam, until further notice.</p><ul><li>The Court's order comes as Khedkar appealed against the Delhi High Court's rejection of her anticipatory bail plea.</li><li>Khedkar is accused of misusing reservation meant for Other Backward Classes (OBC) and Persons with Benchmark Disabilities.</li><li>The Supreme Court issued a notice to the state and scheduled the next hearing for 14 February 2025.</li><li>Senior Advocate Siddharth Luthra represents Khedkar and argues for her protection claiming strong findings against her.</li><li>After allegations surfaced, the UPSC cancelled her selection and permanently barred her from future exams.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“If matter goes to trial there will be conviction.. there are strong findings.”</p></blockquote><p>The Supreme Court's decision offers temporary respite for Khedkar as she navigates the legal challenges ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/supreme-court-grants-interim-protection-arrest-ex-ias-trainee-puja-khedkar</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/supreme-court-grants-interim-protection-arrest-ex-ias-trainee-puja-khedkar</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:45:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Engineer Baba’: The viral story of Haryanvi IITian who found his spiritual calling at Kumbh - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxNejk5ckxSZmgzbHFlUEU0RTl6bnpVeFR1RjJaVVExX2R5VmNEakkxNDl4NURWQm41TW1aMFJTcUVtWUstelV4R3hDUVk1ZEE5N1VvenJtal9VSkhjYU1uR0R2elJFRmhuX0c0WjVnSjJFQS1TSmtmNmh4UkY0azdoWG1QRVhGRWhBa25XdVpkY0V3U2NZbTlDSmNuMi1vdUJyd0J5My1WR0xZZ3BwMmhfNTY0QWl6N28zb0hwaVRGWDNiTjcxSXBfb3cxNnJpUERDcmRj0gHXAUFVX3lxTE5oUDBLRmRvbVNZczVwdEk1cXFhNXg0SjJFOVpyOVlreVRUVXhMaWxKcW5PejZIeVFpa2Fac1lsLTRlWDh3QTVXMnZBaHBHa3pkdDlrUmpOWmQ1bDFjdnpXaXJxZVFIUmYtYmcyNlBERzl1TnN1WGktQXhrUGJENGtmLTRhSnUtNzBucDlXekx0YUxhSzlyQllSVWNqNUJGMFVNcVNCaDJOTkRzNmpGTVFsbVhOSWV1NVhMSEpsckp2OGdYbF85WGI4dmptSG1nN0pKaEhiWWhn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxNejk5ckxSZmgzbHFlUEU0RTl6bnpVeFR1RjJaVVExX2R5VmNEakkxNDl4NURWQm41TW1aMFJTcUVtWUstelV4R3hDUVk1ZEE5N1VvenJtal9VSkhjYU1uR0R2elJFRmhuX0c0WjVnSjJFQS1TSmtmNmh4UkY0azdoWG1QRVhGRWhBa25XdVpkY0V3U2NZbTlDSmNuMi1vdUJyd0J5My1WR0xZZ3BwMmhfNTY0QWl6N28zb0hwaVRGWDNiTjcxSXBfb3cxNnJpUERDcmRj0gHXAUFVX3lxTE5oUDBLRmRvbVNZczVwdEk1cXFhNXg0SjJFOVpyOVlreVRUVXhMaWxKcW5PejZIeVFpa2Fac1lsLTRlWDh3QTVXMnZBaHBHa3pkdDlrUmpOWmQ1bDFjdnpXaXJxZVFIUmYtYmcyNlBERzl1TnN1WGktQXhrUGJENGtmLTRhSnUtNzBucDlXekx0YUxhSzlyQllSVWNqNUJGMFVNcVNCaDJOTkRzNmpGTVFsbVhOSWV1NVhMSEpsckp2OGdYbF85WGI4dmptSG1nN0pKaEhiWWhn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:44:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court stays arrest of ex-IAS trainee Puja Khedkar in UPSC cheating case - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Stays Arrest of Former IAS Trainee Puja Khedkar in UPSC Cheating Case</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/puja_khedkar_upsc_probe_1722423465046_1736926259885.jpg" alt="UPSC had cancelled the candidature of Puja Khedkar from IAS, debarring her from all future selections.(HT File)"><figcaption>UPSC had cancelled the candidature of Puja Khedkar from IAS, debarring her from all future selections.(HT File)</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court has ordered a stay on the arrest of former IAS officer Puja Khedkar, accused of fraudulently appearing for the UPSC civil service examination in 2022. The court issued a notice to the Delhi Police and the UPSC regarding her plea for anticipatory bail.</p><ul><li>Puja Khedkar is accused of misrepresenting information to avail reservation benefits in her UPSC application.</li><li>The Delhi High Court previously rejected her anticipatory bail request, citing a strong prima facie case.</li><li>The Supreme Court has scheduled a hearing for February 14 and ordered that no coercive action be taken against her in the meantime.</li><li>Delhi Police assert that a deeper investigation is needed due to emerging conspiracy allegations.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's a classic example of fraud, not only with a constitutional body but also with society and the nation as a whole.”</blockquote><p>The Supreme Court's intervention provides temporary relief to Khedkar as the legal battle continues around her allegations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/supreme-court-stays-arrest-of-ex-ias-trainee-puja-khedkar-101736925994374.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/supreme-court-stays-arrest-of-ex-ias-trainee-puja-khedkar-101736925994374.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:36:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court's shocker to KTR - Deccan Chronicle]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court's Decision Affects KTR in Formula E Race Scam</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 9, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Chronicle</p><img src="https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2025/01/09/1879933-ktr.webp" alt="Supreme Courts shocker to KTR" title="Supreme Courts shocker to KTR"><figcaption>Supreme Courts shocker to KTR</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court declined to entertain a quash petition filed by K T Rama Rao concerning the Formula E race scam, leading to withdrawal of the petition and clearing legal obstacles for an investigation.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court dismissed KTR's quash petition regarding the Formula E race scandal.</li><li>KTR withdrew the petition after the court's refusal, acknowledging the need for investigation.</li><li>The Telangana High Court had mentioned a prima facie case of misuse of public funds.</li><li>The ED has summoned KTR to appear for questioning on Thursday.</li></ul><blockquote>The case warranted investigation. - Supreme Court</blockquote><p>This development signifies a crucial step towards addressing allegations against KTR and the potential financial misconduct related to the event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/formula-e-race-case-sc-wont-entertain-ktr-quah-petition-1854205</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/formula-e-race-case-sc-wont-entertain-ktr-quah-petition-1854205</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:16:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Formula-E case: Supreme Court's shocker to KTR - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Rejects KTR's Plea in Formula-E Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/supremecourt11736924770.jpg" alt="Formula-E case: Supreme Court's shocker to KTR"><figcaption>Formula-E case: Supreme Court's shocker to KTR</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court has dealt a significant blow to K T Rama Rao, rejecting his petition to quash the FIR related to the Formula-E car race case. The court upheld the investigation into alleged financial irregularities.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court refused to interfere with the ongoing investigation.</li><li>KTR's legal counsel withdrew the petition seeking to overturn the high court's decision.</li><li>The case involves claims of financial mismanagement during the Formula-E race in Hyderabad.</li><li>The Telangana government has filed a caveat, ensuring it can present its arguments before any decisions are made.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is not appropriate to quash the case which is still in the investigation stage.” - Mukul Rohatgi, Senior Lawyer</blockquote><p>This ruling marks a significant moment in ongoing legal challenges faced by KTR, as he continues to contest the findings related to the Formula-E event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/telangana-news/formula-e-case-supreme-courts-shocker-to-ktr-143422</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/telangana-news/formula-e-case-supreme-courts-shocker-to-ktr-143422</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:11:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai News Live Updates: India set to become major maritime power, says PM Modi as Navy gets 3 new frontline combatants - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Set to Become Major Maritime Power as PM Modi Commissions Three New Naval Combatants</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 15 January 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/modi-MLA-meet.jpg?w=640" alt="modi, mumbai, naval vessels" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi Wednesday commissioned three naval frontline combatants — INS Surat, INS Nilgiri and INS Vaghsheer — at the Mumbai dock. (x/@CMOMaharashtra)</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi commissioned three new naval frontline combatants in Mumbai, stating that India is on the path to becoming a significant maritime power.</p>
<ul>
  <li>INS Surat and INS Nilgiri are part of a new class of warships designed to enhance India’s naval capabilities.</li>
  <li>PM Modi emphasized the importance of securing trade routes and protecting territorial waters.</li>
  <li>These ships represent a crucial step in enhancing India's military and maritime strength.</li>
  <li>India is exporting defense equipment to over 100 countries, reflecting its growing defense production.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It is important to protect territorial waters, freedom of navigation, and secure trade supply lines and sea routes.” - PM Modi</blockquote>
<p>This commissioning marks a pivotal movement in enhancing India's naval strength and global standing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/mumbai-news-live-updates-modi-weather-9779502/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/mumbai-news-live-updates-modi-weather-9779502/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:56:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Non-sense, it's treason': Rahul Gandhi slams RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat's ‘true Independence’ statement - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rahul Gandhi Critiques RSS Chief Mohan Bhagwat's Independence Remarks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Rahul_Gandhi_Mohan_Bhagwat_1736921911827_1736921930546.jpg" alt="Rahul Gandhi said that Mohan Bhagwat saying that India did not get independence in 1947 was an insult to every single Indian person.(PTI)" title="Rahul Gandhi said that Mohan Bhagwat saying that India did not get independence in 1947 was an insult to every single Indian person.(PTI)"><figcaption>Rahul Gandhi said that Mohan Bhagwat saying that India did not get independence in 1947 was an insult to every single Indian person.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Rahul Gandhi launched a strong attack on RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat for his statement that India's 'true independence' began with the construction of the Ram Mandir in Ayodhya, calling it treason and an insult to Indians.</p><ul><li>Mohan Bhagwat claimed India attained 'true independence' with the Ram Mandir consecration.</li><li>Rahul Gandhi condemned Bhagwat's remarks, stating they undermine India's independence movement and the Constitution.</li><li>The statements have sparked widespread political backlash.</li></ul><blockquote>“What he said yesterday is treason because it states that the Constitution is invalid, and the fight against the British was invalid.” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Gandhi's criticism highlights ongoing political tensions and differing views on India's historical narrative.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/nonsense-its-treason-rahul-gandhi-slams-rss-chief-mohan-bhagwats-true-independence-statement-101736921458788.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/nonsense-its-treason-rahul-gandhi-slams-rss-chief-mohan-bhagwats-true-independence-statement-101736921458788.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:53:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gwalior 'honour killing': Girl declares love for boyfriend 4 days before 'forced' marriage, shot dead by - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bhopal/gwalior-honour-killing-girl-declares-love-for-boyfriend-4-days-before-forced-marriage-shot-dead-by-father/articleshow/117256915.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bhopal/gwalior-honour-killing-girl-declares-love-for-boyfriend-4-days-before-forced-marriage-shot-dead-by-father/articleshow/117256915.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Budget 2025: Will Sitharaman make roti, kapada, makaan affordable again? - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxNMDBpbTQ1bExtRU5OYmdQbDM2bEswQUZIQ0k1S0p2RkZ1Z3hEWFRWOWF1dEpzT3E2SWNvN29UVG5GSmxUVHlWLWR0djdSdC12MUNHY2NVOFIxNW1sQ3B1cjByeHNDajdqVTM3UWR0ckM5VUM5YzFyTlBlbzVhNDFoWmw5aTVJbGxuSlhUNmpRUWVsTGxOaHpUaTZPQksyNXBfbjkyYU1tSlowcDQ0d3RBbkVtYWJtWWpETUVyQ2NSbEg5TzR5Q1NSODRuUTdBcUM5SzcxVGl5RFdPZ9IB3wFBVV95cUxNc0xZYU8zVktfVjIxRlk5U2dsUkt0X1JlYmpXclNJMlU3Y3lJTE1mMHEzYTROajF4OTlZNU1PTWpDU0hPeUpZSjdxOWtNVzZJTklVYTVnNmpTS3Qzc3U0M2xiWDhDV3JhdEpKWjFYaTFOSkV3bXhPNHVUZ0J2Q0RYTzhWZE9xamNXVWdrWnRCU1VwSGlIRFAyRkxYblhsQ3MwX0s1M1N5d0p2Sm9CWVFqY3YxNmJtTHN4SkoyQXIxZWs2N3ZDR09IMDhwaFo2cmdEVnZvVllfdTJHZng1ZWln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxNMDBpbTQ1bExtRU5OYmdQbDM2bEswQUZIQ0k1S0p2RkZ1Z3hEWFRWOWF1dEpzT3E2SWNvN29UVG5GSmxUVHlWLWR0djdSdC12MUNHY2NVOFIxNW1sQ3B1cjByeHNDajdqVTM3UWR0ckM5VUM5YzFyTlBlbzVhNDFoWmw5aTVJbGxuSlhUNmpRUWVsTGxOaHpUaTZPQksyNXBfbjkyYU1tSlowcDQ0d3RBbkVtYWJtWWpETUVyQ2NSbEg5TzR5Q1NSODRuUTdBcUM5SzcxVGl5RFdPZ9IB3wFBVV95cUxNc0xZYU8zVktfVjIxRlk5U2dsUkt0X1JlYmpXclNJMlU3Y3lJTE1mMHEzYTROajF4OTlZNU1PTWpDU0hPeUpZSjdxOWtNVzZJTklVYTVnNmpTS3Qzc3U0M2xiWDhDV3JhdEpKWjFYaTFOSkV3bXhPNHVUZ0J2Q0RYTzhWZE9xamNXVWdrWnRCU1VwSGlIRFAyRkxYblhsQ3MwX0s1M1N5d0p2Sm9CWVFqY3YxNmJtTHN4SkoyQXIxZWs2N3ZDR09IMDhwaFo2cmdEVnZvVllfdTJHZng1ZWln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:36:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CLAT 2025: Supreme Court moots transfer of cases to a single High Court - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CLAT 2025: Supreme Court moots transfer of cases to a single High Court</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><div><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="CJI Sanjiv Khanna and Justice PV Sanjay Kumar " width="100%" height="100%" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 90vw, 50vw"><figcaption>CJI Sanjiv Khanna and Justice PV Sanjay Kumar</figcaption></div><p>The Supreme Court has proposed to consolidate all cases related to CLAT in a single High Court to expedite the decision-making process and reduce conflicting judgments.</p><ul><li>The Court rejected the NLU Consortium's request to transfer the cases to itself.</li><li>It emphasized that transferring cases to one High Court could increase efficiency in handling the matters.</li><li>The potential High Courts under consideration include Karnataka, Delhi, and Punjab and Haryana High Courts.</li><li>Solicitor General Tushar Mehta expressed a preference for the Karnataka High Court.</li><li>The Court noted a previous ruling by the Punjab and Haryana High Court and stated it would deliberate on which High Court to choose during the next hearing.</li></ul><blockquote>“We can’t take it here, we already rejected under Article 32. We will send you to a High Court.” - Supreme Court</blockquote><p>The Supreme Court aims to streamline the process for CLAT cases while addressing the concerns raised by legal representatives during the proceedings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/clat-2025-supreme-court-moots-transfer-cases-single-high-court</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/clat-2025-supreme-court-moots-transfer-cases-single-high-court</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:30:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man Shoots Daughter In Front Of Cops, Panchayat, Days Before Her Wedding - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxOcGlyVlhLYUxsSk5UR3lkM1QzM1BqOXJBVkhqaVJCS280X3Fybm1rWkhWVmlVQmZ3ejNMeU1JQmt0OTFJSTBkS2NBdllBMUZjVGlMZG1IUGM1aHZ4ckUtZk5pUlNHel95azJsNThGSkRGazhOb1BZSkFqQkVjem5vd3F5U1JLcWx1cnpYUmV1cnFPelBkMWVOTzNiVjFkNS0wT2czQ21sQnhTOVRZcFZR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxOcGlyVlhLYUxsSk5UR3lkM1QzM1BqOXJBVkhqaVJCS280X3Fybm1rWkhWVmlVQmZ3ejNMeU1JQmt0OTFJSTBkS2NBdllBMUZjVGlMZG1IUGM1aHZ4ckUtZk5pUlNHel95azJsNThGSkRGazhOb1BZSkFqQkVjem5vd3F5U1JLcWx1cnpYUmV1cnFPelBkMWVOTzNiVjFkNS0wT2czQ21sQnhTOVRZcFZR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:22:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi commissions 3 naval warships in Mumbai - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Commissions 3 Naval Warships in Mumbai</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/cishss/article69100132.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/PTI01_15_2025_000195B.jpg" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi during a ceremony to dedicate frontline naval combatants INS Surat, INS Nilgiri and INS Vaghsheer to the nation, at the Naval Dockyard in Mumbai." title="Prime Minister Narendra Modi during a ceremony to dedicate frontline naval combatants INS Surat, INS Nilgiri and INS Vaghsheer to the nation, at the Naval Dockyard in Mumbai.">
<figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi during a ceremony to dedicate frontline naval combatants INS Surat, INS Nilgiri and INS Vaghsheer to the nation, at the Naval Dockyard in Mumbai. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption>
<p>The Indian Navy commissioned three new warships, INS Surat, INS Nilgiri, and INS Vaghsheer, in Mumbai, emphasizing India's growing maritime power and role as a responsible global partner.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Three naval warships were commissioned: a destroyer, a frigate, and a submarine.</li>
  <li>Prime Minister Modi highlighted India's commitment to a secure and inclusive Indo-Pacific region.</li>
  <li>Emphasis on the ‘Atmanirbhar Bharat’ initiative promoting self-reliance in defense.</li>
  <li>Over the last decade, India inducted 33 ships and seven submarines into its navy.</li>
  <li>India’s defense production has reached ₹1.25 lakh crore, with exports to over 100 countries.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We should become a global partner in securing the sea from drugs, weapons and terrorism and make it safe and prosperous.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the commissioning of these warships marks a significant step in enhancing India's naval capabilities and its commitment to global maritime security.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/three-naval-warships-commissioned-in-mumbai-pm-modi-attends-event/article69099605.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/three-naval-warships-commissioned-in-mumbai-pm-modi-attends-event/article69099605.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9A, Kotla Road: Congress gets new headquarters ‘Indira Bhawan’ in Sonia Gandhi, Mallikarjun Kharge's presence - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Inaugurates New Headquarters 'Indira Bhawan' in New Delhi</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Congress_1736919818159_1736919841881.jpg" alt="Congress president Mallikarjun Kharge and former president Sonia Gandhi light a lamp during the inauguration of new party headquarters in New Delhi on Tuesday.(ANI)" title="Congress president Mallikarjun Kharge and former president Sonia Gandhi light a lamp during the inauguration of new party headquarters in New Delhi on Tuesday.(ANI)">
<figcaption>Congress president Mallikarjun Kharge and former president Sonia Gandhi light a lamp during the inauguration of new party headquarters in New Delhi on Tuesday.(ANI)</figcaption>
<p>The Congress party has officially inaugurated its new headquarters, Indira Bhawan, at 9A Kotla Road in New Delhi, marking a significant transition after 47 years at its previous location, 24 Akbar Road.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sonia Gandhi, Congress Parliamentary Party chief, led the inauguration ceremony.</li>
  <li>Key party leaders including Mallikarjun Kharge and Rahul Gandhi participated in the event.</li>
  <li>The move symbolizes a potential resurgence for the party following losses in recent elections.</li>
  <li>Supporting speeches emphasized the significance of this new beginning for the party and nation.</li>
  <li>Rahul Gandhi criticized RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat's remarks about the Indian Constitution during the event.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"It is a new beginning. We are very happy that we have a new headquarters. I hope this will bring better things for the party and the country." - Sachin Pilot</blockquote>
<p>The inauguration of Indira Bhawan is seen as a strategic move for the Congress party, aiming to revitalize its operations and outreach as it navigates through challenging political waters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/9a-kotla-road-congress-gets-new-headquarters-indira-bhawan-in-sonia-gandhi-mallikarjun-kharges-presence-101736918836388.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/9a-kotla-road-congress-gets-new-headquarters-indira-bhawan-in-sonia-gandhi-mallikarjun-kharges-presence-101736918836388.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:13:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dr. V. Narayanan Assumed Charge of Secretary, Department of Space and Chairman, Space Commission - ISRO]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOWFVQZmZUWEkxaTR5ejY1TEtVcVYyTktyNlluVXB2VUhCWUJPS1pTVzhfN3dGb2hUenBSVUM4TE5FU0RBdUlkd3FTTGxkQWxmUVhxWXpTU2RGXy02cjY5aGpxbGs4cGdLdVpjQnk0TTBUcTJ4R1FNZEdZQ0J2LTE2RVFrbDhFQk9vNGVseXhfVzdjQl8zSlR1Y3dTUnQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOWFVQZmZUWEkxaTR5ejY1TEtVcVYyTktyNlluVXB2VUhCWUJPS1pTVzhfN3dGb2hUenBSVUM4TE5FU0RBdUlkd3FTTGxkQWxmUVhxWXpTU2RGXy02cjY5aGpxbGs4cGdLdVpjQnk0TTBUcTJ4R1FNZEdZQ0J2LTE2RVFrbDhFQk9vNGVseXhfVzdjQl8zSlR1Y3dTUnQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:09:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Mohan Bhagwat has committed treason… attacked the Constitution’: Rahul Gandhi at launch of Congress’s new headquarters - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘We are fighting BJP, RSS, and the Indian state itself’: Rahul Gandhi hits out at Mohan Bhagwat</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Rahul-Gandhi-Constitution.jpg?w=640" alt="Congress Rahul Gandhi Mohan Bhagwat" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Congress leader Rahul Gandhi made the comments during the inauguration of Congress's new headquarters. (Photo: PTI)</figcaption><p>During the inauguration of Congress's new headquarters, Rahul Gandhi criticized BJP and RSS for allegedly capturing all institutions in India, asserting that Mohan Bhagwat's comments on India's independence were treasonous.</p><ul><li>Gandhi claimed that the RSS chief's remarks undermined the true significance of India's independence in 1947.</li><li>He emphasized the Congress vision as one that respects diverse languages and cultures.</li><li>Gandhi described Bhagwat's perspective as a centralized ideology that threatens democratic values.</li><li>He warned against the agenda that seeks to suppress the voices of marginalized communities in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“To say that India did not get Independence in 1947 is an insult to every single Indian.” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote><p>The confrontation highlights an ideological clash between Congress and RSS, with Gandhi positioning Congress as the defender of India's secular and democratic fabric.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/mohan-bhagwat-constitution-rahul-gandhi-congresss-new-headquarters-9779671/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/mohan-bhagwat-constitution-rahul-gandhi-congresss-new-headquarters-9779671/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 05:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>