<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:32:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:32:21 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament session LIVE: Amit Shah's Ambedkar remarks stir row, Lok Sabha adjourned till 2pm - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-session-live-rajya-sabha-lok-sabha-amit-shah-one-nation-one-election-bill-latest-updates-today-december-18-101734492559242.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-session-live-rajya-sabha-lok-sabha-amit-shah-one-nation-one-election-bill-latest-updates-today-december-18-101734492559242.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 05:41:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J&K: Former DSP among 6 killed after fire breaks out at house in Kathua - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tragic Fire in Kathua Claims Six Lives Including Former DSP</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/gda9c0b0b5a4fb513497faf37a3166_1734498862175_1734498862349.jpg" alt="Locals saw the house on fire after 2 AM. (Representative Image)" title="Locals saw the house on fire after 2 AM. (Representative Image)"><figcaption>Locals saw the house on fire after 2 AM. (Representative Image)</figcaption><p>A significant fire incident occurred in Jammu and Kashmir’s Kathua district, leading to the tragic deaths of six individuals, including a former deputy superintendent of police and his young grandson. The fire broke out in the early hours, with locals discovering it around 2:30 AM.</p><ul><li>The deceased include Avtar Krishen Raina, 81, former DSP, and his 3-year-old grandson.</li><li>Four others were injured and are receiving treatment at the Government Medical College in Kathua.</li><li>Preliminary investigations indicate that victims died from smoke inhalation.</li><li>Union Minister Jitendra Singh expressed his condolences on social media.</li><li>The police have initiated an investigation into the incident.</li></ul><blockquote>“Deeply shocked to learn about the accidental death of 6 members of a family resulting from fire incident in the Shiv Nagar area of Kathua city.” - Jitendra Singh</blockquote><p>This unfortunate incident has highlighted serious concerns regarding fire safety and the urgent need for better awareness in residential areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jk-former-dsp-among-6-killed-after-fire-breaks-out-at-house-in-kathua-101734498758157.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jk-former-dsp-among-6-killed-after-fire-breaks-out-at-house-in-kathua-101734498758157.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 05:38:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NSA Ajit Doval meets China FM Wang Yi; Beijing says 'ready to work with India' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NSA Ajit Doval meets China FM Wang Yi; Beijing says 'ready to work with India'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Publication Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name Here]</p><p>This article discusses the recent meeting between India's National Security Advisor Ajit Doval and Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi, where both parties expressed readiness to strengthen bilateral relations.</p><ul><li>Ajit Doval and Wang Yi held discussions on various strategic issues between India and China.</li><li>Beijing emphasized its willingness to collaborate and improve ties with India.</li><li>The meeting comes in the backdrop of ongoing border disputes and regional security concerns.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are ready to work with India on mutual interests,” said Wang Yi during the meeting.</blockquote><p>This meeting signifies an important step towards enhancing cooperation between India and China amidst ongoing challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ready-to-work-with-india-china-ahead-of-key-meet-between-ajit-doval-and-wang-yi/articleshow/116417490.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ready-to-work-with-india-china-ahead-of-key-meet-between-ajit-doval-and-wang-yi/articleshow/116417490.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 05:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Ready To Work With India': China Ahead Of Crucial Meeting With Ajit Doval - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Ready to Collaborate with India as Doval-Wang Meeting Begins</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="NSA Ajit Doval is slated to meet China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi to discuss bilateral ties. (PTI/File)" />
<figcaption>NSA Ajit Doval is slated to meet China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi to discuss bilateral ties. (PTI/File)</figcaption>
<p>China has expressed its readiness to work with India to enhance bilateral relations ahead of a crucial meeting between National Security Advisor Ajit Doval and Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi in Beijing.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The talks aim to restore relations following the October 21 agreement to disengage troops in eastern Ladakh.</li>
  <li>This meeting marks the first high-level talks between India and China since December 2019.</li>
  <li>Focus areas include the India-China boundary question and strengthening mutual trust through dialogue.</li>
  <li>China is committed to respect India's core interests and bring relations back to stable development.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“China is ready to work with India to implement the important common understandings between the leaders of China and India.” - Lin Jian, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson</blockquote>
<p>This meeting underscores the ongoing diplomatic efforts to normalize ties after years of tensions, particularly following the Galwan Valley clash in 2020.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/china-says-ready-to-work-with-india-to-improve-bilateral-ties-ahead-of-ajit-dovals-visit-9159882.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/china-says-ready-to-work-with-india-to-improve-bilateral-ties-ahead-of-ajit-dovals-visit-9159882.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 03:41:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J&K: Six die in a short circuit in Kathua - Cross Town News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQMndRMDRRLWZubFpNemtvbGg1VllLZXBPa1lpaDZ6aGt2Ymk4S0ZwdzRUVWNCdVEtTkxQQWFxTkdRbWhDSmlZSDIxMElhTEJ6SDd0Mkg4bS0xaTZ1ck1MandGamJIamtNVnpvMW91RjZ2MkFGaUtMWjE5aGdNU0VVM0VVZ2dIM3dGUFN5OVF3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQMndRMDRRLWZubFpNemtvbGg1VllLZXBPa1lpaDZ6aGt2Ymk4S0ZwdzRUVWNCdVEtTkxQQWFxTkdRbWhDSmlZSDIxMElhTEJ6SDd0Mkg4bS0xaTZ1ck1MandGamJIamtNVnpvMW91RjZ2MkFGaUtMWjE5aGdNU0VVM0VVZ2dIM3dGUFN5OVF3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 03:33:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jharkhand govt initiates process for legal action to realise 'coal dues' from Centre | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/jharkhand-govt-initiates-process-for-legal-action-to-realise-coal-dues-from-centre-11734491907656.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/jharkhand-govt-initiates-process-for-legal-action-to-realise-coal-dues-from-centre-11734491907656.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 03:18:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cold wave in Delhi to worsen this winter? City shivers, IMD predicts mercury may drop to... | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cold Wave in Delhi: IMD Predicts Worsening Conditions This Winter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Delhi is experiencing a notable cold wave, with the India Meteorological Department (IMD) forecasting further drops in temperature, potentially worsening the conditions this winter.</p><ul><li>The IMD recorded a temperature of 8 degrees Celsius in Delhi at 2.30 AM on Tuesday.</li><li>A cold wave warning has been issued across various northern states in India, including Jammu and Kashmir, Punjab, Haryana, and Uttar Pradesh.</li><li>Delhi's air quality has deteriorated significantly, registering a severe Air Quality Index (AQI) reading of 481.</li><li>The school system in Delhi-NCR has shifted to a hybrid mode due to the reintroduction of anti-pollution measures under the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP).</li></ul><blockquote>“Delhi’s air quality plummeted to alarming levels despite strict measures.”</blockquote><p>The cold wave and poor air quality have raised concerns among residents and authorities, highlighting the urgent need for effective measures to address these challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/cold-wave-in-delhi-to-worsen-this-winter-city-shivers-imd-predicts-mercury-may-drop-to-11734488377935.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/cold-wave-in-delhi-to-worsen-this-winter-city-shivers-imd-predicts-mercury-may-drop-to-11734488377935.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 02:48:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Priyanka Gandhi on Yogi Adityanath's jibe at her Palestine bag: ‘Throwing youths into…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Priyanka Gandhi Responds to Yogi Adityanath's Comments on Her Palestine Bag</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/Priyanka_Gandhi_1734489411587_1734489411846.jpg" alt="Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra at Parliament premises during the winter session, in New Delhi on December 16. (ANI)" title="Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra at Parliament premises during the winter session, in New Delhi on December 16. (ANI)"><figcaption>Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra at Parliament premises during the winter session, in New Delhi on December 16. (ANI)</figcaption><p>Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra has reacted to Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath's remarks regarding her bag featuring the term 'Palestine'. She criticized the state's policy of sending youths to Israel for work in conflict zones, calling it shameful.</p><ul><li>Priyanka Gandhi carried a 'Palestine' bag to Parliament, which attracted criticism from BJP leaders.</li><li>Yogi Adityanath stated that over 5,600 youths from UP have gone to Israel for employment, emphasizing their safety and salaries.</li><li>Priyanka labeled sending youths into a war zone for jobs as a disgrace and highlighted the unemployment issues in UP.</li><li>She spoke out against the exploitation of these youths and their families, who live in constant fear.</li></ul><blockquote>"Throwing our youths into the war zone for employment is not something to pat on the back but a matter of shame." - Priyanka Gandhi</blockquote><p>This exchange underscores ongoing tensions between political leaders regarding employment strategies and international relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/priyanka-gandhi-on-yogi-adityanaths-jibe-at-her-palestine-bag-throwing-youths-into-101734488461414.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/priyanka-gandhi-on-yogi-adityanaths-jibe-at-her-palestine-bag-throwing-youths-into-101734488461414.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 02:44:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Ready to work with India': China ahead of key meet between Ajit Doval and Wang Yi - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NSA Ajit Doval meets China FM Wang Yi; Beijing says 'ready to work with India'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>In a significant diplomatic meeting, Indian National Security Advisor Ajit Doval engaged with China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi, where both parties expressed a willingness to collaborate and work together, indicating a thaw in relations.</p><ul><li>Ajit Doval and Wang Yi met to discuss enhancing bilateral ties between India and China.</li><li>Beijing has shown a readiness to cooperate with India on various fronts.</li><li>The discussions signify a move towards stabilizing relations post recent tensions.</li></ul><blockquote>"Both nations are ready to build a robust partnership for mutual interests."</blockquote><p>This meeting is seen as a crucial step in addressing longstanding issues and paving the way for future collaborations between the two countries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ready-to-work-with-india-china-ahead-of-key-meet-between-ajit-doval-and-wang-yi/articleshow/116417490.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/ready-to-work-with-india-china-ahead-of-key-meet-between-ajit-doval-and-wang-yi/articleshow/116417490.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 02:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi AQI: Air quality at ‘severe-plus’ category in some areas amid GRAP curbs - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi AQI: Air quality at ‘severe-plus’ category in some areas amid GRAP curbs</h1><p><strong>Date: December 18, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/delhi_aqi_1734487671985_1734487672482.jpg" alt="Smog seen engulfed in the late hours of the day amid increase in pollution levels at Kartavya Path in New Delhi, India, on Monday, December 16, 2024. (Sanchit Khanna/ Hindustan Times)" title="Smog seen engulfed in the late hours of the day amid increase in pollution levels at Kartavya Path in New Delhi, India, on Monday, December 16, 2024. (Sanchit Khanna/ Hindustan Times)"><figcaption>Smog seen engulfed in the late hours of the day amid increase in pollution levels at Kartavya Path in New Delhi, India, on Monday, December 16, 2024. (Sanchit Khanna/ Hindustan Times)</figcaption><p>Delhi faced dangerously high levels of air pollution with the overall Air Quality Index (AQI) reaching over 440, classifying the air quality as ‘severe’. The city implemented Stage 4 restrictions under the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) to combat the pollution crisis.</p><ul><li>Overall AQI recorded at 442 at 7 am on December 18, 2024.</li><li>Some monitoring stations reported AQI levels in the ‘severe-plus’ category beyond 450.</li><li>AQI levels at worst stations: Nehru Nagar (480), Alipur (471), Anand Vihar (481).</li><li>Stage 4 restrictions include a ban on construction activities and non-essential vehicle entry into Delhi.</li><li>Experts attribute rising pollution to low wind speeds and various local factors.</li></ul><blockquote>“Breathing Delhi's polluted air is equivalent to smoking approximately 10 cigarettes a day.”</blockquote><p>The ongoing air quality crisis necessitates urgent action and compliance with GRAP restrictions to protect public health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-aqi-air-quality-severe-plus-category-grap-4-delhi-weather-cold-wave-101734484847481.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-aqi-air-quality-severe-plus-category-grap-4-delhi-weather-cold-wave-101734484847481.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 02:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump threatens ‘reciprocal’ tax on India: ‘If India charges us 100%…’ | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/donald-trump-threatens-reciprocal-tax-high-tariff-on-india-they-are-taxing-us-we-havent-been-taxing-them-11734486997521.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/donald-trump-threatens-reciprocal-tax-high-tariff-on-india-they-are-taxing-us-we-havent-been-taxing-them-11734486997521.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 02:14:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Ready to work with India’, says China ahead of key Doval-Wang talks | What's on agenda - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Ready to Collaborate with India Before Key Doval-Wang Talks</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/St-Petersburg--National-Security-Advisor-Ajit-Dova_1726281895745_1734484279881.jpg" alt="St Petersburg: National Security Advisor Ajit Doval with Chinese foreign minister Wang Yi" title="St Petersburg: National Security Advisor Ajit Doval with Chinese foreign minister Wang Yi">
<figcaption>St Petersburg: National Security Advisor Ajit Doval with Chinese foreign minister Wang Yi (both in centre) during their talks, in St. Petersburg, Russia, on September 12, 2024. (PTI)</figcaption>
<p>China is prepared to work with India to restore bilateral relations ahead of upcoming talks between India's National Security Advisor Ajit Doval and Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi, marking the first meeting of Special Representatives in five years.</p>
<ul>
  <li>First Doval-Wang meeting since December 2019 will take place in Beijing.</li>
  <li>China's foreign ministry emphasizes readiness to strengthen mutual trust and settle differences.</li>
  <li>The two leaders will discuss border management and explore solutions to the boundary dispute.</li>
  <li>Recent agreements were reached regarding patrolling arrangements along the Line of Actual Control.</li>
  <li>The military standoff, starting in May 2020, has strained India-China relations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“China is ready to work with India to implement the important common understandings between our leaders... and bring bilateral relations back to the track of stable and healthy development as soon as possible.”</blockquote>
<p>This structured dialogue represents a critical step in rebuilding relationships strained by previous military clashes and ongoing tensions along the Indo-China border.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ready-to-work-with-india-says-china-ahead-of-key-doval-wang-talks-whats-on-agenda-101734483991216.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ready-to-work-with-india-says-china-ahead-of-key-doval-wang-talks-whats-on-agenda-101734483991216.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 02:11:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh makes another SHOCKING statement, says ‘India was nothing…’ - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/bangladesh-makes-another-shocking-statement-says-india-was-nothing-merely-an-ally-in-this-victory-bangladeshs-victory-day-pm-modis-vijay-diwas-post-7473272/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/bangladesh-makes-another-shocking-statement-says-india-was-nothing-merely-an-ally-in-this-victory-bangladeshs-victory-day-pm-modis-vijay-diwas-post-7473272/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 01:31:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh makes another SHOCKING statement, says 'India was nothing...' - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAJBVV95cUxOX2FXLWdRejFEbEZFb0Q4MFRVUGFNQnVTcHVfcXgxcDRabmY1N25GQUVzQmZWZ0lMbWQwNV9lWlhzNDdWcDJjeXJiaFBSZUthQTdBbDVlWG9DQVpLYTAwaUplSjJIUHZobEtKbmI1SFlrMU5HYzN4NC1kZWhOb0JadXo5YU4xQU10RFR0MlBjV0RocFgtRnhKR3hNcl9fVDF6bFItcU5DbHFWalNGbHpSVkczZjRUQVZKbkxxNHJtSUZkanZ4VnpkbVlGU0VIV05yMW9OR1Y3WHlQZVVIdHBDd05FZURhRjRyYlJ2RGZ4WVppcGpiYXBrM2QxQ2hleEVtM1JQVGx5WkNxNW5HdW5ISDlaSlVNRnRw0gGeAkFVX3lxTFBRTHF1d2FmV3cxbUFidFN3aEkwZG9xekE1N3RzdmRCVzJmdjZ5UWh5YV9CUGQ3bHF0bVFESXE4bWxkcWotY0hfYXFvVTBPU05DOVFTbFFqZWxVMl9WMVlIS2t5S1ZTX2FYd2R0SGtib3VwTlpTUUVQcXcycWdENnZRZGQ2dVhUbEwzNW5SbENiR1NOdFpTRHUyODJPLU5nLVBZT19yeHU0S25peHpsc0wyczVtWUFDRU5WNUVPejJkak5UYmJDZHNUVC0xNElsWTJfMTl5Y2tUMk8zb05DOWpPQzJfbmVCN0tOT3lVZ2ktSGVtb0JIMFhoY0RqeXdYMi1LZkExSUl4U1RSX2pJd3Vobkxnc2xzZTZwajNvNnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAJBVV95cUxOX2FXLWdRejFEbEZFb0Q4MFRVUGFNQnVTcHVfcXgxcDRabmY1N25GQUVzQmZWZ0lMbWQwNV9lWlhzNDdWcDJjeXJiaFBSZUthQTdBbDVlWG9DQVpLYTAwaUplSjJIUHZobEtKbmI1SFlrMU5HYzN4NC1kZWhOb0JadXo5YU4xQU10RFR0MlBjV0RocFgtRnhKR3hNcl9fVDF6bFItcU5DbHFWalNGbHpSVkczZjRUQVZKbkxxNHJtSUZkanZ4VnpkbVlGU0VIV05yMW9OR1Y3WHlQZVVIdHBDd05FZURhRjRyYlJ2RGZ4WVppcGpiYXBrM2QxQ2hleEVtM1JQVGx5WkNxNW5HdW5ISDlaSlVNRnRw0gGeAkFVX3lxTFBRTHF1d2FmV3cxbUFidFN3aEkwZG9xekE1N3RzdmRCVzJmdjZ5UWh5YV9CUGQ3bHF0bVFESXE4bWxkcWotY0hfYXFvVTBPU05DOVFTbFFqZWxVMl9WMVlIS2t5S1ZTX2FYd2R0SGtib3VwTlpTUUVQcXcycWdENnZRZGQ2dVhUbEwzNW5SbENiR1NOdFpTRHUyODJPLU5nLVBZT19yeHU0S25peHpsc0wyczVtWUFDRU5WNUVPejJkak5UYmJDZHNUVC0xNElsWTJfMTl5Y2tUMk8zb05DOWpPQzJfbmVCN0tOT3lVZ2ktSGVtb0JIMFhoY0RqeXdYMi1LZkExSUl4U1RSX2pJd3Vobkxnc2xzZTZwajNvNnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 01:31:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress accuses Amit Shah of insulting Ambedkar in Parliament speech, demands apology - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Demands Apology from Amit Shah for Comments on Ambedkar</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> HT News Desk</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/Amit_Shah_and_Mallikarjun_Kharge_1712414447105_1734483774420.jpg" alt="Union home minister Amit Shah and Congress president Mallikarjun Kharge.(X)">
<figcaption>Union home minister Amit Shah and Congress president Mallikarjun Kharge.(X)</figcaption>
<p>The Congress party criticized Amit Shah for his comments regarding BR Ambedkar during a Rajya Sabha address, demanding an apology from the Home Minister.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Amit Shah accused Congress of using Ambedkar's name as a political tool.</li>
  <li>Shah stated that citing Ambedkar had become a 'fashion' for Congress.</li>
  <li>Congress leaders, including Rahul Gandhi and Mallikarjun Kharge, condemned Shah's remarks.</li>
  <li>Kharge emphasized that Ambedkar is revered as a messiah for marginalized communities.</li>
  <li>Jairam Ramesh labeled Shah's comments as disgusting and reflective of BJP's deep-seated animosity towards Ambedkar.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“For crores of people like me, Babasaheb Ambedkar is no less than God.” - Mallikarjun Kharge</blockquote>
<p>In light of Shah's comments, the Congress party continues to assert the importance of Ambedkar's legacy and the need for respect towards it.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/congress-accuses-amit-shah-of-insulting-ambedkar-in-parliament-speech-demands-apology-101734482557480.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/congress-accuses-amit-shah-of-insulting-ambedkar-in-parliament-speech-demands-apology-101734482557480.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 01:14:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What the uproar over Atul Subhash’s death by suicide says about gender relations in India - Scroll.in]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxNZzZuMF9rbmc2U3pEbVppM3VUWWsyaHk2b1cyYkVYbzFwaVZxNkRaTFBIV2REaTFLbnYySzRhVExZSVZteV9fZ2dYNDJfYndWejBVVExfOHhiOUtKTXNMdVRwdE0ya2w2aTEtTXpIbnByUlJWS1piMlpqOENFZWlrMXpJWEJJQVdtMzVfVHVLVHI0Rk1xR1BseWtDVjIwbDFaOF9BLW8tUW5Ua1E2dnhFZU5GRnNZLUdSTXdGV2pLRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxNZzZuMF9rbmc2U3pEbVppM3VUWWsyaHk2b1cyYkVYbzFwaVZxNkRaTFBIV2REaTFLbnYySzRhVExZSVZteV9fZ2dYNDJfYndWejBVVExfOHhiOUtKTXNMdVRwdE0ya2w2aTEtTXpIbnByUlJWS1piMlpqOENFZWlrMXpJWEJJQVdtMzVfVHVLVHI0Rk1xR1BseWtDVjIwbDFaOF9BLW8tUW5Ua1E2dnhFZU5GRnNZLUdSTXdGV2pLRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump's message to India over high tariffs: 'They tax us, we tax them' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump's Stance on High Tariffs: A Call for Reciprocity with India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/trump_india_tax_1734482858933_1734482859199.jpg" alt="US President-elect Donald Trump speaks during a news conference at Trump Tower, May 31, 2024, in New York. (AP)"><figcaption>US President-elect Donald Trump speaks during a news conference at Trump Tower, May 31, 2024, in New York. (AP)</figcaption><p>Donald Trump, in a recent statement, made it clear that fairness in trade is crucial, emphasizing that the United States will impose reciprocal tariffs on countries like India that impose high tariffs on American goods.</p><ul><li>Trump plans to implement tariffs equivalent to those charged by other nations on US exports.</li><li>He expressed that if India charges a 100% tariff on US products, the US will respond similarly.</li><li>His comments were aimed at highlighting inequities in trade practices between the US and countries like India and Brazil.</li></ul><blockquote>“Reciprocal. If they tax us, we tax them the same amount,” Trump stated.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Trump's administration is likely to continue focusing on ensuring equitable trade practices and considering reciprocity in tariff policies, which may shape future US-India trade relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/donald-trumps-message-to-india-over-high-tariffs-they-tax-us-we-tax-them-101734481055748.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/donald-trumps-message-to-india-over-high-tariffs-they-tax-us-we-tax-them-101734481055748.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:58:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why bring religion into the armed forces, ex-servicemen organisation poses questions to CDS and chiefs - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Veterans Question Religious Symbols in Armed Forces After Painting Removal</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 18, 2024 - <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ml93uy/article68993374.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/32_A_historical_memories_of_painting-1971_War_25_05_Del.jpg" alt="A historic photograph related to the 1971 war" title="A historic photograph related to the 1971 war">
<figcaption>A historical memory of painting at Defence Minister Manohar Parikkar’s office, showing Lt. Gen. A.A.K. Niazi of the Pakistan Army signing the surrender documents in Dacca on December 16, 1971.</figcaption>
<p>Veterans have expressed concerns over the introduction of religious themes in military symbols following the controversial removal of a historic painting commemorating the 1971 India-Pakistan war from the Army chief's lounge.</p>
<ul>
<li>Brigadier Inder Mohan Singh from the IESL questioned the relevance of introducing religion in the armed forces.</li>
<li>The painting was replaced with a new artwork that included cultural symbols like Garuda and Krishna's chariot.</li>
<li>Mohan emphasized that the removal was seen as an attack on historical military heritage.</li>
<li>The new painting, 'Karam Kshetra - Field of Deeds', features modern military equipment along with historically significant imagery.</li>
<li>Mohan called to gift the historical painting to the IESL for preservation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“To finish photos which reflect history is an unpardonable act.” – Brigadier Inder Mohan Singh</blockquote>
<p>The discussion continues as veterans seek clarity on how these changes reflect the values and traditions of the armed forces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/why-bring-religion-into-the-armed-forces-ex-servicemen-organisation-poses-questions-to-cds-chiefs/article68997094.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/why-bring-religion-into-the-armed-forces-ex-servicemen-organisation-poses-questions-to-cds-chiefs/article68997094.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nitin Gadkari, Jyotiraditya Scindia among MPs playing truant despite Lok Sabha whip - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MPs Defying Lok Sabha Whip: Nitin Gadkari and Jyotiraditya Scindia Under Scrutiny</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>An overview of significant absences among MPs Nitin Gadkari and Jyotiraditya Scindia despite party mandates in the Lok Sabha.</p><ul><li>Nitin Gadkari and Jyotiraditya Scindia criticized for not attending key sessions.</li><li>The Lok Sabha whip requires attendance for important votes.</li><li>Concerns raised regarding the discipline and accountability of MPs.</li></ul><blockquote>“Absenteeism undermines the democratic process and the responsibilities of elected officials.”</blockquote><p>This trend highlights a growing issue of accountability among elected representatives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/nitin-gadkari-jyotiraditya-scindia-among-mps-playing-truant-despite-lok-sabha-whip/articleshow/116413696.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/nitin-gadkari-jyotiraditya-scindia-among-mps-playing-truant-despite-lok-sabha-whip/articleshow/116413696.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rs 14,000 crore returned to banks from Mallya assets sales: FM Nirmala Sitharaman - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rs 14,000 crore returned to banks from Mallya assets sales: FM Nirmala Sitharaman</h1><p><strong>Publication Date & Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a significant financial development, Indian Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman announced that ₹14,000 crore has been returned to banks through the sale of assets linked to businessman Vijay Mallya. This repayment represents a crucial step in addressing the financial misconduct associated with Mallya's dealings.</p><ul><li>The amount recovered is part of the ongoing efforts to compensate banks affected by Mallya's business failures.</li><li>These asset sales have helped in mitigating some of the financial losses incurred.</li><li>The government remains committed to bolstering financial accountability and transparency.</li></ul><blockquote>“The recovery of ₹14,000 crore is a testament to our resolve against financial wrongdoing,” said Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman.</blockquote><p>The recovery of these funds marks a notable achievement in the Indian government's efforts to combat financial corruption and restore asset value to banks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/rs-14000-crore-returned-to-banks-from-mallya-assets-sales-fm-nirmala-sitharaman/articleshow/116412680.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/rs-14000-crore-returned-to-banks-from-mallya-assets-sales-fm-nirmala-sitharaman/articleshow/116412680.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 22:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avoidable: Supreme Court Collegium to Allahabad HC judge on his remarks against Muslims - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Collegium Advises Allahabad HC Judge on Controversial Remarks</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<p>The Supreme Court Collegium, led by Chief Justice Sanjiv Khanna, addressed Justice Shekhar Kumar Yadav's controversial statements regarding Muslims made at a recent event, emphasizing that these remarks were avoidable.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The meeting with Justice Yadav lasted about 30 minutes.</li>
  <li>Yadav's remarks have spurred opposition calls for his impeachment due to accusations of hate speech.</li>
  <li>He framed the debate about the Uniform Civil Code in a contentious manner, contrasting reforms in Hindu practices with the Muslim stance.</li>
  <li>Justice Yadav expressed views that Islam lacks the seeds of tolerance that Hinduism possesses.</li>
  <li>Opposition figures have criticized Yadav's remarks, raising concerns about justice for minority communities.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“No litigant can hope for justice in a court in which a member holds such a biased, prejudiced, publicly expressed opinion against the minority community.” - Brinda Karat</blockquote>
<p>The remarks, while attracting significant backlash, have raised questions about the impartiality of judicial members and their ability to administer justice fairly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/avoidable-supreme-court-collegium-to-justice-yadav-on-his-remarks-against-muslims-9730849/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/avoidable-supreme-court-collegium-to-justice-yadav-on-his-remarks-against-muslims-9730849/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 22:30:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani deal under bribery scrutiny was approved against officials' advice - Reuters India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/india/adani-deal-under-bribery-scrutiny-was-approved-against-officials-advice-2024-12-17/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/india/adani-deal-under-bribery-scrutiny-was-approved-against-officials-advice-2024-12-17/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 22:17:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Noida Authority CEO Punishes Staff To Stand And Work For 20 Minutes After Elderly Man Made To Wait - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxON2NwTHZsZ0VXTnhnejY4MVp3dUpSYXU2bDlISWtqdEx0M0dXWU5Id2hxUndaYXBmU3lHMkZRU0VEU09jcDZlUXFzVjRwSTM2dk1YS0w3bklfWmplYVIzSkh1X0w0MlkxUGZWXzFvTVd5bXA2SUE3eVkxTnQxQ09Lb3lOWEtKclBucjBJZ1ZMSXFOUFJCQlNyWExCSzBjTHdSbDdUY3NTa3c0RUpPcGZzaW13dHZjcWxxTnVjcGhGVlhreTZicUJUM3pWU1IySWJBdzBSNmdiY9IB3AFBVV95cUxOMWlTbUJzVS1zdk1sREtTcE56dDFDVHQzZWtqRU4zQ19ma2FmMjg2OWZ1TFJsdWJVYlFUdXdQTUlZQXAtY3hPekhYRWNfZkg1cGUzZWRLdHhoRC1QMjFFRlFoUWhva25Jb3lnZmVrMXVqSm05VFdPSjZ3c1JkRnFkUWxhTVZUeFVQRmJYdThOZVd1UFRFWm1Ydk1OUkxGNG5PRm5QeWZscHZqMkNfQlYzQk5VOC1vZDFwcjltUWk2UDUtNGNPV0U5MjA1bmF1LWdLMHgycHlnd255YWYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxON2NwTHZsZ0VXTnhnejY4MVp3dUpSYXU2bDlISWtqdEx0M0dXWU5Id2hxUndaYXBmU3lHMkZRU0VEU09jcDZlUXFzVjRwSTM2dk1YS0w3bklfWmplYVIzSkh1X0w0MlkxUGZWXzFvTVd5bXA2SUE3eVkxTnQxQ09Lb3lOWEtKclBucjBJZ1ZMSXFOUFJCQlNyWExCSzBjTHdSbDdUY3NTa3c0RUpPcGZzaW13dHZjcWxxTnVjcGhGVlhreTZicUJUM3pWU1IySWJBdzBSNmdiY9IB3AFBVV95cUxOMWlTbUJzVS1zdk1sREtTcE56dDFDVHQzZWtqRU4zQ19ma2FmMjg2OWZ1TFJsdWJVYlFUdXdQTUlZQXAtY3hPekhYRWNfZkg1cGUzZWRLdHhoRC1QMjFFRlFoUWhva25Jb3lnZmVrMXVqSm05VFdPSjZ3c1JkRnFkUWxhTVZUeFVQRmJYdThOZVd1UFRFWm1Ydk1OUkxGNG5PRm5QeWZscHZqMkNfQlYzQk5VOC1vZDFwcjltUWk2UDUtNGNPV0U5MjA1bmF1LWdLMHgycHlnd255YWYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 21:03:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court collegium ticks off HC judge Shekhar Kumar Yadav for his speech at VHP event - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court collegium ticks off HC judge Shekhar Kumar Yadav for his speech at VHP event</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [date not provided]<strong>Source:</strong> [source not provided]</p><p>This article discusses the Supreme Court collegium's reprimand of High Court judge Shekhar Kumar Yadav due to his recent speech at a VHP event, raising concerns about judicial impartiality.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court collegium criticized judge Shekhar Kumar Yadav.</li><li>The speech in question was made at a VHP event, which has implications for judicial ethics.</li><li>This action signifies the collegium's commitment to maintaining the integrity of the judiciary.</li></ul><blockquote>“Judges must uphold the law impartially and without bias.”</blockquote><p>The Supreme Court's response underscores its oversight role in ensuring judges remain unbiased in their public engagements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/supreme-court-collegium-ticks-off-hc-judge-shekhar-kumar-yadav-for-his-speech-at-vhp-event/articleshow/116412546.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/supreme-court-collegium-ticks-off-hc-judge-shekhar-kumar-yadav-for-his-speech-at-vhp-event/articleshow/116412546.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 20:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi remains India’s most polluted city for second day in a row; GRAP Stage IV restrictions kick in - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi remains India’s most polluted city for second day in a row; GRAP Stage IV restrictions kick in</h1><p><strong>Published: December 18, 2024 - Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/o7y685/article68998605.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/AIR%20POLLUTION%20STANDALONE_17_12_9.jpg" alt="A thick layer of smog covered the Yamuna river, as according to the Commission for Air Quality Management (CAQM), Delhi’s air quality has worsened further on Tuesday (December 17, 2024), with levels again breaching the 400 mark and falling into the ‘severe’ category." /><figcaption>A thick layer of smog covered the Yamuna river, according to the CAQM.</figcaption><p>Delhi's air quality has deteriorated significantly, making it the most polluted city in India for two consecutive days. The Central Pollution Control Board (CPCB) has issued warnings about the health impacts of this severe pollution.</p><ul><li>Delhi's air quality index (AQI) reached severe levels, recording a measure of 401 at 10 p.m. on December 6, 2024.</li><li>The AQI is on a scale of 0-500, where 401-450 is 'severe'.</li><li>Pollution levels are attributed to stubble burning, vehicular emissions, and stagnant weather conditions.</li><li>Stage IV of the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) has been implemented, limiting construction activities and older vehicles.</li><li>Pollution is expected to stay high with PM2.5 levels at 251.5 micrograms per cubic meter, exceeding WHO's safe limit.</li></ul><blockquote>“Severe-level air pollution affects healthy people and seriously impacts those with existing diseases.” - CPCB</blockquote><p>The ongoing pollution crisis in Delhi is prompting renewed calls for action and greater awareness of air quality issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/delhi-remains-indias-most-polluted-city-for-second-day-in-a-row/article68997223.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/delhi-remains-indias-most-polluted-city-for-second-day-in-a-row/article68997223.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 19:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['One Nation, One Election' bill introduced in Lok Sabha, Opposition demands withdrawal - The New Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>One Nation, One Election Bill Introduced Amidst Opposition Demands for Withdrawal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 17 Dec 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The New Indian Express</p><p>Union Law Minister Arjun Ram Meghwal introduced the 'One Nation, One Election' bill, seeking to hold simultaneous Lok Sabha and state assembly elections, facing strong opposition urging its withdrawal.</p><ul><li>Introduction of the Constitution (One Hundred and Twenty-Ninth Amendment) Bill, 2024, and the Union Territories Laws (Amendment) Bill, 2024.</li><li>First-time use of electronic voting in the Lok Sabha.</li><li>269 members in favor and 198 against during the introduction of the bills.</li><li>Opposition parties claim the bills are anti-democratic and violate the Constitution.</li><li>Support from NDA allies, but uncertainty from fence-sitters.</li></ul><blockquote>“Beyond the seventh schedule of the Constitution is the basic structured doctrine and that basic structure doctrine spells out that there are certain features of the Indian Constitution which are beyond the amending power of this House also.” - Congress MP Manish Tewari</blockquote><p>The introduction of the ONOE bills marks a significant step towards electoral reform, yet faces a complex path filled with political contention and opposition scrutiny.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/nation/2024/Dec/17/one-nation-one-election-bill-introduced-in-lok-sabha-opposition-demands-withdrawal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newindianexpress.com/nation/2024/Dec/17/one-nation-one-election-bill-introduced-in-lok-sabha-opposition-demands-withdrawal</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 19:38:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chennai Weather: Heavy Rain Likely In Chennai For 2 Days, Orange Alert In 4 TN Districts - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chennai Weather: Heavy Rain Likely In Chennai For 2 Days, Orange Alert In 4 TN Districts</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Weather warning in Chennai" title="The impact of this system is likely to persist until the day after tomorrow, with rain continuing in many parts of Chennai on December 20. (News18 Tamil)"><figcaption>The impact of this system is likely to persist until the day after tomorrow, with rain continuing in many parts of Chennai on December 20. (News18 Tamil)</figcaption><p>The Indian Meteorological Department (IMD) has issued a weather warning for Chennai due to a low-pressure area in the Bay of Bengal. The effects are expected to last for several days.</p><ul><li>A low-pressure area has formed over the South Bay of Bengal.</li><li>An orange alert has been issued for very heavy rainfall in several districts.</li><li>Heavy rain is expected in Chennai and surrounding areas on December 17 and 18.</li><li>The rain is likely to intensify on December 19 and continue until December 20.</li><li>Chennai, Chengalpattu, Tiruvallur, and Puducherry are among the districts affected.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Meteorological Department warns of very heavy rainfall on Tuesday and expects rainfall to begin around 1 pm, intensifying throughout the day."</blockquote><p>This weather condition is significant for the affected areas, with warnings issued to prepare for potential heavy rainfall impacts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/chennai-weather-imd-tamil-nadu-weather-heavy-rains-low-pressure-cyclone-bay-of-bengal-ws-b-9158714.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/chennai-weather-imd-tamil-nadu-weather-heavy-rains-low-pressure-cyclone-bay-of-bengal-ws-b-9158714.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 18:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘BJP Ended One Nation, Two Constitutions’: JP Nadda On J&K During Rajya Sabha Debate - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Ends One Nation, Two Constitutions Policy in J&K: JP Nadda</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 17, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="BJP chief JP Nadda addresses Rajya Sabha on Tuesday. (Screengrab/ANI)"><figcaption>BJP chief JP Nadda addresses Rajya Sabha on Tuesday. (Screengrab/ANI)</figcaption></figure><p>During a debate in the Rajya Sabha, Union Minister JP Nadda highlighted that the BJP-led government has ended the policy of one nation, two constitutions in Jammu and Kashmir. He criticized the Congress for its historical decisions and emphasized the importance of constitutional amendments.</p><ul><li>Nadda stated that 106 laws passed by Parliament were not applicable to J&K under the previous policy.</li><li>He invoked Sardar Patel and criticized the Congress for its historical handling of Jammu and Kashmir.</li><li>Nadda invited Congress to mark the 50th anniversary of the Emergency imposed in India.</li><li>He argued against the practice of triple talaq in the context of Islamic nations.</li><li>The debate continues in the Rajya Sabha following significant discussions in the Lok Sabha on constitutional significance.</li></ul><blockquote>“The then Home Minister Sardar Patel was given the work of uniting the country and I was very happy that after a long time, I heard the name of Sardar Patel from the Congress side too.” - JP Nadda</blockquote><p>This debate reflects ongoing political tensions in India regarding the interpretation and application of constitutional provisions in varying contexts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/bjp-ended-one-nation-two-constitution-jp-nadda-on-jk-during-samvidhan-debate-in-rajya-sabha-9158876.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/bjp-ended-one-nation-two-constitution-jp-nadda-on-jk-during-samvidhan-debate-in-rajya-sabha-9158876.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 18:29:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GRAP-4: Delhi-NCR Schools To Go Hybrid For All Classes Except Grades 10, 12 - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GRAP-4: Delhi-NCR Schools To Go Hybrid For All Classes Except Grades 10, 12</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Schools In Delhi NCR to go hybrid for all classes except for grade 10 and 12. (Representative Image)" title="Schools In Delhi NCR to go hybrid for all classes except for grade 10 and 12. (Representative Image)"><figcaption>Schools In Delhi NCR to go hybrid for all classes except for grade 10 and 12. (Representative Image)</figcaption></figure><p>Schools in Delhi-NCR will shift to hybrid classes, combining online and physical attendance for most grades, due to severe air quality issues.</p><ul><li>Classes VI to IX and XI will now be hybrid as part of the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) Stage 4.</li><li>Decision triggered by alarming Air Quality Index levels surpassing 400.</li><li>Schools in districts like Gurugram, Faridabad, and Ghaziabad are included in this mandate.</li><li>Despite guidelines, some Noida schools are reportedly not following the hybrid directive and are still conducting in-person classes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Noida schools are very much offline; they have not declared hybrid classes.” - Ayesha Singh, Parent</blockquote><p>The hybrid model aims to ensure safety and continuity of education amid worsening air quality in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/education-career/grap-4-delhi-ncr-schools-to-go-hybrid-for-all-classes-except-grades-10-12-9158719.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/education-career/grap-4-delhi-ncr-schools-to-go-hybrid-for-all-classes-except-grades-10-12-9158719.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:57:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCP's Chhagan Bhujbal Out Of Cabinet, Opposition Lends A Shoulder - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxONWlGNVNiejN4ckhSeE9lOHluRC1qU0w1VGM4dUN6ME5GZkdzd3B5eUNNRUF0LWZKRWF2bjlSc0liR0RUUWh0UEJCbWNOUzVhY3k2N3YtMWNFM1NfSXhmVzZ4dHZ0RVdnaUt3RDQ3aDh6bHhaZVZ6bXFtSEFoUmNJblFRMk1mV3VFUlQ3Wnd1clZ1eUMtQURrRmZoRXB2MGJBbUhSaUtB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxONWlGNVNiejN4ckhSeE9lOHluRC1qU0w1VGM4dUN6ME5GZkdzd3B5eUNNRUF0LWZKRWF2bjlSc0liR0RUUWh0UEJCbWNOUzVhY3k2N3YtMWNFM1NfSXhmVzZ4dHZ0RVdnaUt3RDQ3aDh6bHhaZVZ6bXFtSEFoUmNJblFRMk1mV3VFUlQ3Wnd1clZ1eUMtQURrRmZoRXB2MGJBbUhSaUtB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:47:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>