<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:28:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:28:37 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Can't Speak Kannada? Come To Delhi": CEO's Hiring Post Sparks Controversy - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxNMFlrYmlxUFRkNUthMllHT1N6d0l2azk0ZTltX2FUeDFOQ2VoR0M1ak1FUDg1c1l5S3Jub05SYTh5dGVHNG9ZNTJfRzlaX2VuOXF3ZmsweHVXYldIdlpJTkIyWVZCbVBaeDJWSEdxRlN5anc3YlBQUUJpbTNLcFdnaWE2RVFZSHZrUENpU2d5aWdlcDZrbUtkaXFYZi14MHRHbXg1WTZFNnREakZ2ck9qdmFEeDgwM3czVmZ5TnluSGhUY3pYSmNJR9IB0AFBVV95cUxQWFVZR3Zaem1ZWmRuLXdzVVNtMVdjY0xCU09PY1NIcnZNWDJpNWdER3J6RGJtSThmc0NKeHUxWms4M1p2bTFMYkxzcTNXZzZGaENWQjdQNzAwWlBsTE40ek1MUm5KLVljWUJ4RVFaRnAtdnAyV0VSUENGUHJ1OUo5UDVMcU04dF9MQ1hiVENXVEVDUHcwR2xiN1dOWElGaGRYU0lBN05Nb2N2VDdyN2xLbzN2NS1NeGFHT2Z0dW5sdGtkOVAtclJFZ0FtWGNNM0dv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxNMFlrYmlxUFRkNUthMllHT1N6d0l2azk0ZTltX2FUeDFOQ2VoR0M1ak1FUDg1c1l5S3Jub05SYTh5dGVHNG9ZNTJfRzlaX2VuOXF3ZmsweHVXYldIdlpJTkIyWVZCbVBaeDJWSEdxRlN5anc3YlBQUUJpbTNLcFdnaWE2RVFZSHZrUENpU2d5aWdlcDZrbUtkaXFYZi14MHRHbXg1WTZFNnREakZ2ck9qdmFEeDgwM3czVmZ5TnluSGhUY3pYSmNJR9IB0AFBVV95cUxQWFVZR3Zaem1ZWmRuLXdzVVNtMVdjY0xCU09PY1NIcnZNWDJpNWdER3J6RGJtSThmc0NKeHUxWms4M1p2bTFMYkxzcTNXZzZGaENWQjdQNzAwWlBsTE40ek1MUm5KLVljWUJ4RVFaRnAtdnAyV0VSUENGUHJ1OUo5UDVMcU04dF9MQ1hiVENXVEVDUHcwR2xiN1dOWElGaGRYU0lBN05Nb2N2VDdyN2xLbzN2NS1NeGFHT2Z0dW5sdGtkOVAtclJFZ0FtWGNNM0dv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:12:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session Day 21 Live Updates: Rajya Sabha resume; on last day of Winter Session, Lok Sabha adjourned ‘sine die’ amid Centre-Oppn uproar - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament Winter Session Day 21 Live Updates: On last day of Winter Session, both Houses adjourned ‘sine die’ amid Centre-Oppn uproar</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 21, 2024 | Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/parliament_03039a.jpg?w=640" alt="Parliament Winter Session Day 21 Live Updates: lok sabha, rajya sabha" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Parliament Winter Session Day 21 Live Updates: Members in the Lok Sabha during the Winter session of Parliament, in New Delhi. (PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>On the final day of the Winter Session of Parliament, both Houses were adjourned sine die shortly after reconvening amidst a faceoff between the Centre and Opposition MPs, related to protests over comments made about B R Ambedkar.</p><ul><li>The Lok Sabha adopted a resolution referring bills on simultaneous elections to a joint parliamentary committee.</li><li>Protests in Parliament led to a scuffle involving Opposition and BJP MPs.</li><li>Two BJP MPs were reportedly injured during the confrontations.</li></ul><blockquote>“In a decisive move aimed at maintaining decorum, Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla issued instructions that no political party or groups of MPs will be allowed to hold any protest at the gates of Parliament House.”</blockquote><p>This session's conclusion highlights ongoing tensions between political parties in India, particularly concerning the treatment of historical figures like Dr B R Ambedkar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/parliament-winter-session-day-21-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-bjp-congress-9735436/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/parliament-winter-session-day-21-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-bjp-congress-9735436/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:01:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Haryana CM Om Prakash Chautala passes away in Gurugram - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Former Haryana CM Om Prakash Chautala passes away in Gurugram</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> HT News Desk</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/om_prakash_chautala_1734678150981_1734678151186.jpg" alt="Former Haryana Chief Minister Om Prakash Chautala after casting his vote for the Haryana Assembly elections, at a polling station in Chautala village in Sirsa on Oct 5(ANI)"><figcaption>Former Haryana Chief Minister Om Prakash Chautala after casting his vote for the Haryana Assembly elections, at a polling station in Chautala village in Sirsa on Oct 5(ANI)</figcaption><p>Om Prakash Chautala, the former chief minister of Haryana and Indian National Lok Dal (INLD) supremo, passed away at the age of 89 due to a cardiac arrest.</p><ul><li>Chautala was last seen publicly during Haryana's Assembly elections held on October 5, 2024.</li><li>He was the son of former Deputy Prime Minister Chaudhary Devi Lal and served as Haryana's chief minister multiple times.</li><li>Chautala had a controversial political career, including jail time related to a disproportionate assets case.</li><li>He is survived by three daughters and two sons, with notable political figures in his family.</li></ul><blockquote>“Om Prakash Chautala was a prominent political figure whose career encompassed significant controversies and achievements.”</blockquote><p>His passing marks the end of an era in Haryana politics, reflective of his father’s legacy and his lengthy career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/former-haryana-cm-om-prakash-chautala-passes-away-in-gurugram-101734678003812.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/former-haryana-cm-om-prakash-chautala-passes-away-in-gurugram-101734678003812.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:01:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[52 kg gold, Rs 10 crore cash seized by IT linked to Lokayukta raid on ex-RTO constable and associate - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>52 kg gold, Rs 10 crore cash seized by IT linked to Lokayukta raid on ex-RTO constable and associate</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>In a significant operation, the Indian Tax authorities seized 52 kg of gold and Rs 10 crore in cash linked to a Lokayukta raid involving a former RTO constable and his associate.</p><ul><li>Seizure includes 52 kg of gold.</li><li>Cash amounting to Rs 10 crore was also confiscated.</li><li>The operation is linked to allegations against a former RTO constable.</li></ul><blockquote>“This operation highlights the ongoing efforts to combat corruption and illegal wealth accumulation.”</blockquote><p>The raid marks a critical step in addressing corruption within public services.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/massive-seizure-in-it-raids-52-kg-gold-over-rs-10-crore-cash-found-in-abandoned-vehicle-in-bhopal/articleshow/116491497.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/massive-seizure-in-it-raids-52-kg-gold-over-rs-10-crore-cash-found-in-abandoned-vehicle-in-bhopal/articleshow/116491497.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament LIVE | Lok Sabha adjourned sine die; RS proceedings under way - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament LIVE | Stormy Winter Session Ends with Both Houses Adjourned Sine Die</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 20 December 2024, 03:02 IST</p><p>The Winter Session of Parliament concluded with both the Lok Sabha and Rajya Sabha adjourned sine die amidst protests and controversies, including issues around B R Ambedkar and the introduction of a joint committee to examine election bills.</p><ul><li>Lok Sabha adjourned amid protests from opposition and treasury benches.</li><li>Speaker Om Birla directed members against demonstrations at Parliament gates.</li><li>Resolution for a joint committee on 'one nation, one election' was presented.</li><li>Rajya Sabha also adjourned sine die, reflecting on session productivity of 40.03%.</li><li>Opposition leaders boycotted a customary meeting with the Speaker.</li></ul><blockquote>“As we conclude the session, coinciding with the 75th anniversary of our constitution, we face a moment of serious reflection.”</blockquote><p>This session has been marked by significant tensions and the clear divide between the ruling and opposition parties.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/parliament-live-updates-news-bjp-narendra-modiamit-shah-rahul-gandhi-congress-mallikarjun-kharge-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-opposition-om-birla-jagdeep-dhankhar-winter-session-3325878</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/parliament-live-updates-news-bjp-narendra-modiamit-shah-rahul-gandhi-congress-mallikarjun-kharge-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-opposition-om-birla-jagdeep-dhankhar-winter-session-3325878</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:31:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DND flyway to remain toll-free; Supreme Court dismisses appeal against HC order - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>DND flyway to remain toll-free; Supreme Court dismisses appeal against HC order</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source]</p><p>The Supreme Court has upheld a decision by the High Court, ensuring that the DND flyway will remain toll-free. This decision is significant for commuters in the region.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court dismissed an appeal regarding the toll status of the DND flyway.</li><li>This ruling is expected to benefit daily commuters traveling via this route.</li><li>The decision reinforces the earlier High Court verdict regarding tolls on the DND flyway.</li></ul><blockquote>This decision is a victory for the residents and commuters of the area.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the ruling by the Supreme Court marks a vital moment for traffic regulation and public accessibility in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/dnd-flyway-to-remain-toll-free-supreme-court-dismisses-appeal-against-hc-order/articleshow/116491963.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/dnd-flyway-to-remain-toll-free-supreme-court-dismisses-appeal-against-hc-order/articleshow/116491963.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Andhra Woman Opens Parcel, Finds Man's Body And Letter Demanding Rs 1.3 Crore - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/andhra-pradesh-news/andhra-woman-opens-electrical-appliances-delivery-finds-dead-body-7291341</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/andhra-pradesh-news/andhra-woman-opens-electrical-appliances-delivery-finds-dead-body-7291341</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:46:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Toll Be Reimposed On Delhi-Noida (DND) Flyway? What Supreme Court Said - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQM0JzR0ZGMnR4VFV0ZkNmcVFKVkZHWVJKRjdhMmx2RHNwc1JUOFhTejhNWU1TN21lelJtNkFXY1lYS2tPOTB0UUxBckJIQktJT1VyV2h2RUN1T2RKb2oxZkZReGRGUkxMYzJ0NnpXRkJERlRXR1pwd0xjWU1sRXpiVWtRQUFvdkxvbGMxM3RvYVJKdDAtYVpma3ZIaHdLeUl4cDlxX1Zmbm44NlY5VE5yaWtR0gG6AUFVX3lxTE12akEtV210SjNEbkw5U2ZqZ1NuSTFLQWtXYll1dEFxdnRjQnluUUtKVksyWmJRWnRBVmpKOHF0U1kwTXRXMHp5UWRiUHVmSUlaU0MweU9LaHhwcHREaVNXbE5iN1lGQ2J3QmJsU0xUQ3ktOGN6Xzg5VUNMUG1WWEZhMlRPWGN0ZV9PYVBSQ3ktSk10OFdKUzk5TjdNdEpZMlZtUklZTktuSXJ6ODJnUGdyWF92WjdlcG5hQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQM0JzR0ZGMnR4VFV0ZkNmcVFKVkZHWVJKRjdhMmx2RHNwc1JUOFhTejhNWU1TN21lelJtNkFXY1lYS2tPOTB0UUxBckJIQktJT1VyV2h2RUN1T2RKb2oxZkZReGRGUkxMYzJ0NnpXRkJERlRXR1pwd0xjWU1sRXpiVWtRQUFvdkxvbGMxM3RvYVJKdDAtYVpma3ZIaHdLeUl4cDlxX1Zmbm44NlY5VE5yaWtR0gG6AUFVX3lxTE12akEtV210SjNEbkw5U2ZqZ1NuSTFLQWtXYll1dEFxdnRjQnluUUtKVksyWmJRWnRBVmpKOHF0U1kwTXRXMHp5UWRiUHVmSUlaU0MweU9LaHhwcHREaVNXbE5iN1lGQ2J3QmJsU0xUQ3ktOGN6Xzg5VUNMUG1WWEZhMlRPWGN0ZV9PYVBSQ3ktSk10OFdKUzk5TjdNdEpZMlZtUklZTktuSXJ6ODJnUGdyWF92WjdlcG5hQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:41:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Seven dead, many injured in massive LPG tanker explosion on Jaipur-Ajmer Highway, 40 vehicles burnt - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Eight Dead in Massive LPG Tanker Explosion on Jaipur-Ajmer Highway</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent Incident<br><strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/jaipur-blast-1734662905.webp" alt="Jaipur explosion" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Screen grab shows thick smoke emerging out of the explosion site.</figcaption><p>A tragic LPG tanker explosion on the Jaipur-Ajmer Highway resulted in eight fatalities and numerous injuries. The incident caused extensive damage, engulfing approximately 40 vehicles in flames.</p><ul><li>The explosion occurred early Friday morning after a collision between an LPG tanker and a truck.</li><li>39 individuals received treatment at SMS Hospital for severe burn injuries.</li><li>Over 20 fire engines responded to the scene to control the blaze.</li><li>The Rajasthan Chief Minister visited the injured at the hospital and expressed condolences on social media.</li><li>Rescue operations successfully saved people trapped in their vehicles, including a passenger bus.</li></ul><blockquote>“Deeply saddened to hear the news of casualties in the gas tanker fire incident on the Jaipur-Ajmer National Highway.” - CM Bhajanlal Sharma</blockquote><p>This devastating incident highlights the dangers associated with transporting hazardous materials and the urgent need for safety measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/rajasthan/massive-tanker-explosion-near-jaipur-dps-school-vehicles-burnt-casualties-2024-12-20-967112</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/rajasthan/massive-tanker-explosion-near-jaipur-dps-school-vehicles-burnt-casualties-2024-12-20-967112</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:21:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka Deputy CM Shivakumar rules out any interference in police action against BJP leader Ravi - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka Deputy CM Shivakumar Comments on Police Action Against BJP Leader</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 20 December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p>
<p>Karnataka Deputy Chief Minister D K Shivakumar stated that there will be no interference in the police action against BJP leader C T Ravi, who was arrested for allegedly using derogatory language against Minister Laxmi Hebbalkar.</p>
<ul>
<li>Shivakumar referred to Ravi as having a "filthy mouth" and criticized his past behavior.</li>
<li>Ravi has accused the police of violating his human rights after being taken on rounds following his arrest.</li>
<li>Shivakumar commented on BJP leaders meeting Ravi at the police station, questioning the appropriateness of such a meeting.</li>
<li>A case was registered against Ravi under sections related to sexual harassment and insult to modesty based on a complaint by Minister Hebbalkar.</li>
<li>Shivakumar offered to release audio or video evidence of the incident if the media did not possess it.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is not new for him (Ravi). He had used words against several people in the past...” – D K Shivakumar</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights the tensions between political parties in Karnataka, particularly regarding the use of language and accountability among public officials.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/karnataka-deputy-cm-shivakumar-rules-out-any-interference-in-police-action-against-bjp-leader-ravi-3326041</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/karnataka-deputy-cm-shivakumar-rules-out-any-interference-in-police-action-against-bjp-leader-ravi-3326041</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:09:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Not Acceptable": RSS Chief Frowns Upon New Temple-Mosque Disputes - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxNN2I5QlZzdnFrWkE1Q0pYbzJPaFBxUjJBemRrRnpKQnlhdXJGbGdhMDlPMFpEVXhyQTV5eFBtcmZ0LUU5WEthN1JJNUZnTk11SDc0NWVfZ2dGUkFPUUJNc2I3Z0w0NUpiOV9IUDdPem1XVjFfdzNxMkJfRUx0aldVTVBGNjA3TWdEM0c3T01VU0pQRVdhU0xFUGxtMlVIZEFEcjBGcU1MY09lSnJpTFlwc19B0gG6AUFVX3lxTE9vXzk5VzY5QWU2UmJXbFl4NnRORC1GTVRtS3FwRDhVR2dKVV81NHdxSFRWWDhZcHgxY2tiSUhGSkNOQ21ILVJTVHltMHZPeVFyM3F5ejRyeHZyT3dBZ3NKTG50ZWpYMDUtZG4xS0piaEM2RC1yU01MY0pUVlBfSFRmcVpPZ09FMmZEdnVuSWxCTnpSZ1pwVU0yb0xtRERtNGVjNXBKbGs4V2ZieVVYY2tPUFE4Tmh3QndlZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxNN2I5QlZzdnFrWkE1Q0pYbzJPaFBxUjJBemRrRnpKQnlhdXJGbGdhMDlPMFpEVXhyQTV5eFBtcmZ0LUU5WEthN1JJNUZnTk11SDc0NWVfZ2dGUkFPUUJNc2I3Z0w0NUpiOV9IUDdPem1XVjFfdzNxMkJfRUx0aldVTVBGNjA3TWdEM0c3T01VU0pQRVdhU0xFUGxtMlVIZEFEcjBGcU1MY09lSnJpTFlwc19B0gG6AUFVX3lxTE9vXzk5VzY5QWU2UmJXbFl4NnRORC1GTVRtS3FwRDhVR2dKVV81NHdxSFRWWDhZcHgxY2tiSUhGSkNOQ21ILVJTVHltMHZPeVFyM3F5ejRyeHZyT3dBZ3NKTG50ZWpYMDUtZG4xS0piaEM2RC1yU01MY0pUVlBfSFRmcVpPZ09FMmZEdnVuSWxCTnpSZ1pwVU0yb0xtRERtNGVjNXBKbGs4V2ZieVVYY2tPUFE4Tmh3QndlZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 04:14:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP leader C.T. Ravi likely to be produced before Special Court in Bengaluru - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Leader C.T. Ravi to Appear Before Special Court in Bengaluru</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png" alt="BJP MLC C.T. Ravi files a complaint against unidentified supporters of Minister Lakshmi Hebbalkar and others at the Khanapur police station." title="BJP MLC C.T. Ravi files a complaint against unidentified supporters of Minister Lakshmi Hebbalkar and others at the Khanapur police station."><figcaption>Photo Credit: Special arrangement</figcaption><p>BJP MLC C.T. Ravi, arrested for making derogatory remarks about Minister Lakshmi Hebbalkar, is expected to appear in court today, following protests against his treatment by the police.</p><ul><li>C.T. Ravi was arrested on December 19, 2024, after allegedly insulting Minister Laxmi Hebbalkar.</li><li>Following his arrest, there were protests by Ravi against the police actions.</li><li>Ravi accused the police of conspiracy and assault, while authorities refuted his claims.</li><li>He faces charges of sexual assault and outraging a woman's modesty.</li><li>There is public unrest surrounding his arrest, with BJP supporters gathering to support him.</li></ul><blockquote>“The police commissioner and other officers have taken the law in their own hands,” said BJP MLA Basanagouda Patil Yatnal.</blockquote><p>The case surrounding C.T. Ravi's remarks has caused significant political tension and public demonstrations in Karnataka, indicating ongoing issues within local governance and law enforcement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/bjp-leader-ct-ravi-likely-to-be-taken-to-bengaluru/article69007530.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/bjp-leader-ct-ravi-likely-to-be-taken-to-bengaluru/article69007530.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 03:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Decode Politics: From ‘alarm’ to ‘adoration’, how RSS, BJP evolved in their view of B R Ambedkar - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Decode Politics: From ‘alarm’ to ‘adoration’, how RSS, BJP evolved in their view of B R Ambedkar</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/BJP-Ambedkar.jpg?w=640" alt="Ambedkar" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>BJP MPs stage a protest alleging insult of Dr B R Ambedkar by the Congress party, at Parliament complex in New Delhi on Thursday. (Photo: PTI)</figcaption>
<p>The ongoing political dynamics in India have spotlighted the BJP's shifting stance towards Dr. B R Ambedkar, especially amidst recent tensions in Parliament regarding remarks made by Union Home Minister Amit Shah.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The recent showdown in Parliament highlights the BJP's evolving stance on Ambedkar.</li>
  <li>The BJP seeks to attract all Hindu castes, including Dalits, into its political fold.</li>
  <li>The party’s engagement with Ambedkar is described as politically expedient, especially in competition with the weakened Congress.</li>
  <li>Ambedkar's history as a critic of the caste system complicates his place within Hindu nationalist politics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The BJP has attempted to bring all Hindu castes, including Dalits, under the fold of Hindutva — constantly redefining its position on Ambedkar.”</blockquote>
<p>This transformation in the BJP's approach to Ambedkar reflects broader changes in India's political landscape and the party’s strategy to unify diverse groups under its ideology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/rss-bjp-ambedkar-parliament-protests-9735500/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/rss-bjp-ambedkar-parliament-protests-9735500/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:58:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jaipur fire: 5 dead, 37 injured in fire after truck carrying chemical collides with other vehicles - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jaipur fire: 5 dead, 37 injured in fire after truck carrying chemical collides with other vehicles</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/baycxm/article69008005.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_20_2024_000082A.jpg" alt="Firefighters douse the fire at the site of the accident after a truck loaded with a chemical collided with some other vehicles and caught fire on the Jaipur-Ajmer Highway in Jaipur on Friday (December 20, 2024)." />
<figcaption>Firefighters douse the fire at the site of the accident after a truck loaded with a chemical collided with other vehicles.</figcaption>
<p>A deadly collision involving a gas tanker and multiple vehicles turned a stretch of the Jaipur-Ajmer highway into an inferno, resulting in the deaths of seven people and injuring over 35. The incident occurred on Friday morning, December 20, 2024.</p>
<ul>
<li>Collision involved a gas tanker and multiple vehicles.</li>
<li>Eyewitnesses reported flames visible from nearly a kilometer away.</li>
<li>Seven confirmed dead, with reports suggesting that others might have been trapped inside vehicles.</li>
<li>Chief Minister and Health Minister visited the hospital where the injured were treated.</li>
<li>Green corridor established for quick transportation of victims.</li>
<li>Prime Minister announced ex-gratia compensation for victims' families.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Deeply saddened by the loss of lives in the accident on Jaipur-Ajmer highway in Rajasthan.” - PM Modi</blockquote>
<p>The incident has raised concerns about safety measures and emergency responses on highways, emphasizing the need for thorough investigations and measures to prevent such tragedies in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rajasthan/truck-carrying-chemical-hits-other-vehicles-catches-fire-on-jaipur-ajmer-highway-police/article69007509.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rajasthan/truck-carrying-chemical-hits-other-vehicles-catches-fire-on-jaipur-ajmer-highway-police/article69007509.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Several feared dead, vehicles burnt in massive fire at Jaipur CNG pump - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxPSWg3UEJhUXZXa0lXcGxmbkZ0WUVid2lWNWZSVjJOUE9aR01KaGF0SGZ5SF9kVWtHaXlCeldnZTlsTUo5Q1hpMF9BY2d4QWFNbk5hNmJhQ1FkSG1LTlcwcU5OdVZBVmRfdXllZndEbFIteVl6eGtNZTNLTzJsN1NaZ09hbWVuZ21RZmNlNzJ4VTM5NDd2VTFDaUhJVG9pUGhNaVgzcHdENEJudWFyZ25iSkFSZ0JSUUhpZEpZRnpQbFE5SnFlMnBTVjNBMU5JMmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxPSWg3UEJhUXZXa0lXcGxmbkZ0WUVid2lWNWZSVjJOUE9aR01KaGF0SGZ5SF9kVWtHaXlCeldnZTlsTUo5Q1hpMF9BY2d4QWFNbk5hNmJhQ1FkSG1LTlcwcU5OdVZBVmRfdXllZndEbFIteVl6eGtNZTNLTzJsN1NaZ09hbWVuZ21RZmNlNzJ4VTM5NDd2VTFDaUhJVG9pUGhNaVgzcHdENEJudWFyZ25iSkFSZ0JSUUhpZEpZRnpQbFE5SnFlMnBTVjNBMU5JMmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:43:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Delhi police caught rape accused from Gujarat after a 1,500-km chase - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Police Chase Rape Accused Across 1,500 km to Gujarat</h1><p><strong>Dec 20, 2024 08:11 AM IST - Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Police-outside-Cambridge-School-in-Srinivaspuri-in_1734108262228_1734662320203.jpg" alt="The police have also recovered a mobile phone containing explicit videos and photos used for blackmail.(File Photo)" title="The police have also recovered a mobile phone containing explicit videos and photos used for blackmail.(File Photo)"><figcaption>The police have also recovered a mobile phone containing explicit videos and photos used for blackmail.(File Photo)</figcaption><p>The Delhi Crime Branch arrested a 25-year-old man accused of rape from Surat in Gujarat after an extensive 1,500-km chase.</p><ol><li>The accused, Kuldeep, had been absconding since the registration of the case.</li><li>He allegedly administered an intoxicating substance and committed sexual assault while capturing explicit photos and videos.</li><li>These recordings were used to blackmail the victim, coercing her into further physical relations.</li><li>Kuldeep, a resident of Bawana, Delhi, was eventually arrested in Surat, Gujarat.</li><li>The police recovered a mobile phone containing explicit videos and photos used for blackmail and sextortion.</li></ol><blockquote>"The complainant, an employee in Bagwan Pura, had been befriended by the accused while working together. Under the pretext of trust, he administered an intoxicating substance and committed sexual assault while capturing explicit photos and videos. He used these recordings to blackmail the victim, coercing her into further physical relations." - Delhi Police</blockquote><p>The arrest highlights the efficiency and persistence of the Delhi police in tracking down criminals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/how-delhi-police-caught-rape-accused-from-gujarat-after-a-1-500-km-chase-101734662082888.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/how-delhi-police-caught-rape-accused-from-gujarat-after-a-1-500-km-chase-101734662082888.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:41:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi's overall air quality remains ‘severe’, AQI over 450 in some areas - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi's Air Quality Remains ‘Severe’, AQI Over 450 in Some Areas</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 08:05 AM IST, Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/delhi_air_quality_aqi_1734661750870_1734661751122.jpg" alt="Commuters make their way through an old iron bridge on a smoggy winter morning in New Delhi on December 19, 2024. (AFP)"><figcaption>Commuters make their way through an old iron bridge on a smoggy winter morning in New Delhi on December 19, 2024. (AFP)</figcaption><p>Delhi's air quality on Thursday plunged into the 'severe plus' category, with a 24-hour average AQI of 451 recorded at 4 pm, according to CPCB data.</p><ul><li>The overall AQI at around 8 am on Friday in Delhi stood at 434 - what the CPCB classifies as the severe category. Of the 35 monitoring stations listed on the government's Sameer app, Rohini, RK Puram, Sirifort, Dwarka Sector 8, Wazirpur were among those that recorded an AQI of over 450.</li><li>As per the CPCB, an AQI between 0 and 50 is considered 'good,' 51-100 'satisfactory,' 101-200 'moderate,' 201-300 'poor,' 301-400 'very poor,' 401-450 'severe,' and above 450 'severe plus.'</li><li>On Thursday, the city saw dangerously high levels of PM2.5, the primary pollutant, with 32 of the 35 monitoring stations recording air quality in the severe plus category. Some areas recorded AQI readings as high as 470. The PM2.5 particles, measuring 2.5 micrometers or less in diameter, pose significant health risks as they can penetrate deep into the lungs when inhaled.</li></ul><blockquote>Delhi remains under Stage IV of the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP), which includes the most stringent anti-pollution measures. The measures involve a complete ban on construction activities and the entry of non-essential polluting trucks into the city.</blockquote><p>The Indian Meteorological Department (IMD) had issued a yellow alert for Friday, warning of very dense fog in some areas. The maximum temperature on Thursday was recorded at 23 degrees Celsius, slightly above the season's normal, while the minimum temperature was five degrees Celsius, three notches below normal, as per IMD.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhis-overall-air-quality-remains-severe-aqi-over-450-in-some-areas-101734659783501.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhis-overall-air-quality-remains-severe-aqi-over-450-in-some-areas-101734659783501.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:33:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FIR against Rahul Gandhi is diversionary tactic in response to his protest against Amit Shah: Congress - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Claims FIR Against Rahul Gandhi is a Diversionary Tactic</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/j9azzp/article69007497.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241219287L.jpg" alt="New Delhi, Dec 19 (ANI): Leader of Opposition in Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi in a conversation with Congress MP KC Venugopal during a press conference, at Congress HQ in New Delhi on Thursday. (ANI Photo/Rahul Singh)"><figcaption>New Delhi, Dec 19 (ANI): Leader of Opposition in Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi in a conversation with Congress MP KC Venugopal during a press conference, at Congress HQ in New Delhi on Thursday. (ANI Photo/Rahul Singh)</figcaption><p>The Congress party has alleged that the FIR against Rahul Gandhi is merely a distraction from his protests against Home Minister Amit Shah's remarks regarding B.R. Ambedkar.</p><ul><li>Congress general secretary K.C. Venugopal stated the FIR serves as a diversionary tactic from Gandhi's protests.</li><li>Venugopal reiterated that defending Ambedkar's legacy is an honor for Gandhi.</li><li>Delhi Police has registered an FIR against Rahul Gandhi amidst political tension between Congress and BJP.</li></ul><blockquote>The FIR against Shri <a href="https://twitter.com/RahulGandhi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RahulGandhi</a> ji is nothing but a diversionary tactic in response to his staunch protest against the Home Minister. — K C Venugopal (@kcvenugopalmp)</blockquote><p>The situation reflects ongoing conflict and accusations of political vendetta among parties.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/fir-against-rahul-gandhi-is-diversionary-tactic-in-response-to-his-protest-against-amit-shah-congress/article69007492.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/fir-against-rahul-gandhi-is-diversionary-tactic-in-response-to-his-protest-against-amit-shah-congress/article69007492.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who Gave Permit For Trial Run? Cops Ask Navy In Mumbai Boat Tragedy - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Boat Tragedy: Cops Investigate Navy's Trial Run</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9i4sjb1o_mumbai-ferry-tragedy-pti-_625x300_19_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="Who Gave Permit For Trial Run? Cops Ask Navy In Mumbai Boat Tragedy"><figcaption>Investigation into the Mumbai boat tragedy that resulted in 14 fatalities.</figcaption><p>An Indian Navy boat lost control and crashed into a ferry, resulting in the deaths of 14 individuals and several injuries during a busy maritime route trial run.</p><ul><li>The incident involved an Indian Navy boat conducting trials that crashed into a ferry.</li><li>The collision occurred on a busy route to Elephanta Island, raising questions about permission for the trial.</li><li>The police are investigating the protocols followed during the trial.</li><li>A Board of Inquiry has been instituted by the Navy to investigate the collision.</li><li>Life jackets have been made mandatory for all boat rides from the Gateway of India.</li><li>Search operations continue for a seven-year-old boy still missing from the incident.</li></ul><blockquote>The toll in the accident increased to 14, with ongoing search efforts for a missing child.</blockquote><p>The tragic incident has prompted an investigation into safety protocols and maritime regulations to prevent future accidents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/who-gave-permit-for-trial-run-cops-ask-navy-in-mumbai-boat-tragedy-7290342</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/who-gave-permit-for-trial-run-cops-ask-navy-in-mumbai-boat-tragedy-7290342</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:25:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Dead, Many Critical In Huge Jaipur Fire As 2 Trucks Collide Outside Petrol Pump - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/jaipur-news/several-feared-dead-many-vehicles-damaged-due-to-fire-outside-jaipur-petrol-pump-7290340</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/jaipur-news/several-feared-dead-many-vehicles-damaged-due-to-fire-outside-jaipur-petrol-pump-7290340</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:21:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Dead, 35 Hurt In Huge Jaipur Fire As 2 Trucks Collide Outside Petrol Pump - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Dead, 35 Hurt In Huge Jaipur Fire As 2 Trucks Collide Outside Petrol Pump</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="5 Dead, 35 Hurt In Huge Jaipur Fire As 2 Trucks Collide Outside Petrol Pump" alt="5 Dead, 35 Hurt In Huge Jaipur Fire As 2 Trucks Collide Outside Petrol Pump" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/29jig628_jaipur-petrol-pump-fire_625x300_20_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>Fire engulfs trucks after a collision outside a petrol pump.</figcaption><p>A catastrophic fire broke out in Jaipur due to a truck collision early this morning, resulting in at least five fatalities and 35 injuries.</p><ul><li>The fire started around 5:30 AM on Ajmer Road after a CNG tanker caught fire.</li><li>Many vehicles were destroyed, with reports of several drivers suffering from severe burns.</li><li>The explosion from the fire was audible from as far as 10 kilometers away.</li><li>Chief Minister Bhajanlal Sharma has visited the hospital to oversee treatment for the injured.</li><li>Rescue operations are ongoing, with victims being transported to medical facilities.</li></ul><blockquote>"I pray to God to grant the departed souls a place in his supreme abode, give the bereaved families strength to bear this immense loss, and provide speedy recovery to the injured." — Bhajanlal Sharma</blockquote><p>This tragic incident highlights the dangers of road transport and the need for stringent safety measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/jaipur-news/several-feared-dead-many-vehicles-damaged-due-to-fire-outside-jaipur-petrol-pump-7290340</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/jaipur-news/several-feared-dead-many-vehicles-damaged-due-to-fire-outside-jaipur-petrol-pump-7290340</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:21:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Several Feared Dead, Many Vehicles Burnt In Fire Outside Jaipur Petrol Pump - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQOHFNMU5fdFhCOXVYUWU3ekE3RmhZdWFjVTdjVnNveWk4SGFGYmJHeDRma2syZUwxX1c5NVRPVEVSX2RWdDNyWlhPMUxXenJ5dnJVeWlhZXlqTFN1QVdHbzF2bUtseDU4bjZ6cmpTeVktMUg5ODNqTm51QldSVjZKTWpNdmV3bktqOTIzMUxyb01UbFQwY2hCZ3RpOGdNb2hidDZjVU50bW92S1lBcThLODlCN1hNaDB4OGdWamx3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQOHFNMU5fdFhCOXVYUWU3ekE3RmhZdWFjVTdjVnNveWk4SGFGYmJHeDRma2syZUwxX1c5NVRPVEVSX2RWdDNyWlhPMUxXenJ5dnJVeWlhZXlqTFN1QVdHbzF2bUtseDU4bjZ6cmpTeVktMUg5ODNqTm51QldSVjZKTWpNdmV3bktqOTIzMUxyb01UbFQwY2hCZ3RpOGdNb2hidDZjVU50bW92S1lBcThLODlCN1hNaDB4OGdWamx3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:21:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Human Error’ Behind 2021 Chopper Crash That Killed CDS Bipin Rawat, His Wife, 11 Others: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/human-error-behind-2021-chopper-crash-that-killed-cds-bipin-rawat-his-wife-11-others-report-9162329.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/human-error-behind-2021-chopper-crash-that-killed-cds-bipin-rawat-his-wife-11-others-report-9162329.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:11:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Human error’ caused Gen Bipin Rawat's chopper crash on December 8, 2021- Here's what parliamentary panel report said | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/gen-bipin-rawat-death-did-human-error-cause-chopper-crash-on-december-8-2021-report-says-11734659711878.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/gen-bipin-rawat-death-did-human-error-cause-chopper-crash-on-december-8-2021-report-says-11734659711878.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai boat tragedy: Survivor claims Navy boat driver was 'showing off', contests claims of engine failure - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Boat Tragedy: Survivor Alleges Navy Driver Was Showing Off</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Dec 20, 2024, HT News Desk</p><p>In a tragic incident off the Mumbai coast, a survivor of the boat accident has contested the Navy's claim of engine failure, stating that the speedboat driver was 'showing off' before the collision.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The Navy speedboat collided with the ferry Neel Kamal, resulting in 14 deaths.</li><li>Survivor Gaurav Gupta claimed the driver was 'in a playful mood' and zig-zagging through waters.</li><li>Many passengers on the ferry were not wearing life jackets at the time of the accident.</li><li>Gupta's aunt was among those who perished during the tragedy.</li></ul><blockquote>"It felt like a display... his stunt ended in tragedy," said survivor Gaurav Gupta.</blockquote><p>This incident raises serious concerns about safety protocols and accountability in naval operations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mumbai-boat-tragedy-survivor-claims-navy-boat-driver-was-showing-off-contests-claims-of-engine-failure-101734655858383.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mumbai-boat-tragedy-survivor-claims-navy-boat-driver-was-showing-off-contests-claims-of-engine-failure-101734655858383.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 01:13:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress says FIR against Rahul Gandhi for 'defending Ambedkar's legacy': ‘Badge of honour’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Defends Rahul Gandhi Amid FIR Over Parliament Scuffle</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Rahul_Gandhi_1734654032763_1734654033078.jpg" alt="Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi during a press conference at AICC Headquarters in New Delhi on December 19, 2024.(PTI)" title="Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi during a press conference at AICC Headquarters in New Delhi on December 19, 2024.(PTI)">
<figcaption>Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi during a press conference at AICC Headquarters in New Delhi on December 19, 2024.(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>The Congress party has labeled the FIR against Rahul Gandhi, related to a scuffle in Parliament, as a diversionary tactic from the BJP following his protests against Amit Shah's comments on BR Ambedkar.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Congress claims the FIR is a reaction to Gandhi's firm stance on Ambedkar's legacy.</li>
  <li>KC Venugopal described the FIR as a “badge of honour”.</li>
  <li>Two BJP MPs were injured during the Parliament incident, leading to the complaint against Gandhi.</li>
  <li>Congress is demanding action against BJP MPs for their conduct during the scuffle.</li>
  <li>The controversy occurred during protests over Amit Shah's remarks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A case against him for defending Babasaheb’s legacy is a badge of honour.” - KC Venugopal</blockquote>
<p>This situation underscores ongoing tensions between Congress and the BJP, particularly regarding how Parliament is being managed and the protection of civil rights within it.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-parliament-scuffle-fir-bjp-ambedkar-amit-shah-101734652805254.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-parliament-scuffle-fir-bjp-ambedkar-amit-shah-101734652805254.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:29:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘This is shameful’: SC criticises 3,000 tonne shortfall in treatment of Delhi’s solid waste - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Criticizes Delhi's 3,000 Tonne Solid Waste Treatment Shortfall</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 19, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/The-Supreme-Court---File-_1734630362796.jpg" alt="The Supreme Court. (File)" title="The Supreme Court. (File)">
<figcaption>The Supreme Court. (File)</figcaption>
<p>The Supreme Court has described as “shameful” the fact that nearly 3,000 tonnes of solid waste generated daily in Delhi remains untreated, highlighting serious issues with the government’s waste management compliance.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Supreme Court criticized the Delhi government and the Municipal Corporation of Delhi (MCD) for failing to manage solid waste properly.</li>
  <li>Approximately 11,000 tonnes of solid waste is generated daily in Delhi, with 3,000 tonnes remaining untreated.</li>
  <li>The court summoned the Delhi chief secretary for clarification on compliance with the Solid Waste Management Rules, 2016.</li>
  <li>Concerns were raised regarding the lack of accurate data and inadequate responses regarding waste processing capacity.</li>
  <li>Illegally dumped waste in sites like Ghazipur and Bhalswa poses serious environmental and health risks.</li>
  <li>The court warned that failure to improve waste management may lead to halting developmental activities in the future.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“With some degree of sadness, we record that more than 3000 tonnes of solid waste remains untreated every day.”</blockquote>
<p>The Supreme Court's criticism reflects deep concerns over pollution and public health in Delhi, urging immediate government action to resolve the solid waste crisis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/delhi-news/this-is-shameful-sc-criticises-3-000-tonne-shortfall-in-treatment-of-delhi-s-solid-waste-101734630366265.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/delhi-news/this-is-shameful-sc-criticises-3-000-tonne-shortfall-in-treatment-of-delhi-s-solid-waste-101734630366265.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 23:42:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IAF chopper that crashed with Gen Rawat was due to human error of aircrew, House panel report - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Human Error Blamed for IAF Chopper Crash that Killed Gen Rawat, House Report Reveals</h1><p><strong>Published on: December 20, 2024</strong></p><p><strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/lzl4r1/article69006599.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_19_2024_000520B.jpg" alt="Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat. File." title="Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat. File."><figcaption>Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat. File. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>The Mi-17 chopper crash that led to the death of Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat has been attributed to human error, according to a report by the Parliamentary standing committee on defence.</p><ul><li>The crash occurred on December 8, 2021, during a flight from Sulur to Wellington.</li><li>Out of 34 helicopter crashes in the 2017-22 period, 19 were due to human error.</li><li>The IAF emphasizes that there was no mechanical failure or sabotage involved.</li></ul><blockquote>“The accident was a result of entry into clouds due to unexpected change in weather conditions...”</blockquote><p>The report indicates that corrective measures have been enacted to reduce future risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/gen-bipin-rawat-death-human-error-behind-december-8-chopper-crash/article69006598.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/gen-bipin-rawat-death-human-error-behind-december-8-chopper-crash/article69006598.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 23:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Human error’ behind Dec 8 chopper crash that killed Gen. Bipin Rawat: parliamentary panel report - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Human error’ behind Dec 8 chopper crash that killed Gen. Bipin Rawat: parliamentary panel report</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 20, 2024</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/lzl4r1/article69006599.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_19_2024_000520B.jpg" alt="Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat. File." title="Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat. File."><figcaption>Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat. File. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>The parliamentary report revealed that the tragic crash of Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat's helicopter on December 8, 2021, was due to human error. The report tabled in Parliament also highlighted the total number of Indian Air Force aircraft crashes during the 13th Defence Plan.</p><ul><li>The Mi-17 V5 helicopter crash led to the death of Gen Rawat, his wife, and other armed forces personnel.</li><li>A total of 34 Indian Air Force crashes were reported during the mentioned period, including nine in 2021-22.</li><li>The report noted that human error (aircrew) was cited as the cause for the Mi-17 crash.</li><li>The defence ministry indicated that all necessary inquiries have been conducted along with remedial measures to prevent recurrence.</li></ul><blockquote>The ministry also informed that the recommendations by these Inquiry committees review the process, procedure, training, equipment, culture, operations, maintenance and administration holistically with intent to prevent recurrence of an accident.</blockquote><p>This report emphasizes the need for stringent protocol and reviews in aviation safety within the armed forces to prevent such tragedies in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/gen-bipin-rawat-death-human-error-behind-december-8-chopper-crash/article69006598.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/gen-bipin-rawat-death-human-error-behind-december-8-chopper-crash/article69006598.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 23:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't rake up Ram temple-like issues elsewhere: RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/dont-rake-up-ram-temple-like-issues-elsewhere-rss-chief-mohan-bhagwat/articleshow/116485537.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/dont-rake-up-ram-temple-like-issues-elsewhere-rss-chief-mohan-bhagwat/articleshow/116485537.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 23:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>