<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 12:37:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 12:37:59 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pune woman stabbed by colleague in office parking as bystanders watch - Video - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pune Woman Stabbed by Colleague in Office Parking</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 12, 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>A woman in Pune was stabbed by a colleague in the office parking lot, with multiple bystanders witnessing the incident.</p><ul><li>The attack occurred during work hours.</li><li>Bystanders did not intervene during the stabbing.</li><li>The assailant was taken into custody.</li><li>Victim is receiving medical treatment.</li></ul><blockquote>Witnesses reported feeling helpless as the incident unfolded.</blockquote><p>This incident raises concerns about workplace safety and bystander intervention in violent situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pune-woman-stabbed-by-colleague-in-office-parking-as-bystanders-watch-video/articleshow/117085886.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pune-woman-stabbed-by-colleague-in-office-parking-as-bystanders-watch-video/articleshow/117085886.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 11:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AIIMS CRE Group B & C Online Form 2025 - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMic0FVX3lxTE42c2Vwa3plS3RPMkZXVmRTTmRpSHlodGdZa3hMTXFOczdGV005TjA2YjZSaW9SSlhZbzZxQTUwcGVleTBaWldBN3VFMmpYeEl2b2NzN2pmRWdBUXBGVTNRVFBUNUVlbndXdzBzZkRTMjVtdjQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMic0FVX3lxTE42c2Vwa3plS3RPMkZXVmRTTmRpSHlodGdZa3hMTXFOczdGV005TjA2YjZSaW9SSlhZbzZxQTUwcGVleTBaWldBN3VFMmpYeEl2b2NzN2pmRWdBUXBGVTNRVFBUNUVlbndXdzBzZkRTMjVtdjQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 11:40:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal asks EC to bar Parvesh Verma from Delhi election, 'raid his house' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Demands Action Against BJP's Parvesh Verma Ahead of Delhi Elections</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 09, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/ANI-20250109079-0_1736422386009_1736422399219.jpg" alt="Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) national convener Arvind Kejriwal addresses a press conference.(ANI)" title="Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) national convener Arvind Kejriwal addresses a press conference.(ANI)">
<figcaption>Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) national convener Arvind Kejriwal addresses a press conference.(ANI)</figcaption>
<p>Arvind Kejriwal, chief of the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP), has called for the Election Commission to bar BJP candidate Parvesh Verma from the Delhi assembly elections, citing allegations of corrupt practices.</p>
<ul>
<li>Kejriwal accuses Verma of distributing money and organizing job camps in violation of election rules.</li>
<li>He urges for an investigation into fake voter registrations and cancellations in the constituency.</li>
<li>Kejriwal alleges a broader scheme involving fake applications from individuals purportedly in their names.</li>
<li>The Delhi assembly elections are set for February 5, with vote counting on February 8.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The BJP candidate in the New Delhi Assembly constituency, Parvesh Verma, is organising job camps, openly distributing money... These things come under corrupt practices.” - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote>
<p>The AAP leader emphasizes the need for action from the Election Commission to ensure fair electoral practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/arvind-kejriwal-asks-ec-to-bar-parvesh-verma-from-delhi-election-raid-his-house-101736422138989.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/arvind-kejriwal-asks-ec-to-bar-parvesh-verma-from-delhi-election-raid-his-house-101736422138989.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 11:33:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal wants inclusion of Delhi Jats in Central OBC list, BJP questions timing - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Demands Inclusion of Delhi Jats in OBC List Amidst Political Tensions</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 09, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/Arvind_Kejriwal_1736413999211_1736413999476.jpg" alt="Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) chief Arvind Kejriwal addresses a press conference, in New Delhi, Thursday.(Manvender Vashist Lav/PTI)" /><figcaption>Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) chief Arvind Kejriwal addresses a press conference, in New Delhi, Thursday.(Manvender Vashist Lav/PTI)</figcaption><p>Aam Aadmi Party convenor Arvind Kejriwal has called for the inclusion of Delhi's Jat community in the Centre's Other Backward Classes (OBC) list, questioning the discrepancy in reservation rights between Delhi Jats and those from Rajasthan.</p><ul><li>Kejriwal accused the Central government of misleading the Jat community for the past decade.</li><li>He highlighted promises made by BJP leaders regarding OBC inclusion, which remain unfulfilled.</li><li>Kejriwal noted that Jat students from Delhi face barriers in securing admission to Delhi University due to lack of OBC status.</li><li>He emphasized the need for inclusion to ensure job and college admission reservations for Delhi's Jat community.</li><li>The BJP responded, questioning Kejriwal's sudden interest in the Jat community ahead of elections.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is nothing but betrayal. The Centre must include Delhi's Jat community in the OBC list.” - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote><p>The ongoing political discourse surrounding the demand emphasizes the importance of the upcoming Delhi assembly elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/arvind-kejriwal-wants-inclusion-of-delhi-jats-in-central-obc-list-bjp-questions-timing-101736414010564.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/arvind-kejriwal-wants-inclusion-of-delhi-jats-in-central-obc-list-bjp-questions-timing-101736414010564.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:44:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pariksha Pe Charcha Registers Record-Breaking Participation In 8th Edition - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pariksha Pe Charcha Registers Record-Breaking Participation In 8th Edition</h1><p><strong>Date: January 2025</strong></p><p><strong>Source: NDTV</strong></p><p>This year's Pariksha Pe Charcha has garnered over 2.79 crore registrations, marking a significant milestone in its history. Students, teachers, and parents from across India are invited to engage with Prime Minister Modi.</p><ul><li>Over 2.79 crore registrations from across India and abroad.</li><li>Online registration runs from December 14, 2024, to January 14, 2025.</li><li>Participants can include students in classes 6 to 12, teachers, and parents.</li><li>The main event will take place at Bharat Mandapam, New Delhi.</li><li>Activities leading up to the event include indigenous games, marathons, and mental health workshops.</li></ul><blockquote>“Participants will have the opportunity to ask questions from the Prime Minister in the interactive programme.”</blockquote><p>The Pariksha Pe Charcha 2025 aims to alleviate exam stress and foster a collaborative conversation between students and the Prime Minister.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/education/pariksha-pe-charcha-registers-record-breaking-participation-in-8th-edition-7434757</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/education/pariksha-pe-charcha-registers-record-breaking-participation-in-8th-edition-7434757</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:39:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skeletons tumble out of Bengaluru tunnel road project reports, BBMP left red-faced - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxQdXZTV1pqVWp3RFJtRkNmVTZlOEhRM3lGWnBsMDBqUEFja25LYlg1NUFXMkZKWEVTdlY3VzNkcDBVc2xiemtxMlQ4dmNKeXExWm9mTG5IRWRxR3ZUZ3FHcEkyQ0JlazZPVE1ZdXVZRkdhdmJJZUNvZzR5SHBEVlpoQ1hrcnRGczJDX0ZhRTdPcHdEMVptZi0tT0Y1UnJ2S1k4WTNqUUFla0dXRTFPMXNWVmRzalVUX1hnRE9iTzJZTEFGZDdPZDd3amJiUlVwSWMy0gHWAUFVX3lxTFA2NmdJVHV1ck1haGl2UTJUM29zTEpnNFpFc251RVp1aU9DMFMzbG9yMjgybmNOb3Utd0dtT3BxS0h2aGRRWV9GM0wtR05pek1OeV9XazNzalRMWDlhcVdZcWtmQkV2VXU2SzRBWW03YnVyS0I2aWY0MG81QzFHUl9CUnM4TDBtTk5WUHpQODJLOXhwRzQ1ek0yQjZCQ1BzODVySU8xWWZNOGlkNlNxRGRSc3czVmMxWGlEMEsxVWpZenFsdUdEdVROTEFsRmVVS1h5Mmt5YXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxQdXZTV1pqVWp3RFJtRkNmVTZlOEhRM3lGWnBsMDBqUEFja25LYlg1NUFXMkZKWEVTdlY3VzNkcDBVc2xiemtxMlQ4dmNKeXExWm9mTG5IRWRxR3ZUZ3FHcEkyQ0JlazZPVE1ZdXVZRkdhdmJJZUNvZzR5SHBEVlpoQ1hrcnRGczJDX0ZhRTdPcHdEMVptZi0tT0Y1UnJ2S1k4WTNqUUFla0dXRTFPMXNWVmRzalVUX1hnRE9iTzJZTEFGZDdPZDd3amJiUlVwSWMy0gHWAUFVX3lxTFA2NmdJVHV1ck1haGl2UTJUM29zTEpnNFpFc251RVp1aU9DMFMzbG9yMjgybmNOb3Utd0dtT3BxS0h2aGRRWV9GM0wtR05pek1OeV9XazNzalRMWDlhcVdZcWtmQkV2VXU2SzRBWW03YnVyS0I2aWY0MG81QzFHUl9CUnM4TDBtTk5WUHpQODJLOXhwRzQ1ek0yQjZCQ1BzODVySU8xWWZNOGlkNlNxRGRSc3czVmMxWGlEMEsxVWpZenFsdUdEdVROTEFsRmVVS1h5Mmt5YXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:25:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Transfer Of Govt Employee On Request Can't Be Termed Transfer In Public Interest Or Administrative... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Transfer Of Govt Employee On Request Can't Be Termed Transfer In Public Interest Or Administrative Exigencies</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 11, 2024<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p>
<img src="https://www.livelaw.in/h-upload/2024/11/11/750x450_570708-supreme-court-sc-01.webp" alt="Transfer Of Govt Employee On Request Cant Be Termed Transfer In Public Interest Or Administrative Exigencies : Supreme Court" title="Transfer Of Govt Employee On Request Cant Be Termed Transfer In Public Interest Or Administrative Exigencies : Supreme Court">
<figcaption>Supreme Court ruling on the transfer of government employees.</figcaption>
<p>The Supreme Court has clarified that transfers based on employee requests cannot be classified as transfers in public interest, as they are not made in the interest of public administration.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Court stated that the government is the best judge of employee service utilization.</li>
  <li>Transfers on request are not based on public interest or administrative needs.</li>
  <li>The ruling impacts seniority claims within the Kerala Government service.</li>
  <li>Employees transferred via absorption retain their seniority in the previous department.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It cannot be disputed that the Government is the best judge to decide how to distribute and utilise the services of an employee...such transfer cannot be termed as transfer in public interest because it is on the request of the employee and not in the exigencies of the public administration.”</blockquote>
<p>This ruling emphasizes the distinction between voluntary transfers at an employee's request and those made in the public's interest.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/transfer-of-govt-employee-on-request-cant-be-termed-transfer-in-public-interest-or-administrative-exigencies-supreme-court-280431</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/transfer-of-govt-employee-on-request-cant-be-termed-transfer-in-public-interest-or-administrative-exigencies-supreme-court-280431</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:20:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tirupati stampede live: CM Chandrababu Naidu visits incident spot - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tirupati stampede live: CM Chandrababu Naidu visits incident spot</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 9, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/PTI01-09-2025-000008B-0_1736412881062_1736412892926.jpg" alt="Tirupati stampede live: Injured victims of a stampede at Lord Venkateswara Swamy temple, being treated at a hospital, in Tirupati, Andhra Pradesh, Thursday, Jan. 9, 2025." title="Tirupati stampede live: Injured victims of a stampede at Lord Venkateswara Swamy temple, being treated at a hospital, in Tirupati, Andhra Pradesh, Thursday, Jan. 9, 2025."><figcaption>Injured victims of the stampede at Tirupati Temple receiving treatment.</figcaption><p>At least six people were killed and many others injured during a stampede at Vishnu Nivasam in Tirupati as devotees jostled for tickets for the upcoming Vaikunta Dwara Darshan event.</p><ul><li>Andhra Pradesh Chief Minister Chandrababu Naidu visited the incident spot and expressed deep shock over the casualties.</li><li>The government has announced ₹25 lakh ex-gratia to the families of the deceased.</li><li>Tamil Nadu CM MK Stalin announced financial assistance of ₹2 lakh for the family of a victim from Tamil Nadu.</li><li>TTD board member Bhanu Prakash issued an apology to the devotees for the tragedy.</li></ul><blockquote>“For five minutes, we thought all of us were dead,” said a survivor reflecting on the horror of the incident.</blockquote><p>The freak accident highlights the need for better crowd control measures during major religious events. Ensuring safety for devotees is paramount to prevent such tragedies in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/tirupati-stampede-live-updates-deaths-injuries-vaikunta-dwara-darshanam-ticket-andhra-pradesh-101736355724734.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/tirupati-stampede-live-updates-deaths-injuries-vaikunta-dwara-darshanam-ticket-andhra-pradesh-101736355724734.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:20:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coach attendant, TTE thrash passenger onboard Amritsar-Katihar Express after 'booze party'; video goes vi - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Passenger Assaulted by Coach Attendant and TTE on Amritsar-Katihar Express After Alleged Alcohol Party</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>This article discusses an incident where a passenger was assaulted by a coach attendant and Ticket Examiner (TTE) onboard the Amritsar-Katihar Express following an alleged drunken celebration. The incident has sparked outrage on social media after a video of the event went viral.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The assault occurred during a booze party on the train.</li>
    <li>A video capturing the incident gained significant traction online.</li>
    <li>Witnesses reported the passenger's violent treatment by the coach attendant and TTE.</li>
    <li>The railway authorities are expected to investigate the incident.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This type of behavior is unacceptable on public transport, and we expect swift action from the authorities." - A concerned passenger</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights ongoing issues with passenger safety on trains and the need for stricter regulations regarding the conduct of train staff.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/coach-attendant-tte-thrash-passenger-onboard-amritsar-katihar-express-after-booze-party-video-goes-viral/articleshow/117080178.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/coach-attendant-tte-thrash-passenger-onboard-amritsar-katihar-express-after-booze-party-video-goes-viral/articleshow/117080178.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tirupati Darshan stampede: Nearly 1.20 lakh ‘Vaikunta Dwara Darshan’ tokens at Tirumala temple exhausted in whiff - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tirupati Darshan stampede: Nearly 1.20 lakh ‘Vaikunta Dwara Darshan’ tokens at Tirumala temple exhausted in whiff</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/andhra-pradesh/otkk3z/article69080109.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/10745_9_1_2025_13_58_52_1_IMG_20250109_WA0036.JPG" alt="Devotees moving in a queue at one of the Vaikunta Ekadasi token issue centres in Tirupati." title="Devotees moving in a queue at one of the Vaikunta Ekadasi token issue centres in Tirupati.">
<figcaption>Devotees moving in a queue at one of the Vaikunta Ekadasi token issue centres in Tirupati. Normalcy returned after the stampede and 1.20 lakh tokens were exhausted within a few hours.</figcaption>
<p>The Tirumala Tirupati Devasthanams (TTD) faced a tragic incident with a stampede claiming six lives as tokens for the ‘Vaikunta Dwara Darshan’ were exhausted in hours. This annual event holds significant importance for devotees.</p>
<ul>
<li>1.20 lakh tokens were released for the first three days of the event.</li>
<li>Tokens were available from multiple locations in Tirupati for the first time to accommodate residents.</li>
<li>Stampede led to early opening of token counters, causing confusion among devotees.</li>
<li>Historical trends show a preference for the first two days of darshan among devotees.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Normalcy returned after the stampede and 1.20 lakh tokens were exhausted within a few hours.”</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights the immense demand and risk associated with significant religious events drawing large crowds.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/120-lakh-vaikunta-dwara-darshan-tokens-exhausted-in-a-whiff/article69079948.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/120-lakh-vaikunta-dwara-darshan-tokens-exhausted-in-a-whiff/article69079948.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Protesting farmer consumes poison at Shambhu border, dies at Patiala hospital - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Farmer Dies After Consuming Poison During Protest at Shambhu Border</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a tragic incident, a farmer consumed poison during a protest at the Shambhu border and later died at a hospital in Patiala. This act has highlighted ongoing tensions surrounding farmer protests in the region.</p><ul><li>The farmer was participating in a protest against governmental policies.</li><li>The incident occurred at the Shambhu border, which has been a focal point for protests.</li><li>Officials report the farmer was hurriedly taken to a nearby hospital, where he succumbed to his condition.</li><li>The incident sparked outrage and calls for justice among protestors and farmer unions.</li></ul><blockquote>“We demand accountability from the government for the treatment of our farmers,” said a representative of the protesting farmers.</blockquote><p>This incident sheds light on the dire situation faced by farmers and the urgent need for dialogue and resolution of their grievances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/protesting-farmer-commits-suicide-at-shambhu-border-dies-at-patiala-hospital/articleshow/117080451.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/protesting-farmer-commits-suicide-at-shambhu-border-dies-at-patiala-hospital/articleshow/117080451.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J&K govt can’t fight with Centre; Omar is people’s CM: Farooq Abdullah responds to Aga Ruhullah - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNQ3ZHSm1PdnVMWl9hNElRZC1JNkR3d2VzQXZiYUVjdXE3YU5lT0xKeGZYbmVEdnE2WTlOWkhxVmRvX0gyTXZrUUp3R0FYZGZEX1k2ekcwU29WbVY3Zk13WHE5VkVFd24tM2V4LUhyYlI3SFN4NGx4ZDM0U1BveEZHYWlrcGJQOWJOVXBpRExTTXVWRExwd2lDZXFDRzJyaFJDMVpjLThJY2NXeTTSAa4BQVVfeXFMTTBmZHpvZ2NET002UTJJcGUxZ1A3UTAySHNNLUZFc24wcnExeG84a1lGcFFMT3BtNHQzYmIzbzFsZXpCc1ZlbE9lTHc2dUZ3UFpLNkduZlhlVC1ZN0VSZTl6R2JqU1Q0cW80ZUNMVTBBeTVuS1lZb0ZzU1pHblIwSHBfQlZ1eTQtVEJYNmhybnNWWldreGVXNy1rNUh2THlqWkJySGVrRU54N080V2Jn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNQ3ZHSm1PdnVMWl9hNElRZC1JNkR3d2VzQXZiYUVjdXE3YU5lT0xKeGZYbmVEdnE2WTlOWkhxVmRvX0gyTXZrUUp3R0FYZGZEX1k2ekcwU29WbVY3Zk13WHE5VkVFd24tM2V4LUhyYlI3SFN4NGx4ZDM0U1BveEZHYWlrcGJQOWJOVXBpRExTTXVWRExwd2lDZXFDRzJyaFJDMVpjLThJY2NXeTTSAa4BQVVfeXFMTTBmZHpvZ2NET002UTJJcGUxZ1A3UTAySHNNLUZFc24wcnExeG84a1lGcFFMT3BtNHQzYmIzbzFsZXpCc1ZlbE9lTHc2dUZ3UFpLNkduZlhlVC1ZN0VSZTl6R2JqU1Q0cW80ZUNMVTBBeTVuS1lZb0ZzU1pHblIwSHBfQlZ1eTQtVEJYNmhybnNWWldreGVXNy1rNUh2THlqWkJySGVrRU54N080V2Jn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:54:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Farmer, who attempted suicide at Shambhu border, dies at Patiala hospital - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Farmer Dies After Suicide Attempt at Shambhu Border</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 09, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/Farmers--under-the-banner-of-SKM--Non-Political--a_1736410568235_1736410579521.jpg" alt="Farmers protesting at Shambhu border" title="Farmers, under the banner of SKM (Non-Political) and Kisan Mazdoor Morcha, have been protesting at the Shambhu and Khanauri border points between Punjab and Haryana since February 13, after their march to Delhi was blocked by security forces. (PTI)(HT_PRINT)"><figcaption>Farmers protesting at Shambhu border</figcaption><p>A 55-year-old farmer protesting at the Shambhu border between Punjab and Haryana allegedly died by suicide, marking the second such incident at the protest site within three weeks. The farmer, from Pahuwind in Tarn Taran district, took this extreme step due to frustrations regarding unresolved issues despite ongoing protests for a minimum support price (MSP).</p><ul><li>The farmer attempted suicide at the Shambhu border.</li><li>He was later taken to Rajindra Hospital in Patiala where he died.</li><li>Another farmer had died by suicide just weeks prior due to distress over a leader’s health.</li><li>Farmer leaders warned of potential unrest if health issues persist among leaders.</li></ul><blockquote>“God forbid if anything untoward happens to Dallewal ji, then perhaps the situation may not remain under control of the Central government,” - Farmer leader Abhimanyu Kohar</blockquote><p>This incident highlights ongoing tensions at the protest sites and the urgent need for dialogue between farmers and the government.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/farmer-who-attempted-suicide-at-shambhu-border-dies-at-patiala-hospital-101736409821424.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/farmer-who-attempted-suicide-at-shambhu-border-dies-at-patiala-hospital-101736409821424.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:25:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I will fight poll from New Delhi only': Arvind Kejriwal dismisses reports of contesting from two seats - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal to Contest Only from New Delhi, Clarifies on Reports of Dual Candidacy</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Kejriwal" width="600" height="400">
<figcaption>Arvind Kejriwal at a press event</figcaption>
<p>Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal has unequivocally stated that he will only be contesting the upcoming elections from the New Delhi constituency, dismissing rumors about running from two seats.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kejriwal confirmed his sole candidacy for New Delhi.</li>
  <li>He emphasized the importance of focusing on one constituency for effective campaigning.</li>
  <li>The clarification comes in response to speculations regarding dual candidacy.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I have always contested from New Delhi, and I will continue to do so. There is no question of contesting from multiple seats."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Kejriwal remains committed to representing New Delhi in the elections, aiming for a focused and effective campaign without spreading his efforts across multiple constituencies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/i-will-fight-poll-from-new-delhi-only-arvind-kejriwal-dismisses-reports-of-contesting-from-two-seats/articleshow/117076771.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/i-will-fight-poll-from-new-delhi-only-arvind-kejriwal-dismisses-reports-of-contesting-from-two-seats/articleshow/117076771.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Really worrisome: Supreme Court on Allahabad High Court functioning - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Raises Concerns Over Allahabad High Court's Case Listings</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 09 Jan 2025, 7:52 am</p><div><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justice Surya Kant and Justice N Kotiswar Singh" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Justice Surya Kant and Justice N Kotiswar Singh</figcaption></div><p>The Supreme Court expressed worry about the operations of the Allahabad High Court regarding case listings during a hearing related to a property dispute involving Uttar Pradesh MLA Abbas Ansari.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court is concerned about how cases are being listed at the Allahabad High Court.</li><li>Justice Surya Kant stated significant issues exist with filing and listing of cases.</li><li>Abbas Ansari's plea highlighted a lack of timely hearings for his property dispute.</li><li>Previous directives to the High Court to expedite the hearing were not followed.</li><li>The Supreme Court ordered status quo at the site in question until the High Court hears Ansari's plea.</li></ul><blockquote>“If high courts do this, where does the citizen go?” - Kapil Sibal</blockquote><p>The Supreme Court's concern highlights ongoing issues within the High Court, urging immediate action for the sake of justice.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/really-worrisome-supreme-court-allahabad-high-court-functioning</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/really-worrisome-supreme-court-allahabad-high-court-functioning</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:52:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[19 years, 1 wedding photo, and AI: Kerala’s chilling triple murder mystery solved - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/19-years-1-wedding-photo-and-ai-kerala-s-chilling-triple-murder-mystery-solved-101736408070616.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/19-years-1-wedding-photo-and-ai-kerala-s-chilling-triple-murder-mystery-solved-101736408070616.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:43:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Wind up alliance’: Omar Abdullah on Tejashwi Yadav's ‘INDIA bloc limited to 2024 polls’ remark - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Omar Abdullah Reacts to Tejashwi Yadav's Remarks on INDIA Bloc's Future</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 09, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/Omar_Abdullah_1736406422680_1736406422987.jpg" alt="Jammu and Kashmir chief minister Omar Abdullah.(Mohammad Amin War/ANI file photo)" title="Jammu and Kashmir chief minister Omar Abdullah.(Mohammad Amin War/ANI file photo)"><figcaption>Jammu and Kashmir chief minister Omar Abdullah.(Mohammad Amin War/ANI file photo)</figcaption><p>Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah responded to RJD leader Tejashwi Yadav's comments regarding the INDIA bloc's limitations concerning the upcoming Lok Sabha elections.</p><ul><li>Tejashwi Yadav indicated that the INDIA bloc's purpose is primarily to defeat the BJP in the 2024 elections.</li><li>Omar Abdullah stated that there has been no formal leadership or agenda established for the bloc, questioning its future beyond the elections.</li><li>He emphasized that the alliance shouldn't just exist for the elections, hinting at the need for clarity and active participation from member parties.</li></ul><blockquote>“As far as I remember, there was no time limit to the INDIA alliance.” - Omar Abdullah</blockquote><p>Abdullah urged the Congress party to justify its leadership within the INDIA bloc, highlighting that their collaboration should extend beyond just the upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/wind-up-alliance-omar-abdullah-on-tejashwi-yadavs-india-bloc-limited-to-2024-polls-remark-101736405065543.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/wind-up-alliance-omar-abdullah-on-tejashwi-yadavs-india-bloc-limited-to-2024-polls-remark-101736405065543.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:20:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru techie suicide: Wife Nikita Singhania reveals son’s location in Supreme Court hearing - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru Techie's Son's Location Revealed in Supreme Court Hearing</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 09, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/The-Supreme-Court-of-India--Amal-KS-HT-PHOTO-_1733979800810_1736407083875.jpg" alt="The Supreme Court of India (Amal KS/HT PHOTO)">
<figcaption>The Supreme Court of India (Amal KS/HT PHOTO)</figcaption>
<p>The Supreme Court was informed about the location of a four-year-old boy in a custody battle after the suicide of his father, Atul Subhash. His mother, Nikita Singhania, revealed he is at a boarding school in Faridabad, Haryana.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The child is currently at a boarding school in Faridabad, Haryana.</li>
  <li>The Supreme Court is hearing a custody petition filed by Atul’s mother.</li>
  <li>Atul Subhash died by suicide on December 9, 2024, leaving behind a note accusing his wife’s family of harassment.</li>
  <li>Nikita Singhania was granted bail and assured the court of the child's well-being.</li>
  <li>The Karnataka High Court declined to quash a criminal complaint against Nikita regarding abetting Atul's suicide.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The child has one surviving parent. His grandmother, while well-meaning, is not the natural guardian.” - Supreme Court Bench</blockquote>
<p>This case highlights the complexities surrounding family disputes and the impact of personal tragedies on custody arrangements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/bengaluru-news/bengaluru-techie-suicide-wife-nikita-singhania-reveals-son-s-location-in-supreme-court-hearing-101736406839073.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/bengaluru-news/bengaluru-techie-suicide-wife-nikita-singhania-reveals-son-s-location-in-supreme-court-hearing-101736406839073.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:19:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Back off!' How Sharad Pawar nixed nephew Ajit Pawar's 'plan for another NCP mutiny' - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Back off!' How Sharad Pawar nixed nephew Ajit Pawar's 'plan for another NCP mutiny'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250109070417_Sharad.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="File: Sharad Pawar (L) and Ajit Pawar" title="File: Sharad Pawar (L) and Ajit Pawar"><figcaption>File: Sharad Pawar (L) and Ajit Pawar</figcaption><p>Ajit Pawar's faction attempted to poach MPs from Sharad Pawar's camp, prompting a strong reaction from the veteran leader.</p><ul><li>Ajit Pawar proposed to welcome MPs from the NCP (Sharad Pawar faction) except for Sharad Pawar and his daughter Supriya Sule.</li><li>He aimed to recruit seven out of eight MPs from Sharad's camp last December.</li><li>Sharad Pawar warned his nephew against attempts to create a mutiny within the party.</li><li>The proposal to switch parties was rejected by Sharad Pawar's loyalists.</li></ul><blockquote>“Back off!” Sharad Pawar admonished his nephew's supporters for plotting another mutiny.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights ongoing tensions within the Nationalist Congress Party as factions vie for power.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/back-off-how-sharad-pawar-nixed-nephew-ajit-pawar-s-plan-for-another-ncp-mutiny-12906418.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/back-off-how-sharad-pawar-nixed-nephew-ajit-pawar-s-plan-for-another-ncp-mutiny-12906418.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:04:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Flags Off Pravasi Bharatiya Express, Says Future Is Not In War, It Is In Buddha - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Flags Off Pravasi Bharatiya Express, Says Future Is Not In War, It Is In Buddha</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi | Image/ANI" title="Prime Minister Narendra Modi | Image/ANI"><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi | Image/ANI</figcaption></figure><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi inaugurated the 18th Pravasi Bharatiya Divas in Odisha, emphasizing the importance of the Indian diaspora and advocating for peace over conflict.</p><ul><li>PM Modi highlighted that the Pravasi Bharatiya Divas serves to strengthen the connection between India and its overseas community.</li><li>The event is being organized by the Indian government in collaboration with the Odisha state government from January 8 to 10.</li><li>He noted the upcoming celebration of various festivals, linking them to the spirit of togetherness and celebration.</li><li>He reflected on Mahatma Gandhi's return to India in 1915, marking its significance in Indian history.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pravasi Bharatiya Divas has become an institution to strengthen the bond between India and its diaspora.” - PM Modi</blockquote><p>PM Modi's speech at the Pravasi Bharatiya Divas reinforces the idea that fostering relationships with the diaspora is crucial for India’s future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-inaugurates-pravasi-bharatiya-divas-flags-off-pravasi-bharatiya-express-9182802.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-inaugurates-pravasi-bharatiya-divas-flags-off-pravasi-bharatiya-express-9182802.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:04:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tirupati stampede: Andhra Pradesh government announces ex-gratia of ₹25 lakh to the kin of deceased - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Andhra Pradesh Government Offers ₹25 Lakh to Families of Tirupati Stampede Victims</h1><p><strong>Date: January 09, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/9nmmp7/article69079719.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/10745_9_1_2025_12_2_42_1_IMG_20250109_WA0017.JPG" alt="Ministers consoling the kin of the deceased in the Tirupati stampede"/><figcaption>Ministers consoling the kin of the deceased in the Tirupati stampede</figcaption><p>The Andhra Pradesh government has announced an ex-gratia payment of ₹25 lakh to the families of those who lost their lives in a tragic stampede that occurred at token distribution centers for the Vaikunta Ekadasi darshan.</p><ul><li>Six devotees died in the stampede, with several others injured.</li><li>The incident took place just two days before the important religious festival Vaikunta Ekadasi.</li><li>Cabinet ministers visited the hospitals to console the victims' families.</li><li>A police complaint has been filed regarding the stampede incident.</li><li>The deceased were from Visakhapatnam and Tamil Nadu, identified as S. Lavanya, Malliga, Buddeti Naidu Babu, Kandipalli Santhi, G. Rajini, and V. Nirmala.</li></ul><blockquote>“A pall of gloom descended over SVIMS super specialty hospital and SVR Ruia Government General Hospital campuses in Tirupati over the death of six devotees.”</blockquote><p>This event underscores the need for better crowd management during large religious events to prevent such tragedies in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/tirupati-stampede-state-announces-ex-gratia-of-25-lakh-to-the-kin-of-deceased/article69079635.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/andhra-pradesh/tirupati-stampede-state-announces-ex-gratia-of-25-lakh-to-the-kin-of-deceased/article69079635.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MPESB Parvekshak Online Form 2025 - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPWGdFWV9qOXhiQkI2ZHdYMUR3VTF4YlN6YUl3TjVjaDg2TDg3M2JPYnBHQUNtdkxfQXJWZmdGbDZrWktFWXhYSi1YRkloM0hCbTdJY1dkLUVwMlFsV1JZSmNKamZKZ0tlY0ZuVGRXcHluWm1nbjFfUDluRlVNbnNGay1ZTFFIUFJ2bnNvOHlwY3FYUUU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPWGdFWV9qOXhiQkI2ZHdYMUR3VTF4YlN6YUl3TjVjaDg2TDg3M2JPYnBHQUNtdkxfQXJWZmdGbDZrWktFWXhYSi1YRkloM0hCbTdJY1dkLUVwMlFsV1JZSmNKamZKZ0tlY0ZuVGRXcHluWm1nbjFfUDluRlVNbnNGay1ZTFFIUFJ2bnNvOHlwY3FYUUU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:01:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Is women travelling buses for free fair?': Bengaluru man's post saying freebies money can be used better - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is women travelling buses for free fair?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>An ongoing debate has emerged regarding a Bengaluru man's post questioning the fairness of offering free bus travel for women, suggesting that the funds could be utilized in a more effective manner.</p><ul><li>The article discusses a social media post that sparked diverse opinions.</li><li>Key arguments include the benefits of free transportation for women's safety versus the cost of the initiative.</li><li>Public responses reveal a split between support and criticism of the measure.</li></ul><blockquote>“These funds could be used for better public amenities instead.” - Anonymous commenter</blockquote><p>This conversation touches on broader themes of social equity, public funding, and gender issues in transportation policy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/is-women-travelling-buses-for-free-fair-bengaluru-mans-post-saying-freebies-money-can-be-used-better-sparks-debate/articleshow/117075666.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/is-women-travelling-buses-for-free-fair-bengaluru-mans-post-saying-freebies-money-can-be-used-better-sparks-debate/articleshow/117075666.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No takers for Congress? Most INDIA bloc allies back AAP in Delhi, snub grand old party - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Most INDIA bloc allies back AAP in Delhi elections, sidelining Congress</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250109064539_Kejriwal-Mamata.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="West Bengal CM Mamata Banerjee on Wednesday announced support for Arvind Kejriwal's AAP for the Delhi Assembly elections. (File Photo: PTI)" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>West Bengal CM Mamata Banerjee on Wednesday announced support for Arvind Kejriwal's AAP for the Delhi Assembly elections. (File Photo: PTI)</figcaption><p>The Congress party faces increasing isolation as opposition parties from the INDIA bloc support AAP in the upcoming Delhi Assembly elections.</p><ul><li>West Bengal CM Mamata Banerjee announced support for AAP, expressing gratitude on social media.</li><li>Trinamool Congress has criticized Congress, asserting its position within the INDIA bloc.</li><li>Other allies, including Samajwadi Party and Shiv Sena (UBT), have also pledged support to AAP.</li><li>Commentary from various leaders questions the relevance of the INDIA bloc, with Tejashwi Yadav voicing doubts about its significance.</li><li>Congress candidates express skepticism about AAP's rallying cry for support from other states.</li><li>Delhi elections scheduled for February 5, with results to be declared on February 8.</li></ul><blockquote>“AAP is the only party in Delhi which can defeat BJP. This is why other parties are coming out to support us.” - Sanjay Singh, AAP MP</blockquote><p>The shifting support dynamics highlight Congress's struggles and set the stage for a competitive election among AAP, BJP, and Congress in Delhi.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/no-takers-for-congress-most-india-bloc-allies-back-aap-in-delhi-snub-grand-old-party-12906438.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/no-takers-for-congress-most-india-bloc-allies-back-aap-in-delhi-snub-grand-old-party-12906438.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:47:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AIIMS CRE Recruitment 2025 Notification Released for 4576 Vacancies, Check Details and Apply Online - Pasteur Institute of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AIIMS CRE Recruitment 2025 Notification Released for 4597 Vacancies</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> AIIMS New Delhi</p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.pasteurinstituteindia.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/AIIMS-.jpg" alt="AIIMS" width="1280" height="720"><figcaption>AIIMS Recruitment 2025</figcaption><p>The AIIMS Common Recruitment Examination (CRE) 2025 provides a significant opportunity for candidates looking to fill 4597 non-faculty Group B and C roles across numerous AIIMS institutions and other central government bodies. Applications are open until January 31, 2025.</p><ul><li><strong>Conducting Authority:</strong> AIIMS New Delhi</li><li><strong>Total Posts:</strong> 4597</li><li><strong>Exam Dates:</strong> February 26 to 28, 2025</li><li><strong>Eligibility:</strong> Various educational qualifications needed; age limits are 18 to 35 years with relaxations.</li><li><strong>Application Fee:</strong> ₹3000 for General/OBC, ₹2400 for SC/ST/EWS, exempted for PwBD.</li></ul><blockquote>“Candidates must read the detailed notification before applying.”</blockquote><p>To apply, visit the official website <a href="https://www.aiimsexams.ac.in/">aiimsexams.ac.in</a>.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pasteurinstituteindia.com/aiims-cre-recruitment/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pasteurinstituteindia.com/aiims-cre-recruitment/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:33:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra's 'hair loss mystery': Why have villagers gone bald in a week? - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOZlJaQWtDRXRQZW1wLWlEV2ZSMGNndW5OelloLUtBdU54ZDlpMmNqaWx3UXhfVE5rMFZVMGY4dTJrRnphNFlfNzBZbFhoZWtVdkY1RnI1cDlBa2MyNjhvTEk3MW1DT29YZFB4ZEx3SnhIaFpwMHFlbWpENTVZdzVpYlhOcmhjMG01ZE05NHk0X2JaRkNqSjhsUi1lSmFEZGRWY29SZF92RnliaFZheE1MZ1FnUdIBuAFBVV95cUxNWkp3aVVnanRnRjdTaFZoQWNjdUwzYUxpN21vX3FjZUw2TVhPbmV6S1llaFh1S3cyeFlOQWtBMldUOVBBeUJYOUR3VmxzaC1JVzhtam1iMUc0dXlYeHEwLVpRRFlYWnBCazhuSXRsMWxFUXNzR1o0N3JkdDdhRTZfQVhERG5XQWVaTHdLbmhZdlhLTXVMMThjNzhzVDhIRG9NOFBFUngwcEZsR0lFN2I4U0RfN2JpRE9l?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOZlJaQWtDRXRQZW1wLWlEV2ZSMGNndW5OelloLUtBdU54ZDlpMmNqaWx3UXhfVE5rMFZVMGY4dTJrRnphNFlfNzBZbFhoZWtVdkY1RnI1cDlBa2MyNjhvTEk3MW1DT29YZFB4ZEx3SnhIaFpwMHFlbWpENTVZdzVpYlhOcmhjMG01ZE05NHk0X2JaRkNqSjhsUi1lSmFEZGRWY29SZF92RnliaFZheE1MZ1FnUdIBuAFBVV95cUxNWkp3aVVnanRnRjdTaFZoQWNjdUwzYUxpN21vX3FjZUw2TVhPbmV6S1llaFh1S3cyeFlOQWtBMldUOVBBeUJYOUR3VmxzaC1JVzhtam1iMUc0dXlYeHEwLVpRRFlYWnBCazhuSXRsMWxFUXNzR1o0N3JkdDdhRTZfQVhERG5XQWVaTHdLbmhZdlhLTXVMMThjNzhzVDhIRG9NOFBFUngwcEZsR0lFN2I4U0RfN2JpRE9l?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:31:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taliban calls India a ‘significant regional partner’ after Dubai meeting - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Taliban Recognizes India as Key Regional Partner After Dubai Meeting</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 09, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/t3mezx/article69079604.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20250108257L.jpg" alt="Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri meets Afghanistan Acting Foreign Minister Mawlawi Amir Khan Muttaqi, in Dubai on January 8, 2025" title="Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri meets Afghanistan Acting Foreign Minister Mawlawi Amir Khan Muttaqi, in Dubai on January 8, 2025"><figcaption>Image of Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri meeting with Taliban Foreign Minister Amir Khan Muttaqi in Dubai.</figcaption><p>The Taliban's foreign ministry has identified India as a "significant regional and economic partner" following high-level talks in Dubai. Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri discussed expanding relations and trade opportunities.</p><ul><li>The meeting took place on January 8, 2025, marking the highest level talks since the Taliban's takeover of Afghanistan in 2021.</li><li>Discussions aimed at enhancing trade through Chabahar Port in Iran.</li><li>India is considering engaging in development projects within Afghanistan.</li><li>The Taliban administration is not officially recognized by any foreign government.</li><li>Relations between Pakistan and Afghanistan have been strained, especially regarding accusations of cross-border militant attacks.</li></ul><blockquote>“In line with Afghanistan's balanced and economy-focused foreign policy, the Islamic Emirate aims to strengthen political and economic ties with India.”</blockquote><p>This meeting sets a potential positive trajectory for diplomatic and economic cooperation between India and Afghanistan amidst regional tensions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/taliban-calls-india-a-significant-regional-partner-after-dubai-meeting/article69079599.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/taliban-calls-india-a-significant-regional-partner-after-dubai-meeting/article69079599.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court orders Centre to introduce scheme for cashless medical treatment in golden hour - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Orders Cashless Medical Treatment Scheme for Accident Victims</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 09 Jan 2025, 6:18 am</p><div><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justice Abhay S Oka and Justice Augustine George Masih" width="100%" height="100%" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 90vw, 50vw"><figcaption>Justice Abhay S Oka and Justice Augustine George Masih</figcaption></div><p>The Supreme Court has mandated the Central government to create a cashless medical treatment scheme for motor accident victims during the critical golden hour period.</p><ul><li>The golden hour is the first 60 minutes post-injury when timely medical treatment can be life-saving.</li><li>The Court emphasized the Central government's legal obligation to establish this scheme under Section 162 of the Motor Vehicles Act.</li><li>The scheme is required to be notified by March 14, with no further extensions allowed.</li><li>A draft proposal from the Centre suggested a maximum treatment cost of ₹1.5 lakh, but the Court found this insufficient.</li><li>The implementation of Section 164-B, aimed at creating a motor vehicle accident fund, is also pending.</li></ul><blockquote>“The scheme must be such that it serves the object of saving lives by providing immediate medical treatment in the golden hour.”</blockquote><p>The Court's directive aims to ensure that victims receive swift care to prevent unnecessary fatalities resulting from delays in medical treatment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/supreme-court-orders-scheme-cashless-medical-treatment-golden-hour</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/supreme-court-orders-scheme-cashless-medical-treatment-golden-hour</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:18:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RGNUL Registrar Anand Pawar suspended over sexual harassment, misconduct - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RGNUL Registrar Anand Pawar Suspended Over Sexual Harassment, Misconduct</h1><p><strong>Published on: </strong><time datetime="2025-01-09T06:12:44.014Z" title="2025-01-09 06:12">09 Jan 2025, 6:12 am</time></p><p>Dr. <strong>Anand Pawar</strong>, the Registrar of Rajiv Gandhi National University of Law (RGNUL), Patiala, has been suspended following serious allegations of sexual harassment, academic and administrative misconduct, and financial irregularities.</p><ul><li>Pawar faces accusations of bigamy, as confirmed by a previous ruling from the High Court of Madhya Pradesh barring him from remarrying.</li><li>He has been accused by an Assistant Professor of sexual harassment, leading to a legal compensation order of ₹3 lakh in favor of the complainant.</li><li>Further allegations include financial misconduct where Pawar misused his position to secure personal benefits, including special allowances and misuse of university assets.</li><li>The suspension order prevents him from tampering with evidence and mandates an inquiry into other unmentioned allegations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Your conduct is against decency, and morality and involves moral turpitude. Your conduct lacks integrity and is unbecoming to hold such a high office.”</blockquote><p>The university's administration aims to ensure a thorough investigation into the serious allegations against Pawar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/lawschools/rgnul-registrar-anand-pawar-suspended-over-sexual-harassment-misconduct</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/lawschools/rgnul-registrar-anand-pawar-suspended-over-sexual-harassment-misconduct</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:12:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India-Taliban talks: Region in flux and 5 reasons behind Delhi’s decision to engage Kabul - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India-Taliban talks: Region in flux and 5 reasons behind Delhi’s decision to engage Kabul</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 9, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Foreign-Secretary-Vikram-Misri-Afghan-acting-Foreign-Minister-Amir-Khan-Muttaqi-with-their-teams-in-Dubai.-X@MEAIndia-1.jpg?w=640" alt="India-Afghanistan talks Dubai" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri, Afghan acting Foreign Minister Amir Khan Muttaqi with their teams in Dubai. (Image source: X@MEAIndia_)</figcaption><p>The recent meeting between Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri and Taliban-ruled Afghanistan’s acting Foreign Minister Amir Khan Muttaqi comes amidst changing geopolitical landscapes.</p><ul><li>India is pursuing its national and security interests amidst regional instability.</li><li>No official recognition of the Taliban government is planned yet.</li><li>Efforts are being made to adapt to the evolving situation in Afghanistan.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is an effort by India to secure its own national and security interests with many moving parts in play.”</blockquote><p>The dialogue signifies India's strategic engagement as it navigates the complexities of its relationship with Afghanistan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/india-taliban-talks-region-in-flux-and-5-reasons-behind-delhis-decision-to-engage-kabul-9767919/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/india-taliban-talks-region-in-flux-and-5-reasons-behind-delhis-decision-to-engage-kabul-9767919/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>