<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 03:20:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 03:20:57 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R G Kar rape and murder case: I have three daughters, can understand the pain, says Sanjoy Roy’s mother after his conviction - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/rg-kar-rape-murder-case-sanjoy-roy-mother-sister-9786049/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/rg-kar-rape-murder-case-sanjoy-roy-mother-sister-9786049/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 02:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R G Kar rape and murder case: I have three daughters, can understand the pain, says Sanjoy Roy’s mother after his conviction - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/rg-kar-rape-murder-case-sanjoy-roy-mother-sister-9786049/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/rg-kar-rape-murder-case-sanjoy-roy-mother-sister-9786049/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 02:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fadnavis first Maha CM to become guardian minister - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fadnavis first Maha CM to become guardian minister</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified & <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Fadnavis as Guardian Minister">
<figcaption>Devendra Fadnavis at the swearing-in ceremony.</figcaption>
<p>Devendra Fadnavis has made history by becoming the first Chief Minister of Maharashtra to take on the role of guardian minister. This significant move is expected to enhance governance and community relations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Fadnavis announces his commitment to improve local governance.</li>
  <li>The decision aims to deepen the connection between the government and citizens.</li>
  <li>This role is expected to engage with various community concerns directly.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I am deeply honored to take on this role and will work tirelessly for the betterment of our citizens,” Fadnavis stated.</blockquote>
<p>This appointment reflects Fadnavis's continuous effort to strengthen ties with the public and address local issues effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/fadnavis-first-maha-cm-to-become-guardian-minister/articleshow/117364890.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/fadnavis-first-maha-cm-to-become-guardian-minister/articleshow/117364890.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi: Property cards under SVAMITVA will unlock economic activity worth over Rs 100 lakh crore - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi: Property cards under SVAMITVA will unlock economic activity worth over Rs 100 lakh crore</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Saturday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Official Announcement</p><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi announced that the property cards issued under the SVAMITVA scheme will ensure economic security and unlock significant economic activity across rural India.</p><ul><li>Over 65 lakh property cards distributed across 50,000 villages in 230 districts.</li><li>Approximately 2.25 crore rural residents have received legal documentation for their properties.</li><li>The implementation of the scheme has been linked to facilitating loans for small businesses among rural families.</li><li>Modi highlighted that the scheme aims to alleviate the issues faced by Dalit, backward, and tribal families against illegal property occupation.</li><li>The expected economic activity to be unlocked through this initiative is estimated to be over Rs 100 lakh crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“After getting legal documents, lakhs of people have taken loans from banks on the basis of their houses and property.”</blockquote><p>The Prime Minister emphasized the importance of property rights in reducing poverty and criticized past governments for failing to address property ownership issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/pm-modi-property-cards-under-svamitva-will-unlock-economic-activity-worth-over-rs-100-lakh-crore-9786311/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/pm-modi-property-cards-under-svamitva-will-unlock-economic-activity-worth-over-rs-100-lakh-crore-9786311/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Centre invites farmers for talks, Dallewal agrees to take medical aid - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Centre Invites Farmers for Talks as Dallewal Agrees to Medical Aid</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 18, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Dallewal-farmers-union.jpg?w=640" alt="Jagjit Singh Dallewal" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Earlier a delegation from the Union Ministry of Agriculture, led by Joint Secretary Priya Ranjan, arrived at the Khanauri border on Saturday evening to meet fasting farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal. (Express Photo)</figcaption>
<p>The Centre has invited farmers for talks next month to discuss their demands, a move aimed at resolving the ongoing farmers' protest. Jagjit Singh Dallewal, who has been fasting, accepted medical aid on the same day he was invited for a meeting.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The meeting for discussions is scheduled for February 14 at the Mahatma Gandhi Institute of Public Administration in Chandigarh.</li>
  <li>Jagjit Singh Dallewal was on a fast unto death since November 26 last year.</li>
  <li>The invitation follows a meeting between Dallewal and officials from the Union Agriculture Ministry.</li>
  <li>Over 121 farmers joined Dallewal on hunger strike at the Khanauri border.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If 121 farmers sitting on hunger strike tell me, I will take medical assistance but will not take any food until the demands, including the most important one seeking MSP as a legal guarantee, are not met.” – Jagjit Singh Dallewal</blockquote>
<p>The discussions are seen as crucial as the protests continue. The significant health concerns over Dallewal were acknowledged, prompting the Centre's outreach.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/in-a-first-central-official-meets-fasting-leader-dallewal-set-to-give-him-a-proposal-9786125/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/in-a-first-central-official-meets-fasting-leader-dallewal-set-to-give-him-a-proposal-9786125/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[65 lakh rural land owners across 50,000 villages get property cards - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>65 Lakh Rural Land Owners Across 50,000 Villages Get Property Cards</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>An extensive initiative has granted property cards to 65 lakh rural landowners across 50,000 villages in India, enhancing their land ownership rights and access to services.</p><ul><li>The program aims to secure land rights for rural populations.</li><li>This initiative is a part of the government's efforts to digitize land records.</li><li>It is expected to improve access to credit for farmers.</li></ul><blockquote>"This initiative will empower rural landowners and boost the agricultural economy," a government official stated.</blockquote><p>This significant step towards land rights aims to enhance the livelihoods of rural communities and streamline agricultural processes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/65-lakh-rural-land-owners-across-50000-villages-get-property-cards/articleshow/117362949.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/65-lakh-rural-land-owners-across-50000-villages-get-property-cards/articleshow/117362949.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 22:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan Stabbing Case: Accused Arrested From Thane, Mumbai Cops To Question Him - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-case-accused-arrested-from-thane-mumbai-cops-to-question-him-9193901.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-case-accused-arrested-from-thane-mumbai-cops-to-question-him-9193901.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 22:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan stabbing case: Mumbai Police arrests accused in Thane - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Police Arrests Suspect in Saif Ali Khan Stabbing Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p><img src="https://example.com/image.jpg" alt="Saif Ali Khan" /><figcaption>Saif Ali Khan at a recent event.</figcaption><p>The recent stabbing case involving Bollywood actor Saif Ali Khan has seen an arrest in Thane, as Mumbai Police continue their investigation.</p><ul><li>The police apprehended a suspect connected to the stabbing incident.</li><li>Authorities are gathering evidence and statements from witnesses.</li><li>The attack reportedly occurred in a public area, raising safety concerns.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are determined to ensure the safety of public figures and citizens alike.” - Mumbai Police</blockquote><p>Authorities remain vigilant as the case develops, emphasizing the commitment to security and public safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-mumbai-police-arrests-accused-from-thane/articleshow/117362474.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-mumbai-police-arrests-accused-from-thane/articleshow/117362474.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 21:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[American podcaster Lex Fridman to host podcast with PM Modi in February - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lex Fridman to Host Podcast with PM Modi in February</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 19, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Screenshot_2025-01-19_012547_1737230161019_1737230241957.png" alt="American podcaster Lex Fridman (screengrab)" title="American podcaster Lex Fridman (screengrab)">
<figcaption>American podcaster Lex Fridman (screengrab)</figcaption>
<p>American podcaster Lex Fridman announced that he will host a podcast with Prime Minister Narendra Modi at the end of February. Fridman expressed excitement about visiting India for the first time.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Fridman has previously hosted figures such as Elon Musk, Donald Trump, and Zelenskyy on his podcast.</li>
  <li>He aims to experience the vibrant culture and meet the people of India.</li>
  <li>This podcast marks a significant moment as it is Modi's engagement in the podcasting space.</li>
  <li>Fridman has over 4.5 million subscribers on his YouTube channel.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I will be doing a podcast with Narendra Modi (@narendramodi), Prime Minister of India, at the end of February. I've never been to India, so I'm excited to finally visit and experience many facets of its vibrant, historic culture and its amazing people as fully as I can.” – Lex Fridman</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming podcast is set to explore various topics, potentially including India's technological growth and leadership philosophies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/american-podcaster-lex-fridman-to-host-podcast-with-pm-modi-in-february-101737228806410.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/american-podcaster-lex-fridman-to-host-podcast-with-pm-modi-in-february-101737228806410.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 19:59:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R G Kar rape and murder case: Let Sanjoy Roy get the punishment he deserves, say mother and sister - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/rg-kar-rape-murder-case-sanjoy-roy-mother-sister-9786049/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/rg-kar-rape-murder-case-sanjoy-roy-mother-sister-9786049/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 19:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R G Kar rape and murder case: Let Sanjoy Roy get the punishment he deserves, say mother and sister - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/rg-kar-rape-murder-case-sanjoy-roy-mother-sister-9786049/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/rg-kar-rape-murder-case-sanjoy-roy-mother-sister-9786049/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 19:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP Challenges Arvind Kejriwal’s Nomination From New Delhi Seat Over Criminal Cases, Assets - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Challenges Arvind Kejriwal’s Nomination From New Delhi Seat Over Criminal Cases, Assets</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)"><figcaption>Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)</figcaption><p>BJP candidate Parvesh Verma has filed a complaint challenging the nomination of former Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal for alleged income discrepancies, failure to disclose criminal cases, and voter registration issues.</p><ul><li>Parvesh Verma's complaint seeks the cancellation of Kejriwal's nomination.</li><li>It highlights incorrect income figures reported by Kejriwal in his affidavits for the years 2019–23.</li><li>The complaint questions Kejriwal's voter registration status and notes that he has failed to disclose details of four FIRs against him.</li><li>Delhi Assembly elections for all 70 constituencies are scheduled for February 5, with results on February 8.</li></ul><blockquote>“Election commission will decide on it but since he is a public figure, this is a serious matter and should be investigated.” - Virendra Sachdeva, Delhi BJP President</blockquote><p>Kejriwal has urged voters to focus on developmental work done by his party.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/elections/bjp-challenges-arvind-kejriwals-nomination-over-criminal-cases-assets-decision-on-hold-9193252.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/elections/bjp-challenges-arvind-kejriwals-nomination-over-criminal-cases-assets-decision-on-hold-9193252.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 19:47:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What youth hit by Arvind Kejriwal's car claim, and AAP's response - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What youth hit by Arvind Kejriwal's car claim, and AAP's response</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not Provided</p><p>In a recent incident, youth have come forward with claims regarding being hit by a car driven by Arvind Kejriwal, leading to a response from the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP).</p><ul><li>Details of the incident have caused a stir on social media.</li><li>AAP has issued a statement addressing the claims made by the youth.</li><li>Public reaction has been mixed, with calls for accountability.</li></ul><blockquote>“We urge the authorities to look into this matter seriously.”</blockquote><p>The incident has raised questions about public safety and accountability for political figures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/kejriwal-signalled-driver-what-youth-hit-by-ex-cms-car-said/articleshow/117356282.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/kejriwal-signalled-driver-what-youth-hit-by-ex-cms-car-said/articleshow/117356282.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 18:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Centre proposes meeting with protesting farmers on February 14 in Chandigarh - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Centre proposes meeting with protesting farmers on February 14 in Chandigarh</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> February 12, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p><p>The Centre has invited protesting farmers for a meeting to discuss their demands, scheduled for February 14 in Chandigarh. The meeting follows concerns for a farmer leader who has been on a hunger strike for over 54 days.</p><ul><li>The meeting will take place at the Mahatama Gandhi State Institute of Public Administration.</li><li>Priya Ranjan, Joint Secretary, led the delegation that invited farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal.</li><li>Dallewal is urging the acceptance of farmers' demands through his fast.</li><li>Farmer leaders have encouraged Dallewal to seek medical assistance to attend the meeting.</li></ul><blockquote>“I hope Dallewal will break his fast and participate in talks,” said a government official.</blockquote><p>This proposed dialogue marks a crucial step in addressing the farmers' long-standing concerns and health risks posed by ongoing protests.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/punjab/centre-proposes-meeting-with-protesting-farmers-on-february-14-in-chandigarh/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/punjab/centre-proposes-meeting-with-protesting-farmers-on-february-14-in-chandigarh/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:28:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Odisha will become growth engine of the country: CM Mohan Majhi - OTV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Odisha aims to be India's growth engine by 2036, says CM Mohan Majhi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> No date provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Odisha TV</p><img src="https://odishatv.in/commondir/images/Whatsapp-Logo.png" alt=""> <figcaption>Join OTV News on Whatsapp for updates</figcaption><p>Odisha Chief Minister Mohan Majhi has set a bold vision for the State to achieve economic prosperity by 2036, highlighting its potential to become a growth engine for India.</p><ul><li>The Odisha government aims to enhance infrastructure and attract investments.</li><li>Eight significant MoUs have been signed with Singapore, including an industrial park.</li><li>There are plans for a green shipping corridor and a modern city near Bhubaneswar.</li><li>Majhi believes these developments will bring Odisha in line with developed countries.</li><li>He projects Odisha will rank among the top five states in India by 2036.</li></ul><blockquote>“Odisha will have economic prosperity and is on track to rank among the top five states in India by 2036,” said CM Majhi.</blockquote><p>This ambitious plan reflects Odisha's commitment to leverage international partnerships for future growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/odisha-will-become-growth-engine-of-the-country-cm-mohan-majhi-253846</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/odisha-will-become-growth-engine-of-the-country-cm-mohan-majhi-253846</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:19:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saif Ali Khan stabbing news: How railway police zeroed in on suspect in train - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saif Ali Khan Stabbing: Suspect Detained by Railway Police</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Jan 18, 2025, Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/ANI-20250118239-0_1737219873669_1737219901739.jpg" alt="The suspect, Akash Kanojia." title="The suspect, Akash Kanojia."><figcaption>The suspect, Akash Kanojia.</figcaption>
<p>The Railway Protection Force (RPF) detained a suspect in the Saif Ali Khan stabbing case while he was travelling by the Jnaneswari Express train in Durg district, Chhattisgarh.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The suspect, Aakash Kanojia, was located using information from the Mumbai police.</li>
  <li>Kanojia was apprehended in the train's general coach based on a photo and tower location provided by the Mumbai police.</li>
  <li>Saif Ali Khan was attacked in his home, resulting in multiple stab wounds.</li>
  <li>He was treated at Lilavati Hospital and is reported to be out of danger.</li>
  <li>The Mumbai police have assembled over 20 teams to find the intruder who attacked Khan.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The suspect's identity was confirmed through a video call with Mumbai Police. He has been detained. Further interrogation will be done by Mumbai Police." - Sanjay Sinha, RPF in-charge at Durg</blockquote>
<p>The swift action by the RPF showcases the effective collaboration between state police forces in the wake of a serious incident involving a public figure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-news-how-railway-police-zeroed-in-on-suspect-in-train-101737219571970.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/saif-ali-khan-stabbing-news-how-railway-police-zeroed-in-on-suspect-in-train-101737219571970.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Home ministry forms team to investigate deaths due to ‘mysterious illness’ in J&K Rajouri - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Investigation Launched into Mysterious Illness Causing Deaths in J&K Rajouri</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Jan 19, 2025, HT News</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Rajouri_1737214567064_1737214567319.jpeg" alt="Officials visited Badhal village in Kotranka subdivision of the Rajouri district to access the ground situation. (Source: X)(HT_PRINT)">
<figcaption>Officials visited Badhal village in Kotranka subdivision of the Rajouri district to access the ground situation. (Source: X)(HT_PRINT)</figcaption>
<p>A total of 15 deaths in Budhal village have raised concerns, prompting the Union home minister to form a specialized investigation team.</p>
<ul>
<li>15 deaths reported in the past 45 days from three inter-related families.</li>
<li>Patients showed symptoms of fever, pain, nausea, and loss of consciousness.</li>
<li>The investigative team will include experts from various ministries and institutions.</li>
<li>Local administration will collaborate to provide immediate relief and preventive measures.</li>
<li>Investigation aims to understand causative factors, ruling out communicable diseases.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Experts from some of the most reputed institutions of the country have been arranged to manage the situation and understand the causative factors of deaths."</blockquote>
<p>The government continues to seek explanations for these tragic incidents while ensuring support for the affected communities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/home-ministry-forms-team-to-investigate-deaths-due-to-mysterious-illness-in-j-k-rajouri-101737213467032.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/home-ministry-forms-team-to-investigate-deaths-due-to-mysterious-illness-in-j-k-rajouri-101737213467032.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:45:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nitish Kumar stokes another row with ‘girls did not wear clothes’ remark - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitish Kumar stokes another row with ‘girls did not wear clothes’ remark</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 18, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/z0f0a4/article69113706.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI01_11_2025_000232A.jpg" alt="Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar" title="Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar"><figcaption>Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>Bihar Chief Minister Nitish Kumar has stirred controversy with a remark suggesting that women historically did not wear clothes, made during his Pragati Yatra in Begusarai. The comment has drawn sharp criticism, particularly from opposition leader Tejashwi Yadav, who labeled it as disrespectful to women.</p><ul><li>Kumar made the remarks while speaking to a group of <i>Jeevika Didis</i>.</li><li>The statement prompted backlash from Tejashwi Yadav, who condemned it as an insult to women in Bihar.</li><li>Kumar's remarks indicated that women's situation has improved, with a focus on clothing and etiquette.</li><li>This is not the first controversial statement from Kumar; he faced criticism in the past over comments regarding women's education and population control.</li></ul><blockquote>“Earlier, the daughters of Bihar wore not only clothes but also self-respect, self-reliance and honour.” - Tejashwi Yadav</blockquote><p>The controversy reflects ongoing tensions surrounding women's rights and representation in Bihar, raising questions about Kumar’s leadership and sensitivity towards women's issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/bihar/nitish-kumar-stokes-another-row-with-girls-did-not-wear-clothes-remark/article69113294.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/bihar/nitish-kumar-stokes-another-row-with-girls-did-not-wear-clothes-remark/article69113294.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Centre forms inter-ministerial team to probe mysterious deaths in J-Ks Rajouri - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Centre forms inter-ministerial team to probe mysterious deaths in Jammu's Rajouri</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent; <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p><p>The Central Government has formed an inter-ministerial team to investigate 15 mysterious deaths in Badhaal village, Jammu and Kashmir, over the past month and a half.</p><ul><li>The team, led by the Union Home Ministry, will include experts from various ministries.</li><li>The goal is to determine the cause of deaths and provide immediate relief and preventive measures.</li><li>Symptoms among victims included vomiting and loss of consciousness.</li><li>The Jammu and Kashmir Health Minister has stated that all tests have ruled out any mysterious disease.</li></ul><blockquote>“All tests conducted both within and outside the Union Territory have shown negative results.” - Sakeena Masood</blockquote><p>This investigation highlights ongoing health concerns in the region and the need for thorough examination of the events leading to these fatalities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/j-k/centre-forms-inter-ministerial-team-to-probe-mysterious-deaths-in-jammus-rajouri/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/j-k/centre-forms-inter-ministerial-team-to-probe-mysterious-deaths-in-jammus-rajouri/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:17:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['25 Years Jail Or Death Penalty': Kolkata Court To Sanjay Roy After Convicting Him In RG Kar Rape Case - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/rg-kar-rape-and-murder-case-verdict-sanjoy-roy-convicted-9193379.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/rg-kar-rape-and-murder-case-verdict-sanjoy-roy-convicted-9193379.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:10:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RG Kar rape case verdict: BJP alleges evidence was 'tampered' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rg-kar-rape-case-verdict-live-updates-kolkata-court-rape-murder-judgment-cbi-sanjay-roy-101737170770711.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rg-kar-rape-case-verdict-live-updates-kolkata-court-rape-murder-judgment-cbi-sanjay-roy-101737170770711.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:55:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RG Kar rape case verdict live: Judgment today by Kolkata court, victim's kin say ‘more involved’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RG Kar rape case verdict: BJP alleges evidence was 'tampered'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/sealdah_1737208588219_1737208588543.jpg" alt="RG Kar rape case highlights: View from the outside of the civil and criminal court in Sealdah on Saturday, January 18, 2025." title="RG Kar rape case highlights: View from the outside of the civil and criminal court in Sealdah on Saturday, January 18, 2025."><figcaption>RG Kar rape case highlights: View from the outside of the civil and criminal court in Sealdah on Saturday, January 18, 2025.</figcaption><p>On January 18, 2025, a court in Kolkata found Sanjay Roy guilty of the rape-murder of a 31-year-old trainee doctor, whose body was discovered in the RG Kar Medical College &amp; Hospital seminar hall on August 9, 2024. The ruling has raised concerns over the investigation, with allegations of evidence tampering from various political representatives.</p><ul><li>The body of a trainee doctor was found dead in RG Kar Medical College on August 9, 2024.</li><li>Sanjay Roy, a civic volunteer, was arrested shortly after the incident, following CCTV footage linking him to the crime.</li><li>The case led to widespread protests by junior doctors demanding justice and better safety measures.</li><li>The trial began on November 12, 2024, with a total of 50 witnesses presented.</li></ul><blockquote>“The court has convicted him (Sanjay Roy), but the people of West Bengal believe that more than one person may have been involved in the incident.” - Sukanta Majumdar, Union Minister</blockquote><p>The court is set to determine Sanjay Roy's sentence on January 20, 2025, amidst calls from the public for the maximum possible punishment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rg-kar-rape-case-verdict-live-updates-kolkata-court-rape-murder-judgment-cbi-sanjay-roy-101737170770711.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rg-kar-rape-case-verdict-live-updates-kolkata-court-rape-murder-judgment-cbi-sanjay-roy-101737170770711.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:55:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sanjay Roy convicted in RG Kar case: What happens next, what punishment he may get - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sanjay Roy convicted in RG Kar case: What happens next, what punishment he may get</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a significant legal development, Sanjay Roy has been convicted in the RG Kar case, raising questions about the potential punishments he may face.</p><ul><li>The conviction is a notable outcome of the ongoing judicial proceedings.</li><li>Possible sentences include imprisonment and fines, reflecting the severity of the offenses.</li><li>The case highlights ongoing legal challenges within the system and its implications for justice.</li></ul><blockquote>“This conviction represents a step forward in the pursuit of justice in complex cases,” legal experts say.</blockquote><p>As the legal process unfolds, it remains to be seen what specific penalties will be imposed on Roy, but the case reiterates the importance of accountability in public service.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/sanjay-roy-convicted-in-rg-kar-case-what-happens-next-what-punishment-he-may-get/articleshow/117357854.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/sanjay-roy-convicted-in-rg-kar-case-what-happens-next-what-punishment-he-may-get/articleshow/117357854.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mukesh Ambani, Nita Ambani to attend Donald Trump's inauguration: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mukesh-ambani-nita-ambani-to-attend-donald-trumps-inauguration-report-101737211468187.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mukesh-ambani-nita-ambani-to-attend-donald-trumps-inauguration-report-101737211468187.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:51:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Fish, Meat Or Any Non-Veg Food To Be Sold In Bengaluru's Yelahanka For A Month | Here's Why - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>No Fish, Meat Or Any Non-Veg Food To Be Sold In Bengaluru's Yelahanka For A Month | Here's Why</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The Aero India 2025 will take place in Bengaluru from February 10 to 14. (PTI Image)"><figcaption>The Aero India 2025 will take place in Bengaluru from February 10 to 14. (PTI Image)</figcaption></figure><p>The Bruhat Bengaluru Mahanagara Palike (BBMP) has announced a prohibition on the sale of meat, fish, and non-vegetarian items in a 13 km radius around Air Force Station Yelahanka from January 23 to February 17, 2025, due to the upcoming Aero India 2025 airshow.</p><ul><li>The prohibition aims to prevent bird strikes during airplane practice sessions.</li><li>The event will occur from February 10 to 14, featuring various aviation displays.</li><li>Any violations of the prohibition will face penalties under local regulations.</li></ul><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Karnataka | Aero India-2025 show will be held at Airforce station Yelahanka from Feb 10 to 14. Due to this, sale of non-veg food is prohibited within 13 km radius of the Airforce station from Jan 23 to Feb 17: BBMP <a href="https://t.co/aiDFzkdVOl" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/aiDFzkdVOl</a>— ANI (@ANI) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI/status/1880555895933063375?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">January 18, 2025</a></p></blockquote><p>This year's Aero India will bring together international and local firms to explore partnerships in the aerospace sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/bengaluru-news-aero-india-2025-no-fish-meat-or-any-non-veg-food-to-be-sold-9193468.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/bengaluru-news-aero-india-2025-no-fish-meat-or-any-non-veg-food-to-be-sold-9193468.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:45:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab State Lohri Makar Sankranti Bumper Lottery Result 2025 LIVE Updates: Winner for 1st prize Rs 10 cr JACKPOT OUT - Check other winning numbers online, offline - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Punjab State Lohri Makar Sankranti Bumper Lottery Result 2025 LIVE Updates: Winners list OUT!</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> ET Now News</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Punjab State Lohri Makar Sankranti Bumper Lottery Result 2025 LIVE">
<figcaption>Punjab State Lohri Makar Sankranti Bumper Lottery Result 2025 LIVE</figcaption>
<p>The Punjab State Lohri Makar Sankranti Bumper Lottery has announced its results today, revealing the winners of various prize categories. The lottery is celebrated alongside major Indian festivals and draws significant public attention.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The 1st prize winner has claimed a JACKPOT of Rs 10 crore with the number <strong>B5 66370</strong>.</li>
  <li>2nd prize winner: Rs 1 crore, winning number: <strong>A5 81656</strong>.</li>
  <li>3rd prize winner: Rs 50 lakh, winning number: <strong>B3 25586</strong>.</li>
  <li>4th prize winners include several ticket numbers, with a prize of Rs 10 lakh.</li>
  <li>The lottery results can be checked online or through local newspapers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The draw will take place under the supervision of the Punjab State Lottery Department, ensuring transparency in the lottery process."</blockquote>
<p>This event draws large participation and excitement among the public, marking it as one of the most anticipated lotteries of the year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/news/punjab-state-lohri-makar-sankranti-bumper-lottery-2025-live-updates-check-draw-date-winning-jackpot-prize-money-and-winners-list-article-117357176</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/news/punjab-state-lohri-makar-sankranti-bumper-lottery-2025-live-updates-check-draw-date-winning-jackpot-prize-money-and-winners-list-article-117357176</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:14:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab State Lohri Makar Sankranti Bumper Lottery 2025 Live Updates: Rs 10 crore JACKPOT for 1st prize - Winners list to be OUT at 8 PM | How to check online & offline - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Punjab State Lohri Makar Sankranti Bumper Lottery Result 2025 LIVE Updates</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ET Now News</p>
<p><img src='https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg' alt='Punjab State Lohri Makar Sankranti Bumper Lottery Result 2025' /></p>
<figcaption>Punjab State Lohri Makar Sankranti Bumper Lottery Result Live</figcaption>
<p>The Punjab State Lohri Makar Sankranti Bumper Lottery 2025 has unveiled its winners, with the 1st prize amounting to Rs 10 crores. This lottery is celebrated in conjunction with the major festivals Lohri and Makar Sankranti, making it a highly anticipated event.</p>
<ul>
<li>The draw takes place under the supervision of the Punjab State Lottery Department, ensuring transparency.</li>
<li>The winners list for the lottery was announced at 8 PM on January 18.</li>
<li>The lottery is well-known for its generous cash prizes and high levels of public participation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>1st prize winning number for JACKPOT Rs 10 crore: <strong>B5 66370</strong></blockquote>
<p>Punjab State Lottery offers a variety of prizes, including 2nd prize of Rs 1 crore, 3rd prize of Rs 50 lakh, and multiple other categories. The prize claiming process requires verification and submission of necessary documents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/news/punjab-state-lohri-makar-sankranti-bumper-lottery-2025-live-updates-check-draw-date-winning-jackpot-prize-money-and-winners-list-article-117357176</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/news/punjab-state-lohri-makar-sankranti-bumper-lottery-2025-live-updates-check-draw-date-winning-jackpot-prize-money-and-winners-list-article-117357176</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:14:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HM Amit Shah Constitutes Inter-Ministerial Team to Investigate recent Deaths in Badhal Rajouri - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxNeVg0c19fUVlVZkt6Z0ZGeklxR01UeXB0MUdDWWJIbXZ6QTJ1UkxKY0M1YjJSbzJEN0VRZjNvc3VjZ0I5RTFBZEp1NklETDg1OVJqdWFFTUZCUVh5RnlEVlI5ZnVYdjFjeks4ZV83NGR4VnJVUl9TODJkTkIxbTlaaTBiam9UQzFIRUlWWEJFQk5YWThWSVJnS2gwalZHYTQwX1dKbWUxS3oyUmpZVkFmSmdXbmcwSlVOZ2xWZGRqeEZlZjg4S2sxaGdSWjAwVzJtRzA5SdIB2gFBVV95cUxNOGdUSTc2N2ZYZkMwOEFEN205bnlZWGVmOWhkc3c5bDZsSXdGSXBnM216cWFaUW1CQ1d0YXNEdTgtNHpWXzZJakc3bmJNTnhfdWgxWDlwbnc2NWZIMllnX0YzUEhCbDhCczhKZDBXalNxOTd0Z1ZXV3hUUVBsdDhwOVZMdTZEYUg4eTdFeTZqWk1lWGFKa3c2Q0JYOHhFeWN1ci0xRngxaDgzZHJNWlVaa2NXYUJIZVdHTk1KQmRneVhCakhhQ3gtX1hqMVFxd1p5OW40M2lLdXhNUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxNeVg0c19fUVlVZkt6Z0ZGeklxR01UeXB0MUdDWWJIbXZ6QTJ1UkxKY0M1YjJSbzJEN0VRZjNvc3VjZ0I5RTFBZEp1NklETDg1OVJqdWFFTUZCUVh5RnlEVlI5ZnVYdjFjeks4ZV83NGR4VnJVUl9TODJkTkIxbTlaaTBiam9UQzFIRUlWWEJFQk5YWThWSVJnS2gwalZHYTQwX1dKbWUxS3oyUmpZVkFmSmdXbmcwSlVOZ2xWZGRqeEZlZjg4S2sxaGdSWjAwVzJtRzA5SdIB2gFBVV95cUxNOGdUSTc2N2ZYZkMwOEFEN205bnlZWGVmOWhkc3c5bDZsSXdGSXBnM216cWFaUW1CQ1d0YXNEdTgtNHpWXzZJakc3bmJNTnhfdWgxWDlwbnc2NWZIMllnX0YzUEhCbDhCczhKZDBXalNxOTd0Z1ZXV3hUUVBsdDhwOVZMdTZEYUg4eTdFeTZqWk1lWGFKa3c2Q0JYOHhFeWN1ci0xRngxaDgzZHJNWlVaa2NXYUJIZVdHTk1KQmRneVhCakhhQ3gtX1hqMVFxd1p5OW40M2lLdXhNUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:00:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RG Kar verdict: What went inside court room where Sanjoy Roy was held guilty - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/kolkata-news/rg-kar-verdict-what-went-inside-court-room-where-sanjoy-roy-was-held-guilty-101737208163795.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/kolkata-news/rg-kar-verdict-what-went-inside-court-room-where-sanjoy-roy-was-held-guilty-101737208163795.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:49:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who is Chanderkant Jha, the ‘Butcher of Delhi’ caught by police today? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/who-is-chanderkant-jha-the-butcher-of-delhi-caught-by-police-today-101737202270992.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/who-is-chanderkant-jha-the-butcher-of-delhi-caught-by-police-today-101737202270992.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:38:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>