<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 03:27:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 03:27:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Several feared dead, vehicles burnt in massive fire at Jaipur CNG pump - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxPSWg3UEJhUXZXa0lXcGxmbkZ0WUVid2lWNWZSVjJOUE9aR01KaGF0SGZ5SF9kVWtHaXlCeldnZTlsTUo5Q1hpMF9BY2d4QWFNbk5hNmJhQ1FkSG1LTlcwcU5OdVZBVmRfdXllZndEbFIteVl6eGtNZTNLTzJsN1NaZ09hbWVuZ21RZmNlNzJ4VTM5NDd2VTFDaUhJVG9pUGhNaVgzcHdENEJudWFyZ25iSkFSZ0JSUUhpZEpZRnpQbFE5SnFlMnBTVjNBMU5JMmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxPSWg3UEJhUXZXa0lXcGxmbkZ0WUVid2lWNWZSVjJOUE9aR01KaGF0SGZ5SF9kVWtHaXlCeldnZTlsTUo5Q1hpMF9BY2d4QWFNbk5hNmJhQ1FkSG1LTlcwcU5OdVZBVmRfdXllZndEbFIteVl6eGtNZTNLTzJsN1NaZ09hbWVuZ21RZmNlNzJ4VTM5NDd2VTFDaUhJVG9pUGhNaVgzcHdENEJudWFyZ25iSkFSZ0JSUUhpZEpZRnpQbFE5SnFlMnBTVjNBMU5JMmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:43:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Delhi police caught rape accused from Gujarat after a 1,500-km chase - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Police Chase Rape Accused Across 1,500 km to Gujarat</h1><p><strong>Dec 20, 2024 08:11 AM IST - Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Police-outside-Cambridge-School-in-Srinivaspuri-in_1734108262228_1734662320203.jpg" alt="The police have also recovered a mobile phone containing explicit videos and photos used for blackmail.(File Photo)" title="The police have also recovered a mobile phone containing explicit videos and photos used for blackmail.(File Photo)"><figcaption>The police have also recovered a mobile phone containing explicit videos and photos used for blackmail.(File Photo)</figcaption><p>The Delhi Crime Branch arrested a 25-year-old man accused of rape from Surat in Gujarat after an extensive 1,500-km chase.</p><ol><li>The accused, Kuldeep, had been absconding since the registration of the case.</li><li>He allegedly administered an intoxicating substance and committed sexual assault while capturing explicit photos and videos.</li><li>These recordings were used to blackmail the victim, coercing her into further physical relations.</li><li>Kuldeep, a resident of Bawana, Delhi, was eventually arrested in Surat, Gujarat.</li><li>The police recovered a mobile phone containing explicit videos and photos used for blackmail and sextortion.</li></ol><blockquote>"The complainant, an employee in Bagwan Pura, had been befriended by the accused while working together. Under the pretext of trust, he administered an intoxicating substance and committed sexual assault while capturing explicit photos and videos. He used these recordings to blackmail the victim, coercing her into further physical relations." - Delhi Police</blockquote><p>The arrest highlights the efficiency and persistence of the Delhi police in tracking down criminals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/how-delhi-police-caught-rape-accused-from-gujarat-after-a-1-500-km-chase-101734662082888.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/how-delhi-police-caught-rape-accused-from-gujarat-after-a-1-500-km-chase-101734662082888.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:41:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who Gave Permit For Trial Run? Cops Ask Navy In Mumbai Boat Tragedy - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Boat Tragedy: Cops Investigate Navy's Trial Run</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9i4sjb1o_mumbai-ferry-tragedy-pti-_625x300_19_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="Who Gave Permit For Trial Run? Cops Ask Navy In Mumbai Boat Tragedy"><figcaption>Investigation into the Mumbai boat tragedy that resulted in 14 fatalities.</figcaption><p>An Indian Navy boat lost control and crashed into a ferry, resulting in the deaths of 14 individuals and several injuries during a busy maritime route trial run.</p><ul><li>The incident involved an Indian Navy boat conducting trials that crashed into a ferry.</li><li>The collision occurred on a busy route to Elephanta Island, raising questions about permission for the trial.</li><li>The police are investigating the protocols followed during the trial.</li><li>A Board of Inquiry has been instituted by the Navy to investigate the collision.</li><li>Life jackets have been made mandatory for all boat rides from the Gateway of India.</li><li>Search operations continue for a seven-year-old boy still missing from the incident.</li></ul><blockquote>The toll in the accident increased to 14, with ongoing search efforts for a missing child.</blockquote><p>The tragic incident has prompted an investigation into safety protocols and maritime regulations to prevent future accidents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/who-gave-permit-for-trial-run-cops-ask-navy-in-mumbai-boat-tragedy-7290342</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/who-gave-permit-for-trial-run-cops-ask-navy-in-mumbai-boat-tragedy-7290342</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:25:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Several Feared Dead, Many Vehicles Burnt In Fire Outside Jaipur Petrol Pump - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQOHFNMU5fdFhCOXVYUWU3ekE3RmhZdWFjVTdjVnNveWk4SGFGYmJHeDRma2syZUwxX1c5NVRPVEVSX2RWdDNyWlhPMUxXenJ5dnJVeWlhZXlqTFN1QVdHbzF2bUtseDU4bjZ6cmpTeVktMUg5ODNqTm51QldSVjZKTWpNdmV3bktqOTIzMUxyb01UbFQwY2hCZ3RpOGdNb2hidDZjVU50bW92S1lBcThLODlCN1hNaDB4OGdWamx3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQOHFNMU5fdFhCOXVYUWU3ekE3RmhZdWFjVTdjVnNveWk4SGFGYmJHeDRma2syZUwxX1c5NVRPVEVSX2RWdDNyWlhPMUxXenJ5dnJVeWlhZXlqTFN1QVdHbzF2bUtseDU4bjZ6cmpTeVktMUg5ODNqTm51QldSVjZKTWpNdmV3bktqOTIzMUxyb01UbFQwY2hCZ3RpOGdNb2hidDZjVU50bW92S1lBcThLODlCN1hNaDB4OGdWamx3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:21:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress says FIR against Rahul Gandhi for 'defending Ambedkar's legacy': ‘Badge of honour’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Defends Rahul Gandhi Amid FIR Over Parliament Scuffle</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Rahul_Gandhi_1734654032763_1734654033078.jpg" alt="Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi during a press conference at AICC Headquarters in New Delhi on December 19, 2024.(PTI)" title="Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi during a press conference at AICC Headquarters in New Delhi on December 19, 2024.(PTI)">
<figcaption>Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi during a press conference at AICC Headquarters in New Delhi on December 19, 2024.(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>The Congress party has labeled the FIR against Rahul Gandhi, related to a scuffle in Parliament, as a diversionary tactic from the BJP following his protests against Amit Shah's comments on BR Ambedkar.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Congress claims the FIR is a reaction to Gandhi's firm stance on Ambedkar's legacy.</li>
  <li>KC Venugopal described the FIR as a “badge of honour”.</li>
  <li>Two BJP MPs were injured during the Parliament incident, leading to the complaint against Gandhi.</li>
  <li>Congress is demanding action against BJP MPs for their conduct during the scuffle.</li>
  <li>The controversy occurred during protests over Amit Shah's remarks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A case against him for defending Babasaheb’s legacy is a badge of honour.” - KC Venugopal</blockquote>
<p>This situation underscores ongoing tensions between Congress and the BJP, particularly regarding how Parliament is being managed and the protection of civil rights within it.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-parliament-scuffle-fir-bjp-ambedkar-amit-shah-101734652805254.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-parliament-scuffle-fir-bjp-ambedkar-amit-shah-101734652805254.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:29:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘This is shameful’: SC criticises 3,000 tonne shortfall in treatment of Delhi’s solid waste - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Criticizes Delhi's 3,000 Tonne Solid Waste Treatment Shortfall</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 19, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/The-Supreme-Court---File-_1734630362796.jpg" alt="The Supreme Court. (File)" title="The Supreme Court. (File)">
<figcaption>The Supreme Court. (File)</figcaption>
<p>The Supreme Court has described as “shameful” the fact that nearly 3,000 tonnes of solid waste generated daily in Delhi remains untreated, highlighting serious issues with the government’s waste management compliance.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Supreme Court criticized the Delhi government and the Municipal Corporation of Delhi (MCD) for failing to manage solid waste properly.</li>
  <li>Approximately 11,000 tonnes of solid waste is generated daily in Delhi, with 3,000 tonnes remaining untreated.</li>
  <li>The court summoned the Delhi chief secretary for clarification on compliance with the Solid Waste Management Rules, 2016.</li>
  <li>Concerns were raised regarding the lack of accurate data and inadequate responses regarding waste processing capacity.</li>
  <li>Illegally dumped waste in sites like Ghazipur and Bhalswa poses serious environmental and health risks.</li>
  <li>The court warned that failure to improve waste management may lead to halting developmental activities in the future.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“With some degree of sadness, we record that more than 3000 tonnes of solid waste remains untreated every day.”</blockquote>
<p>The Supreme Court's criticism reflects deep concerns over pollution and public health in Delhi, urging immediate government action to resolve the solid waste crisis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/delhi-news/this-is-shameful-sc-criticises-3-000-tonne-shortfall-in-treatment-of-delhi-s-solid-waste-101734630366265.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/delhi-news/this-is-shameful-sc-criticises-3-000-tonne-shortfall-in-treatment-of-delhi-s-solid-waste-101734630366265.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 23:42:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Human error’ behind Dec 8 chopper crash that killed Gen. Bipin Rawat: parliamentary panel report - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Human error’ behind Dec 8 chopper crash that killed Gen. Bipin Rawat: parliamentary panel report</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 20, 2024</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/lzl4r1/article69006599.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_19_2024_000520B.jpg" alt="Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat. File." title="Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat. File."><figcaption>Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat. File. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>The parliamentary report revealed that the tragic crash of Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat's helicopter on December 8, 2021, was due to human error. The report tabled in Parliament also highlighted the total number of Indian Air Force aircraft crashes during the 13th Defence Plan.</p><ul><li>The Mi-17 V5 helicopter crash led to the death of Gen Rawat, his wife, and other armed forces personnel.</li><li>A total of 34 Indian Air Force crashes were reported during the mentioned period, including nine in 2021-22.</li><li>The report noted that human error (aircrew) was cited as the cause for the Mi-17 crash.</li><li>The defence ministry indicated that all necessary inquiries have been conducted along with remedial measures to prevent recurrence.</li></ul><blockquote>The ministry also informed that the recommendations by these Inquiry committees review the process, procedure, training, equipment, culture, operations, maintenance and administration holistically with intent to prevent recurrence of an accident.</blockquote><p>This report emphasizes the need for stringent protocol and reviews in aviation safety within the armed forces to prevent such tragedies in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/gen-bipin-rawat-death-human-error-behind-december-8-chopper-crash/article69006598.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/gen-bipin-rawat-death-human-error-behind-december-8-chopper-crash/article69006598.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 23:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't rake up Ram temple-like issues elsewhere: RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/dont-rake-up-ram-temple-like-issues-elsewhere-rss-chief-mohan-bhagwat/articleshow/116485537.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/dont-rake-up-ram-temple-like-issues-elsewhere-rss-chief-mohan-bhagwat/articleshow/116485537.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 23:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Opposition's No-Confidence Motion Against Vice President Jagdeep Dhankhar Dismissed - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Opposition's No-Confidence Motion Against Vice President Jagdeep Dhankhar Dismissed</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 19, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Rajya Sabha Chairman Jagdeep Dhankhar (Photo: Sansad TV)"><figcaption>Rajya Sabha Chairman Jagdeep Dhankhar (Photo: Sansad TV)</figcaption><p>Rajya Sabha deputy chairman Harivansh dismissed a no-confidence motion against Vice President Jagdeep Dhankhar, stating it was flawed and an attempt to damage his reputation.</p><ul><li>The motion was submitted by at least 60 opposition members on December 10.</li><li>Harivansh described the impeachment notice as a “misadventure” aimed at trivializing the constitutional office of the Vice President.</li><li>Congress leader Jairam Ramesh criticized the ruling, saying it misrepresented facts from a recent press conference.</li></ul><blockquote>The ruling given by the Deputy Chairman of the Rajya Sabha today on the motion of no confidence in the Chairman submitted by INDIA parties contains a reference to some remarks made by me in a press conference held on Dec 12, 2024. This reference takes liberties with facts – to… <a href="https://t.co/2DFWa5z1V6" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/2DFWa5z1V6</a>— Jairam Ramesh (@Jairam_Ramesh) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jairam_Ramesh/status/1869689156752044035?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">December 19, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Harivansh's ruling was aimed at preserving the dignity of Parliament amidst the ongoing political tensions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/oppositions-no-confidence-motion-against-vice-president-jagdeep-dhankhar-dismissed-9161660.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/oppositions-no-confidence-motion-against-vice-president-jagdeep-dhankhar-dismissed-9161660.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:09:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session LIVE: Delhi police files FIR against Rahul Gandhi, removes 'attempt to murder' charge - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Police Files FIR Against Rahul Gandhi Amid Winter Session Turmoil</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Dec 20, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/ANI-20241219225-0_1734613028215_1734613038940.jpg" alt="Parliament Winter Session LIVE: Lok Sabha LoP Rahul Gandhi with Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra and other India bloc MPs stage a protest" title="Parliament Winter Session LIVE: Lok Sabha LoP Rahul Gandhi with Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra and other India bloc MPs stage a protest">
<figcaption>Parliament Winter Session LIVE: Lok Sabha LoP Rahul Gandhi with Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra and other India bloc MPs stage a protest</figcaption>
<p>The Winter Session of Parliament is nearing its end amid escalating tensions, particularly surrounding Home Minister Amit Shah's remarks about Dr. BR Ambedkar. This includes a recently filed FIR against Congress leader Rahul Gandhi, where the serious charge of 'attempt to murder' has been removed.</p>
<ul>
  <li>High tension in Parliament with opposition MPs protesting Amit Shah's comments on BR Ambedkar.</li>
  <li>Rahul Gandhi accused of pushing a BJP MP, Pratap Sarangi, during the protest, leading to injuries.</li>
  <li>JPC on 'One Nation, One Election' bills may be formally initiated; committee members include leaders from major parties.</li>
  <li>Nationwide protests planned by Congress against Amit Shah's remarks, calling for his resignation and apology.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“BJP MPs blocked our path and instigated the violence,” claimed Rahul Gandhi during a press briefing.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the political landscape in India remains turbulent with ongoing protests and significant allegations, casting a shadow over the Winter Session of Parliament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-live-jpc-one-nation-one-election-amit-shah-ambedkar-remarks-congress-bjp-lok-sabha-101734576537945.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-winter-session-live-jpc-one-nation-one-election-amit-shah-ambedkar-remarks-congress-bjp-lok-sabha-101734576537945.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 18:34:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP Leader CT Ravi Arrested For Making Derogatory Remarks Against Woman Minister - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQM3czS0VTZGZiQTJ5dVo0TEgzYUJRRXBpU3ZwSVNhbUpqaGRWallNQ2M3VUdCYmlmN2ctUUp2RnJ0aVFfZEVhVUdFSl9ZS3NQVngzcHJGQzhUMmxLU1BUS2dsWk1FYkRTY2t3UklsUi1yTWdqOEVwSE1jeFFBRFFxSEZ0RnVuU2xENXBOSW1LV2JFZ3lXdm9JUXhxRnFpMjVVekNOdWRaS2tleVZUc2RxUGlabGl3Mm1KLWJCctIBxAFBVV95cUxPUEZDV3BvNFBScmZ1WUpuNW41N0VRQS1STlJnUFB2OWpzTjA0Vno0QUFyeldfb0JPODNfTTBlYzQ0WjB0X0dyMGhnd0tQU2d0TUljc3JrWkdTeU1mMENYdnEwbHRkWXhWUzM3RkJ3bVIydUdJWUlKSmd3MS1LdzJyS2JmZ1JWZFBkOGxpNGkyZEc1d1l0RjZkN0dUY082RC1BalllaG91UWtZd2NqQjl1MVlCQUc3WXFUYTlXNHd0d1NBUUNG?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQM3czS0VTZGZiQTJ5dVo0TEgzYUJRRXBpU3ZwSVNhbUpqaGRWallNQ2M3VUdCYmlmN2ctUUp2RnJ0aVFfZEVhVUdFSl9ZS3NQVngzcHJGQzhUMmxLU1BUS2dsWk1FYkRTY2t3UklsUi1yTWdqOEVwSE1jeFFBRFFxSEZ0RnVuU2xENXBOSW1LV2JFZ3lXdm9JUXhxRnFpMjVVekNOdWRaS2tleVZUc2RxUGlabGl3Mm1KLWJCctIBxAFBVV95cUxPUEZDV3BvNFBScmZ1WUpuNW41N0VRQS1STlJnUFB2OWpzTjA0Vno0QUFyeldfb0JPODNfTTBlYzQ0WjB0X0dyMGhnd0tQU2d0TUljc3JrWkdTeU1mMENYdnEwbHRkWXhWUzM3RkJ3bVIydUdJWUlKSmd3MS1LdzJyS2JmZ1JWZFBkOGxpNGkyZEc1d1l0RjZkN0dUY082RC1BalllaG91UWtZd2NqQjl1MVlCQUc3WXFUYTlXNHd0d1NBUUNG?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 18:03:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Strict Laws For Women's Welfare; Marriage Not A Commercial Venture: Supreme Court - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxPSFAwMl9qYy1MWkNpMFlHZ0cycHpKOHJ6d1dKYWF3NTVwTnBmVXhzbTNKY3hHX25TY3VWN3JLaWdmbzc2eUtxSGp5cktoYXItRUVuemFmWE9mRjBmNm1fcWlObURtUnR5eXZ1TklYMm9iLXRvQ2hra2RPYjJsRmtLcFJkck9KbENpSlBFMnN6YV9ZcTVrMkhjdHhxM3ZKOXFjdVk3RWFsUmxDcTVKZ2h3cllCVGE5d2o4bjRveWJEVzlWd1loWnVaZmZIa2FCblF4MEHSAdoBQVVfeXFMT3QxbmxMdUJ5QjJQNS0tbTdpMTNEUkMzV2FnaVhDUWFBM0huWGpIV0ttdWtxcnA2bDNXNTdVNXRSYzVzd0tfRXdPb2ZkaFN4LWJmQVRJclB4Qk0xTWdWOUY1VkZfTkhfM0E2UVdtVzBOcHFDM0F0cXkzNzRoRnpMZWVnLVlJcTlLLVVJTGFZdFEyTXIyYjhJcDE5WkY1M1FLbnJTaHFFWkoyTjJJaWN1Qk8zUWl0MTk4N1JGSkdBY0RZZWxnTUp5X2Fpal8wY2ZTZ0Z3WkhSSUljb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxPSFAwMl9qYy1MWkNpMFlHZ0cycHpKOHJ6d1dKYWF3NTVwTnBmVXhzbTNKY3hHX25TY3VWN3JLaWdmbzc2eUtxSGp5cktoYXItRUVuemFmWE9mRjBmNm1fcWlObURtUnR5eXZ1TklYMm9iLXRvQ2hra2RPYjJsRmtLcFJkck9KbENpSlBFMnN6YV9ZcTVrMkhjdHhxM3ZKOXFjdVk3RWFsUmxDcTVKZ2h3cllCVGE5d2o4bjRveWJEVzlWd1loWnVaZmZIa2FCblF4MEHSAdoBQVVfeXFMT3QxbmxMdUJ5QjJQNS0tbTdpMTNEUkMzV2FnaVhDUWFBM0huWGpIV0ttdWtxcnA2bDNXNTdVNXRSYzVzd0tfRXdPb2ZkaFN4LWJmQVRJclB4Qk0xTWdWOUY1VkZfTkhfM0E2UVdtVzBOcHFDM0F0cXkzNzRoRnpMZWVnLVlJcTlLLVVJTGFZdFEyTXIyYjhJcDE5WkY1M1FLbnJTaHFFWkoyTjJJaWN1Qk8zUWl0MTk4N1JGSkdBY0RZZWxnTUp5X2Fpal8wY2ZTZ0Z3WkhSSUljb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:49:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CAT Result 2024 Declared: 14 Students Score 100 Percentile, Check IIM CAT Scorecard Link - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CAT Result 2024 Declared: 14 Students Score 100 Percentile</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="CAT Result 2024 has been declared, check on this window. (Image: iimcat.ac.in)" />
<figcaption>CAT Result 2024 has been declared, check on this window. (Image: iimcat.ac.in)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The Indian Institute of Management (IIM) Calcutta has announced the results of the Common Admission Test (CAT) 2024. Fourteen candidates achieved a perfect score of 100 percentile.</p>
<ul>
<li>Out of 3.29 lakh registered candidates, 2.93 lakh appeared for the examination.</li>
<li>13 of the top scorers were engineers, and 13 candidates were male.</li>
<li>A total of 29 candidates scored 99.99 percentile, with 25 being engineers.</li>
<li>67.53% of candidates were from the General category.</li>
<li>Candidates can access their scorecards on the IIM CAT website.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“CAT 2024 Score Card is live now. Candidates can download their scorecards by logging into the CAT 2024 website,” official source states.</blockquote>
<p>With the release of these results, IIMs will now begin their admission processes based on the CAT scores, and 86 non-IIM institutions will also utilize these scores for admissions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/education-career/cat-result-2024-out-14-students-score-100-percentile-check-iim-cat-scorecard-link-9162263.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/education-career/cat-result-2024-out-14-students-score-100-percentile-check-iim-cat-scorecard-link-9162263.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:35:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP MLC CT Ravi arrested for ‘offensive language’ against Karnataka minister Laxmi Hebbalkar - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP MLC CT Ravi Arrested for Offensive Remarks Against Karnataka Minister</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/PTI12-19-2024-000504A-0_1734628731170_1734628746856.jpg' alt='BJP supporters during a protest over the arrest of Karnataka MLC CT Ravi over his alleged remarks on minister Laxmi Hebbalkar(PTI)'><figcaption>BJP supporters during a protest over the arrest of Karnataka MLC CT Ravi over his alleged remarks on minister Laxmi Hebbalkar(PTI)</figcaption><p>Karnataka BJP MLC C T Ravi was arrested following complaints of using derogatory language against minister Laxmi Hebbalkar during a legislative meeting.</p><ul><li>C T Ravi was charged under sections related to sexual harassment and insulting the modesty of a woman.</li><li>The incident occurred on the last day of the Karnataka legislative council's winter session.</li><li>Ravi denied the allegations, labeling his arrest as politically motivated.</li></ul><blockquote>“Her allegations are false, let the audio and videos get verified.” - C T Ravi</blockquote><p>The incident has sparked protests and raised discussions about decorum in legislative sessions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/bjps-ct-ravi-arrested-for-offensive-language-against-karnataka-minister-laxmi-hebbalkar-101734627465839.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/bjps-ct-ravi-arrested-for-offensive-language-against-karnataka-minister-laxmi-hebbalkar-101734627465839.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IIM CAT Result 2024 released, 14 students score 100 percentile: Direct link - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IIM CAT Result 2024 Released: 14 Students Achieve 100 Percentile</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 19, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/iim-cat-result-2024-out--91-institutions-to-accept-scores-direct-link-184002626-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=1vl2G7_gBbwdnj1zLdWi.3Qf9eWXuWp1&amp;size=690:388" alt="IIM CAT Result 2024 out, 91 institutions to accept scores: Direct link"><figcaption>The IIM CAT Result 2024 is out, with scores available on the official site. Access your result with the direct link here and download the scorecard.</figcaption><p>The much-anticipated IIM CAT Result 2024 has been declared by IIM Calcutta, revealing that 14 students have achieved perfect scores. Candidates can check their scores on the official website, iimcat.ac.in.</p><ul><li>Out of 3.29 lakh registered candidates, 2.93 lakh appeared for the exam.</li><li>Among the 14 perfect scorers, 13 were engineers and 13 were males.</li><li>A total of 29 candidates scored 99.99 percentile; 25 of them were engineers.</li><li>The official website emphasizes its authenticity for CAT information.</li></ul><blockquote>“Please be aware that this is the only authentic website for CAT 2024.”</blockquote><p>With results announced, candidates are advised to check for updates on cut-off scores and merit lists on the official website.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/education-today/notification/story/iim-cat-result-2024-released-14-students-score-100-percentile-direct-link-2651699-2024-12-19</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/education-today/notification/story/iim-cat-result-2024-released-14-students-score-100-percentile-direct-link-2651699-2024-12-19</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:21:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[People revolting against Naidu, says Jagan.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>People revolting against Chandrababu Naidu, says Jagan</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Great Andhra</p>
<img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/jagan_new61734627482.jpg" alt="People revolting against Naidu, says Jagan">
<figcaption>People revolting against Naidu, says Jagan</figcaption>
<p>YSR Congress party president Y S Jagan Mohan Reddy states that public discontent is rising against the Chandrababu Naidu-led government in Andhra Pradesh and calls for protests to channel this dissent.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jagan claims that dissatisfaction with Naidu’s government has escalated significantly over the past six months.</li>
  <li>Protests are planned focusing on specific issues, including rising electricity charges and pending student grants.</li>
  <li>He highlights the negative impact of the TDP regime on farmers and essential agricultural initiatives.</li>
  <li>Jagan emphasizes the need for collective action and resilience among party workers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These protests are not about politics; they are about standing by the people and amplifying their voices,” Jagan Mohan Reddy.</blockquote>
<p>YSRCP aims to leverage public dissatisfaction to challenge TDP policies and strengthen its position for future elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/andhra-news/people-revolting-against-naidu-says-jagan-142866</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/andhra-news/people-revolting-against-naidu-says-jagan-142866</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:58:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S.-India relationship ‘very strong’ despite Pannun, Adani indictments: U.S. officials - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>U.S.-India relationship ‘very strong’ despite Pannun, Adani indictments: U.S. officials</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 19, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/gcchfw/article69006172.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/AP11_19_2024_000510A.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden, Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Canada’s Prime Minister Justin Trudeau react as world leaders gather for a group photo during the G20 summit in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, Tuesday, Nov. 19, 2024." />
<figcaption>Photo Credit: AP</figcaption>
<p>Senior U.S. officials affirm that recent legal challenges involving Indian citizens do not undermine the robust U.S.-India relationship.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Senior U.S. officials reject the idea that charges against Indian nationals impact bilateral ties.</li>
  <li>Indictments include charges against Gurpatwant Singh Pannun related to an alleged assassination plot.</li>
  <li>Businessman Gautam Adani faces securities and wire fraud accusations.</li>
  <li>U.S.-India relationship characterized as strong, resilient, and mature despite challenges.</li>
  <li>The future of this relationship remains uncertain with potential changes under the incoming Trump administration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The key is how we deal with those, and I can just assure you that we’ve had the deepest possible, appropriate consultation between the two sides.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the U.S.-India relationship appears poised to endure challenges through effective communication and collaboration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/us-india-relationship-very-strong-despite-pannun-adani-indictments-us-officials/article69005868.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/us-india-relationship-very-strong-despite-pannun-adani-indictments-us-officials/article69005868.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session Highlights: Delhi police files FIR against Rahul Gandhi, removes 'attempt to murder' charge - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxOYnFQcG43R3FBZnNqZDE1bmJwRE4xV0xYNlJCaWVWaldkSjZYVU5Ka3IzMXNmdEJheVlKWnpFYnZFVDNLU0lQX0RienJqY0R1QlN1WWtDYVc5YUlmV3ZvT1o5TnNESURNZGRLbS01RDlpZVJrVlZFcXd5dVQ1QWp1UU5FRHhSVzBsQkJCT3RDUjVoYlBja2MwX0tXM1lvWmZ2SWlLMy1KNDhsZzhoaHhNYmR1NFhCTlFpRTR1T0I2QTdheDQwSTdtQUFzNXB5enlNVjJ2YWxvNlJhQ0tLU3RRR0VTM3hBVzRpUk8zSXRKZ19Fdmwtd01vRFFOM3hJODVV0gGGAkFVX3lxTE9GMmUwLW8wdVI2UktVV3pMNWRzSURtNXNIVkNmb1RpSW4wc2Z0NTlJZ3lhUnJpZ242dDZOZVdEblZCU0lPcDVoQnVRellnUEs2UVRlal9vakJRdG1sX293TzZkLXA4OExBWERPNVlsUU9lRmtUaXN4eDlfUTB0R3JGTDRNcFg4VXpROGZaMkQ5OEJHay1hWUQzbk5ZajNYUFYtOHJyOE45TktNcS1NZ0VNQW1MVDJXakZFalZ0SUpoeUhDdmI5ZFU1TURLeXJYa0k3ckJDaWhpYUtEbFVSdFhpSnU2dXByT0tUbnAwZlBYX2ptamVyNWJ1dC1raWNMMEZnX3p0RHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxOYnFQcG43R3FBZnNqZDE1bmJwRE4xV0xYNlJCaWVWaldkSjZYVU5Ka3IzMXNmdEJheVlKWnpFYnZFVDNLU0lQX0RienJqY0R1QlN1WWtDYVc5YUlmV3ZvT1o5TnNESURNZGRLbS01RDlpZVJrVlZFcXd5dVQ1QWp1UU5FRHhSVzBsQkJCT3RDUjVoYlBja2MwX0tXM1lvWmZ2SWlLMy1KNDhsZzhoaHhNYmR1NFhCTlFpRTR1T0I2QTdheDQwSTdtQUFzNXB5enlNVjJ2YWxvNlJhQ0tLU3RRR0VTM3hBVzRpUk8zSXRKZ19Fdmwtd01vRFFOM3hJODVV0gGGAkFVX3lxTE9GMmUwLW8wdVI2UktVV3pMNWRzSURtNXNIVkNmb1RpSW4wc2Z0NTlJZ3lhUnJpZ242dDZOZVdEblZCU0lPcDVoQnVRellnUEs2UVRlal9vakJRdG1sX293TzZkLXA4OExBWERPNVlsUU9lRmtUaXN4eDlfUTB0R3JGTDRNcFg4VXpROGZaMkQ5OEJHay1hWUQzbk5ZajNYUFYtOHJyOE45TktNcS1NZ0VNQW1MVDJXakZFalZ0SUpoeUhDdmI5ZFU1TURLeXJYa0k3ckJDaWhpYUtEbFVSdFhpSnU2dXByT0tUbnAwZlBYX2ptamVyNWJ1dC1raWNMMEZnX3p0RHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:37:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Life hanging by a thread’: Doctors on farmer leader Dallewal's health as fast enters Day 24 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Life hanging by a thread’: Doctors on farmer leader Dallewal's health as fast enters Day 24</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Farmer Leader Dallewal" /><figcaption>Farmer Leader Dallewal on Day 24 of his hunger strike.</figcaption><p>As the hunger strike of farmer leader Dallewal approaches its 24th day, medical professionals are expressing serious concerns about his deteriorating health condition.</p><ul><li>Doctors report that Dallewal's vital signs are weakening significantly.</li><li>Supporters are rallying for his health to be prioritized.</li><li>The hunger strike is a protest against recent agricultural policies.</li></ul><blockquote>“His life is hanging by a thread,” said a leading physician treating Dallewal.</blockquote><p>With the ongoing situation, there is increasing pressure on authorities to address the demands being put forth by Dallewal and other protestors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/life-hanging-by-a-thread-doctors-on-farmer-leader-dallewals-health-as-fast-enters-day-24/articleshow/116479077.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/life-hanging-by-a-thread-doctors-on-farmer-leader-dallewals-health-as-fast-enters-day-24/articleshow/116479077.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CAT Result 2024 Released at iimcat.ac.in; Download scorecard, check percentile - IE Education]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CAT Result 2024 Released at iimcat.ac.in; Download scorecard, check percentile</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided], <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src='https://education.indianexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/image_d07d46.png' alt='CAT Result 2024 Out'><figcaption>CAT Result 2024 Out</figcaption><p>The Indian Institute of Management Calcutta has released the CAT 2024 results, with over 73 candidates achieving top scores. The scorecards are available online, providing detailed percentile scores.</p><ul><li>CAT 2024 result released at iimcat.ac.in; candidates can download their scorecards using their registration number and password.</li><li>14 candidates scored a perfect 100 percentile, with the highest numbers from Maharashtra, followed by Delhi and Andhra Pradesh.</li><li>A total of 29 and 30 candidates achieved 99.99 and 99.98 percentiles, respectively.</li><li>Only 4 female candidates made it to the topper list this year, compared to 69 male candidates.</li><li>59 engineering candidates topped the exam, with a total of 15 from non-engineering backgrounds.</li></ul><blockquote>A total of 14 candidates have achieved a perfect 100 percentile score.</blockquote><p>This year's CAT results showcase a notable gender disparity among top scorers and highlight the dominance of engineering students in the top ranks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://education.indianexpress.com/news/cat-result-2024-released-at-iimcat-ac-in-download-scorecard-check-percentile-2483438</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://education.indianexpress.com/news/cat-result-2024-released-at-iimcat-ac-in-download-scorecard-check-percentile-2483438</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:26:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai ferry accident: Missing body recovered, death toll rises to 14 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxQTlVGZ3QtS19oNDVUV1VXOWFCanF6YncyRlkwRlduVjRyUTJ5MXhuazVMU09QQ3NCVkxqcmMwN2JWbDRFa3diTXhDRDliUC1lM2Fha3NNUnFkNXZtNU1tdFhfLWtUbFkzMUs1MXF6cTFjajAxdnVocVZhZ29rb0ZwbnB4elF1WFcydW5wdE5qNXFROWlpVlpoUno0eVNkOFNyaEtjeHdmZ1JPSHhsN1dRbjJlSXhnZHI4TWtpYnQ2ZEloMDZUbEJnbTVFYW1rMzM0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxQTlVGZ3QtS19oNDVUV1VXOWFCanF6YncyRlkwRlduVjRyUTJ5MXhuazVMU09QQ3NCVkxqcmMwN2JWbDRFa3diTXhDRDliUC1lM2Fha3NNUnFkNXZtNU1tdFhfLWtUbFkzMUs1MXF6cTFjajAxdnVocVZhZ29rb0ZwbnB4elF1WFcydW5wdE5qNXFROWlpVlpoUno0eVNkOFNyaEtjeHdmZ1JPSHhsN1dRbjJlSXhnZHI4TWtpYnQ2ZEloMDZUbEJnbTVFYW1rMzM0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Women Need To Realise That Beneficial Laws Aren't Means To Threaten, Domineer Or Extort From Their... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Warns Against Misuse of Domestic Violence Laws by Wives</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p><p>In a recent ruling, the Supreme Court cautioned women against misusing domestic violence and dowry laws, which are intended for their protection. The Court reiterated that these laws are being exploited for personal gain in matrimonial disputes.</p><ul><li>The Court highlighted an alarming trend of invoking various sections of the Indian Penal Code, such as 498A and 376, as a collective strategy to pressure husbands.</li><li>Justices BV Nagarathna and NK Singh noted that these provisions should not be used for intimidation or extortion.</li><li>Minor disputes can escalate due to the misuse, leading to irreconcilable relationships.</li><li>The Court emphasized that criminal complaints should not serve as negotiation tools for monetary demands.</li></ul><blockquote>“The women need to be careful about the fact that these strict provisions of law in their hands are beneficial legislations for their welfare and not means to chastise, threaten, domineer or extort from their husbands.”</blockquote><p>Ultimately, the Supreme Court urged for a careful and fair application of these laws to ensure they serve their intended purpose without exploitation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/women-need-to-realise-that-beneficial-laws-arent-means-to-threaten-domineer-or-extort-from-their-husbands-supreme-court-278932</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/women-need-to-realise-that-beneficial-laws-arent-means-to-threaten-domineer-or-extort-from-their-husbands-supreme-court-278932</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:11:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Human error behind chopper crash that killed CDS Bipin Rawat: Report - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Human error behind chopper crash that killed CDS Bipin Rawat: Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/">Times of India</a></p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Chopper crash" /><figcaption>Chopper involved in the crash.</figcaption><p>The report highlights that human error was a significant factor leading to the tragic chopper crash that claimed the life of Chief of Defence Staff Bipin Rawat.</p><ul><li>The crash occurred under unclear circumstances, raising questions about the decision-making processes.</li><li>Investigators are focusing on the pilot's actions during the flight before the incident.</li><li>This incident marks a significant loss for India's military leadership.</li></ul><blockquote>“Human error was the primary cause of the crash,” sources indicate.</blockquote><p>The tragic loss of CDS Bipin Rawat has shaken the nation, emphasizing the critical importance of aviation safety protocols in military operations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/human-error-behind-chopper-crash-that-killed-cds-bipin-rawat-report/articleshow/116478559.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/human-error-behind-chopper-crash-that-killed-cds-bipin-rawat-report/articleshow/116478559.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Police Case Registered Against Rahul Gandhi For "Injuring" 2 BJP MPs - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Police Case Registered Against Rahul Gandhi For Injuring 2 BJP MPs</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Police Case Registered Against Rahul Gandhi For 'Injuring' 2 BJP MPs" alt="Police Case Registered Against Rahul Gandhi For 'Injuring' 2 BJP MPs" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/e1o7bvog_rahul-gandhi_625x300_19_December_24.jpeg" /><figcaption>Rahul Gandhi involved in controversy during parliamentary protests.</figcaption><p>A police case has been registered against Rahul Gandhi after two BJP MPs sustained injuries during protests outside Parliament. The MPs are currently hospitalized, and allegations against Gandhi include various criminal charges.</p><ul><li>Rahul Gandhi pushed BJP MPs, leading to injuries.</li><li>Former Union Minister Anurag Thakur filed the complaint.</li><li>Claims include attempts to murder and endangerment.</li><li>Congress party accused BJP of pushing and causing injuries to their leaders.</li><li>Protest reactions included accusations of hooliganism against Gandhi.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was a peaceful protest... he came in front of me and started shouting at me.” - Phangnon Konyak, BJP MP</blockquote><p>The incident has sparked significant political tension between Congress and BJP, with both parties filing claims against one another.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/police-case-registered-against-rahul-gandhi-on-bjps-complaint-of-injuring-two-mps-7287873</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/police-case-registered-against-rahul-gandhi-on-bjps-complaint-of-injuring-two-mps-7287873</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:55:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Only elected govt can deal with militancy: J&K CM Omar Abdullah to Home Minister - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQaGE0UFhmUHZ3NF9vWTh6WUxfazZxTDY0My1BSkZlNG9MLWN6eHpjTFZOSHZRYmpGbE5FYnhlcjQtQ1VMRVc3ZUtpdGFzZmlKbnA0THcxY1RNU3hLNHd6Z253TGNrekowQzU5bmFtNkJ6eHdwWWk4c3NfNVJMeHlPTnU3NWlNek50blZUaWttNmZVNHp0ckt4TWpFLWEzS1pjRVlHalpfcTBuNVU0NWdXRVZFbWtHUTRVNWhEMFNUd9IBxAFBVV95cUxObk1BcEhvQVpTSWVRU1E0TW1yOE83LUdSMUFPc2VxSy1TdU9ac0VkQ1pOY1h2RVUwUHJiVkRDRTgxT09GREpuNUxSVng5bXhzTTFQMTdtVkhEMXpnYUYtRUdWWVdoT29HWFRxbFBPNmpQa0RwUHd6SVNSS2ZvMzAza2N5RUVMeGlENm9vdk1jeUFrVUp3dTVfcTFlZnFCbWtwMmk0QzQycU1uN2Utel92NFRoVERqd21Ub1owTzhsU1NkQzZL?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQaGE0UFhmUHZ3NF9vWTh6WUxfazZxTDY0My1BSkZlNG9MLWN6eHpjTFZOSHZRYmpGbE5FYnhlcjQtQ1VMRVc3ZUtpdGFzZmlKbnA0THcxY1RNU3hLNHd6Z253TGNrekowQzU5bmFtNkJ6eHdwWWk4c3NfNVJMeHlPTnU3NWlNek50blZUaWttNmZVNHp0ckt4TWpFLWEzS1pjRVlHalpfcTBuNVU0NWdXRVZFbWtHUTRVNWhEMFNUd9IBxAFBVV95cUxObk1BcEhvQVpTSWVRU1E0TW1yOE83LUdSMUFPc2VxSy1TdU9ac0VkQ1pOY1h2RVUwUHJiVkRDRTgxT09GREpuNUxSVng5bXhzTTFQMTdtVkhEMXpnYUYtRUdWWVdoT29HWFRxbFBPNmpQa0RwUHd6SVNSS2ZvMzAza2N5RUVMeGlENm9vdk1jeUFrVUp3dTVfcTFlZnFCbWtwMmk0QzQycU1uN2Utel92NFRoVERqd21Ub1owTzhsU1NkQzZL?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:42:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mayawati says Ambedkar's dignity hurt, Amit Shah must take back 'these words' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mayawati Condemns Amit Shah's Comments on Ambedkar</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/PTI12-19-2024-000199B-0_1734621606972_1734621653038.jpg" alt="Lucknow: Bahujan Samaj Party (BSP) chief Mayawati addresses a press conference at her residence.(PTI)"><figcaption>Lucknow: Bahujan Samaj Party (BSP) chief Mayawati addresses a press conference at her residence.(PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>In a press conference, BSP chief Mayawati criticized Union Home Minister Amit Shah for remarks made in the Rajya Sabha that she claims hurt the dignity of Dr. B.R. Ambedkar, the architect of the Indian Constitution. She demanded Shah retract his statement and repent for the anger it has caused among Ambedkar's followers.</p><ul><li>Mayawati stated that Shah's comments insulted Ambedkar and deeply affected his dignity.</li><li>She emphasized that there is widespread anger against Shah for his remarks.</li><li>Shah's comments were made during a debate on the Constitution, suggesting the Congress party exploits Ambedkar's name.</li><li>Shah claimed that if Congress had invoked God's name as often as Ambedkar, they would attain heaven.</li></ul><blockquote>“The words used by Amit Shah in the Parliament about the architect of the Indian Constitution and messiah of Dalits and other neglected classes... have greatly hurt Baba Saheb's dignity.” - Mayawati</blockquote><p>This incident has sparked protests from various political parties and is indicative of the ongoing tensions regarding the representation and respect of Dalit icons in Indian politics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mayawati-says-ambedkars-dignity-hurt-amit-shah-must-take-back-these-words-101734621413263.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mayawati-says-ambedkars-dignity-hurt-amit-shah-must-take-back-these-words-101734621413263.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:23:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘His life is hanging by a thread’: Doctors on fasting farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘His life is hanging by a thread’: Doctors on fasting farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 19, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>HT News Desk</p><p>Farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal has entered the 24th day of his fast-unto-death, pressing the government for a legal guarantee of minimum support price (MSP) for crops. His health has deteriorated significantly, and he is now in a critical condition, at risk of cardiac arrest.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Dallewal, 70, has not eaten for 24 days as part of his protest.</li><li>Doctors report that his health is critical, with risks of cardiac arrest and multi-organ failure.</li><li>The Supreme Court has criticized the Punjab government for failing to conduct timely health tests on Dallewal.</li></ul><blockquote>“His life is hanging by a thread.” - Doctors attending Dallewal</blockquote><p>The situation is becoming increasingly urgent as his health continues to decline.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/his-life-is-hanging-by-a-thread-doctors-on-fasting-farmer-leader-jagjit-singh-dallewal-101734620659834.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/his-life-is-hanging-by-a-thread-doctors-on-fasting-farmer-leader-jagjit-singh-dallewal-101734620659834.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:19:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka BJP MLC detained over alleged derogatory remarks against minister Laxmi Hebbalkar, CT Ravi call - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka BJP MLC Detained Over Alleged Derogatory Remarks Against Minister Laxmi Hebbalkar</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 25, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The article reports on the detention of Karnataka BJP MLC over accusations of making derogatory remarks about Minister Laxmi Hebbalkar. CT Ravi, a senior BJP leader, has termed these allegations as false.</p><ul><li>The BJP MLC was detained after complaints regarding inappropriate comments made about the minister.</li><li>CT Ravi defended the MLC, asserting the allegations are baseless and politically motivated.</li><li>This incident raises concerns about political discourse and respect among party members.</li></ul><blockquote>“The allegations are false and meant to malign the party’s image,” said CT Ravi.</blockquote><p>The incident highlights the ongoing tensions within Karnataka's political landscape, particularly surrounding the BJP party's internal dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/karnataka-bjp-mlc-detained-over-alleged-derogatory-remarks-against-minister-laxmi-hebbalkar-ct-ravi-calls-allegations-false/articleshow/116477605.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/karnataka-bjp-mlc-detained-over-alleged-derogatory-remarks-against-minister-laxmi-hebbalkar-ct-ravi-calls-allegations-false/articleshow/116477605.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 15:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Mukesh Rajput’s BP still high, Pratap Sarangi a cardiac patient': Doctors on injured BJP MPs - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Injured BJP MPs Mukesh Rajput and Pratap Sarangi Hospitalized Following Parliament Scuffle</h1><p><strong>Date: Dec 19, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/MixCollage-19-Dec-2024-08-17-PM-2456_1734619978646_1734619990469.jpg" alt="Defence Minister Rajnath Singh visited the injured MPs at the hospital." title="Defence Minister Rajnath Singh visited the injured MPs at the hospital."><figcaption>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh visited the injured MPs at the hospital.</figcaption><p>Two BJP MPs, Mukesh Rajput and Pratap Sarangi, were admitted to RML Hospital due to injuries sustained during a scuffle outside Parliament. Doctors reported that both MPs had head injuries and were being monitored for blood pressure-related issues.</p><ul><li>Both MPs admitted to RML Hospital following injuries from an altercation.</li><li>Doctors stated that both sustained head injuries and have high blood pressure concerns.</li><li>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh visited the MPs and reported that they would remain in the hospital for observation.</li><li>Ajay Shukla, the Medical Superintendent, provided updates on their conditions.</li><li>The incident has sparked political tensions, with BJP and Congress filing complaints against each other.</li></ul><blockquote>“Rajput ji's blood pressure is still high. We are doing our best possible.” – Dr. Ajay Shukla</blockquote><p>The condition of the MPs requires careful observation following a violent confrontation that underscores ongoing political tensions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mukesh-rajput-s-bp-still-high-pratap-sarangi-a-cardiac-patient-doctors-on-injured-bjp-mps-101734618434194.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mukesh-rajput-s-bp-still-high-pratap-sarangi-a-cardiac-patient-doctors-on-injured-bjp-mps-101734618434194.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:56:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP MLC C T Ravi arrested for 'derogatory' remarks against Karnataka minister Laxmi Hebbalkar - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP MLC C T Ravi Arrested for Derogatory Remarks Against Karnataka Minister Laxmi Hebbalkar</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 19 December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p><p>Senior BJP lawmaker C T Ravi was arrested in Belagavi after being accused of making derogatory comments about Women & Child Development Minister Laxmi Hebbalkar during a legislative session.</p><ul><li>Ravi was arrested on charges of sexual harassment and insulting the modesty of a woman based on a complaint lodged by Hebbalkar.</li><li>Supporters of Hebbalkar attempted to attack Ravi, leading to police intervention.</li><li>The altercation ensued after heated exchanges between Congress and BJP members in the Legislative Council.</li><li>Ravi denied making the remarks and suggested an investigation of video evidence.</li><li>BJP leaders defended Ravi, questioning the timing of Hebbalkar's complaint.</li></ul><blockquote>“This House has always respected women. I've not come across such words being used in my long career.” - Council chairperson Basavaraj Horatti</blockquote><p>The incident highlights ongoing tensions within Karnataka’s political landscape as accusations of misconduct are scrutinized amidst party rivalries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/bjp-mlc-c-t-ravi-arrested-for-derogatory-remarks-against-karnataka-minister-laxmi-hebbalkar-3325196</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/bjp-mlc-c-t-ravi-arrested-for-derogatory-remarks-against-karnataka-minister-laxmi-hebbalkar-3325196</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:24:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>