<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:17:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lohri, Makar Sankranti Bank stock market holidays on 13, 14 January 2025? NSE, BSE open or closed? Trading off or not? Exchanges calendar 2025 - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/lohri-makar-sankranti-bank-stock-market-holidays-on-13-14-january-2025-nse-bse-open-or-closed-trading-off-or-not-exchanges-calendar-2025-article-117173136</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/lohri-makar-sankranti-bank-stock-market-holidays-on-13-14-january-2025-nse-bse-open-or-closed-trading-off-or-not-exchanges-calendar-2025-article-117173136</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:14:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lohri, Makar Sankranti Bank stock market holidays on 13, 14 January 2025? NSE, BSE open or closed? Trading off or not? Exchanges calendar 2025 - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/lohri-makar-sankranti-bank-stock-market-holidays-on-13-14-january-2025-nse-bse-open-or-closed-trading-off-or-not-exchanges-calendar-2025-article-117173136</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/lohri-makar-sankranti-bank-stock-market-holidays-on-13-14-january-2025-nse-bse-open-or-closed-trading-off-or-not-exchanges-calendar-2025-article-117173136</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:14:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh summons Indian High Commissioner over rising border tensions - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh Summons Indian Envoy Over Border Tensions</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Pranay-Verma.jpg?w=640" alt="Pranay Verma" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>While no official statement was issued by the interim government regarding the discussions, officials confirmed that Pranay Verma (left) has been summoned. (Photo: X/ MoFA Bangladesh)</figcaption><p>Bangladesh faced off with India Sunday over tensions at the border as the neighbouring country’s foreign ministry summoned High Commissioner Pranay Verma to express “deep concern” over “recent activities of the Border Security Force (BSF)”.</p><p>This came hours after Dhaka alleged that India was attempting to construct fences at five locations along the Indo-Bangla border, violating a bilateral agreement.</p><p>After meeting Bangladesh Foreign Secretary Jashim Uddin, the Indian High Commissioner said: “I just met Foreign Secretary to discuss India’s commitment to ensuring a crime-free border, effectively addressing challenges of smuggling, movement of criminals and trafficking.” “We have an understanding with regard to fencing the border for security. BSF and BGB (Border Guard Bangladesh) have been in communication in this regard. We expect that understandings will be implemented and there will be a cooperative approach to combating crime,” Verma said in Dhaka.</p><p>Earlier in the day, Bangladesh Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd.) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said that India had halted the construction of barbed wire fencing along the border after strong opposition from the BGB and local residents.</p><p>According to the Bangladesh Foreign Ministry, Jashim Uddin told the Indian envoy that the “unauthorized attempt” to construct fences and related operational actions by BSF have caused tensions along the border.</p><p>“He emphasised that the construction of barbed wire fences without proper authorization undermines the spirit of cooperation and friendly relations between the two neighboring countries. He hoped that the upcoming BGB-BSF DG Level Talks would be able to discuss the matter at length,” it said in a statement.</p><p>“Referring to the recent killing of a Bangladesh citizen at Sunamganj by BSF, Foreign Secretary… strongly resented these acts of killing and called for urgent action by the Indian authorities to stop recurrence of such incidents and conduct enquiries into all these border killings and take actions against those responsible,” it said.</p><p>He said Bangladesh believes such issues should be resolved through dialogue.</p><p>This article went live on January 12, 2025, at 6:06 PM.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-indian-high-commissioner-border-tensions-9774904/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-indian-high-commissioner-border-tensions-9774904/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Re-designation of Asad Aijaz as Secretary to Government in J&K - Cross Town News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crosstownnews.in/post/137746/re-designation-of-asad-aijaz-as-secretary-to-government-in-jk.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crosstownnews.in/post/137746/re-designation-of-asad-aijaz-as-secretary-to-government-in-jk.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:57:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BPSC Row: Supporters Of Pappu Yadav Burn Tyres, Block Roads In Bihar - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Protest Erupts in Bihar as Pappu Yadav's Supporters Demand BPSC Exam Cancellation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Pappu Yadav's supporters block roads demanding cancellation and re-examination of BPSC exams. (Courtesy: ANI)"/><figcaption>Pappu Yadav's supporters block roads demanding cancellation and re-examination of BPSC exams. (Courtesy: ANI)</figcaption><p>Independent MP Pappu Yadav’s supporters protested in Patna, calling for the cancellation and re-examination of the Bihar Public Service Commission (BPSC) exam.</p><ul><li>Protesters burned tyres and blocked roads in a demonstration against the BPSC.</li><li>Pappu Yadav has called for a statewide 'Bihar Bandh' today.</li><li>This protest follows long-standing demands from aspirants regarding irregularities in the BPSC exam held on December 13, 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no strength bigger than people’s strength.” - Prashant Kishor</blockquote><p>As tensions escalated, police detained some protesters. The ongoing protests reflect broader issues surrounding the integrity of the BPSC exams and the concerns raised by candidates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/bpsc-row-supporters-of-pappu-yadav-burn-tyres-block-roads-in-bihar-9186198.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/bpsc-row-supporters-of-pappu-yadav-burn-tyres-block-roads-in-bihar-9186198.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:46:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘People in Maharashtra showed Sharad Pawar, Uddhav Thackeray their place’: Amit Shah’s dig over poll results - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amit Shah Criticizes Sharad Pawar and Uddhav Thackeray After Maharashtra Poll Results</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Amit_Shah_1736682210598_1736682210926.jpg" alt="Union Home Minister Amit Shah.(PTI)" title="Union Home Minister Amit Shah.(PTI)"><figcaption>Union Home Minister Amit Shah.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Union Home Minister Amit Shah took a dig at Sharad Pawar and Uddhav Thackeray, stating that the recent Maharashtra assembly election results clearly showed them their place in the political landscape.</p><ul><li>Shah emphasized that the results rejected the politics of dynasty and betrayal.</li><li>The BJP-led Mahayuti alliance secured a historic 233 seats in the assembly elections.</li><li>The Congress-led MVA won only 16 seats, while Thackeray's Shiv Sena secured 20 and Pawar’s NCP just 10.</li></ul><blockquote>“People in Maharashtra showed that Eknath Shinde's Shiv Sena is Balasaheb's Shiv Sena.”</blockquote><p>Shah expressed confidence in winning upcoming elections and remarked that the opposition's confidence has been shaken by the defeat in Maharashtra.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/people-in-maharashtra-showed-sharad-pawar-uddhav-thackeray-their-place-amit-shah-s-dig-over-poll-results-101736681036917.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/people-in-maharashtra-showed-sharad-pawar-uddhav-thackeray-their-place-amit-shah-s-dig-over-poll-results-101736681036917.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:29:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi pollution: GRAP 3 revoked after air quality improves due to rainfall - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Pollution: Stage-I and Stage-II Measures, However, Will Remain in Effect</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 07:20 PM IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Delhi_rain_1736684414274_1736684414603.jpg" alt="New Delhi, Jan 11 (ANI): A man passes on a bicycle at the Kartavya Path as drizzle lashes, in New Delhi on Saturday. (ANI Photo/Ishant)(Ishant )" title="New Delhi, Jan 11 (ANI): A man passes on a bicycle at the Kartavya Path as drizzle lashes, in New Delhi on Saturday. (ANI Photo/Ishant)(Ishant )"><figcaption>New Delhi, Jan 11 (ANI): A man passes on a bicycle at the Kartavya Path as drizzle lashes, in New Delhi on Saturday. (ANI Photo/Ishant)(Ishant )</figcaption></figure><p>The Commission of Air Quality Management (CAQM) revoked the Stage III restrictions under the anti-pollution Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) in Delhi-NCR after the AQI improved due to rainfall.</p><ul><li>The revocation was due to significant improvement in AQI, which dropped from 'very poor' to 'poor' following rain.</li><li>Stage-I and Stage-II measures will remain in effect, including restrictions on private construction.</li><li>The average AQI in Delhi was recorded at 284 post-rain on Sunday.</li></ul><blockquote>“The rain was caused by a western disturbance affecting northwest India,” said Mahesh Palawat, vice president at Skymet.</blockquote><p>The rain has led to a temporary improvement in air quality, providing relief to residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-pollution-grap-3-revoked-after-air-quality-improves-due-to-rainfall-101736684324277.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-pollution-grap-3-revoked-after-air-quality-improves-due-to-rainfall-101736684324277.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:22:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swapping trains at Katra will ensure safety: CM Omar Abdullah - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Safety Measures for Passengers at Katra Railway Station, Says CM Omar Abdullah</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 12, 2023</strong> | <strong>Source: Kashmir News Observer</strong></p>
<p>Chief Minister Omar Abdullah emphasized the importance of passenger safety, supporting the practice of swapping trains at Katra railway station to address security concerns.</p>
<ul>
<li>Omar Abdullah stated that security of passengers is a priority.</li>
<li>He believes people should accept train swapping at Katra if it enhances safety.</li>
<li>The Chief Minister discussed the ski slopes in Gulmarg and the potential for tourism in areas like Sonamarg.</li>
<li>He announced plans for a new convention center in Gulmarg to attract international events.</li>
<li>The long-awaited Z-Morh Tunnel will improve connectivity for local residents and travelers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“At the end of the day, safety must come first,” said Omar Abdullah.</blockquote>
<p>The Chief Minister's remarks highlight the ongoing efforts to ensure passenger safety while promoting tourism and infrastructure development in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/kashmir/swapping-trains-at-katra-will-ensure-safety-cm-omar-abdullah/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/kashmir/swapping-trains-at-katra-will-ensure-safety-cm-omar-abdullah/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:12:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Victory in Maharashtra stopped betrayal politics of Sharad Pawar, Uddhav Thackeray': Amit Shah's big att - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Victory in Maharashtra stopped betrayal politics of Sharad Pawar, Uddhav Thackeray: Amit Shah's big attack on MVA</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Amit Shah delivered a pointed critique of the current Maharashtra government, asserting that their victory signifies a halt to the deceptive politics previously observed.</p><ul><li>Shah claims the MVA alliance betrays public trust.</li><li>Highlights the need for accountability within Maharashtra's political framework.</li><li>Sets the stage for upcoming electoral challenges.</li></ul><blockquote>“Maharashtra has decided to reject betrayal politics,” said Amit Shah during his speech.</blockquote><p>This statement marks a significant moment in the ongoing political narrative of Maharashtra as it addresses issues of integrity and public trust in leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/victory-in-maharashtra-stopped-betrayal-politics-of-sharad-pawar-uddhav-thackeray-amit-shahs-big-attack-on-mva/articleshow/117173752.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/victory-in-maharashtra-stopped-betrayal-politics-of-sharad-pawar-uddhav-thackeray-amit-shahs-big-attack-on-mva/articleshow/117173752.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NEET PG 2024: MCC round 3 counselling deadline extended - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NEET PG 2024: MCC round 3 counselling deadline extended</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source: </strong>Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/11/Untitled-design-78-1.jpg?w=640" alt="NEET PG 2024 Counselling: MCC round 3 choice filing window to begin today at mcc.nic.in" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>The registration deadline for round three has been extended to January 15. (File)</figcaption><p>The Medical Counselling Committee (MCC) has announced an extension for the choice filling and locking window for round three of NEET PG counselling, now set to end on January 16 by 8 am.</p><ul><li>The final seat allotment list is scheduled for release on January 18.</li><li>Eligible candidates can register for PG medical colleges by January 15.</li><li>Reporting and joining at allotted colleges will occur between January 18 and January 25.</li><li>The cut-off percentile has been reduced, with new eligibility criteria for various categories in place.</li></ul><blockquote>“The general and EWS category students scoring 15 percentile and above will be eligible to participate in the counselling.”</blockquote><p>The MCC's revised schedule aims to accommodate students impacted by the new percentile cut-offs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/education/mcc-neet-pg-2024-counselling-round-3-choice-filing-window-out-mcc-nic-in-9774350/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/education/mcc-neet-pg-2024-counselling-round-3-choice-filing-window-out-mcc-nic-in-9774350/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ramesh Bidhuri refutes AAP's 'BJP CM face' claim: 'Arvind Kejriwal accepted...' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ramesh Bidhuri refutes AAP's 'BJP CM face' claim: 'Arvind Kejriwal accepted...'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/PTI01-11-2025-000279A-0_1736680715234_1736680760404.jpg" alt="Ramesh Bidhuri at a BJP event.(PTI file photo)" title="Ramesh Bidhuri at a BJP event.(PTI file photo)">
<figcaption>Ramesh Bidhuri at a BJP event.(PTI file photo)</figcaption>
<p>Ramesh Bidhuri, the BJP candidate for the Kalkaji assembly seat, has rejected Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) chief Arvind Kejriwal's assertion that he would be the chief ministerial face of the BJP, calling it misleading propaganda.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bidhuri emphasizes his loyalty to the BJP and clarity about not seeking any post.</li>
  <li>Kejriwal’s claim implied that BJP would win the upcoming Delhi assembly elections.</li>
  <li>Bidhuri mentions public dissatisfaction with Kejriwal’s governance, citing several scams and issues faced by the people of Delhi.</li>
  <li>Kejriwal challenged Bidhuri to a public debate regarding his candidacy for CM.</li>
  <li>The Delhi assembly election is scheduled for February 5, 2025, with results on February 8.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The party has given me a lot, I have no claim for any post. Arvind Kejriwal has continuously started misleading propaganda against me." - Ramesh Bidhuri</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Ramesh Bidhuri calls for support for the BJP, aiming to reassure the citizens of Delhi of his dedication and intent.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ramesh-bidhuri-reacts-to-arvind-kejriwals-bjp-cm-face-claim-not-a-claimant-for-101736680438254.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ramesh-bidhuri-reacts-to-arvind-kejriwals-bjp-cm-face-claim-not-a-claimant-for-101736680438254.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:21:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Baseless to refer me as BJP's CM face': Ramesh Bidhuri slams Arvind Kejriwal over 'misleading propaganda - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baseless to refer me as BJP's CM face: Ramesh Bidhuri slams Arvind Kejriwal over misleading propaganda</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Available] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Not Available]</p><p>Ramesh Bidhuri has publicly refuted claims made by Arvind Kejriwal, labeling them as misleading propaganda. Bidhuri stated that it is unfounded to refer to him as the BJP's Chief Ministerial candidate.</p><ul><li>Bidhuri denies being the BJP's candidate for CM.</li><li>Accuses Kejriwal of spreading misleading information.</li><li>The political rivalry between BJP and AAP intensifies.</li></ul><blockquote>Bidhuri remarked, "It is baseless to refer to me in such a context."</blockquote><p>Bidhuri's strong stance underscores the ongoing political tensions in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/baseless-to-refer-me-as-bjps-cm-face-ramesh-bidhuri-slams-arvind-kejriwal-over-misleading-propaganda/articleshow/117172859.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/baseless-to-refer-me-as-bjps-cm-face-ramesh-bidhuri-slams-arvind-kejriwal-over-misleading-propaganda/articleshow/117172859.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates: In trial attempt at docking, SpaDeX satellites successfully come 3 meters to each other, says ISRO - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> April 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2023/04/SpaDex_d73f5d.jpg?w=640" alt="ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates: SpaDeX satellites hold position at 15m. (@isro/X)</figcaption><p>In a recent trial attempt, the ISRO conducted a successful maneuver with its SpaDeX satellites, bringing them as close as 3 meters to one another. This experiment is a crucial step towards demonstrating in-space docking.</p><ul><li>The SpaDeX mission aims to demonstrate in-space docking using small spacecraft.</li><li>If successful, India will become the fourth nation capable of this technology, joining the US, Russia, and China.</li><li>The mission is significant for future projects, including lunar missions and establishing a space station by 2035.</li><li>ISRO emphasizes caution due to the complexity of docking moving satellites.</li></ul><blockquote>“Since this is just a technology demonstration mission, getting it right is more important that getting it done on schedule.”</blockquote><p>The SpaDeX mission is an important step for ISRO as it develops its capabilities for future space exploration endeavors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/science/isro-spadex-docking-mission-live-updates-9773511/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/science/isro-spadex-docking-mission-live-updates-9773511/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:00:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Vivekananda said young generation will find solution to all problems, have absolute faith in him': PM Mo - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Highlights Faith in Youth's Problem-Solving Abilities Inspired by Vivekananda</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Various news outlets</p><p>Prime Minister Modi emphasized that the younger generation possesses the capacity to tackle various challenges by drawing inspiration from Swami Vivekananda.</p><ul><li>PM Modi expressed confidence in the youth's problem-solving skills.</li><li>He referenced Vivekananda's teachings as a guide for the younger generation.</li><li>The statement aims to inspire and encourage youth involvement in societal issues.</li></ul><blockquote>"Young generation will find solutions to all problems, have absolute faith in him."</blockquote><p>This message serves to motivate the youth and highlight the importance of their role in shaping the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/vivekananda-said-young-generation-will-find-solution-to-all-problems-have-absolute-faith-in-him-pm-modi/articleshow/117172649.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/vivekananda-said-young-generation-will-find-solution-to-all-problems-have-absolute-faith-in-him-pm-modi/articleshow/117172649.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Developed nation is achievable with the strength of India’s youth: PM Modi - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Emphasizes Youth's Role in Achieving a Developed India</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Jan 12, 2025, Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Prime-Minister-Narendra-Modi-attends-the-Viksit-Bh_1736679526138_1736679762993.jpg" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi attends the Viksit Bharat Young Leaders Dialogue 2025 on Sunday (ANI)"><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi attends the Viksit Bharat Young Leaders Dialogue 2025 on Sunday (ANI)</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi addressed the Viksit Bharat Young Leaders Dialogue 2025, emphasizing the critical role of India's youth in transforming the nation into a developed country over the next 25 years.</p><ul><li>Modi highlighted Swami Vivekananda's faith in the potential of Indian youth.</li><li>The event marked National Youth Day and had 3,000 participants aged 15 to 29.</li><li>Modi shared anecdotes illustrating his trust in youth and their capabilities.</li><li>He mentioned the G-20 Summit and its significance for India's future.</li><li>A book titled 'Yuva Shakti’s Vision for Viksit Bharat @ 2047' was released during the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“I firmly believe that with the strength of India’s youth, the dream of a developed nation is achievable.” - PM Modi</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Modi's optimism and vision for India's youth are pivotal in steering the nation towards development.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/strength-of-youth-power-will-make-india-a-developed-nation-pm-modi-101736679533107.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/strength-of-youth-power-will-make-india-a-developed-nation-pm-modi-101736679533107.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:58:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Quite shocking’: Shashi Tharoor slams Nitesh Rane on EVM remark - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Quite shocking’: Shashi Tharoor slams Nitesh Rane on EVM remark</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/tharoor-rane.jpg?w=640" alt="shashi tharoor" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Shashi Tharoor responds to Nitesh Rane's statements.</figcaption><p>Congress MP Shashi Tharoor condemned Maharashtra Minister Nitesh Rane's remarks about EVMs, calling them 'quite shocking' and emphasizing the need for equality and unity in India.</p><ul><li>Tharoor reacted negatively to Rane's statement equating EVMs with anti-Muslim sentiment.</li><li>He highlighted the historical lessons from India's freedom struggle about religious equality.</li><li>Rane's comments drew criticism for targeting specific communities.</li></ul><blockquote>“This kind of thing is quite shocking... We are all equal individual citizens of India.” - Shashi Tharoor</blockquote><p>Tharoor insists that the principles of equality must remain central to India's identity as a nation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/pune/quite-shocking-shashi-tharoor-slams-nitesh-rane-on-evm-remark-9773830/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/pune/quite-shocking-shashi-tharoor-slams-nitesh-rane-on-evm-remark-9773830/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Torres fraud: Ukrainian masterminds fled India under garb of Christmas leave - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ukrainian Masterminds of Torres Fraud Scheme Escape on Christmas Leave</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/torres-ponzi-scheme.jpg?w=640" alt="Torres" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>An EOW probe revealed that a heated argument over unpaid salaries on January 5 at Torres' Dadar store led to a leak of financial irregularities (Express)</figcaption><p>Two Ukrainian women, suspected masterminds of a significant fraud case, fled India under the guise of taking Christmas leave, prompting an investigation by the Mumbai police Economic Offences Wing (EOW).</p><ul><li>The women were identified as Victoriia Kovalenko and Olena Stoian, directors of Platinum Hern Pvt Ltd, which operates the Torres jewellery brand.</li><li>Three additional individuals were arrested in connection with the Torres Ponzi scheme, with a substantial amount of cash seized.</li><li>An internal conflict at the Torres Dadar store exposed financial irregularities that led to widespread investor concern, gathering about 600 investors outside the store.</li><li>Ongoing investigations are looking into possible connections to other fraud cases in Turkey.</li></ul><blockquote>“Internal fights exposed the collapse of the company,” said a source involved in the investigation.</blockquote><p>This case underscores the risks in investment schemes and the need for due diligence among investors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/mumbai-ukrainian-masterminds-fled-india-under-garb-of-christmas-leave-9772262/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/mumbai-ukrainian-masterminds-fled-india-under-garb-of-christmas-leave-9772262/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Military Digest | ‘Army is the servant of people…exists to defend democracy’: remembering General Cariappa’s legacy - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Army is the servant of people…exists to defend democracy’: remembering General Cariappa’s legacy</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<p>This article commemorates Army Day and reflects on the legacy of General K M Cariappa, the first Indian general and commander-in-chief of the Indian Army. It highlights his emphasis on the army's role in defending democracy and serving the people.</p>
<ul>
<li>Army Day is observed in memory of General K M Cariappa, who became commander-in-chief on January 15, 1949.</li>
<li>General Cariappa stated, “The Army is the servant of the people and it exists to defend democracy and protect…”</li>
<li>He advocated for discipline and moral integrity within the army as custodians of taxpayer-funded resources.</li>
<li>Introduced voluntary military training for civilians to instill a sense of discipline among the public.</li>
<li>The training proposal included physical training and sanitation talks but was not approved by the political establishment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Remember the Army, and everything in it, is the property of the taxpayer.” – General K M Cariappa</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, General Cariappa's vision for a disciplined army that serves the public remains relevant, although some of his training proposals faced political resistance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/military-digest-general-cariappas-legacy-army-day-independence-9774401/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/military-digest-general-cariappas-legacy-army-day-independence-9774401/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In challenge to Amit Shah, Kejriwal says won’t contest Delhi polls if Centre assures houses for all slum-dwellers in court - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Challenges Amit Shah Over Slum Housing in Delhi Elections</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/expressintro-72.jpg?w=640" alt="Arvind Kejriwal Delhi polls" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Arvind Kejriwal making a statement about slum housing.</figcaption>
<p>AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal has stated that he will not contest the Delhi elections unless the central government drops cases against slum demolitions and assures housing for evicted slum-dwellers.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kejriwal positioned himself as the protector of slum residents.</li>
  <li>He criticized BJP for exploiting slum residents during elections.</li>
  <li>Kejriwal warned that voting for BJP would lead to further slum demolitions.</li>
  <li>He challenged Amit Shah to commit to housing slum dwellers.</li>
  <li>Kejriwal reported only 4,000 houses built for 400,000 slum residents under the current scheme.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If you vote for BJP, it will be like signing your own suicide note.”</blockquote>
<p>Kejriwal emphasizes the need for government accountability regarding slum housing, stating his intentions to protect slum residents in the upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/delhi/kejriwal-amit-shah-slums-delhi-polls-2025-houses-9774640/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/delhi/kejriwal-amit-shah-slums-delhi-polls-2025-houses-9774640/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jaishankar to represent India at Donald Trump’s swearing-in as US President - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jaishankar to Represent India at Donald Trump’s Swearing-in Ceremony</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Jaishankar-US-Visit.jpg?w=640" alt="Jaishankar Donald Trump swearing in ceremony" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>In the last week of December, Jaishankar had met Mike Waltz in the US. (Photo: X)</figcaption>
<p>External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar will attend Donald Trump’s swearing-in ceremony on January 20, as confirmed by the external affairs ministry.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jaishankar will represent the Government of India at the event.</li>
  <li>The event is organized by the Trump-Vance Inaugural Committee.</li>
  <li>He will also hold meetings with members of the incoming administration and other dignitaries.</li>
  <li>Jaishankar previously met NSA designate Mike Waltz during a visit in late December.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“EAM will also have meetings with representatives of the incoming Administration, as also some other dignitaries visiting the US on that occasion.”</blockquote>
<p>This significant visit highlights India's diplomatic engagement with the United States and the importance of the upcoming administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/jaishankar-represent-india-donald-trump-swearing-in-us-president-9774296/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/jaishankar-represent-india-donald-trump-swearing-in-us-president-9774296/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kerala Lottery Results 12.01.2025: Akshaya AK-685 Winners Declared; Full List Here! - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kerala Lottery Results Today: Here's FULL LIST of winning numbers for Akshaya AK-685 lucky draw for Sunday, January 12, 2025.</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 12, 2025, 21:28 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Kerala Lottery Akshaya AK-685 Results: The first prize winner of Akshaya AK-685 will get Rs 70 Lakh." title="Kerala Lottery Akshaya AK-685 Results: The first prize winner of Akshaya AK-685 will get Rs 70 Lakh."><figcaption>Kerala Lottery Akshaya AK-685 Results: The first prize winner of Akshaya AK-685 will get Rs 70 Lakh. (Image: Shutterstock)</figcaption></figure><p>The Kerala State Lottery Department has announced the results for the Akshaya AK-685 lottery with significant prizes awarded. The first prize winner receives Rs 70 lakh, while second and third prizes are Rs 5 lakh and Rs 1 lakh, respectively. The winning numbers include:</p><ul><li>First Prize: AB 846639 (Payyannur)</li><li>Second Prize: AH 243577 (Kottayam)</li><li>Third Prizes: AA 196854, AB 838400, AC 745225, AD 622450, AE 129668, AF 115526, AG 659827, AH 715095, AJ 303880, AK 692810, AL 579215, AM 889232.</li></ul><p>Winning numbers for the consolation prize of Rs 8,000 are also listed. For those wishing to check their tickets, the results can be confirmed at <a href="www.keralalottery.info">www.keralalottery.info</a>.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/kerala-lottery-results-today-live-updates-akshaya-ak-685-winners-list-guessing-numbers-for-12-january-2025-9183125.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/kerala-lottery-results-today-live-updates-akshaya-ak-685-winners-list-guessing-numbers-for-12-january-2025-9183125.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:28:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi polls: Congress announces scheme for unemployed youth, promises ₹8500 per month - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Elections: Congress Unveils 'Yuva Udaan Yojana' for Unemployed Youth</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Screenshot_2025-01-12_142754_1736675323252_1736675331999.png" alt="Congress leader Sachin Pilot (ANI)" />
<figcaption>Congress leader Sachin Pilot (ANI)</figcaption>
<p>The Congress party has announced the 'Yuva Udaan Yojana' scheme to provide ₹8,500 monthly for one year to unemployed youth in Delhi, contingent on their election victory.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The scheme targets educated yet unemployed youth.</li>
  <li>Beneﬁciaries are required to demonstrate their skills through work placements.</li>
  <li>This initiative is part of a broader campaign including the 'Pyari Didi Yojana' and 'Jeevan Raksha Yojana'.</li>
  <li>Polling for Delhi assembly elections is set for February 5, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We will provide financial assistance to youths who can show their skills in a company, factory or organisation.” - Sachin Pilot</blockquote>
<p>The announcement signifies the Congress's attempt to regain influence in a region where they have not held power since 2013.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-polls-congress-announces-scheme-for-unemployed-youth-promises-rs-8500-per-month-101736675031595.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-polls-congress-announces-scheme-for-unemployed-youth-promises-rs-8500-per-month-101736675031595.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 09:49:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Yuva Udaan Yojana': Congress promises Rs 8,500 to educated unemployed youth in Delhi - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Yuva Udaan Yojana’: Congress promises Rs 8,500 to educated unemployed youth in Delhi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>This article discusses the Congress Party's proposed initiative to provide financial support of Rs 8,500 to educated unemployed youth in Delhi through the 'Yuva Udaan Yojana'. This initiative aims to tackle unemployment among the youth in the region.</p><ul><li>The Yuva Udaan Yojana aims to support educated unemployed youth in Delhi.</li><li>Congress promises a financial assistance of Rs 8,500 to eligible applicants.</li><li>The initiative intends to address the rising unemployment rates among young graduates.</li><li>Officials from Congress stated that this will empower youth and promote self-sufficiency.</li></ul><blockquote>“This initiative is our commitment to uplift the youth and offer them the support they need to thrive.”</blockquote><p>The Yuva Udaan Yojana represents a significant step towards addressing youth unemployment, highlighting the need for government intervention in the job market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/yuva-udaan-yojana-congress-promises-rs-8500-to-educated-unemployed-youth-in-delhi/articleshow/117171611.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/yuva-udaan-yojana-congress-promises-rs-8500-to-educated-unemployed-youth-in-delhi/articleshow/117171611.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 09:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyderabad roads wear deserted look ahead of Sankranti - Deccan Chronicle]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hyderabad roads wear deserted look ahead of Sankranti</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Chronicle</p><div><img src="https://www.deccanchronicle.com/h-upload/2025/01/12/1880851-img-20250112-wa0058.webp" alt="Photo: Prathyush Nallella"><figcaption>Photo: Prathyush Nallella</figcaption></div><p>Hyderabad experienced a quiet morning as many residents traveled to their hometowns for the Sankranti festival, leading to almost empty streets.</p><ul><li>Sultan Bazaar, usually bustling, was nearly deserted.</li><li>On Saturday evening, bus depots, railway stations, and toll plazas were crowded with people heading home.</li><li>Videos of heavy traffic filled social media.</li><li>The Telangana Government announced a week-long holiday for school students from January 11 to 17.</li><li>Authorities advised residents to secure their homes and avoid sharing travel plans on social media.</li></ul><blockquote>“The police authorities are urging citizens to follow precautionary measures and shift their valuables to a bank or a safer location, while they leave their house.”</blockquote><p>The pre-festival rush has made the city streets deserted, showcasing the significance of the Sankranti holiday.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/hyderabad-roads-wear-deserted-look-ahead-of-sankranti-1853727</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanchronicle.com/southern-states/telangana/hyderabad-roads-wear-deserted-look-ahead-of-sankranti-1853727</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 09:39:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tamil Nadu governor reacts to MK Stalin's ‘childish’ jibe: ‘Arrogance’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/tamil-nadu-governor-rn-ravi-mk-stalin-national-anthem-row-101736672090707.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/tamil-nadu-governor-rn-ravi-mk-stalin-national-anthem-row-101736672090707.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 09:36:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Consulate in Bengaluru: Site dedication ceremony on January 17 - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Consulate in Bengaluru: Site Dedication Ceremony Set for January 17</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 / 14:11 IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/12/20241219100454_BeFunky-collage-2024-12-19T153304.276.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Bengaluru" title="Bengaluru" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Bengaluru</figcaption><p>In a significant development, a site dedication ceremony for the US Consulate in Bengaluru is scheduled for January 17, aimed at supporting techies, business visitors, and students.</p><ul><li>The ceremony will take place at JW Marriott on Vittal Mallya Road at 9:30 AM.</li><li>Temporary operations may commence at JW Marriott before a more extensive campus is established.</li><li>Visa issuance is expected to start a few months post-ceremony.</li></ul><blockquote>"The ceremony marks a long-standing demand in the region," - Moneycontrol.</blockquote><p>This event signifies a move towards improved consular services in Bengaluru, meeting the needs of an expanding population of US nationals and businesses.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/us-consulate-in-bengaluru-site-dedication-ceremony-on-january-17-12908304.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/us-consulate-in-bengaluru-site-dedication-ceremony-on-january-17-12908304.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 08:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telangana to issue new ration cards to eligible from Jan 26 - The Siasat Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telangana to Issue New Ration Cards Starting January 26</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Siasat Daily</p>
<img src="https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/ASEEM-urges-Revanth-to-issue-smart-ration-cards-780x470.jpg" alt="ASEEM urges CM Revanth Reddy to issue smart ration cards in place of digital family cards to beneficiaries." width="1200" height="900">
<figcaption>ASEEM urges CM Revanth Reddy to issue smart ration cards in place of digital family cards to beneficiaries.</figcaption>
<p>The government of Telangana will start issuing new ration cards from January 26, 2024. Beneficiaries will be identified through a verification process scheduled between January 16 and 20.</p>
<ul>
  <li>New ration cards will be issued as per previous eligibility rules; no new criteria have been established.</li>
  <li>Applications for new ration cards and Indiramma housing will be accepted.</li>
  <li>Priority will be given to families with land in Hyderabad for housing schemes.</li>
  <li>Multiple initiatives including Rythu Bharosa and Indiramma Atmiya Bharosa will be launched on January 26.</li>
  <li>18.32 lakh individuals have been identified through the Indiramma app for housing assistance.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our goal is to build houses for all homeless families.” - Chief Minister A. Revanth Reddy</blockquote>
<p>The initiative aims to ensure that all eligible families receive support and assistance, reinforcing the government’s commitment to social welfare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.siasat.com/telangana-to-issue-new-ration-cards-to-eligible-from-jan-26-3163505/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.siasat.com/telangana-to-issue-new-ration-cards-to-eligible-from-jan-26-3163505/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 08:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Adani announces ₹65,000 crore investment in energy, cement projects in Chhattisgarh - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Adani announces ₹65,000 crore investment in energy, cement projects in Chhattisgarh</h1>
<p><strong>Published on: January 12, 2025 | Source: The Hindu</strong></p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/5z48gy/article69091647.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/GhEloLEbkAA7HGd.jpg" alt="Gautam Adani also assured the state government of a ₹10,000 crore impetus over the next four years to support initiatives in education, healthcare, skill development and tourism under the Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR)." />
<figcaption>Photo Credit: X/@ChhattisgarhCMO</figcaption>
<p>Industrialist Gautam Adani announced significant investments in Chhattisgarh aimed at expanding energy and cement production while also contributing to social initiatives.</p>
<ul>
  <li>₹65,000 crore investment in energy and cement projects.</li>
  <li>₹60,000 crore to enhance the power generation capacity by 6,120 MW across Raipur, Korba, and Raigarh.</li>
  <li>₹5,000 crore committed for the expansion of cement plants.</li>
  <li>Assurance of ₹10,000 crore over the next four years for CSR initiatives.</li>
  <li>Potential collaborations in manufacturing defense equipment and establishing data centers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In a meeting with the Honourable Chief Minister of Chhattisgarh, Shri Vishnu Deo Sai, Gautam Adani, Chairman of the Adani Group, announced a planned investment of ₹60,000 crore to expand the group's power plants in Raipur, Korba, and Raigarh.”</blockquote>
<p>This investment is expected to boost Chhattisgarh's economy significantly while also addressing social development through corporate responsibility initiatives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/business/gautam-adani-announces-65000-crore-investment-in-energy-cement-projects-in-chhattisgarh/article69091641.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/business/gautam-adani-announces-65000-crore-investment-in-energy-cement-projects-in-chhattisgarh/article69091641.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 08:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP will demolish all slums if it comes to power in Delhi, says Arvind Kejriwal - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Accuses BJP of Planning Slum Demolitions if Elected in Delhi</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src='https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/5o3m17/article69091624.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/WhatsApp%20Image%202025-01-12%20at%2012.28.28_71eba9f1.jpg' alt='Former Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal speaking at Shakur basti in New Delhi on Sunday, January 12, 2025'><figcaption>Former Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal speaking at Shakur basti in New Delhi on Sunday, January 12, 2025 | Photo Credit: Sushil Kumar Verma</figcaption><p>Arvind Kejriwal, leader of AAP, claims that if BJP gains power in Delhi, slum clusters will be demolished immediately post-election.</p><ul><li>Kejriwal states that BJP has plans to demolish all slums quickly and warns slum dwellers against voting for the party.</li><li>He challenges Home Minister Amit Shah to withdraw cases against slum dwellers and resettle those evicted, or he will contest the elections.</li><li>Kejriwal criticizes BJP’s 'Jahan Jhuggi Wahan Makaan' scheme, describing it as ineffective.</li><li>The Delhi Assembly elections are set for February 5, with results on February 8.</li></ul><blockquote>“If Delhi’s slum dwellers give their vote to the BJP, it’ll be like signing off on your own suicide.” - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote><p>This statement highlights the urgency of upcoming Delhi elections and the significant concerns regarding slum housing policies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/elections/delhi-assembly/bjp-will-demolish-all-slums-if-it-comes-to-power-in-delhi-kejriwal/article69091612.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/elections/delhi-assembly/bjp-will-demolish-all-slums-if-it-comes-to-power-in-delhi-kejriwal/article69091612.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 07:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J-K higher reaches likely to receive snow on Jan 16, says MeT - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQb2Nnb1E5SEszX2JwVmNpdm1PeHlNS2RYVjJJaUtXWGR4QlcwNTBnUGR3WVN3VUZKeVh2Ympidk1BeE0wU1E3RExWUWF4S25Jdl9EYmhHQmRnOFZSZ25EM25lU1JsR1B0U2djeTBpQ1ZMVWRRZVlMSVZtNm8xbWczN1VvMlRzeWJfTHBqODNFLTBvcUpJdDlmeUhpWi1rTWd4VFltSnRfa2o3Z9IBrAFBVV95cUxPLTVIcjJ0dGRuVFlyTE9zbWQ5YU1UbGhiSS1KckxQSG9HSjhHX0t5R2pUZHVwMHNHTFRWY3BRZUpJUVFOTGdHX09YNEx1bXJ6SktXR2lWWE9VLXZ0Qk04dnhHSlItZm5LLUw0RUFoVkowbldiZEZrWjF2R1l5Q1BRbVhTNUtnei1Pck5nU0lkeW1oTlJHN0x6Z1doUmx2cFFBVE53MDFFMC04c3Vz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQb2Nnb1E5SEszX2JwVmNpdm1PeHlNS2RYVjJJaUtXWGR4QlcwNTBnUGR3WVN3VUZKeVh2Ympidk1BeE0wU1E3RExWUWF4S25Jdl9EYmhHQmRnOFZSZ25EM25lU1JsR1B0U2djeTBpQ1ZMVWRRZVlMSVZtNm8xbWczN1VvMlRzeWJfTHBqODNFLTBvcUpJdDlmeUhpWi1rTWd4VFltSnRfa2o3Z9IBrAFBVV95cUxPLTVIcjJ0dGRuVFlyTE9zbWQ5YU1UbGhiSS1KckxQSG9HSjhHX0t5R2pUZHVwMHNHTFRWY3BRZUpJUVFOTGdHX09YNEx1bXJ6SktXR2lWWE9VLXZ0Qk04dnhHSlItZm5LLUw0RUFoVkowbldiZEZrWjF2R1l5Q1BRbVhTNUtnei1Pck5nU0lkeW1oTlJHN0x6Z1doUmx2cFFBVE53MDFFMC04c3Vz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 07:51:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>