<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:27:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:27:32 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Assam, a rathole miner’s tale of survival: ‘Men scrambled out of tunnels and were swept into each other’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/long-reads/assam-mine-tragedy-a-rathole-miners-tale-of-survival-men-scrambled-out-of-tunnels-and-were-swept-into-each-other-9770534/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/long-reads/assam-mine-tragedy-a-rathole-miners-tale-of-survival-men-scrambled-out-of-tunnels-and-were-swept-into-each-other-9770534/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My thinking in 3rd term has changed vastly in terms of vision, scope: PM Modi on podcast with Nikhil Kama - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Discusses Changed Vision in 3rd Term on Podcast with Nikhil Kamath</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The Prime Minister of India, Narendra Modi, shared insights into how his vision and approach have significantly evolved during his third term in office during a podcast conversation with entrepreneur Nikhil Kamath.</p><ul><li>Modi emphasized the importance of adapting and broadening perspectives in governance.</li><li>He discussed various initiatives that reflect this evolved vision.</li><li>The podcast highlighted moments of personal reflection and key decision-making processes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Leadership is about evolving, understanding, and meeting the challenges of the time.” - PM Narendra Modi</blockquote><p>This dialogue illustrates how political leaders are increasingly aware of the need for adaptability in response to contemporary challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/my-thinking-in-3rd-term-has-changed-vastly-in-terms-of-vision-scope-pm-modi-on-podcast-with-nikhil-kamath/articleshow/117118701.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/my-thinking-in-3rd-term-has-changed-vastly-in-terms-of-vision-scope-pm-modi-on-podcast-with-nikhil-kamath/articleshow/117118701.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi court to CBI in Karti Chidambaram corruption case: 'Give 3-day pre-arrest notice' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Court Orders CBI to Give Pre-Arrest Notice in Karti Chidambaram Case</h1><p><strong>Date: Jan 10, 2025 | Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/PTI08-03-2023-000102A-0_1691234324994_1736520282744.jpg" alt="Congress MP Karti Chidambaram(PTI)"><figcaption>Congress MP Karti Chidambaram(PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>The Delhi court has instructed the CBI to provide a three-day written notice before arresting Congress MP Karti Chidambaram as part of a fresh corruption investigation.</p><ul><li>A court ordered the CBI to notify Chidambaram about his arrest three days in advance.</li><li>Chidambaram is accused of aiding Diageo Scotland regarding the ban on duty-free liquor sales.</li><li>The CBI's investigation is centered around suspicious payments to Advantage Strategic Consulting, linked to Chidambaram.</li></ul><blockquote>"The investigating agency shall give three days written notice before the applicant in case his arrest is required..." - Judge Kaveri Baweja</blockquote><p>This case adds to Chidambaram's ongoing legal challenges, including accusations related to the INX Media case.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-court-to-cbi-in-karti-chidambaram-corruption-case-give-3-day-pre-arrest-notice-101736519884484.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-court-to-cbi-in-karti-chidambaram-corruption-case-give-3-day-pre-arrest-notice-101736519884484.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:47:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Makar Sankranti 2025: What it means for your zodiac sign - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Makar Sankranti 2025: What it means for your zodiac sign</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/3675372_16822_1736517631293_1736517638048.jpg" alt="Makar sankranti horoscope 2025 for each zodiac sign" title="Makar sankranti horoscope 2025 for each zodiac sign">
<figcaption>Makar sankranti horoscope 2025 for each zodiac sign</figcaption>
<p>The auspicious festival of Makar Sankranti will be celebrated on January 14, 2025, marking the Sun's shift into Capricorn, symbolizing the end of winters and the arrival of brighter days. It is a time of hope, growth, and fresh goals.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Sun’s presence in Capricorn encourages discipline and hard work.</li>
<li>This period is ideal for self-reflection and planning for the year ahead.</li>
<li>Each zodiac sign experiences unique influences and opportunities during this transit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It is a time of introspection and goal-setting for the year.”</blockquote>
<p>Makar Sankranti invites individuals to align their ambitions with practical actions, creating a fertile ground for personal growth and zodiac-specific insights.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/makar-sankranti-2025-what-it-means-for-your-zodiac-sign-101736517196554.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/astrology/horoscope/makar-sankranti-2025-what-it-means-for-your-zodiac-sign-101736517196554.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:01:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Class 3 girl collapses in school lobby, dies of suspected cardiac arrest in Ahmedabad - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Class 3 Girl Dies of Suspected Cardiac Arrest in Ahmedabad School</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250110132806_Child-death.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Class 3 girl collapses in school lobby, dies of suspected cardiac arrest in Ahmedabad"/><figcaption>Police have sent the girl’s body for postmortem and initiated an investigation. (Representational image)</figcaption><p>A Class 3 girl passed away of a suspected cardiac arrest after she collapsed in the lobby at her school in Ahmedabad, Gujarat, on Friday.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred in Zebar School for Children in the Thaltej area around Friday morning.</li><li>Gargi Ranpara, the eight-year-old student, fell unconscious shortly after sitting in the lobby.</li><li>CCTV footage shows her walking towards her classroom before collapsing.</li></ul><blockquote>“The eight-year-old girl, Gargi Ranpara, fell unconscious soon after she sat on a chair in the lobby while going towards her classroom in the morning,” - Sharmishtha Sinha, Principal</blockquote><p>The police have launched an investigation to determine the exact cause of her death.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/class-3-girl-collapses-in-school-lobby-dies-of-suspected-cardiac-arrest-in-ahmedabad-12907749.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/class-3-girl-collapses-in-school-lobby-dies-of-suspected-cardiac-arrest-in-ahmedabad-12907749.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:30:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JEE Main exam city intimation slip 2025 released at jeemain.nta.nic.in: Direct link to download here - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/education/news/jee-main-exam-city-intimation-slip-2025-released-at-jeemain-nta-nic-in-direct-link-to-download-here/articleshow/117122415.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/education/news/jee-main-exam-city-intimation-slip-2025-released-at-jeemain-nta-nic-in-direct-link-to-download-here/articleshow/117122415.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JEE Main exam city intimation slip 2025 released at jeemain.nta.nic.in: Direct link to download here - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/education/news/jee-main-exam-city-intimation-slip-2025-released-at-jeemain-nta-nic-in-direct-link-to-download-here/articleshow/117122415.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/education/news/jee-main-exam-city-intimation-slip-2025-released-at-jeemain-nta-nic-in-direct-link-to-download-here/articleshow/117122415.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yogi Adityanath's ‘denting-painting’ warning to Waqf ahead of Maha Kumbh 2025 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yogi Adityanath's Warning to Waqf Ahead of Maha Kumbh 2025</h1><p><strong>Date: January 10, 2025</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Yogi_Adityanath_1736512586661_1736512587042.jpg" alt="Uttar Pradesh chief minister Yogi Adityanath.(Nitin Sharma/ANI)" title="Uttar Pradesh chief minister Yogi Adityanath.(Nitin Sharma/ANI)"><figcaption>Uttar Pradesh chief minister Yogi Adityanath.(Nitin Sharma/ANI)</figcaption><p>The Maha Kumbh is being celebrated after 12 years, with a huge turnout of devotees expected in Prayagraj from January 13 to February 26.</p><ul><li>Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath issued a warning to the Waqf Board regarding land claims ahead of the Maha Kumbh.</li><li>He stated that anyone wishing to claim land would face consequences, referring to 'denting-painting'.</li><li>Adityanath welcomed those respecting Indian traditions but criticized claims from the Waqf Board regarding land issues.</li><li>The statement comes after an AIMJ president's claim about land rights and entry for Muslims during the Kumbh Mela preparations.</li><li>No discrimination during the Maha Kumbh was promised by Adityanath, but he affirmed the reclaiming of Waqf land.</li><li>The event is anticipated to attract over 45 crore devotees.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Kumbh has been a symbol of India's heritage for thousands of years and has always taken place here.”</blockquote><p>The Maha Kumbh 2025 is expected to be a significant event, marking a major spiritual gathering with a large influx of devotees in Prayagraj.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/yogi-adityanaths-denting-painting-warning-to-waqf-ahead-of-maha-kumbh-2025-101736512594655.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/yogi-adityanaths-denting-painting-warning-to-waqf-ahead-of-maha-kumbh-2025-101736512594655.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:55:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who would be Narendra Modi's first call after his happiest moment? PM answers - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who would be Narendra Modi's first call after his happiest moment? PM answers</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/pm_modi_1736433371032_1736506368577.png" alt="In the podcast, released by Zerodha co-founder Nikhil Kamath, PM Narendra Modi recalled a conversation with his mother.(X/nikhilkamathco)"> <figcaption>In the podcast, released by Zerodha co-founder Nikhil Kamath, PM Narendra Modi recalled a conversation with his mother.(X/nikhilkamathco)</figcaption><p>In his first podcast appearance, Prime Minister Narendra Modi shared that his mother would have been the first person he would call during his happiest moment. He reflected on significant events in his life and emphasized the importance of family.</p><ul><li>PM Modi discussed personal moments, including a pivotal call to his mother after hoisting the Indian flag at Lal Chowk in Srinagar.</li><li>He recalled his experience during an attack on his convoy in Punjab and the emotional significance of the call.</li><li>Modi talked about his childhood, political challenges, and lessons learned along the way.</li><li>The Prime Minister acknowledged his humanity and the inevitability of making mistakes.</li></ul><blockquote>“For me, it was a moment of joy and I also thought that my mother would have been worried.” - PM Narendra Modi</blockquote><p>This podcast marks an intimate look at Modi's thoughts on family, politics, and his life experiences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/who-would-be-narendra-modis-first-call-after-his-happiest-moment-pm-answers-101736505969452.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/who-would-be-narendra-modis-first-call-after-his-happiest-moment-pm-answers-101736505969452.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:50:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Needless inconvenience: PDP criticises reports of mandatory deboarding of train passengers at Katra - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PDP Criticises Mandatory Deboarding of Train Passengers at Katra</h1><p><strong>Date: January 10</strong> | <strong>Source: Srinagar</strong></p><p>The People's Democratic Party (PDP) has criticized the reports requiring train passengers traveling to and from Kashmir to deboard at Katra due to security issues, calling it a needless inconvenience.</p><ul><li>The PDP labels the requirement as an unnecessary burden on Kashmiris.</li><li>Party officials argue that this contradicts the purported benefits of train services to the region.</li><li>PDP leader Mohammad Khurshid Alam expressed that this directive undermines the promised convenience in travel for Kashmiris.</li><li>The measure particularly affects vulnerable groups like the elderly and those seeking medical treatment.</li></ul><blockquote>“For years, we were told that train services to Kashmir would benefit the common masses and ease travel. This latest directive shows that Kashmiris are still far from experiencing any real travel convenience.” - Mohammad Khurshid Alam</blockquote><p>This move has sparked concerns about the effectiveness and intentions behind the security measures being implemented.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/latest-news/needless-inconvenience-pdp-criticises-reports-of-mandatory-deboarding-of-train-passengers-at-katra/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/latest-news/needless-inconvenience-pdp-criticises-reports-of-mandatory-deboarding-of-train-passengers-at-katra/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:50:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JEE Main 2025 City Intimation Slip released at jeemain.nta.nic.in; Direct link here - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JEE Main 2025 City Intimation Slip Released</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250110124558_JEE.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431' alt='JEE Main 2025 City Intimation Slip'><figcaption>JEE Main 2025 City Intimation Slip Released.</figcaption><p>The National Testing Agency (NTA) has released the JEE Main 2025 City Allotment Slip for Session 1. Candidates can now check their allotted exam city on the official website jeemain.nta.nic.in.</p><ul><li>JEE Main 2025 City Allotment Slip has been made available.</li><li>Candidates can download the slip from the official NTA website.</li><li>This slip includes important information about exam center locations.</li></ul><blockquote>“JEE Main 2025 City Allotment Slip OUT!”</blockquote><p>For students appearing for JEE Main Session 1, this is crucial information regarding their exam schedule.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/education/jee-main-2025-city-intimation-slip-released-at-jeemain-nta-nic-in-direct-link-here-article-12907726.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/education/jee-main-2025-city-intimation-slip-released-at-jeemain-nta-nic-in-direct-link-here-article-12907726.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:46:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sambhal mosque well row: SC orders status quo, issues notice to Centre, ASI - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Maintains Status Quo at Sambhal Mosque</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ovztwn/article69085027.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/IMG_SAMBHAL_MOSQUE_STORY_2_1_TUDQUHL2.jpg" alt="The Main gate of the jama masjid mosque at Sambhal in Uttar Pradesh." title="The Main gate of the jama masjid mosque at Sambhal in Uttar Pradesh.">
<figcaption>The Main gate of the jama masjid mosque at Sambhal in Uttar Pradesh. | Photo Credit: R.V. Moorthy</figcaption>
<p>The Supreme Court has directed that the status quo be maintained regarding a well near the Shahi Jama Masjid at Sambhal, Uttar Pradesh, following an application from the mosque management committee.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The court issued directives to local authorities and private respondents to file counter-affidavits within two weeks.</li>
  <li>Concerns were raised regarding plans to refer the site as ‘Hari Mandir’ and the commencement of religious activities.</li>
  <li>Legal representatives presented historical significance of the well and its longstanding usage by the mosque.</li>
  <li>The case is scheduled to be posted for hearing on February 25, 2025.</li>
  <li>Last year, the Supreme Court intervened to maintain peace following violent clashes in the area.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“No such activities will be permitted. Please file a status report,” - Chief Justice Khanna</blockquote>
<p>This ruling aims to preserve the historical and cultural heritage associated with the mosque and its surroundings, continuing to monitor any future developments related to the site.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/sambhal-mosque-well-row-sc-orders-status-quo-issues-notice-to-centre-asi/article69084777.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/sambhal-mosque-well-row-sc-orders-status-quo-issues-notice-to-centre-asi/article69084777.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SAD working committee accepts Sukhbir Badal’s resignation as party chief - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxNeklmSWFVQVItdkp1dTBVOWhCS2Y5QjZOMGxWa3djOUFnXzlwUFFzb1ozX1lGd0xEdDJDamVnQm1BVU01RzJyUmNTd0psVmlha0lZNlNkdGc1VUk2STJiSFNUdFpmYjg0QnRKelBuVDd3U09hZDRST2tTMVBkdko2Q2xBa3ZRQXc1VUhxRXQ4NVJqSjJMZnY4OFNTM2tNTVg4ZUFObF9B0gGqAUFVX3lxTFBHcVBqM0xHSEpLZ2RDd2swUmYwQ3oxeTktaFVzVXM4QzYzTjJqVC1idWFyQnAtQ2dKbEdDNlU3aDc5RUJiU0paSWY5M3RPclJwZ1JBaHBUWTRmTUUxd3lOYmhZczFqOFI5TDM2QVJ1TE5KUHFFT3dSaWowU244d0VkNFNMUEE4VUVFQmJ0elFHNHE4Zml6aGFtTDJJVlBGaVNZeTZtZlB6dFRB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxNeklmSWFVQVItdkp1dTBVOWhCS2Y5QjZOMGxWa3djOUFnXzlwUFFzb1ozX1lGd0xEdDJDamVnQm1BVU01RzJyUmNTd0psVmlha0lZNlNkdGc1VUk2STJiSFNUdFpmYjg0QnRKelBuVDd3U09hZDRST2tTMVBkdko2Q2xBa3ZRQXc1VUhxRXQ4NVJqSjJMZnY4OFNTM2tNTVg4ZUFObF9B0gGqAUFVX3lxTFBHcVBqM0xHSEpLZ2RDd2swUmYwQ3oxeTktaFVzVXM4QzYzTjJqVC1idWFyQnAtQ2dKbEdDNlU3aDc5RUJiU0paSWY5M3RPclJwZ1JBaHBUWTRmTUUxd3lOYmhZczFqOFI5TDM2QVJ1TE5KUHFFT3dSaWowU244d0VkNFNMUEE4VUVFQmJ0elFHNHE4Zml6aGFtTDJJVlBGaVNZeTZtZlB6dFRB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:30:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Srinagar-Delhi train service should operate directly without causing inconvenience to passengers: Altaf Bukhari - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Srinagar-Delhi Train Service Should Be Direct, Says Altaf Bukhari</h1><p><strong>Date: January 10</strong> | <strong>Source: Jammu & Kashmir Apni Party</strong></p><p>Jammu & Kashmir Apni Party (JKAP) president Syed Mohammad Altaf Bukhari has expressed concerns over the proposed Srinagar-Delhi train service, urging that the service operate directly without requiring passengers to switch trains at the Katra Railway Station.</p><ul><li>Bukhari highlighted that reports indicated passengers would need to change trains at the Mata Vaishno Devi Railway Station in Katra.</li><li>Passengers would have to disembark, leave the station, re-enter, and rescan luggage, which he described as troubling and humiliating.</li><li>He called for railway authorities to find alternative safety measures rather than inconveniencing travelers.</li><li>Bukhari criticized the current arrangements as turning a potentially seamless journey into a hectic one.</li></ul><blockquote>“This arrangement would be troubling and humiliating for the passengers.”</blockquote><blockquote>“Amid much hype, people believed that the first-ever Srinagar-Delhi train service would be fast, seamless, and comfortable.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Bukhari urges the railway authorities to prioritize passenger comfort and streamline the service to maintain its intended benefits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/politics/srinagar-delhi-train-service-should-operate-directly-without-causing-inconvenience-to-passengers-altaf-bukhari/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/politics/srinagar-delhi-train-service-should-operate-directly-without-causing-inconvenience-to-passengers-altaf-bukhari/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:13:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress takes dig at PM Modi over ‘I'm not a God' remark in podcast with Nikhil Kamath - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Criticizes PM Modi for His 'I'm Not a God' Comment in Recent Podcast</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Jan 10, 2025</strong></p>
<p><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Jairam_Ramesh_1736507057701_1736507057925.jpg" alt="Congress leader Jairam Ramesh.(PTI )" title="Congress leader Jairam Ramesh.(PTI )">
<figcaption>Congress leader Jairam Ramesh.(PTI )</figcaption>
<p>In a recent podcast with Zerodha co-founder Nikhil Kamath, Prime Minister Narendra Modi stated, 'I am human who can make mistakes, not some God,' prompting a reaction from the Congress party.</p>
<ul>
<li>The podcast aired on YouTube, where PM Modi discussed his past as Gujarat's chief minister.</li>
<li>Congress MP Jairam Ramesh criticized Modi's comment as a form of damage control.</li>
<li>Ramesh referred to Modi's previous assertion that he was 'sent by God' before the 2024 Lok Sabha elections.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Key Remarks from PM Modi</h2>
<p>During the podcast, he emphasized, 'Everyone makes mistakes, including me,' contrasting earlier statements where he claimed divine inspiration for his actions.</p>
<blockquote>“Until my mother was alive, I used to think I was born biologically... I am convinced that I was sent by God.”</blockquote>
<p>The Congress party's response highlights ongoing political tensions as the elections approach.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/congress-takes-dig-at-pm-modi-over-im-not-a-god-remark-in-podcast-with-nikhil-kamath-101736505505210.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/congress-takes-dig-at-pm-modi-over-im-not-a-god-remark-in-podcast-with-nikhil-kamath-101736505505210.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:09:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video shocker: Pune BPO worker was killed in front of several bystanders in office parking lot - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pune BPO Worker Killed in Office Parking Lot Shocker</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>In a shocking incident, a BPO worker in Pune was killed in front of numerous bystanders in the office parking lot, raising serious security concerns.</p><ul><li>The victim was attacked during daylight hours.</li><li>Witnesses reported a lack of immediate intervention.</li><li>The incident has sparked outrage and calls for better security measures.</li></ul><blockquote>Witnesses expressed concern over the safety of employees in the area.</blockquote><p>This tragic event highlights the urgent need for improved safety protocols in workplaces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/pune/video-shocker-pune-bpo-worker-was-killed-in-front-of-several-bystanders-in-office-parking-lot/articleshow/117097094.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/pune/video-shocker-pune-bpo-worker-was-killed-in-front-of-several-bystanders-in-office-parking-lot/articleshow/117097094.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ACB files case against 2 Srinagar Smart City Limited officials - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ACB Files Case Against Two Officials of Srinagar Smart City Limited</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Jan 10, <strong>Source: </strong>Greater Kashmir</p><p>The Anti-Corruption Bureau (ACB) has registered cases against two employees of Srinagar Smart City Limited for allegedly possessing disproportionate assets.</p><ul><li>ACB officials announced the registration at a press conference.</li><li>Individuals involved are Sajid Yousuf Bhat, Chief Financial Officer, and Zahoor Ahmad Dar, Executive Engineer.</li><li>The bureau is currently conducting searches at seven locations related to the investigation.</li><li>Details regarding the investigation are limited pending searches.</li></ul><blockquote>The ACB stated, “The duo has managed to get assets much higher than their lawful income.”</blockquote><p>The investigation is ongoing, and further details will be provided after its completion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/latest-news/acb-files-case-against-2-srinagar-smart-city-limited-officials/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/latest-news/acb-files-case-against-2-srinagar-smart-city-limited-officials/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:39:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yogi Adityanath's stern 'denting, painting' warning over Waqf claims on Prayagraj Kumbh land - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxOUXlITlZmQkRrYWxobFBtbXdRZWV0enFKVjVwNnBIYnNnRXV5RW1SWnVlUGY5VmsxTFBfYUMtd2hMVVZ3Vl9NQk9xVnVWYVZod3prNllTU3VrY3M0VzYzdHcxVHJXT3BKZjh4YkdKWHhtWDM5RG5CT28tYmtjYWdtYVJ4ZjJaWE52aFZNa08xSEdIUjhoajNWYmtJdmlIZkotX09WNUdYWUE1TGdtSUZ6OHZlWndMeGVTTEFvYUZKcHU2ZU12Nmp3aVZuNUdldV9lOEc0eU16eVRsSFHSAeABQVVfeXFMUGc1TzFTakYzU25lRzllRzRVdVN5UXJPcjV6MWhyd1ZfSDlZMVF3WUR4RE8wUVNZNXFhbE1lamQ1ZXpVdHdBWko3WlBFMVI3dFVONW9LZVFpLWxzOU9DSHpBZnJscFZRUkRFUUpzNHNXQll0MnBDOW81Q0hzRXEtOHp1TzYybnpxekthTFJnUC1RRTVNR2IydVVWZWp5NnQ3Tkd6UWtraTVPUm1GRjcyVE01WXJoeGVGRy1HQUxJd1BYbW92TGRnUkJmRS03eWtZZUVHZHpfR3lKblZoZEdTdVA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxOUXlITlZmQkRrYWxobFBtbXdRZWV0enFKVjVwNnBIYnNnRXV5RW1SWnVlUGY5VmsxTFBfYUMtd2hMVVZ3Vl9NQk9xVnVWYVZod3prNllTU3VrY3M0VzYzdHcxVHJXT3BKZjh4YkdKWHhtWDM5RG5CT28tYmtjYWdtYVJ4ZjJaWE52aFZNa08xSEdIUjhoajNWYmtJdmlIZkotX09WNUdYWUE1TGdtSUZ6OHZlWndMeGVTTEFvYUZKcHU2ZU12Nmp3aVZuNUdldV9lOEc0eU16eVRsSFHSAeABQVVfeXFMUGc1TzFTakYzU25lRzllRzRVdVN5UXJPcjV6MWhyd1ZfSDlZMVF3WUR4RE8wUVNZNXFhbE1lamQ1ZXpVdHdBWko3WlBFMVI3dFVONW9LZVFpLWxzOU9DSHpBZnJscFZRUkRFUUpzNHNXQll0MnBDOW81Q0hzRXEtOHp1TzYybnpxekthTFJnUC1RRTVNR2IydVVWZWp5NnQ3Tkd6UWtraTVPUm1GRjcyVE01WXJoeGVGRy1HQUxJd1BYbW92TGRnUkJmRS03eWtZZUVHZHpfR3lKblZoZEdTdVA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:36:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twist in ‘rape-suicide’ case of 2 girls in Palakkad as CBI arraigns parents as accused - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Twist in 'Rape-Suicide' Case of Two Girls in Palakkad as CBI Files Charges Against Parents</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/CBI-Raid_6c1f5c.jpeg?w=640" alt="Walayar rape case, 2017 Walayar rape case, CBI, Kochi’s CBI court, POCSO Act, Indian express news, current affairs" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Following appeals by the state and the girls’ mother, a sessions court in August 2022 ordered the CBI to probe the case further.</figcaption><p>A 2017 case involving the alleged suicide of two minor girls in Palakkad has seen a significant development with the CBI charging the parents as accused for abetting the abuse and subsequent suicides.</p><ul><li>The two girls, aged 9 and 13, were found hanging at their home in 2017.</li><li>The parents are charged under IPC section 109 and the POCSO Act for failing to report the abuse.</li><li>The CBI's supplementary chargesheet states that the parents were aware of the abuse but did not inform authorities.</li><li>A special POCSO court had previously acquitted four of the accused in 2019 due to lack of evidence.</li><li>Political fallout ensued as the victims' mother alleged police misconduct and later contested in elections.</li></ul><blockquote>“This case continues to stir political and social dialogues about justice and accountability.”</blockquote><p>The developments in this case highlight the complexities surrounding allegations of abuse and the law's response to these tragic events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/thiruvananthapuram/2017-walayar-rape-case-cbi-books-victims-parents-for-abetting-crime-9770586/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/thiruvananthapuram/2017-walayar-rape-case-cbi-books-victims-parents-for-abetting-crime-9770586/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gauri Lankesh murder: All accused out on bail after Bengaluru court grants bail to last one in custody - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/bengaluru-court-grants-bail-to-another-accused-in-gauri-lankesh-murder-case-all-accused-facing-trial-out-on-bail</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/bengaluru-court-grants-bail-to-another-accused-in-gauri-lankesh-murder-case-all-accused-facing-trial-out-on-bail</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:21:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maha Kumbh goes digital: 2,700 CCTVs, AI to track crowd, underwater drones - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maha Kumbh goes digital: 2,700 CCTVs, AI to track crowd, underwater drones</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/expressintro-52.jpg?w=640" alt="Monitored by over 2,750 CCTV cameras bolstered by AI to track the movement of the anticipated 40 crore pilgrims, this Kumbh will be the largest face recognition exercise in the country thus far." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Monitored by over 2,750 CCTV cameras bolstered by AI to track the movement of the anticipated 40 crore pilgrims, this Kumbh will be the largest face recognition exercise in the country thus far. (Express photo by Vishal Srivastava)</figcaption><p>This year's Maha Kumbh in Prayagraj features significant technological advancements with extensive use of CCTV and AI.</p><ul><li>Over 2,750 CCTV cameras will monitor the festival grounds.</li><li>The initiative aims to manage the anticipated influx of 40 crore pilgrims.</li><li>Vijaypuri Bapu, a sadhu, faces challenges with internet connectivity affecting his use of Kumbh apps.</li><li>The Digi Kumbh initiative marks a substantial investment in digital infrastructure by the Uttar Pradesh government.</li></ul><blockquote>“I have been playing bhajans (hymns) and taking photos on my phone. Since there is no Internet, I cannot use any of the Kumbh apps,” says Vijaypuri Bapu.</blockquote><p>The digital advancements aim to enhance safety and service at the Maha Kumbh mela, making it a technologically advanced gathering.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/long-reads/maha-kumbh-goes-digital-2700-cctvs-ai-to-track-crowd-underwater-drones-9770545/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/long-reads/maha-kumbh-goes-digital-2700-cctvs-ai-to-track-crowd-underwater-drones-9770545/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After two postponements in maiden space docking mission, Isro says it will now ‘dock and inform’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After two postponements in maiden space docking mission, Isro says it will now ‘dock and inform’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>The Indian Space Research Organisation (Isro) has decided to proceed with its SpaDeX space docking mission without public announcement after two previous postponements. The agency will conduct the docking and subsequently inform the public.</p><ul><li>The docking was initially scheduled for January 7 and then postponed to January 9.</li><li>A new chairman for Isro, V Narayanan, will assume leadership on January 14.</li><li>The SpaDeX mission is a technology demonstrator for future space operations such as the Chandrayaan missions and building a space station.</li><li>The spacecraft, SDX01 and SDX02, launched on December 30, will gradually approach each other for docking.</li></ul><blockquote>“The docking experiment is called for on account of many reasons. The immediate one is Chandrayaan 4 but later for the space station planned for India,” stated a former Isro official.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Isro's revised approach reflects the agency's commitment to ensuring successful autonomy in space operations, emphasizing reliable and efficient communication with the public moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/space-docking-mission-postponements-isro-9771576/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/space-docking-mission-postponements-isro-9771576/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:39:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Damage control': Congress mock PM Modi 'not a God' remark in his first podcast appearance - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/damage-control-congress-mock-pm-modi-not-a-god-remark-in-his-first-podcast-appearance/articleshow/117117857.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/damage-control-congress-mock-pm-modi-not-a-god-remark-in-his-first-podcast-appearance/articleshow/117117857.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meerut murders: Family of five wiped out, children’s bodies found in bed box - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/uttar-pradesh/meerut-murders-family-of-five-wiped-out-childrens-bodies-found-in-bed-box/article69084394.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/uttar-pradesh/meerut-murders-family-of-five-wiped-out-childrens-bodies-found-in-bed-box/article69084394.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi election: Atishi predicts BJP's CM face citing 'credible sources' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/bjps-cm-face-will-be-atishis-big-claim-on-delhi-assembly-election-101736502028420.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/bjps-cm-face-will-be-atishis-big-claim-on-delhi-assembly-election-101736502028420.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:45:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Srinagar woman abandons marriage for Facebook romance, travels 1,300 km to marry in UP - The Kashmiriyat]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxPbTM2SE9wZmZXVzl5N3FyYmYtMXh3emlrN3RUQnlnSEkyQjV6YkdnOXhLd2FQNElvRExCVUxjUUNhOU1JTEtsUGxSNDJRd1lfYTlTaEUzS2tIZ09GT3ZSbGpoQnQ5ZGhxX3JhSkwyR1ZhQmVuV1VvRnFHRFh3dTk1RTR3Z3REbGhHenlUTGVkS3FUTVdydzJsN3ZQeWtyN1I3VmJsRnIwNW5TMmhCQmthWVVmQ0HSAbQBQVVfeXFMT20zNkhPcGZmV1c5eTdxcmJmLTF4d3ppazd0VEJ5Z0hJMkI1emJHZzl4S3dhUDRJb0RMQlVMY1FDYTlNSUxLbFBsUjQyUXdZX2E5U2hFM0trSGdPRk92UmxqaEJ0OWRocV9yYUpMMkdWYUJlbldVb0ZxR0RYd3U5NUU0d2d0RGxoR3p5VExlZEtxVE1XcncybDd2UHlrcjdSN1ZibEZyMDVuUzJoQkJrYVlVZkNB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxPbTM2SE9wZmZXVzl5N3FyYmYtMXh3emlrN3RUQnlnSEkyQjV6YkdnOXhLd2FQNElvRExCVUxjUUNhOU1JTEtsUGxSNDJRd1lfYTlTaEUzS2tIZ09GT3ZSbGpoQnQ5ZGhxX3JhSkwyR1ZhQmVuV1VvRnFHRFh3dTk1RTR3Z3REbGhHenlUTGVkS3FUTVdydzJsN3ZQeWtyN1I3VmJsRnIwNW5TMmhCQmthWVVmQ0HSAbQBQVVfeXFMT20zNkhPcGZmV1c5eTdxcmJmLTF4d3ppazd0VEJ5Z0hJMkI1emJHZzl4S3dhUDRJb0RMQlVMY1FDYTlNSUxLbFBsUjQyUXdZX2E5U2hFM0trSGdPRk92UmxqaEJ0OWRocV9yYUpMMkdWYUJlbldVb0ZxR0RYd3U5NUU0d2d0RGxoR3p5VExlZEtxVE1XcncybDd2UHlrcjdSN1ZibEZyMDVuUzJoQkJrYVlVZkNB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:37:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I'm Only Human, Not God": PM Modi In Podcast Debut With Zerodha Chief Nikhil Kamath - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>I'm Only Human, Not God: PM Modi In Podcast Debut With Zerodha Chief Nikhil Kamath</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News Article</p><p>In his debut podcast appearance on Zerodha co-founder Nikhil Kamath's show, Prime Minister Narendra Modi acknowledged his flaws, stating, 'I too can make mistakes.' He comforted Kamath over his Hindi skills, emphasizing their shared understanding.</p><ul><li>Prime Minister Modi discusses his humanity and the inevitability of mistakes.</li><li>Nikhil Kamath expresses concerns about his language skills due to his South Indian background.</li><li>The podcast covers Modi’s childhood, education, and challenges faced in politics.</li><li>PM Modi actively engages with Kamath, making the dialogue personal and relatable.</li><li>Modi shared a light-hearted anecdote about his childhood chores.</li></ul><blockquote>'Mistakes happen, and I too can make some. I am also a human, not god.' - PM Modi</blockquote><p>Modi shared a heartfelt message with listeners, hoping they enjoyed the podcast as much as he did creating it.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-nikhil-kamath-zerodha-im-also-human-not-god-pm-modi-in-podcast-debut-with-zerodhas-chief-7442315</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-nikhil-kamath-zerodha-im-also-human-not-god-pm-modi-in-podcast-debut-with-zerodhas-chief-7442315</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:18:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creamy Layer Exclusion From SC/ST Reservation To Be Decided By Executive/Legislature : Supreme Court... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court to Decide on Exclusion of 'Creamy Layer' from SC/ST Reservation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>The Supreme Court has declined to hear a petition seeking the exclusion of the children of IAS/IPS/IFS/IRS/Class-I officers from SC/ST reservation, stating that the issue falls under the domain of the executive and legislature.</p><ul><li>The court upheld the petitioner’s right to withdraw the petition while allowing further legal action.</li><li>It was argued that a definition of 'creamy layer' should be established for the SC/ST reservation policy.</li><li>Counsel referred to a prior Supreme Court judgment advocating for a classification within SC/ST beneficiaries.</li><li>Justice Gavai emphasized that reservation is an enabling provision and not mandatory.</li><li>The current status of the state of MP was criticized for a lack of action following the Supreme Court's earlier judgment.</li></ul><blockquote>“Reservation is not mandatory. It is for the executive and for the legislature to provide reservation or not.” - Justice BR Gavai</blockquote><p>The Supreme Court refrains from interfering at this stage, leaving the decision to the legislative process regarding the exclusion policy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-court-plea-seeking-direction-to-mp-govt-to-frame-policy-for-exclusion-of-creamy-layer-from-sc-st-reservation-withdrawn-280573</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-court-plea-seeking-direction-to-mp-govt-to-frame-policy-for-exclusion-of-creamy-layer-from-sc-st-reservation-withdrawn-280573</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:13:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Authorization of further funds under Revenue Budget out of BE 2024-25 in J&K - Cross Town News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxPX1pZYzUwNlQtbUdWdndQVzZaZ0hyNHJDNlo4VWY4ZGdtdDAySmViaEVDUVhwUEt4cDZZZS1aMVRiSmxVYUl0VVNxMG54cXdGd29QSFZDaG8tX3VtTVlsOXlhdlJaLUg0WEZfS1laUXZfdWlfZnhNZkR2MXhXZ0lYV3pEOWNfazV4bC1DVjRnVmZmS2MzTmVrMEJWcXUwMXZTcHlEMVo5dFVuWHdQeHczbTVJYl90QzNhekc4VmVn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxPX1pZYzUwNlQtbUdWdndQVzZaZ0hyNHJDNlo4VWY4ZGdtdDAySmViaEVDUVhwUEt4cDZZZS1aMVRiSmxVYUl0VVNxMG54cXdGd29QSFZDaG8tX3VtTVlsOXlhdlJaLUg0WEZfS1laUXZfdWlfZnhNZkR2MXhXZ0lYV3pEOWNfazV4bC1DVjRnVmZmS2MzTmVrMEJWcXUwMXZTcHlEMVo5dFVuWHdQeHczbTVJYl90QzNhekc4VmVn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:11:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pune BPO accountant’s murder: Video shows attacker with cleaver in office parking lot, being nabbed after attack - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/pune/pune-bpo-accountant-murder-video-attacker-with-cleaver-office-parking-lot-nabbed-9771139/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/pune/pune-bpo-accountant-murder-video-attacker-with-cleaver-office-parking-lot-nabbed-9771139/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>