<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 13:22:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 13:22:04 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai Ferry Accident: Missing 7-Year-Old Boy's Body Found Off City Coast; Death Toll Rises To 15 - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Ferry Accident: Missing 7-Year-Old Boy's Body Found, Death Toll Rises to 15</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The Neelkamal ferry was on way to Elephanta Islands, a popular tourist destination near Mumbai, when the speed boat crashed into it around 4 pm. (Image: PTI)"><figcaption>The Neelkamal ferry was on way to Elephanta Islands, a popular tourist destination near Mumbai, when the speed boat crashed into it around 4 pm. (Image: PTI)</figcaption><p>The body of a seven-year-old boy who went missing after a ferry capsized off the Mumbai coast was found after a three-day search operation, raising the death toll to 15.</p><ul><li>A Navy speedboat crashed into the ferry on December 18, leading to the accident.</li><li>The Navy and Coast Guard conducted extensive search operations for the missing.</li><li>Of the 113 people on board, 15 have died and 98 were rescued, including two injured.</li><li>The ferry was overloaded, violating safety regulations.</li><li>Investigations are underway into the cause of the accident, with a case registered against the driver of the Navy vehicle.</li></ul><blockquote>Officials stated, "The Navy has launched a probe into one of the deadliest crashes in the city’s coastal area." </blockquote><p>This incident has highlighted serious safety concerns regarding passenger ferries and the enforcement of maritime regulations in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/mumbai-ferry-accident-missing-7-year-old-boys-body-found-off-city-coast-death-toll-rises-to-15-9163796.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/mumbai-ferry-accident-missing-7-year-old-boys-body-found-off-city-coast-death-toll-rises-to-15-9163796.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 12:58:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi meets 101-year-old ex-IFS officer in Kuwait after granddaughter's request - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi meets 101-year-old ex-IFS officer in Kuwait after granddaughter's request</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 21, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/Screenshot_2024-12-21_162839_1734778754027_1734778771362.png" alt="PM Modi met a 101-year-old ex-IFS officer in Kuwait" title="PM Modi met a 101-year-old ex-IFS officer in Kuwait"><figcaption>PM Modi met a 101-year-old ex-IFS officer in Kuwait</figcaption></figure><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi met a 101-year-old former Indian Foreign Service officer in Kuwait after his granddaughter requested a meeting on social media.</p><ul><li>PM Modi's visit is notable as it is the first by an Indian Prime Minister to Kuwait in 43 years.</li><li>The meeting was initiated by a social media request from Mangal Sain Handa’s granddaughter.</li><li>Mangal Sain Handa has a significant legacy as a former IFS officer.</li><li>Kuwait has a large Indian diaspora, constituting 21% of its total population.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is an experience of a lifetime. PM Modi said he especially came here to meet him (my father). We are grateful to Prime Minister Modi.” - Dilip Handa</blockquote><p>PM Modi's visit emphasizes the strong ties between India and Kuwait, highlighting historical connections and mutual interests.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-meets-101-year-old-ex-ifs-officer-in-kuwait-at-granddaughters-request-101734776972325.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-meets-101-year-old-ex-ifs-officer-in-kuwait-at-granddaughters-request-101734776972325.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 12:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab Municipal Elections Live Updates: Voting over amid sporadic incidents of clashes; check results here - PTC News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxPRmdaMm1MdzgtRUwtRGJpSm52YjBIQ3pqMnRCTjBtdjk0enFhendJZi1QQkdWVG1kdTk3c0lXc09SWWh4U1FnSEQ0eC15VmdxRHhFX2Y4RmRub1FtN3Z5MFBJRF96cFlfRXBpTTdUdlNOby1sUUpEYUVhS2hGb0Joa0V4em5mUE1tT0FKQnpNc2hXTzN1TFVnUjlTWW50d3ZWUmszMkJKUzV6QmtoR1FJeWlyTkxtTVRDWXlRb19pWdIBxAFBVV95cUxPa1ZJRXN2SEQyMmZhUldESWpkQkx3WDc1bUNTSUIxRjI3ZTVqQW5zX1dSVGppaHRuRFpWUzBhZm1NS3l0X3p0QkZSeGNTZkhxNzBSR1ZGTk14NUR4RE5lY1AxeF9jQXN3T3Q1LV9pT2FxZmFCdmU1MHVpMmZhUzQ4ZXU4MVlma0JWQ0NjWVNZY0E5d195eVNpYjlIYnNJcTcwdGxxM3JkZWtEcXYzeEw0U01EWnRUYWN2b0pUQWtSQ2ZQWi1H?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxPRmdaMm1MdzgtRUwtRGJpSm52YjBIQ3pqMnRCTjBtdjk0enFhendJZi1QQkdWVG1kdTk3c0lXc09SWWh4U1FnSEQ0eC15VmdxRHhFX2Y4RmRub1FtN3Z5MFBJRF96cFlfRXBpTTdUdlNOby1sUUpEYUVhS2hGb0Joa0V4em5mUE1tT0FKQnpNc2hXTzN1TFVnUjlTWW50d3ZWUmszMkJKUzV6QmtoR1FJeWlyTkxtTVRDWXlRb19pWdIBxAFBVV95cUxPa1ZJRXN2SEQyMmZhUldESWpkQkx3WDc1bUNTSUIxRjI3ZTVqQW5zX1dSVGppaHRuRFpWUzBhZm1NS3l0X3p0QkZSeGNTZkhxNzBSR1ZGTk14NUR4RE5lY1AxeF9jQXN3T3Q1LV9pT2FxZmFCdmU1MHVpMmZhUzQ4ZXU4MVlma0JWQ0NjWVNZY0E5d195eVNpYjlIYnNJcTcwdGxxM3JkZWtEcXYzeEw0U01EWnRUYWN2b0pUQWtSQ2ZQWi1H?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 11:39:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How L-G Nod To Prosecute Arvind Kejriwal Could Impact Delhi Election Game - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Impact of L-G's Approval to Prosecute Arvind Kejriwal on Delhi Elections</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The AAP will try to incur sympathy and use the L-G’s nod to reach out to its voters for Delhi polls. (PTI)" title="The AAP will try to incur sympathy and use the L-G’s nod to reach out to its voters for Delhi polls. (PTI)"><figcaption>The AAP will try to incur sympathy and use the L-G’s nod to reach out to its voters for Delhi polls. (PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>Delhi L-G VK Saxena's approval for the Enforcement Directorate (ED) to prosecute former chief minister Arvind Kejriwal heats up the forthcoming Delhi elections, scheduled for February.</p><ul><li>The Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) seeks to frame the prosecution as evidence of BJP's misuse of power against its opponents.</li><li>BJP presents the approval as proof of Kejriwal's involvement in corruption related to the Delhi excise policy.</li><li>Congress enters the fray, challenging Kejriwal with its candidate, Sandeep Dikshit, highlighting past evidence against him.</li><li>The excise case involves allegations of corruption and kickbacks related to the government's excise policy, now scrapped.</li><li>The political tussle is intensified as both BJP and AAP leverage the corruption narrative ahead of elections.</li></ul><blockquote>“If the L-G has given the go-ahead to ED to prosecute, then where is the copy of this? It’s clear this is a rumour.” - Manish Sisodia</blockquote><p>As the election approaches, the battle centers on accusations of corruption and misuse of authority, with both AAP and BJP staking their claims for voter support.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/elections/how-l-g-nod-to-prosecute-arvind-kejriwal-could-change-delhi-election-game-9163787.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/elections/how-l-g-nod-to-prosecute-arvind-kejriwal-could-change-delhi-election-game-9163787.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 11:17:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi keeps promise made on X, meets woman's 101-year-old grandfather in Kuwait - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Keeps Promise Made on X, Meets Woman's 101-Year-Old Grandfather in Kuwait</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 20, 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a heartfelt gesture, Prime Minister Narendra Modi fulfilled a promise made on X by meeting the 101-year-old grandfather of a woman who expressed her wish to see Modi during his visit to Kuwait.</p><ul><li>Modi's visit to Kuwait marked a significant diplomatic engagement.</li><li>The PM shared a personal moment with the elderly man, emphasizing the importance of connecting with citizens.</li><li>This meeting highlights Modi's commitment to addressing the sentiments of the Indian diaspora.</li></ul><blockquote>“This moment is precious and symbolizes our connection to our elders and our homeland.”</blockquote><p>The meeting showcases not only personal connections but also the attention to the Indian community living abroad, aiming to strengthen ties between India and its global citizens.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pm-modi-keeps-promise-made-on-x-meets-mans-101-year-old-father-in-kuwait/articleshow/116535592.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pm-modi-keeps-promise-made-on-x-meets-mans-101-year-old-father-in-kuwait/articleshow/116535592.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 11:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi liquor case: BJP calls Kejriwal 'kingpin', AAP cries conspiracy after LG nod on ED action - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Liquor Case: BJP Calls Kejriwal 'Kingpin' Amid AAP's Conspiracy Claims</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Delhi liquor case" /><figcaption>Delhi liquor scandal involved political players.</figcaption><p>The Delhi liquor case has escalated with the BJP labeling Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal as the 'kingpin' of the alleged scam, while the AAP is decrying this as a conspiracy following the Lieutenant Governor's approval for ED investigations.</p><ul><li>The BJP claims Kejriwal orchestrated the illicit liquor policy.</li><li>Deepening confrontation between BJP and AAP amidst ongoing investigations.</li><li>AAP alleges political vendetta against its leadership.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a political ploy to undermine our administration,” stated an AAP spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This ongoing saga highlights rising tensions between the ruling party and the opposition in Delhi, as both sides prepare for heightened political battles over the scandal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/delhi-liquor-case-bjp-calls-kejriwal-kingpin-aap-cries-conspiracy-after-lg-nod-on-ed-action/articleshow/116534548.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/delhi-liquor-case-bjp-calls-kejriwal-kingpin-aap-cries-conspiracy-after-lg-nod-on-ed-action/articleshow/116534548.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 11:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISRO finds new partner in Europe to help with space exploration - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ISRO Collaborates with ESA for Enhanced Space Exploration</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 21, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/photo-1446776709462-d6b525c57bd3_1734777886896_1734777940603.jpg" alt="One of the first major projects under the new agreement will be the Axiom-4 mission.(Representational Image)" title="One of the first major projects under the new agreement will be the Axiom-4 mission.(Representational Image)">
<figcaption>One of the first major projects under the new agreement will be the Axiom-4 mission.(Representational Image)</figcaption>
<p>The Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) and the European Space Agency (ESA) have forged a new collaboration aimed at advancing human space exploration. The two agencies signed a comprehensive agreement on Saturday to cooperate on astronaut training, mission implementation, and a variety of research experiments in space.</p>
<ul>
  <li>ISRO and ESA have signed a collaboration agreement for astronaut training and mission implementation.</li>
  <li>The Axiom-4 mission will be among the first significant projects under this partnership.</li>
  <li>The agreement covers human and biomedical research, space experiments, and educational outreach.</li>
  <li>ISRO plans to expand its presence in space with upcoming projects like the Bharatiya Antariksh Station.</li>
  <li>Both agencies have expressed satisfaction with the progress of the Axiom-4 mission.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>Somanath highlighted ISRO's roadmap for human spaceflight, emphasizing the agency’s long-term vision for expanding its presence in space.</p></blockquote>
<p>This partnership is set to open new avenues for scientific research and technology advancements in space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/isro-finds-new-partner-in-europe-to-help-with-space-exploration-101734777808858.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/isro-finds-new-partner-in-europe-to-help-with-space-exploration-101734777808858.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 10:48:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Day after Andhra woman was delivered body in crate, police on lookout for brother-in-law - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Andhra Woman Receives Body in Crate: Police Hunt for Brother-in-Law</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 21, 2024 - Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Indian-Express-17_20241221104156.jpg?w=640" alt="The body has yet to be identified but police say it is likely from a nearby village “because the sender would not take the risk of sending the parcel with a dead body inside from a far-off location”. (File Photo)" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>The body has yet to be identified but police say it is likely from a nearby village “because the sender would not take the risk of sending the parcel with a dead body inside from a far-off location”. (File Photo)</figcaption>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> A woman in Undi, Andhra Pradesh, received a body with a disfigured face in a wooden crate, prompting a police investigation and a search for her brother-in-law.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Body Delivery:</strong> The body was sent to R Tulasi’s under-construction house, wrapped in plastic sheets within a wooden crate along with electrical wires.</li>
<li><strong>Police Investigation:</strong> The police are investigating a call made to Tulasi informing her of the parcel delivery.</li>
<li><strong>Suspect:</strong> C Sridhar alias Varma, Tulasi’s brother-in-law, is the prime suspect and has been absconding since Friday.</li>
<li><strong>Note Found:</strong> A note claiming that Tulasi’s husband owed Rs 3 lakh, now standing at Rs 1.30 crore with interest, was found.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>“This was very carefully planned, the way the body was packed and stuffed in the crate, and how it was ensured that it was delivered to the house. So far, no one from any village has come forward to report their family member or relative missing,” SP Asmi said.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The body has been sent for post-mortem, and the police are continuing their investigation into the identity of the deceased and the motive behind the crime.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/andhra-woman-delivered-body-crate-police-lookout-brother-in-law-9737741/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/andhra-woman-delivered-body-crate-police-lookout-brother-in-law-9737741/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 10:44:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kerala Lottery Results 21.12.2024: Karunya KR-685 Winners Announced; Full List Here! - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kerala Lottery Results: Karunya KR-685 Winners Announced</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong><time>December 21, 2024</time>, <strong>Source: </strong>News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Kerala Lottery Results" />
<figcaption>Kerala Lottery Karunya KR-685 Results: The first prize winner of Karunya KR-685 will get Rs 80 lakh. (Image: Shutterstock)</figcaption>
<p>The results of the Kerala Lottery's Karunya KR-685 lucky draw have been announced, revealing significant cash prizes including a top reward of Rs 80 lakh.</p>
<ul>
<li>First prize: KV 829857 (Vadakara) - Rs 80 lakh</li>
<li>Second prize: KW 948415 (Thirur) - Rs 5 lakh</li>
<li>Third prize: KN 945606 (Thirur) and others - Rs 1 lakh</li>
<li>Consolation prizes of Rs 8,000 were awarded to several ticket numbers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Winners have 30 days from the draw date to present their winning ticket.”</blockquote>
<p>This lottery continues to be a significant event in Kerala, providing substantial rewards and is followed closely by the public.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/kerala-lottery-result-today-live-updates-karunya-kr-685-winners-list-for-21-december-2024-9161174.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/kerala-lottery-result-today-live-updates-karunya-kr-685-winners-list-for-21-december-2024-9161174.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 10:40:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Perpetual Toll Collection Arbitrary; No Entity Can't Be Allowed Unjust Enrichment At Public Cost :... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Rejects Toll Imposition Plea for DND Flyway</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>2024</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Live Law</p><p>The Supreme Court dismissed a plea to impose tolls on Delhi Noida Direct (DND) flyway, emphasizing that no entity should profit unjustly at the cost of public suffering.</p><ul><li>The Court found the contract with Noida Toll Bridge Company Limited (NTBCL) unfair and inconsistent with Constitutional norms.</li><li>Public infrastructure projects must serve the public and not merely enrich private entities.</li><li>NTBCL has already recovered costs and made substantial profits from user fees/tolls.</li><li>The clause allowing NTBCL to collect user fees indefinitely was deemed opposed to public policy.</li><li>The Court expressed concern over transparency and fairness in public projects and called for investigations into potential corruption.</li></ul><blockquote>“When a state undertakes a project involving an overwhelming public element, comprising of public funds and public assets, its actions must remain free of arbitrariness and remain grounded in a just, transparent and a well-defined policy.”</blockquote><p>The ruling reinforces the need for fairness in public infrastructure contracts and highlights the potential misuse of power by officials.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-court-delhi-noida-flyway-toll-no-entity-can-be-allowed-unjust-enrichment-at-cost-of-public-suffering-279132</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-court-delhi-noida-flyway-toll-no-entity-can-be-allowed-unjust-enrichment-at-cost-of-public-suffering-279132</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 10:05:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Couple Threatened And Extorted, Woman Molested At Madhya Pradesh Picnic Spot - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Couple Threatened and Extorted, Woman Molested at Madhya Pradesh Picnic Spot</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 28 September 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Couple Threatened And Extorted, Woman Molested At Madhya Pradesh Picnic Spot" alt="Couple Threatened And Extorted, Woman Molested At Madhya Pradesh Picnic Spot" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lt7o5idg_rewa-police_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>Incident under investigation by Rewa police</figcaption><p>In a troubling incident in Madhya Pradesh's Rewa district, a young couple was threatened and extorted by a group while on a picnic. A viral video of the event has raised public concern and prompted police action.</p><ul><li>A couple was caught in a secluded area by a group of individuals.</li><li>The perpetrators extorted money and molested the woman, as seen in a viral video.</li><li>The Rewa police have initiated an investigation and are seeking the victims to ensure their safety and confidentiality.</li><li>Police teams from multiple stations are involved in gathering information.</li><li>This incident follows a previous attack on a couple near a temple that resulted in severe violence.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are actively searching for the victims and appeal to them to come forward. Their identities will be kept confidential, and the culprits will face stringent action.” - Superintendent of Police (SP) Rewa</blockquote><p>The incident highlights ongoing concerns about safety in secluded areas and the need for increased vigilance to protect individuals from harassment and violence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/bhopal-news/couple-threatened-and-extorted-woman-molested-at-madhya-pradesh-picnic-spot-7300664</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/bhopal-news/couple-threatened-and-extorted-woman-molested-at-madhya-pradesh-picnic-spot-7300664</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:54:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wife's Financial Independence No Bar To Grant Alimony If It's Necessary To Secure Dignity & Social... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Grants Permanent Alimony to Secure Financial Independence Post-Divorce</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p><p>The Supreme Court has ruled that maintenance can be granted even if a party is financially independent, emphasizing the necessity to uphold dignity and financial stability following divorce.</p><img src='https://www.livelaw.in/images/alimony-supreme-court.jpg' alt='Supreme Court ruling on alimony'><figcaption>Supreme Court ruling on alimony.</figcaption><p>The Court awarded Rs 50 lakhs as permanent alimony to a wife, taking into consideration the length of marriage, earning capacities, and the emotional and financial burdens faced during litigation.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court emphasized that financial independence does not negate the need for maintenance.</li><li>The Court granted Rs 50 lakhs as permanent alimony for dignity and stability.</li><li>Factors for awarding alimony include marriage duration, earning capacities, and contributions to the marriage.</li><li>Past case references were made to reinforce the judgment's rationale.</li></ul><blockquote><i>“The financial independence of a party does not preclude the High Court from granting maintenance if it is necessary to secure dignity...”</i></blockquote><p>This ruling reaffirms the position that alimony is essential for post-divorce sustenance while considering the well-being of dependent parties.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/wifes-financial-independence-no-bar-to-grant-alimony-if-its-necessary-to-secure-dignity-social-standing-post-divorce-supreme-court-279128</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/wifes-financial-independence-no-bar-to-grant-alimony-if-its-necessary-to-secure-dignity-social-standing-post-divorce-supreme-court-279128</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:37:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chennai man plays online rummy with money for mother's cancer treatment, dies by suicide: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxPSTRpLWJKSFdPT1NxN1hVTzVrV001NmNZUWJJd2s3djg1VmFaVkhzUHo3YzFoSmJCSFdMLUcya0hWUUtnUENseWdBTE1qUVhIV1duY3JXUjh6Q1ZtVFFaRzRkUmJJWHNHN282eDZQNmRHUC1rby1jU0ctVy1ZYkRfV3RLa1JxSXYzM1F1SkV6eFRrbkltUTJtWW1KN1hMM3VOVjhjOFR0YUs0NlRydURoTm12dUtmTUo5RTN6aUhFTVpNYm5tSUV0S2Q3YUxVZE5JV3p6cURKQ0FseXMwM3EydG83ZGNDSTZVOUxCLTdB0gHzAUFVX3lxTFBjMlFKT2ppcUcwT2t0eW0xREVrb1hVZkpVaGUzYnlXOHBEU3I2c1M0QjlSck9tMVBGUDBoN0praWhodnNDcmt0RE1RelhzWkdhV1RhQ01EZC1wbzRSVzVSLW9pZWJzcWxkYmt0MkhTX3VDSkJzWXZkcWFnYlp2cUdONUtZN3ZfX0FqQXBQUEMtVXZQZjcyOFNhNEJVZlU2eklHeHNrMDJjWjFzTFoxWWlsdWVrRUFWdmpfbFBkbVVRN0pFbExKdnRUbHVSSzFselNCNmFjVmFrU3pDSlc1OE9pQmNGX0lPb3R5X201aWN6V2Q0Yw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxPSTRpLWJKSFdPT1NxN1hVTzVrV001NmNZUWJJd2s3djg1VmFaVkhzUHo3YzFoSmJCSFdMLUcya0hWUUtnUENseWdBTE1qUVhIV1duY3JXUjh6Q1ZtVFFaRzRkUmJJWHNHN282eDZQNmRHUC1rby1jU0ctVy1ZYkRfV3RLa1JxSXYzM1F1SkV6eFRrbkltUTJtWW1KN1hMM3VOVjhjOFR0YUs0NlRydURoTm12dUtmTUo5RTN6aUhFTVpNYm5tSUV0S2Q3YUxVZE5JV3p6cURKQ0FseXMwM3EydG83ZGNDSTZVOUxCLTdB0gHzAUFVX3lxTFBjMlFKT2ppcUcwT2t0eW0xREVrb1hVZkpVaGUzYnlXOHBEU3I2c1M0QjlSck9tMVBGUDBoN0praWhodnNDcmt0RE1RelhzWkdhV1RhQ01EZC1wbzRSVzVSLW9pZWJzcWxkYmt0MkhTX3VDSkJzWXZkcWFnYlp2cUdONUtZN3ZfX0FqQXBQUEMtVXZQZjcyOFNhNEJVZlU2eklHeHNrMDJjWjFzTFoxWWlsdWVrRUFWdmpfbFBkbVVRN0pFbExKdnRUbHVSSzFselNCNmFjVmFrU3pDSlc1OE9pQmNGX0lPb3R5X201aWN6V2Q0Yw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:28:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GST Council Meeting Highlights: Nirmala Sitharaman defers decision on insurance tax, sweet popcorn to attract 18% tax - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GST Council Meeting Highlights: Nirmala Sitharaman defers decision on insurance tax, sweet popcorn to attract 18% tax</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date]</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>The 55th GST Council meeting, chaired by Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman, introduced key changes to the taxation framework while deferring decisions regarding GST restructuring for insurance products.</p><ul><li><strong>Popcorn Taxation:</strong> Unpackaged popcorn will attract 5% GST, pre-packaged popcorn a 12% rate, and caramel-coated popcorn will be taxed at 18%.</li><li><strong>Fortified Rice Kernels:</strong> GST rate standardized at 5%, down from 18%.</li><li><strong>ACC Blocks:</strong> GST for blocks with over 50% fly ash reduced to 12% from 18%.</li><li><strong>Used Cars and EVs:</strong> GST increased on the sale of old vehicles to 18% from 12%.</li></ul><blockquote>“Some members said more discussions are required. We (GoM) will meet in January again,” - Bihar Deputy Chief Minister Samrat Chaudhary</blockquote><p>The Council concluded that further technical discussions are necessary for insurance-related GST changes, postponing any immediate decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/economy/gst-council-meeting-today-key-highlights-meeting-nirmala-sitharaman-rate-cut-key-decisions-popcorn-used-car-insurance-11734771690354.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/economy/gst-council-meeting-today-key-highlights-meeting-nirmala-sitharaman-rate-cut-key-decisions-popcorn-used-car-insurance-11734771690354.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:17:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Priyanka Gandhi bristles as BJP MP gifts her 'Sikh genocide' bag - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Priyanka Gandhi Responds to BJP MP's 'Sikh Genocide' Bag Gift</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified | <strong>Source: </strong>Not specified</p><p>In a controversial incident, Congress leader Priyanka Gandhi expressed her displeasure when a BJP MP presented her with a bag labeled 'Sikh genocide', highlighting the ongoing political tensions in India.</p><ul><li>The incident took place during a recent political event.</li><li>Gandhi's reaction was widely covered in news and social media.</li><li>Political observers noted the implications of such gestures in the context of ongoing communal tensions in the country.</li></ul><blockquote>“Such acts only aim to provoke and distract from real issues.”</blockquote><p>This incident further escalates the ongoing political discourse around communalism and historical grievances in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/priyanka-gandhi-bristles-as-bjp-mp-gifts-her-sikh-genocide-bag/articleshow/116516498.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/priyanka-gandhi-bristles-as-bjp-mp-gifts-her-sikh-genocide-bag/articleshow/116516498.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ambedkar row: Amit Shah bitten by 'rabid dog,' says Karnataka minister Priyank Kharge - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka Minister Priyank Kharge Criticizes Amit Shah's Remarks on Ambedkar</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 21 December 2024, 08:50 IST</p><p>Karnataka Minister for IT and BT, Priyank Kharge, condemned Union Home Minister Amit Shah's comments regarding B.R. Ambedkar, accusing him of being out of touch with the principles of equality.</p><ul><li>Kharge stated that Shah has been "bitten by a rabid dog" in his views about Ambedkar.</li><li>The minister emphasized the importance of Ambedkar's philosophy for achieving political, social, and economic equality.</li><li>Shah's remarks have stirred controversy, with accusations that the Congress party is misrepresenting his statements.</li></ul><blockquote>"The more Ambedkar and Basava philosophy grow, the RSS ideology will diminish." – Priyank Kharge</blockquote><p>This exchange highlights ongoing tensions in Indian politics regarding legacy figures like Ambedkar and the interpretation of equality in contemporary discourse.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/ambedkar-row-amit-shah-bitten-by-rabid-dog-says-karnataka-minister-priyank-kharge-3327835</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/ambedkar-row-amit-shah-bitten-by-rabid-dog-says-karnataka-minister-priyank-kharge-3327835</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 08:50:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sanction To Prosecute Arvind Kejriwal? AAP Demands Copy Of Approval Letter - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxOZDVCbGtmSDdkWHlwUEdGc2JmZUh2bEFwb2VXMDdqWWpEdzA1THpEU0VHbmh4Qk83R0libWJxaUdZMXlZUTBSY0JGdUQ3RTA3ZmFuZUFBZXFQVGFsZHlYUVN3cThxOEpsd0EwVFJuS3NxaE41ZGtBOENUZkk0SkNYY1JvVlJXS0pJTmtHMlQ0Y2xScGVRT0xjWnhjd0JzMnd2WkFWWTRyaEhiTUs3MkVUVldxYVJybVpJWG1XZTU5R1poMTRJNFVFRTl0WDQtUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxOZDVCbGtmSDdkWHlwUEdGc2JmZUh2bEFwb2VXMDdqWWpEdzA1THpEU0VHbmh4Qk83R0libWJxaUdZMXlZUTBSY0JGdUQ3RTA3ZmFuZUFBZXFQVGFsZHlYUVN3cThxOEpsd0EwVFJuS3NxaE41ZGtBOENUZkk0SkNYY1JvVlJXS0pJTmtHMlQ0Y2xScGVRT0xjWnhjd0JzMnd2WkFWWTRyaEhiTUs3MkVUVldxYVJybVpJWG1XZTU5R1poMTRJNFVFRTl0WDQtUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 08:30:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Depression over Bay of Bengal: IMD predicts system's next course, rainfall in Odisha - OTV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQZlk1MV9fbHVzVVM5UlBoX1Q2UVpQNHhoZkdHS01FeTZFYXVGRGx2R0Z5bEpkMGg1eFVKcFpoY0M3Y2hFTHNoTWVrbjBtSDc3d1lDVUxCcVhQazI3Q0lJUU54ZGRoT3B0Y2lEZVZvMG95Yi1ZeEFiakRWcFgzSnBCaTNSRmV6dFlhT2Mwek50TTljMkVWcjhZSDlGTjdlOVBxOTZ4eE1HSTNHWDFVZU5zX3J3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQZlk1MV9fbHVzVVM5UlBoX1Q2UVpQNHhoZkdHS01FeTZFYXVGRGx2R0Z5bEpkMGg1eFVKcFpoY0M3Y2hFTHNoTWVrbjBtSDc3d1lDVUxCcVhQazI3Q0lJUU54ZGRoT3B0Y2lEZVZvMG95Yi1ZeEFiakRWcFgzSnBCaTNSRmV6dFlhT2Mwek50TTljMkVWcjhZSDlGTjdlOVBxOTZ4eE1HSTNHWDFVZU5zX3J3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 08:27:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka: 6 of family dead in horrific car accident - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tragic Car Accident Claims Six Lives in Karnataka Family</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 24, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>A horrific car accident in Karnataka has resulted in the death of six family members, marking a devastating loss for the local community.</p><ul><li>Six individuals from the same family lost their lives.</li><li>The accident occurred on a highway in Karnataka.</li><li>The car reportedly collided with a truck.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is an unthinkable tragedy for our community," said a local resident.</blockquote><p>The incident has sparked discussions about road safety and the risks associated with highway travel.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/karnataka-6-of-family-dead-in-horrific-car-accident/articleshow/116531385.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/karnataka-6-of-family-dead-in-horrific-car-accident/articleshow/116531385.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 08:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trouble For Arvind Kejriwal, Delhi Lt Governor Allows Probe Agency To Prosecute Him - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AAP Demands Copy of Sanction as Kejriwal Faces Prosecution</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> February 4, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Sanction To Prosecute Arvind Kejriwal? AAP Demands Copy Of Approval Letter" alt="Sanction To Prosecute Arvind Kejriwal? AAP Demands Copy Of Approval Letter" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/8nom5n9g_vk-saxena-arvind-kejriwal_625x300_04_February_24.jpg"><figcaption>Sanction To Prosecute Arvind Kejriwal</figcaption><p>In a significant development, the Lieutenant Governor VK Saxena has sanctioned the Enforcement Directorate to prosecute former Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal in an alleged money laundering case linked to a liquor policy scam. This decision comes ahead of crucial Delhi elections.</p><ul><li>The AAP has labeled the sanction as "false and misleading" and requested the ED to disclose the approval letter from the Lt Governor.</li><li>The case accusations relate to the Prevention of Money Laundering Act, with a previous trial against Kejriwal pending.</li><li>Delhi BJP chief Virendra Sachdeva has welcomed the sanction, asserting Kejriwal's involvement in corruption.</li><li>Chief Minister Atishi criticized the timing of the news as a distraction tactic and demanded transparency from the ED.</li><li>The liquor policy scam continues to be a major point of contention between the AAP and the BJP.</li></ul><blockquote>“If LG sahab has given permission to prosecute Arvind Kejriwal ji, then what is the problem for ED in making the copy of the approval public?” - Chief Minister Atishi</blockquote><p>This political turmoil adds to the drama leading up to the elections, with the opposition intensifying its campaign against Kejriwal and his party.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/delhi-lt-governor-allows-probe-agency-to-prosecute-arvind-kejriwal-in-liquor-policy-scam-case-7299507</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/delhi-lt-governor-allows-probe-agency-to-prosecute-arvind-kejriwal-in-liquor-policy-scam-case-7299507</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 07:59:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arrested members of banned outfit had plans to target ‘Chicken’s Neck’, create instability: West Bengal Police - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/west-bengal/arrested-members-of-banned-outfit-had-plans-to-target-chickens-neck-create-instability-west-bengal-police/article69012127.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/west-bengal/arrested-members-of-banned-outfit-had-plans-to-target-chickens-neck-create-instability-west-bengal-police/article69012127.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 07:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marriage Built On Mutual Trust, Companionship; When These Missing, Marital Bond Becomes Mere Legal... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/supreme-court/marriage-built-on-mutual-trust-companionship-when-these-missing-marital-bond-becomes-mere-legal-formality-supreme-court-279110</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/supreme-court/marriage-built-on-mutual-trust-companionship-when-these-missing-marital-bond-becomes-mere-legal-formality-supreme-court-279110</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 07:55:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GST Council Meeting Live Updates: Defers insurance overhaul, recommends 18% tax on used EVs and smaller cars - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxOY1F1a0hfZ2lMRkE1Wm9xeFBPWWhibFR0cnlqYWRweFVDMy1YUU1ONEJMd0xackxxdTNud3o1UWNER3FRXzBSeXZBTEQ3akpqS1FVUFhhREtTX2FxMXN1azI3MlhVMDN3dWYzSDh6Umh6WnlaeXBIZ3FwTXhsZXJZNTB5blYtcEwwTkhHbm9qb0pxY0JBSEs3RmVJNklzU0hJV3kzenJNOHJfVk0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxOY1F1a0hfZ2lMRkE1Wm9xeFBPWWhibFR0cnlqYWRweFVDMy1YUU1ONEJMd0xackxxdTNud3o1UWNER3FRXzBSeXZBTEQ3akpqS1FVUFhhREtTX2FxMXN1azI3MlhVMDN3dWYzSDh6Umh6WnlaeXBIZ3FwTXhsZXJZNTB5blYtcEwwTkhHbm9qb0pxY0JBSEs3RmVJNklzU0hJV3kzenJNOHJfVk0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 07:55:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai boat accident: Body of missing boy found off Mumbai coast; toll rises to 15 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Boat Accident: Recovery of Missing Boy Raises Death Toll to 15</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> December 21, 2024 01:05 pm IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/lk4317/article69012142.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241220255L.jpg" alt="The body of a seven-year-old boy missing in the ferry-Navy craft crash off the Mumbai coast was recovered. File " /><figcaption>The body of a seven-year-old boy missing in the ferry-Navy craft crash off the Mumbai coast was recovered. File | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The body of a seven-year-old boy missing from the Mumbai ferry accident was recovered, raising the death toll from the tragedy to 15. The Navy has launched an investigation into this incident.</p><ul><li>The boy was among those missing after a ferry collided with a Navy craft on December 18, 2024.</li><li>A total of 113 people were on board both vessels; 98 were rescued, including two injured.</li><li>The ferry was reportedly overloaded and had permission for only 90 people according to maritime documents.</li><li>The license of the ferry has been cancelled by the Maharashtra Maritime Board due to the overcrowding.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is one of the deadliest crashes in the city's harbour area,” said a Navy official.</blockquote><p>As investigations continue, actions are being taken against those responsible for the tragic incident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/mumbai-boat-accident-body-of-missing-boy-found-off-mumbai-coast-toll-rises-to-15/article69012138.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/mumbai-boat-accident-body-of-missing-boy-found-off-mumbai-coast-toll-rises-to-15/article69012138.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 07:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GST Council meet key decisions: Clarity on tax rate on popcorn, GST rate on sale of used cars increased, - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GST Council meet key decisions: Clarity on tax rate on popcorn, GST rate on sale of used cars increased, says report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>2023-10-20 <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><p>The recent GST Council meeting has clarified tax rates on popcorn and increased GST rates on the sale of used cars, impacting consumers and businesses alike.</p><ul><li>The tax rate on popcorn served in cinemas has been standardized.</li><li>The GST rate on used cars has been raised, affecting second-hand car sales.</li><li>These changes aim to simplify tax structures and enhance revenue generation.</li></ul><blockquote>“These decisions reflect our commitment to simplifying taxation and ensuring fair compliance across sectors,” said the Finance Minister.</blockquote><p>This decision marks a significant shift in GST regulations, with potential long-term impacts on consumer choices and market dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/gst-council-meeting-key-decisions-highlights-goods-and-services-tax-nirmala-sitharaman-top-55th-gst-council-meet-takeaways/articleshow/116529340.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/gst-council-meeting-key-decisions-highlights-goods-and-services-tax-nirmala-sitharaman-top-55th-gst-council-meet-takeaways/articleshow/116529340.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 07:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi L-G gives nod to ED to prosecute Kejriwal in excise policy scam case, AAP calls it ‘harassment’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi L-G Gives Nod to ED to Prosecute Kejriwal in Excise Policy Scam Case</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/AAP-LG.jpeg?w=640" alt="Arvind Kejriwal" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Relations between Delhi Lieutenant Governor V K Saxena and Arvind Kejriwal have been strained for a long time now. (File Photo)</figcaption>
<p>Delhi Lieutenant Governor V K Saxena has approved the Enforcement Directorate (ED) to prosecute Arvind Kejriwal in a case related to an excise policy scam, a move AAP describes as harassment.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The ED sought permission to prosecute Kejriwal regarding irregularities in the excise policy for the year 2021-22.</li>
  <li>Several AAP leaders have been jailed amid the ongoing investigation.</li>
  <li>AAP claims the prosecution sanction is a political tool used against them.</li>
  <li>The investigation has led to extensive raids and document filings without any financial recovery.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The so-called liquor scam investigation has dragged on for two years... not a single penny has been recovered,” AAP alleged.</blockquote>
<p>The decision has further intensified the political conflict between the AAP government and the Lieutenant Governor's office, highlighting ongoing tensions in Delhi's governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/delhi/delhi-lg-ed-prosecute-arvind-kejriwal-excise-policy-scam-case-9737448/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/delhi/delhi-lg-ed-prosecute-arvind-kejriwal-excise-policy-scam-case-9737448/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 06:52:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MPESB Group 5 Online Form 2025 - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMia0FVX3lxTFBIYzR1dDBwUHRXV1FNT1k3QTVDWWNsYmRmaENjNk5nTmdzaHdtZEc0MTFabFhNVHh5b20zS3BYeTBZS3Ytdjh4ZHhJRkxhaGR6VDZpSHNxZl9PM1hpakFvb2R6NXRIR3h1QVNj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMia0FVX3lxTFBIYzR1dDBwUHRXV1FNT1k3QTVDWWNsYmRmaENjNk5nTmdzaHdtZEc0MTFabFhNVHh5b20zS3BYeTBZS3Ytdjh4ZHhJRkxhaGR6VDZpSHNxZl9PM1hpakFvb2R6NXRIR3h1QVNj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 06:34:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GST Council Meeting Live Updates: 55th meeting kicks off under Nirmala Sitharaman’s chairmanship, with key participation from State leaders - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxOY1F1a0hfZ2lMRkE1Wm9xeFBPWWhibFR0cnlqYWRweFVDMy1YUU1ONEJMd0xackxxdTNud3o1UWNER3FRXzBSeXZBTEQ3akpqS1FVUFhhREtTX2FxMXN1azI3MlhVMDN3dWYzSDh6Umh6WnlaeXBIZ3FwTXhsZXJZNTB5blYtcEwwTkhHbm9qb0pxY0JBSEs3RmVJNklzU0hJV3kzenJNOHJfVk0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxOY1F1a0hfZ2lMRkE1Wm9xeFBPWWhibFR0cnlqYWRweFVDMy1YUU1ONEJMd0xackxxdTNud3o1UWNER3FRXzBSeXZBTEQ3akpqS1FVUFhhREtTX2FxMXN1azI3MlhVMDN3dWYzSDh6Umh6WnlaeXBIZ3FwTXhsZXJZNTB5blYtcEwwTkhHbm9qb0pxY0JBSEs3RmVJNklzU0hJV3kzenJNOHJfVk0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 06:33:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[40 kg silver, bundles of notes recovered from former Transport Department constable's house in Bhopal - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>40 kg silver, bundles of notes recovered from former Transport Department constable's house in Bhopal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 21 December 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p><p>Bundles of notes and 40 kg of silver were recovered from the house of a former constable of the Transport Department during a Lokayukta Raid in Bhopal.</p><blockquote>"#WATCH | Madhya Pradesh | 40 kg of silver and bundle of notes were recovered from the house of a former constable of the Transport Department during a Lokayukta Raid, yesterday, in Bhopal: Lokayukta" — ANI</blockquote><ul><li>The raid took place on December 20, 2024.</li><li>This incident follows a previous raid where assets worth over Rs 3 crore were found, including cash and gold.</li><li>Documents related to properties were found and are under scrutiny.</li></ul><p>This incident raises concerns about corruption within the Transport Department in Madhya Pradesh.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/madhya-pradesh/40-kg-silver-bundles-of-notes-recovered-from-former-transport-department-constables-house-in-bhopal-3327745</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/madhya-pradesh/40-kg-silver-bundles-of-notes-recovered-from-former-transport-department-constables-house-in-bhopal-3327745</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 06:06:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jaipur-Ajmer highway truck fire: Death toll rises to 14; Sachin Pilot meets victims at SMS hospitals - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rajasthan/death-toll-in-jaipur-ajmer-highway-truck-fire-rises/article69011934.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rajasthan/death-toll-in-jaipur-ajmer-highway-truck-fire-rises/article69011934.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 06:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>