<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:21:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:21:20 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swami Vivekananda’s visit to Belagavi recalled - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Swami Vivekananda’s Visit to Belagavi Recalled</h1><p><strong>Published: January 13, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/az655e/article69093235.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/9727_12_1_2025_21_13_44_1_13BGMVIVEKNADIGE1.JPEG" alt="BJP members taking out Vivek Nadige Marathon to mark Swami Vivekananda Jayanti in Belagavi on Sunday." /><figcaption>BJP members taking out Vivek Nadige Marathon to mark Swami Vivekananda Jayanti in Belagavi on Sunday. | Photo Credit: P.K. Badiger</figcaption><p>Rich tributes were paid to Swami Vivekananda by various organisations, students unions, and academic institutions on his 163rd birth anniversary.</p><ul><li>Events were held in Dharwad, attended by students from schools, colleges, and Karnatak University.</li><li>At JSS college, JSS secretary Ajit Prasad highlighted Swami Vivekananda's teachings on willpower and self-conquest.</li><li>The importance of determination, concentration, and patience in achieving goals was emphasized.</li><li>In Belagavi, local MLA Balachandra Jarkiholi urged youth to draw inspiration from Vivekananda.</li><li>A Viveka Nadige Marathon was organized, starting from the Ramakrishna Mission Ashram.</li><li>BJP district president Subhash Patil spoke on Vivekananda's contributions and his historical visit to Belagavi in 1892.</li></ul><blockquote>“Swami Vivekananda dedicated his life for the upliftment of society. It should inspire us all.” - Subhash Patil</blockquote><p>The celebrations of Vivekananda’s legacy continue to inspire people, especially the youth, in their pursuits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/swami-vivekanandas-visit-to-belagavi-recalled/article69093019.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/swami-vivekanandas-visit-to-belagavi-recalled/article69093019.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh Mela 2025 Live Updates: 1.5 crore people bathe at Sangam on 1st day, Yogi Adityanath congratulates seers, devotees - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh Mela 2025 Live Updates: 1.5 Crore People Bathe at Sangam on 1st Day</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source: </strong>The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Mahakumbh-1.jpg?w=640" alt="Mahakumbh 2025 Day 1:" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Devotees taking holy dip at the bank of Triveni Sangam during Maha Kumbh in Prayagraj.</figcaption><p>At the onset of the Maha Kumbh festival, approximately 1.5 crore devotees gathered to take a holy dip at Sangam on the auspicious occasion of Paush Purnima. Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath commended various organizations for their efforts in making the first day successful.</p><ul><li>The Kumbh fair runs until February 26, with 50 lakh participants planning to stay for the entire duration.</li><li>549 projects have been initiated for the event with a budget of Rs 6,990 crore.</li><li>Installation of 2,300 CCTV cameras for crowd management and safety purposes.</li></ul><blockquote>“I thank the Mela and Prayagraj administrations, state police, and local civic bodies for their support.” – Yogi Adityanath</blockquote><p>The Mahakumbh Mela is a significant cultural and spiritual gathering, marked by its ancient ties to Hindu mythology and history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-uttar-pradesh-yogi-adityanath-9774779/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-uttar-pradesh-yogi-adityanath-9774779/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:21:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025 live: Holy dip performed by 1.5 cr devotees on first day, says UP CM - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh 2025 Live: 1.5 Crore Devotees Take Holy Dip on Day One</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/prayagraj_maha_kumbh_1736743787205_1736772264252.jfif" alt="Mahakumbh 2025: Devotees at Mahakumbh on Day 1" />
<figcaption>Mahakumbh 2025 live: Devotees at Mahakumbh on Day 1. (Prayagraj District Administration via ANI)</figcaption>
</div>
<p>The Mahakumbh Mela 2025 has commenced in Prayagraj, attracting an estimated 1.5 crore (15 million) devotees on the first day. This 45-day event is expected to witness a total of over 40 crore attendees, celebrated for its spiritual richness and cultural heritage.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The event kicked off on Paush Purnima, which features significant bathing rituals.</li>
  <li>UP CM Yogi Adityanath greeted attendees, calling it a unique opportunity to experience cultural and spiritual heritage.</li>
  <li>Over 40,000 security personnel are deployed to ensure the safety of pilgrims.</li>
  <li>Various safety arrangements were established, including traffic management and health facilities.</li>
  <li>Upcoming major bathing dates include January 14 (Makar Sankranti) and January 29 (Mauni Amavasya).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Today, Mahakumbh has begun. I congratulate all devotees, pilgrims, and the saints. Everyone should take part in the holy 'snan' during the Mahakumbh and get rid of all sins,” - Uttarakhand CM Pushkar Singh Dhami.</blockquote>
<p>The event continues to draw worldwide attention, marking a significant cultural gathering with profound spiritual implications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-sangam-shahi-snan-paush-purnima-holy-dip-jan-13-2025-101736725472437.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-sangam-shahi-snan-paush-purnima-holy-dip-jan-13-2025-101736725472437.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:44:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ashwini Vaishnaw fact-checks Mark Zuckerberg over India polls remark: 'Misinformation' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashwini Vaishnaw fact-checks Mark Zuckerberg over India polls remark: 'Misinformation'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/Union-Minister-Ashwini-Vaishnaw---PTI-_1736772952241_1736772971994.jpg" alt="Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw. (PTI)"><figcaption>Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw. (PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>Union minister Ashwini Vaishnaw criticized Mark Zuckerberg's remark that India's ruling party lost major elections, stressing the importance of factual accuracy during discussions.</p><ul><li>Vaishnaw refuted Zuckerberg's claim about India's elections, highlighting the victory of the BJP in the 2024 general elections.</li><li>Zuckerberg suggested a global trend of incumbent losses due to various factors, including economic policies and pandemic responses.</li><li>Vaishnaw stated that over 640 million voters reaffirmed their trust in PM Narendra Modi's leadership.</li><li>He called for maintaining facts and credibility in discussions, especially from influential figures like Zuckerberg.</li></ul><blockquote>"Let’s uphold facts and credibility," Vaishnaw stressed.</blockquote><p>The exchange emphasizes the impact of misinformation in the digital age, particularly from high-profile individuals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ashwini-vaishnaw-fact-checks-mark-zuckerberg-over-india-polls-remark-misinformation-101736772820372.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ashwini-vaishnaw-fact-checks-mark-zuckerberg-over-india-polls-remark-misinformation-101736772820372.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:57:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On India-China border situation, Army chief rules out ‘buffer zones’ along LAC - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Army Chief Discusses India-China Border Stability and Disengagement</h1><p><strong>Date: January 13, 2025</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/Depsang_and_Demchok_1729852593379_1736771364261.jpg" alt="Both the Indian and Chinese armies pulled back their forward-deployed troops and equipment from the two flashpoints along the contested LAC." title="Both the Indian and Chinese armies pulled back their forward-deployed troops and equipment from the two flashpoints along the contested LAC."><figcaption>Both the Indian and Chinese armies pulled back their forward-deployed troops and equipment from the two flashpoints along the contested LAC.</figcaption><p>Army Chief General Upendra Dwivedi stated that the border situation with China is stable but sensitive, denying the existence of buffer zones along the Line of Actual Control (LAC).</p><ul><li>Both Indian and Chinese armies completed disengagement at Depsang and Demchok in eastern Ladakh last October.</li><li>General Dwivedi emphasized the need for a broader understanding to rebuild trust.</li><li>Verification patrolling has been successfully conducted by both sides.</li></ul><blockquote>"It is stable but sensitive... overall, both sides will remain back and will not go to the common areas because we still feel that if we meet at those places, the violence level may go high." - General Upendra Dwivedi</blockquote><p>This ongoing dialogue and military disengagement are crucial for maintaining peace along the contentious border.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/on-india-china-border-situation-army-chief-rules-out-buffer-zones-along-lac-101736770328328.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/on-india-china-border-situation-army-chief-rules-out-buffer-zones-along-lac-101736770328328.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:36:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['PM Modi’s decisive 3rd term victory': Union minister Ashwini Vaishnaw fact checks Mark Zuckerberg on 202 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi’s decisive 3rd term victory</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Image related to the article"/><figcaption>Image caption can go here.</figcaption><p>Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw fact-checked the statements made by Mark Zuckerberg regarding the upcoming 2024 Lok Sabha elections, pointing out inaccuracies and emphasizing the electoral strength of PM Modi.</p><ul><li>Mark Zuckerberg commented on the political landscape post-election victory.</li><li>Vaishnaw highlighted the misconceptions regarding Modi's electoral influence.</li><li>The article discusses implications for political campaigns and social media influence on voters.</li></ul><blockquote>“Zuckerberg's comments do not reflect the ground reality of Indian politics,” said Vaishnaw.</blockquote><p>This article underscores the importance of accurate information in the political arena, particularly in the context of social media influence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pm-modis-decisive-3rd-term-victory-union-minister-ashwini-vaishnaw-fact-checks-mark-zuckerberg-on-india-elections/articleshow/117206369.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pm-modis-decisive-3rd-term-victory-union-minister-ashwini-vaishnaw-fact-checks-mark-zuckerberg-on-india-elections/articleshow/117206369.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Disappointing to see misinformation from Mark Zuckerberg': Ashwini Vaishnaw hits back - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Disappointing to see misinformation from Mark Zuckerberg': Ashwini Vaishnaw hits back</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/10/20241024092150_Ashwini-Vaishnaw.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431' alt='Ashwini Vaishnaw' title='Ashwini Vaishnaw' width='770' height='431'>
<figcaption>Ashwini Vaishnaw</figcaption>
<p>BJP leader and Railway minister Ashwini Vaishnaw criticized Mark Zuckerberg’s remarks about the Indian Parliamentary elections of 2024, calling them disappointing and factually incorrect.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Vaishnaw responded to Zuckerberg's claim that incumbent governments lost post-COVID, citing India's 2024 election as a success.</li>
  <li>He emphasized that over 640 million voters participated in the elections, reaffirming trust in PM Narendra Modi and the NDA.</li>
  <li>Vaishnaw noted India’s achievements during the pandemic, such as free food and vaccines for a large population.</li>
  <li>He tweeted about the importance of facts and credibility, tagging Meta in his message.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It’s disappointing to see misinformation from Mr. Zuckerberg himself. Let’s uphold facts and credibility.”</blockquote>
<p>This exchange highlights the ongoing debate around misinformation and the importance of accurate reporting in media and politics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/disappointing-to-see-misinformation-from-mark-zuckerberg-ashwini-vaishnaw-hits-back-12909616.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/disappointing-to-see-misinformation-from-mark-zuckerberg-ashwini-vaishnaw-hits-back-12909616.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:28:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025 live: Holy dip performed by 1.6 crore people till 4 pm on first day - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxPTlhWMGwxdWJBTlZyYS1NcHVSWHFfQmtLTUUzUnpVVTFJSTVfaWhfUHNLcmpXS1FQMVRXQ1hvS3d3XzhrQ3pzM3Z1N0M4NUxIeUZtZktkUkhkby1jMFlsZm5Ic21ZT1hjMHpDU0lwZGJodEZlU1JVdkhQNXpyNkJvc2N1MWdDOFc1TEo1ajBLdTlKWFMwSENzZ1d1bjF2NnBQY3ZCUVRzZkpCbjlNZXhXeld0ajl5STljNFVzMFVBUnhObGNwNkxkLXhjYjNlSWZTR1YtS3RUV3kxcVhzSnExcmRRR2V2S0l0WE9ad1RheWRJR0c5ZzAyWHJSTU0wZzlRN1k0WkJTNnJqMTlkOEHSAZMCQVVfeXFMUGhKTjZCUE9Nejc0MEFKVDFYRmFSTEcwSzBVN3ZjMlBhckp5V05hNmNQWXl3TUN4dHRlWGhhVUM0OWhkbGNvNjJuTUFQNE9ZSWJFdUxRMjljcFh2UmtSUkY2MXZOTWVKQWVyVGptZnZhbE84SWpfcjJtMTdSUHR5ZDFJUkFvbDdUNDloQkVCN3ZxbWhUWmpzTExoVF9Wbm1GNVlrT0FILXZqMXUtWTRBMkpudWRyODZyZ3plVkFpZUlWZjVVbWMtWkswMkRURHg1eFV3dlNmYXNocW9TN3ZwVkpKWU1kNDJSWkx4NjFnMkgxcG1QQ0xVNFU2Y20xWnRYcGs5VWhicGE1Nng2ZEdEbzBFOG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxPTlhWMGwxdWJBTlZyYS1NcHVSWHFfQmtLTUUzUnpVVTFJSTVfaWhfUHNLcmpXS1FQMVRXQ1hvS3d3XzhrQ3pzM3Z1N0M4NUxIeUZtZktkUkhkby1jMFlsZm5Ic21ZT1hjMHpDU0lwZGJodEZlU1JVdkhQNXpyNkJvc2N1MWdDOFc1TEo1ajBLdTlKWFMwSENzZ1d1bjF2NnBQY3ZCUVRzZkpCbjlNZXhXeld0ajl5STljNFVzMFVBUnhObGNwNkxkLXhjYjNlSWZTR1YtS3RUV3kxcVhzSnExcmRRR2V2S0l0WE9ad1RheWRJR0c5ZzAyWHJSTU0wZzlRN1k0WkJTNnJqMTlkOEHSAZMCQVVfeXFMUGhKTjZCUE9Nejc0MEFKVDFYRmFSTEcwSzBVN3ZjMlBhckp5V05hNmNQWXl3TUN4dHRlWGhhVUM0OWhkbGNvNjJuTUFQNE9ZSWJFdUxRMjljcFh2UmtSUkY2MXZOTWVKQWVyVGptZnZhbE84SWpfcjJtMTdSUHR5ZDFJUkFvbDdUNDloQkVCN3ZxbWhUWmpzTExoVF9Wbm1GNVlrT0FILXZqMXUtWTRBMkpudWRyODZyZ3plVkFpZUlWZjVVbWMtWkswMkRURHg1eFV3dlNmYXNocW9TN3ZwVkpKWU1kNDJSWkx4NjFnMkgxcG1QQ0xVNFU2Y20xWnRYcGs5VWhicGE1Nng2ZEdEbzBFOG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:17:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AIBE 19 Result Expected To Be Declared Soon, Where And How To Check? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AIBE 19 Result Expected To Be Declared Soon, Where And How To Check?</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 13, 2025, 19:24 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="AIBE 19 Result: The exam was held on December 22, 2024. (Representative/File)"><figcaption>AIBE 19 Result: The exam was held on December 22, 2024. (Representative/File)</figcaption></figure><p>The Bar Council of India (BCI) is expected to release the All India Bar Examination (AIBE) 19 result soon. Candidates who took the exam can check the result on the official website at allindiabarexamination.com, using their registration ID and password.</p><h2>AIBE 19 Result: Key Points</h2><ul><li>The BCI will release the scorecards based on the answer key objections.</li><li>Results can be checked on the official website.</li><li>Correct answers are awarded one mark, with no negative marking.</li><li>Passing marks for general candidates range from 40% to 45%.</li><li>The pass rate for SC, ST, and PWD candidates has been raised to 40% from 35%.</li></ul><h2>AIBE 19 Result: Steps to Check</h2><ol><li>Visit the official BCI website.</li><li>Navigate to the ‘Results’ section.</li><li>Click on the AIBE 19 Result link.</li><li>Enter your login credentials.</li><li>Submit and review your result.</li><li>Download and print your result for future reference.</li></ol><h2>Notable Quote</h2><blockquote>“There is no need to worry about any mismatch between the QP booklet number and OMR answer sheet serial number,” the BCI has informed.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, candidates should stay tuned for the results and be prepared to check them as soon as they are released.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/education-career/aibe-19-result-expected-to-be-declared-soon-where-and-how-to-check-9186925.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/education-career/aibe-19-result-expected-to-be-declared-soon-where-and-how-to-check-9186925.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:49:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian fighting for Russia killed in Ukraine war, deceased hailed from Kerala: Report - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian from Kerala Dies Fighting for Russia in Ukraine War</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2025/01/Firstpost-2025-01-13T165825.935-2025-01-373a213377941c7df0d507f6e0b4beef.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Indian fighting for Russia killed in Ukraine war, deceased hailed from Kerala: Report"><figcaption>A serviceman of pro-Russian militia walks near a military convoy in Ukraine.</figcaption><p>A man from Kerala named Binil TB has died while fighting for the Russian military in Ukraine. This report highlights the recruitment of Indian nationals to the ongoing conflict, often through fraudulent means.</p><ul><li>Binil TB was 32 years old and hailed from Thrissur, Kerala.</li><li>His relative, Jain TK, was injured in the same incident.</li><li>Officials from the Indian embassy in Moscow verbally confirmed his death.</li><li>Binil's family reported that he died in a drone attack.</li><li>Indians recruited for military roles often find themselves on the frontlines despite being promised non-combatant jobs.</li><li>Ajith Kolassery from NORKA ROOTS mentioned there is a lack of formal information on the incident from the Ministry of External Affairs.</li></ul><blockquote>“Mentally and physically, we are exhausted. We have been pleading with local commanders for our release.” - Binil TB</blockquote><p>This incident raises concerns over the plight of foreign fighters in Ukraine and the deceptive recruitment practices used by the Russian military.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/india/indian-fighting-for-russia-killed-in-ukraine-war-deceased-hailed-from-kerala-report-13852418.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/india/indian-fighting-for-russia-killed-in-ukraine-war-deceased-hailed-from-kerala-report-13852418.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:32:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025 live: Holy dip performed by nearly 1 crore people on first day - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxPTlhWMGwxdWJBTlZyYS1NcHVSWHFfQmtLTUUzUnpVVTFJSTVfaWhfUHNLcmpXS1FQMVRXQ1hvS3d3XzhrQ3pzM3Z1N0M4NUxIeUZtZktkUkhkby1jMFlsZm5Ic21ZT1hjMHpDU0lwZGJodEZlU1JVdkhQNXpyNkJvc2N1MWdDOFc1TEo1ajBLdTlKWFMwSENzZ1d1bjF2NnBQY3ZCUVRzZkpCbjlNZXhXeld0ajl5STljNFVzMFVBUnhObGNwNkxkLXhjYjNlSWZTR1YtS3RUV3kxcVhzSnExcmRRR2V2S0l0WE9ad1RheWRJR0c5ZzAyWHJSTU0wZzlRN1k0WkJTNnJqMTlkOEHSAZMCQVVfeXFMUGhKTjZCUE9Nejc0MEFKVDFYRmFSTEcwSzBVN3ZjMlBhckp5V05hNmNQWXl3TUN4dHRlWGhhVUM0OWhkbGNvNjJuTUFQNE9ZSWJFdUxRMjljcFh2UmtSUkY2MXZOTWVKQWVyVGptZnZhbE84SWpfcjJtMTdSUHR5ZDFJUkFvbDdUNDloQkVCN3ZxbWhUWmpzTExoVF9Wbm1GNVlrT0FILXZqMXUtWTRBMkpudWRyODZyZ3plVkFpZUlWZjVVbWMtWkswMkRURHg1eFV3dlNmYXNocW9TN3ZwVkpKWU1kNDJSWkx4NjFnMkgxcG1QQ0xVNFU2Y20xWnRYcGs5VWhicGE1Nng2ZEdEbzBFOG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxPTlhWMGwxdWJBTlZyYS1NcHVSWHFfQmtLTUUzUnpVVTFJSTVfaWhfUHNLcmpXS1FQMVRXQ1hvS3d3XzhrQ3pzM3Z1N0M4NUxIeUZtZktkUkhkby1jMFlsZm5Ic21ZT1hjMHpDU0lwZGJodEZlU1JVdkhQNXpyNkJvc2N1MWdDOFc1TEo1ajBLdTlKWFMwSENzZ1d1bjF2NnBQY3ZCUVRzZkpCbjlNZXhXeld0ajl5STljNFVzMFVBUnhObGNwNkxkLXhjYjNlSWZTR1YtS3RUV3kxcVhzSnExcmRRR2V2S0l0WE9ad1RheWRJR0c5ZzAyWHJSTU0wZzlRN1k0WkJTNnJqMTlkOEHSAZMCQVVfeXFMUGhKTjZCUE9Nejc0MEFKVDFYRmFSTEcwSzBVN3ZjMlBhckp5V05hNmNQWXl3TUN4dHRlWGhhVUM0OWhkbGNvNjJuTUFQNE9ZSWJFdUxRMjljcFh2UmtSUkY2MXZOTWVKQWVyVGptZnZhbE84SWpfcjJtMTdSUHR5ZDFJUkFvbDdUNDloQkVCN3ZxbWhUWmpzTExoVF9Wbm1GNVlrT0FILXZqMXUtWTRBMkpudWRyODZyZ3plVkFpZUlWZjVVbWMtWkswMkRURHg1eFV3dlNmYXNocW9TN3ZwVkpKWU1kNDJSWkx4NjFnMkgxcG1QQ0xVNFU2Y20xWnRYcGs5VWhicGE1Nng2ZEdEbzBFOG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:47:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi, accompanied by Nitin Gadkari, Omar Abdullah, and others, inaugurates Z-Morh tunnel in J&K’s Sonamarg - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Inaugurates Z-Morh Tunnel in Sonamarg, J&K</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/kxj2yt/article69095354.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI01_13_2025_000257B.jpg" alt="In this image released by PMO on January 13, 2025, Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the inauguration of the Z-Morh tunnel, in J&K." />
<figcaption>In this image released by PMO on January 13, 2025, Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the inauguration of the Z-Morh tunnel, in J&K.</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi inaugurated the strategic Z-Morh tunnel in Ganderbal’s Sonamarg area, highlighting its significance in connecting the region and boosting tourism.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Z-Morh tunnel, 6.5 kilometers long, was constructed at a cost of ₹2,700 crore.</li>
  <li>Modi emphasized that the tunnel will make Sonamarg a year-round tourist destination.</li>
  <li>He acknowledged the sacrifices of workers, including those who lost their lives during construction.</li>
  <li>The project connects Kashmir with Ladakh and will ease access during harsh weather.</li>
  <li>Modi remains non-committal on the timeline for restoring Statehood to J&K.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I salute the dedication of workers who braved harsh weather conditions and even risked their lives to complete this project,” said PM Modi.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the inauguration of the Z-Morh tunnel represents a significant step towards improving infrastructure and connectivity in Jammu and Kashmir, contributing to a new era of progress in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/prime-minister-narendra-modi-inaugurates-z-morh-tunnel-in-sonamarg-on-janury-13-2025/article69094897.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/prime-minister-narendra-modi-inaugurates-z-morh-tunnel-in-sonamarg-on-janury-13-2025/article69094897.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Budget 2025: Revised Income Tax Slabs, Higher Standard Deduction, Section 80C Limit Increase – Know Key Exp - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Budget 2025: Revised Income Tax Slabs, Higher Standard Deduction, Section 80C Limit Increase – Know Key Expectations</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Budget 2025: In the upcoming budget, the government is likely to provide income tax relief." title="Budget 2025: In the upcoming budget, the government is likely to provide income tax relief."><figcaption>Budget 2025: In the upcoming budget, the government is likely to provide income tax relief.</figcaption></figure><p>As Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman prepares for the Budget 2025 announcements, significant changes to income tax are anticipated, primarily aimed at benefiting salaried individuals.</p><ul><li><strong>Increase in Standard Deduction:</strong> The standard deduction may increase from ₹50,000 to a maximum cap of ₹1 lakh.</li><li><strong>Revised Income Tax Slabs:</strong> Speculation about changing the 30% tax rate to apply for income above ₹20 lakh for a fairer tax structure.</li><li><strong>Senior Citizens’ Tax Reforms:</strong> Possible increases in exemption limits for taxpayers aged 60 and above.</li><li><strong>Raising Section 80C Deduction Limit:</strong> Experts suggest increasing the deduction limit under Section 80C from ₹1.5 lakh to ₹3.5 lakh.</li><li><strong>Possible Import Duty Hike on Gold:</strong> An increase in import duty on gold may be considered to address trade deficits.</li></ul><blockquote>“Budget 2025 aims to provide significant income tax relief for salaried individuals.”</blockquote><p>Overall, these proposed changes could significantly impact taxpayers, potentially easing their financial burden as the cost of living continues to rise.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/tax/budget-2025-revised-income-tax-slabs-higher-standard-deduction-section-80c-limit-increase-know-key-expectations-9186868.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/tax/budget-2025-revised-income-tax-slabs-higher-standard-deduction-section-80c-limit-increase-know-key-expectations-9186868.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:40:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Dragged Your Feet To Avoid Assembly Session': Delhi HC Raps AAP Govt Over Liquorgate CAG Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxQR3JrWnhNY2l6TkcyQkpyQkhzWnFCb0hnOU1HaFVGY1hCZTl4TWdzcnR2MGtjRjJlX2ZVOThSQnI0alQ3WmtVMzEyX3p0U1Q4dmtoM1l0aTdnblFpUGtfM0U4LXd2UGpDUHZrSjllZlpiMmJxd2RxaURPc05CRGxzc09ZS2thMzlOQ3c4N1ljYXVlckw3cW5Rek8yaVpOQWVVS0pXdjhWd3JlR2tFZndaZ25zSXhrbU1VN0c0Y3NmZnRxVzdoVUdUcDJsd0JveDDSAdQBQVVfeXFMTWxvOEVfZmE3eHk4bm8zd0l5LTF3NzhyMzBCSzRnanUzVjRjRmNNWUFmcHlaS01mUW9GVXhKcFVvVFlqeTV2aWNPaUpkSWZVRVlYcjRody1KQXQxZDAxMXc5OHFEQ0dRXy1pdGVVUDBzYkhZQ2dXRmgweGVyb2lSU2hkM3lRaU93VndSVTYwN0hSbms0ajhOTWFOTWFyUUhJMDJ0X3gwWHRqZlM4NGdTa3NiMmpsQVZHVjNvcmRFNlpmY0MwUlJxUmIxV0pEQm4wMGpxNTE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxQR3JrWnhNY2l6TkcyQkpyQkhzWnFCb0hnOU1HaFVGY1hCZTl4TWdzcnR2MGtjRjJlX2ZVOThSQnI0alQ3WmtVMzEyX3p0U1Q4dmtoM1l0aTdnblFpUGtfM0U4LXd2UGpDUHZrSjllZlpiMmJxd2RxaURPc05CRGxzc09ZS2thMzlOQ3c4N1ljYXVlckw3cW5Rek8yaVpOQWVVS0pXdjhWd3JlR2tFZndaZ25zSXhrbU1VN0c0Y3NmZnRxVzdoVUdUcDJsd0JveDDSAdQBQVVfeXFMTWxvOEVfZmE3eHk4bm8zd0l5LTF3NzhyMzBCSzRnanUzVjRjRmNNWUFmcHlaS01mUW9GVXhKcFVvVFlqeTV2aWNPaUpkSWZVRVlYcjRody1KQXQxZDAxMXc5OHFEQ0dRXy1pdGVVUDBzYkhZQ2dXRmgweGVyb2lSU2hkM3lRaU93VndSVTYwN0hSbms0ajhOTWFOTWFyUUhJMDJ0X3gwWHRqZlM4NGdTa3NiMmpsQVZHVjNvcmRFNlpmY0MwUlJxUmIxV0pEQm4wMGpxNTE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:35:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘When will you add Delhi’s Jats to Centre’s OBC list?': Arvind Kejriwal asks PM Modi, Amit Shah - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Presses for Delhi Jats' Inclusion in OBC List</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/Arvind_Kejriwal_1736764060393_1736764060588.jpg" alt="Former Delhi CM and AAP national convenor Arvind Kejriwal.(HT_PRINT)" title="Former Delhi CM and AAP national convenor Arvind Kejriwal.(HT_PRINT)">
<figcaption>Former Delhi CM and AAP national convenor Arvind Kejriwal.(HT_PRINT)</figcaption>
<p>Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) convenor Arvind Kejriwal has once again called for the inclusion of Delhi's Jat community in the Centre's Other Backward Classes (OBC) list, after meeting with a delegation of Jat leaders who expressed grievances over unfulfilled promises from the government.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kejriwal met with Jat leaders and highlighted their voting power in Delhi.</li>
  <li>He emphasized that while Jats in Rajasthan benefit from OBC status, Delhi's Jats do not receive similar privileges.</li>
  <li>Kejriwal questioned Prime Minister Modi and Home Minister Shah regarding the delay in including Delhi's Jats in the OBC list.</li>
  <li>The BJP criticized Kejriwal's call as an election gimmick and claimed he had not previously raised the issue.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The top two leaders of the country -- Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Union Home Minister Amit Shah -- had promised the Jat community of Delhi that they will be given OBC reservation at the central level but the promise remains unfulfilled.” - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote>
<p>This development highlights ongoing tensions between the AAP and the BJP regarding promises made to the Jat community and the political implications as elections approach.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/when-will-you-add-delhi-s-jats-to-centre-s-obc-list-arvind-kejriwal-asks-pm-modi-amit-shah-101736763103287.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/when-will-you-add-delhi-s-jats-to-centre-s-obc-list-arvind-kejriwal-asks-pm-modi-amit-shah-101736763103287.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:33:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India summons top Bangladesh diplomat day after Dhaka summoned Indian envoy: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India summons top Bangladesh diplomat day after Dhaka summoned Indian envoy</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/External_affairs_ministry_1736761710525_1736761710716.jpg" alt="The ministry of external affairs on Monday summoned Bangladesh's deputy high commissioner Nural Islam(Sanchit Khanna/HT File Photo)" title="The ministry of external affairs on Monday summoned Bangladesh's deputy high commissioner Nural Islam(Sanchit Khanna/HT File Photo)">
<figcaption>The ministry of external affairs on Monday summoned Bangladesh's deputy high commissioner Nural Islam(Sanchit Khanna/HT File Photo)</figcaption>
<p>India summoned Bangladesh's deputy high commissioner Nural Islam in response to escalating diplomatic tensions following Bangladesh's foreign ministry calling in India's high commissioner.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Bangladeshi foreign ministry expressed concerns over actions taken by India's Border Security Force along the border.</li>
<li>Indian high commissioner Pranay Verma emphasized India's commitment to maintaining a crime-free border and cooperation between BSF and Bangladesh's border forces.</li>
<li>Tensions have increased since Bangladesh's Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina fled to India amid political unrest, coinciding with incidents of violence against minority Hindus in Bangladesh.</li>
<li>Reports indicate over 2,000 incidents of communal violence have occurred since the political upheaval.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>“Our two border guard forces, BSF and BGB have been in communication and understanding will be implemented and co-operative approach to combating crimes.” - Pranay Verma</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the current diplomatic exchanges highlight the fragile relationship between India and Bangladesh amidst political unrest and rising tensions along the border.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-summons-top-bangladesh-diplomat-day-after-dhaka-summoned-indian-envoy-report-101736761228867.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-summons-top-bangladesh-diplomat-day-after-dhaka-summoned-indian-envoy-report-101736761228867.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 09:44:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India summons top Bangladesh diplomat amid border fencing row - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India summons top Bangladesh diplomat amid border fencing row</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>India has summoned the top diplomat from Bangladesh to discuss ongoing tensions regarding border fencing issues.</p><ul><li>The meeting aims to address concerns over illegal crossings and security challenges.</li><li>Both nations are working to strengthen their border management strategies.</li><li>Recent events have raised questions about cooperation between India and Bangladesh.</li></ul><blockquote>"We must find a collaborative approach to resolve these border issues effectively." - Indian Diplomat</blockquote><p>This diplomatic engagement highlights the ongoing importance of cooperation and communication in managing border disputes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-summons-top-bangladesh-diplomat-amid-border-fencing-row/articleshow/117199714.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-summons-top-bangladesh-diplomat-amid-border-fencing-row/articleshow/117199714.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 09:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fire breaks out at laddu distribution counter at Tirupati temple - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fire Breaks Out at Laddu Distribution Counter at Tirupati Temple</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <em>Unknown</em> | <strong>Source:</strong> <em>Unknown</em></p><p>On a busy day at the Tirupati temple, a fire incident has disrupted the laddu distribution counter, causing chaos among the devotees.</p><ul><li>The fire was reported around noon, resulting in immediate evacuation of the area.</li><li>No injuries have been reported, with prompt action taken by the temple's fire safety team.</li><li>The cause of the fire is currently under investigation.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are thankful that no temple visitors were harmed during this incident,” said a temple representative.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the importance of safety measures in crowded areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/amaravati/fire-breaks-out-at-laddu-distribution-counter-at-tirupati-temple/articleshow/117199677.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/amaravati/fire-breaks-out-at-laddu-distribution-counter-at-tirupati-temple/articleshow/117199677.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Election 2025: Full list of BJP candidates and their Assembly constituencies - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Election 2025: Full list of BJP candidates and their Assembly constituencies</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250113092447_BJP-flag.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431' alt='The BJP has announced its candidates for 59 constituencies for the Delhi elections. (File Photo: PTI)' width='770' height='431'><figcaption>The BJP has announced its candidates for 59 constituencies for the Delhi elections. (File Photo: PTI)</figcaption><p>The Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) has declared the names of 59 candidates for the upcoming Delhi elections, aiming to regain power after a long absence.</p><ul><li>The BJP has released three lists of candidates for the election.</li><li>The party is targeting key constituencies and keeping caste dynamics in mind.</li><li>This election is crucial for the BJP, which has faced consecutive defeats in past Delhi elections.</li></ul><blockquote>“With Prime Minister Narendra Modi as its mascot, the BJP hopes to end its power drought of almost three decades.”</blockquote><p>This election is seen as a significant opportunity for the BJP to regain influence in Delhi after the challenges faced in recent years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/delhi-election-2025-full-list-of-bjp-candidates-and-their-assembly-constituencies-12909305.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/delhi-election-2025-full-list-of-bjp-candidates-and-their-assembly-constituencies-12909305.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 09:25:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India summons top Bangladeshi diplomat as border row escalates - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Summons Bangladeshi Diplomat as Border Row Escalates</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> New Delhi</p><p>India summoned the top Bangladeshi diplomat in response to escalating tensions at the India-Bangladesh border related to fencing issues.</p><ul><li>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) is resisting India's ongoing border fencing efforts.</li><li>Indian Border Security Force (BSF) and BGD have held discussions but BSF is pushing to complete the fencing.</li><li>Approximately 3,180 km of the 4,096.7 km border has been fenced so far.</li><li>Recent high-level talks between Indian High Commissioner and Bangladesh Foreign Secretary addressed border issues.</li><li>Concerns over minority treatment in Bangladesh have also contributed to strained relations.</li><li>Reports indicate a significant rise in politically motivated attacks against minorities.</li></ul><blockquote>“Construction of barbed wire fences without proper authorisation undermines the spirit of cooperation and friendly relations between the two neighbouring countries.”</blockquote><p>The ongoing border issues and the treatment of minorities in Bangladesh continue to strain the diplomatic relations between India and Bangladesh.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/india-news/india-summons-top-bangladeshi-diplomat-as-border-row-escalates-8617965</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/india-news/india-summons-top-bangladeshi-diplomat-as-border-row-escalates-8617965</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 09:09:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Isro aborted SpaDeX docking after satellites triggered safe mode in space - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxOVFo5SEVyWFkwbVRGSHVsN3hGc1dkY2tqQnZnQ3J2ZElYSWhENTl1NUVfQnNkRDROWHphZHRKMjQteXdNRUhweThiNUtyUDdZWWRPRDQ0WUlSejF5d1JGVThVcURUMFdRTm1wbDQwRUtUbnQzbjgxcVB5TGRVOUdVM2pNbHVocFA3M2x0ZE9Gc2Y5NWhienVBSzdySXZ5S2pJSkNvZGxVdlJKY0dBaDZsS2dqV1VVRUlOMlg2SVphTHF0Qm9UOXozdkw0bHA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxOVFo5SEVyWFkwbVRGSHVsN3hGc1dkY2tqQnZnQ3J2ZElYSWhENTl1NUVfQnNkRDROWHphZHRKMjQteXdNRUhweThiNUtyUDdZWWRPRDQ0WUlSejF5d1JGVThVcURUMFdRTm1wbDQwRUtUbnQzbjgxcVB5TGRVOUdVM2pNbHVocFA3M2x0ZE9Gc2Y5NWhienVBSzdySXZ5S2pJSkNvZGxVdlJKY0dBaDZsS2dqV1VVRUlOMlg2SVphTHF0Qm9UOXozdkw0bHA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:51:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swami Kailashanand Giri on Steve Jobs’s wife not being allowed to touch Kashi Vishwanath shivling - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxQQTNFbERXbzdiLVI3OXNFam5tNFM5YjliOTVBb1NkLVFqTENKWUlFanRlYU1xTXhfdXJmR3k0VHY2RHNhR3hlUzF6aWExcHMxZl9wUnRDdHBfTE9qSnpKOTRVQVc5ekdqNzBIbVVsTTliYzhQV0hKaVdsS091aG42aElXcVhjdmNlZU9hU2dEdm1tSU5SakwzUVdxTTlyVm4tNjBGZWtLLXRRLXBWSHd4cUpMOWtRVkt4ZnRRMHZGNjg2Z3QydzFxYWs1Wll1SE1mR0R1RWs2WXNOUzBCRGfSAeIBQVVfeXFMTzJ3Yi13YU9ObjM0Y09RM0Z4b2lMemhVd1EzTFRnd1RxOTlxMXFCWjJPb1dQbnFyMERweHFLZncyRElxTUdJYktxaEdicnhvc0NXZkN4MlEzbnlQUHZmN1J6X3RhbllzcEFkbHlmaU9CcjhFYnUtcXMtVnd4SmxqTTl5OVBPdUc3eXhjX2laY3c3S09WMTRVR2xsV0ZaUkl3WWZkLW9nMFJzd1Iwc3BUVDNkZ3ZCS3AySlNyYU5keEE0Q09SdkNPNmR6LXItblU3eHFzQm04SmZHeGRaM0h0ZWhVUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxQQTNFbERXbzdiLVI3OXNFam5tNFM5YjliOTVBb1NkLVFqTENKWUlFanRlYU1xTXhfdXJmR3k0VHY2RHNhR3hlUzF6aWExcHMxZl9wUnRDdHBfTE9qSnpKOTRVQVc5ekdqNzBIbVVsTTliYzhQV0hKaVdsS091aG42aElXcVhjdmNlZU9hU2dEdm1tSU5SakwzUVdxTTlyVm4tNjBGZWtLLXRRLXBWSHd4cUpMOWtRVkt4ZnRRMHZGNjg2Z3QydzFxYWs1Wll1SE1mR0R1RWs2WXNOUzBCRGfSAeIBQVVfeXFMTzJ3Yi13YU9ObjM0Y09RM0Z4b2lMemhVd1EzTFRnd1RxOTlxMXFCWjJPb1dQbnFyMERweHFLZncyRElxTUdJYktxaEdicnhvc0NXZkN4MlEzbnlQUHZmN1J6X3RhbllzcEFkbHlmaU9CcjhFYnUtcXMtVnd4SmxqTTl5OVBPdUc3eXhjX2laY3c3S09WMTRVR2xsV0ZaUkl3WWZkLW9nMFJzd1Iwc3BUVDNkZ3ZCS3AySlNyYU5keEE0Q09SdkNPNmR6LXItblU3eHFzQm04SmZHeGRaM0h0ZWhVUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:50:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Violence level being orchestrated by epicentre of terror that is Pakistan': Army chief on J&K situation - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Violence level being orchestrated by epicentre of terror that is Pakistan: Army chief on J&K situation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Provided, <strong>Source:</strong> Not Provided</p><p>The Indian Army Chief has raised concerns over the escalating violence in Jammu and Kashmir, attributing it to Pakistan's influence as a major center of terrorism.</p><ul><li>The Army Chief describes Pakistan as the 'epicentre of terror.'</li><li>He emphasizes the need for regional stability and security.</li><li>The statement reflects ongoing tensions in Jammu and Kashmir amid rising violence.</li></ul><blockquote>"The level of violence being orchestrated implies external influences."</blockquote><p>This statement by the Army Chief underscores the critical issues of cross-border terrorism and the need for security measures in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/60-of-terrorists-eliminated-last-year-80-of-those-remaining-in-jk-are-of-pakistani-origin-army-chief-upendra-dwivedi/articleshow/117195640.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/60-of-terrorists-eliminated-last-year-80-of-those-remaining-in-jk-are-of-pakistani-origin-army-chief-upendra-dwivedi/articleshow/117195640.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025 live: Nearly 60 lakh take holy dip on day 1; ‘Amrit Snan’ scheduled for tomorrow - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh 2025 Live: Nearly 60 Lakh Take Holy Dip on Day 1; ‘Amrit Snan’ Scheduled for Tomorrow</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/WhatsApp_Image_2025-01-13_at_10.55.14_1736747084339_1736747092564.jpeg" alt="Devotees take a holy dip in Sangam" title="Devotees took a holy dip in the Sangam during the Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, on Monday. To mark the beginning of the Maha Kumbh on Paush Purnima, the Uttar Pradesh Police established a floating chowki at Triveni Sangam for enhanced security and assistance.">
<figcaption>Devotees took a holy dip in the Sangam during the Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, on Monday. To mark the beginning of the Maha Kumbh on Paush Purnima, the Uttar Pradesh Police established a floating chowki at Triveni Sangam for enhanced security and assistance.</figcaption>
<p>The 45-day Mahakumbh Mela 2025 commenced with nearly 60 lakh devotees participating in the holy dip at Triveni Sangam by 9:30 AM on day 1, with an expected attendance of over 40 crore devotees throughout the event.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The first major Shahi Snan, or Amrit Snan, will take place on January 14, 2025, coinciding with Makar Sankranti.</li>
  <li>Significant measures are implemented for security, health, and traffic management.</li>
  <li>Devotees from around the world gathered for this auspicious occasion, sharing their emotions and experiences.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Maha Kumbh 2025 has begun today, with about 60 lakh people taking a holy dip. This year, it is a blend of faith and modernity.” - UP DGP Prashant Kumar</blockquote>
<p>As the festival proceeds, comprehensive arrangements are in place to ensure the safety and well-being of all attendees, highlighting the cultural significance of the Mahakumbh.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-sangam-shahi-snan-paush-purnima-holy-dip-jan-13-2025-101736725472437.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-sangam-shahi-snan-paush-purnima-holy-dip-jan-13-2025-101736725472437.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:47:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Live News Updates: Modi inaugurates the Z-Morh tunnel on the Srinagar-Leh National Highway in Jam... - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAJBVV95cUxNYjBrc20tS2Z1bTFBNVJ1RlJXNGJOcVU2T0FpVmw5VUhwTVVvcDJTVmZsOEROcFZ4T20yVTR4V3lUWnZzZ2VIZERDM19US0RMTnZpTmNVVklkY0pFYURabV8wMG1TaXM2UlpaQ0Q4dUN3ZEtWdmp2THVnOEFfbFhJSTF3VE5TVG9kYmFIZ2NXdDJ4OEd0QmR1NzNmVDZuQ3pFZ1VDcm5FUmpzQVJWeVB6ZWlPdVpYRU1sdHVPTVVQNlRqVG9yU3lFUk9xRmEzVkVZWkY3M1FjeHE2OU0wTUhWNF9aZ215V1F3LS1nZTBiUlF0TFJHeThVcVRmRndQM2ZEejNsQWNpa3QtZHlMZUFkb9IBlgJBVV95cUxQSWs1OHJWYzNXTHJYMlF6NkR3RmhUN1VEekIyQkRCM241RmtMa1ZhZ2ppbjQ0VmEtWGUxSi04MmUzZFltbVdGa2VySnF6ZXRfZk85Yk12UXRzR2E1bWtnNS04SVBEWlFCbVN5YThxQ0RGUENLajBBOGdDUXI0OEZ4cmRCb3l5TGIwNFN0NmZGbkMyZTl2aDRQNlYxaUtpTUVLMFRhcnd3MHZubEtKeHptM1V0aS0wU1ZKUTFBMHdMelp1Zk81Zl9HSDV2c2JqTU1KTTA2TjhNSFdETVNkbzZlNk9ETUpLYVIyOXJNRll3MkZGNGRRVWN3alN5b0dFZHBkSjA1TlJ3b25PRHNfN2RsNEt3Rl9NQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAJBVV95cUxNYjBrc20tS2Z1bTFBNVJ1RlJXNGJOcVU2T0FpVmw5VUhwTVVvcDJTVmZsOEROcFZ4T20yVTR4V3lUWnZzZ2VIZERDM19US0RMTnZpTmNVVklkY0pFYURabV8wMG1TaXM2UlpaQ0Q4dUN3ZEtWdmp2THVnOEFfbFhJSTF3VE5TVG9kYmFIZ2NXdDJ4OEd0QmR1NzNmVDZuQ3pFZ1VDcm5FUmpzQVJWeVB6ZWlPdVpYRU1sdHVPTVVQNlRqVG9yU3lFUk9xRmEzVkVZWkY3M1FjeHE2OU0wTUhWNF9aZ215V1F3LS1nZTBiUlF0TFJHeThVcVRmRndQM2ZEejNsQWNpa3QtZHlMZUFkb9IBlgJBVV95cUxQSWs1OHJWYzNXTHJYMlF6NkR3RmhUN1VEekIyQkRCM241RmtMa1ZhZ2ppbjQ0VmEtWGUxSi04MmUzZFltbVdGa2VySnF6ZXRfZk85Yk12UXRzR2E1bWtnNS04SVBEWlFCbVN5YThxQ0RGUENLajBBOGdDUXI0OEZ4cmRCb3l5TGIwNFN0NmZGbkMyZTl2aDRQNlYxaUtpTUVLMFRhcnd3MHZubEtKeHptM1V0aS0wU1ZKUTFBMHdMelp1Zk81Zl9HSDV2c2JqTU1KTTA2TjhNSFdETVNkbzZlNk9ETUpLYVIyOXJNRll3MkZGNGRRVWN3alN5b0dFZHBkSjA1TlJ3b25PRHNfN2RsNEt3Rl9NQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:41:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Raises doubts about your bona fides’: Delhi High Court raps AAP government over CAG report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi High Court Criticizes AAP Government for Delaying CAG Report Discussion</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/PTI11-26-2024-000245B-0_1732622965039_1736752611352.jpg" alt="Delhi High Court reprimands AAP government for mishandling CAG report. (PTI FILE PHOTO)" title="Delhi High Court reprimands AAP government for mishandling CAG report. (PTI FILE PHOTO)">
<figcaption>Delhi High Court reprimands AAP government for mishandling CAG report. (PTI FILE PHOTO)</figcaption>
<p>The Delhi High Court has reprimanded the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) government for mishandling a report from the Comptroller and Auditor General (CAG), accusing it of delaying necessary discussions.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The court stated that the AAP government “dragged its feet” to prevent an assembly session from taking place.</li>
    <li>Justice Sachin Datta highlighted that reports should have been promptly forwarded to the Speaker for discussion.</li>
    <li>The Delhi government argued that upcoming elections hindered the holding of assembly sessions.</li>
    <li>Seven BJP MLAs petitioned to table 14 CAG reports in the assembly, claiming their right to engage with the documents.</li>
    <li>The court declined to immediately order a special assembly session, emphasizing the need for both parties to be heard first.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The way you have dragged your feet raises doubts about your bona fides.” – Justice Sachin Datta</blockquote>
<p>This judicial rebuke highlights concerns about government accountability and the implications for democratic processes leading up to elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/raises-doubts-about-your-bona-fides-delhi-high-court-raps-aap-government-over-cag-report-101736750967716.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/raises-doubts-about-your-bona-fides-delhi-high-court-raps-aap-government-over-cag-report-101736750967716.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:26:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kerala teen athlete ‘subjected to multiple gangrapes, blackmail’; 14 more arrested, 13 FIRs filed - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/kerala-teen-athlete-subjected-to-multiple-gangrapes-blackmail-14-more-arrested-13-firs-filed-9775556/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/kerala-teen-athlete-subjected-to-multiple-gangrapes-blackmail-14-more-arrested-13-firs-filed-9775556/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kerala teen athlete ‘subjected to multiple gangrapes, blackmail’; 14 more arrested, 13 FIRs filed - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/kerala-teen-athlete-subjected-to-multiple-gangrapes-blackmail-14-more-arrested-13-firs-filed-9775556/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/kerala-teen-athlete-subjected-to-multiple-gangrapes-blackmail-14-more-arrested-13-firs-filed-9775556/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why was Steve Jobs's wife not allowed to touch Shivling in Kashi? Seer answers - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why was Steve Jobs's wife not allowed to touch Shivling in Kashi? Seer answers</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/ANI-20250112320-0_1736749881070_1736749891544.jpg" alt="Laurene Powell Jobs, wife of the late Apple co-founder Steve Jobs reaches Niranjani Akhara at Mahakumbh, in Prayagraj on Sunday. (ANI)" title="Laurene Powell Jobs, wife of the late Apple co-founder Steve Jobs reaches Niranjani Akhara at Mahakumbh, in Prayagraj on Sunday. (ANI)"><figcaption>Laurene Powell Jobs, wife of the late Apple co-founder Steve Jobs reaches Niranjani Akhara at Mahakumbh, in Prayagraj on Sunday. (ANI)</figcaption><p>Laurene Powell Jobs, wife of the late Apple co-founder Steve Jobs, visited the Kashi Vishwanath Temple but was not permitted to touch the Shivling due to temple traditions. Spiritual leader Swami Kailashanand Giri explained the strict protocols regarding non-Hindus touching the Shivling, highlighting her respect for Indian spirituality.</p><ul><li>Laurene Powell Jobs visited the Kashi Vishwanath Temple in Varanasi.</li><li>She was not allowed to touch the Shivling as per temple protocols.</li><li>Swami Kailashanand Giri emphasized that he must uphold traditions.</li><li>Laurene participated in rituals, received prasad and a garland.</li><li>The Mahakumbh festival is expected to attract over 40 crore devotees.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is a tradition that anyone other than a Hindu cannot touch Kashi Vishwanath.” - Swami Kailashanand Giri Maharaj</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Laurene Powell Jobs's visit to the Kashi Vishwanath Temple reflects her reverence for Indian culture while adhering to local traditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/why-was-steve-jobs-wife-not-allowed-to-touch-shivling-in-kashi-laurene-powell-jobs-101736748328520.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/why-was-steve-jobs-wife-not-allowed-to-touch-shivling-in-kashi-laurene-powell-jobs-101736748328520.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:23:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi inaugurates Z-Morh tunnel in J&K’s Sonamarg - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi inaugurates Z-Morh tunnel in J&K’s Sonamarg</h1><p><strong>Published on: January 13, 2025</strong> by The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/d2xah4/article69094931.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI01_13_2025_000133A.jpg" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the inauguration of the Z-Morh tunnel, in Jammu and Kashmir. on January 13, 2025. Photo: YouTube/NarendraModi via PTI"><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the inauguration of the Z-Morh tunnel, in Jammu and Kashmir. on January 13, 2025. Photo: YouTube/NarendraModi via PTI</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi inaugurated the Z-Morh tunnel in Kashmir’s Ganderbal district, improving all-weather connectivity to the tourist destination of Sonmarg.</p><ul><li>Inauguration took place on January 13, 2025, accompanied by key officials and ministers.</li><li>The tunnel is a strategic project that enhances road connectivity between Srinagar and Sonmarg.</li><li>Constructed at an altitude of over 8,650 feet, it bypasses landslide-prone areas.</li><li>The two-lane tunnel was built at a cost of over ₹2,700 crores.</li></ul><blockquote>“The tunnel provides all-weather road access to Sonmarg, which is vital for locals and tourists alike.”</blockquote><p>The Z-Morh tunnel represents a significant engineering achievement, connecting critical geographical points in Jammu and Kashmir.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/prime-minister-narendra-modi-inaugurates-z-morh-tunnel-in-sonamarg-on-janury-13-2025/article69094897.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/prime-minister-narendra-modi-inaugurates-z-morh-tunnel-in-sonamarg-on-janury-13-2025/article69094897.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>