<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:17:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:17:42 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Hum Ho Na Ho...': CEC Rajiv Kumar's 'Shayaris' Go Viral Amid Delhi Election Dates Announcement | Video - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Hum Ho Na Ho...': CEC Rajiv Kumar's 'Shayaris' Go Viral Amid Delhi Election Dates Announcement | Video</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='Delhi elections 2025: Rajiv Kumar recited at least three poetries in Urdu before announcing poll dates.' /><figcaption>Delhi elections 2025: Rajiv Kumar recited at least three poetries in Urdu before announcing poll dates.</figcaption><p>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) Rajiv Kumar made headlines with his unique approach of using 'shayari' (poetry) during the announcement of the 2025 Delhi election dates. This method not only entertained but also highlighted key issues around the electoral process.</p><ul><li>CEC Rajiv Kumar's media interaction is marked by his use of Urdu poetry.</li><li>He recited three poetries while addressing concerns about EVMs and electoral integrity.</li><li>His quotes addressed the importance of questioning and accountability in the electoral process.</li><li>Kumar's poetic style has previously gone viral, capturing public interest during significant announcements.</li></ul><blockquote>All the concerns raised by Congress party have been answered by CEC Rajiv Kumar through his shayaris. 3 shayari for all the questions and accountability done…! — Venisha G Kiba (@KibaVenisha) January 7, 2025</blockquote><p>The event showcases how CEC Rajiv Kumar blends tradition with modern engagement, making the electoral process more relatable and approachable.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/viral-shayaris-of-cec-rajiv-kumar-delhi-elections-2025-9180693.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/viral-shayaris-of-cec-rajiv-kumar-delhi-elections-2025-9180693.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 16:03:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chief Minister condoles sudden demise of son of Tahir Ajaz - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chief Minister Condoles Sudden Demise of Son of Tahir Ajaz</h1><p><strong>Date: January 07, 2023 | Source: New Delhi</strong></p><p>Chief Minister Omar Abdullah has expressed profound grief over the sudden demise of Imad Tahir, a student of Class 10 and son of Tahir Ajaz, Additional Secretary in the Chief Minister’s Secretariat. The Chief Minister extended his heartfelt sympathy to the bereaved family during this tragic time.</p><ul><li>The Chief Minister expressed deep sorrow over the loss.</li><li>Imad Tahir passed away at his residence in Srinagar.</li><li>Omar Abdullah assured support and solidarity to the grieving family.</li><li>All staff members of the Chief Minister's Secretariat also extended their condolences.</li></ul><blockquote>“The news of Imad’s untimely passing has left me at a loss for words. I can only pray that the family finds the strength and forbearance to cope with this devastating tragedy.” – Chief Minister Omar Abdullah</blockquote><p>This tragic event has been felt deeply within the community, as the Chief Minister and his staff convey their condolences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/latest-news/chief-minister-condoles-sudden-demise-of-son-of-tahir-ajaz/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/latest-news/chief-minister-condoles-sudden-demise-of-son-of-tahir-ajaz/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:48:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Her family supported Parliament attack convict Afzal Guru': BJP's fresh attack on Delhi CM Atishi - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Intensifies Criticism of Delhi CM Atishi Over Family Ties to Afzal Guru</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/atishi_afzal_guru_1736258576802_1736258577161.jpg" alt="Delhi Chief Minister Atishi addresses a press conference after the announcement of Delhi Assembly Election dates, in New Delhi on Tuesday. (ANI)" title="Delhi Chief Minister Atishi addresses a press conference after the announcement of Delhi Assembly Election dates, in New Delhi on Tuesday. (ANI)">
<figcaption>Delhi Chief Minister Atishi addresses a press conference after the announcement of Delhi Assembly Election dates, in New Delhi on Tuesday. (ANI)</figcaption>
<p>The Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) has mounted a fresh attack on Delhi Chief Minister Atishi, alleging that her family has supported Afzal Guru, who was convicted in a Parliament attack. This comes amid ongoing tensions between the BJP and the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP).</p>
<ul>
  <li>BJP leader Baijayant Jay Panda asserts that Atishi's family supported Afzal Guru.</li>
  <li>Previous controversies involving BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri have escalated tensions between the parties.</li>
  <li>Atishi claims the BJP has wrongfully cancelled her official residence allotment.</li>
  <li>The BJP criticizes Atishi for not distancing herself from her family’s past association with Afzal Guru.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Her family staunchly supported Parliament attack convict Afzal Guru.” - Baijayant Jay Panda, BJP Leader</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing political battle highlights the strained relations between the BJP and AAP as they approach the upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/her-family-supported-parliament-attack-convict-afzal-guru-bjps-fresh-attack-on-delhi-cm-atishi-101736256482585.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/her-family-supported-parliament-attack-convict-afzal-guru-bjps-fresh-attack-on-delhi-cm-atishi-101736256482585.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BREAKING| SC Collegium Recommends Elevation Of Patna HC CJ Vinod Chandran As Supreme Court Judge - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Collegium Recommends Justice K Vinod Chandran for Elevation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>In a significant development, the Supreme Court Collegium has recommended the elevation of Justice K Vinod Chandran, currently the Chief Justice of the Patna High Court, to the Supreme Court.</p><ul><li>Justice K Vinod Chandran was appointed as a High Court Judge on 8th November 2011.</li><li>He became the Chief Justice of the Patna High Court on 29th March 2023.</li><li>The Collegium's recommendation acknowledges the lack of representation from the High Court of Kerala in the Supreme Court.</li><li>Justice Chandran has been noted for his extensive experience in various legal fields during his tenure.</li></ul><blockquote>“Justice Vinod Chandran has acquired significant experience in diverse fields of law.”</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/sc-collegium-recommends-elevation-of-patna-hc-cj-vinod-chandran-to-supreme-court-280248</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/sc-collegium-recommends-elevation-of-patna-hc-cj-vinod-chandran-to-supreme-court-280248</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:59:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disquiet within BJP over Delhi poll ticket to Ramesh Bidhuri, talks held on ‘shifting, if not cancelling’ candidature - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Disquiet within BJP over Delhi poll ticket to Ramesh Bidhuri, talks held on ‘shifting, if not cancelling’ candidature</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>Ramesh Bidhuri, a BJP leader, faces backlash following derogatory remarks about rivals while campaigning for the Delhi Assembly elections, raising questions about his candidacy.</p><ul><li>Bidhuri made controversial comments about Delhi Chief Minister Atishi during a recent campaign.</li><li>His remarks have led to internal party discussions regarding the potential replacement of his candidacy.</li><li>Despite backlash, Bidhuri has a notable political history, being a two-time Lok Sabha MP and three-time MLA.</li></ul><blockquote>“My intention was not to insult anyone. But still, if anyone has been hurt then I express my regret.” - Ramesh Bidhuri</blockquote><p>The BJP is considering various options for a potential candidate replacement, amidst a growing narrative against Bidhuri's candidacy from the opposition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/disquiet-bjp-delhi-poll-ticket-ramesh-bidhuri-cancelling-candidature-9765532/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/disquiet-bjp-delhi-poll-ticket-ramesh-bidhuri-cancelling-candidature-9765532/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:58:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Memorial to be set up for Pranab Mukherjee at Rashtriya Smriti, daughter Sharmistha thanks PM Modi - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Centre earmarks memorial for Pranab Mukherjee</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/e55ind/article69073738.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20250107203L.jpg" alt="former President Pranab Mukherjee’s daughter Sharmistha Mukherjee meets Prime Minister Narendra Modi, in New Delhi on January 7, 2025. Photo: X/@Sharmistha_GK via ANI" title="former President Pranab Mukherjee’s daughter Sharmistha Mukherjee meets Prime Minister Narendra Modi, in New Delhi on January 7, 2025. Photo: X/@Sharmistha_GK via ANI"><figcaption>former President Pranab Mukherjee’s daughter Sharmistha Mukherjee meets Prime Minister Narendra Modi, in New Delhi on January 7, 2025. Photo: X/@Sharmistha_GK via ANI</figcaption><p>The Centre has designated a site at the Rashtriya Smriti complex for a memorial dedicated to the late President Pranab Mukherjee.</p><ul><li>The designation was confirmed by the Union Ministry of Housing and Urban Development in a letter to Mukherjee's daughter, Sharmishtha Mukherjee.</li><li>The memorial comes amid discussions regarding a memorial for former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh following his passing.</li><li>Sharmishtha Mukherjee expressed her gratitude to Prime Minister Narendra Modi for the decision, emphasizing that they did not request the memorial.</li><li>Pranab Mukherjee passed away on August 31, 2020, and was awarded the Bharat Ratna in 2019.</li></ul><blockquote>“Immensely touched by this unexpected but truly gracious gesture by PM,” said Sharmishtha Mukherjee.</blockquote><p>This memorial not only honors Mukherjee's legacy but also highlights ongoing discussions about memorials for prominent leaders in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/memorial-to-be-set-up-for-pranab-mukherjee-at-rashtriya-smriti-daughter-sharmistha-thanks-pm-modi/article69073062.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/memorial-to-be-set-up-for-pranab-mukherjee-at-rashtriya-smriti-daughter-sharmistha-thanks-pm-modi/article69073062.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru techie suicide: Denying grandson's custody, SC says deceased's mother 'stranger to child' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/bengaluru-techie-suicide-denying-grandsons-custody-sc-says-deceaseds-mother-stranger-to-child-101736256404060.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/bengaluru-techie-suicide-denying-grandsons-custody-sc-says-deceaseds-mother-stranger-to-child-101736256404060.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:20:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Centre earmarks site for memorial of Pranab Mukherjee, ex-President's daughter thanks PM Modi - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Memorial Site Approved for Pranab Mukherjee, Daughter Thanks PM Modi</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Pranab_Mukherjee_1736253977750_1736253978164.jpg" alt="Former President Pranab Mukherjee.(Reuters file photo)"><figcaption>Former President Pranab Mukherjee.(Reuters file photo)</figcaption></figure><p>The Narendra Modi government has allocated a site at the 'Rashtriya Smriti' complex for a memorial for former President Pranab Mukherjee. His daughter, Sharmistha Mukherjee, expressed gratitude towards PM Modi for this decision.</p><ul><li>The memorial will be located at the Rajghat precinct, a significant area in Delhi.</li><li>Pranab Mukherjee served as the President of India from 2012 to 2017 and was awarded the Bharat Ratna.</li><li>Sharmistha Mukherjee publicly thanked PM Modi, highlighting that the memorial was unexpected and appreciated.</li><li>She criticized the Congress party for its response to her father's passing in comparison to their treatment of other leaders.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s more cherished considering that we didn’t ask for it. Immensely touched by this unexpected but truly gracious gesture by PM,” Sharmistha Mukherjee said.</blockquote><p>This memorial symbolizes the respect and honor for Pranab Mukherjee’s contributions to the nation, as expressed through the government’s decision and the heartfelt response from his family.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/centre-approves-memorial-for-pranab-mukherjee-ex-presidents-daughter-thanks-pm-modi-101736253981414.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/centre-approves-memorial-for-pranab-mukherjee-ex-presidents-daughter-thanks-pm-modi-101736253981414.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:12:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Lying, doesn’t want to offend Arvind Kejriwal': BJP shares PWD letter after Atishi's claim over being th - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Responds to Atishi's Claims About Delhi CM House Incident</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert date here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert source here]</p><p>In a recent development, the BJP has shared a Public Works Department (PWD) letter following Atishi's allegations of being ejected from the Delhi Chief Minister's residence, claiming misinformation.</p><ul><li>The BJP released a letter purportedly from the PWD.</li><li>Atishi alleged that she was removed from the CM house.</li><li>The incident has intensified political tensions in Delhi.</li><li>The BJP accuses Atishi of spreading falsehoods.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are presenting the official document to clarify the situation,” said a BJP spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This incident underlines the ongoing political rivalry and the challenges of accountability faced by public officials.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/lying-doesnt-want-to-offend-arvind-kejriwal-bjp-shares-pwd-letter-after-atishis-claim-over-being-thrown-out-of-delhi-cm-house/articleshow/117024427.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/lying-doesnt-want-to-offend-arvind-kejriwal-bjp-shares-pwd-letter-after-atishis-claim-over-being-thrown-out-of-delhi-cm-house/articleshow/117024427.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 12:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marriage Equality Case| New Bench Of Supreme Court To Consider Review Petitions On January 9 - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Set to Review Marriage Equality Petitions on January 9</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 9, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p><p>The Supreme Court will hear review petitions against the verdict that refused to recognize queer marriages in India. A new bench, which includes Justice PS Narasimha from the original bench, will consider these petitions in chambers.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court denied legal recognition for queer marriages on October 17, 2023.</li><li>The court stated that the matter should be decided by the legislature.</li><li>The Union of India is expected to examine the rights of queer unions.</li><li>Despite the denial of marriage recognition, the court acknowledged the right of queer couples to cohabit safely.</li><li>Review petitions were filed claiming the original judgment failed to protect fundamental rights.</li></ul><blockquote>The Court recognizes that the Petitioners' fundamental rights are being violated by the State through discrimination but fails to take the logical next step of prohibiting this discrimination.</blockquote><p>This forthcoming review highlights ongoing debates around queer rights and legal recognition in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/marriage-equality-case-new-bench-of-supreme-court-to-consider-review-petitions-on-january-9-280230</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/marriage-equality-case-new-bench-of-supreme-court-to-consider-review-petitions-on-january-9-280230</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:54:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atishi claims Centre 'snatched away' her official house; BJP says 'Delhi CM' lying - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Atishi claims Centre 'snatched away' her official house; BJP says 'Delhi CM' lying</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Delhi-chief-minister-Atishi---Sanchit-Khanna-HT-Ph_1735752431235_1736248116804.jpg" alt="Delhi chief minister Atishi. (Sanchit Khanna/HT Photo)" title="Delhi chief minister Atishi. (Sanchit Khanna/HT Photo)">
<figcaption>Delhi chief minister Atishi. (Sanchit Khanna/HT Photo)</figcaption>
<p>Delhi Chief Minister Atishi alleged that the central government cancelled her allotment of the CM residence just before the assembly elections. Her accusations were met with a rebuttal from the BJP, asserting she was lying.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Atishi claimed eviction by the BJP-led Central government from her official residence.</li>
  <li>This incident occurred a day before the announcement of the Delhi assembly election schedule.</li>
  <li>Atishi accused the BJP of undermining her position and efforts as CM.</li>
  <li>BJP's Amit Malviya claimed Atishi hasn’t taken possession of her allotted residence, resulting in its retraction.</li>
  <li>The Delhi assembly elections will take place on February 5, with results announced on February 8.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“But, I want to tell people of Delhi that the work won't stop even if they take away our home.” - Atishi</blockquote>
<p>The recent conflict highlights the ongoing political tensions between the AAP and BJP, with implications for the upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/atishi-claims-centre-snatched-away-her-official-house-bjp-says-delhi-cm-lying-101736247299674.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/atishi-claims-centre-snatched-away-her-official-house-bjp-says-delhi-cm-lying-101736247299674.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:12:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['No flirting with cashier, no digging nose': Pune cafe's no-nonsense rules will leave you in splits - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pune Cafe's Hilarious Menu Rules Go Viral</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Ggmh0Q5aAAE25NP_1736247851537_1736247861639.jpg" alt="The menu of the Irani cafe not only listed the food items they serve but also a long list of rules to follow.(X/saysomethingsus)">
<figcaption>The menu of the Irani cafe not only listed the food items they serve but also a long list of rules to follow.(X/saysomethingsus)</figcaption>
<p>The menu of an Irani café in Pune has gone viral due to its quirky and humorous rules, highlighting the café's no-nonsense theme along with its culinary offerings.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The café is famous for its old-world charm and simple menu of chai and bun maska.</li>
  <li>A social media post revealed the café's amusing menu rules, including: 'No flirting with cashier', 'No mobile games', and 'No digging nose'.</li>
  <li>Many of the rules reflect common issues faced by cafés, while others are more comedic in nature.</li>
  <li>The café's owner has garnered attention on social media, with users sharing their reactions and jokes about the rules.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“No flirting with cashier” still intrigues me what must’ve happened to put that up. Their cashier is an uncle.</blockquote>
<p>The humorous rules of the Pune café resonate with many people, bringing both laughter and curiosity about the stories behind them.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/no-flirting-with-cashier-no-digging-nose-pune-cafes-no-nonsense-rules-will-leave-you-in-splits-101736247590109.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/no-flirting-with-cashier-no-digging-nose-pune-cafes-no-nonsense-rules-will-leave-you-in-splits-101736247590109.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:07:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Election Live: ‘BJP is targeting my family,' alleges CM Atishi - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwJBVV95cUxNZEhoNms1WTdMN3JQNjJRd0pBeGZ1TjdqVDhZalZlMkNneW5SRFFnWDVqOFlXdk5HQi1VU2w3Z0QzWGNsbERtZjJFc1RqRGVHam5GX1dMLXBqOGZoY1NwMFBxbmhPMk5JdWg1ekwxZmxJM3NSZnMtLWpHTGZscmU3ZXhqcmpXWFJXZEZva2hfdnhtRFR2U3dmOV9LNVhESWVDbDFFMTYwZ1RZdXJmalhYLXdCN2s1ekFuSXFWVXVFT0N0cU9vMFBJejAyOTdrVFlVMmZiemtEN0owVlp5bk1Cd041eXgyVERKSXNCODZvbl9KTDVzRzJ2Z2JaOVJQaGFOZk5YcV8yNW1Db3VZT2VZ0gGUAkFVX3lxTE9UTWpEU3V1bjU1dnptMGxuSEwtTzVWTkpHZlhkY3NHZFJleEw1dU0wc1RJcTRoaDZmZk5vZnpFVUZEZlpxNUV1WWZxSEdlbFdUYkFyT2d2VzQtOTkxYlZ3blM1QWdiSjNwTHpCSjFUOEhad2lKVnAtSHlhQTRwVFB6LXU3NzVJcExVTmZ5eWtmUFRQaHpFU2RZV3BESmVtRmtBbHE0Rkp6SktXeTU4czhVdFFDU0hiZGxjUmwwaDJCdVROTVBLZUx4UkhTYllBTUxDcE1PSlJrNW9LSDU1YUNyQWVrVGZnVHd3blF4OUhnWlVxZGhKd3dHT1EzWmVTNmkyTUsxdHJZcXA3bFNsX19EbUxBXw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwJBVV95cUxNZEhoNms1WTdMN3JQNjJRd0pBeGZ1TjdqVDhZalZlMkNneW5SRFFnWDVqOFlXdk5HQi1VU2w3Z0QzWGNsbERtZjJFc1RqRGVHam5GX1dMLXBqOGZoY1NwMFBxbmhPMk5JdWg1ekwxZmxJM3NSZnMtLWpHTGZscmU3ZXhqcmpXWFJXZEZva2hfdnhtRFR2U3dmOV9LNVhESWVDbDFFMTYwZ1RZdXJmalhYLXdCN2s1ekFuSXFWVXVFT0N0cU9vMFBJejAyOTdrVFlVMmZiemtEN0owVlp5bk1Cd041eXgyVERKSXNCODZvbl9KTDVzRzJ2Z2JaOVJQaGFOZk5YcV8yNW1Db3VZT2VZ0gGUAkFVX3lxTE9UTWpEU3V1bjU1dnptMGxuSEwtTzVWTkpHZlhkY3NHZFJleEw1dU0wc1RJcTRoaDZmZk5vZnpFVUZEZlpxNUV1WWZxSEdlbFdUYkFyT2d2VzQtOTkxYlZ3blM1QWdiSjNwTHpCSjFUOEhad2lKVnAtSHlhQTRwVFB6LXU3NzVJcExVTmZ5eWtmUFRQaHpFU2RZV3BESmVtRmtBbHE0Rkp6SktXeTU4czhVdFFDU0hiZGxjUmwwaDJCdVROTVBLZUx4UkhTYllBTUxDcE1PSlJrNW9LSDU1YUNyQWVrVGZnVHd3blF4OUhnWlVxZGhKd3dHT1EzWmVTNmkyTUsxdHJZcXA3bFNsX19EbUxBXw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:00:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Railway Safety Commissioner starts inspection of Udhampur-Baramulla rail link - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxPajhUMkRuQlUxems2ektVZkJyWk51S1l1US1ORzNGaTNETGVveHdhX3NSQ3lhSkhCUngtdTBma2JseDdHMG5CLUplMUpPeXJRSXVzQ2lQbExycGYtV2cyMmpuY3Jwc0RwWS0wdFAxbTZZNm5LanNUYVg5ejF6Ny1nS1A1WnFuMkpENVpBYVdmcHBvRzBfTGZzVTd0U2gzdW9QM3p6ZnpzMWJtQ2FGMG5XMmZydWNyc3Z2LVI4YkdsNzPSAcMBQVVfeXFMTUcxV213Q19lVGRtTE0zeWtwOGpseEhMMFRCVzJqYzMyRFNYZDVMVllHc1BZR053bnVvNEttOVNPMG1WMUR5NU1Db3o2djVWWHlta09IRmJiSy1XUUk3WWJCTnFiTi12c3ZMenlaY08zTHNwYzlWYnRZdGxRUjNmeVJLMkM0eUlaRDRFM2FVRXdDNFcxT0hueHV3blBkVDBaMXlQeTZNUGYxbnpBdkpCbmZ1V1duYlpPTElwdU0wdUFaYjg0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxPajhUMkRuQlUxems2ektVZkJyWk51S1l1US1ORzNGaTNETGVveHdhX3NSQ3lhSkhCUngtdTBma2JseDdHMG5CLUplMUpPeXJRSXVzQ2lQbExycGYtV2cyMmpuY3Jwc0RwWS0wdFAxbTZZNm5LanNUYVg5ejF6Ny1nS1A1WnFuMkpENVpBYVdmcHBvRzBfTGZzVTd0U2gzdW9QM3p6ZnpzMWJtQ2FGMG5XMmZydWNyc3Z2LVI4YkdsNzPSAcMBQVVfeXFMTUcxV213Q19lVGRtTE0zeWtwOGpseEhMMFRCVzJqYzMyRFNYZDVMVllHc1BZR053bnVvNEttOVNPMG1WMUR5NU1Db3o2djVWWHlta09IRmJiSy1XUUk3WWJCTnFiTi12c3ZMenlaY08zTHNwYzlWYnRZdGxRUjNmeVJLMkM0eUlaRDRFM2FVRXdDNFcxT0hueHV3blBkVDBaMXlQeTZNUGYxbnpBdkpCbmZ1V1duYlpPTElwdU0wdUFaYjg0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:48:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thousands of Madurai farmers, villagers take out 25-km long procession against tungsten mining project - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Thousands of Madurai farmers, villagers take out 25-km long procession against tungsten mining project</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><figure><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/tamil-nadu/h8i02o/article69072017.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/Madurai%20tungsten%20procession%202.jpeg" alt="Farmers and villagers of Melur walked in procession from Narasingampatti on January 7, 2025" title="Farmers and villagers of Melur walked in procession from Narasingampatti on January 7, 2025"><figcaption>Farmers and villagers of Melur walked in procession from Narasingampatti on January 7, 2025 | Photo Credit: G. Moorthy</figcaption></figure><p>Over 10,000 farmers and villagers from Melur and surrounding areas protested against a tungsten mining project, marching 25 km to Tamil Nadu Agricultural University and Tallakulam.</p><ul><li>The procession began at Narasingampatti and ended in Madurai city.</li><li>Protesters faced police barricades but continued their march.</li><li>Detentions occurred, leading to demands for the release of protesters.</li><li>Demonstrators voiced concerns over environmental damage and its effects on agriculture.</li></ul><blockquote>“As we have already seen plenty of damage to the environment through projects like granite quarrying, we cannot withstand the destruction to our land anymore,” they added.</blockquote><p>The protest highlights community concern over the potential impact of the mining project on local livelihoods and the environment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/tamil-nadu/thousands-of-madurai-farmers-villagers-take-out-25-km-long-procession-against-tungsten-mining-project/article69071887.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/tamil-nadu/thousands-of-madurai-farmers-villagers-take-out-25-km-long-procession-against-tungsten-mining-project/article69071887.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court asks DoPT, States for timeline within which CIC, SIC vacancies will be filled - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court asks DoPT, States for timeline within which CIC, SIC vacancies will be filled</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> 07 Jan 2025, 10:36 am</p>
<div>
<figure>
<img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justices Surya Kant, Justice NK Singh" width="100%" height="100%">
<figcaption>Justices Surya Kant, Justice NK Singh</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>The Supreme Court has mandated a timeline for filling pending vacancies in the Central Information Commission (CIC) and State Information Commissions (SIC), requiring the Department of Personnel and Training (DoPT) to submit this timeline within two weeks.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Supreme Court ordered DoPT to file an affidavit detailing the timeline for completing the selection process.</li>
    <li>State governments are required to notify the list of applicants and the search committee within one week.</li>
    <li>Interviews must be completed no later than two weeks after the search committee finalizes candidates.</li>
    <li>Competent authorities must appoint selected members within two weeks thereafter.</li>
    <li>The Chief Secretaries of all States are to file a compliance affidavit regarding these processes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"It takes more than one year for a case to be listed today. This is the scenario and also this is how RTI is being defunct..." — Adv Prashant Bhushan</blockquote>
<p>The Court expressed concern over the delays in filling SIC vacancies, echoing the request to ensure timely appointments and compliance with existing legal judgments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/supreme-court-dopt-timeline-cic-sic-vacancies-filled</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/supreme-court-dopt-timeline-cic-sic-vacancies-filled</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:36:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP Candidates List for Delhi Assembly Election 2025, Including Constituencies and Districts​​​ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxQY0tpMFo5SGxqNF9hY2VNcnNzRC1DUHhaU3QyZDdMWktRS0pDNElQV2VPQjQyVWdJVVNkc1dMYm9DUDJKMS1qaUhaVkwwQXlaaTRkajJhWW9zRWhIV3BvbWJVd1lUNXVWeWJqWjJzdFItRzFJd2l1Q0VmaGtjUi1wOTI5ZGJDcGhFUmZGYTdwcHlyZTJsT3pxQ2Y5dEl1d2VxLTFZOWhVYzlsc0NydEVEeUJ4aEVkb0toVDhHSHlfc2kyY19GUGQwV05Sc21xRS01R3Nzb3A0cWlodURvZV8taUJKVEFnWmNJS05PY0MxcjF2LWFSRmY40gH8AUFVX3lxTE9BWl9GV2tGWjhJYWVDWk5hOV9wUy12TEdJYmJJTW9wV1dCdXdzYnZOaFY5UEh3NVh4M3drWUN0TXJHT0o0eFJpSEt6aWVTSG5DWHBtUEl6NUV6QlQ2TEJkWlpMM1JTM2c2MDR4ZnlhT0g0Z3RXd0F6ME9lbDlaYl9WdEU0ZnE2cEdOZThvdFJWNDlQb25GV00yRzQ1SnpxQ1RRajFYT1pmeGxVWkZ1Y0doTjVhU2RyU3FLdXZ4NjR1eEVnVndIdGtkN0NqLVRmZkZ4WlBYcW00TjR5aEdhMTVlNUx1Y0JmTS1DaE5TQXliUEd4Z1Y2cERWM3pxRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxQY0tpMFo5SGxqNF9hY2VNcnNzRC1DUHhaU3QyZDdMWktRS0pDNElQV2VPQjQyVWdJVVNkc1dMYm9DUDJKMS1qaUhaVkwwQXlaaTRkajJhWW9zRWhIV3BvbWJVd1lUNXVWeWJqWjJzdFItRzFJd2l1Q0VmaGtjUi1wOTI5ZGJDcGhFUmZGYTdwcHlyZTJsT3pxQ2Y5dEl1d2VxLTFZOWhVYzlsc0NydEVEeUJ4aEVkb0toVDhHSHlfc2kyY19GUGQwV05Sc21xRS01R3Nzb3A0cWlodURvZV8taUJKVEFnWmNJS05PY0MxcjF2LWFSRmY40gH8AUFVX3lxTE9BWl9GV2tGWjhJYWVDWk5hOV9wUy12TEdJYmJJTW9wV1dCdXdzYnZOaFY5UEh3NVh4M3drWUN0TXJHT0o0eFJpSEt6aWVTSG5DWHBtUEl6NUV6QlQ2TEJkWlpMM1JTM2c2MDR4ZnlhT0g0Z3RXd0F6ME9lbDlaYl9WdEU0ZnE2cEdOZThvdFJWNDlQb25GV00yRzQ1SnpxQ1RRajFYT1pmeGxVWkZ1Y0doTjVhU2RyU3FLdXZ4NjR1eEVnVndIdGtkN0NqLVRmZkZ4WlBYcW00TjR5aEdhMTVlNUx1Y0JmTS1DaE5TQXliUEd4Z1Y2cERWM3pxRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why is Delhi assembly election scheduled on Wednesday? CEC Rajiv Kumar explains - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Assembly Election Scheduled for February: CEC Rajiv Kumar Explains the Midweek Vote</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 07, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Chief_Election_Commissioner_Rajiv_Kumar_1736241921296_1736241921641.jpeg" alt="Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar.(Raj K Raj/HT Photo)" title="Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar.(Raj K Raj/HT Photo)">
<figcaption>Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar.(Raj K Raj/HT Photo)</figcaption>
<p>The Election Commission of India has announced that voting for the Delhi assembly will take place in all 70 constituencies on February 5, with results to be counted on February 8. Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar emphasized the choice of a Wednesday for voting to encourage turnout.</p>
<ul>
<li>Voting is scheduled for February 5, 2025, with counting on February 8.</li>
<li>The final voter list shows 1,55,24,858 registered voters, an increase of 1.09%.</li>
<li>Nomination filing ends on January 17; scrutiny on January 18; withdrawal on January 20.</li>
<li>The timing aims to overcome urban apathy in voting.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“India is the gold standard of elections. There is no scope of any irregularity in the commission, the procedures are so detailed.” - CEC Rajiv Kumar</blockquote>
<p>The scheduling of the election on a Wednesday is intended to maximize voter participation, similar to previous elections in Maharashtra. The entire election process is expected to conclude by February 10.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/why-is-delhi-assembly-election-scheduled-on-wednesday-cec-rajiv-kumar-explains-101736241831558.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/why-is-delhi-assembly-election-scheduled-on-wednesday-cec-rajiv-kumar-explains-101736241831558.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:21:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['You cannot call Nikita guilty, this is not a media trial': Supreme Court rejects child custody claim by Atul Subhash' mother - OpIndia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'You cannot call Nikita guilty, this is not a media trial': Supreme Court rejects child custody claim by Atul Subhash' mother</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Business Today</p><p>The Supreme Court has ruled against the child custody claim made by the mother of Atul Subhash, asserting that the child's best interests are served under the care of its living parent, Nikita Singhania.</p><ul><li>The court emphasized the mother's rights as the child's sole living parent.</li><li>It stated that Atul Subhash's mother is 'virtually a stranger' to the child.</li><li>Justice B Nagarathna cautioned against labeling Nikita as 'guilty' prior to a court ruling.</li><li>The court suggested a formal process for Atul Subhash's parents if they wished to seek custody.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is not a media trial. This is court. Only a court trial can pronounce a person guilty.” - Justice B Nagarathna</blockquote><p>The ruling underscores the importance of maintaining the child's connection with the living parent while providing a clear guideline for custody disputes involving extended family.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.opindia.com/news-updates/you-cannot-call-nikita-guilty-this-is-not-a-media-trial-supreme-court-rejects-child-custody-claim-by-atul-subhash-mother/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opindia.com/news-updates/you-cannot-call-nikita-guilty-this-is-not-a-media-trial-supreme-court-rejects-child-custody-claim-by-atul-subhash-mother/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:20:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘You Are Virtually A Stranger’: Supreme Court To Atul Subhash’s Mother Who Sought Kid’s Custody - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/atul-subhash-suicide-bengaluru-techie-mother-child-custody-plea-supreme-court-karnataka-hc-wife-nikita-singhania-9180540.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/atul-subhash-suicide-bengaluru-techie-mother-child-custody-plea-supreme-court-karnataka-hc-wife-nikita-singhania-9180540.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:16:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fastag To Be Mandatory For All Vehicles In Maharashtra From April 1, 2025 - Pune Pulse]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxNMUNaWGctYzRRekJkSmVjS2gzLTlQNDVMdE9aRFNxYW5lekROQ2ZpZU1NQ0ZqQXRnbmJoVlBqWFpPVVIxamZGVzhPRTZ1SUdyb3dhd0tHdXRKcTNkbk5GYTluQ2paT1MxMEROcE5TVXkxVHp2QzlqWE82VlJNR3RjYmZsMFpXQTBVTXg5SzU3RGpmTzhUUXJNTmp3M3lCQUxtSVJF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxNMUNaWGctYzRRekJkSmVjS2gzLTlQNDVMdE9aRFNxYW5lekROQ2ZpZU1NQ0ZqQXRnbmJoVlBqWFpPVVIxamZGVzhPRTZ1SUdyb3dhd0tHdXRKcTNkbk5GYTluQ2paT1MxMEROcE5TVXkxVHp2QzlqWE82VlJNR3RjYmZsMFpXQTBVTXg5SzU3RGpmTzhUUXJNTmp3M3lCQUxtSVJF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:00:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BPSC Paper Leak : Supreme Court Refuses To Entertain Plea Challenging BPSC Exam, Asks Petitioner To... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxNeTE1YmV1Q0ppQUxJLWpJcjB0ZHpnZmRZLUlOU0lTY0RFYlRNYVNoSUlmYWUtSDRFVHBKUVlmRTdfMmwtSkx5ZmlKWV9tOGIzN0ZSMndGZXp0MjA5V2R4SFAwcE5IUkFEN2tlVmF2bEQ3c3ZoYldfZHNmSmNzQll2YU9ENFdaX1k2VTNMNWZRU0lCb1owdU1PcUtKYWRsblhUbHlqNG5yRFFxLWY4WnIyMmplNnlrMS1hbkhHdmdFdW9YRnRpeFctMzBzdHdveTVHNzBmS0FRekYtaGtZU25FRTRlc29ZRFVROGFZV9IB8gFBVV95cUxOclRaRk9PUG1OMHo0T1ZGdHhBMWN6X0d6VGNnRXlMcHRBa3cxZzZkZjROd3VxX3hYZzVNZDRxTkY0OFhMYmZKREFjQm44bWZHY1A3TTRXallMVUVmRGtzQmdmdE1TLXRmZlQtOTNXV3BNVGJROGFxeEdEcFdxUlQzS2xDN0RiZ2VZRHAzWnBseTlWOVYxYk5pMFdGOEQyOEhTQVFZWjBiYlhoSGhIdGJXV1JVaDl2SVpmLTJQUzNyZFphQXBpM1JjaV9pOXU4Q2dSb2xsWVAyWDJZTThWVGNsQWdnSjNZY1hoYU05YmJwbzJpUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxNeTE1YmV1Q0ppQUxJLWpJcjB0ZHpnZmRZLUlOU0lTY0RFYlRNYVNoSUlmYWUtSDRFVHBKUVlmRTdfMmwtSkx5ZmlKWV9tOGIzN0ZSMndGZXp0MjA5V2R4SFAwcE5IUkFEN2tlVmF2bEQ3c3ZoYldfZHNmSmNzQll2YU9ENFdaX1k2VTNMNWZRU0lCb1owdU1PcUtKYWRsblhUbHlqNG5yRFFxLWY4WnIyMmplNnlrMS1hbkhHdmdFdW9YRnRpeFctMzBzdHdveTVHNzBmS0FRekYtaGtZU25FRTRlc29ZRFVROGFZV9IB8gFBVV95cUxOclRaRk9PUG1OMHo0T1ZGdHhBMWN6X0d6VGNnRXlMcHRBa3cxZzZkZjROd3VxX3hYZzVNZDRxTkY0OFhMYmZKREFjQm44bWZHY1A3TTRXallMVUVmRGtzQmdmdE1TLXRmZlQtOTNXV3BNVGJROGFxeEdEcFdxUlQzS2xDN0RiZ2VZRHAzWnBseTlWOVYxYk5pMFdGOEQyOEhTQVFZWjBiYlhoSGhIdGJXV1JVaDl2SVpmLTJQUzNyZFphQXBpM1JjaV9pOXU4Q2dSb2xsWVAyWDJZTThWVGNsQWdnSjNZY1hoYU05YmJwbzJpUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:43:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Elections 2025 Date Announcement Live: Delhi To Vote On February 5, Counting On February 8 - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Elections 2025 Date Announcement Live: Delhi To Vote On February 5, Counting On February 8</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 &nbsp;| &nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>The assembly elections in Delhi will occur in a single phase on February 5, with votes counted on February 8, as announced by the Election Commission.</p><ul><li>Election scheduled for February 5, 2025.</li><li>Counting of votes set for February 8, 2025.</li><li>The current 70-member Assembly's term ends on February 23, requiring elections to form a new House.</li><li>AAP aims for a third consecutive term, facing competition from BJP and Congress.</li><li>India to reach one billion voters soon, setting a new record.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are going to be a nation of one billion voters very soon, which will be another record in voting,” said Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar.</blockquote><p>This announcement sets the stage for the upcoming electoral battle, highlighting the contest among major political parties and the increasing voter population in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/delhi-news/delhi-elections-2025-date-announcement-live-updates-poll-body-to-release-assembly-election-schedule-as-aap-bjp-congress-pm-modi-arvind-kejriwal-fight-7417380</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/delhi-news/delhi-elections-2025-date-announcement-live-updates-poll-body-to-release-assembly-election-schedule-as-aap-bjp-congress-pm-modi-arvind-kejriwal-fight-7417380</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:26:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India will soon set new record of one billion-plus voters: CEC Rajiv Kumar - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Will Soon Set New Record of One Billion Plus Voters</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/6xthh9/article69071766.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/CECRajivKumar.jpg" alt="Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar addressing the media" title="Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar addressing the media on Delhi Assembly Election at Vigyan Bhawan on January 7, 2025." />
<figcaption>Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar addressing the media on Delhi Assembly Election at Vigyan Bhawan on January 7, 2025.</figcaption>
<p>India is poised to create a new record of over one billion voters, as announced by Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar during a press conference in New Delhi.</p>
<ul>
  <li>2024 is expected to be a significant election year globally.</li>
  <li>Kumar highlighted improved voter participation, especially among women.</li>
  <li>The electoral rolls indicate that India will soon cross 99 crore voters, reaching the one billion mark.</li>
  <li>States including Uttar Pradesh, Rajasthan, Bihar, and Punjab will contribute to this voter milestone.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We are going to be a nation of one billion voters very soon, which will be another record in voting." - Rajiv Kumar</blockquote>
<p>This development emphasizes India's vibrant democracy and increasing voter engagement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/india-will-soon-set-new-record-of-one-billion-plus-voters-cec-rajiv-kumar/article69071754.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/india-will-soon-set-new-record-of-one-billion-plus-voters-cec-rajiv-kumar/article69071754.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi High Court rejects plea against CAT 2024 results - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi High Court Dismisses Petition Challenging CAT 2024 Results</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-07T09:08:45.347Z">07 Jan 2025, 9:08 am</time></p><figure><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justice Tara Vitasta Ganju" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Justice Tara Vitasta Ganju</figcaption></figure><p>The Delhi High Court has dismissed a petition challenging the results of the Common Admission Test (CAT) 2024, rejecting claims of errors in the answer key that affected the outcomes for candidates.</p><ul><li>The petition was filed by candidate Aditya Kumar Mallick, alleging uncorrected errors in the CAT exam answer key.</li><li>Justice Tara Vitasta Ganju stated, "We find no reason to interfere; the petition is accordingly dismissed."</li><li>The court emphasized its limitation in intervening in competitive exam disputes, intervening only under significant circumstances.</li><li>The CAT 2024 exam was conducted on November 24, and results were announced on December 19, prompting the petitioner's objection.</li><li>A total of 272 objections were recorded concerning a specific question in the exam.</li></ul><blockquote>"272 objections were filed on this one question...Even if two options are correct, we (candidates who did not choose the answer marked as correct in the answer key) are benefiting," argued advocate Praveen Kumar Singh.</blockquote><p>The court's decision underscores the challenges candidates face in contesting exam results, emphasizing the authority of the examiners in determining correct answers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/delhi-high-court-rejects-plea-against-cat-2024-results</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/delhi-high-court-rejects-plea-against-cat-2024-results</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:08:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Class 9 student stabs classmate in Odisha’s Balasore; injured admitted to hospital - OTV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/class-9-student-stabs-classmate-in-odisha-s-balasore-252897</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/class-9-student-stabs-classmate-in-odisha-s-balasore-252897</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:55:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Class 9 student stabs classmate in Odisha’s Balasore; injured admitted to hospital - OTV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/class-9-student-stabs-classmate-in-odisha-s-balasore-252897</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/class-9-student-stabs-classmate-in-odisha-s-balasore-252897</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:55:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GATE 2025 Admit Card Live Updates: Website to download GATE hall ticket - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GATE 2025 Admit Card Live Updates: GATE hall ticket out; steps to download</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>2025-01-01 <strong>Source: </strong>The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/gate-2025-admit-card-live.jpg?w=640" alt="GATE Admit Card 2025 Live: Websites to check GATE hall tickets at gate2025.iitr.ac.in"><figcaption>GATE Admit Card 2025 Live: The Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering (GATE) 2025 will be conducted between February 1 and 16. (File)</figcaption><p>The Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Roorkee has released the GATE 2025 admit cards on the official website, gate2025.iitr.ac.in. Candidates can download their admit cards and verify all printed information.</p><ul><li>The GATE 2025 exams will take place between February 1 and 16.</li><li>Candidates may appear for one or two test papers from a total of 30 available.</li><li>Exams will be conducted in forenoon (9.30 am to 12.30 pm) and afternoon (2.30 pm to 5.30 pm) sessions.</li></ul><blockquote>“If candidates find any discrepancies in the admit card, they should immediately contact the GATE administering body.”</blockquote><p>This year, GATE is essential for admission to master’s and doctoral programmes as well as recruitment by some public sector undertakings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/education/gate-admit-card-2025-live-updates-hall-tickets-released-websites-to-check-steps-direct-link-gate2025-iitr-ac-in-9760765/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/education/gate-admit-card-2025-live-updates-hall-tickets-released-websites-to-check-steps-direct-link-gate2025-iitr-ac-in-9760765/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:50:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FastTag To Be Mandatory For All Vehicles In Maharashtra From April 1, 2025 - Pune Pulse]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxQZEk1TlhBbmxLSDYydS1tdzZPWVhjdkoyWlV0QWloeHh3QlR1X2RNazF1T3VNakFyM3dMZU9TcjU2MDd1NzZqcWlyMEpCY2dCY3VoZWhxYWtFRDYyWkNVbllMaXJVaU5pa2JkTndnbFZlQWtWYkY0dmxkZnFiMEhfQW1HcHlaWHJwcDYxV1lneDc3cnp5RXVqSFJiTVhmczFMM0gwZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxQZEk1TlhBbmxLSDYydS1tdzZPWVhjdkoyWlV0QWloeHh3QlR1X2RNazF1T3VNakFyM3dMZU9TcjU2MDd1NzZqcWlyMEpCY2dCY3VoZWhxYWtFRDYyWkNVbllMaXJVaU5pa2JkTndnbFZlQWtWYkY0dmxkZnFiMEhfQW1HcHlaWHJwcDYxV1lneDc3cnp5RXVqSFJiTVhmczFMM0gwZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:47:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Assembly poll schedule LIVE updates: Election Commission to announce dates shortly - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Assembly Elections 2025 LIVE: Voting on February 5, counting on February 8</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 07, 2025 - The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/9f0ws4/article69071757.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/WhatsApp%20Image%202025-01-07%20at%202.35.36%20PM.jpeg" alt="Delhi Assembly Election 2025" /><figcaption>Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar addressed the media on Delhi Assembly Election at Vigyan Bhawan on January 7, 2025. | Photo Credit: Sushil Kumar Verma</figcaption><p>The announcement for the Delhi Assembly elections has been made, with voting scheduled for February 5, 2025, and counting of votes set for February 8, 2025.</p><ul><li>Single-phase elections will be conducted in Delhi.</li><li>The Delhi Chief Election Commissioner emphasized a crackdown on the use of money power during elections.</li><li>Easy access and provisions for senior citizens and persons with disabilities will be ensured.</li></ul><blockquote>“India has a gold standard of elections, it’s a shared legacy for all of us including all political parties,” - CEC Rajiv Kumar.</blockquote><p>This election is poised to influence the political landscape of Delhi significantly, highlighting key issues such as electoral integrity and participation rights.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/elections/delhi-assembly/delhi-assembly-election-schedule-election-commission-live-updates/article69070928.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/elections/delhi-assembly/delhi-assembly-election-schedule-election-commission-live-updates/article69070928.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>