<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:24:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:24:59 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AAP's Sanjay Singh accuses Delhi poll official of secretly reposting BJP's X posts; DEO responds - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AAP's Sanjay Singh Accuses Delhi Poll Official of Secretly Reposting BJP Posts</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Sanjay_Singh_1736959016344_1736959016657.jpg" alt="Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leader Sanjay Singh.(PTI)"><figcaption>Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leader Sanjay Singh.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) MP Sanjay Singh has accused the New Delhi district election officer of secretly reposting posts from the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) on social media.</p><ul><li>Elections for the Delhi legislative assembly are scheduled for February 5, with results on February 8.</li><li>Singh shared a screenshot showing the district election officer's repost of a BJP post featuring party leaders.</li><li>He claimed this is unprecedented in India, suggesting the DEO has political affiliations with the BJP.</li><li>The DEO responded, clarifying that the repost was inadvertent and claiming to promote accuracy in official communication.</li><li>The Social Media Cell responsible for the DEO's social media has been reorganized to prevent future errors.</li></ul><blockquote>“For the first time in the history of India - Election Officer of New Delhi started retweeting BJP's tweets secretly.” - Sanjay Singh</blockquote><p>This incident raises concerns over the impartiality of election officials ahead of the crucial assembly elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/aaps-sanjay-singh-accuses-delhi-poll-official-of-secretly-reposting-bjps-x-posts-deo-responds-101736959022636.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/aaps-sanjay-singh-accuses-delhi-poll-official-of-secretly-reposting-bjps-x-posts-deo-responds-101736959022636.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal net worth: A look at ex-Delhi CM's assets, how his income changed in 5 years - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arvind Kejriwal net worth: A look at ex-Delhi CM's assets, how his income changed in 5 years</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 15, 2025</strong> / <strong>Source: Moneycontrol</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250115064236_Arvind-Kejriwal-Delhi-election.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled to take place on February 5, with the results to be announced on February 8." title="The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled to take place on February 5, with the results to be announced on February 8." width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled to take place on February 5, with the results to be announced on February 8.</figcaption>
<p>Arvind Kejriwal, the national convenor of the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP), has seen a marginal increase in his family net worth over the past five years, rising from Rs 3.4 crore to Rs 4.2 crore.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kejriwal declared net assets totaling Rs 1.73 crore in his affidavit.</li>
  <li>His assets include bank savings of Rs 2.96 lakh and cash of Rs 50,000.</li>
  <li>He owns immovable assets worth Rs 1.7 crore but has no car or house listed.</li>
  <li>For the financial year 2023-24, Kejriwal reported an income of Rs 7.21 lakh.</li>
  <li>His wife, Sunita Kejriwal, has assets totaling Rs 2.5 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Kejriwal’s declared family net worth has increased marginally from Rs 3.4 crore to Rs 4.2 crore over five years."</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the couple’s total net worth amounts to Rs 4.23 crore, showing a steady increase in their declared assets over time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/elections/assembly-election/delhi/arvind-kejriwal-net-worth-a-look-at-ex-delhi-cm-s-assets-how-his-income-changed-in-5-years-article-12911736.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/elections/assembly-election/delhi/arvind-kejriwal-net-worth-a-look-at-ex-delhi-cm-s-assets-how-his-income-changed-in-5-years-article-12911736.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:29:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['A clear message': US removes 3 Indian entities from restrictive list, adds 11 from China over national s - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘A clear message’: US removes 3 Indian entities from restrictive list, adds 11 from China over national security concerns</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 19, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="US-China Relations" width="600" height="400"><figcaption>The US has made significant adjustments to its list of entities over national security concerns.</figcaption><p>The recent changes made by the US in its restrictions on entities reveal a strategic shift, emphasizing its ongoing concerns regarding national security from both Indian and Chinese firms.</p><ul><li>The US has removed three Indian entities from its restrictive list.</li><li>In contrast, the US has added 11 new entities from China, highlighting rising tensions.</li><li>Officials stated that the decision aims to protect US national security interests.</li></ul><blockquote>“The list changes reflect our commitment to safeguarding our technological and national security interests,” said a senior US official.</blockquote><p>This decision illustrates the shifting dynamics in US-India-China relations and underscores the complexities involved in international trade and security.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/a-clear-message-us-removes-3-indian-entities-from-restrictive-list-adds-11-from-china-over-national-security-concerns/articleshow/117273169.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/a-clear-message-us-removes-3-indian-entities-from-restrictive-list-adds-11-from-china-over-national-security-concerns/articleshow/117273169.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We are fighting BJP, RSS, and the Indian state itself, says Rahul Gandhi; Nadda hits back - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>We are fighting BJP, RSS, and the Indian state itself, says Rahul Gandhi; Nadda hits back</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Wednesday, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/New-Congress-HQ.jpeg' alt='Congress’s new headquarters in New Delhi.'><figcaption>Congress’s new headquarters in New Delhi. (Express Photo)</figcaption><p>In his recent address, Rahul Gandhi criticized the BJP and RSS for allegedly capturing key institutions in India. He condemned the remarks made by Mohan Bhagwat regarding India's true Independence and characterized them as treasonous. Gandhi emphasized the ideological conflict between the Congress party and the RSS.</p><ul><li>Rahul Gandhi stated that the BJP and RSS have captured every institution in India.</li><li>He condemned Mohan Bhagwat's remarks about India's Independence and suggested that they undermine the Constitution.</li><li>During the inauguration of Congress’s new headquarters, Gandhi asserted the need to fight against the BJP and RSS’s vision for India.</li><li>BJP president JP Nadda responded to Gandhi's comments by accusing him of attempting to divide the country.</li><li>Gandhi highlighted the importance of India’s diversity and criticized the current power holders for their centralized and exclusionary vision.</li></ul><blockquote>“To say that India did not get Independence in 1947 is an insult to every single Indian.” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote><p>The ongoing political discourse highlights a growing divide between the Congress party's vision of inclusivity and the RSS's centralized ideology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/mohan-bhagwat-constitution-rahul-gandhi-congresss-new-headquarters-9779671/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/mohan-bhagwat-constitution-rahul-gandhi-congresss-new-headquarters-9779671/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh Mela 2025 Live Updates: Day 3 begins, over 3.5 crore devotees take dip in Sangam on first ‘Amrit Snan’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh Mela 2025 Live Updates: Day 3 begins, over 3.5 crore devotees take dip in Sangam on first ‘Amrit Snan’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/kumbh.png?w=640" alt="Mahakumbh 2025, kumbh mela" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Day 3 of Mahakumbh 2025 kicked off with thousands of devotees taking a dip in the Sangam (Photo - UP CM/X)</figcaption><p>Kicking off the third day of the Mahakumbh Mela in Prayagraj, thousands of devotees flocked to the ghats of Triveni Sangam for a holy dip. On the first day of the ‘Amrit Snan’, over 3.5 crore devotees participated, with rose petals showered from helicopters.</p><ul><li>Thousands of devotees at Triveni Sangam for holy dip.</li><li>Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath reported over 3.5 crore devotees on the first day.</li><li>High-security measures with 11 tethered drones for surveillance.</li><li>Up to 50 crore people expected to attend the Mela, including over 20 lakh foreign travelers.</li><li>Kumbh Mela has deep roots in Hindu mythology and is the largest religious gathering globally.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Kumbh Mela dates back thousands of years to ancient Hindu epics and literature.”</blockquote><p>The Mahakumbh Mela represents a significant cultural and religious event, embodying a deep connection to Hindu tradition and spirituality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/mahakumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-amrit-snan-9779388/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/mahakumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-amrit-snan-9779388/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:13:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GRAP-4 restrictions reimposed in Delhi-NCR as air quality worsens - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GRAP-4 restrictions reimposed in Delhi-NCR as air quality worsens</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/v9124m/article69101524.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/WEATHER%20FOG%2015%2001%20NEW%20DELHI%2017.JPG" alt="A thick layer of fog engulfs New Delhi on January 15, 2025." title="A thick layer of fog engulfs New Delhi on January 15, 2025."><figcaption>A thick layer of fog engulfs New Delhi on January 15, 2025. | Photo Credit: Shashi Shekhar Kashyap</figcaption><p>The Centre's panel on Delhi-NCR's air quality has reimposed curbs under stage 4 of the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) due to a sharp decline in air quality. Meteorological conditions have contributed to a significant rise in the air quality index (AQI), prompting immediate action.</p><ul><li>Air quality index soared to 396 on January 15, 2025.</li><li>Stage 4 curbs include banning construction activities and entry of non-essential polluting trucks.</li><li>School classes for grades other than 10 and 12 shifted to hybrid mode.</li><li>Non-essential diesel trucks banned from entering Delhi.</li><li>CAQM directed immediate action under stages 3 and 4 due to worsening air quality forecasts.</li></ul><blockquote>The India Meteorological Department predicts AQI may breach the 400 mark soon.</blockquote><p>This decision is aimed at combating hazardous air quality levels that particularly worsen during winter months in the Delhi-NCR region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/grap-4-curbs-invoked-in-delhi-ncr-amid-sharp-dip-in-air-quality/article69101457.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/grap-4-curbs-invoked-in-delhi-ncr-amid-sharp-dip-in-air-quality/article69101457.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NEET PG 2024 Counselling: MCC To Fill 24,314 Seats In Round 3 After Cut-Off Reduction - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NEET PG 2024 Counselling: MCC To Fill 24,314 Seats In Round 3 After Cut-Off Reduction</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="NEET PG 2024: Candidates can select the preferences up to 8 AM on January 16, 2025." title="NEET PG 2024: Candidates can select the preferences up to 8 AM on January 16, 2025." loading="eager">
<figcaption>NEET PG 2024: Candidates can select the preferences up to 8 AM on January 16, 2025. (Representative Image)</figcaption>
<p>The Medical Counselling Committee (MCC) has announced significant updates regarding the NEET PG 2024 counselling process, with 24,314 vacancies available for Round 3 due to a reduction in cut-offs aimed at filling vacant seats.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The MCC has announced 15,902 virtual vacancies for Round 3, allowing candidates to update or vacate their previously allotted seats.</li>
  <li>A total of 8,313 clear vacancies have been identified, along with 99 new seats added for Round 3 across various states.</li>
  <li>Revised cut-offs now allow General Category/EWS candidates with 15 percentile and above, and SC/ST/OBC/PwD candidates with 10 percentile to participate in counselling.</li>
  <li>Registration for Round 3 will end by 12 PM on January 15, 2025, and candidates can choose preferences until 8 AM on January 16, 2025.</li>
  <li>Reporting to allotted colleges will be from January 18 to January 25, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The cut-offs were lowered to prevent PG seats in medical colleges from remaining vacant.”</blockquote>
<p>This initiative is aimed at maximizing the admission rates for NEET PG, ensuring that more candidates can secure their places in medical colleges across India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/education-career/neet-pg-2024-counselling-mcc-to-fill-24314-seats-in-round-3-after-cut-off-reduction-9189098.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/education-career/neet-pg-2024-counselling-mcc-to-fill-24314-seats-in-round-3-after-cut-off-reduction-9189098.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:37:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court calls for separate toilets for men, women, PwD, transgender persons in all courts - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Mandates Separate Toilets in All Courts for Men, Women, PwD, and Transgender Persons</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 15 Jan 2025, 2:28 pm</p><figure><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justice JB Pardiwala and Justice R Mahadevan" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Justice JB Pardiwala and Justice R Mahadevan</figcaption></figure><p>The Supreme Court has issued a pivotal directive for all states and High Courts to provide separate toilet facilities for men, women, persons with disabilities, and transgender individuals at court premises, emphasizing sanitation as a human right.</p><ul><li>All States and High Courts must construct separate toilet facilities for men, women, PwD, and transgender persons.</li><li>These facilities must be identifiable and accessible to judges, advocates, litigants, and court staff.</li><li>States must allocate sufficient funds for construction and maintenance of these facilities.</li><li>Toilets should contain stocked sanitary pad dispensers where applicable.</li></ul><blockquote>“Access to proper sanitation is recognized as a fundamental right under Article 21 of the Constitution.”</blockquote><p>This ruling was made in response to a petition advocating for the need for separate restroom facilities, addressing the basic human rights linked to sanitation in the justice system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/supreme-court-separate-toilets-men-women-pwd-transgender-persons-all-courts</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/supreme-court-separate-toilets-men-women-pwd-transgender-persons-all-courts</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:28:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi pollution: Centre imposes GRAP 4 restrictions as air quality worsens in Capital - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi pollution: Centre imposes GRAP 4 restrictions as air quality worsens in Capital</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The Indian government has implemented GRAP 4 restrictions in response to worsening air quality in Delhi. These measures aim to control pollution levels and improve public health.</p><ul><li>The air quality in Delhi has severely declined, prompting urgent governmental action.</li><li>GRAP (Graded Response Action Plan) Level 4 includes various restrictions to mitigate pollution.</li><li>Health officials warn of the potential health risks associated with prolonged exposure to the polluted air.</li><li>Citizens are urged to minimize outdoor activities during high pollution days.</li></ul><blockquote>“The air quality in Delhi poses a significant risk to public health and requires immediate action,” a health officials stated.</blockquote><p>This decision highlights the ongoing struggle against air pollution in urban areas and the need for heightened measures to protect citizens' health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/delhi-pollution-centre-imposes-grap-4-restrictions-as-air-quality-worsens-in-capital/articleshow/117270213.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/delhi-pollution-centre-imposes-grap-4-restrictions-as-air-quality-worsens-in-capital/articleshow/117270213.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stricter Pollution Curbs Under GRAP-4 Reimposed In Delhi - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stricter Pollution Curbs Under GRAP-4 Reimposed In Delhi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 25, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Commission for Air Quality Management</p><p>With dense fog enveloping Delhi and the air quality index hovering dangerously close to the 'severe' category, the Centre's anti-pollution panel has reimposed stricter pollution curbs in the capital and surrounding areas.</p><ul><li>Stricter measures under GRAP-3 were revoked only recently; GRAP-4 measures have not been in effect since December 24.</li><li>The air quality index (AQI) has climbed to 396, likely to exceed the 400 mark.</li><li>Action has been taken under Stage-III and Stage-IV of the GRAP to tackle the severe air quality.</li><li>Restrictions include the use of certain vehicles, potential closure of physical classes, work from home measures, and bans on truck traffic.</li></ul><blockquote>“In an effort to prevent further deterioration of the air quality, the Sub Committee on GRAP hereby decides to straightway invoke ALL actions under Stage-III and Stage-IV of extant Schedule of GRAP...”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the reintroduction of these measures underscores the urgent need to address the critical air quality situation in Delhi and its adjoining regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/stricter-pollution-curbs-under-grap-4-reimposed-in-delhi-7480569</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/stricter-pollution-curbs-under-grap-4-reimposed-in-delhi-7480569</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:26:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UP School Holiday: Sambal, Bareilly, & others extend winter vacations due to coldwave - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UP School Holiday: Sambal, Bareilly, & others extend winter vacations due to coldwave</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/coldwave-up-school-holiday.jpg?w=640" alt="UP School Holiday: Lucknow, Bareilly, &amp; others extends winter vacations due to coldwave" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Check the comprehensive list of UP districts where the schools till class 8 are closed. (File)</figcaption><p>Amid the cold wave conditions in North India, various districts in Uttar Pradesh have extended the winter vacations for school students up to Class 8.</p><ul><li>Schools in Meerut, Mathura, Kanpur, Agra, Varanasi, Prayagraj, Amethi, Barabanki, Gorakhpur, and Ballia are open for all classes.</li><li>For Moradabad and Rampur, school timings for Classes 9 to 12 have been revised to 10 am to 3 pm.</li><li>In Ghaziabad, winter vacations for classes 1 to 8 have been extended until January 18.</li></ul><blockquote>The School Education Department in Jammu and Kashmir has also announced a winter holiday schedule.</blockquote><p>Students are advised to stay in touch with their respective schools for information regarding the holiday schedule.</p><p>This article went live on January fifteenth, twenty twenty-five, at forty-two minutes past eleven in the morning.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/education/up-school-holiday-lucknow-bareilly-extend-winter-vacations-ncr-coldwave-9779587/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/education/up-school-holiday-lucknow-bareilly-extend-winter-vacations-ncr-coldwave-9779587/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ED arrests former Chhattisgarh minister Kawasi Lakhma in ‘liquor scam’, he says ‘I’m illiterate, don’t know what I signed’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ED Arrests Former Chhattisgarh Minister Kawasi Lakhma in Liquor Scam</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/kawasi_20250115124925.jpg?w=640" alt="former Chhattisgarh minister Kawasi Lakhma" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Former Chhattisgarh minister Kawasi Lakhma. (Express)</figcaption><p>The Enforcement Directorate (ED) arrested former Chhattisgarh excise minister Kawasi Lakhma in a multi-crore liquor scam that allegedly occurred under the previous Congress government.</p><ul><li>Lakhma was questioned for several days at the ED's Raipur office before the arrest.</li><li>He maintains that he is innocent and claims to have cooperated with the investigation.</li><li>Raids were conducted at Lakhma's official residence and his son's residence.</li><li>Lakhma alleges that he signed papers without understanding them, due to his claim of being 'illiterate.'</li><li>The case involves a criminal syndicate accused of bootlegging alcohol and extorting commissions from government shops.</li></ul><blockquote>“Not even a single penny has been found from me but still they have arrested me. I was cooperating with them.” - Kawasi Lakhma</blockquote><p>The case is significant as it involves 70 accused individuals, including notable government officials, and suggests a larger corruption issue in the state's excise department.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/ed-arrests-former-chhattisgarh-minister-kawasi-lakhma-liquor-scam-9780621/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/ed-arrests-former-chhattisgarh-minister-kawasi-lakhma-liquor-scam-9780621/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai News Live Updates: Prime Minister Narendra Modi inaugurates ISKCON temple in Navi Mumbai’s Kharghar - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPS3BoeFh2NTVDZHk3Q2pFUlAwOV9GQ2pPQTZ2bnlodVhpUGgwdVNnQWMyZThvVHRrVTV1OHFxRHBrTU5Lb2ZxTVB0RVRobWxBR3JEMjduZzdsdjBBVE1rSmFDUmxGNUI3M3gtWDByaUp6UnlVWUh6TkRubEJneG5QaFpxQVZYcU1sSGNkU0tjSG01R0Y4cGRiUGN30gGgAUFVX3lxTFBRQkd1Y3ExWDZsbV9PM2lMS2xIMjdfeUJuZml2eXFpVUIyOEw0eTJiVW9vTWNYN2FvS1phYXBJMU1HaFV3Zjc2RjI3S21DR1FzdWZHbzY1czVfLWhUM3JPd1RiRmhBbzhFZnRaY3FFNWJFN3pKbWRnV0tlU0VUdWVQc0VJRTdnZ3Fmd3Q5SFRmWUFnMWpmWHY5cm1UaFRVYko?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPS3BoeFh2NTVDZHk3Q2pFUlAwOV9GQ2pPQTZ2bnlodVhpUGgwdVNnQWMyZThvVHRrVTV1OHFxRHBrTU5Lb2ZxTVB0RVRobWxBR3JEMjduZzdsdjBBVE1rSmFDUmxGNUI3M3gtWDByaUp6UnlVWUh6TkRubEJneG5QaFpxQVZYcU1sSGNkU0tjSG01R0Y4cGRiUGN30gGgAUFVX3lxTFBRQkd1Y3ExWDZsbV9PM2lMS2xIMjdfeUJuZml2eXFpVUIyOEw0eTJiVW9vTWNYN2FvS1phYXBJMU1HaFV3Zjc2RjI3S21DR1FzdWZHbzY1czVfLWhUM3JPd1RiRmhBbzhFZnRaY3FFNWJFN3pKbWRnV0tlU0VUdWVQc0VJRTdnZ3Fmd3Q5SFRmWUFnMWpmWHY5cm1UaFRVYko?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:50:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Facial recognition, AI to trace missing persons: How authorities are managing crowds at Mahakumbh - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Facial recognition, AI to trace missing persons: How authorities are managing crowds at Mahakumbh</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/INDIA-RELIGION-KUMBH-SECURITY-0_1736940989088_1736941831448.JPG" alt="Mahakumbh, day 3: Police officers monitor screens at the Integrated Command and Control Center which is set up to manage and control the crowd during the ongoing Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj, January 15, 2025 (Reuters)" title="Mahakumbh, day 3: Police officers monitor screens at the Integrated Command and Control Center which is set up to manage and control the crowd during the ongoing Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj, January 15, 2025 (Reuters)">
<figcaption>Mahakumbh, day 3: Police officers monitor screens at the Integrated Command and Control Center which is set up to manage and control the crowd during the ongoing Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj, January 15, 2025 (Reuters)</figcaption>
<p>The Mahakumbh Mela in Prayagraj has introduced technology for the first time to help locate missing individuals and control crowds, with expectations of attracting 450 million devotees.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Authorities are utilizing facial recognition and AI to trace missing persons.</li>
  <li>SSP Rajesh Dwivedi acknowledges potential limitations of the technology.</li>
  <li>AI tools will create digital images to assist in locating missing individuals.</li>
  <li>Various technologies are being employed, including RFID wristbands and crowd monitoring systems.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“For the first time, we'll use facial recognition and artificial intelligence (AI) to locate lost people,” - SSP Rajesh Dwivedi</blockquote>
<p>This initiative hopes to leverage technology for better crowd management and safety during the religious gathering.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/facial-recognition-ai-how-authorities-are-managing-crowds-at-mahakumbh-101736941836349.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/facial-recognition-ai-how-authorities-are-managing-crowds-at-mahakumbh-101736941836349.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:49:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi’s ‘fighting Indian state’ remarks: BJP says ‘Congress’ ugly truth now stands exposed by their own leader‘ - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/congress-ugly-truth-now-stands-exposed-by-their-own-leader-bjp-condemns-rahul-gandhis-remarks/article69100765.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/congress-ugly-truth-now-stands-exposed-by-their-own-leader-bjp-condemns-rahul-gandhis-remarks/article69100765.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Centre recommends legal action against ‘individual’ accused of murder plot by US - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Centre recommends legal action against individual accused of murder plot by US</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/MHA_1736943985061_1736943985448.jpg" alt="A high-powered enquiry panel submitted its report on the activities of some organised criminal groups and terrorist organisations, which undermined the security interests of both India and the United States(PTI filed)" title="A high-powered enquiry panel submitted its report on the activities of some organised criminal groups and terrorist organisations, which undermined the security interests of both India and the United States(PTI filed)"> <figcaption>A high-powered enquiry panel submitted its report on the activities of some organised criminal groups and terrorist organisations, which undermined the security interests of both India and the United States(PTI filed)</figcaption> <p>A high-powered enquiry panel submitted its report regarding activities that threatened the security interests of both India and the United States. The investigation was prompted by allegations of a murder plot against Khalistani terrorist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun.</p> <ul> <li>The enquiry panel was established in November 2023 after the US raised concerns about an attempted murder.</li> <li>Vikash Yadav, identified by the US, has been linked to the failed assassination attempt.</li> <li>The enquiry committee conducted thorough investigations, receiving full cooperation from US authorities.</li> <li>Legal action has been recommended against an individual involved in the plot based on criminal links discovered during the investigation.</li> <li>The committee suggested improvements in systems to enhance India’s response to such matters.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“The Committee further recommended functional improvements in systems and procedures as also initiation of steps that could strengthen India’s response capability.”</blockquote> <p>This development highlights an essential collaboration between India and the US in addressing security threats, emphasizing the importance of coordinated efforts in combating terrorism.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/centre-recommends-legal-action-against-individual-accused-of-murder-plot-by-us-101736942016845.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/centre-recommends-legal-action-against-individual-accused-of-murder-plot-by-us-101736942016845.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:33:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On SP backing AAP over Congress for Delhi election, Akhilesh Yadav says this - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Akhilesh Yadav Backs AAP Over Congress for Delhi Elections</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/PTI05-16-2024-000014A-0_1715844989480_1736941600642.jpg" alt="AAP convenor Arvind Kejriwal and Samajwadi Party chief Akhilesh Yadav at their joint press conference. (file)(HT Print)" title="AAP convenor Arvind Kejriwal and Samajwadi Party chief Akhilesh Yadav at their joint press conference. (file)(HT Print)">
<figcaption>AAP convenor Arvind Kejriwal and Samajwadi Party chief Akhilesh Yadav at their joint press conference. (file)(HT Print)</figcaption>
<p>Samajwadi Party (SP) chief Akhilesh Yadav declares support for the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) over Congress in the upcoming Delhi assembly elections, emphasizing the need to strengthen regional parties against the BJP.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The SP is prioritizing support for the strongest candidates to challenge the BJP in elections.</li>
  <li>Akhilesh Yadav advocates for unity among the INDIA bloc parties to defeat the BJP.</li>
  <li>He cites ongoing political tensions as part of the BJP's strategy against opposition leaders.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We must support whichever party is strong and in a position to give a fight to BJP... our common goal is the defeat of BJP.” - Akhilesh Yadav</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing alignment within the INDIA bloc demonstrates a strategic approach to maximizing electoral strength in regional contests.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/on-sp-backing-aap-over-congress-for-delhi-election-akhilesh-yadav-says-this-101736940157289.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/on-sp-backing-aap-over-congress-for-delhi-election-akhilesh-yadav-says-this-101736940157289.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:26:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As Meta official apologises, Nishikant Dubey says Zuckerberg remarks issue now 'closed' - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/as-meta-official-apologises-nishikant-dubey-says-zuckerberg-remarks-issue-now-closed-3356420</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/as-meta-official-apologises-nishikant-dubey-says-zuckerberg-remarks-issue-now-closed-3356420</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:19:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Commissions Three Made-In-India Frontline Naval Combatants In Major Defence Boost - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-dedicate-three-naval-ships-to-nation-in-mumbai-ins-surat-nilgiri-vaghsheer-indian-navy-9189211.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-dedicate-three-naval-ships-to-nation-in-mumbai-ins-surat-nilgiri-vaghsheer-indian-navy-9189211.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:13:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J&K Police Constable result 2024 declared - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>J&amp;K Police Constable Result 2024 Declared</h1><p><strong>Date: January 15, 2025 | Source: Greater Kashmir</strong></p><img src="https://greaterkashmir.imagibyte.sortdcdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/GdoY_e8awAAU9Qc.jpg?type=webp&amp;quality=80" alt="J&K Police Constable Result 2024" /><figcaption>Image showing the announcement of the J&K Police Constable results.</figcaption><p>The Jammu and Kashmir Services Selection Board (JKSSB) has announced the results for the J&amp;K Police Constable written examination conducted on December 1, 2024. This recruitment drive aims to fill 4,002 constable vacancies across various departments within the Jammu and Kashmir Police.</p><p>Download PDF here: <a href="https://www.greaterkashmir.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Result_Constable_15012025.pdf">Result_Constable_15012025</a></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/jammu-kashmir/jk-police-constable-result-2024-declared/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/jammu-kashmir/jk-police-constable-result-2024-declared/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kerala High Court refuses to stay exhumation of Gopan Swamy's body amid dispute over Samadhi claim - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kerala High Court refuses to stay exhumation of Gopan Swamy's body amid dispute over Samadhi claim</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> 15 Jan 2025, 11:56 am</p>
<div><figure><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justice CS Dias" width="100%" height="100%"></figure>
<figcaption>Justice CS Dias</figcaption></div>
<p>The Kerala High Court has refused to stay the exhumation of Gopan Swamy's body, which has sparked controversy after his family claimed he attained 'Samadhi' rather than dying.</p>
<ul>
<li>The court ruled that the investigation into the nature of Gopan Swamy's death should proceed.</li>
<li>Gopan Swamy's family argues that exhumation would violate their religious beliefs.</li>
<li>Justice CS Dias questioned the unregistered nature of Gopan Swamy's death and called for a death certificate.</li>
<li>The police have the authority to investigate under the Kerala Police Act.</li>
<li>The family plans to challenge the exhumation order based on religious rights and procedural violations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Produce the death certificate and I will accept your contention. Why are you apprehensive? You tell me, how did he die?" - Justice CS Dias</blockquote>
<p>The matter will be revisited in court next week.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/kerala-high-court-refuses-stay-exhumation-gopan-swamy-body-samadhi-claim</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/kerala-high-court-refuses-stay-exhumation-gopan-swamy-body-samadhi-claim</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:56:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The ‘Steve Jobs wish’ behind wife Laurene Powell Jobs attending Kumbh Mela - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The ‘Steve Jobs Wish’ Behind Laurene Powell Jobs' Attendance at Kumbh Mela</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Laurene Powell Jobs, the widow of Steve Jobs, attended the Kumbh Mela, reflecting on her late husband's influence and vision.</p><ul><li>Laurene's presence at Kumbh Mela highlights her spiritual beliefs and commitment to social issues.</li><li>She expressed a hope that her attendance would motivate young people towards service and community.</li><li>The event is one of the largest religious gatherings in the world, attracting millions.</li></ul><blockquote>“I hope my participation encourages youth to engage more in community service.”</blockquote><p>This event marks a unique intersection of technology, spirituality, and community service.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/the-steve-jobs-wish-behind-wife-laurene-powell-jobs-attending-kumbh-mela/articleshow/117267317.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/the-steve-jobs-wish-behind-wife-laurene-powell-jobs-attending-kumbh-mela/articleshow/117267317.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025 Live: 21-member foreign delegation to take holy dip in Triveni Sangam on Jan 16 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxPaDdLWnF1aS1GcFNjR2hhZ3JZSDFPSmdzUzlEazhpTTFRQkdQdlh0NC1WY1RhaHM5RjZlWXNTbW81NUw4LXNHbTJmU2x4bENOREZ1ZmFfYmt0NTYxUnJORGxqc3JVelN0NWc3NDF5eXVIMzZ5QjN5NVFTUGI4c1k0SDFEZm01MDlRVU1ISTZsLWphN2EwVE1SWmE0YVFkUjZkaHFqVHlNd1FOSXFPb0pFbEMxTVBNakZ5ZnJuNHNWZW9oakx4UzBxNXFZWHJEbHZVUzJyR2ppeTR4aHhMQVF1ZXR3RUJNSlozVk1MUlhSc05xTlhHc1BaOG8zLXZHWjVDZjd3adIBigJBVV95cUxObS1mSldZdVB2MGEzclpkeFJpUnROYXp3TXRQVFJyaEhDM3FQNko0NVZhY1ZLYnhwQjhtRWs1N1g4YV9CQjVhLVZZT0dTQnZzdnVucG5rQmVHdVdvdVpFam5saFUyTWhHODNxc1VwdDJDZ0xtbVEzd3RkZlpydGpnWXlxSW1ncDhfVVU0b2JIdjB3QUFxcE9VVTVvS3hrOHdZSS1lUFJldVE3a1NQZU1md3BubWFPd09LQThTUDh6Z3lscFFQRlMzY2dRaFNSdkMwa1NQMGhRczh2WW8wa1NfTGFxTkxDdHREWWxoa0pYS1plcUJvS2hxSEp4LS1Bc3VmQXA4dWlFS0U2QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxPaDdLWnF1aS1GcFNjR2hhZ3JZSDFPSmdzUzlEazhpTTFRQkdQdlh0NC1WY1RhaHM5RjZlWXNTbW81NUw4LXNHbTJmU2x4bENOREZ1ZmFfYmt0NTYxUnJORGxqc3JVelN0NWc3NDF5eXVIMzZ5QjN5NVFTUGI4c1k0SDFEZm01MDlRVU1ISTZsLWphN2EwVE1SWmE0YVFkUjZkaHFqVHlNd1FOSXFPb0pFbEMxTVBNakZ5ZnJuNHNWZW9oakx4UzBxNXFZWHJEbHZVUzJyR2ppeTR4aHhMQVF1ZXR3RUJNSlozVk1MUlhSc05xTlhHc1BaOG8zLXZHWjVDZjd3adIBigJBVV95cUxObS1mSldZdVB2MGEzclpkeFJpUnROYXp3TXRQVFJyaEhDM3FQNko0NVZhY1ZLYnhwQjhtRWs1N1g4YV9CQjVhLVZZT0dTQnZzdnVucG5rQmVHdVdvdVpFam5saFUyTWhHODNxc1VwdDJDZ0xtbVEzd3RkZlpydGpnWXlxSW1ncDhfVVU0b2JIdjB3QUFxcE9VVTVvS3hrOHdZSS1lUFJldVE3a1NQZU1md3BubWFPd09LQThTUDh6Z3lscFFQRlMzY2dRaFNSdkMwa1NQMGhRczh2WW8wa1NfTGFxTkxDdHREWWxoa0pYS1plcUJvS2hxSEp4LS1Bc3VmQXA4dWlFS0U2QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:54:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JK Police Constable Result 2025 out @ jkssb.nic.in, direct link here - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JK Police Constable Result 2025 Released</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250115113821_JK-Police-Result-2025.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="JK Police Result 2025" title="JK Police Result 2025" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>JK Police Result 2025</figcaption>
<p>The Jammu and Kashmir Services Selection Board (JKSSB) has officially released the JK Police Constable Result 2025. Candidates who took the written examination can now access their results on the official website, jkssb.nic.in.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The JK Police Constable exam was conducted on December 1, 8, and 22, 2024.</li>
  <li>The examination format was offline and comprised 100 multiple-choice questions.</li>
  <li>Candidates had a total of 2 hours to complete the exam.</li>
  <li>The exam evaluated general knowledge, aptitude, and job-specific skills.</li>
  <li>Each correct answer earned 1 mark, while incorrect ones incurred a 0.25 mark penalty.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Candidates who appeared for the written examination can now access their results.”</blockquote>
<p>This release is a significant milestone for candidates awaiting their results, and they are encouraged to check the official website for further details.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/education/jk-police-constable-result-2025-out-jkssb-nic-in-direct-link-here-article-12911498.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/education/jk-police-constable-result-2025-out-jkssb-nic-in-direct-link-here-article-12911498.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:40:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cold wave intensifies in Kashmir - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxPWE9Tb3ZldUZaSl9JSUlhZW13UnFacTRTN29iU2xzOEthMm5Jb0NsZDVPZ24tNUk4TjcwYUNwVHY0TjZGNFBlaHpxMExTZXFDdWc0MEwzNWRhTWFnX0lkbVItNzU3aS1telc2YmZYVnBab2JEeWVPNGN1bF8zMktzZmR4bExIYzTSAYoBQVVfeXFMTjhjZ1FtOHJkYndWWlBPczFqNmZKMmdySmcwVW5lWEN5OFoxeFNyYU5tSFljUG5ZQ2hMMlllOWRjeV9PdzVqR2JkemxST0pXM3RCMHNacEduWmZGQ3psdDZZMm5OZnpNckVrdFFIOE9CM1FmbEg3OXl3V0dOVlNpbHh2VGRfRy1zZ053?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxPWE9Tb3ZldUZaSl9JSUlhZW13UnFacTRTN29iU2xzOEthMm5Jb0NsZDVPZ24tNUk4TjcwYUNwVHY0TjZGNFBlaHpxMExTZXFDdWc0MEwzNWRhTWFnX0lkbVItNzU3aS1telc2YmZYVnBab2JEeWVPNGN1bF8zMktzZmR4bExIYzTSAYoBQVVfeXFMTjhjZ1FtOHJkYndWWlBPczFqNmZKMmdySmcwVW5lWEN5OFoxeFNyYU5tSFljUG5ZQ2hMMlllOWRjeV9PdzVqR2JkemxST0pXM3RCMHNacEduWmZGQ3psdDZZMm5OZnpNckVrdFFIOE9CM1FmbEg3OXl3V0dOVlNpbHh2VGRfRy1zZ053?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:40:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka High Court Lifts Stay On Lokayukta Probe In MUDA Scam Case Against Siddaramaiah - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka High Court Lifts Stay On Lokayukta Probe In MUDA Scam Case Against Siddaramaiah</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Karnataka Chief Minister Siddaramaiah. (PTI file photo)" title="Karnataka Chief Minister Siddaramaiah. (PTI file photo)"><figcaption>Karnataka Chief Minister Siddaramaiah. (PTI file photo)</figcaption></figure><p>The Karnataka High Court has lifted the stay on the Lokayukta investigation into the MUDA scam case involving Chief Minister Siddaramaiah and has directed the investigation to continue.</p><ul><li>The court requested a report from the Lokayukta by January 27.</li><li>All documents collected so far must be submitted by tomorrow.</li><li>The case involves allegations against Siddaramaiah and his family.</li><li>The investigation is to be overseen by the IG of Police of Lokayukta.</li></ul><blockquote>“Lokayukta to place on record the details of investigation conducted till today. The investigation by Lokayukta shall continue.” - Justice M Nagaprasanna</blockquote><p>The court's decision is aimed at ensuring a fair and independent investigation into the alleged corruption case.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/karnataka-high-court-lifts-stay-on-lokayukta-probe-in-muda-scam-case-siddaramaiah-congress-bjp-latest-updates-9189354.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/karnataka-high-court-lifts-stay-on-lokayukta-probe-in-muda-scam-case-siddaramaiah-congress-bjp-latest-updates-9189354.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:37:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet IITian Abhay Singh alias ‘Engineer Baba’, who is grabbing limelight at Mahakumbh - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meet IITian Abhay Singh alias ‘Engineer Baba’, who is grabbing limelight at Mahakumbh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Baba_Abhay_Singh_1736938892580_1736938892848.png" alt="Abhay Singh alias 'Engineer Baba' has grabbed the spotlight during the ongoing Mahakumbh." title="Abhay Singh alias 'Engineer Baba' has grabbed the spotlight during the ongoing Mahakumbh."><figcaption>Abhay Singh alias 'Engineer Baba' has grabbed the spotlight during the ongoing Mahakumbh.(ANI/X)</figcaption></figure><p>The Mahakumbh 2025 is currently attracting millions of devotees, and among them is ‘Engineer Baba’, a notable figure known for making spiritual concepts accessible through engineering principles.</p><ul><li>Abhay Singh is a former aerospace engineering student from IIT Bombay.</li><li>He engages devotees with diagrams and visual presentations to explain spirituality.</li><li>He has a quest for knowledge that led him to explore the significance of Sanskrit and the workings of the mind.</li><li>Around 3.5 crore devotees joined the Mahakumbh, especially on the auspicious day of 'Makar Sankranti.'</li></ul><blockquote>“Science helps explain the physical world but its deeper study inevitably leads one towards spirituality. A true understanding of life ultimately brings one closer to spirituality.” - Abhay Singh</blockquote><p>The Mahakumbh serves as a blending of modern intellect and traditional spirit, promoting the importance of spirituality among youth and professionals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/meet-iitian-abhay-singh-alias-engineer-baba-who-is-grabbing-limelight-at-mahakumbh-101736938897278.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/meet-iitian-abhay-singh-alias-engineer-baba-who-is-grabbing-limelight-at-mahakumbh-101736938897278.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:32:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MHA nod to prosecute Arvind Kejriwal: What next for AAP chief? - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/mha-nod-to-prosecute-arvind-kejriwal-what-next-for-aap-chief-12911413.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/mha-nod-to-prosecute-arvind-kejriwal-what-next-for-aap-chief-12911413.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:23:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who is Harsha Richhariya? The viral ‘beautiful sadhvi’ of Maha Kumbh 2025 - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxPNGJqVFlnMmNFVUlWMjdrRGJEUlhyc2Q3V1RJTWRDYUMwTzA1alJJbHU2VEF1RjZrRF9nLU1jYXFldFFBS0FTNXpkY0FRMnQ5a3Y2RlYtSERQUkdhNklLMnRjZW8zaldORnBwY2VDSXZVU2NWdXlCUnpTSXNpUnB2b2JUN09jRnpjQkhMQU9NNjhDbWJScVQ2Ukg2SktRdk5EWk5FVHdyOHQ2cHZ5MGx1bmlJaE5CWjdnWW1HOEQ2UmFqWExuNnE1bnloWjBaNG1zdEJjVTJxT1RGQkVra3AtQnNzVVNSUdIB6wFBVV95cUxOcjFjdDV3TzFEYmhBNjFwR2xUc0pTRnZvaGRrc01aZjBoSmtCeDIyMnEzQ2JXSGhmWjQtMnF2dm9fdTM4UWt6UnV1aC1jdV91c3lhUnpWWXFkM2tvbjNGekNSWW9KeFlRSUFuajBxNnpKam5QaXl4OElzbGNMa0lWcGlFQ0E1T1V2djJ3UWJiZVN4aU8zODJ3eE1BYzBCRllXMldON29lOHl6NGtZUnVIc3ZUNzJ6MHZ2TzdHTnV3MEFCQ0h3a3ZjTEZqd2hJemk0azVfa2FaNEtNd3lybGhwWnA1RFJ0bmN1SEEw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxPNGJqVFlnMmNFVUlWMjdrRGJEUlhyc2Q3V1RJTWRDYUMwTzA1alJJbHU2VEF1RjZrRF9nLU1jYXFldFFBS0FTNXpkY0FRMnQ5a3Y2RlYtSERQUkdhNklLMnRjZW8zaldORnBwY2VDSXZVU2NWdXlCUnpTSXNpUnB2b2JUN09jRnpjQkhMQU9NNjhDbWJScVQ2Ukg2SktRdk5EWk5FVHdyOHQ2cHZ5MGx1bmlJaE5CWjdnWW1HOEQ2UmFqWExuNnE1bnloWjBaNG1zdEJjVTJxT1RGQkVra3AtQnNzVVNSUdIB6wFBVV95cUxOcjFjdDV3TzFEYmhBNjFwR2xUc0pTRnZvaGRrc01aZjBoSmtCeDIyMnEzQ2JXSGhmWjQtMnF2dm9fdTM4UWt6UnV1aC1jdV91c3lhUnpWWXFkM2tvbjNGekNSWW9KeFlRSUFuajBxNnpKam5QaXl4OElzbGNMa0lWcGlFQ0E1T1V2djJ3UWJiZVN4aU8zODJ3eE1BYzBCRllXMldON29lOHl6NGtZUnVIc3ZUNzJ6MHZ2TzdHTnV3MEFCQ0h3a3ZjTEZqd2hJemk0azVfa2FaNEtNd3lybGhwWnA1RFJ0bmN1SEEw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:18:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ED arrests ex-Chhattisgarh excise minister Kawasi Lakhma in liquor scam - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ED Arrests Former Chhattisgarh Minister Kawasi Lakhma in Liquor Scam</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/kawasi_lakhma_1736940415794_1736940434403.jfif" alt="Congress MLA Kawasi Lakhma.(X/@Kawasilakhma)" title="Congress MLA Kawasi Lakhma.(X/@Kawasilakhma)"><figcaption>Congress MLA Kawasi Lakhma.(X/@Kawasilakhma)</figcaption><p>The Enforcement Directorate (ED) has arrested former Chhattisgarh excise minister Kawasi Lakhma in connection with a liquor scam involving approximately ₹2,161 crore.</p><ul><li>Lakhma purportedly received substantial monthly cash payments from the proceeds of the alleged liquor scam.</li><li>The scam was said to take place between 2019 and 2022, involving illegal commissions and bribes collected from distillers.</li><li>Illegal sales of country liquor through state-run outlets contributed to the syndicate's profits.</li><li>Multiple search operations were conducted by the ED across Raipur, Dhamtari, and Sukma districts.</li><li>Evidence supporting charges against Lakhma and others has led to five arrests and attachments of ₹205 crore.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kawasi Lakhma was the main recipient of proceeds of crime in cash during his regime as excise minister.”</blockquote><p>The ongoing investigations have revealed a broader scheme involving multiple individuals and state institutions, reflecting significant corruption and misuse of public resources.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ed-arrests-ex-chhattisgarh-excise-minister-kawasi-lakhma-in-liquor-scam-101736939254125.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ed-arrests-ex-chhattisgarh-excise-minister-kawasi-lakhma-in-liquor-scam-101736939254125.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:08:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>