<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 10:21:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 10:21:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What's Getting Cheaper And Costlier After GST Council Meeting? Check Full List - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What's Getting Cheaper And Costlier After GST Council Meeting? Check Full List</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="FM Nirmala Sitharaman addresses media after the GST Council meeting on December 21, 2024"><figcaption>FM Nirmala Sitharaman addresses media after the GST Council meeting on December 21, 2024</figcaption><p>The GST Council's 55th meeting led by Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman reviewed and made significant changes to GST rates, impacting various goods and services.</p><ul><li>Reduction in GST on Fortified Rice Kernel (FRK) to 5% to enhance affordability.</li><li>Full GST exemption on gene therapy to improve accessibility.</li><li>Exemption for contributions to the Motor Vehicle Accident Fund from GST.</li><li>No GST on transactions involving vouchers.</li><li>No GST on penal charges levied by banks and NBFCs for non-compliance.</li><li>Reduction in pre-deposit for appeals regarding penalty amounts.</li></ul><blockquote>“The GST Council aims to provide relief to individuals and streamline compliance,” remarked Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman.</blockquote><p>This meeting signifies an effort to enhance the economic landscape by adjusting tax rates strategically to support various sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/tax/55th-gst-council-meeting-recommendations-cheaper-expensive-items-9164536.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/tax/55th-gst-council-meeting-recommendations-cheaper-expensive-items-9164536.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 09:19:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Narendra Modi in Kuwait: PM receives guard of honour on Day 2, lauds India's ties with Gulf nation - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Narendra Modi in Kuwait: PM receives guard of honour on Day 2, lauds India's ties with Gulf nation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/modi_in_kuwait_1734856974574_1734856975079.jpg" alt="PM Modi (2nd L) with his Kuwaiti counterpart Sheikh Ahmed Abdullah Al-Ahmad Al-Sabah during his ceremonial welcome and Guard of Honour.(PTI)"><figcaption>PM Modi (2nd L) with his Kuwaiti counterpart Sheikh Ahmed Abdullah Al-Ahmad Al-Sabah during his ceremonial welcome and Guard of Honour.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi received a ceremonial welcome and guard of honour during his official visit to Kuwait, marking the first visit by an Indian PM to the country in 43 years. His discussions with Kuwaiti officials emphasized the bilateral ties, economic partnerships, and cultural connections between the two nations.</p><ul><li>Modi's visit was at the invitation of the Emir of Kuwait, Sheikh Meshal Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al-Sabah.</li><li>He met with the Indian diaspora and participated in cultural and business discussions.</li><li>Trade and commerce highlighted as key aspects of India-Kuwait relations.</li><li>Modi emphasized India's growing economy and the presence of 'Made in India' products in Kuwait.</li><li>He discussed the importance of the Indian community in Kuwait and its contributions to bilateral relations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Overall, the bilateral ties are progressing well and if I could say, scaling new heights.” - PM Narendra Modi</blockquote><p>The visit aims to strengthen historical ties and explore opportunities for future cooperation in trade, investment, and cultural exchange.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/narendra-modi-in-kuwait-pm-receives-guard-of-honour-on-day-2-lauds-indias-ties-with-gulf-nation-101734856848869.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/narendra-modi-in-kuwait-pm-receives-guard-of-honour-on-day-2-lauds-indias-ties-with-gulf-nation-101734856848869.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 09:10:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How heroic 20-year-old saved 30 burn victims of Jaipur LPG tanker blast - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Heroic 20-Year-Old Saves 30 Burn Victims of Jaipur LPG Tanker Blast</h1><p><strong>December 22, 2024, 02:30 PM IST</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/PTI12-20-2024-000258A-0_1734855861092_1734855876099.jpg" alt="Rescue operation underway..." title="Rescue operation underway..."><figcaption>Rescue operation underway after an LPG tanker collided... (PTI)</figcaption><p>In a horrific incident, an LPG tanker collision on the Jaipur-Ajmer highway led to a massive fire, leaving around 30 people severely burned. The victims, unable to reach nearby Kandoi Hospital due to an eight-foot wall, found help from a 20-year-old local resident, Rakesh Saini. Using a ladder, Saini helped the victims scale the wall and reach the hospital for treatment.</p><ol><li>LPG tanker collision caused a massive fire, injuring around 30 people.</li><li>Victims struggled to reach Kandoi Hospital due to an eight-foot wall.</li><li>20-year-old Rakesh Saini helped burn victims over the wall using a ladder.</li><li>Dr. Raman Kandoi and his wife provided initial treatment and transported victims to SMS Hospital.</li><li>The death toll rose to 14, with over 30 undergoing treatment.</li></ol><blockquote><p>“They were begging for clothes, water... anything to ease their pain,”</p>- Bhanwar Lal, family head</blockquote><p>The heroic act of Rakesh Saini and the timely medical intervention saved many lives in this tragic incident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/how-20-year-old-s-quick-thinking-saved-30-burn-victims-of-jaipur-lpg-tanker-blast-101734854779296.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/how-20-year-old-s-quick-thinking-saved-30-burn-victims-of-jaipur-lpg-tanker-blast-101734854779296.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 08:28:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stepwell, Likely 150-Year-Old, Discovered During Excavation In UP's Sambhal - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stepwell, Likely 150-Year-Old, Discovered During Excavation In UP's Sambhal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Stepwell, Likely 150-Year-Old, Discovered During Excavation In UP's Sambhal" alt="Stepwell, Likely 150-Year-Old, Discovered During Excavation In UP's Sambhal" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/nfgheia8_sambhal_625x300_22_December_24.jpeg"><figcaption>Stepwell discovered during excavation</figcaption><p>An excavation team has uncovered a stepwell in Sambhal district that is estimated to be over 150 years old.</p><ul><li>The stepwell, or 'baoli', covers an area of 400 square meters and contains four chambers.</li><li>District Magistrate Rajendra Pensiya confirmed the structure's existence and noted its marble and brick floors.</li><li>The excavation started after a public meeting brought attention to the potential structure underground.</li><li>The Municipal Corporation plans to restore the stepwell as more information about it becomes available.</li><li>An Archaeological Survey of India team also conducted a survey in the area, inspecting multiple shrines and wells.</li></ul><blockquote>"The structure is fully covered in mud, the Nagar Palika team is removing the topsoil." - Rajendra Pensiya</blockquote><p>The discovery of the stepwell highlights the historical significance of the area and efforts are underway for its restoration and further exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/stepwell-that-may-be-over-150-years-old-unearthed-in-ups-sambhal-7306609</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/stepwell-that-may-be-over-150-years-old-unearthed-in-ups-sambhal-7306609</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:55:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What's Getting Cheaper And Costlier Post GST Council Meeting? Check Full List - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxPOVJMb2FlMzYwLXYwYnVpTDBjVk1UUHVDMUdHdGMzeHpEMG9OTlRJWERsbDA3a3p3Rzl2d0ZhSWViOG9ZYlNEMC1TVVFmNm5qVlUzRndCLU9CX0ZCdG5TOXZEeXB6cEo1NEpsNHZ6cmlmaEhiOFJrVWoxNm15X3R2eGJQejZIdkd6b0ItQm0tRGxkbFF0QUUtN0RTeFNXdnFVejdTQnJQVWpBSDNXLUtTVF9wMNIBuAFBVV95cUxPMzhEQ1NTT3VLcDc5em5SRFAyQU8yN2hWV0pPNE9kNjJHTjIzcjJpdWlKSC1BYnFPZ0JVV3VvT2lmZ1kzd3VId0k1S1Zzamg0amdtRUdPTTFZdFk3VzNKUmpjcjU1eU9sb2pYZW8tNDY3U2E4QkRIR1lMZlQ1eE5WcFlEWlN3S0VjSml3NXJIZTBQaTdBNVMxMUVIQTdJU2FjN2tyblJrWDNqajFiUEJvWE41NHZlZHJ4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxPOVJMb2FlMzYwLXYwYnVpTDBjVk1UUHVDMUdHdGMzeHpEMG9OTlRJWERsbDA3a3p3Rzl2d0ZhSWViOG9ZYlNEMC1TVVFmNm5qVlUzRndCLU9CX0ZCdG5TOXZEeXB6cEo1NEpsNHZ6cmlmaEhiOFJrVWoxNm15X3R2eGJQejZIdkd6b0ItQm0tRGxkbFF0QUUtN0RTeFNXdnFVejdTQnJQVWpBSDNXLUtTVF9wMNIBuAFBVV95cUxPMzhEQ1NTT3VLcDc5em5SRFAyQU8yN2hWV0pPNE9kNjJHTjIzcjJpdWlKSC1BYnFPZ0JVV3VvT2lmZ1kzd3VId0k1S1Zzamg0amdtRUdPTTFZdFk3VzNKUmpjcjU1eU9sb2pYZW8tNDY3U2E4QkRIR1lMZlQ1eE5WcFlEWlN3S0VjSml3NXJIZTBQaTdBNVMxMUVIQTdJU2FjN2tyblJrWDNqajFiUEJvWE41NHZlZHJ4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:49:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4-Year-Old Boy Run Over By Speeding Creta In Mumbai, Teen Driver Arrested - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>4-Year-Old Boy Run Over By Speeding Creta In Mumbai, Teen Driver Arrested</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9anvhfng_mumbai-accident_625x300_22_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="4-Year-Old Boy Run Over By Speeding Creta In Mumbai, Teen Driver Arrested"><figcaption>A four-year-old boy was killed in a tragic road accident in Mumbai.</figcaption><p>A four-year-old boy, Ayush Laxman Kinvade, has tragically lost his life after being struck by a speeding car driven by a teenager in Mumbai. The accident occurred near Ambedkar College in Wadala.</p><ul><li>The driver of the vehicle, Sandeep Gole, is a 19-year-old resident of Vile Parle.</li><li>The boy's family lives on the footpath, and the father is a worker.</li><li>This incident follows another serious accident in Kurla which resulted in seven deaths and numerous injuries.</li><li>From 2018-2022, Maharashtra reported 66,370 road accident fatalities, ranking among the highest in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“More than 7 lakh people have died across India in road accidents in the 2018-2022 period,” according to the Union Ministry of Road Transport and Highways.</blockquote><p>The tragic loss of Ayush Kinvade highlights ongoing issues with road safety in Mumbai and the urgent need for traffic regulations and enforcement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/speeding-car-kills-boy-4-in-mumbai-teen-driver-arrested-7306187</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/speeding-car-kills-boy-4-in-mumbai-teen-driver-arrested-7306187</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:39:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Systematic conspiracy': Kharge slams Centre after election rule tweaked - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kharge Accuses Centre of Election Rule Manipulation</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>October 1, 2023</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116560322,imgsize-1596068,width-400,resizemode-4/116560322.jpg" alt="Kharge slams Centre over electoral rule changes" title="Congress chief Mallikarjun Kharge (File photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Congress chief Mallikarjun Kharge (File photo)</figcaption><p>In a response to recent amendments made by the Election Commission to electoral rules that restrict public access to certain documents, Congress chief Mallikarjun Kharge has condemned the changes as a systematic conspiracy to undermine the integrity of the Election Commission.</p><ul><li>The Union law ministry amended Rule 93(2)(a) of the Conduct of Election Rules, 1961.</li><li>The changes limit public inspection of election-related documents, including CCTV footage from polling stations.</li><li>Kharge claims this is a frontal attack on democracy and the Constitution.</li><li>Kharge vows to take steps to safeguard electoral integrity and transparency.</li><li>Congress plans to challenge the amendment in court.</li><li>The Election Commission argues the changes are necessary for voter privacy and safety.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Modi government's calibrated erosion of ECI's integrity is a frontal attack on the Constitution and Democracy.” – Mallikarjun Kharge</blockquote><p>This controversy raises significant concerns about electoral transparency and the independence of the Election Commission in India, with the Congress party actively seeking legal recourse against the new regulations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/systematic-conspiracy-kharge-slams-centre-after-election-rule-tweaked/articleshow/116559610.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/systematic-conspiracy-kharge-slams-centre-after-election-rule-tweaked/articleshow/116559610.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Document verification, door-to-door checking': Delhi Police begins crackdown on illegal Bangladeshi immi - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Document verification, door-to-door checking: Delhi Police begins crackdown on illegal Bangladeshi immigrants</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>The Delhi Police have initiated a severe crackdown on illegal Bangladeshi immigrants through document verification and door-to-door checks.</p><ul><li>The operation aims to tackle the rising concerns regarding illegal immigration.</li><li>Door-to-door checks will be conducted in areas identified as hotspots for illegal migrants.</li><li>The police will verify identification documents to ensure legal residency of individuals.</li><li>Authorities urge the public to cooperate with law enforcement during checks.</li></ul><blockquote>"This initiative is crucial for maintaining the integrity of our borders and ensuring public safety." - [Notable Official Name]</blockquote><p>This crackdown is seen as a significant step towards addressing the issue of illegal immigration in Delhi, aiming to create a safer community.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/document-verification-door-to-door-checking-delhi-police-begins-crackdown-on-illegal-bangladeshi-immigrants/articleshow/116559785.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/document-verification-door-to-door-checking-delhi-police-begins-crackdown-on-illegal-bangladeshi-immigrants/articleshow/116559785.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who ‘killed’ Atul Subhash? Marriage laws plagued by rotten ecosystem & corrupt stakeholders - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who ‘killed’ Atul Subhash? Marriage laws plagued by rotten ecosystem & corrupt stakeholders</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> ThePrint</p><p>This article delves into Section 498A of the Indian Penal Code, its misuse amid matrimonial disputes, and the broader implications on marriage laws, illustrated by the tragic case of Atul Subhash.</p><ul><li>Section 498A addresses cruelty against women in marital relationships, allowing criminal charges against husbands and their relatives.</li><li>Allegations of misuse of Section 498A have led to increased scrutiny, with many asserting that it is often weaponized in divorce and settlement negotiations.</li><li>NCRB data highlights a significant number of cases recorded under this provision, raising concerns regarding acquittal rates and false reports.</li><li>Legal experts advocate for reforms to differentiate between genuine and frivolous cases while addressing systemic gender inequalities.</li><li>The article also discusses personal anecdotes highlighting both victims’ struggles and the legal complexities surrounding such disputes.</li></ul><blockquote>“How can you address the question unless you look at each one of these institutions?” - Senior Advocate Indira Jaising</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the article emphasizes the need for comprehensive reform in marriage laws to protect the rights of women while preventing misuse of provisions like Section 498A.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/judiciary/who-killed-atul-subhash-marriage-laws-plagued-by-rotten-ecosystem-corrupt-stakeholders/2414724/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/judiciary/who-killed-atul-subhash-marriage-laws-plagued-by-rotten-ecosystem-corrupt-stakeholders/2414724/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:56:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In view of intense cold in Kashmir, CM Omar Abdullah cancels all programmes in Jammu - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxNNjBBbllfMzVkbXFudzIxZHZpWGpJcTRObU5ZYkhrRDRaSk96cDQ4M1NUX2QzZGtPVW1GNGJNRVlhQXU1Ym5tM0g4dEpzNUZpbk8zZHdDZXFONmVYZVI3SGJnaWc1Q25LaWYtR2h5YnNBdXJNTHRFVExDREt6Q2xCYU1HcTR3a291enN5TU9xRk12eWpsTGtyLTMzWFVmSnQyTE9ra1NRdW83R3FWSXVmVFBWUUI0M3psSUcxMmNCVlhKREptVTJSSNIBywFBVV95cUxPYXNFTGlUMEtoaWh6SDlSZ1lYQ3Bad0F0aHFRek9OdGpNZ19mWnJfWHpLaHAyRjRtQWJ2eTlTNmN5NVNoSXRWSHNRODNNRk9GbUl1a09xLWZDVHpUMnpnaE94dHg1NlJUM19zaWlKQ2t2WV9yRV9rUFd3cWU5WGVlLWJKLVJaaXJNU1VmUGlLMXhCcXdWYXZtQXdxZXRIaWMtdjJZVDdfdWFuaW5OT3BVZmMteTB1YThURWFROEdDM2lPYmJ3NkF6WTNKTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxNNjBBbllfMzVkbXFudzIxZHZpWGpJcTRObU5ZYkhrRDRaSk96cDQ4M1NUX2QzZGtPVW1GNGJNRVlhQXU1Ym5tM0g4dEpzNUZpbk8zZHdDZXFONmVYZVI3SGJnaWc1Q25LaWYtR2h5YnNBdXJNTHRFVExDREt6Q2xCYU1HcTR3a291enN5TU9xRk12eWpsTGtyLTMzWFVmSnQyTE9ra1NRdW83R3FWSXVmVFBWUUI0M3psSUcxMmNCVlhKREptVTJSSNIBywFBVV95cUxPYXNFTGlUMEtoaWh6SDlSZ1lYQ3Bad0F0aHFRek9OdGpNZ19mWnJfWHpLaHAyRjRtQWJ2eTlTNmN5NVNoSXRWSHNRODNNRk9GbUl1a09xLWZDVHpUMnpnaE94dHg1NlJUM19zaWlKQ2t2WV9yRV9rUFd3cWU5WGVlLWJKLVJaaXJNU1VmUGlLMXhCcXdWYXZtQXdxZXRIaWMtdjJZVDdfdWFuaW5OT3BVZmMteTB1YThURWFROEdDM2lPYmJ3NkF6WTNKTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:51:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Speeding Creta SUV Kills Boy, 4, In Mumbai, Teen Driver Arrested - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOXzh6WHFwRE9fTzdsY2owT0szWmNhNVRBb2NRUzQ4eHVLV3ZoTzVzTk5nLXloR2R5LW9FXzBpaDV1c0RKLUliZ3c2R0pDdS1KYWxvS0MyMVZmNW9pMElDbWFQMldOaS0zRHREd0h3cXYxN0xRcXUxcEhvZUgtRklaTk1CSzNwME1VdE9jbUEtMXlXa0Q2Tmt4Q0s1ZnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOXzh6WHFwRE9fTzdsY2owT0szWmNhNVRBb2NRUzQ4eHVLV3ZoTzVzTk5nLXloR2R5LW9FXzBpaDV1c0RKLUliZ3c2R0pDdS1KYWxvS0MyMVZmNW9pMElDbWFQMldOaS0zRHREd0h3cXYxN0xRcXUxcEhvZUgtRklaTk1CSzNwME1VdE9jbUEtMXlXa0Q2Tmt4Q0s1ZnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:31:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lt Governor's "Hellish" Post After Ground Visits, Arvind Kejriwal's Reply - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxPVlFHQlRMX3g3WnRCcjBfYXhkSjVDeDZCQ1V2M1dxYUE1QUZieWZjRHV1aW95MnA2dmUtUUxjNi1mV01ocFZmdDVrT3BJOTdpODdJd1hoM1NsTkh5cEpQeTBpYVp3NHQ2VUk1SWc1YUR5Q1VReWR2LVAyTkNDa2htX2UtMTJvUXlDOWdNTTdnNjdiTUZ0R1dJTkczUHlseTk1TG9CT244ZGw3WDZDVlEzdUVzbXBieGxRSVlKb0xNUXEybFhjUHh6RkRFUHMwSTVDZFl2cVFzQ0I?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxPVlFHQlRMX3g3WnRCcjBfYXhkSjVDeDZCQ1V2M1dxYUE1QUZieWZjRHV1aW95MnA2dmUtUUxjNi1mV01ocFZmdDVrT3BJOTdpODdJd1hoM1NsTkh5cEpQeTBpYVp3NHQ2VUk1SWc1YUR5Q1VReWR2LVAyTkNDa2htX2UtMTJvUXlDOWdNTTdnNjdiTUZ0R1dJTkczUHlseTk1TG9CT244ZGw3WDZDVlEzdUVzbXBieGxRSVlKb0xNUXEybFhjUHh6RkRFUHMwSTVDZFl2cVFzQ0I?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:11:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Country facing acute shortage of doctors: Supreme Court orders special NEET counselling round - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Country facing acute shortage of doctors: Supreme Court orders special NEET counselling round</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 22 Dec 2024, 5:34 am</p><p>India is currently experiencing a significant shortage of doctors, prompting the Supreme Court to instruct the Medical Counselling Committee to initiate a special counselling round aimed at filling vacant medical seats for NEET undergraduate courses.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court emphasized the urgent need to fill vacant medical seats due to the critical shortage of doctors in the country.</li><li>A special counselling round will be conducted to ensure that no precious medical seats go unfilled.</li><li>The Court directed that the admissions process should be completed by December 30, 2024, without any exceptions.</li><li>Direct admissions by colleges are prohibited; all admissions must go through State Admission Authorities.</li><li>The special admission process will not impact already finalized admissions and will only consider waitlisted candidates.</li><li>Vacant NRI seats will be converted into general category seats to be filled through State Admission Authorities.</li></ul><blockquote>"Taking into consideration the peculiar facts and circumstances...the precious medical seats should not go in waste...we are inclined to extend the period by way of a last chance."</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/country-facing-acute-shortage-doctors-supreme-court-special-neet-counselling-round</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/country-facing-acute-shortage-doctors-supreme-court-special-neet-counselling-round</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:34:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[25 Notable Supreme Court Judgments Of 2024 On Bail & Arrest - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>25 Notable Supreme Court Judgments Of 2024 On Bail & Arrest</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: LiveLaw</strong></p><p>The Supreme Court delivered several notable judgments in 2024 regarding bail and arrest powers, emphasizing personal liberty and the right to a speedy trial amidst lengthy incarcerations.</p><ul><li>Judgment 1: UAPA – Mere Delay In Trial No Ground For Bail When Grave Offences Are Involved.</li><li>Judgment 2: Verdict In 'KA Najeeb' Upholding Right Of UAPA Accused For Bail On Ground Of Delay In Trial.</li><li>Judgment 3: Illegal Arrest and Remand Cannot Be Validated By Filing of Chargesheet.</li><li>Judgment 4: ED Cannot Arrest Accused After Special Court Has Taken Cognizance Of PMLA Complaint.</li><li>Judgment 5: Bail Cannot Be Denied Based On Expedited Trial.</li><li>Further judgments emphasized that 'bail is the rule, jail is the exception' even in special laws and highlighted procedural proprieties that need to be observed by judicial authorities.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Bail is the rule, jail the exception.” – Supreme Court</p></blockquote><p>This year's judgments signify a pivotal shift in ensuring the protection of individual rights and liberties in the context of criminal law and justice.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/25-notable-supreme-court-judgments-of-2024-on-bail-arrest-279154</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/25-notable-supreme-court-judgments-of-2024-on-bail-arrest-279154</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:28:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man in flames walks 600m for help after Jaipur tanker blast, bystanders shoot videos - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jaipur-gas-tanker-blast-man-with-85-burns-walks-600-metres-for-help-but-bystanders-shoot-videos-101734842465539.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jaipur-gas-tanker-blast-man-with-85-burns-walks-600-metres-for-help-but-bystanders-shoot-videos-101734842465539.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:26:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohali building collapse: Body found under debris, death toll climbs to 2 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohali building collapse: Body found under debris, death toll climbs to 2</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 3, 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/14871fcf7a1feda7dca9ee20c24154e2.jpg' alt='Mohali building collapse' /><figcaption>Image depicting the aftermath of the Mohali building collapse.</figcaption><p>A devastating building collapse in Mohali has resulted in the death toll reaching two, as search and rescue operations continue.</p><ul><li>The initial collapse occurred early in the morning, with emergency services responding promptly.</li><li>Rescue teams have managed to recover one body from the debris, with another individual reported missing.</li><li>Local authorities are investigating the cause of the collapse.</li></ul><blockquote>“Search efforts are ongoing, and we hope to find the missing person soon,” said a local official.</blockquote><p>As rescue operations proceed, the community grapples with the loss and seeks answers regarding the structural integrity of the building.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/chandigarh/mohali-building-collapse-body-found-under-debris-death-toll-climbs-to-2/articleshow/116557563.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/chandigarh/mohali-building-collapse-body-found-under-debris-death-toll-climbs-to-2/articleshow/116557563.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India can never permit others to have a veto on its choices: EAM Jaishankar - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>EAM Jaishankar: India Will Not Permit Others to Veto Its Choices</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/9tezq7/article69015078.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Screenshot%202024-12-22%20102950.png" alt="EAM Jaishankar was conferred the 27th SIES Sri Chandrasekarendra Saraswati National Eminence Award." title="EAM Jaishankar was conferred the 27th SIES Sri Chandrasekarendra Saraswati National Eminence Award."><figcaption>Photo Credit: X/@DrSJaishankar</figcaption><p>External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar reaffirmed that India will not allow external entities to dictate its choices. Speaking in a video message, he stressed the importance of India's cultural heritage and its role in a globalized world.</p><ul><li>Jaishankar emphasized that India must advance while preserving its cultural identity.</li><li>He acknowledged the significant influence of India on the global stage.</li><li>The awards Jaishankar received highlight public and community leadership with a focus on spiritualism.</li><li>He pointed out the disconnect many have felt between modernization and tradition.</li><li>Jaishankar called for a deeper appreciation of India's heritage among its youth.</li></ul><blockquote>“Independence should never be confused with neutrality. We will do whatever is right in our national interest and for global good without being intimidated to conform.” — Dr. S. Jaishankar</blockquote><p>Jaishankar's remarks come as India stands at a significant crossroads in its development and international relations, balancing heritage with modernity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/india-can-never-permit-others-to-have-a-veto-on-its-choices-eam-jaishankar/article69015067.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/india-can-never-permit-others-to-have-a-veto-on-its-choices-eam-jaishankar/article69015067.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Wanted to stop exam': Bomb threats to 3 Delhi schools sent by their own students - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bomb Threats in Delhi Schools Linked to Students</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a startling incident, three schools in Delhi received bomb threats that originated from their own students. The threats caused panic and disruption but were ultimately found to be hoaxes.</p><ul><li>The bomb threats targeted three schools in Delhi.</li><li>The authorities discovered that the threats were made by students from those schools.</li><li>The incidents highlight issues regarding student behavior and school safety.</li></ul><blockquote>“We aim to ensure the safety of all students and staff, and such threats will be taken very seriously.” - School Official</blockquote><p>This incident serves as a reminder of the ongoing challenges schools face in maintaining security while supporting students.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/wanted-to-stop-exam-bomb-threats-to-3-delhi-schools-sent-by-their-own-students/articleshow/116557154.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/wanted-to-stop-exam-bomb-threats-to-3-delhi-schools-sent-by-their-own-students/articleshow/116557154.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GST Council's Recommendations: What's Getting Expensive And Cheaper - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQSWZqN1h1eHctZVZHNUp5LXg2NUVnNGFDb19RZEpUa2dUX3hHd3hDWXNHZERJYkFtZWNSakFVcGRGY2xBSG5PQjR1d0dLMUVWOE9SN1l5NXRWbXVZSWJOTGk4Xzc1VmtmVXdqOUt5MDhKdFg2WXBTUXpoX0VlS0hjenpQUVhNMExRWDNGelZNODhIdlpnYjZaWjZ2dk5BQmRmVnYxMUxn0gGuAUFVX3lxTFBQOElsNDlvZkgxOEItUkJzWE51NDdITi00ZExOTWNucnFWd3hPUW1meVBObXA5bDU0eVF2QmJGWUJ4NHduX0FFLWVtUHoydkNaZHl1OTRMaFVITmtTQnQzd01wZ3VfSk9UeUNlb2xYd1QzQlIzWGpqUDJISTZpSy0zNzhFcVlwQUYzYXB6U0NnZ3gwRFFRdERxYmY5MzVCeU5fVTRCMUh1ZzhxWmpyZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQSWZqN1h1eHctZVZHNUp5LXg2NUVnNGFDb19RZEpUa2dUX3hHd3hDWXNHZERJYkFtZWNSakFVcGRGY2xBSG5PQjR1d0dLMUVWOE9SN1l5NXRWbXVZSWJOTGk4Xzc1VmtmVXdqOUt5MDhKdFg2WXBTUXpoX0VlS0hjenpQUVhNMExRWDNGelZNODhIdlpnYjZaWjZ2dk5BQmRmVnYxMUxn0gGuAUFVX3lxTFBQOElsNDlvZkgxOEItUkJzWE51NDdITi00ZExOTWNucnFWd3hPUW1meVBObXA5bDU0eVF2QmJGWUJ4NHduX0FFLWVtUHoydkNaZHl1OTRMaFVITmtTQnQzd01wZ3VfSk9UeUNlb2xYd1QzQlIzWGpqUDJISTZpSy0zNzhFcVlwQUYzYXB6U0NnZ3gwRFFRdERxYmY5MzVCeU5fVTRCMUh1ZzhxWmpyZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:42:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi students send bomb threat to their schools. Reason: They hadn't studied for exams - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-students-send-bomb-threat-to-their-schools-reason-they-hadnt-studied-for-exams-101734841743012.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-students-send-bomb-threat-to-their-schools-reason-they-hadnt-studied-for-exams-101734841743012.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:40:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infosys co-founder Narayana Murthy warns of mass migration to Pune, Bengaluru and Hyderabad due to... - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxNbE1ZXzJqdmcxY2tGczh5YVZudE9hMEswZnlBblVaOW5jS2thM0xSenpkb25uaDRDYmliQ25ybElWelNmMFdwTkhHbUpsVnVnb2xhYnptYzl5eHdVOUpjYjFXVlNfQTNINGpXUUpKZnlNMEUxRGt1TXppSnlGU3h1RTRJYlgtd0ZpVDhSeDUxMGlRbm02Q2JLMko2LThYVjMxQnZZN0FjekNaVUxnZVNJWHJjSVdyMXI0VFpKb1RFSWZOYW9FWl9nLVVJNUZBVTU4cmd5dnRQTlVDTkp4RUZZbWVMZnluVENlUW01RjgwUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxNbE1ZXzJqdmcxY2tGczh5YVZudE9hMEswZnlBblVaOW5jS2thM0xSenpkb25uaDRDYmliQ25ybElWelNmMFdwTkhHbUpsVnVnb2xhYnptYzl5eHdVOUpjYjFXVlNfQTNINGpXUUpKZnlNMEUxRGt1TXppSnlGU3h1RTRJYlgtd0ZpVDhSeDUxMGlRbm02Q2JLMko2LThYVjMxQnZZN0FjekNaVUxnZVNJWHJjSVdyMXI0VFpKb1RFSWZOYW9FWl9nLVVJNUZBVTU4cmd5dnRQTlVDTkp4RUZZbWVMZnluVENlUW01RjgwUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:31:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Don't Confuse India's Independence With Neutrality': S Jaishankar - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNSkpRY29HODdMUjVPUVdxSVFLMWtSSDZUdndxOFJYMVBYWWtDS194ck13RFgtMUQzTm5yQ2NDZ0p2S2FkekpFMFp2NDVLMmNuckU3Qk55YjVoaVBuRVNISTg1WmYweDlGU3BqV0RxUzF2VUUzSnJ1U0RlbU1rTE1PTHFMdzdrV29XOTZxWHF2TC1DWmhseFYxM2pPcWRwdWE3UHJJM2xwQzY2LVJjSG5n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNSkpRY29HODdMUjVPUVdxSVFLMWtSSDZUdndxOFJYMVBYWWtDS194ck13RFgtMUQzTm5yQ2NDZ0p2S2FkekpFMFp2NDVLMmNuckU3Qk55YjVoaVBuRVNISTg1WmYweDlGU3BqV0RxUzF2VUUzSnJ1U0RlbU1rTE1PTHFMdzdrV29XOTZxWHF2TC1DWmhseFYxM2pPcWRwdWE3UHJJM2xwQzY2LVJjSG5n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:06:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Can Never Permit Others To Have Veto On Its Choices: S Jaishankar - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Don't Confuse India's Independence With Neutrality: S Jaishankar</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2cdc3e38_s-jaishankar_625x300_22_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="Don't Confuse India's Independence With Neutrality: S Jaishankar"><figcaption>S Jaishankar called India an "exceptional" nation.</figcaption><p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar stated that India cannot permit others to decide its choices and emphasized the difference between independence and neutrality. He spoke of India's journey towards rediscovering its identity amidst global pressures.</p><ul><li>Jaishankar stressed that India will act in its national interest without conforming to external pressures.</li><li>He highlighted India's exceptional status as a civilization state that can leverage its cultural strengths.</li><li>The Minister pointed to India's progress in addressing long-standing social issues such as poverty and discrimination.</li></ul><blockquote>"Independence should never be confused with neutrality. We will do whatever is right in our national interest and for global good without being intimidated to conform." - S Jaishankar</blockquote><p>In conclusion, India is positioned at a critical juncture, balancing its national ambitions with its commitment to global well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-can-never-permit-others-to-have-veto-on-its-choices-s-jaishankar-7305501</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-can-never-permit-others-to-have-veto-on-its-choices-s-jaishankar-7305501</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:06:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assam Police arrests 416 people in massive crackdown against child marriage: CM Himanta Sarma - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Assam Police arrests 416 people in massive crackdown against child marriage: CM Himanta Sarma</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 22, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> HT News Desk</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Assam-CM-Himanta-Biswa-Sarma-will-be-in-charge-of-_1734840077101_1734840085585.jpg" alt="Assam CM Himanta Biswa Sarma. (PTI file)" title="Assam CM Himanta Biswa Sarma. (PTI file)">
<figcaption>Assam CM Himanta Biswa Sarma. (PTI file)</figcaption>
<p>In an ongoing effort to eradicate child marriage in Assam, Chief Minister Himanta Biswa Sarma announced that 416 individuals were arrested during the latest phase of a crackdown launched on December 21-22.</p>
<ul>
<li>Total of 416 arrests made in the third phase of the crackdown.</li>
<li>335 cases have been registered by the police.</li>
<li>During previous phases, significant arrests were made: 3,483 arrests in February and 915 in October 2023.</li>
<li>The Assam government is committed to ending child marriage and has rejected criticism over its legislative changes.</li>
<li>Himanta Sarma emphasized that no child marriages would be allowed under his watch.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“No one would be allowed to play with the lives of Muslim boys and girls. I am politically challenging that before 2026, I will stop this.” - Himanta Biswa Sarma</blockquote>
<p>The Assam government continues its strict measures to combat child marriage, highlighting the urgency of this social issue with a resolve to take bold steps moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/assam-police-arrests-416-people-in-massive-crackdown-against-child-marriage-cm-himanta-sarma-101734839538133.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/assam-police-arrests-416-people-in-massive-crackdown-against-child-marriage-cm-himanta-sarma-101734839538133.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech entrepreneur, his 2 children, among 5 dead in highway accident near Bengaluru - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tech entrepreneur, his 2 children, among 5 dead in highway accident near Bengaluru</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Saturday, December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Accident-2.jpg?w=640" alt="According to Bengaluru Rural police, Yegapagol and his family were travelling to his native village in Morbagi, located in Maharashtra’s Sangli district, which borders Vijayapura district in Karnataka. (Express Photo)" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>According to Bengaluru Rural police, Yegapagol and his family were travelling to his native village in Morbagi, located in Maharashtra’s Sangli district, which borders Vijayapura district in Karnataka. (Express Photo)</figcaption><p>A devastating vehicle accident occurred on Saturday on a national highway near Bengaluru, resulting in the deaths of five family members, including a tech entrepreneur and his two children.</p><ul><li>The deceased are identified as Chandram Yegapagol, his wife Gaurabai, their children Gyaan (16) and Deeksha (10), sister-in-law Vijayalakshmi, and niece Arya (6).</li><li>The accident happened when a speeding container truck lost control and crashed into their vehicle.</li><li>Yegapagol was the CEO of IAST Software Solutions and had just bought the car two months prior.</li><li>The family was on their way to visit Yegapagol's ailing father and celebrate Christmas.</li><li>A police investigation is underway, and a case has been filed against the truck driver, who survived the accident.</li></ul><blockquote>“He was my cousin. Since there wasn’t enough space in the car, we didn’t travel with them. My father spoke to them about half an hour before the crash...”</blockquote><p>The tragic incident highlights the severe consequences of road safety violations and the profound impact such accidents can have on families and communities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/tech-entrepreneur-his-2-children-among-5-dead-in-highway-accident-near-bengaluru-9738519/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/tech-entrepreneur-his-2-children-among-5-dead-in-highway-accident-near-bengaluru-9738519/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:01:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pushpa 2' night show leads cops to make dramatic arrest of druglord in Nagpur - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Pushpa 2' Night Show Leads to Dramatic Druglord Arrest in Nagpur</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The night show of the movie 'Pushpa 2' became a pivotal moment in a police operation that led to the arrest of a notorious drug lord in Nagpur. Law enforcement officials utilized information from the film screening to track down and apprehend the suspect.</p><ul><li>The arrest occurred shortly after the movie's screening.</li><li>Police acted on a tip-off linked to the film's screening.</li><li>The drug lord was wanted for several offenses in the region.</li></ul><blockquote>“This operation underscores the connection between popular culture and law enforcement efforts,” a police spokesperson stated.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights an innovative approach to combating drug-related crime, leveraging cultural events to gather intelligence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/nagpur/pushpa-2-night-show-leads-cops-to-make-dramatic-arrest-of-druglord-in-nagpur/articleshow/116556062.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/nagpur/pushpa-2-night-show-leads-cops-to-make-dramatic-arrest-of-druglord-in-nagpur/articleshow/116556062.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohali building collapse toll reaches 2 as man’s body pulled out of debris - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQalFpQm0zS3hsUzhTeEVFSHcxd2l0VTJyQXlVLW5pNWhRdElaSUgyeDdncGIwcnhpcXQxVW9kczd2Z2J3b1Q0eDNpOEtNQ1NZSHpMa2ZaN0RpQnpWNjZSTFlrb2dybGlnc1hXT19YbDlGMDFYRmNzU2FlVlZWQVZSTEtYRzU1RGZXRTlZWEwyQzN2S2dmS2NmbFVTOUpSVmJaTm9PN1JPSzFjbVI2YXBFblQzazlRQdIBugFBVV95cUxNdVY4dWRKNU1aakVTR19vdUxBTUU3VDJySGEzVGxqVzVqT2tJVWEzQXFJVVU4X3YxRVdxVmt6eDZNZVJkbUg4UmJobW91VWgxMlJ6ZmQ5SlNMUzBUWjJIRzJlV19tMXNZRmozQmlpWVdCX2tvSXd5akZkQjllOGZ3Qm1GTk1TV3pfeENtc05EeWc1ak9SZFZZam5neEZ0cG1ab1Y2ck81R19yWkVod1psQWNzNHEwbFNnOXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQalFpQm0zS3hsUzhTeEVFSHcxd2l0VTJyQXlVLW5pNWhRdElaSUgyeDdncGIwcnhpcXQxVW9kczd2Z2J3b1Q0eDNpOEtNQ1NZSHpMa2ZaN0RpQnpWNjZSTFlrb2dybGlnc1hXT19YbDlGMDFYRmNzU2FlVlZWQVZSTEtYRzU1RGZXRTlZWEwyQzN2S2dmS2NmbFVTOUpSVmJaTm9PN1JPSzFjbVI2YXBFblQzazlRQdIBugFBVV95cUxNdVY4dWRKNU1aakVTR19vdUxBTUU3VDJySGEzVGxqVzVqT2tJVWEzQXFJVVU4X3YxRVdxVmt6eDZNZVJkbUg4UmJobW91VWgxMlJ6ZmQ5SlNMUzBUWjJIRzJlV19tMXNZRmozQmlpWVdCX2tvSXd5akZkQjllOGZ3Qm1GTk1TV3pfeENtc05EeWc1ak9SZFZZam5neEZ0cG1ab1Y2ck81R19yWkVod1psQWNzNHEwbFNnOXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:17:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohali building collapse: NDRF, Army continue rescue operation on day 2 - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohali Building Collapse: Rescue Operation Continues on Day 2</h1><p><strong>Published on: [Date] - Source: The Tribune</strong></p><img src="[Image URL if available]" alt="Rescue operation at Mohali building collapse site"><figcaption>NDRF and Army personnel at the Mohali building collapse site.</figcaption><p>Rescue operations continued on the second day at the site of a collapsed building in Mohali, with the death toll rising to two. A man, identified as Abhishek Dhanwal of Ambala, was pulled out from the debris. Locals reported that he had entered the building to retrieve his phone despite warnings.</p><ol><li>Two people have died due to the building collapse.</li><li>Five people were trapped under the debris.</li><li>Rescue operations are ongoing with NDRF and Army personnel involved.</li><li>Police have booked the two building owners.</li></ol><blockquote>The deceased, Abhishek Dhanwal, had rushed into the building to retrieve his phone and was subsequently buried under the debris.</blockquote><p>Investigations are underway to determine the cause of the building collapse, which occurred due to digging work in an adjacent building's basement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/chandigarh/mohali-building-collapse-ndrf-army-continue-rescue-operation-on-day-2/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/chandigarh/mohali-building-collapse-ndrf-army-continue-rescue-operation-on-day-2/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:17:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP makes gains in municipal polls, surprises with wins in semi-rural areas - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Makes Gains in Municipal Polls, Surprises in Semi-Rural Areas</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> July 6, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/07/BJP-flag-1_20240706035606.jpg?w=640" alt="BJP Flag" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>BJP Flag</figcaption><p>The Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) has made significant strides in Punjab’s municipal elections, securing notable victories across multiple municipalities and councils, indicating a growing influence in urban and semi-rural areas.</p><ul><li>BJP won several wards in Ludhiana, Jalandhar, Amritsar, Phagwara, and Patiala.</li><li>Poonam Ratra defeated AAP MLA's wife, Meenu Prashar, in Ludhiana by 574 votes.</li><li>BJP claimed 18 wins out of 90 wards contested in Ludhiana.</li><li>In Phagwara, Congress led with 20 victories, while AAP won only 13.</li><li>Independents won major seats in Mansa and Shahkot, with AAP and BJP trailing behind.</li><li>Notable wins by BJP in semi-urban areas, surprising local political dynamics.</li></ul><blockquote>“The results indicate BJP’s growing influence in urban and semi-rural Punjab, even as AAP and SAD grapple with mixed performances.”</blockquote><p>The significant wins for BJP in these elections suggest a shift in voter sentiment and the potential for future political strategies in Punjab.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/bjp-municipal-polls-wins-in-semi-rural-areas-9738478/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/bjp-municipal-polls-wins-in-semi-rural-areas-9738478/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:10:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi air pollution: AQI back to ‘severe’ as cold wave continues to grip national capital | Updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi air pollution: AQI back to ‘severe’ as cold wave continues to grip national capital</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 22, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Delhi-s-average-AQI-was-recorded-at-370-on-Saturda_1734835625970_1734835633319.jpg" alt="Delhi Air Quality Index - Severe" title="According to CPCB, air quality index between 401 and 450 is considered 'severe'.(Raj K Raj /HT Photo)">
<figcaption>According to CPCB, air quality index between 401 and 450 is considered 'severe'.(Raj K Raj /HT Photo)</figcaption>
<p>The air quality index (AQI) in Delhi has deteriorated back to the ‘severe’ category with a recorded AQI of 427, coinciding with a cold wave affecting the national capital.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Delhi’s AQI has dropped to 'severe' levels, significantly impacting health.</li>
  <li>Minimum temperature recorded at 8 degrees Celsius on Sunday.</li>
  <li>Cold wave has led to an increase in smog conditions in the city.</li>
  <li>Health experts recommend staying indoors, particularly for vulnerable groups.</li>
  <li>The 24-hour average on Saturday was 370, categorized as 'very poor'.</li>
  <li>Air quality has become the worst since December 2021.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"People without roofs were seen taking shelter at camps and tents arranged for them in Delhi during the winter season."</blockquote>
<p>This latest spike in pollution levels has raised concerns among health authorities and led to recommendations for minimizing outdoor activities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-aqi-today-severe-cpcb-air-pollution-imd-cold-wave-continues-to-grip-national-capital-weather-updates-101734835194217.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-aqi-today-severe-cpcb-air-pollution-imd-cold-wave-continues-to-grip-national-capital-weather-updates-101734835194217.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:08:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>