<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:22:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:22:04 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi shivers for third consecutive cold day; Himachal, J&K brace for fresh snowfall | Weather updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi shivers for third consecutive cold day; Himachal, J&K brace for fresh snowfall | Weather updates</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 08:14 AM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/The-average-AQI-last-year-was-209--which-was-Delhi_1735751711087_1735777101896.jpg" alt="At Safdarjung in Delhi the maximum temperature was recorded at 15 degrees Celsius, 4.3 degrees below normal, while the Palam weather station registered a maximum of 12.8 degrees Celsius, two degrees below normal. (Arvind Yadav/HT Photo)" title="At Safdarjung in Delhi the maximum temperature was recorded at 15 degrees Celsius, 4.3 degrees below normal, while the Palam weather station registered a maximum of 12.8 degrees Celsius, two degrees below normal. (Arvind Yadav/HT Photo)"><figcaption>At Safdarjung in Delhi the maximum temperature was recorded at 15 degrees Celsius, 4.3 degrees below normal, while the Palam weather station registered a maximum of 12.8 degrees Celsius, two degrees below normal. (Arvind Yadav/HT Photo)</figcaption></figure><p>Delhi has experienced its third consecutive day of cold weather, with temperatures significantly below normal. The India Meteorological Department (IMD) predicts even colder conditions ahead for the region.</p><ul><li>Minimum temperature in Delhi dropped to 7.4 degrees Celsius.</li><li>Forecast indicates incoming snowfall for Himachal Pradesh and Jammu & Kashmir.</li><li>Cold conditions affecting Rajasthan and Uttar Pradesh as well.</li><li>Fresh snowfall expected in the mid and high hill regions of Himachal Pradesh from January 2.</li><li>Kashmir preparing for light snow due to western disturbances.</li></ul><blockquote>“Smog/moderate fog at most places and dense fog at isolated places is likely in the morning,” IMD forecasts.</blockquote><p>As the cold weather persists across northern India, anticipation builds for snowfall in the hilly states, which could lead to significant changes in temperatures and daily life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-shivers-on-3rd-straight-cold-day-himachal-j-k-brace-for-fresh-snowfall-weather-updates-101735775891134.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-shivers-on-3rd-straight-cold-day-himachal-j-k-brace-for-fresh-snowfall-weather-updates-101735775891134.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:41:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After 40 years, convoy carrying gas tragedy waste heads out of Bhopal - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After 40 Years, Convoy Carries Gas Tragedy Waste Out of Bhopal</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article discusses the significant moment occurring after 40 years since the Bhopal gas tragedy, as a convoy transports hazardous waste away from the site.</p><ul><li>The convoy marks a historic step in the long-term cleanup efforts of the Bhopal gas tragedy.</li><li>This operation is part of a larger initiative to manage the waste safely and prevent potential environmental hazards.</li><li>Local authorities have been involved in planning and executing this operation to ensure safety protocols are met.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a crucial development for Bhopal's environmental recovery.”</blockquote><p>The transport of this waste is seen as an essential step toward healing and addressing the lingering effects of one of the world's worst industrial disasters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/after-40-years-convoy-carrying-gas-tragedy-waste-heads-out-of-bhopal/articleshow/116867788.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/after-40-years-convoy-carrying-gas-tragedy-waste-heads-out-of-bhopal/articleshow/116867788.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Bakery Owner Dies By Suicide Amid Divorce Dispute, Family Says 'Wife Mentally Tortured Him' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/delhi-bakery-owner-dies-by-suicide-amid-divorce-dispute-was-upset-in-last-call-to-wife-9174436.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/delhi-bakery-owner-dies-by-suicide-amid-divorce-dispute-was-upset-in-last-call-to-wife-9174436.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 21:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sandhya 70mm stampede case: NHRC serves notice to DGP and Hyd CP - 123telugu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sandhya 70mm stampede case: NHRC serves notice to DGP and Hyd CP</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 2, 2025 2:55 am IST</p><img src="https://cdn.123telugu.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Allu-Arjun-1.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333"><figcaption>Actor Allu Arjun amidst the ongoing legal situation.</figcaption><p>The sensational Sandhya 70mm stampede case is witnessing new twists and turns with each passing day. The NHRC has taken action following a complaint regarding police conduct during the stampede.</p><ul><li>The NHRC served a notice to Telangana DGP and Hyderabad Police Commissioner.</li><li>They must submit an Action Taken Report (ATR) regarding the December 4 stampede.</li><li>A woman named Revathi lost her life in the incident, and her son was severely injured.</li><li>The incident involved the police allegedly using excessive force leading to the stampede.</li></ul><blockquote>“The NHRC has issued the notice following a complaint filed by Advocate Rama Rao Immaneni.”</blockquote><p>This case continues to develop as authorities are pressed for accountability, and updates will follow.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/sandhya-70mm-stampede-case-nhrc-serves-notice-to-dgp-and-hyd-cp.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.123telugu.com/mnews/sandhya-70mm-stampede-case-nhrc-serves-notice-to-dgp-and-hyd-cp.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 21:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch Mumbai Station's Unique New Year Tradition As Trains Honk In Synchrony - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watch Mumbai Station's Unique New Year Tradition As Trains Honk In Synchrony</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Mumbai: Trains at the iconic Chhatrapati Shivaji Terminus (CST) station welcomed the New Year with synchronized honking." />
<figcaption>Mumbai: Trains at the iconic Chhatrapati Shivaji Terminus (CST) station welcomed the New Year with synchronized honking.</figcaption>
<p>The iconic Chhatrapati Shivaji Terminus (CST) station echoed with a symphony of train horns as the clock struck midnight, showcasing a unique New Year’s Eve tradition.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The synchronized honking tradition has become synonymous with CST station.</li>
  <li>Many commuters documented the event on social media, highlighting its popularity.</li>
  <li>Railway enthusiasts have coordinated this event for several years, turning it into a much-anticipated spectacle.</li>
  <li>The atmosphere is filled with joy and camaraderie, celebrating unity among diverse groups.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Sea vessels also blow their horns at full volume,” commented an observer on social media.</blockquote>
<p>This heartwarming tradition not only brings joy to the commuters but also preserves the railway heritage of Mumbai.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/mumbai-bonds-at-symphony-of-train-horns-in-this-unique-new-year-tradition-watch-9174317.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/mumbai-bonds-at-symphony-of-train-horns-in-this-unique-new-year-tradition-watch-9174317.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjabi actor-singer Diljit Dosanjh meets PM Modi: ‘A fantastic start to 2025’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Diljit Dosanjh Meets PM Modi: A Memorable Start to 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Wednesday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Modi-Dosanjh.jpg?w=640" alt="Modi Dosanjh" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Diljit Dosanjh met Prime Minister Narendra Modi. (X/diljitdosanjh)</figcaption><p>Punjabi actor-singer Diljit Dosanjh met Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Wednesday, marking a significant interaction filled with discussions about music and culture.</p><ul><li>Dosanjh described the meeting as “A fantastic start to 2025.”</li><li>The meeting included discussions on various topics, especially music.</li><li>PM Modi praised Dosanjh’s blend of talent and tradition and highlighted his journey from modest beginnings to international success.</li><li>Dosanjh expressed admiration for Modi’s sentiments toward his mother and the Ganga river.</li></ul><blockquote>“He has been winning over people,” Modi joked, referring to Diljit Dosanjh.</blockquote><p>Overall, the meeting signifies a blend of culture and recognition for Dosanjh's contributions to music and society.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/punjabi-actor-singer-diljit-dosanjh-meets-pm-modi-2025-9755327/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/punjabi-actor-singer-diljit-dosanjh-meets-pm-modi-2025-9755327/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 18:09:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Army chief calls for national consensus, ‘political government’, tones down anti-India rhetoric - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh Army Chief Advocates Political Consensus and Cools Anti-India Sentiments</h1>
<p><strong>Published: January 01, 2025 | Source: The Hindu</strong></p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/omo4t6/article69051417.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-09-24T000131Z_521340642_RC266AAI7PDQ_RTRMADP_3_BANGLADESH-POLITICS-ARMY.JPG" alt="Bangladesh’s Chief of Army Staff General Waker-uz-Zaman" title="Bangladesh’s Chief of Army Staff General Waker-uz-Zaman cooled down the heated anti-India rhetoric that was heard in the student-led “unity rally” of December 31."><figcaption>Bangladesh’s Chief of Army Staff General Waker-uz-Zaman</figcaption>
<p>In a recent interview, Bangladesh Army Chief General Waker-uz-Zaman emphasized the need for national reconciliation and a political government to ensure stability in Bangladesh. He noted that both Bangladesh and India depend on each other and highlighted the importance of a peaceful environment for development.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Army Chief called for the creation of a national consensus to restore tolerance among citizens.</li>
  <li>General Waker-uz-Zaman criticized the current interim administration's policing failures.</li>
  <li>He acknowledged the interdependence of India and Bangladesh for security and economic stability.</li>
  <li>The interview followed rising tensions regarding a call to dismantle the 1972 Constitution, which met opposition even from within the political ranks.</li>
  <li>General Waker-uz-Zaman pledged support for the interim government but stressed the need for a politically empowered government.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We want a peaceful environment. Peace and stability is very important now for Bangladesh’s economy and social development.” - General Waker-uz-Zaman</blockquote>
<p>The Army Chief's interview has raised significant discussions about the military's role in Bangladeshi politics and the future of civil governance in the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/bangladesh-army-chief-calls-for-national-consensus-political-government-tones-down-anti-india-rhetoric/article69051142.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/bangladesh-army-chief-calls-for-national-consensus-political-government-tones-down-anti-india-rhetoric/article69051142.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Engineering student nabbed for killing parents over academic, career dispute - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Engineering Student Murders Parents Over Academic Dispute</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: Jan 01, 2025 11:12 PM IST</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/01/550x309/police_Gujarat_1733658757088_1735752476346.png" alt="Police said the 25-year-old accused hid their bodies and told his relatives that his parents had gone to Bengaluru to take part in a meditation programme. (Representational photo)(HT File)" title="Police said the 25-year-old accused hid their bodies and told his relatives that his parents had gone to Bengaluru to take part in a meditation programme. (Representational photo)(HT File)"><figcaption>Police said the 25-year-old accused hid their bodies and told his relatives that his parents had gone to Bengaluru to take part in a meditation programme. (Representational photo)(HT File)</figcaption>
<p>An engineering student in Maharashtra's Nagpur allegedly killed his parents over differences regarding his academic record and career, news agency PTI reported. The 25-year-old accused, Utkarsh Dhakhole, killed his parents at their residence in Kapil Nagar area on December 26. He also hid their bodies and told his relatives that his parents had gone to Bengaluru to take part in a meditation programme. Days later, Dhakole's neighbours complained to the police of a foul smell in the neighbourhood, leading to the discovery of the bodies and his arrest.</p>
<p><strong>Key Points:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The victim's parents wanted him to quit engineering due to his poor academic record.</li>
<li>Utkarsh allegedly strangled his mother and stabbed his father to death.</li>
<li>He confessed to the crime during police investigation.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Notable Quote:</strong></p>
<blockquote>“Utkarsh failed to clear several subjects during his engineering course. His parents, therefore, wanted him to quit engineering and choose something else. However, he was against their suggestion,” the official added.</blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong></p>
<p>The incident serves as a grim reminder of the pressure students face regarding academic expectations and career choices, often leading to tragic consequences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/engineering-student-nabbed-for-killing-parents-over-academic-career-dispute-101735751101945.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/engineering-student-nabbed-for-killing-parents-over-academic-career-dispute-101735751101945.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:42:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lucknow Horror: Man Shoots Murder Video, Shows Lifeless Bodies & Explains How He Killed Family - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/lucknow-murder-accused-arshad-blames-community-video-of-lifeless-bodies-of-mothers-sisters-9174419.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/lucknow-murder-accused-arshad-blames-community-video-of-lifeless-bodies-of-mothers-sisters-9174419.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:40:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjabi actor-singer Diljit Dosanjh meets PM Modi: ‘A fantastic start to 2025’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/punjabi-actor-singer-diljit-dosanjh-meets-pm-modi-a-fantastic-start-to-2025-101735752115399.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/punjabi-actor-singer-diljit-dosanjh-meets-pm-modi-a-fantastic-start-to-2025-101735752115399.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:40:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dallewal hunger strike: Will accept Supreme Court’s decision, says Centre - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Centre Accepts Supreme Court's Decision on Dallewal's Hunger Strike</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source: January 1, 2025, The Hindu</strong></p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/gqnysq/article69051348.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI01_01_2025_000311A.jpg" alt="Punjabi singer Babbu Maan meets farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal" width="400"><figcaption>Punjabi singer Babbu Maan meets farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal, who is on a hunger strike at Khanauri border in Sangrur district of Punjab on January 1, 2025.</figcaption>
<p>Introduction: Union Agriculture Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan stated that the Centre will abide by the Supreme Court’s directions regarding farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal's indefinite hunger strike.</p>
<ul>
<li>Dallewal's hunger strike entered its 37th day with no signs of relenting.</li>
<li>Farmers' demands include a legal guarantee for MSP and a farm loan waiver.</li>
<li>Samyukt Kisan Morcha has declined the Supreme Court's invitation for discussions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Supreme Court is looking into the matter. We will accept whatever decision the apex court takes." - Shivraj Singh Chouhan, Union Agriculture Minister</blockquote>
<p>Conclusion: The Centre's acceptance of the Supreme Court's decision on Dallewal's hunger strike may bring some resolution to the ongoing farmers' protests.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/will-accept-supreme-court-decision-on-dallewal-stir-centre/article69050638.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/will-accept-supreme-court-decision-on-dallewal-stir-centre/article69050638.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Year night revelries end in tragedy for nine in Chennai city - DTNEXT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tragedy Strikes New Year Celebrations in Chennai: Nine Lives Lost</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 1, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>Recent New Year revelries turned tragic in Chennai as nine individuals lost their lives in various incidents, primarily road accidents.</p><ul><li>Seven fatalities resulted from road accidents.</li><li>Two twin brothers drowned off the coast of Kalpakkam.</li><li>Deepak Garg, a 30-year-old, died after losing control of his motorcycle.</li><li>L Sarukesh, a 19-year-old hotel management student, died in a crash involving a parked tanker.</li><li>Six other individuals were identified as victims of separate accidents.</li><li>An elderly man was also run over by an unidentified vehicle in another incident.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is tragic to see so many lives lost during what should be a joyful celebration,” said a local police officer.</blockquote><p>The events highlight the potential dangers associated with celebrations that involve alcohol and reckless driving.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dtnext.in/news/chennai/new-year-night-revelries-end-in-tragedy-for-nine-in-chennai-city-817645</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dtnext.in/news/chennai/new-year-night-revelries-end-in-tragedy-for-nine-in-chennai-city-817645</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:40:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Haryana CM welcomes decisions taken for farmers at 1st Cabinet meet of 2025 - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Haryana CM Applauds Farmer-Friendly Decisions from 2025 Cabinet Meeting</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><p>Haryana Chief Minister Nayab Singh Saini has expressed his support for the farmer-focused decisions made during the first Union Cabinet meeting of 2025, emphasizing their potential benefits for farmers in Haryana.</p><ul><li>The Union Cabinet announced a subsidy on DAP fertiliser costing up to Rs 3,850 crore.</li><li>Extension of two crop insurance schemes - PMFBY and RWBCIS - for an additional year.</li><li>Creation of a new Rs 824.77-crore fund aimed at enhancing technology in flagship schemes.</li><li>Plans to encourage crop diversification and sustainable agriculture practices in Haryana.</li><li>Announcement of immediate registration for farmers on the 'kshatipurti' portal for timely compensation due to recent weather damages.</li></ul><blockquote>"The thoughtful decisions taken by the Union Cabinet will benefit lakhs of farmers in Haryana," said Chief Minister Saini.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the decisions made by the Union Cabinet are seen as a significant step towards supporting farmers, improving agricultural sustainability, and addressing recent challenges faced by the farming community.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/haryana-cm-welcomes-decisions-taken-for-farmers-at-1st-cabinet-meet-of-2025-125010100970_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/haryana-cm-welcomes-decisions-taken-for-farmers-at-1st-cabinet-meet-of-2025-125010100970_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:38:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra polls done and dusted, calls from both NCP factions for ‘reunion’; Praful Patel says Sharad Pawar ‘our deity’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maharashtra: Calls for 'Reunion' Between Ajit and Sharad Pawar after polls</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 1, 2025 &bull; The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/sharad-pawar-3.jpg" alt="sharad pawar" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Maharashtra election results gave Ajit an edge over Sharad Pawar, under whose shadow the nephew had long stayed &mdash; and finally rebelled against. (File Photo)</figcaption><p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Amidst the Maharashtra election results, calls for a reunion between Ajit and Sharad Pawar, the nephew and uncle leaders of the Nationalist Congress Party (NCP), are growing. Ajit's mother Asha Pawar has prayed for their reunion, and NCP members have expressed a desire for the duo to come together.</p><ol><li>Ajit's mother Asha Pawar prays for their reunion.</li><li>NCP members, including Praful Patel and Narhari Zirwal, express a desire for the Pawar family to reunite.</li><li>The BJP has no objections to the reunion.</li><li>The NCP (SP), led by Sharad Pawar, finished last in the recent Assembly elections.</li></ol><blockquote>Sharad Pawar is our deity. We have a high degree of respect for him. If the Pawar family comes together, it will make us extremely happy. I consider myself a member of the Pawar family. - Praful Patel</blockquote><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> Though some NCP leaders like Jitendra Awhad and Rohit Pawar might pose a hurdle, the desire for a reunion between Ajit and Sharad Pawar is growing within the party after the recent elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/maharashtra-polls-ncp-factions-praful-patel-sharad-pawar-deity-9755207/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/maharashtra-polls-ncp-factions-praful-patel-sharad-pawar-deity-9755207/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:32:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tragic end: 3-year-old girl found dead after 10-day rescue from borewell in Rajasthan - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tragic end: 3-year-old girl found dead after 10-day rescue from borewell in Rajasthan</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>A heartbreaking incident concluded with the discovery of a 3-year-old girl who had been trapped in a borewell for 10 days in Rajasthan, India. Despite extensive rescue efforts, she could not be saved.</p><ul><li>The girl fell into the borewell while playing near her home.</li><li>Rescue operations involved numerous teams working tirelessly over 10 days.</li><li>Authorities expressed their condolences to the family and emphasized the need for better safety measures.</li></ul><blockquote>“We did everything we could, but it is a tragic loss.”</blockquote><p>This tragic event highlights the dangers of open borewells and the need for increased safety awareness in rural areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/tragic-end-3-year-old-girl-found-dead-after-10-day-rescue-from-borewell-in-rajasthan/articleshow/116860705.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/tragic-end-3-year-old-girl-found-dead-after-10-day-rescue-from-borewell-in-rajasthan/articleshow/116860705.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hindu bodies differ on allowing men to wear shirt in Kerala temples - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hindu bodies differ on allowing men to wear shirt in Kerala temples</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/s1yjuy/article69051258.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/23tv%20sivagiri.jpg" alt="Sree Narayana Dharma Sangham Trust president Swami Sathchidananda has given a call to end the practice of men removing shirts in temples, terming it “regressive”. File" /><figcaption>Sree Narayana Dharma Sangham Trust president Swami Sathchidananda has given a call to end the practice of men removing shirts in temples, terming it “regressive”. File | Photo Credit: Special Arrangement</figcaption><p>The article discusses the differing opinions among major Hindu organisations in Kerala regarding allowing men to wear shirts while entering temples. The Sree Narayana Dharma Sangham Trust has called for an end to the practice of removing shirts, labeling it as “regressive.” Meanwhile, some organisations support the change while others leave it up to individual temple authorities to decide.</p><ul><li>Sree Narayana Dharma Sangham Trust president advocates ending shirt removal, supported by Chief Minister Pinarayi Vijayan.</li><li>The Sree Narayana Dharma Paripalana Yogam advocates allowing shirts, while the Nair Service Society prefers individual temple discretion.</li><li>Major temples run by Travancore and Guruvayur Devaswom Boards have yet to take a position.</li><li>There is no uniform practice across Kerala temples; the decision is often left to local temple authorities.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Yogam will direct all its office-bearers to end the outdated practice in the temples managed by them,” said Vellapally Natesan, general secretary of the SNDP Yogam.</blockquote><p>The debate highlights the changing attitudes toward traditional practices in Hindu temples and reflects a broader discussion on reform within religious customs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/keralas-hindu-organisations-divided-over-men-wearing-shirts-in-temples/article69050470.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/keralas-hindu-organisations-divided-over-men-wearing-shirts-in-temples/article69050470.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One dead, several children injured as school bus overturns in Kannur - Onmanorama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxOU0FjdDQ1enJrMTdka29Kd2g5T1c5WXpLRkZPdXJPMnFVbm5IMnVrbW9jOFA2VGdRUG41QllBbl9nN1RGZE0tTEVMd0U0dllKTWZWWWF4TTRiWm02M21iRHhxdVZRLU01ZUJjc3ZxYUhpYjVUbHhxUmxfNnU5US1LZ0lxcEVoQWRVUzZGSVlRcWk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxOU0FjdDQ1enJrMTdka29Kd2g5T1c5WXpLRkZPdXJPMnFVbm5IMnVrbW9jOFA2VGdRUG41QllBbl9nN1RGZE0tTEVMd0U0dllKTWZWWWF4TTRiWm02M21iRHhxdVZRLU01ZUJjc3ZxYUhpYjVUbHhxUmxfNnU5US1LZ0lxcEVoQWRVUzZGSVlRcWk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:18:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4 construction firm employees injured in attack on bus by masked men in J&Ks Ramban - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQZzI1ZTlMRnZYTUw4Zk1qZmJtOFZLZlNWeHVVUDBLZVR5TzUycHlQRU1ObWpEbGg2RUs5NUdCN291UEx1VG9LN1pGNlVGZTg1T2RuNVpqTGhoQTI3a01obDRENVpVaXRrRDlHeUtRd0Ntcy1jc0JXM002R2pBMXMxT2FSd3dIdnJ2eS1sM3FLWnhDODdDTHdTd2hqZE1aMXlVdF9EY1pSM29rMF9ueTJpZUFZVXMtSXZHU1ZzYmNUMnFINUVuX3B30gHKAUFVX3lxTFBjdklEd3BQb2ZsVHhXSWQ0aUU3STg1ejFleVpueXNiWjNITFZSb0JsdWVNUXB5bElpMjg0eTNXdFBsUVNYZ0NGSzhudHE3ODJfUEU2aWdZaVVqYUtoNjVLWWlNV1pzazNFUjBYS2JRaFIyR3F4dXFjZkQxekdscWFnLW9GZW12TUJwRTc4S1ZMV2pwYlZfY3VOU2luQlJOTDRnN3c5eGFOYzRMNUhKakprYk9NNGdmc1NxVlcwbmxKenEzWjFweF9vWGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQZzI1ZTlMRnZYTUw4Zk1qZmJtOFZLZlNWeHVVUDBLZVR5TzUycHlQRU1ObWpEbGg2RUs5NUdCN291UEx1VG9LN1pGNlVGZTg1T2RuNVpqTGhoQTI3a01obDRENVpVaXRrRDlHeUtRd0Ntcy1jc0JXM002R2pBMXMxT2FSd3dIdnJ2eS1sM3FLWnhDODdDTHdTd2hqZE1aMXlVdF9EY1pSM29rMF9ueTJpZUFZVXMtSXZHU1ZzYmNUMnFINUVuX3B30gHKAUFVX3lxTFBjdklEd3BQb2ZsVHhXSWQ0aUU3STg1ejFleVpueXNiWjNITFZSb0JsdWVNUXB5bElpMjg0eTNXdFBsUVNYZ0NGSzhudHE3ODJfUEU2aWdZaVVqYUtoNjVLWWlNV1pzazNFUjBYS2JRaFIyR3F4dXFjZkQxekdscWFnLW9GZW12TUJwRTc4S1ZMV2pwYlZfY3VOU2luQlJOTDRnN3c5eGFOYzRMNUhKakprYk9NNGdmc1NxVlcwbmxKenEzWjFweF9vWGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 16:14:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court's Tryst With Politicians' Bail In 2024 - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court's Bail Decisions for Political Leaders in 2024</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Various decisions throughout 2024.</p><img src="https://example.com/image.jpg" alt="Supreme Court image" /><figcaption>The Supreme Court of India.</figcaption><p>In 2024, the Supreme Court of India decided on bail pleas from several political leaders, including Aam Aadmi Party leaders Arvind Kejriwal, Manish Sisodia, and Sanjay Singh; BRS leader K Kavitha; former Tamil Nadu minister V Senthil Balaji; Jharkhand CM Hemant Soren; UP MLA Abbas Ansari; and former West Bengal Education Minister Partha Chatterjee.</p><ol><li><strong>Sanjay Singh</strong>: Granted bail in the Delhi Liquor Policy case after ED's concession.</li><li><strong>Hemant Soren</strong>: Dismissed ED's plea against his bail in a Jharkhand High Court order.</li><li><strong>Manish Sisodia</strong>: Granted bail in CBI and ED cases after long incarceration and trial delay.</li><li><strong>K Kavitha</strong>: Granted bail in money laundering and corruption cases, with criticism of CBI/ED's fairness.</li><li><strong>Arvind Kejriwal</strong>: Granted interim bail for elections, with conditions on visiting the CM office and Secretariat.</li><li><strong>Abbas Ansari</strong>: Granted bail in multiple cases, including illegal jail meetings and money laundering.</li><li><strong>V Senthil Balaji</strong>: Granted bail despite a prima facie case, with Court surprise at his ministerial appointment.</li><li><strong>Partha Chatterjee</strong>: Directed release on bail in the ED case, despite prima facie evidence.</li></ol><blockquote><em>"Long incarceration running around 17 months and trial having not been commenced, the appellant has been deprived of the right to speedy trial."</em> - Supreme Court in Manish Sisodia's bail order.</blockquote><p>Notable quotes include the Court's concern for suspects' fundamental rights and criticism of prosecution agencies' fairness. The Court stressed the importance of timely trials and the principle that pre-trial detention should not amount to punitive detention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-court-tryst-with-politicians-bail-in-2024-kejriwal-sisodia-soren-chatterjee-kavita-abbas-ansari-senthil-balaji-sanjay-singh-279777</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-court-tryst-with-politicians-bail-in-2024-kejriwal-sisodia-soren-chatterjee-kavita-abbas-ansari-senthil-balaji-sanjay-singh-279777</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 15:47:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punched, Dragged Each Other By Hair: Two School Girls Clash 'Over Same Boy' In UP - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Two School Girls Clash Over Boy in Uttar Pradesh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Viral video of UP girls fighting over boy (Photo: X)" title="Viral video of UP girls fighting over boy (Photo: X)"><figcaption>Viral video of UP girls fighting over boy (Photo: X)</figcaption></figure><p>Two teenage girls engaged in a public fight over the affections of the same boy in Baghpat, Uttar Pradesh, which was captured in a viral video.</p><ul><li>The incident took place in Aminagar Sarai town.</li><li>Both girls are in Class 10 and were reportedly friends until they discovered their mutual feelings for a boy.</li><li>The altercation involved punching, kicking, and hair-pulling, with onlookers attempting to separate them.</li><li>The police have launched an investigation following the video's circulation on social media.</li></ul><blockquote>The police confirmed that they are looking into the incident after receiving the viral video.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the challenges young people face with interpersonal relationships and the resulting conflicts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/punched-dragged-each-other-by-hair-two-school-girls-clash-over-same-boy-in-up-9174700.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/punched-dragged-each-other-by-hair-two-school-girls-clash-over-same-boy-in-up-9174700.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 15:35:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab & Haryana HC Denies Protection To Live-In Couple Citing Bigamy And Violation Of Spousal Rights - Verdictum]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxPQ25DOGJkam5mbmZXbjFfM0ExYXk0bFBXaXMxRkE0MTRmY0xFWHdlVnJDVjFTMkNwWXRSY0dfb1BVRHhpYTRpc1RBXzFnLVhiaTd5WGpDZDNmNThpdHdJamJ5R1lEa1lZUHZkOEFFUFo5TU5fbmJlME1wbkllTVhvaVVMZEJvRndxemVtSER2dFRzQdIBlwFBVV95cUxQd29DZkRNYkJUY1FINUdSQjZlVVZSX192SFV2eVNtTlo0dU5OcFdWN1NLSlNwRHUySGRXeG5HUFJWekZTeDVvOWNONERmWUg2anVFNDFhWFVlUktqZnVERS02cUVzaEtBY2JRVEx6b3A5MEhLZllpMTJWNXcxMkhFZ2R5bTZ0RnZ2M1IyRFoxVGhrcmR6VTZZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxPQ25DOGJkam5mbmZXbjFfM0ExYXk0bFBXaXMxRkE0MTRmY0xFWHdlVnJDVjFTMkNwWXRSY0dfb1BVRHhpYTRpc1RBXzFnLVhiaTd5WGpDZDNmNThpdHdJamJ5R1lEa1lZUHZkOEFFUFo5TU5fbmJlME1wbkllTVhvaVVMZEJvRndxemVtSER2dFRzQdIBlwFBVV95cUxQd29DZkRNYkJUY1FINUdSQjZlVVZSX192SFV2eVNtTlo0dU5OcFdWN1NLSlNwRHUySGRXeG5HUFJWekZTeDVvOWNONERmWUg2anVFNDFhWFVlUktqZnVERS02cUVzaEtBY2JRVEx6b3A5MEhLZllpMTJWNXcxMkhFZ2R5bTZ0RnZ2M1IyRFoxVGhrcmR6VTZZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 15:30:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Land Mafias Wanted To Sell My Sisters': In Murder Video, UP Man Reveals Why He Killed Family - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<html><body>
<h1>Chilling Murder-Suicide: UP Man Kills Family, Blames Land Mafia and Neighbors</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Last Updated: January 01, 2025, 20:11 IST</p>
<figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&width=360&height=270" alt="Arshad was arrested at the crime scene..." title="Arshad was arrested at the crime scene and the victims have been identified as his mother Asma and sisters Alia (9), Alshia (19), Aksa (16) and Rahmeen (18)."><figcaption>Arshad and his family</figcaption></figure>
<p>In a shocking turn of events, a 24-year-old man from Uttar Pradesh named Arshad murdered his mother and four sisters before sharing a video of the crime online. Arshad was later arrested at the crime scene in Lucknow.</p>
<p>The chilling video, which emerged hours after the murders, shows Arshad alleging that neighbors and land mafia in their hometown of Budaun had captured their house and planned to traffic his sisters. He claimed that he killed his family members to prevent this from happening.</p>
<ol>
<li>Arshad choked and slit the wrists of his mother and sisters.</li>
<li>He blamed local land mafia and neighbors for harassing his family and capturing their house.</li>
<li>Arshad requested Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath for justice.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p>"I have killed my mother and sisters. When police get this video, they must know that the locals are responsible. They harassed us to capture our house. We raised our voice, but no one heard. It has been 15 days that we have been sleeping on the footpath, wandering in the cold. We don’t want the children to wander in the cold. They have captured our house. The documents are with us."<br>
- Arshad</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Arshad also claimed that his family wanted to live peacefully and had approached many people for help, but no one assisted them. He expressed fear that his sisters were dying and that he himself would not live much longer.</p>
</body></html>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/land-mafias-wanted-to-sell-my-sisters-in-murder-video-up-man-reveals-why-he-killed-family-9174473.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/land-mafias-wanted-to-sell-my-sisters-in-murder-video-up-man-reveals-why-he-killed-family-9174473.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 15:06:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Struggling with studies, student kills parents who told him to quit engineering - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Student Murders Parents over Disagreement on Career Path</h1>
<p><strong>Published on 01 January 2025, 14:31 IST</strong></p>
<img src='' alt=''>
<p>A 25-year-old engineering student in Nagpur, Maharashtra, allegedly killed his parents due to disagreements over his education and career, with police arresting him on Wednesday. Utkarsh Dhakhole, the accused, confessed to strangling his mother, a teacher, and stabbing his father, a power plant technician and social worker, to death.</p>
<ul>
<li>The motive appears to be a dispute over Utkarsh's struggling academic record and career.</li>
<li>Utkarsh's parents wanted him to quit engineering, but he was against their suggestion.</li>
<li>After the murder, Utkarsh took his sister to their uncle's residence and claimed that their parents had gone to Bengaluru for a meditation program.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The decomposed bodies of the parents were recovered on Wednesday morning after neighbors complained of a foul smell.</blockquote>
<p>The deceased were identified as Liladhar Dhakhole (55) and his 50-year-old wife Aruna.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/maharashtra/struggling-with-studies-student-kills-parents-who-told-him-to-quit-engineering-3338338</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/maharashtra/struggling-with-studies-student-kills-parents-who-told-him-to-quit-engineering-3338338</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 14:31:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi to send Chadar to Khwaja Moinuddin Chishti's Dargah on occasion of 813th Urs - ANI News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxPUVJWM0lfSncwU2ZlVlBwNEtwaU5FenBPQUdibWNvekdlbWE3UlpSa1U5SEw5SkFSaThtZGxVSTRVd3pkdFJWNFJrc012a1k4TFNtelVVSnRWa0pjWG1GSHp6ZGtsZFRlM1dDOEpzTFhvOTcyNXNmanRrb0tIYlpBbXF1eXJTYkNMZW1ud1puNzVlQmNpUDQ5Z3l4anZhODlJVkhGczVmdlkzbjZKdlpJLW9tSlZzU0lHcTczd25PZ1NJcndWTHQ2WE1iMGRPa0VWZWVxNG9ITDBhSVFWYkJqT3dB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxPUVJWM0lfSncwU2ZlVlBwNEtwaU5FenBPQUdibWNvekdlbWE3UlpSa1U5SEw5SkFSaThtZGxVSTRVd3pkdFJWNFJrc012a1k4TFNtelVVSnRWa0pjWG1GSHp6ZGtsZFRlM1dDOEpzTFhvOTcyNXNmanRrb0tIYlpBbXF1eXJTYkNMZW1ud1puNzVlQmNpUDQ5Z3l4anZhODlJVkhGczVmdlkzbjZKdlpJLW9tSlZzU0lHcTczd25PZ1NJcndWTHQ2WE1iMGRPa0VWZWVxNG9ITDBhSVFWYkJqT3dB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 14:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyderabad Metro Expansion: Congress govt tweaks BRS-proposed Paradise-Medchal, JBS-Shamirpet corridors - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxNeFZkUDhrUUNsM1ltLVFWYTNPMUtKdHlzSmtETWFfNFFxX1ZwUVlxaWRBOERKaVo0TXVJa2dyNW1EeFB1ZzhvU0lPa2hPV0lKRUdVRVlDclpNMDRqZjBSVjZGd0xid3ZENEtoU1dVeWZBbVJrUkhvZ1A5akEyLW1pak1RZTNtYnVpZ05HQXY3MlpNbGstTzVwdkFwUTVEaVgxSjczcEwxbjI3V0RUN0dwcFZKQWEycVNCUHIzaGkwRlAzS05wYXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxNeFZkUDhrUUNsM1ltLVFWYTNPMUtKdHlzSmtETWFfNFFxX1ZwUVlxaWRBOERKaVo0TXVJa2dyNW1EeFB1ZzhvU0lPa2hPV0lKRUdVRVlDclpNMDRqZjBSVjZGd0xid3ZENEtoU1dVeWZBbVJrUkhvZ1A5akEyLW1pak1RZTNtYnVpZ05HQXY3MlpNbGstTzVwdkFwUTVEaVgxSjczcEwxbjI3V0RUN0dwcFZKQWEycVNCUHIzaGkwRlAzS05wYXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 14:28:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress attempts to weave Gandhi and Ambedkar’s legacies into singular narrative of social justice - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Attempts to Weave Gandhi and Ambedkar’s Legacies into Singular Narrative of Social Justice</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> January 01, 2025 07:49 pm IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src='https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/7s4i67/article69050905.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_Mallikarjun_Kharge_a_4_1_O6DP6DGF.jpg' alt='Congress MP and LoP in Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi and party president Mallikarjun Kharge at CWC meeting' />
<figcaption>Congress MP and LoP in Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi and party president Mallikarjun Kharge attend the extended two-day Congress Working Committee (CWC) meeting, ‘Nav Satyagrah Baithak’, in Belagavi on December 26, 2024.</figcaption>
<p>The Congress party is set to combine the legacies of Mahatma Gandhi and Dr. B.R. Ambedkar into a coherent narrative of social justice, launching a campaign that will commence on January 3, 2025.</p>
<ul>
<li>The campaign follows a pause due to the passing of former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh.</li>
<li>The CWC endorsed a month-long program culminating on January 26, 2025, at Mhow, the birthplace of Dr. Ambedkar.</li>
<li>The initiative emphasizes the need to protect the Constitution and the ideals of the Indian Independence Movement.</li>
<li>The Congress aims to reconnect its politics of social justice with the legacies of both leaders.</li>
<li>The movement will extend into a nationwide public outreach program from January 26, 2025, to January 26, 2026.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The CWC and the Indian National Congress are fiercely committed to protecting the Indian Constitution and the ideals of the Indian Independence Movement.”</blockquote>
<p>This effort represents an ambitious attempt to address complex historical narratives and the differences between Gandhi and Ambedkar regarding caste and social reform.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/congress-attempts-to-weave-gandhi-and-ambedkars-legacies-into-singular-narrative-of-social-justice/article69050069.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/congress-attempts-to-weave-gandhi-and-ambedkars-legacies-into-singular-narrative-of-social-justice/article69050069.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 14:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J&K Bank launches special one-time settlement scheme ‘KARZ SE MUKTI’ - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQMjE2VG5DOVFjczRYUFVKOVZMNHhnVGJ1SEhaaGthY3FDQjR1REJOOWtlQ3hveEw3LWFDOGt2UUpiN0pxS3NLck51MVBzZVlFTENqNGlvZl9UdzVzZEZxT2hnd3BEcHM0cXRuOENIWnkzR0t5OVFnWmk1bDNLNk1paDloRjh2RDBCd1YtOTJPOTB5WU9mNWZIbzcyeG15SzVGMVNSQjVNbGY4UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQMjE2VG5DOVFjczRYUFVKOVZMNHhnVGJ1SEhaaGthY3FDQjR1REJOOWtlQ3hveEw3LWFDOGt2UUpiN0pxS3NLck51MVBzZVlFTENqNGlvZl9UdzVzZEZxT2hnd3BEcHM0cXRuOENIWnkzR0t5OVFnWmk1bDNLNk1paDloRjh2RDBCd1YtOTJPOTB5WU9mNWZIbzcyeG15SzVGMVNSQjVNbGY4UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 14:17:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaDeX first of many as ISRO prepares for Chandrayaan-4 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ISRO Launches SpaDeX as Preparation for Chandrayaan-4</h1><p><strong>Published: January 01, 2025, Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/oc17yu/article69045706.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_31_2024_000001A.jpg" alt="ISRO Chairman S. Somanath with senior ISRO scientists during a press conference" /> <figcaption>ISRO Chairman S. Somanath with senior ISRO scientists during a press conference after successfully launching the first SpaDeX mission in Sriharikota on December 30, 2024.</figcaption><p>The Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) has begun a series of docking experiments in preparation for the upcoming Chandrayaan-4 mission aimed at returning lunar soil samples to Earth. The SpaDeX mission, which launched two satellites, is a critical step for the upcoming lunar mission.</p><ul><li>The C60 mission successfully placed two satellites into orbit on December 30, 2024.</li><li>Rendezvous and docking of the two SpaDeX satellites are scheduled for approximately January 7, 2025.</li><li>Chandrayaan-4 will utilize two LVM-3 rockets for its mission modules.</li><li>ISRO aims to master docking technology for future missions, including the Bharatiya Antariksh Station (BAS).</li><li>The lunar sample retrieval process involves complex docking and transferring methodology.</li></ul><blockquote>ISRO Chairman S. Somanath stated, "Docking is important for all future missions of ISRO because you cannot launch everything in one go."</blockquote><p>The continued development of space docking technology is vital for India's ambitions in space exploration, ensuring safe transport of modules and applications beyond the current mission.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/spadex-first-of-many-as-isro-prepares-for-chandrayaan-4/article69049856.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/spadex-first-of-many-as-isro-prepares-for-chandrayaan-4/article69049856.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 14:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 days after she fell in, 3-year-old girl rescued from 170-feet borewell in Rajasthan - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tragic End: 3-Year-Old Girl Pulled Out Dead from Rajasthan Borewell After 10 Days</h1>
<p><strong>Published on January 2, 2023, in Indian Express</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/borewell-rajasthan.jpg?w=640" alt="The child was closely wrapped in a white cloth when rescuers pulled her out." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>The child was closely wrapped in a white cloth when rescuers pulled her out. (Express)</figcaption>
<p>A three-year-old girl who fell into a 170-feet deep borewell in Rajasthan's Kotputli on December 23 was finally pulled out after 10 days of unsuccessful rescue attempts. She was declared dead on arrival at the hospital.</p>
<ol>
  <li>The girl was rescued from the borewell after five failed attempts.</li>
  <li>Rescuers drilled a parallel hole to reach the girl.</li>
  <li>The girl was brought dead to Kotputli’s BDM Hospital.</li>
  <li>This is the second such incident in a month in Rajasthan.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
  "We have put 30 officials of NDRF on work to get the girl out of safety."
  - Yogesh Meena, NDRF Chief
</blockquote>
<p>A postmortem was to be conducted to determine the exact time of death.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/girl-rescued-170-feet-borewell-rajasthan-9755071/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/girl-rescued-170-feet-borewell-rajasthan-9755071/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DSSSB PGT Recruitment 2025: Registration for 432 posts begins on January 16 at dsssb.delhi.gov.in - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>DSSSB PGT Recruitment 2025: Registration for 432 posts begins on January 16</h1><p><strong>Date: January 01, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/01/550x309/DSSSB_admit_card_july_1688296447706_1735739871425.jpg" alt="DSSSB PGT Recruitment 2025: Registration for 432 posts begins on January 16"><figcaption>DSSSB PGT Recruitment 2025: Registration for 432 posts begins on January 16</figcaption></figure><p>The Delhi Subordinate Services Selection Board (DSSSB) has announced the recruitment for 432 Post Graduate Teacher (PGT) positions. Eligible candidates can apply online starting January 16, 2025.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The application process opens on January 16 and closes on February 14, 2025.</li><li>There are a total of 432 vacancies across various subject codes.</li><li>The selection will be based on a One Tier Examination (Tier-I).</li><li>The examination lasts for 3 hours and includes 300 questions.</li><li>The application fee is ₹100, with exemptions for certain categories.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quote:</h2><blockquote>The candidates submitting their application online should pay the requisite fees only through SBI e-pay.</blockquote><p>For more details, candidates can check the official DSSSB website.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/education/employment-news/dsssb-pgt-recruitment-2025-registration-for-432-posts-begins-on-january-16-at-dsssbdelhigovin-101735739686819.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/education/employment-news/dsssb-pgt-recruitment-2025-registration-for-432-posts-begins-on-january-16-at-dsssbdelhigovin-101735739686819.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 13:58:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>