<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:18:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:18:38 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As dense fog persists, IMD issues ‘orange’ alert across Delhi-NCR; routes to airport, highways likely to be affected - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>As Dense Fog Persists, IMD Issues ‘Orange’ Alert Across Delhi-NCR</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/indian-express-56.jpg?w=640" alt="Delhi air quality, orange alert, imd, weather updates, delhi fog, delhi," width="640" height="360"><figcaption>In light of these conditions, IMD has also issued several safety recommendations for commuters, including careful travel while driving or on any transport. (Express Photo)</figcaption><p>As Delhi woke up to dense fog, the IMD issued an ‘orange’ warning impacting travel across the national capital. Routes to the airport and major highways may face delays and poor visibility is noted.</p><ul><li>IMD has reported extremely low visibility levels, dropping to 50 meters at the Delhi airport.</li><li>Travelers are encouraged to use fog lights and stay updated with their travel services.</li><li>The minimum expected temperature is 7 degrees Celsius, while the maximum is 19 degrees Celsius.</li><li>Air quality has improved yet remains “poor” at an AQI of 278.</li><li>Recent disruptions included delays in 209 flights and 45 trains due to dense fog.</li></ul><blockquote>“The last time visibility dropped to zero was between January 2 and 3,” according to IMD.</blockquote><p>With additional dense fog expected, residents must prepare for continued travel complications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/delhi/delhi-ncr-dense-fog-weather-today-orange-alert-aqi-imd-air-quality-9775611/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/delhi/delhi-ncr-dense-fog-weather-today-orange-alert-aqi-imd-air-quality-9775611/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 03:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Z-Morh tunnel: Security heightened in Kashmir as PM Modi visits today to inaugurate ‘engineering marvel’ | Details - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Security Enhanced in Kashmir for PM Modi's Z-Morh Tunnel Inauguration</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/z_morh_tunnel_srinagar_1736734895493_1736734895770.jpg" alt="Security personnel stand guard near the Z-Morh tunnel project site, in J&K. The tunnel is scheduled to be inaugurated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday. (PTI)" title="Security personnel stand guard near the Z-Morh tunnel project site, in J&K. The tunnel is scheduled to be inaugurated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday. (PTI)"><figcaption>Security personnel stand guard near the Z-Morh tunnel project site, in J&K. The tunnel is scheduled to be inaugurated by Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday. (PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi is visiting Jammu and Kashmir to inaugurate the Z-Morh tunnel, a significant infrastructure project aimed at enhancing connectivity to the Ladakh region.</p><ul><li>Enhanced security measures are in place, including deployment of police, paramilitary forces, and the Army.</li><li>The Z-Morh tunnel is a 6.5 km long, strategically important tunnel built at a cost of ₹2,400 crore.</li><li>It is anticipated to provide all-weather connectivity between Srinagar and the Ladakh region, promoting tourism and local economies.</li><li>The project was initiated in May 2015 and was completed last year.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Sonamarg Tunnel in Jammu and Kashmir is a game-changer for the region,” NHIDCL stated.</blockquote><p>This event underscores the importance of infrastructure development in enhancing connectivity and security in strategically sensitive regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/zmorh-tunnel-inauguration-sonmarg-security-upped-kashmir-pm-modi-srinagar-visit-ladakh-101736733070813.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/zmorh-tunnel-inauguration-sonmarg-security-upped-kashmir-pm-modi-srinagar-visit-ladakh-101736733070813.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:57:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CATS Warrior Drone: Why IAF Is Unlikely To Place Orders For HAL’s “Stealth UAV” Despite All The Hoopla? - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CATS Warrior Drone: Why IAF Is Unlikely To Place Orders For HAL’s “Stealth UAV” Despite All The Hoopla?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Aeronautics Limited (HAL)</p>
<figure><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/GhA6T9wbcAAIeK_?format=jpg&amp;name=large" alt="CATS Warrior"><figcaption>The flagship program of HAL, the Combat Air Teaming System, achieved a milestone by successfully conducting the Engine Ground Run of a Full-Scale Demonstrator, CATS – Warrior. Via: HAL</figcaption></figure>
<p>HAL's CATS Warrior drone has accomplished a significant engine ground run, sparking both interest and concern about its operational capabilities and design.</p>
<ul>
<li>The CATS program includes multiple UAVs designed for collaboration in contested airspace.</li>
<li>The Warrior drone is intended for autonomous operations with a range of 800 km and a speed of ~850 km/h.</li>
<li>Key specifications include a maximum weight of 1,300 kg and the ability to carry various weapons.</li>
<li>HAL emphasizes stealth characteristics, aiming to minimize radar detection.</li>
<li>Challenges remain, notably in engine power and the quest for true stealth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The promise of CATS will only be realized if the Warrior and Hunter drones are adequately stealthy.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while HAL's technology demonstrator showcases advancements, there remain significant hurdles before the CATS can be considered operational. IAF's commitment to the project is premature and should be approached with caution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/cats-warrior-drone-why-iaf-is-unlikely/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/cats-warrior-drone-why-iaf-is-unlikely/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:21:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How 2 Ukrainians Planned And Executed Rs 1,000 Crore Torres Ponzi Mumbai Scam - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How 2 Ukrainians Planned And Executed Rs 1,000 Crore Torres Ponzi Mumbai Scam</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Unknown<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-117167368,thumbsize-1186599,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/117167368.jpg" alt="Ukrainian Nationals Behind Mumbai's Torres Ponzi Scheme Police Investigate" title="Ukrainian Nationals Behind Mumbai's Torres Ponzi Scheme Police Investigate"><figcaption>Ukrainian Nationals Behind Mumbai's Torres Ponzi Scheme Police Investigate<br>Photo: Times Now</figcaption><p>Two Ukrainian nationals, Artem and Olena Stoin, are identified as the key figures behind the Torres jewellery Ponzi scheme that defrauded over 1.25 lakh investors in Mumbai by promising high returns on investments in gemstones, gold, and silver.</p><ul><li>The scam involved 14 luxury cars given as lucky draw prizes to attract investors.</li><li>Torres jewellery stores abruptly shut down, leading to concerns over fake stones and unpaid dues for investors.</li><li>The scheme promised a 6% annual return, increasing to 11%, but payments ceased two months prior to the article.</li><li>The police have registered a case against the holding firm, with multiple executives charged with criminal conspiracy and related offences.</li><li>The masterminds have fled the country, but assets worth crores have already been seized by authorities.</li></ul><blockquote>“This remains one of the most significant financial fraud cases in Mumbai.”</blockquote><p>The investigation continues as authorities work to trace the ownership of luxury cars and other assets related to the scam.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/mumbai/how-2-ukrainians-planned-and-executed-rs-1000-crore-torres-ponzi-mumbai-scam-article-117166989</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/mumbai/how-2-ukrainians-planned-and-executed-rs-1000-crore-torres-ponzi-mumbai-scam-article-117166989</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Budget 2025: Income Tax Slabs For FY 2025-26, Comparing Old And New Tax Regimes - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/tax/budget-2025-income-tax-slabs-old-regime-vs-new-regime-9186222.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/tax/budget-2025-income-tax-slabs-old-regime-vs-new-regime-9186222.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:31:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Budget 2025: Income Tax Slabs For FY 2025-26, Comparing Old And New Tax Regimes - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/tax/budget-2025-income-tax-slabs-old-regime-vs-new-regime-9186222.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/tax/budget-2025-income-tax-slabs-old-regime-vs-new-regime-9186222.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:31:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UP: Lawyer's plan to murder girlfriend's family goes wrong as hitmen end up killing wrong person - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/up-lawyers-murder-plan-goes-haywire-as-hitmen-end-up-killing-wrong-person-101736729336283.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/up-lawyers-murder-plan-goes-haywire-as-hitmen-end-up-killing-wrong-person-101736729336283.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:30:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senior advocate Iqbal Chagla passes away: A Bombay High Court icon who raised voice against corruption in judiciary - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Senior Advocate Iqbal Chagla Passes Away: A Champion Against Judicial Corruption</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/iqbal-chagla-1.jpg?w=640" alt="Iqbal Chagla" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Iqbal Chagla, a prominent figure in the Bombay High Court, has passed away at the age of 85.</figcaption><p>Iqbal M Chagla, a renowned senior advocate and former president of the Bombay Bar Association, passed away in Mumbai at the age of 85. Known for his strong stance against corruption in the judiciary, Chagla was instrumental in advocating for accountability among judges in the 1990s.</p><ul><li>Chagla was the son of M C Chagla, a former Chief Justice of the Bombay High Court.</li><li>He was a staunch advocate for judicial reforms and took notable actions against corrupt judges during his tenure as president of the Bombay Bar Association.</li><li>Chagla’s efforts led to resignations and significant debates within the judiciary.</li></ul><blockquote>“Iqbal was one of the greatest giants of the legal profession... He set the standard,” said senior advocate Rafique Dada.</blockquote><p>Chagla's contributions to the legal field and his unwavering commitment to justice leave a lasting legacy in the legal community and beyond.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/iqbal-chagla-dead-senior-advocate-9775310/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/iqbal-chagla-dead-senior-advocate-9775310/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lohri, Makar Sankranti stock market holidays on 13, 14 January 2025? NSE, BSE open or closed? Trading off or not? Exchanges calendar 2025 - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stock Market Status on Lohri and Makar Sankranti 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ET Now News</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Stock Market Holiday On Makar Sankranti Stock Market Holiday On Lohri" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Stock Market Holiday On Makar Sankranti, Stock Market Holiday On Lohri</figcaption>
<p>Lohri and Makar Sankranti are not recognized as trading holidays in 2025. The stock market will operate as usual on both days.</p>
<ul>
<li>Lohri is celebrated on January 13 and Makar Sankranti on January 14.</li>
<li>Both BSE and NSE will remain open for trading on these days.</li>
<li>Makar Sankranti is celebrated with various names across India such as Uttarayan and Pongal.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Lohri marks the end of the sowing season and welcomes the harvest season."</blockquote>
<p>The stock response indicates that for traders and investors, there is no need to concern themselves with market closures on these auspicious days.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/markets/lohri-makar-sankranti-bank-stock-market-holidays-on-13-14-january-2025-nse-bse-open-or-closed-trading-off-or-not-exchanges-calendar-2025-article-117173136</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/markets/lohri-makar-sankranti-bank-stock-market-holidays-on-13-14-january-2025-nse-bse-open-or-closed-trading-off-or-not-exchanges-calendar-2025-article-117173136</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 23:51:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maha Kumbh: Steve Jobs' wife to take holy dip on January 14 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxORjVFamM0LWJmV2I3OVd0c3pqUGc5QUxBY2hieXVhck5Dd1hpLVhBSHZ2QUNYbnR0WGRWamJmTjhDbnhYdjROYmRUckxpVkNfRG92Q3dkaVN4bnJESWg1QWlRVXJtVUY3MXUwUm95Ym56U1lGRVFOM2tkX0N6LUZMeFZ5OFZSMFBiaUFpMGVjOEVRTHQtcXluWDBzMFhjOFRwTG9kV2k3czdhVy1NZUtaV3hxVVVtMXcwbFRVc0Nxc0RMOTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxORjVFamM0LWJmV2I3OVd0c3pqUGc5QUxBY2hieXVhck5Dd1hpLVhBSHZ2QUNYbnR0WGRWamJmTjhDbnhYdjROYmRUckxpVkNfRG92Q3dkaVN4bnJESWg1QWlRVXJtVUY3MXUwUm95Ym56U1lGRVFOM2tkX0N6LUZMeFZ5OFZSMFBiaUFpMGVjOEVRTHQtcXluWDBzMFhjOFRwTG9kV2k3czdhVy1NZUtaV3hxVVVtMXcwbFRVc0Nxc0RMOTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 23:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maha Kumbh: Steve Jobs' wife to take holy dip on January 14 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxORjVFamM0LWJmV2I3OVd0c3pqUGc5QUxBY2hieXVhck5Dd1hpLVhBSHZ2QUNYbnR0WGRWamJmTjhDbnhYdjROYmRUckxpVkNfRG92Q3dkaVN4bnJESWg1QWlRVXJtVUY3MXUwUm95Ym56U1lGRVFOM2tkX0N6LUZMeFZ5OFZSMFBiaUFpMGVjOEVRTHQtcXluWDBzMFhjOFRwTG9kV2k3czdhVy1NZUtaV3hxVVVtMXcwbFRVc0Nxc0RMOTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxORjVFamM0LWJmV2I3OVd0c3pqUGc5QUxBY2hieXVhck5Dd1hpLVhBSHZ2QUNYbnR0WGRWamJmTjhDbnhYdjROYmRUckxpVkNfRG92Q3dkaVN4bnJESWg1QWlRVXJtVUY3MXUwUm95Ym56U1lGRVFOM2tkX0N6LUZMeFZ5OFZSMFBiaUFpMGVjOEVRTHQtcXluWDBzMFhjOFRwTG9kV2k3czdhVy1NZUtaV3hxVVVtMXcwbFRVc0Nxc0RMOTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 23:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BPSC Row: Supporters Of Pappu Yadav Burn Tyres, Block Roads In Bihar - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pappu Yadav's Supporters Protest for BPSC Exam Cancellation in Bihar</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Pappu Yadav's supporters block roads demanding cancellation and re-examination of BPSC exams. (Courtesy: ANI)"><figcaption>Pappu Yadav's supporters block roads demanding cancellation and re-examination of BPSC exams. (Courtesy: ANI)</figcaption><p>Independent MP Pappu Yadav’s supporters conducted a protest in Patna, demanding the cancellation of the Bihar Public Service Commission (BPSC) exam and a re-examination.</p><ul><li>A ‘Bihar Bandh’ was called by Yadav.</li><li>Supporters burned tyres and blocked roads.</li><li>Police detained some protesters during the demonstration.</li><li>Protests against BPSC have been ongoing since December 2024.</li><li>The Supreme Court did not hear a related petition regarding alleged exam malpractices.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“There is no strength bigger than people’s strength.” - Prashant Kishor, Jan Suraaj Party chief</p></blockquote><p>This protest reflects mounting public frustration over the BPSC's handling of the examination process, emphasizing community engagement in political issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/bpsc-row-supporters-of-pappu-yadav-burn-tyres-block-roads-in-bihar-9186198.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/bpsc-row-supporters-of-pappu-yadav-burn-tyres-block-roads-in-bihar-9186198.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 22:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India eyes mega defence deals worth Rs 1.5 lakh crore before March 31 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-eyes-mega-defence-deals-worth-rs-1-5-lakh-crore-before-march-31/articleshow/117182178.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-eyes-mega-defence-deals-worth-rs-1-5-lakh-crore-before-march-31/articleshow/117182178.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 21:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India eyes mega defence deals worth Rs 1.5 lakh crore before March 31 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-eyes-mega-defence-deals-worth-rs-1-5-lakh-crore-before-march-31/articleshow/117182178.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-eyes-mega-defence-deals-worth-rs-1-5-lakh-crore-before-march-31/articleshow/117182178.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 21:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rs 1.2 crore deal lost by pitchers after Vineeta Singh calls them 'fake'; founders fire back at Shark Tank - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shark Tank Controversy: Pitchers Fire Back at Vineeta Singh's 'Fake' Claims</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Panache Magazine</p>
<p>Entrepreneurs Ashish and Aditi Jawa express frustration after Vineeta Singh questions the authenticity of their pitch on Shark Tank India, accusing them of inflating their business figures.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The founders sought an investment of Rs 1.2 crore for 1% equity.</li>
    <li>Vineeta Singh raised doubts about their social media reach and sales figures.</li>
    <li>Claims of manipulating business numbers led to an emotional response from the pitchers.</li>
    <li>Aditi emphasized the genuine growth of their community and brand on social media.</li>
    <li>The pitchers urged their loyal customers to showcase their support online to counter the accusations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Daal mein kuch kaala hai” - Vineeta Singh, indicating her skepticism about the pitchers' claims.</blockquote>
<p>Despite not receiving a deal, Ashish and Aditi were more hurt by the public questioning of their achievements than the lack of investment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/rs-1-2-crore-deal-lost-by-pitchers-after-vineeta-singh-calls-them-fake-founders-fire-back-at-shark-tank-india-season-4-judges/articleshow/117181861.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/rs-1-2-crore-deal-lost-by-pitchers-after-vineeta-singh-calls-them-fake-founders-fire-back-at-shark-tank-india-season-4-judges/articleshow/117181861.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 20:31:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025: Underwater drones, AI cameras, NSG commandos part of security detail; over 45 crore visitors expected - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh 2025: Underwater drones, AI cameras, NSG commandos part of security detail; over 45 crore visitors expected</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-13">January 13, 2025</time> | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/mahakumbh_1736700393552_1736700393846.jpg" alt="Prayagraj: Commandos conduct a mock drill ahead of the Mahakumbh 2025, in Prayagraj, Saturday, Jan. 11, 2025. (PTI Photo)(PTI)" title="Prayagraj: Commandos conduct a mock drill ahead of the Mahakumbh 2025, in Prayagraj, Saturday, Jan. 11, 2025. (PTI Photo)(PTI)">
<figcaption>Prayagraj: Commandos conduct a mock drill ahead of the Mahakumbh 2025, in Prayagraj, Saturday, Jan. 11, 2025. (PTI Photo)(PTI)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The Prayagraj police have set up extensive security measures as over 45 crore visitors are expected to attend the Mahakumbh, which occurs once every 12 years.</p>
<ul>
<li>Comprehensive security measures include a circular security system with 102 checkpoints along key routes, vehicle checks, and individual frisking.</li>
<li>More than 1,000 police personnel are deployed, supplemented by 71 inspectors, 234 sub-inspectors, and 645 constables.</li>
<li>Security resources also include 10 drones, 5 Vajra vehicles, and several anti-sabotage teams.</li>
<li>A multi-layered security system termed “impenetrable security chakravyuh” protects critical installations like temples and akhadas.</li>
<li>Innovative technologies, such as 2,700 AI-enabled cameras and 113 underwater drones, have been incorporated.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We are committed to ensuring the safety of all participants," said DGP Prashant Kumar.</blockquote>
<p>The Mahakumbh will span from January 13 to February 26, with major rituals scheduled on auspicious days, attracting millions of pilgrims to the holy Sangam.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-2025-underwater-drones-ai-cameras-nsg-commandos-part-of-security-detail-over-45-crore-visitors-expected-101736663127056.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-2025-underwater-drones-ai-cameras-nsg-commandos-part-of-security-detail-over-45-crore-visitors-expected-101736663127056.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Such arrogance is not good': Tamil Nadu governor slams CM MK Stalin over national anthem row - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Such arrogance is not good': Tamil Nadu governor slams CM MK Stalin over national anthem row</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>The Tamil Nadu governor criticized Chief Minister MK Stalin regarding the ongoing national anthem controversy, emphasizing the need for respect and unity.</p><ul><li>The governor highlighted the importance of upholding national values.</li><li>Stalin's approach to handling the controversy was questioned.</li><li>Public response has been divided, with various viewpoints on the matter.</li></ul><blockquote>“Such arrogance is not good for our national integrity.”</blockquote><p>The governor's remarks aim to address the need for a cohesive response to national symbols and unity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/such-arrogance-is-not-good-tamil-nadu-raj-bhavan-slams-cm-mk-stalin-over-national-anthem-row/articleshow/117170841.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/such-arrogance-is-not-good-tamil-nadu-raj-bhavan-slams-cm-mk-stalin-over-national-anthem-row/articleshow/117170841.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra poll victory has ended Pawar’s ‘politics of deceit’, says Amit Shah - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNQTdLbFZnelg0TzNOeWlxMzBrR0ZNcGc2TGVOdXVaekV5Zm1Fb3pDdG5tNEVyUFhvdEhWVnZ4ZGx5TGx3emtROUZJQm5yUkdkWjZPczB6VlFGekNuYnZiakxFWEJrTnYxcHRNa1ZDMVFDSHk5ZFk1UkF1b2d3NWlieW9ubEQ3SUgyOW0xSUNOSmxsM2RmY0JrOEFNT3VMdWMyRG16Wk04WlF4MmU2Sk41aG9xWmw4RHlhTHA2c09qd2xzaWhhdXNZRzlPUnNzcTZicVkzWmxhNNIB3AFBVV95cUxPN2NNRlFnT0Qyc2JDYzlUTmFMMU1NeW1KQWR4anFMYlkxVjRkWmpTRVJoTHpXOGN0anp1VnRrSFJkbmtXNWw5emgyal9McklDRUlHWklueE9ueGxSWkV2cTNuVnlzekRRS3JvclFHamIwdzh5eFJyU1I3TXhZdzYzX2ptLThzNUI2RnJVOG1iR0lrYk1aQVdyT3U0TkFkOUdqN24xZ192UVVia19raHJxRkVqamhobGFrMk94OFNMNXRGM0xrQ0FodWI5UnJTajBEYXF1cndyNDRlR3I5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNQTdLbFZnelg0TzNOeWlxMzBrR0ZNcGc2TGVOdXVaekV5Zm1Fb3pDdG5tNEVyUFhvdEhWVnZ4ZGx5TGx3emtROUZJQm5yUkdkWjZPczB6VlFGekNuYnZiakxFWEJrTnYxcHRNa1ZDMVFDSHk5ZFk1UkF1b2d3NWlieW9ubEQ3SUgyOW0xSUNOSmxsM2RmY0JrOEFNT3VMdWMyRG16Wk04WlF4MmU2Sk41aG9xWmw4RHlhTHA2c09qd2xzaWhhdXNZRzlPUnNzcTZicVkzWmxhNNIB3AFBVV95cUxPN2NNRlFnT0Qyc2JDYzlUTmFMMU1NeW1KQWR4anFMYlkxVjRkWmpTRVJoTHpXOGN0anp1VnRrSFJkbmtXNWw5emgyal9McklDRUlHWklueE9ueGxSWkV2cTNuVnlzekRRS3JvclFHamIwdzh5eFJyU1I3TXhZdzYzX2ptLThzNUI2RnJVOG1iR0lrYk1aQVdyT3U0TkFkOUdqN24xZ192UVVia19raHJxRkVqamhobGFrMk94OFNMNXRGM0xrQ0FodWI5UnJTajBEYXF1cndyNDRlR3I5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:55:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maha poll victory has ended Pawar’s ‘politics of deceit’, says Amit Shah - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amit Shah Claims Maharashtra Poll Victory Signals End of Pawar's Deceitful Politics</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong><time>Jan 13, 2025</time> <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/ANI-20250112242-0_1736721714116_1736721740869.jpg" alt="Maha poll victory has ended Pawar’s ‘politics of deceit’, says Amit Shah(Devendra Fadnavis-X)" title="Maha poll victory has ended Pawar’s ‘politics of deceit’, says Amit Shah(Devendra Fadnavis-X)">
<figcaption>Maha poll victory has ended Pawar’s ‘politics of deceit’, says Amit Shah(Devendra Fadnavis-X)</figcaption>
<p>Union Home Minister Amit Shah praised the BJP's significant victory in Maharashtra's assembly elections, asserting it will have lasting effects on national politics and end the deceitful tactics of opposing leaders.</p>
<ul>
<li>Shah highlighted that the victory gives a response to Sharad Pawar's politics of deceit, which began in 1978.</li>
<li>The BJP aims to remain "unconquerable" in future elections, according to Shah.</li>
<li>Shah declared that this victory will be remembered for the next 25 years in India's political history.</li>
<li>He emphasized that voters have reinforced their support for Modi's development agenda.</li>
<li>Shah criticized Pawar's leadership, citing failures to address issues like drought and suicide in Maharashtra.</li>
<li>He claimed that the INDIA alliance is fracturing, pointing to internal conflicts among its members.</li>
<li>Shah announced a goal for India to be Naxal-free by March 31, 2026.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The electoral victory (in Maharashtra) has buried the politics of betrayal that started by Sharad Pawar in 1978.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Amit Shah's statements underscore a confidence in the BJP's trajectory moving forward, while making a clear reference to the decline of Sharad Pawar's influence in Maharashtra politics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/mumbai-news/maha-poll-victory-has-ended-pawar-s-politics-of-deceit-says-amit-shah-101736708117330.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/mumbai-news/maha-poll-victory-has-ended-pawar-s-politics-of-deceit-says-amit-shah-101736708117330.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:55:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[25-member SIT set up to probe Dalit athlete’s rape case, 13 more held - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/25member-sit-set-up-to-probe-dalit-athlete-s-rape-case-13-more-held-101736707635804.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/25member-sit-set-up-to-probe-dalit-athlete-s-rape-case-13-more-held-101736707635804.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:47:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pathanamthitta serial sexual abuse case: 28 arrested including minors, SIT deployed - Onmanorama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pathanamthitta Serial Sexual Abuse Case Leads to 28 Arrests, Including Minors</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p>
<p>The sexual abuse case involving a minor girl in Pathanamthitta has prompted the arrest of 28 individuals as investigations continue.</p>
<ul>
  <li>28 individuals have been arrested, including four minors.</li>
  <li>A Special Investigation Team (SIT) has been formed to investigate the case.</li>
  <li>Seven cases have been registered at the Pathanamthitta police station related to the incident.</li>
  <li>The survivor, now 18, revealed her ordeal to a community counsellor.</li>
  <li>The accused befriended the survivor using social media.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The efforts are focused on collecting scientific evidence, including the examination of mobile phones, to strengthen the case."</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing investigation aims to ensure justice and prevent further incidents of abuse.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.onmanorama.com/news/kerala/2025/01/12/pathanamthitta-serial-sexual-abuse-case-arrest-minor-sit-accused-ranni.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.onmanorama.com/news/kerala/2025/01/12/pathanamthitta-serial-sexual-abuse-case-arrest-minor-sit-accused-ranni.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:28:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Retired IAS officer kicked, punched by bus conductor over tiff in Jaipur - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/jaipur/retd-ias-officer-assaulted-by-bus-conductor-fir-filed/articleshow/117180239.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/jaipur/retd-ias-officer-assaulted-by-bus-conductor-fir-filed/articleshow/117180239.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Retired IAS officer kicked, punched by bus conductor over tiff in Jaipur - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/jaipur/retd-ias-officer-assaulted-by-bus-conductor-fir-filed/articleshow/117180239.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/jaipur/retd-ias-officer-assaulted-by-bus-conductor-fir-filed/articleshow/117180239.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates: In trial attempt at docking, SpaDeX satellites successfully come 3 meters to each other, says ISRO - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>April 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2023/04/SpaDex_d73f5d.jpg?w=640" alt="ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>ISRO SpaDeX Docking Mission Live Updates: SpaDeX satellites hold position at 15m. (@isro/X)</figcaption>
<p>The Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) successfully conducted a trial attempt where the SpaDeX satellites came within 3 meters of each other, prior to further data analysis.</p>
<ul>
<li>The docking mission aims to demonstrate in-space docking using small spacecraft.</li>
<li>If successful, India will join the ranks of the US, Russia, and China in mastering complex docking technologies.</li>
<li>ISRO emphasizes caution due to the complexity of docking two moving satellites.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Getting it right is more important than getting it done on schedule.”</blockquote>
<p>This mission is vital for ISRO's future ambitions, including lunar sample return missions and the establishment of a space station by 2035.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/science/isro-spadex-docking-mission-live-updates-9773511/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/science/isro-spadex-docking-mission-live-updates-9773511/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:58:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra: 8 dead, several injured as tempo rams into truck carrying iron rods in Nashik - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maharashtra: 8 dead, several injured as tempo rams into truck carrying iron rods in Nashik</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Mahakumbh_1736700867277_1736700867573.png" alt="Rescue operations were started by police and fire brigade personnel along with residents and passersby in the congested stretch immediately.(PTI)"><figcaption>Rescue operations were started by police and fire brigade personnel along with residents and passersby in the congested stretch immediately.(PTI)</figcaption><p>A tragic accident occurred in Nashik, Maharashtra, where eight individuals lost their lives and several others suffered injuries due to a collision between a tempo and a truck carrying iron rods.</p><ul><li>The accident happened at Dwarka Circle around 7:30 PM.</li><li>The tempo had 16 passengers returning from a religious event in Niphad.</li><li>Initial reports indicated that some victims died on the spot, while others were critically injured.</li><li>Immediate rescue operations were conducted by police, fire brigade personnel, and bystanders.</li><li>The injured are currently receiving treatment at nearby hospitals, with concerns that the death toll may increase.</li></ul><blockquote>“There were 16 passengers in the tempo, which was on its way to CIDCO area here... the tempo driver lost control of the vehicle and rear-ended the truck.” - Police Official</blockquote><p>The incident highlights the urgent need for road safety measures, particularly in densely populated areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maharashtra-8-dead-several-injured-as-tempo-rams-into-truck-carrying-iron-rods-in-nashik-101736700711855.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maharashtra-8-dead-several-injured-as-tempo-rams-into-truck-carrying-iron-rods-in-nashik-101736700711855.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:55:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 killed after bus plunges 100 metres into gorge in Uttarakhand - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 killed after bus plunges 100 metres into gorge in Uttarakhand</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/uttarakhand-accident.jpg?w=640' alt='Uttarakhand bus accident' width='640' height='360'><figcaption>The bus was travelling from Pauri to Dehalchauri with 22 passengers on board. (Express photo)</figcaption><p>Six people died and several were injured after a private bus fell into a gorge in Uttarakhand’s Pauri Garhwal district on Sunday evening.</p><ul><li>The bus was carrying 28 passengers from Pauri to Dehalchauri.</li><li>Emergency services were alerted around 4:30 pm when the bus lost control and fell 100 metres.</li><li>Rescue work was immediately initiated by the State Disaster Response Force and local police.</li><li>The injured were taken to a district hospital; some were referred to Srinagar hospital.</li><li>The deceased included Sunita (25), Pramila, Priyanshu (17), Nagendra, Sulochna, and Prem (70).</li></ul><blockquote>“The deeply tragic news of the bus accident... I pray to the Almighty to grant peace to the departed souls and give strength to the grieving families.” - Chief Minister Pushkar Singh Dhami</blockquote><p>This tragic accident highlights the risks associated with mountainous travel and the urgency for improved road safety measures in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/uttarakhand-bus-accident-five-killed-pauri-garhwal-district-9775116/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/uttarakhand-bus-accident-five-killed-pauri-garhwal-district-9775116/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bus conductor assaults retired IAS officer in Jaipur over Rs 10 - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxOX0tZa0hoZTBOa2ZMSC02a3pzMk5zT0xCeGZsTk92dzZfV25Ra05HMEtfaEl2UXZIalpJTURlU05BcmdjNlFkd3NMOGNQa0NLM2VLN1BUR3VJb0xOY2xTamNoUVhXSy04TFliWnpKQUZxMmNxNjNZRTdBUHU4SmRtMU8ybGVPUXoyWVMtMURMNFZ1WFFtMWNtUVRhMG1NRWRhRFhTRV9wY9IBqwFBVV95cUxNYzNhOC1NeU5ZNUFlUU5jTmV4NEcwTy1RQ0RyME5rQTBqVXFCN1FuVXdyZWhGb1N6M2dGeDZMRmhmS1RLd3Y1bzFnVml1MXlSbFRUN2JIRWp3YmhQbFQ0TW13UnBCcHM0bDlidlZTRzE1UHM3Rk1Xc2VKMVNscll0SlNveDFNTHg4eUlQR1c2NmhWUlZEMXhoVEZRNDFLbVdhM1FiUE9kdHd6WnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxOX0tZa0hoZTBOa2ZMSC02a3pzMk5zT0xCeGZsTk92dzZfV25Ra05HMEtfaEl2UXZIalpJTURlU05BcmdjNlFkd3NMOGNQa0NLM2VLN1BUR3VJb0xOY2xTamNoUVhXSy04TFliWnpKQUZxMmNxNjNZRTdBUHU4SmRtMU8ybGVPUXoyWVMtMURMNFZ1WFFtMWNtUVRhMG1NRWRhRFhTRV9wY9IBqwFBVV95cUxNYzNhOC1NeU5ZNUFlUU5jTmV4NEcwTy1RQ0RyME5rQTBqVXFCN1FuVXdyZWhGb1N6M2dGeDZMRmhmS1RLd3Y1bzFnVml1MXlSbFRUN2JIRWp3YmhQbFQ0TW13UnBCcHM0bDlidlZTRzE1UHM3Rk1Xc2VKMVNscll0SlNveDFNTHg4eUlQR1c2NmhWUlZEMXhoVEZRNDFLbVdhM1FiUE9kdHd6WnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:45:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five killed as bus falls into 100-metre gorge in Uttarakhand's Pauri Garhwal - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Five killed as bus falls into 100-metre gorge in Uttarakhand's Pauri Garhwal</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 23, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Bus accident in Uttarakhand"><figcaption>A bus fell into a gorge in Uttarakhand, resulting in multiple fatalities.</figcaption><p>A tragic bus accident in Uttarakhand's Pauri Garhwal district has claimed the lives of five individuals, adding to the ongoing concerns about road safety in the region.</p><ul><li>The bus fell into a 100-metre gorge.</li><li>Rescue operations were initiated immediately following the incident.</li><li>Authorities are investigating the cause of the accident.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are deeply saddened by the loss of lives in this unfortunate incident,” said a local official.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the pressing need for improved road safety measures to prevent future tragedies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/five-killed-as-bus-falls-into-100-metre-gorge-in-uttarakhands-pauri-garhwal/articleshow/117178174.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/five-killed-as-bus-falls-into-100-metre-gorge-in-uttarakhands-pauri-garhwal/articleshow/117178174.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Motivates Youth To Take Ownership Of 'Viksit Bharat', Warns Against 'Chalta Hai' Attitude - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Motivates Youth To Take Ownership Of 'Viksit Bharat', Warns Against 'Chalta Hai' Attitude</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi addresses the Viksit Bharat Young Leaders Dialogue 2025."><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi addresses the Viksit Bharat Young Leaders Dialogue 2025.</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi emphasized the need for Indian youth to take ownership of the 'Viksit Bharat' initiative during the Viksit Bharat Young Leaders Dialogue 2025. He expressed confidence that India’s youth could help elevate the nation to developed status by 2047.</p><ul><li>Modi urged young people to reject the 'chalta hai' attitude and strive for significant changes in the country.</li><li>He highlighted the importance of setting and achieving ambitious goals, stating that it is a collective responsibility of all citizens.</li><li>He recalled Swami Vivekananda’s faith in the youth, asserting that today's youth are pivotal in solving the nation's challenges.</li><li>Modi mentioned a young athlete’s nickname for him as 'Param Mitra', emphasizing the trust and connection with the youth.</li><li>The Prime Minister affirmed that with unified efforts, no power can stop India's progress.</li></ul><blockquote>“Setting and achieving big goals is not just the work of any one government machinery; it is a must that every citizen of the country joins it...” - PM Modi</blockquote><p>In conclusion, PM Modi's message aims to inspire the younger generation to actively participate in the nation’s development journey towards becoming a fully developed country by the year 2047.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-motivates-youth-to-take-ownership-of-viksit-bharat-warns-against-chalta-hai-attitude-9186253.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-motivates-youth-to-take-ownership-of-viksit-bharat-warns-against-chalta-hai-attitude-9186253.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:28:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cracks in MVA: Uddhav Sena says will go solo in local elections - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxQNFFTbXhlN3FkWlFyMlJDenV5bTc5WmpXVi15REIwdGdTREVsbmdiSzJnOHV2dTFsSG9YalNfV3I2SGUwUlJKWkhnSUl4Y2s4djloUWtIXzgxRmxNUXloTnVXWE0zdDAxRWVGNnJsdUN4X2w4RHlLcUp1dXNOSHlYTzBuUXlfbThZQjd2TUhIS3VEVDB0V2RVZTNRVXpKSDMxdWZVWXJyc2R6SldvZU5N0gG2AUFVX3lxTE9YeEVQdV9zOE5HQzdhM0Rzb1pZZVFscklGOEVuV1FoR3Fvd0d0NUJYMTJYbnJ0c1JMa0VmZDNHY2lVdnY5ZzR4S2o2clUwX3JtUFlXeWZVQlU5cFB1Yl95cmtzVkJCc0VERFE5WlVXQy1STFNZTTl0QXAxZkdzbTdsS0xLSE5Nb3gtdWRxT3lFc3c1S3l2OXBpc19lcjZPdVpzd0c4MXVTc29VSEdmc1ptYWZOMFRn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxQNFFTbXhlN3FkWlFyMlJDenV5bTc5WmpXVi15REIwdGdTREVsbmdiSzJnOHV2dTFsSG9YalNfV3I2SGUwUlJKWkhnSUl4Y2s4djloUWtIXzgxRmxNUXloTnVXWE0zdDAxRWVGNnJsdUN4X2w4RHlLcUp1dXNOSHlYTzBuUXlfbThZQjd2TUhIS3VEVDB0V2RVZTNRVXpKSDMxdWZVWXJyc2R6SldvZU5N0gG2AUFVX3lxTE9YeEVQdV9zOE5HQzdhM0Rzb1pZZVFscklGOEVuV1FoR3Fvd0d0NUJYMTJYbnJ0c1JMa0VmZDNHY2lVdnY5ZzR4S2o2clUwX3JtUFlXeWZVQlU5cFB1Yl95cmtzVkJCc0VERFE5WlVXQy1STFNZTTl0QXAxZkdzbTdsS0xLSE5Nb3gtdWRxT3lFc3c1S3l2OXBpc19lcjZPdVpzd0c4MXVTc29VSEdmc1ptYWZOMFRn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>