<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 22:16:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 22:16:11 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court grants ex-IAS trainee Puja Khedkar interim protection from arrest - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Grants Puja Khedkar Interim Protection from Arrest</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Puja-Khedkar.jpg?w=640" alt="Puja Khedkar" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>On August 1, 2024, a Delhi court dismissed Puja Khedkar’s anticipatory bail plea. (File Photo)</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court has granted interim protection from arrest to former IAS trainee Puja Khedkar, who is accused of fraudulently clearing the civil services examination conducted by the UPSC.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court issued a notice on Khedkar's appeal against a Delhi High Court order denying her anticipatory bail.</li><li>The court has ordered that no coercive actions be taken against her until the next hearing on February 14.</li><li>Khedkar has been accused of cheating and improperly using OBC and disability benefits in the civil services exam.</li><li>She has denied all allegations and claims that the prosecution's case is based on accessible documentary evidence.</li><li>A Delhi court previously dismissed her plea for anticipatory bail, citing strong indications of her intent to deceive the complainant, UPSC.</li></ul><blockquote>“Prima facie, it is established that the conduct of the petitioner has been truly driven with the motive to dupe the complainant.”</blockquote><p>This case highlights significant legal proceedings involving allegations of systemic fraud in civil services recruitment, affecting perceptions of the integrity of public examinations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/supreme-court-ex-ias-trainee-puja-khedkar-arrest-protection-9779919/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/supreme-court-ex-ias-trainee-puja-khedkar-arrest-protection-9779919/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 20:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Train link to Kashmir a step closer to tracks, gets safety clearance for last leg between Katra and Reasi - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Train to Kashmir Soon as Last Leg of Project Gets Safety Clearance</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/kashmir-train-2_20250115104130.jpg?w=640" alt="The Kashmir line or USBRL project was sanctioned in 1994-95." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>The Kashmir line or USBRL project was sanctioned in 1994-95. (Express Archive)</figcaption><p>The long-awaited rail link to Kashmir is set to begin operations as the final segment, the Katra-Reasi section, has received safety clearance from authorities.</p><ul><li>The Commissioner of Railway Safety approved the Katra-Reasi stretch after a detailed investigation.</li><li>Due to security concerns, trains will operate only during daylight hours.</li><li>The maximum speed for trains between Katra and Reasi has been set at 85 km/h.</li><li>The first service will include an eight-coach Vande Bharat train capable of operating in severe winter conditions.</li><li>The project, initiated in 1994-95, faced significant challenges including difficult terrain and the need for advanced construction techniques.</li></ul><blockquote>“Now, the entire link is getting connected and the dream of a train to Kashmir will come true soon.” – Dinesh Chand Deshwal, CRS</blockquote><p>This project marks a significant advancement in connecting Jammu with Srinagar through rail, enhancing accessibility and potentially promoting tourism and economic development in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/business/train-kashmir-railway-approval-katra-resai-9780281/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/business/train-kashmir-railway-approval-katra-resai-9780281/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 20:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Commissions Three Made-In-India Frontline Naval Combatants In Major Defence Boost - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-dedicate-three-naval-ships-to-nation-in-mumbai-ins-surat-nilgiri-vaghsheer-indian-navy-9189211.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/pm-modi-dedicate-three-naval-ships-to-nation-in-mumbai-ins-surat-nilgiri-vaghsheer-indian-navy-9189211.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka High Court Lifts Stay On Lokayukta Probe In MUDA Scam Case Against Siddaramaiah - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka High Court Lifts Stay On Lokayukta Probe In MUDA Scam Case Against Siddaramaiah</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Karnataka Chief Minister Siddaramaiah. (PTI file photo)"><figcaption>Karnataka Chief Minister Siddaramaiah. (PTI file photo)</figcaption></figure><p>The Karnataka High Court has lifted the stay on the Lokayukta probe in the MUDA scam involving Chief Minister Siddaramaiah, directing the investigation to continue with a report due by January 27.</p><ul><li>The High Court required Lokayukta to continue its investigation and submit a report of findings.</li><li>A directive was made for the Lokayukta to present all documentation gathered to date.</li><li>Arguments were made about the potential transfer of the investigation to the CBI, following claims of bias.</li><li>Justice M Nagaprasanna emphasized the importance of a detailed and impartial investigation.</li><li>Future hearings are set with deadlines for report submissions and case reviews.</li></ul><blockquote>“Lokayukta to place on record the details of investigation conducted till today. The investigation by Lokayukta shall continue…” - Justice M Nagaprasanna</blockquote><p>This recent development moves forward the investigations into the allegations against Siddaramaiah, signifying a critical juncture in the case.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/karnataka-high-court-lifts-stay-on-lokayukta-probe-in-muda-scam-case-siddaramaiah-congress-bjp-latest-updates-9189354.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/karnataka-high-court-lifts-stay-on-lokayukta-probe-in-muda-scam-case-siddaramaiah-congress-bjp-latest-updates-9189354.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:07:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet IIT Baba, aerospace engineer whose quest for truth led him to spiritualism - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meet IIT Baba, aerospace engineer whose quest for truth led him to spiritualism</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 15, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p>
<img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/baba-abhay-singh--iit-baba-at-maha-kumbh-155946879-16x9_0.jpeg?VersionId=dJV2lN..qaPTbE3uEcjm.uY4XbzsXdL5&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Baba Abhay Singh, IIT Baba at Maha Kumbh" title="Baba Abhay Singh is an alumnus of IIT-Bombay and has also been a professional photographer in the past." height="388">
<figcaption>Baba Abhay Singh is an alumnus of IIT-Bombay and has also been a professional photographer in the past.</figcaption>
<p>At the Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj, Baba Abhay Singh, known as 'IIT Baba', shares his journey from an IIT-Bombay aerospace engineer to a spiritual seeker. His story is one of transformation, driven by a deep quest for knowledge and personal freedom.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Baba Abhay Singh, originally from Haryana, transitioned from engineering to arts before finding his path in spirituality.</li>
  <li>Faced with familial challenges, including a difficult childhood, he turned to photography and education.</li>
  <li>His journey involved exploring diverse subjects like Sanskrit, psychology, and the intersections of science and spirituality.</li>
  <li>He emphasizes the importance of personal freedom and fluidity in spiritual practice, rejecting formal titles.</li>
  <li>IIT Baba promotes yoga and Vedic teachings as pathways to spiritual liberation (moksha).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I don't want to get stuck, I don't want to stop. When a man doesn't get stuck anywhere, then he becomes free."</blockquote>
<p>Through his experiences, IIT Baba illustrates that the journey of exploration and introspection is crucial for personal and spiritual growth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/baba-abhay-singh-iit-bombay-now-at-maha-kumbh-in-quest-for-knowledge-2665372-2025-01-15</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/baba-abhay-singh-iit-bombay-now-at-maha-kumbh-in-quest-for-knowledge-2665372-2025-01-15</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:24:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AIBE 19 Result 2024 Soon At allindiabarexamination.com, Know Simple Steps To Check - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxOVG94MktFc2dxUmlLM3k4U19EQmktVl81bWZlSUE3Sy1Ddnk4ZVNTc05pV3Y1ZXFIdmRUWklLQnZETzJjTzhScDNZcE9Kd0NZcjNPZ1lRTEt0THdGemFpZ0V2SkJfbjJPZGwxWXV4dkw2UFRyM1FzSFRvcGt4a0hlc2dJZ0p3UVNQZHFlQnBEaEFWckp4SUVvUHN4UlVrel91QVFQU1JfSThVYVZDRGFFaExDU3VhZjBiRWRZUFpMOWU4aVhnc05PcTU0X1dxUUHSAdQBQVVfeXFMT0VtcXpmc3BjOUY5a0tnb0dRalV4WC1wdFJWU1hEa0RDejBVNmtZbzVFY2VxX0h1VjlXcU5BczQ1X0ZQcXJjRXJRV2lheGZSdUJCTHBsQ3pRUmg4aUowam1EbDhKTlUyNmNDTzExMFBkWmJuNkM5QTM5UGI0N05xeXRRenJheFZJcy1Pb0xmd0Y5RkV0b2lsR0dqbnZGZG1VQ3FGS0N1VTVtaXAza1IwNmNRNS0tOEpfenN2QnkzcU53QmZFdDBoMUNEbThMNm1pYTRYYm0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxOVG94MktFc2dxUmlLM3k4U19EQmktVl81bWZlSUE3Sy1Ddnk4ZVNTc05pV3Y1ZXFIdmRUWklLQnZETzJjTzhScDNZcE9Kd0NZcjNPZ1lRTEt0THdGemFpZ0V2SkJfbjJPZGwxWXV4dkw2UFRyM1FzSFRvcGt4a0hlc2dJZ0p3UVNQZHFlQnBEaEFWckp4SUVvUHN4UlVrel91QVFQU1JfSThVYVZDRGFFaExDU3VhZjBiRWRZUFpMOWU4aVhnc05PcTU0X1dxUUHSAdQBQVVfeXFMT0VtcXpmc3BjOUY5a0tnb0dRalV4WC1wdFJWU1hEa0RDejBVNmtZbzVFY2VxX0h1VjlXcU5BczQ1X0ZQcXJjRXJRV2lheGZSdUJCTHBsQ3pRUmg4aUowam1EbDhKTlUyNmNDTzExMFBkWmJuNkM5QTM5UGI0N05xeXRRenJheFZJcy1Pb0xmd0Y5RkV0b2lsR0dqbnZGZG1VQ3FGS0N1VTVtaXAza1IwNmNRNS0tOEpfenN2QnkzcU53QmZFdDBoMUNEbThMNm1pYTRYYm0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:14:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AAP's Sanjay Singh accuses Delhi poll official of secretly reposting BJP's X posts; DEO responds - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AAP's Sanjay Singh Accuses Delhi Poll Official of Secretly Reposting BJP Posts</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Sanjay_Singh_1736959016344_1736959016657.jpg" alt="Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leader Sanjay Singh.(PTI)"><figcaption>Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leader Sanjay Singh.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) MP Sanjay Singh has accused the New Delhi district election officer of secretly reposting posts from the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) on social media.</p><ul><li>Elections for the Delhi legislative assembly are scheduled for February 5, with results on February 8.</li><li>Singh shared a screenshot showing the district election officer's repost of a BJP post featuring party leaders.</li><li>He claimed this is unprecedented in India, suggesting the DEO has political affiliations with the BJP.</li><li>The DEO responded, clarifying that the repost was inadvertent and claiming to promote accuracy in official communication.</li><li>The Social Media Cell responsible for the DEO's social media has been reorganized to prevent future errors.</li></ul><blockquote>“For the first time in the history of India - Election Officer of New Delhi started retweeting BJP's tweets secretly.” - Sanjay Singh</blockquote><p>This incident raises concerns over the impartiality of election officials ahead of the crucial assembly elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/aaps-sanjay-singh-accuses-delhi-poll-official-of-secretly-reposting-bjps-x-posts-deo-responds-101736959022636.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/aaps-sanjay-singh-accuses-delhi-poll-official-of-secretly-reposting-bjps-x-posts-deo-responds-101736959022636.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Strictest pollution curbs back in Delhi: Construction banned, hybrid classes on - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Strictest Pollution Curbs Back in Delhi: Construction Banned, Hybrid Classes On</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/delhi-air-153537725-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=DNzGrNN0JduNJT66Ot8K7OnrLdZ_pMwb&amp;size=690:388" alt="Vehicles move on a road amid dense morning fog in New Delhi. (PTI photo)" />
<figcaption>Vehicles move on a road amid dense morning fog in New Delhi. (PTI photo)</figcaption>
<p>Authorities in Delhi-NCR have implemented the strictest pollution measures due to worsening air quality conditions, leading to significant restrictions on construction and classes.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Air Quality Index (AQI) reached 386, categorized as 'Very Poor'.</li>
  <li>All construction activities have been banned under Stage-4 of the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP).</li>
  <li>Hybrid classes for students in grades 6-9 and 11 may be initiated.</li>
  <li>Non-essential polluting trucks are barred from entering Delhi.</li>
  <li>Favorable weather conditions, vehicle emissions, and other pollution sources contribute to the deteriorating situation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We have seen a significant rise in pollution levels, the AQI jumped from 275 to nearly 400 in just a day.”</blockquote>
<p>These measures are part of a broader response to control air quality in the region, aiming to tackle both immediate and long-term environmental concerns.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/cities/delhi/story/pollution-curbs-grap-iv-delhi-air-quality-worsens-aqi-2665270-2025-01-15</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/cities/delhi/story/pollution-curbs-grap-iv-delhi-air-quality-worsens-aqi-2665270-2025-01-15</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:41:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Duty Of Government & Local Authorities To Provide Basic Toilet & Sanitation Facilities Within Court... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Directs Construction of Toilets in Court Premises for Inclusivity</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p><p>The Supreme Court of India has issued directives for the establishment of toilet facilities in court premises across the country, emphasizing the need for privacy and safety for women and transgender individuals.</p><ul><li>The initiative comes after a writ petition highlighted the absence of basic sanitation facilities for all genders in courts.</li><li>The court referenced constitutional provisions and accessibility guidelines to support its decision.</li><li>It emphasized the importance of clean public toilets for public health and human dignity.</li><li>The directive requires state governments to allocate funds for construction and maintenance of these facilities.</li><li>A status report from all High Courts and States/UTs is mandated within four months to ensure compliance.</li></ul><blockquote>“The entire analysis makes it abundantly clear that public health is of paramount importance...”</blockquote><p>This ruling reflects a commitment to improving sanitation facilities within the judicial system, ensuring dignity and safety for all individuals accessing courts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-court-judgment-toilet-facilities-for-ladies-and-transgenders-right-to-privacy-rajeeb-kalita-vs-union-of-india-281076</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-court-judgment-toilet-facilities-for-ladies-and-transgenders-right-to-privacy-rajeeb-kalita-vs-union-of-india-281076</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:30:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal net worth: A look at ex-Delhi CM's assets, how his income changed in 5 years - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arvind Kejriwal net worth: A look at ex-Delhi CM's assets, how his income changed in 5 years</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 15, 2025</strong> / <strong>Source: Moneycontrol</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250115064236_Arvind-Kejriwal-Delhi-election.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled to take place on February 5, with the results to be announced on February 8." title="The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled to take place on February 5, with the results to be announced on February 8." width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled to take place on February 5, with the results to be announced on February 8.</figcaption>
<p>Arvind Kejriwal, the national convenor of the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP), has seen a marginal increase in his family net worth over the past five years, rising from Rs 3.4 crore to Rs 4.2 crore.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kejriwal declared net assets totaling Rs 1.73 crore in his affidavit.</li>
  <li>His assets include bank savings of Rs 2.96 lakh and cash of Rs 50,000.</li>
  <li>He owns immovable assets worth Rs 1.7 crore but has no car or house listed.</li>
  <li>For the financial year 2023-24, Kejriwal reported an income of Rs 7.21 lakh.</li>
  <li>His wife, Sunita Kejriwal, has assets totaling Rs 2.5 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Kejriwal’s declared family net worth has increased marginally from Rs 3.4 crore to Rs 4.2 crore over five years."</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the couple’s total net worth amounts to Rs 4.23 crore, showing a steady increase in their declared assets over time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/elections/assembly-election/delhi/arvind-kejriwal-net-worth-a-look-at-ex-delhi-cm-s-assets-how-his-income-changed-in-5-years-article-12911736.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/elections/assembly-election/delhi/arvind-kejriwal-net-worth-a-look-at-ex-delhi-cm-s-assets-how-his-income-changed-in-5-years-article-12911736.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:29:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UP: Meerut hospital director, 5 others booked for 'removing' woman's kidney - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UP: Meerut hospital director, 5 others booked for 'removing' woman's kidney</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/India_3_1734523619133_1734523643821.jpg" alt="UP: Meerut hospital director, 5 others booked for 'removing' woman's kidney"><figcaption>UP: Meerut hospital director, 5 others booked for 'removing' woman's kidney</figcaption><p>A case has been registered against six individuals, including the director of a private hospital in Meerut, for allegedly conducting an illegal kidney removal from a patient in 2017.</p><ul><li>The case was initiated after the victim, Kavita Devi, filed a complaint claiming that her kidney was removed during treatment.</li><li>The complaint alleges illegal organ trade and threats from hospital staff when she sought accountability.</li><li>The hospital has denied the allegations and claimed the accusations are an attempt at extortion.</li><li>The police have registered the FIR under various IPC sections and the Transplantation of Human Organs Act.</li></ul><blockquote>“The doctor advised surgery, assuring me it would address internal health issues. However, further tests revealed that my left kidney was missing,” - Kavita Devi.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights serious concerns regarding medical ethics and patient rights within healthcare facilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/up-meerut-hospital-director-5-others-booked-for-removing-woman-s-kidney-101736958460042.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/up-meerut-hospital-director-5-others-booked-for-removing-woman-s-kidney-101736958460042.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:27:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['A clear message': US removes 3 Indian entities from restrictive list, adds 11 from China over national s - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘A clear message’: US removes 3 Indian entities from restrictive list, adds 11 from China over national security concerns</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 19, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="US-China Relations" width="600" height="400"><figcaption>The US has made significant adjustments to its list of entities over national security concerns.</figcaption><p>The recent changes made by the US in its restrictions on entities reveal a strategic shift, emphasizing its ongoing concerns regarding national security from both Indian and Chinese firms.</p><ul><li>The US has removed three Indian entities from its restrictive list.</li><li>In contrast, the US has added 11 new entities from China, highlighting rising tensions.</li><li>Officials stated that the decision aims to protect US national security interests.</li></ul><blockquote>“The list changes reflect our commitment to safeguarding our technological and national security interests,” said a senior US official.</blockquote><p>This decision illustrates the shifting dynamics in US-India-China relations and underscores the complexities involved in international trade and security.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/a-clear-message-us-removes-3-indian-entities-from-restrictive-list-adds-11-from-china-over-national-security-concerns/articleshow/117273169.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/a-clear-message-us-removes-3-indian-entities-from-restrictive-list-adds-11-from-china-over-national-security-concerns/articleshow/117273169.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Wars to turn more violent and unpredictable': Rajnath Singh's warning for Armymen - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Wars to turn more violent and unpredictable': Rajnath Singh's warning for Armymen</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>India's Defence Minister Rajnath Singh cautions Armymen about the increasing unpredictability and violence of future wars, emphasizing the need for preparedness in an evolving global landscape.</p><ul><li>Singh warns that warfare dynamics are changing.</li><li>He emphasizes the importance of modern training and technology for Indian Armed Forces.</li><li>The speech reflects on global conflicts impacting military strategies.</li></ul><blockquote>“The nature of wars is changing, and we must be prepared for this evolution.”</blockquote><p>This warning underscores the shifting paradigm of warfare and the necessity for strategic adaptation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/wars-to-turn-more-violent-and-unpredictable-rajnath-singhs-warning-to-armymen/articleshow/117272958.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/wars-to-turn-more-violent-and-unpredictable-rajnath-singhs-warning-to-armymen/articleshow/117272958.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Inaugurates ISKCON Temple In Navi Mumbai | LIVE - Republic World]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQamZIUXNtcV9OTERCT1NmVzlXZ210bmhVbnc0YW00aHdaWUdxRDYxV0Y2aHBVWkZPTG1qOXhNRTBsSGs3REhIaW4zcHB3V0VlVUs4NzFRWUotTjNiam5ISDJDUGZmRmxod1VMcGI5a2FTakxNRFpHLVB2alVncC1YSVZCV0RmemIxbFhyNXlLajhiNU8xWHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQamZIUXNtcV9OTERCT1NmVzlXZ210bmhVbnc0YW00aHdaWUdxRDYxV0Y2aHBVWkZPTG1qOXhNRTBsSGs3REhIaW4zcHB3V0VlVUs4NzFRWUotTjNiam5ISDJDUGZmRmxod1VMcGI5a2FTakxNRFpHLVB2alVncC1YSVZCV0RmemIxbFhyNXlLajhiNU8xWHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:51:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We are fighting BJP, RSS, and the Indian state itself, says Rahul Gandhi; Nadda hits back - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>We are fighting BJP, RSS, and the Indian state itself, says Rahul Gandhi; Nadda hits back</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Wednesday, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/New-Congress-HQ.jpeg' alt='Congress’s new headquarters in New Delhi.'><figcaption>Congress’s new headquarters in New Delhi. (Express Photo)</figcaption><p>In his recent address, Rahul Gandhi criticized the BJP and RSS for allegedly capturing key institutions in India. He condemned the remarks made by Mohan Bhagwat regarding India's true Independence and characterized them as treasonous. Gandhi emphasized the ideological conflict between the Congress party and the RSS.</p><ul><li>Rahul Gandhi stated that the BJP and RSS have captured every institution in India.</li><li>He condemned Mohan Bhagwat's remarks about India's Independence and suggested that they undermine the Constitution.</li><li>During the inauguration of Congress’s new headquarters, Gandhi asserted the need to fight against the BJP and RSS’s vision for India.</li><li>BJP president JP Nadda responded to Gandhi's comments by accusing him of attempting to divide the country.</li><li>Gandhi highlighted the importance of India’s diversity and criticized the current power holders for their centralized and exclusionary vision.</li></ul><blockquote>“To say that India did not get Independence in 1947 is an insult to every single Indian.” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote><p>The ongoing political discourse highlights a growing divide between the Congress party's vision of inclusivity and the RSS's centralized ideology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/mohan-bhagwat-constitution-rahul-gandhi-congresss-new-headquarters-9779671/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/mohan-bhagwat-constitution-rahul-gandhi-congresss-new-headquarters-9779671/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta India apologises for Zuckerberg’s comment on 2024 Lok Sabha polls, calls it "inadvertent error" - The New Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/nation/2025/Jan/15/meta-india-apologises-for-zuckerbergs-comment-on-2024-lok-sabha-polls-calls-it-inadvertent-error</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newindianexpress.com/nation/2025/Jan/15/meta-india-apologises-for-zuckerbergs-comment-on-2024-lok-sabha-polls-calls-it-inadvertent-error</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:39:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh Mela 2025 Live Updates: Day 3 begins, over 3.5 crore devotees take dip in Sangam on first ‘Amrit Snan’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh Mela 2025 Live Updates: Day 3 begins, over 3.5 crore devotees take dip in Sangam on first ‘Amrit Snan’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/kumbh.png?w=640" alt="Mahakumbh 2025, kumbh mela" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Day 3 of Mahakumbh 2025 kicked off with thousands of devotees taking a dip in the Sangam (Photo - UP CM/X)</figcaption><p>Kicking off the third day of the Mahakumbh Mela in Prayagraj, thousands of devotees flocked to the ghats of Triveni Sangam for a holy dip. On the first day of the ‘Amrit Snan’, over 3.5 crore devotees participated, with rose petals showered from helicopters.</p><ul><li>Thousands of devotees at Triveni Sangam for holy dip.</li><li>Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath reported over 3.5 crore devotees on the first day.</li><li>High-security measures with 11 tethered drones for surveillance.</li><li>Up to 50 crore people expected to attend the Mela, including over 20 lakh foreign travelers.</li><li>Kumbh Mela has deep roots in Hindu mythology and is the largest religious gathering globally.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Kumbh Mela dates back thousands of years to ancient Hindu epics and literature.”</blockquote><p>The Mahakumbh Mela represents a significant cultural and religious event, embodying a deep connection to Hindu tradition and spirituality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/mahakumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-amrit-snan-9779388/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/mahakumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-amrit-snan-9779388/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:13:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GRAP-4 restrictions reimposed in Delhi-NCR as air quality worsens - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GRAP-4 restrictions reimposed in Delhi-NCR as air quality worsens</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/v9124m/article69101524.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/WEATHER%20FOG%2015%2001%20NEW%20DELHI%2017.JPG" alt="A thick layer of fog engulfs New Delhi on January 15, 2025." title="A thick layer of fog engulfs New Delhi on January 15, 2025."><figcaption>A thick layer of fog engulfs New Delhi on January 15, 2025. | Photo Credit: Shashi Shekhar Kashyap</figcaption><p>The Centre's panel on Delhi-NCR's air quality has reimposed curbs under stage 4 of the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) due to a sharp decline in air quality. Meteorological conditions have contributed to a significant rise in the air quality index (AQI), prompting immediate action.</p><ul><li>Air quality index soared to 396 on January 15, 2025.</li><li>Stage 4 curbs include banning construction activities and entry of non-essential polluting trucks.</li><li>School classes for grades other than 10 and 12 shifted to hybrid mode.</li><li>Non-essential diesel trucks banned from entering Delhi.</li><li>CAQM directed immediate action under stages 3 and 4 due to worsening air quality forecasts.</li></ul><blockquote>The India Meteorological Department predicts AQI may breach the 400 mark soon.</blockquote><p>This decision is aimed at combating hazardous air quality levels that particularly worsen during winter months in the Delhi-NCR region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/grap-4-curbs-invoked-in-delhi-ncr-amid-sharp-dip-in-air-quality/article69101457.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/grap-4-curbs-invoked-in-delhi-ncr-amid-sharp-dip-in-air-quality/article69101457.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Regularisation as Section Officers in J&K - Cross Town News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxOd2hCUVFaTVBEUllTR0JoRHhjd2dOdERMU1ZQTEx1c1oyY0VyNzBCRmNiX0E3bTNKY3VXYmlvNThsNDNVX01US3F6UF9yb1Fvcm9GajJPVHBtVVFXd1lNVDAyTzZLOUhNdllscHN2NTlSZzh0TUNQaXVQNGpiTHR4cHJMcU5lOV91VHZuTWc1bw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxOd2hCUVFaTVBEUllTR0JoRHhjd2dOdERMU1ZQTEx1c1oyY0VyNzBCRmNiX0E3bTNKY3VXYmlvNThsNDNVX01US3F6UF9yb1Fvcm9GajJPVHBtVVFXd1lNVDAyTzZLOUhNdllscHN2NTlSZzh0TUNQaXVQNGpiTHR4cHJMcU5lOV91VHZuTWc1bw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:39:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NEET PG 2024 Counselling: MCC To Fill 24,314 Seats In Round 3 After Cut-Off Reduction - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NEET PG 2024 Counselling: MCC To Fill 24,314 Seats In Round 3 After Cut-Off Reduction</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="NEET PG 2024: Candidates can select the preferences up to 8 AM on January 16, 2025." title="NEET PG 2024: Candidates can select the preferences up to 8 AM on January 16, 2025." loading="eager">
<figcaption>NEET PG 2024: Candidates can select the preferences up to 8 AM on January 16, 2025. (Representative Image)</figcaption>
<p>The Medical Counselling Committee (MCC) has announced significant updates regarding the NEET PG 2024 counselling process, with 24,314 vacancies available for Round 3 due to a reduction in cut-offs aimed at filling vacant seats.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The MCC has announced 15,902 virtual vacancies for Round 3, allowing candidates to update or vacate their previously allotted seats.</li>
  <li>A total of 8,313 clear vacancies have been identified, along with 99 new seats added for Round 3 across various states.</li>
  <li>Revised cut-offs now allow General Category/EWS candidates with 15 percentile and above, and SC/ST/OBC/PwD candidates with 10 percentile to participate in counselling.</li>
  <li>Registration for Round 3 will end by 12 PM on January 15, 2025, and candidates can choose preferences until 8 AM on January 16, 2025.</li>
  <li>Reporting to allotted colleges will be from January 18 to January 25, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The cut-offs were lowered to prevent PG seats in medical colleges from remaining vacant.”</blockquote>
<p>This initiative is aimed at maximizing the admission rates for NEET PG, ensuring that more candidates can secure their places in medical colleges across India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/education-career/neet-pg-2024-counselling-mcc-to-fill-24314-seats-in-round-3-after-cut-off-reduction-9189098.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/education-career/neet-pg-2024-counselling-mcc-to-fill-24314-seats-in-round-3-after-cut-off-reduction-9189098.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:37:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court calls for separate toilets for men, women, PwD, transgender persons in all courts - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Mandates Separate Toilets in All Courts for Men, Women, PwD, and Transgender Persons</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 15 Jan 2025, 2:28 pm</p><figure><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justice JB Pardiwala and Justice R Mahadevan" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Justice JB Pardiwala and Justice R Mahadevan</figcaption></figure><p>The Supreme Court has issued a pivotal directive for all states and High Courts to provide separate toilet facilities for men, women, persons with disabilities, and transgender individuals at court premises, emphasizing sanitation as a human right.</p><ul><li>All States and High Courts must construct separate toilet facilities for men, women, PwD, and transgender persons.</li><li>These facilities must be identifiable and accessible to judges, advocates, litigants, and court staff.</li><li>States must allocate sufficient funds for construction and maintenance of these facilities.</li><li>Toilets should contain stocked sanitary pad dispensers where applicable.</li></ul><blockquote>“Access to proper sanitation is recognized as a fundamental right under Article 21 of the Constitution.”</blockquote><p>This ruling was made in response to a petition advocating for the need for separate restroom facilities, addressing the basic human rights linked to sanitation in the justice system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/supreme-court-separate-toilets-men-women-pwd-transgender-persons-all-courts</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/supreme-court-separate-toilets-men-women-pwd-transgender-persons-all-courts</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:28:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Assembly elections: PM Modi, Bansuri Swaraj among BJP's 40 star campaigners - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Assembly elections: PM Modi, Bansuri Swaraj among BJP's 40 star campaigners</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br /><strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/07/PTI07_02_2024_000195B.webp" alt="Bansuri Swaraj" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Bansuri Swaraj</figcaption><p>The Bharatiya Janata Party has announced a list of 40 star campaigners, including Prime Minister Narendra Modi, for the upcoming Delhi Assembly elections. The party seeks to end its 26-year absence of power in Delhi, as the Congress attempts to recover from previous losses.</p><ul><li>BJP releases a list of 40 star campaigners for Delhi Assembly elections.</li><li>Key figures include PM Modi, Bansuri Swaraj, and BJP president JP Nadda.</li><li>The focus of the election campaign includes issues like freebies, law enforcement, education, and governance.</li><li>The election results are scheduled for February 8, following an intense campaign period.</li></ul><blockquote>“The BJP aims to break its 26-year drought of power in Delhi.”</blockquote><p>This election is pivotal for both major parties, as they seek to influence voters and address key issues facing Delhi residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/delhi/delhi-assembly-elections-pm-modi-bansuri-swaraj-among-bjp-s-40-star-campaigners-updates-2025-01-15-971443</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/delhi/delhi-assembly-elections-pm-modi-bansuri-swaraj-among-bjp-s-40-star-campaigners-updates-2025-01-15-971443</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:16:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Police Investigate Hit-and-Run Accident Involving Minister Hebbalkar And MLC On Highway - AllAboutBelgaum]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxPVmxad19IUnRqTnpVOExpTEJNaUdkQld6ODJwWGRzTDQ5ckhQT3hwbEEzMWdTOHA5SkMySV9GOVVna2RkTUJ2VWlNaS12ZlpTYmlrWVliLXRuRTBCbEZYU0xNVmhCZkdtdUNIV2dWV21Mc2dZcHFWZW0wNHdRMTk0NjA1NjFwX29WeTdERFNiNGpNc0hCckxSZm1jZGw2TjVHT3o4dVNZQ25FY0M0SV9LOXdwcVBkT1o5dXV4NUp3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxPVmxad19IUnRqTnpVOExpTEJNaUdkQld6ODJwWGRzTDQ5ckhQT3hwbEEzMWdTOHA5SkMySV9GOVVna2RkTUJ2VWlNaS12ZlpTYmlrWVliLXRuRTBCbEZYU0xNVmhCZkdtdUNIV2dWV21Mc2dZcHFWZW0wNHdRMTk0NjA1NjFwX29WeTdERFNiNGpNc0hCckxSZm1jZGw2TjVHT3o4dVNZQ25FY0M0SV9LOXdwcVBkT1o5dXV4NUp3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:52:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi pollution: Centre imposes GRAP 4 restrictions as air quality worsens in Capital - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi pollution: Centre imposes GRAP 4 restrictions as air quality worsens in Capital</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The Indian government has implemented GRAP 4 restrictions in response to worsening air quality in Delhi. These measures aim to control pollution levels and improve public health.</p><ul><li>The air quality in Delhi has severely declined, prompting urgent governmental action.</li><li>GRAP (Graded Response Action Plan) Level 4 includes various restrictions to mitigate pollution.</li><li>Health officials warn of the potential health risks associated with prolonged exposure to the polluted air.</li><li>Citizens are urged to minimize outdoor activities during high pollution days.</li></ul><blockquote>“The air quality in Delhi poses a significant risk to public health and requires immediate action,” a health officials stated.</blockquote><p>This decision highlights the ongoing struggle against air pollution in urban areas and the need for heightened measures to protect citizens' health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/delhi-pollution-centre-imposes-grap-4-restrictions-as-air-quality-worsens-in-capital/articleshow/117270213.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/delhi-pollution-centre-imposes-grap-4-restrictions-as-air-quality-worsens-in-capital/articleshow/117270213.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GRAP 4 restrictions back in Delhi-NCR amid rising pollution levels - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GRAP 4 Restrictions Reimposed in Delhi-NCR Due to Rising Pollution Levels</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/pollution_1736948238120_1736948238437.jpg" alt="Commuters step out in light foggy winter cold morning amid rising air pollution at Mayur Vihar Road, in New Delhi.(Sunil Ghosh / Hindustan Times)" title="Commuters step out in light foggy winter cold morning amid rising air pollution at Mayur Vihar Road, in New Delhi.(Sunil Ghosh / Hindustan Times)">
<figcaption>Commuters step out in light foggy winter cold morning amid rising air pollution at Mayur Vihar Road, in New Delhi.(Sunil Ghosh / Hindustan Times)</figcaption>
<p>The Central Government has re-imposed GRAP IV restrictions in the Delhi-NCR as the air quality has worsened significantly. This decision comes after Stage 3 restrictions were revoked due to a temporary improvement in air quality.</p>
<ul>
<li>GRAP IV restrictions include a complete ban on all construction activities.</li>
<li>Non-essential polluting trucks are prohibited from entering Delhi.</li>
<li>Schools will shift to online classes except for classes 10 and 12.</li>
<li>Stage 4 is activated due to extremely poor air quality, categorized as 'Severe Plus' (AQI above 450).</li>
<li>The decision was made by the Commission for Air Quality Management (CAQM).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“All actions of the GRAP schedule shall be implemented, monitored and reviewed by all the agencies concerned in the entire NCR to ensure that the AQI levels do not slip further.”</blockquote>
<p>This move aims to protect residents from hazardous air quality during winter months, which is exacerbated by local pollution sources.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/grap-4-restrictions-back-in-delhi-ncr-amid-rising-pollution-levels-101736948031585.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/grap-4-restrictions-back-in-delhi-ncr-amid-rising-pollution-levels-101736948031585.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:35:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stricter Pollution Curbs Under GRAP-4 Reimposed In Delhi - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stricter Pollution Curbs Under GRAP-4 Reimposed In Delhi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 25, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Commission for Air Quality Management</p><p>With dense fog enveloping Delhi and the air quality index hovering dangerously close to the 'severe' category, the Centre's anti-pollution panel has reimposed stricter pollution curbs in the capital and surrounding areas.</p><ul><li>Stricter measures under GRAP-3 were revoked only recently; GRAP-4 measures have not been in effect since December 24.</li><li>The air quality index (AQI) has climbed to 396, likely to exceed the 400 mark.</li><li>Action has been taken under Stage-III and Stage-IV of the GRAP to tackle the severe air quality.</li><li>Restrictions include the use of certain vehicles, potential closure of physical classes, work from home measures, and bans on truck traffic.</li></ul><blockquote>“In an effort to prevent further deterioration of the air quality, the Sub Committee on GRAP hereby decides to straightway invoke ALL actions under Stage-III and Stage-IV of extant Schedule of GRAP...”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the reintroduction of these measures underscores the urgent need to address the critical air quality situation in Delhi and its adjoining regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/stricter-pollution-curbs-under-grap-4-reimposed-in-delhi-7480569</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/stricter-pollution-curbs-under-grap-4-reimposed-in-delhi-7480569</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:26:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[E-Classes Back, Some Categories Of Cars Banned As GRAP 4 Reimposed In Delhi - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/stricter-pollution-curbs-under-grap-4-reimposed-in-delhi-7480569</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/stricter-pollution-curbs-under-grap-4-reimposed-in-delhi-7480569</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:24:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why India is reaching out to the Taliban now - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why India is Engaging with the Taliban: A New Diplomatic Approach</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> BBC News</p>
<img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/f988/live/49a55b20-d268-11ef-9dbb-9559c8b74d9b.jpg.webp" alt="MEA India Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri during a meeting with Acting Foreign Minister of Afghanistan Mawlawi Amir Khan Muttaqi, in Dubai. (Photo Credit: X/@MEAIndia)">
<figcaption>India's foreign secretary Vikram Misri met acting Afghan foreign minister Amir Khan Muttaqi in Dubai</figcaption>
<p>India's recent diplomatic outreach to the Taliban government of Afghanistan marks a notable change in its approach towards regional geopolitics. This engagement follows a significant strategic setback for India after the Taliban's return to power three years ago.</p>
<ul>
<li>India's top diplomat, Vikram Misri, met with Taliban's acting foreign minister, Amir Khan Muttaqi, the highest-level discussion since Kabul's fall.</li>
<li>The meeting signaled the Taliban's interest in enhancing political and economic ties with India.</li>
<li>India aims to leverage trade opportunities and enhance connectivity through Iran's Chabahar port.</li>
<li>Experts suggest this outreach grants the Taliban a degree of international legitimacy.</li>
<li>India has invested heavily in humanitarian efforts in Afghanistan, fostering goodwill among the Afghan people.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The fact that this treatment is coming from India— a nation that never previously had friendly relations with the Taliban— makes this all the more significant...” - Michael Kugelman, Wilson Center</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, India's engagement with the Taliban serves its interest in regional stability and connectivity, amid a complex and challenging geopolitical environment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp8ke9e27dxo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp8ke9e27dxo</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kumbh Mela, explained: Its mythology, history, astrology, and why millions flock to it - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kumbh Mela, explained: Its mythology, history, astrology, and why millions flock to it</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/KUMBH-MELA-1600.jpg?w=640" alt="Kumbh Mela" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>The Kumbh Mela is being held from Jan 13 to Feb 26. (Express photo: Vishal Srivastav)</figcaption><p>The Kumbh Mela takes place in Prayagraj, attracting millions of devotees who seek spiritual merit by bathing in the sacred rivers during the festival. This ancient event blends mythology and astrology, making it one of the largest gatherings in the world.</p><ul><li>The Kumbh Mela is celebrated every 12 years in four locations: Haridwar, Prayagraj, Ujjain, and Nashik.</li><li>The festival's origins are linked to a myth involving gods and demons churning the ocean for the elixir of immortality.</li><li>Devotees believe that bathing in the rivers during Kumbh washes away sins.</li><li>The festival also serves as a meeting point for sadhus and an opportunity for the public to learn from them.</li><li>The next Maha Kumbh will be held in Prayagraj from January 13 to February 26, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“While the importance of the Ganga in Hindu religion is well-known, the Kshipra is believed to have emerged from the heart of Vishnu in his Varah avatar.” - Dr. Dipakbhai Jyotishacharya</blockquote><p>The Kumbh Mela remains a profound cultural and religious phenomenon, drawing immense participation and showcasing the rich traditions of Hinduism.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-culture/kumbh-mela-explained-its-mythology-history-astrology-appeal-9775169/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-culture/kumbh-mela-explained-its-mythology-history-astrology-appeal-9775169/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UP School Holiday: Sambal, Bareilly, & others extend winter vacations due to coldwave - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UP School Holiday: Sambal, Bareilly, & others extend winter vacations due to coldwave</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/coldwave-up-school-holiday.jpg?w=640" alt="UP School Holiday: Lucknow, Bareilly, &amp; others extends winter vacations due to coldwave" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Check the comprehensive list of UP districts where the schools till class 8 are closed. (File)</figcaption><p>Amid the cold wave conditions in North India, various districts in Uttar Pradesh have extended the winter vacations for school students up to Class 8.</p><ul><li>Schools in Meerut, Mathura, Kanpur, Agra, Varanasi, Prayagraj, Amethi, Barabanki, Gorakhpur, and Ballia are open for all classes.</li><li>For Moradabad and Rampur, school timings for Classes 9 to 12 have been revised to 10 am to 3 pm.</li><li>In Ghaziabad, winter vacations for classes 1 to 8 have been extended until January 18.</li></ul><blockquote>The School Education Department in Jammu and Kashmir has also announced a winter holiday schedule.</blockquote><p>Students are advised to stay in touch with their respective schools for information regarding the holiday schedule.</p><p>This article went live on January fifteenth, twenty twenty-five, at forty-two minutes past eleven in the morning.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/education/up-school-holiday-lucknow-bareilly-extend-winter-vacations-ncr-coldwave-9779587/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/education/up-school-holiday-lucknow-bareilly-extend-winter-vacations-ncr-coldwave-9779587/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>