<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:16:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:16:25 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's Modi looks to new economic playbook as risks mount - Reuters India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/india/indias-modi-looks-new-economic-playbook-risks-mount-2025-01-08/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/india/indias-modi-looks-new-economic-playbook-risks-mount-2025-01-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:00:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does woman with below average intelligence have no right to be a mother? Bombay High Court asks - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bombay High Court Addresses Rights of Pregnant Woman with Below Average Intelligence</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 08 Jan 2025, 7:44 am</p><div><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justice Ravindra Ghughe and Justice Rajesh Patil" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Justice Ravindra Ghughe and Justice Rajesh Patil</figcaption></div><p>The Bombay High Court ruled on a case involving a 27-year-old pregnant woman, whose adoptive father sought to terminate her pregnancy due to her below-average intelligence. The court reaffirmed her right to motherhood amid questions about her mental capacity.</p><ul><li>The woman, over 20 weeks pregnant, refused consent for abortion.</li><li>A medical board found both the woman and the foetus to be physically normal.</li><li>The court highlighted that having below-average intelligence does not negate her right to be a mother.</li><li>The father adopted the woman when she was six months old and expressed concerns about her mental health and ability to care for a child.</li><li>The court emphasized parental responsibility and urged the father to support his daughter's choices.</li></ul><blockquote>"Observation is she has below average intelligence. Nobody can be super intelligent.. we are human beings, everybody has different level of intelligence. Because she has below average intelligence, she has no right to be a mother?"</blockquote><p>The case is set to continue on January 13, during which the court will determine if the woman's partner is willing to marry her.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/does-woman-below-average-intelligence-no-right-mother-bombay-high-court-asks</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/does-woman-below-average-intelligence-no-right-mother-bombay-high-court-asks</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:44:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SARFAESI | Borrower's Right Of Redemption Available Only Till Notice For Sale Of Mortgaged Asset Is... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Rules on Borrower's Right of Redemption Under SARFAESI Act</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p><p>The Supreme Court has clarified that the right of a borrower to redeem a secured asset under the SARFAESI Act can only be exercised until a notice for the sale of the property is published.</p><ul><li>The court emphasized the importance of the 2016 amendment to the SARFAESI Act.</li><li>Before the amendment, borrowers could redeem their properties until the sale was completed.</li><li>Now, the redemption right is limited to the period before the sale notice is published.</li><li>The case involved the cancellation of an auction sale by the Delhi High Court, which was overturned by the Supreme Court.</li></ul><blockquote>“...the right of redemption is not unfettered and there is a statutory limitation prescribed to it...”</blockquote><p>Case Title: <strong>Sanjay Sharma v. Kotak Mahindra Bank Ltd.</strong></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/sarfaesi-borrowers-right-of-redemption-available-only-till-notice-for-sale-of-mortgaged-asset-is-published-supreme-court-280293</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/sarfaesi-borrowers-right-of-redemption-available-only-till-notice-for-sale-of-mortgaged-asset-is-published-supreme-court-280293</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:38:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Obscene remarks’ against actor Honey Rose: Businessman Boby Chemmanur taken into Kerala Police custody - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Businessman Boby Chemmanur in Custody for Obscene Remarks Against Actor Honey Rose</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>Kerala Police took businessman Boby Chemmanur into custody on Wednesday for making obscene remarks about Malayalam actor Honey Rose. The case stemmed from comments made during a jewelry showroom inauguration and social media harassment.</p><img src="path/to/image.jpg" alt="Honey Rose" /><figcaption>Honey Rose during a public appearance.</figcaption><p>Honey Rose filed a complaint against Chemmanur along with around 30 others, claiming she was subjected to sexist comments online. She stated, "You (Chemmanur) believe in money power, I believe in the country’s legal system." Chemmanur denied any wrongdoing, claiming his remarks were misunderstood.</p><ul><li>Chemmanur was arrested after police registered a case against him.</li><li>Honey Rose reported psychological distress due to ongoing harassment.</li><li>Prominent figures in the film industry have shown support for Honey Rose.</li></ul><blockquote>Honey Rose expressed relief at the arrest, stating, "I was being stalked and targeted repeatedly... I should have reacted much earlier."</blockquote><p>The incident has been widely discussed in Kerala, raising awareness about harassment and reinforcing support for the actor.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/honey-rose-remark-businessman-boby-chemmanut-kerala-police-custody-9766512/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/honey-rose-remark-businessman-boby-chemmanut-kerala-police-custody-9766512/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[News18 Pulse: One Nation, One Election | 80.1% Respondents Back Reform; Support Highest In Central India - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>News18 Pulse: One Nation, One Election | 80.1% Respondents Back Reform; Support Highest In Central India</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 08, 2025, 17:31 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Around 80.8% respondents believe fewer elections will reduce disruptions to daily life. (PTI/File)" title="Around 80.8% respondents believe fewer elections will reduce disruptions to daily life. (PTI/File)"><figcaption>Around 80.8% respondents believe fewer elections will reduce disruptions to daily life. (PTI/File)</figcaption></figure><p>The proposal for simultaneous elections, known as the One Nation, One Poll (ONOP) plan, has garnered significant support across India, with 80.1% of respondents favoring the move, according to a nationwide News18 survey conducted between December 23-31, 2024.</p><ul><li>90.7% support in Central India.</li><li>87.3% in North India.</li><li>84% in East India.</li><li>Support lower in North East (73.9%), West (72.9%), and South (69.7%).</li><li>81.2% believe simultaneous polls will save public money and reduce expenditure.</li><li>50% confident voters can differentiate between national and state candidates.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Constitution (129th Amendment) Bill and the Union Territories Laws (Amendment) Bill were introduced in the Lok Sabha during the Winter Session.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, public opinion favoring the ONOP proposal indicates a growing sentiment towards reducing electoral disruptions, highlighting the need for legislative and logistical readiness in facilitating this change.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/news18-pulse-one-nation-one-election-80-1-respondents-back-reform-support-highest-in-central-india-9181414.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/news18-pulse-one-nation-one-election-80-1-respondents-back-reform-support-highest-in-central-india-9181414.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:31:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Sheesh Mahal’ row: AAP’s Saurabh Bharadwaj, Sanjay Singh stopped from entering Delhi CM bungalow - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/sheesh-mahal-row-aap-leaders-to-accompany-media-on-visit-to-delhi-cm-residence/article69075266.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/sheesh-mahal-row-aap-leaders-to-accompany-media-on-visit-to-delhi-cm-residence/article69075266.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who is Anita Anand, the Indo-Canadian minister in race to replace Justin Trudeau as PM - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/who-is-anita-anand-the-indo-canadian-minister-in-race-to-replace-justin-trudeau-as-pm/articleshow/117043735.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/who-is-anita-anand-the-indo-canadian-minister-in-race-to-replace-justin-trudeau-as-pm/articleshow/117043735.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kerala businessman Boby Chemmanur taken into custody in sexual harassment case filed by woman actor - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kerala Businessman Boby Chemmanur Arrested Following Sexual Harassment Allegations</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 08, 2025<strong> | Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png" alt="Boby Chemmanur (file)" title="Boby Chemmanur (file)" />
<figcaption>Boby Chemmanur (file) | Photo Credit: MOHD ARIF</figcaption>
<p>The Kochi City police have taken businessman Boby Chemmanur into custody following a complaint by a woman actor alleging sexual harassment. This follows a swift investigation and is part of a broader inquiry into multiple complaints against him.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Chemmanur was taken into custody less than 24 hours after a complaint was made.</li>
  <li>A special investigation team (SIT) is overseeing the case, having extracted him from another district.</li>
  <li>He faces non-bailable charges under various sections of law, including sexual harassment and the transmission of obscene material.</li>
  <li>The actor has provided digital evidence to support her claims and has previously lodged a complaint against multiple individuals for similar behavior.</li>
  <li>The police have already arrested one individual linked to the initial complaints.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“His custody is the culmination of our action initiated from the moment we registered the case on Tuesday evening.” - C. Jayakumar, Assistant Commissioner</blockquote>
<p>This case reflects ongoing concerns regarding online harassment and the treatment of women in the industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/kerala-businessman-bobby-chemmanur-taken-into-custody-in-sexual-harassment-case-filed-by-woman-actor/article69075243.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/kerala-businessman-bobby-chemmanur-taken-into-custody-in-sexual-harassment-case-filed-by-woman-actor/article69075243.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kashmir train service likely to be inaugurated on January 26: MP Mian Altaf - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxPVFNyZlg2eWFOODA1M0RKcVROeURVbFp5SHBIcEtYeW5SeEt4SjRBeE8zRkNNTkcwbmxyMkZtOFl4OExvYlVvUTFycjM2QnNYRXpQOWpiRUdUQ2dVeDM1aTUxOEVRZWs0OURldE50RHVENVhTSGJhS2NFbjRCMldvU04xYlpjYWFGQzc3QU5WSTA5RzhteXZRTlAycVV5Tk9ILXYtLXFiV3djeU1aQTlMamNqT3ZqeEpmckHSAb8BQVVfeXFMTXlSUUJlTGpac0JrMWc3YTV5RV9sNENLbE5mdlE1QTBfNk9mZnJyLUpaT1ZmTmk5eE9RZnlrYlNIWFNmQkdObFpiMHRzS0JDMC1uWlQ3dFJ4U1RwbFVHSnp6bmdBbGZoUWVlLXpHcXEwa25vbFNSNDJZZVJPMlNOSW5KTm5yS05zOW1rcVIxQVVLMk0xQkRQS3pwTUJFejFkOXk2VTE1MG5iT0FKR2stZ29PVHRUQXVJbWJteWp6bGs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxPVFNyZlg2eWFOODA1M0RKcVROeURVbFp5SHBIcEtYeW5SeEt4SjRBeE8zRkNNTkcwbmxyMkZtOFl4OExvYlVvUTFycjM2QnNYRXpQOWpiRUdUQ2dVeDM1aTUxOEVRZWs0OURldE50RHVENVhTSGJhS2NFbjRCMldvU04xYlpjYWFGQzc3QU5WSTA5RzhteXZRTlAycVV5Tk9ILXYtLXFiV3djeU1aQTlMamNqT3ZqeEpmckHSAb8BQVVfeXFMTXlSUUJlTGpac0JrMWc3YTV5RV9sNENLbE5mdlE1QTBfNk9mZnJyLUpaT1ZmTmk5eE9RZnlrYlNIWFNmQkdObFpiMHRzS0JDMC1uWlQ3dFJ4U1RwbFVHSnp6bmdBbGZoUWVlLXpHcXEwa25vbFNSNDJZZVJPMlNOSW5KTm5yS05zOW1rcVIxQVVLMk0xQkRQS3pwTUJFejFkOXk2VTE1MG5iT0FKR2stZ29PVHRUQXVJbWJteWp6bGs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:55:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nitin Gadkari announces nationwide cashless treatment scheme for road accident victims - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitin Gadkari announces nationwide cashless treatment scheme for road accident victims</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/uvuz6d/article68687703.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI09_26_2024_000152A.jpg" alt="Minister Nitin Gadkari addressing the seminar"/><figcaption>Bengaluru: Union Minister for Road Transport & Highways Nitin Gadkari addresses an international seminar on ‘Advances in Bridge Management’ organised by Indian Roads Congress, in Bengaluru, Karnataka, Thursday, Sept. 26, 2024. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>The Central government is set to implement a cashless treatment scheme for road accident victims, allowing up to ₹1.5 lakh per person for medical care.</p><ul><li>The scheme will be applicable for all road accidents involving motor vehicles.</li><li>The National Health Authority will coordinate the implementation with various agencies.</li><li>It will function via a new IT platform integrating existing applications for accident management.</li><li>The pilot programme previously launched in Chandigarh will be expanded nationwide by March 2025.</li><li>Additional discussions on driver fatigue and vehicle safety measures were highlighted during the recent workshop.</li></ul><blockquote>“The broad contours of the pilot programme are -- victims entitled to cashless treatment up to a maximum of ₹1.5 lakh per accident per person for a maximum period of 7 days from the date of the accident.” - Nitin Gadkari</blockquote><p>This initiative aims to provide timely medical assistance to accident victims across India, addressing critical needs in emergency response.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/nitin-gadkari-announces-modified-cashless-treatment-scheme-for-road-accident-victims-nationwide/article69075166.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/nitin-gadkari-announces-modified-cashless-treatment-scheme-for-road-accident-victims-nationwide/article69075166.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bijapur IED blast: Five out of eight security personnel killed in Blast were former Naxalites - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bijapur IED blast: Five out of eight security personnel killed in Blast were former Naxalites</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p>
<img src='https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/6uc13o/article69075193.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI01_06_2025_000328B.jpg' alt='Belongings of District Reserve Guards (DRG) personnel who were killed in a Naxal attack, in Chhattisgarh’s Bijapur district, January 6, 2025.'>
<figcaption>Belongings of District Reserve Guards (DRG) personnel who were killed in a Naxal attack, in Chhattisgarh’s Bijapur district, January 6, 2025.</figcaption>
<p>An IED blast in Chhattisgarh's Bijapur district resulted in the deaths of eight security personnel, five of whom were former Naxalites who had joined the police force after surrendering. This tragic incident marks a significant attack on security forces by Naxalites.</p>
<ul>
<li>Eight security personnel, including five former Naxalites, killed in a Maoist blast.</li>
<li>The attack occurred near Ambeli village on January 6, 2025.</li>
<li>The deceased were part of the District Reserve Guards and Bastar Fighters units.</li>
<li>The incident is noted as the largest strike against security forces by Naxalites in two years.</li>
<li>Last year, 792 Naxalites surrendered in the Bastar region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This is the biggest strike on security forces by Naxalites in Chhattisgarh in the last two years." - Inspector General of Police (Bastar range) Sundarraj P.</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing conflict with Naxalites remains a critical issue in Chhattisgarh, highlighting the sacrifices made by local youth now serving in law enforcement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/chhattisgarh/five-out-of-eight-security-personnel-killed-in-bijapur-ied-blast-were-former-naxalites/article69075149.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/chhattisgarh/five-out-of-eight-security-personnel-killed-in-bijapur-ied-blast-were-former-naxalites/article69075149.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sale By Way Of Public Auction Can't Be Set Aside Unless There's Material Irregularity Or Fraud/Collusion... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sale By Way Of Public Auction Can't Be Set Aside Unless There's Material Irregularity Or Fraud/Collusion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p><p>The Supreme Court has reiterated that public auction sales cannot be set aside unless there is a material irregularity, illegality, fraud, or collusion involved in the auction process.</p><ul><li>The Court cited <i>V.S. Palanivel vs. P. Sriram</i> which established that without serious flaws in the conduct of the auction, it should not be set aside.</li><li>A recent ruling in <i>Celir LLP vs Ms Sumati Prasad Bafna and others</i> confirmed that mere procedural irregularities do not justify the annulment of confirmed sales unless they are fundamental.</li><li>Justice BV Nagaratna and Justice NK Singh emphasized the principle that without material irregularities, auctions should typically be upheld to avoid chaos in transactions.</li><li>The Supreme Court reversed a Delhi High Court decision that invalidated an auction under the SARFAESI Act 2002.</li><li>The borrower had several opportunities to redeem the mortgage, and an alleged possessory claim was dismissed due to lack of valid documentation.</li><li>The auction was conducted following statutory requirements, making it a valid sale.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is now a well-settled principle that a sale by way of public auction cannot be set aside until there is any material irregularity and/or illegality committed in holding the auction or if such auction was vitiated by any fraud or collusion.”</blockquote><p>The Supreme Court's ruling aims to uphold the integrity of auction sales and ensure that legitimate transactions are not disrupted due to minor irregularities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/sale-by-way-of-public-auction-cant-be-set-aside-unless-theres-material-irregularity-or-fraudcollusion-supreme-court-280276</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/sale-by-way-of-public-auction-cant-be-set-aside-unless-theres-material-irregularity-or-fraudcollusion-supreme-court-280276</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:26:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Railways unveils specially designed Vande Bharat train for Kashmir route - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQUFlXeVBmbmIzODZWX25jaHVIdTJRVHI3NzJrckU5QnBBTm9kY0ZUb29tX1RlUkN2SnNUdXRKbUZ6MzVJYWZ5Rm5iYTlzTDgzcmJGbTFsYjlaaGZORVFSMWRpT1RXZ3A0WXlvMkJyYlBhdmw0X0pPSHJVVkxHOW1aVnlZeVhndF9SYjl0NG9JX2gzeDd6SV9yUG1raWl3U0Vybl9wd2piVHZNSURWXzVBQm9ub0ZyME1IOTZtek5qbm9FdGJGMVVwWXRxLWUxQjZvVFHSAdcBQVVfeXFMT0d2LU1MckJ6V0xuaTBha29ENkJGUmhZUy11M0JaYVJjWWh2cFVwS0FzLUZGeHN1dmVjUUlNcnhGVHdmQUdmeUttUXdXN2RHa2JfVVVwUy1zdUJBbkhfRGlCQTZObWRNNWZGYi1TZEk0Ty1jX08zQkNFZ2xpUzZ4RnFxbXlodmVWNGpRMHZwSVpmYm1CYVQzZllrLWFFbkpGMVdlYXRjall1UzZNdURESkRWSW1Ea1VkckgzcVpBcjlHZGk1cmxBc2o1VGxMS0dzR3c2ZDEySzA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQUFlXeVBmbmIzODZWX25jaHVIdTJRVHI3NzJrckU5QnBBTm9kY0ZUb29tX1RlUkN2SnNUdXRKbUZ6MzVJYWZ5Rm5iYTlzTDgzcmJGbTFsYjlaaGZORVFSMWRpT1RXZ3A0WXlvMkJyYlBhdmw0X0pPSHJVVkxHOW1aVnlZeVhndF9SYjl0NG9JX2gzeDd6SV9yUG1raWl3U0Vybl9wd2piVHZNSURWXzVBQm9ub0ZyME1IOTZtek5qbm9FdGJGMVVwWXRxLWUxQjZvVFHSAdcBQVVfeXFMT0d2LU1MckJ6V0xuaTBha29ENkJGUmhZUy11M0JaYVJjWWh2cFVwS0FzLUZGeHN1dmVjUUlNcnhGVHdmQUdmeUttUXdXN2RHa2JfVVVwUy1zdUJBbkhfRGlCQTZObWRNNWZGYi1TZEk0Ty1jX08zQkNFZ2xpUzZ4RnFxbXlodmVWNGpRMHZwSVpmYm1CYVQzZllrLWFFbkpGMVdlYXRjall1UzZNdURESkRWSW1Ea1VkckgzcVpBcjlHZGk1cmxBc2o1VGxMS0dzR3c2ZDEySzA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:04:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Railways unveils Vande Bharat, specially designed for winters in J-K, for Katra-Srinagar route - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQUFlXeVBmbmIzODZWX25jaHVIdTJRVHI3NzJrckU5QnBBTm9kY0ZUb29tX1RlUkN2SnNUdXRKbUZ6MzVJYWZ5Rm5iYTlzTDgzcmJGbTFsYjlaaGZORVFSMWRpT1RXZ3A0WXlvMkJyYlBhdmw0X0pPSHJVVkxHOW1aVnlZeVhndF9SYjl0NG9JX2gzeDd6SV9yUG1raWl3U0Vybl9wd2piVHZNSURWXzVBQm9ub0ZyME1IOTZtek5qbm9FdGJGMVVwWXRxLWUxQjZvVFHSAdcBQVVfeXFMT0d2LU1MckJ6V0xuaTBha29ENkJGUmhZUy11M0JaYVJjWWh2cFVwS0FzLUZGeHN1dmVjUUlNcnhGVHdmQUdmeUttUXdXN2RHa2JfVVVwUy1zdUJBbkhfRGlCQTZObWRNNWZGYi1TZEk0Ty1jX08zQkNFZ2xpUzZ4RnFxbXlodmVWNGpRMHZwSVpmYm1CYVQzZllrLWFFbkpGMVdlYXRjall1UzZNdURESkRWSW1Ea1VkckgzcVpBcjlHZGk1cmxBc2o1VGxMS0dzR3c2ZDEySzA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQUFlXeVBmbmIzODZWX25jaHVIdTJRVHI3NzJrckU5QnBBTm9kY0ZUb29tX1RlUkN2SnNUdXRKbUZ6MzVJYWZ5Rm5iYTlzTDgzcmJGbTFsYjlaaGZORVFSMWRpT1RXZ3A0WXlvMkJyYlBhdmw0X0pPSHJVVkxHOW1aVnlZeVhndF9SYjl0NG9JX2gzeDd6SV9yUG1raWl3U0Vybl9wd2piVHZNSURWXzVBQm9ub0ZyME1IOTZtek5qbm9FdGJGMVVwWXRxLWUxQjZvVFHSAdcBQVVfeXFMT0d2LU1MckJ6V0xuaTBha29ENkJGUmhZUy11M0JaYVJjWWh2cFVwS0FzLUZGeHN1dmVjUUlNcnhGVHdmQUdmeUttUXdXN2RHa2JfVVVwUy1zdUJBbkhfRGlCQTZObWRNNWZGYi1TZEk0Ty1jX08zQkNFZ2xpUzZ4RnFxbXlodmVWNGpRMHZwSVpmYm1CYVQzZllrLWFFbkpGMVdlYXRjall1UzZNdURESkRWSW1Ea1VkckgzcVpBcjlHZGk1cmxBc2o1VGxMS0dzR3c2ZDEySzA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:04:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Railways unveils Vande Bharat, specially designed for winters in J&K, for Katra-Srinagar route - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Railways unveils winter-ready Vande Bharat for Katra-Srinagar route</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/q0ty54/article69075033.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20250107190L.jpg" alt="A view of the Vande Bharat Express specially designed for operation in mountains and ultra-cold areas, at Shakur Basti in New Delhi on January 7, 2025" /><figcaption>A view of the Vande Bharat Express specially designed for operation in mountains and ultra-cold areas, at Shakur Basti in New Delhi on January 7, 2025 | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The Railway Board on January 8, 2025, launched a Vande Bharat Express train tailored for the extreme winter conditions of Jammu & Kashmir, aimed at enhancing connectivity for the Katra-Srinagar route, which is currently under safety inspection.</p><ul><li>The train incorporates special climate adaptations for operations in severe winter conditions.</li><li>It features advanced heating systems to prevent freezing of key components.</li><li>Embedded heating elements in the windshield provide defrosting for clearer visibility.</li><li>Standard amenities include fully air-conditioned coaches and mobile charging sockets.</li><li>Significant for connecting the Kashmir Valley to the national railway network.</li></ul><blockquote>“It has advanced heating systems which prevent freezing of water tank and bio-toilet tanks, ensuring air-brake system functions optimally for smooth operations even in sub-zero temperatures,” said Dileep Kumar, Executive Director (Information & Publicity), Railway Board.</blockquote><p>This innovative train represents a major step in India's effort to enhance connectivity in the challenging terrains of Jammu & Kashmir, symbolizing a commitment to reducing geographical and economic disparities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/jammu-and-kashmir/railways-unveils-vande-bharat-specially-designed-for-winters-in-jk-for-katra-srinagar-route/article69075026.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/jammu-and-kashmir/railways-unveils-vande-bharat-specially-designed-for-winters-in-jk-for-katra-srinagar-route/article69075026.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP Candidates List for Delhi Assembly Election 2025, Including Constituencies and Districts​​​ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxQY0tpMFo5SGxqNF9hY2VNcnNzRC1DUHhaU3QyZDdMWktRS0pDNElQV2VPQjQyVWdJVVNkc1dMYm9DUDJKMS1qaUhaVkwwQXlaaTRkajJhWW9zRWhIV3BvbWJVd1lUNXVWeWJqWjJzdFItRzFJd2l1Q0VmaGtjUi1wOTI5ZGJDcGhFUmZGYTdwcHlyZTJsT3pxQ2Y5dEl1d2VxLTFZOWhVYzlsc0NydEVEeUJ4aEVkb0toVDhHSHlfc2kyY19GUGQwV05Sc21xRS01R3Nzb3A0cWlodURvZV8taUJKVEFnWmNJS05PY0MxcjF2LWFSRmY40gH8AUFVX3lxTE9BWl9GV2tGWjhJYWVDWk5hOV9wUy12TEdJYmJJTW9wV1dCdXdzYnZOaFY5UEh3NVh4M3drWUN0TXJHT0o0eFJpSEt6aWVTSG5DWHBtUEl6NUV6QlQ2TEJkWlpMM1JTM2c2MDR4ZnlhT0g0Z3RXd0F6ME9lbDlaYl9WdEU0ZnE2cEdOZThvdFJWNDlQb25GV00yRzQ1SnpxQ1RRajFYT1pmeGxVWkZ1Y0doTjVhU2RyU3FLdXZ4NjR1eEVnVndIdGtkN0NqLVRmZkZ4WlBYcW00TjR5aEdhMTVlNUx1Y0JmTS1DaE5TQXliUEd4Z1Y2cERWM3pxRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxQY0tpMFo5SGxqNF9hY2VNcnNzRC1DUHhaU3QyZDdMWktRS0pDNElQV2VPQjQyVWdJVVNkc1dMYm9DUDJKMS1qaUhaVkwwQXlaaTRkajJhWW9zRWhIV3BvbWJVd1lUNXVWeWJqWjJzdFItRzFJd2l1Q0VmaGtjUi1wOTI5ZGJDcGhFUmZGYTdwcHlyZTJsT3pxQ2Y5dEl1d2VxLTFZOWhVYzlsc0NydEVEeUJ4aEVkb0toVDhHSHlfc2kyY19GUGQwV05Sc21xRS01R3Nzb3A0cWlodURvZV8taUJKVEFnWmNJS05PY0MxcjF2LWFSRmY40gH8AUFVX3lxTE9BWl9GV2tGWjhJYWVDWk5hOV9wUy12TEdJYmJJTW9wV1dCdXdzYnZOaFY5UEh3NVh4M3drWUN0TXJHT0o0eFJpSEt6aWVTSG5DWHBtUEl6NUV6QlQ2TEJkWlpMM1JTM2c2MDR4ZnlhT0g0Z3RXd0F6ME9lbDlaYl9WdEU0ZnE2cEdOZThvdFJWNDlQb25GV00yRzQ1SnpxQ1RRajFYT1pmeGxVWkZ1Y0doTjVhU2RyU3FLdXZ4NjR1eEVnVndIdGtkN0NqLVRmZkZ4WlBYcW00TjR5aEdhMTVlNUx1Y0JmTS1DaE5TQXliUEd4Z1Y2cERWM3pxRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[V. Narayanan, who is set to take over as ISRO Chairman, terms his new assignment ‘a great responsibility’ - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>V. Narayanan Set to Lead ISRO with Great Responsibility</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/kerala/p9rmlm/article69075001.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/nara1.jpg" alt="V. Narayanan, who will take over as ISRO Chairman from January 14, poses near a model of the Chandrayaan-3 moon lander." title="V. Narayanan, who will take over as ISRO Chairman from January 14, poses near a model of the Chandrayaan-3 moon lander."><figcaption>V. Narayanan, who will take over as ISRO Chairman from January 14, poses near a model of the Chandrayaan-3 moon lander.</figcaption><p>V. Narayanan, a rocket propulsion expert, will take over as the Chairman of ISRO on January 14, 2025. He describes this new role as a significant responsibility and opportunity to lead ISRO during a transformative time in India's space sector.</p><ul><li>Succeeds S. Somanath as ISRO Chairman.</li><li>ISRO has several major projects lined up including Gaganyaan, Chandrayaan-4, and an Indian space station.</li><li>Dr. Narayanan emphasizes the importance of increasing India's presence in space and the role of private sector reforms in achieving this goal.</li><li>He has a substantial background in rocket propulsion, having been with ISRO since 1984.</li></ul><blockquote>“Towards January-end we have the GSLV Mk-II/IRNSS-1 K mission... we have our hands full.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Dr. Narayanan's extensive experience and vision for reform will be crucial as ISRO embarks on its ambitious future projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/v-narayanan-who-is-set-to-take-over-as-isro-chairman-terms-his-new-assignment-as-a-great-responsibility/article69075005.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/v-narayanan-who-is-set-to-take-over-as-isro-chairman-terms-his-new-assignment-as-a-great-responsibility/article69075005.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ramesh Bidhuri to be replaced? Unease in BJP ahead of Delhi election: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unease in BJP Over Ramesh Bidhuri's Controversial Remarks Ahead of Delhi Elections</h1><p><strong>January 08, 2025</strong> - <strong>Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Ramesh-Bidhuri---ANI-_1736303205780_1736303230986.jpg" alt="BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri. (ANI)(HT_PRINT)"><figcaption>BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri. (ANI)(HT_PRINT)</figcaption><p>BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri’s recent controversial remarks about Delhi chief minister Atishi and Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra have sparked a backlash, leading to discussions within the party about replacing him with a woman candidate for the upcoming assembly election.</p><ul><li>There have been at least two organisational meetings regarding Bidhuri's candidacy.</li><li>His remarks led to a reprimand from BJP leader JP Nadda.</li><li>Potential women replacements for Bidhuri are being discussed.</li><li>Bidhuri commented on Atishi's family name change, which drew criticism.</li></ul><blockquote>“Not just against Atishi, Rameshji’s statement on Priyanka Gandhi Vadra led to his being reprimanded by Naddaji within minutes,” a BJP source stated.</blockquote><p>The situation highlights internal tensions in the BJP as it prepares for the February 5 assembly election.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ramesh-bidhuri-to-be-replaced-unease-in-bjp-ahead-of-delhi-election-report-101736299967107.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ramesh-bidhuri-to-be-replaced-unease-in-bjp-ahead-of-delhi-election-report-101736299967107.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:11:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Body recovered from Assam coal mine; efforts on to trace others - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Body Recovered from Assam Coal Mine; Ongoing Search for Others</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/The-workers-are-believed-to-be-trapped-300-feet-un_1736308059537.jpg" alt="The workers are believed to be trapped 300 feet under the ground in the flooded coal mine. (PTI)"><figcaption>The workers are believed to be trapped 300 feet under the ground in the flooded coal mine. (PTI)</figcaption><p>Rescuers recovered a body early on Wednesday from the coal mine in Assam’s Dima Hasao district nearly 48 hours after at least nine workers were trapped due to flooding.</p><ul><li>One person has been arrested for operating the mine illegally.</li><li>The incident occurred in a flooded coal mine, where it is believed that nine to fifteen workers were trapped.</li><li>Rescue operations involve divers from the army, navy, NDRF, and SDRF.</li><li>Confusion over the number of trapped workers persisted, with some reports suggesting varying numbers of victims.</li><li>Assam's Chief Minister expressed condolences and confirmed ongoing rescue efforts.</li></ul><blockquote>“21 Para divers have just recovered a lifeless body from the bottom of the well. Our thoughts and prayers are with the grieving family,” - Himanta Biswa Sarma.</blockquote><p>This tragic incident highlights the dangers associated with illegal mining operations and the urgency of rescue efforts in challenging environmental conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/body-recovered-from-assam-coal-mine-efforts-on-to-trace-others-101736308066541.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/body-recovered-from-assam-coal-mine-efforts-on-to-trace-others-101736308066541.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:47:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[At Maha Kumbh Camp, Agra Teen Decides To Become 'Sadhvi'. Parents 'Donate' Her, 'Pind Daan' To Follow - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Agra Teen Becomes 'Sadhvi' at Maha Kumbh Camp After Spiritual Awakening</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Prayagraj: Agra teenager's mother, Reema Singh, said that her daughter experienced detachment from worldly life during the Maha Kumbh." loading="eager"><figcaption>Prayagraj: Agra teenager's mother, Reema Singh, said that her daughter experienced detachment from worldly life during the Maha Kumbh.</figcaption><p>A 13-year-old girl from Agra has chosen to renounce worldly life and become a 'sadhvi' during her visit to the Maha Kumbh camp in Prayagraj. Her parents supported this decision, viewing it as God's wish.</p><ul><li>The girl's name is Rakhi, and she had dreamed of becoming an IAS officer before her spiritual awakening.</li><li>Her mother, Reema Singh, noted that her daughter felt a strong detachment from worldly life while at the camp.</li><li>The family was invited to serve at the Maha Kumbh by Mahant Kaushal Giri Maharaj.</li><li>Rakhi will undergo 'pind daan' and other rituals on January 19, marking her formal acceptance into the ashram where she will be known as Gauri Giri.</li></ul><blockquote>“The decision was made without any coercion. It was God’s wish.” - Reema Singh, Rakhi's mother.</blockquote><p>This event highlights a significant shift in a young girl's life, showcasing her dedication to spiritual pursuits over conventional aspirations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/maha-kumbh-camp-agra-teen-becomes-sadhvi-parents-donate-her-pind-daan-to-follow-9181446.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/maha-kumbh-camp-agra-teen-becomes-sadhvi-parents-donate-her-pind-daan-to-follow-9181446.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:44:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1 body recovered as forces resume operation to rescue trapped coal miners in Assam - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>1 Body Recovered as Forces Resume Operation to Rescue Trapped Coal Miners in Assam</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The Economic Times</p><p>Rescue operations have resumed in Assam after the recovery of one body of a coal miner. Efforts continue to locate the remaining trapped miners.</p><ul><li>One body has been recovered while others remain missing.</li><li>Rescue teams are engaged in ongoing operations to find the trapped individuals.</li><li>The incident has highlighted safety concerns in coal mining operations.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are working diligently to ensure everyone's safety and get the missing miners out as soon as possible," a rescue official stated.</blockquote><p>The incident raises critical questions about mine safety and the need for improved regulations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/guwahati/1-body-recovered-as-forces-resume-operation-to-rescue-trapped-coal-miners-in-assam/articleshow/117039208.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/guwahati/1-body-recovered-as-forces-resume-operation-to-rescue-trapped-coal-miners-in-assam/articleshow/117039208.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Maoist Movement In Karnataka Can Be Considered Over': Six Naxals Likely To Surrender Today - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maoist Movement in Karnataka Might be Ending as Six Naxals Prepare to Surrender</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="High-level police officials say the six Naxals who have agreed to surrender are among the most wanted Maoists in South India. (Representational Image: PTI)" />
<figcaption>High-level police officials say the six Naxals who have agreed to surrender are among the most wanted Maoists in South India. (Representational Image: PTI)</figcaption>
<p>The Karnataka government's call for wanted Maoists to surrender has come to fruition as six Naxals have announced their intention to surrender, marking a potentially significant turning point in the region's battle against Maoist influence.</p>
<ul>
<li>Top leaders expected to surrender include Mundagaru Latha, Sundari Kuthlur, and Mareppa Aroli.</li>
<li>The surrender will take place at the office of the Deputy Commissioner in Chikkamagaluru.</li>
<li>This event is being seen as a culmination of extensive police efforts and a sign of diminishing Naxal influence in Southern India.</li>
<li>Officials noted that local support for Naxals has waned significantly due to government welfare schemes.</li>
<li>The ongoing counter-insurgency operations have pushed Naxal cadres to surrender.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“With the surrender of these six individuals, the Maoist movement in Karnataka can be considered effectively over.” - Senior officer involved in the surrender process.</blockquote>
<p>The impending surrender of these six Naxals highlights the effectiveness of the government and law enforcement in addressing the longstanding issue of Maoist activity in Karnataka.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/maoist-movement-in-karnataka-can-be-considered-over-six-naxals-likely-to-surrender-today-9181466.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/maoist-movement-in-karnataka-can-be-considered-over-six-naxals-likely-to-surrender-today-9181466.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:36:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kerala Lottery Results: Fifty Fifty FF-124 Winners For January 8, 2025 - Full List Of Winning Numbers! - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kerala Lottery Results Today: Here's FULL LIST of winning numbers for Fifty Fifty FF-124 lucky draw for Wednesday, January 8, 2025.</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> <time>January 08, 2025, 21:57 IST</time></p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Kerala Lottery Fifty Fifty FF-124 Results: The first prize winner of Fifty Fifty FF-124 will get Rs 1 crore." loading="eager"><figcaption>Kerala Lottery Fifty Fifty FF-124 Results: The first prize winner of Fifty Fifty FF-124 will get Rs 1 crore. (Image: Shutterstock)</figcaption></figure><p>The Kerala State Lottery Department has announced the results of the Fifty Fifty (FF-124) lucky draw for Wednesday, January 8. A participant with ticket number FO 303156 has won the first prize worth Rs 1 crore. The jackpot-winning ticket was sold in Guruvayoor by an agent, Satheeshan AD (Agency No.: R 6567). The second prize of Rs 10 lakh will be awarded to the participant with ticket number FW 792121, sold in Adoor by Vinodhini Madhu (Agency No.: H 1070).</p><h2>FULL LIST OF WINNING NUMBERS FOR FIFTY FIFTY FF-124 LOTTERY</h2><ul><li>1st Prize: Rs 1 crore</li><li>2nd Prize: Rs 10 lakh</li><li>3rd Prize: Rs 5,000</li><li>4th Prize: Rs 2,000</li><li>5th Prize: Rs 1,000</li><li>6th Prize: Rs 500</li><li>7th Prize: Rs 100</li><li>Consolation Prize: Rs 8,000</li></ul><p><strong>WINNING NUMBER FOR 1ST PRIZE:</strong> FO 303156 (Guruvayoor)</p><p><strong>WINNING NUMBER FOR 2ND PRIZE:</strong> FW 792121 (Adoor)</p><h2>How to Claim Your Prize Money</h2><ol><li>Compare your ticket number with the official results.</li><li>Claim your prize within 30 days of the draw.</li><li>Visit the Kerala Lottery headquarters with the original winning ticket and a valid photo ID.</li></ol><h2>DOCUMENTS REQUIRED TO CLAIM PRIZE MONEY</h2><ul><li>Photocopy of the winning ticket.</li><li>Passport-sized photographs.</li><li>Signed PAN card.</li></ul><h2>How to Download a PDF with the Full List of Winning Numbers:</h2><p>Visit the official Kerala Lottery Department websites for the full results.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/kerala-lottery-result-today-live-updates-fifty-fifty-ff-124-winners-list-for-8-january-2025-9178181.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/kerala-lottery-result-today-live-updates-fifty-fifty-ff-124-winners-list-for-8-january-2025-9178181.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:30:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Udit Narayan escapes after fire in his building, says incident affected him mentally: ‘Anything could’ve happened' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Udit Narayan Escapes Fire Incident That Affected Him Mentally</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/217034be-aaa6-11ec-91a2-46f8d94c29f3_1648039243232_1736304167848.jpg" alt="Udit Narayan escapes after fire in his building." title="Udit Narayan escapes after fire in his building."><figcaption>Udit Narayan escapes after fire in his building.</figcaption><p>A fire broke out in a flat of the Sky Pan building in Mumbai, where singer Udit Narayan resides. The incident resulted in one death and one injury, affecting Narayan mentally.</p><ul><li>The fire erupted in the B-wing of the building, while Narayan lives in the A-wing.</li><li>The incident led to the death of a 75-year-old man and injuries to a 38-year-old man.</li><li>The fire was extinguished after nearly four hours; it is suspected to have been caused by a short circuit.</li><li>Narayan expressed gratitude for safety but stated the incident had a profound mental impact on him.</li><li>The building's non-functional fire fighting system complicated the response to the fire.</li></ul><blockquote>“This incident has affected me mentally, and it will take a while to get over it.” - Udit Narayan</blockquote><p>This fire incident has raised concerns about safety regulations and fire preparedness in residential buildings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/udit-narayan-escapes-after-fire-in-his-building-says-incident-affected-him-mentally-anything-could-have-happened-101736303589704.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/udit-narayan-escapes-after-fire-in-his-building-says-incident-affected-him-mentally-anything-could-have-happened-101736303589704.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:11:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India on alert regarding China's proposed dam on Brahmaputra: Rajnath Singh - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India on Alert Regarding China's Proposed Mega Dam on Brahmaputra</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/cishnd/article69074914.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241229176L.jpg" alt="File picture of Defence Minister Rajnath Singh"><figcaption>File picture of Defence Minister Rajnath Singh | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh announced that the Indian government is monitoring China's plan to build a mega dam on the Brahmaputra river, indicating potential concerns for downstream water flow and regional security.</p><ul><li>India is closely watching developments regarding China's planned mega dam on the Brahmaputra river.</li><li>The dam poses potential risks to water flow impacting downstream states, prompting the Indian government's alert stance.</li><li>Rajnath Singh emphasized, "The Indian government is on alert" regarding the construction.</li><li>Singh highlighted India's growing global presence and economic strength, aiming to rank among the top three economies in the near future.</li><li>He urged educators to play a pivotal role in shaping the future of students.</li></ul><blockquote>"Earlier, people did not take it seriously when India spoke at international forums, but now when India speaks, the world listens." - Rajnath Singh</blockquote><p>The Indian government remains vigilant on the matter, reinforcing the importance of international dialogue concerning regional water resources.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/india-on-alert-regarding-chinas-proposed-dam-on-brahmaputra-rajnath-singh/article69074912.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/india-on-alert-regarding-chinas-proposed-dam-on-brahmaputra-rajnath-singh/article69074912.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[At least 17 injured after elephant runs amok at festival in Malappuram - Onmanorama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxOWG9wMUpQd001WXNsX0Z6MmJUcTg3OVZjSG5fQjUtbVFENy1DbGx1cklnTUozRFJZZHpDeFVkbEpWYzE3a3JBM2VMQWlidmdjSzgzVURzTkMyX0U0YlFaUHBDaVVjZ195ZFFUMVBrYUVoVlpSQy02M0RLWE8tR3NKVDFfd3VlRHlSZGpqSEVrakxfVzlKTGpaYjE2RGV3M1lWa3RSUA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxOWG9wMUpQd001WXNsX0Z6MmJUcTg3OVZjSG5fQjUtbVFENy1DbGx1cklnTUozRFJZZHpDeFVkbEpWYzE3a3JBM2VMQWlidmdjSzgzVURzTkMyX0U0YlFaUHBDaVVjZ195ZFFUMVBrYUVoVlpSQy02M0RLWE8tR3NKVDFfd3VlRHlSZGpqSEVrakxfVzlKTGpaYjE2RGV3M1lWa3RSUA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:37:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prashant Kishor's health stable, aides urge him to end fast - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prashant Kishor's Health Condition Remains Stable Amid Fast</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 08, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/q98uiq/article69074899.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20250106253L.jpg" alt="Jan Suraaj party Chief Prashant Kishor. File" title="Jan Suraaj party Chief Prashant Kishor. File"><figcaption>Jan Suraaj party Chief Prashant Kishor. File | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The health of Jan Suraaj Party founder Prashant Kishor is stable as he remains hospitalized after starting a fast unto death to support protesting candidates. Party leaders urge him to end his fast for his well-being.</p><ul><li>Kishor was admitted to ICU after suffering from dehydration.</li><li>Leaders from his party urged him to begin eating normally to protect his health.</li><li>Doctors hope if his condition improves, he might be moved out of ICU soon.</li><li>Kishor was fasting in support of BPSC aspirants protesting the examination process.</li><li>His fast began on January 2, culminating in a hospital admission on January 7.</li></ul><blockquote>“His fight is commendable, but Bihar faces many problems and his well-being is necessary for a prolonged struggle.” - Pavan K Varma</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while Kishor's health is stable, the ongoing protests underline significant issues regarding governance and public service examinations in Bihar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/bihar/prashant-kishors-health-stable-aides-urge-him-to-end-fast/article69074893.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/bihar/prashant-kishors-health-stable-aides-urge-him-to-end-fast/article69074893.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dense fog engulfs Delhi as temperature drops to 9°C, air quality remains in ‘poor category’ - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi wakes up to dense fog amid sharp drop in temperature</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/4r01oh/article69074860.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20250107210L.jpg" alt="Shallow fog covers the roads of Vijay Chowk, in New Delhi." title="Shallow fog covers the roads of Vijay Chowk, in New Delhi."><figcaption>Shallow fog covers the roads of Vijay Chowk, in New Delhi. File | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>Dense fog enveloped Delhi with visibility dropping to zero early Wednesday, accompanied by a significant drop in temperature.</p><ul><li>Visibility in Palam dropped to 50 metres at midnight, returning to 500 metres by 2.30 am, and then falling to zero at 5.30 am.</li><li>The minimum temperature recorded was 7.4 degrees Celsius, slightly above normal.</li><li>The maximum temperature is projected to reach around 16 degrees Celsius on Wednesday.</li><li>The Air Quality Index (AQI) recorded was 334, categorizing it as 'very poor'.</li></ul><blockquote>“Palam’s visibility dropped to 50 metres at 12 midnight. It improved to 500 metres by 2.30 am, before dropping to zero at 5.30 am.” - India Meteorological Department (IMD)</blockquote><p>The stark drop in temperature and the dense fog are notable developments for Delhi's winter season, impacting visibility and air quality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/deather-weather-fog-engulfs-minimum-temperature-drops-updates-january-8/article69074857.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/deather-weather-fog-engulfs-minimum-temperature-drops-updates-january-8/article69074857.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After almost five decades, Congress to bid adieu to 24, Akbar Road, move into a new home - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Moves to New Headquarters After Decades at 24, Akbar Road</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>The Congress party is set to bid farewell to its long-standing headquarters at 24, Akbar Road in New Delhi as it prepares to inaugurate its new office, Indira Gandhi Bhawan, located at 9 A, Kotla Road. The shift marks the end of an era for the party, which has seen significant historical events unfold at the Akbar Road location.</p><ul><li>The new headquarters has been under construction for 15 years and will be inaugurated on January 15.</li><li>Top Congress leaders, including AICC president Mallikarjun Kharge and Rahul Gandhi, are expected to attend the inauguration.</li><li>24, Akbar Road has been the Congress headquarters since 1978, witnessing critical moments in Indian political history.</li><li>The party plans to retain the Akbar Road building for high-profile meetings.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is time for us to move ahead with the times and embrace the new.” - K C Venugopal, AICC General Secretary</blockquote><p>The transition to the Indira Gandhi Bhawan symbolizes a modernization effort for the Congress party, aiming to create a workspace that caters to contemporary administrative and strategic needs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/after-five-decades-congress-to-bid-adieu-to-24-akbar-road-move-into-new-home-9766092/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/after-five-decades-congress-to-bid-adieu-to-24-akbar-road-move-into-new-home-9766092/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai Weather and AQI Today: Warm start at 22.99 °C, check weather forecast for January 8, 2025 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Weather and AQI Today: Warm start at 22.99 °C, check weather forecast for January 8, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 8, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/05/29/550x309/heatwave_1682126178495_1717001728091_1717001745747.jpg" alt="Mumbai weather update on January 08, 2025" title="Mumbai weather update on January 08, 2025">
<figcaption>Mumbai weather update on January 08, 2025</figcaption>
<p>Today's weather in Mumbai shows a warm start with temperatures reaching 25.38 °C. The city is experiencing moderate air quality, prompting caution for vulnerable groups.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Temperature Range: Minimum 22.99 °C, Maximum 26.62 °C.</li>
  <li>Relative Humidity: 47%.</li>
  <li>Wind Speed: 47 km/h.</li>
  <li>Air Quality Index (AQI): 185, indicating moderate air quality.</li>
  <li>Forecast for tomorrow predicts a temperature of 23.22 °C to 26.97 °C.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Children and people with respiratory diseases should limit outdoor activity due to moderate air quality."</blockquote>
<p>The weather forecast suggests plan accordingly for a sunny day, and enjoy the warm weather while being mindful of air quality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/mumbai-news/mumbai-weather-today-aqi-and-rain-forecast-updates-january-8-2025-101736299823111.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/mumbai-news/mumbai-weather-today-aqi-and-rain-forecast-updates-january-8-2025-101736299823111.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:30:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>