<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:21:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:21:02 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Home Ministry Okays Arvind Kejriwal's Prosecution In Delhi Liquor Policy Case - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Centre's Key Nod Brings Fresh Trouble For Arvind Kejriwal, Manish Sisodia</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p>
<p>In fresh trouble for Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leader Arvind Kejriwal ahead of the Delhi election, the Union Home Ministry has authorized the Enforcement Directorate to prosecute both him and former Deputy Chief Minister Manish Sisodia in a money laundering case linked to the now-scrapped liquor policy.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Home Ministry's approval removes the legal obstacle for the Enforcement Directorate to proceed with the prosecution.</li>
<li>This development follows a Supreme Court ruling requiring prior sanction for prosecuting public servants.</li>
<li>Kejriwal and Sisodia were arrested in connection with money laundering cases related to the liquor policy and are currently out on bail.</li>
<li>Both leaders have denied the charges, claiming political harassment by the BJP.</li>
<li>The timing of this development may impact their campaign for the upcoming February 5 elections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Enforcement Directorate did not have the sanction to prosecute me.” - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote>
<p>The fresh developments could intensify BJP's criticism of AAP as the elections approach.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/home-ministry-okays-arvind-kejriwals-prosecution-in-delhi-liquor-policy-case-7476239</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/home-ministry-okays-arvind-kejriwals-prosecution-in-delhi-liquor-policy-case-7476239</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 03:36:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh Mela 2025 live: Devotees take holy dip at Triveni Sangam on day 3 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh Mela 2025: Devotees Take Holy Dip at Triveni Sangam on Day 3</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/PTI01-14-2025-000457A-0_1736911046215_1736911065153.jpg" alt="Mahakumbh Mela 2025 live: Naga sadhus of Shri Panchayati Niranjani Akhada arrive to take the first 'Amrit Snan'" title="Naga sadhus of Shri Panchayati Niranjani Akhada arrive to take the first 'Amrit Snan'" /><figcaption>Naga sadhus of Shri Panchayati Niranjani Akhada arrive to take the first 'Amrit Snan'</figcaption><p>The Mahakumbh Mela 2025, celebrated once every 12 years, has entered its third day. An unprecedented number of devotees have gathered for holy bathing rituals during the festival.</p><ul><li>Over 35 million devotees attended the first 'Amrit Snan' on Makar Sankranti, according to UP CM Yogi Adityanath.</li><li>Naga Sadhus led the way for the holy baths, with significant participation from various akharas.</li><li>Schools in Prayagraj will remain closed due to the traffic surge related to the festival.</li><li>Organizers expect up to 450 million attendees throughout the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“My experience was good. Proper safety arrangements were made for the devotees.” - Vijay Katheria, Kanpur resident</blockquote><p>The Mahakumbh Mela will continue until February 26, highlighting its importance as a major cultural and spiritual gathering.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-schools-closed-naga-akhara-triveni-sangam-shahi-snan-january-15-2025-101736902654780.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-schools-closed-naga-akhara-triveni-sangam-shahi-snan-january-15-2025-101736902654780.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 03:21:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh Mela 2025 live updates: Over 3.5 crore take ‘Amrit Snan’; Yogi govt showers flowers on ghats - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh Mela 2025 live: Devotees take holy dip at Triveni Sangam on day 3</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/ANI-20250114368-0_1736905914162_1736905936520.jpg" alt="Naga sadhus take 'Amrit Snan' at Triveni Sangam on the occasion of 'Makar Sankranti' during the Mahakumbh 2025 in Prayagraj on Tuesday." title="Naga sadhus take 'Amrit Snan' at Triveni Sangam on the occasion of 'Makar Sankranti' during the Mahakumbh 2025 in Prayagraj on Tuesday."><figcaption>Naga sadhus take 'Amrit Snan' at Triveni Sangam on the occasion of 'Makar Sankranti' during the Mahakumbh 2025 in Prayagraj on Tuesday.</figcaption><p>On day 3 of the Mahakumbh Mela 2025, over 35 million devotees visited Triveni Sangam to partake in the holy dip. UP Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath reported that the crowd exceeded expectations, highlighting the festival's significance.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>The Mahakumbh Mela, held every 12 years, entered its third day amid a massive gathering of devotees.</li><li>This year's Mela saw participation from more than 35 million individuals during the first Amrit Snan, as confirmed by the CM.</li><li>Naga Sadhus led the procession to the holy bathing area, setting a spiritual tone for the gathering.</li><li>Traffic congestion led to the closure of schools for classes 1 to 8 in Prayagraj.</li></ul><blockquote>“Today, on the first Amrit Snan festival, more than 3.50 crore revered saints and devotees earned the holy benefit of bathing in the uninterrupted-clean Triveni.” - Yogi Adityanath</blockquote><p>The Mahakumbh Mela continues until February 26, with several key dates for holy bathing still to come, ensuring ongoing celebrations for the gathered devotees.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-schools-closed-naga-akhara-triveni-sangam-shahi-snan-january-15-2025-101736902654780.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-schools-closed-naga-akhara-triveni-sangam-shahi-snan-january-15-2025-101736902654780.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 01:55:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi in Navi Mumbai today: Traffic advisory issued. Avoid these routes - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/mumbai-news/pm-narendra-modi-in-navi-mumbai-today-january-15-2025-traffic-advisory-issued-avoid-these-routes-101736902838989.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/mumbai-news/pm-narendra-modi-in-navi-mumbai-today-january-15-2025-traffic-advisory-issued-avoid-these-routes-101736902838989.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 01:47:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why India is reaching out to the Taliban now - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTFA2VWNqLUlBSGEtSnUxMlNnVFNJdkNhVWJ3M04ycTYwM2xwOVhyWm9Ya1hfc0RMbUh6M1RtbTlCVURpV1NOWFJOMV8zUngwMndzRFA1UWEwbllmUdIBX0FVX3lxTE5tTGZTREdSbXhjU0tVR2VZM2ZzVDh2Y21NZ1JTT05JVE5uRzRMOVhPZEJBMHJGaDJ1cDk4QWN6aDRVYlhpTktmLWVzdlJnUUlSNnBqR016QkM3bTZsdlBn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTFA2VWNqLUlBSGEtSnUxMlNnVFNJdkNhVWJ3M04ycTYwM2xwOVhyWm9Ya1hfc0RMbUh6M1RtbTlCVURpV1NOWFJOMV8zUngwMndzRFA1UWEwbllmUdIBX0FVX3lxTE5tTGZTREdSbXhjU0tVR2VZM2ZzVDh2Y21NZ1JTT05JVE5uRzRMOVhPZEJBMHJGaDJ1cDk4QWN6aDRVYlhpTktmLWVzdlJnUUlSNnBqR016QkM3bTZsdlBn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 01:16:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dense fog in Delhi, zero visibility in Noida amid cold wave; IMD predicts rain for today | Weather updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dense Fog in Delhi Causes Zero Visibility in Noida Amid Cold Wave</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/20250113-DNO-SGH-MN-FoggyWeather-006-0_1736901861953_1736901880602.jpg" alt="A view of Noida engulfed in thick layers of fog amid intense cold wave conditions. (Sunil Ghosh/Hindustan Times)" title="A view of Noida engulfed in thick layers of fog amid intense cold wave conditions. (Sunil Ghosh/Hindustan Times)"><figcaption>A view of Noida engulfed in thick layers of fog amid intense cold wave conditions. (Sunil Ghosh/Hindustan Times)</figcaption><p>Dense fog engulfed Delhi and Noida early Wednesday, leading to significantly reduced visibility and potential disruptions to flights and trains amid an ongoing cold wave.</p><ul><li>Visibility issues persisted across the national capital region due to dense fog.</li><li>Delhi's temperature was recorded at 10°C around 5:30 AM, with a forecasted minimum of 9°C and a maximum of 19°C.</li><li>The India Meteorological Department (IMD) warned of ongoing cold conditions and potential rain.</li><li>Passengers faced disruptions at the Delhi airport, particularly for non-CAT III compliant flights.</li><li>Homeless individuals sought refuge in night shelters amid the cold temperatures.</li></ul><blockquote>“Zero visibility has prevailed over Palam since 4:30 IST, with southeasterly winds blowing at 6-8 kmph,” according to IMD.</blockquote><p>The ongoing dense fog has not only impacted transportation but also highlighted the need for vigilance among commuters during this adverse weather condition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/dense-fog-in-delhi-zero-visibility-in-noida-amid-cold-wave-imd-predicts-rain-for-today-january-15-2024-101736900165697.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/dense-fog-in-delhi-zero-visibility-in-noida-amid-cold-wave-imd-predicts-rain-for-today-january-15-2024-101736900165697.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:54:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maha Kumbh Mela 2025: Akhadas lead holy dip on Makar Sankranti, Mahanirvani being first - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maha Kumbh Mela 2025: Akhadas lead holy dip on Makar Sankranti, Mahanirvani being first</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/women-seers-at-the-Triveni-Sangam-on-Tuesday.jpg?resize=600,338" alt="Makar Sankranti"><figcaption>Women seers at the Triveni Sangam on Tuesday (Express/Vishal Srivastav)</figcaption><p>The Maha Kumbh Mela 2025 commenced with the first Amrit Snan at Triveni Sangam on Makar Sankranti, drawing crores of devotees and sadhus. The event marks a significant ritual with the participation of various akhadas.</p><ul><li>3.5 crore devotees participated in the holy dip.</li><li>Naga Sadhus led the holy dip during the sacred ‘Brahmamahurta.’</li><li>For the first time, over 500 transgender sadhus participated, highlighting inclusivity.</li><li>Crowd management was enhanced with advanced technologies for safety.</li><li>International pilgrims found the experience transformative and spiritually significant.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are grateful to Ma Ganga and pray for the country’s progress.” - Tina Ma, transgender sadhu</blockquote><blockquote>“The scale of the event is mind-blowing. I feel blessed to see this all with my own eyes.” - Carlos, yoga teacher from Spain</blockquote><p>The Maha Kumbh continues to be a monumental spiritual gathering, showcasing unity and diversity among participants from across the globe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/lucknow/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-akhadas-lead-holy-dip-on-makar-sankranti-mahanirvani-being-first-9779270/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/lucknow/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-akhadas-lead-holy-dip-on-makar-sankranti-mahanirvani-being-first-9779270/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 21:54:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FIR against AAP over social media posts using images of PM Modi, Amit Shah - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FIRs Filed Against AAP for Allegedly Defamatory Posts on PM Modi and Amit Shah</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/ch1913718.jpg?w=640" alt="arvind kejriwal delhi aap" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Aam Aadmi Party National Convener Arvind Kejriwal during a press conference. Express Photo by Amit Mehra</figcaption><p>In a new episode of tension between the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) and the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), the Delhi Police has registered five FIRs against AAP following complaints by BJP members claiming that AAP's posts on X tarnished the reputations of PM Narendra Modi and Amit Shah.</p><ul><li>Five FIRs were lodged after BJP members accused AAP of creating objectionable posts on social media.</li><li>The posts allegedly aimed to incite communal unrest and promote discrimination.</li><li>Complaints were filed by Brijesh Rai, highlighting posts from January 9 and 10 that were deemed defamatory.</li><li>AAP responded, accusing BJP of using state machinery to suppress their rising popularity.</li></ul><blockquote>“Selectively using power exposes BJP's fear of AAP’s growing popularity.” - AAP</blockquote><p>This incident underscores ongoing political tensions as both parties prepare for upcoming elections, with each accusing the other of spreading misinformation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/delhi/fir-aap-social-media-posts-images-pm-modi-amit-shah-9778049/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/delhi/fir-aap-social-media-posts-images-pm-modi-amit-shah-9778049/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 20:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steve Jobs' letter on attending Kumbh Mela fetches over $500k at auction: 'I wish to go to India...' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Steve Jobs' letter on attending Kumbh Mela fetches over $500k at auction: 'I wish to go to India...'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This article discusses the auction of a letter written by Steve Jobs expressing his desire to attend the Kumbh Mela in India, which sold for over $500,000.</p><ul><li>The letter was written in 1982 and reveals Jobs' cultural interests.</li><li>The auction reflects the significant interest in Jobs' personal artifacts.</li><li>Notable bidders included tech enthusiasts and collectors.</li></ul><blockquote>“I wish to go to India...” - Steve Jobs</blockquote><p>This auction demonstrates the lasting impact of Steve Jobs' legacy and the value of his personal thoughts and aspirations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/steve-jobs-letter-on-attending-kumbh-mela-fetches-over-500k-at-auction-i-wish-to-go-to-india-/articleshow/117245915.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/steve-jobs-letter-on-attending-kumbh-mela-fetches-over-500k-at-auction-i-wish-to-go-to-india-/articleshow/117245915.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 20:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dallewal strike enters Day 50, 111 more to start fast-unto-death - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dallewal strike enters Day 50, 111 more to start fast-unto-death</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='Dallewal strike image' />
<figcaption>Dallewal strike supporters gather for the protest</figcaption>
<p>The Dallewal farmers' strike has reached its 50th day, with escalating tensions as 111 more individuals prepare to join a fast-unto-death protest. The strike is a response to ongoing demands for better agricultural policies and welfare measures.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The protest began over dissatisfaction with government policies.</li>
  <li>Activists express concerns regarding agricultural reforms.</li>
  <li>The movement has gained significant public attention and support.</li>
  <li>Health risks are increasing as more participants enter fasting.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We will not back down until our voices are heard,” said a protest leader.</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing strike highlights the rising tensions in the agricultural community, calling for urgent attention from the government.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/dallewal-strike-enters-day-50-111-more-to-start-fast-unto-death/articleshow/117246388.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/dallewal-strike-enters-day-50-111-more-to-start-fast-unto-death/articleshow/117246388.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 20:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FIR against AAP for posting AI-generated videos of PM Modi, Amit Shah on X - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FIR Filed Against AAP for AI-Generated Videos of PM Modi and Amit Shah</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 15, 2025 12:29 am IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/latest-news/xuceiu/article69099072.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/AAP.jpg" alt="One of the videos posted on AAP’s X handle showed a scene from a 90s Bollywood flick where the faces of villains were swapped with that of BJP leaders and the audio was changed to a conversation on Delhi polls." /><figcaption>One of the videos posted on AAP’s X handle showed a scene from a 90s Bollywood flick where the faces of villains were swapped with that of BJP leaders and the audio was changed to a conversation on Delhi polls. Photo: X/@AamAadmiParty</figcaption><p>Delhi Police have lodged an FIR against the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) for allegedly posting AI-generated images and videos of PM Modi and Amit Shah on social media. The FIR follows complaints about objectionable content on AAP's X handle.</p><ul><li>The complainant reported videos of PM Modi and Amit Shah published on AAP's social media.</li><li>The alleged content includes deepfake videos with altered scenes from a 90s Bollywood movie.</li><li>AP alleges the BJP is using legal tactics to suppress AAP's political activities as elections approach.</li><li>The incident reflects ongoing political tensions as the election period draws near.</li></ul><blockquote>AAP responds, claiming that such actions by BJP are to divert public attention from real issues.</blockquote><p>This situation raises questions about the use of technology in political campaigns and highlights the contentious relationship between AAP and BJP.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/fir-against-aap-for-posting-ai-generated-videos-of-pm-modi-amit-shah-on-x/article69099069.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/fir-against-aap-for-posting-ai-generated-videos-of-pm-modi-amit-shah-on-x/article69099069.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 18:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video | Maha Kumbh: Foreign Tourists Plan Weddings, Seek Profound Experience At Religious Gathering - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Foreign Tourists Embrace Weddings and Spiritual Experiences at Maha Kumbh</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>The Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj attracts not only lakhs of devotees but also numerous foreign tourists who seek to participate in this grand religious gathering, with some choosing to marry during the event.</p><ul><li>Foreign tourists from various European countries are attending the Kumbh Mela.</li><li>Some visitors plan to have their weddings during the sacred festival.</li><li>Others are drawn to the event for a profound spiritual experience.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/video/maha-kumbh-foreign-tourists-plan-weddings-seek-profound-experience-at-religious-gathering-888530</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/video/maha-kumbh-foreign-tourists-plan-weddings-seek-profound-experience-at-religious-gathering-888530</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 18:47:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress Releases Third List of 16 Candidates For Delhi Assembly Elections | LIVE - Republic World]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Releases Third List of 16 Candidates For Delhi Assembly Elections</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p>
<img src="https://www.republicworld.com/_app/immutable/assets/16-9-placeholder.ylpwvwO6.jpg" alt="Congress Leader Sandeep Dikshit" width="100%">
<figcaption>Congress Leader Sandeep Dikshit</figcaption>
<p>The Congress party has announced its third list of candidates for the upcoming Delhi Assembly elections, highlighting key election strategies and selections.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The third list includes 16 candidates.</li>
  <li>This comes ahead of the February 2025 Delhi Assembly elections.</li>
  <li>Key dates for the Maha Kumbh festival are also discussed, marking significant religious observances.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The exam has been postponed... in the interest of the aspirants,” Rajesh Kumar, Director (Exams), NTA.</blockquote>
<p>This election cycle represents a critical juncture for the Congress party in Delhi as they prepare to face the challenges presented during this electoral period.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.republicworld.com/india/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-makar-sankranti-amrit-snan-bpsc-row-pappu-yadav-sambhal-yogi-adityanath-uttrakhand-bus-accident-delhi-polls-pollution-weather-garp-3-smog-fog-flight-delays-trian-disrupted-aap-vs-bjp-arvinf-kejriwal-pm-modi-kerala-rape-hmpv-bangladesh-high-commission-californis-wildfires-live-updates-india-news-today-14-january-live-news</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.republicworld.com/india/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-makar-sankranti-amrit-snan-bpsc-row-pappu-yadav-sambhal-yogi-adityanath-uttrakhand-bus-accident-delhi-polls-pollution-weather-garp-3-smog-fog-flight-delays-trian-disrupted-aap-vs-bjp-arvinf-kejriwal-pm-modi-kerala-rape-hmpv-bangladesh-high-commission-californis-wildfires-live-updates-india-news-today-14-january-live-news</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 18:12:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh: NCP (SP) leader Mahesh Kothe dies of heart attack while taking holy dip at Triveni confluence - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NCP (SP) Leader Mahesh Kothe Dies During Holy Dip at Mahakumbh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/Mahesh_Kothe_1736873100423_1736873263282.jpg" alt="Former Solapur mayor and NCP (SP) leader Mahesh Kothe.(X/Sharad Pawar)" title="Former Solapur mayor and NCP (SP) leader Mahesh Kothe.(X/Sharad Pawar)"><figcaption>Former Solapur mayor and NCP (SP) leader Mahesh Kothe.(X/Sharad Pawar)</figcaption><p>Mahesh Kothe, former Solapur mayor and NCP (SP) leader, tragically died of a heart attack while taking a holy dip at the Triveni Sangam in Prayagraj. He was 60 years old.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred around 7.30 AM during the sacred ceremony on Makar Sankranti.</li><li>Kothe had suffered a heart attack in the water and was declared dead upon arrival at a medical facility.</li><li>He is survived by his wife and son; his body will be taken to Solapur for last rites.</li><li>NCP (SP) chief Sharad Pawar expressed deep sorrow over Kothe's death, emphasizing his influence in Solapur's political landscape.</li><li>On the day of the incident, approximately 3.5 crore devotees participated in the holy dip.</li></ul><blockquote>“In his demise, Solapur has lost a dynamic and dedicated worker. We all stand in solidarity with the Kothe family in grief. Heartfelt condolences!” - Sharad Pawar</blockquote><p>This unfortunate event highlights the risks associated with large religious gatherings, especially during festivals such as Mahakumbh.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-ncp-sp-leader-mahesh-kothe-dies-of-heart-attack-during-holy-dip-in-prayagraj-triveni-sangam-101736872312035.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-ncp-sp-leader-mahesh-kothe-dies-of-heart-attack-during-holy-dip-in-prayagraj-triveni-sangam-101736872312035.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:10:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Sudden emotional outburst’: CM Biren Singh on Congress winning both Lok Sabha seats in Manipur - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CM Biren Singh Attributes Congress Wins in Manipur to Emotional Outburst</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/Manipur-Chief-Minister-N--Biren-Singh--PTI-_1732245255858_1736869448466.jpg" alt="Manipur Chief Minister N. Biren Singh (PTI/File Photo)" title="Manipur Chief Minister N. Biren Singh (PTI/File Photo)">
<figcaption>Manipur Chief Minister N. Biren Singh (PTI/File Photo)</figcaption>
<p>In a recent statement, Manipur Chief Minister N. Biren Singh described the Congress party's victory in both Lok Sabha seats of Manipur as a result of a “sudden emotional outburst” from the electorate.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Biren Singh questioned the performance of the elected MPs regarding key state issues.</li>
  <li>He expressed concern over the lack of discussion on crucial topics such as border fencing and illegal immigration.</li>
  <li>In the 2019 elections, the BJP and a regional party won the seats, but in 2024 Congress secured both seats.</li>
  <li>Singh criticized ex-Union minister P. Chidambaram for his suggestions on regional autonomy amidst ongoing ethnic disputes in the state.</li>
  <li>The state has experienced severe ethnic violence, leading to over 200 deaths since May 2023.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When many have been killed and displaced, how were votes given to them? I want to ask the people, why were votes given to them?” - N. Biren Singh</blockquote>
<p>The Chief Minister's remarks reflect ongoing tensions in Manipur, highlighting the need for accountability from elected representatives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/sudden-emotional-outburst-cm-biren-singh-on-congress-winning-both-lok-sabha-seats-in-manipur-101736869391091.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/sudden-emotional-outburst-cm-biren-singh-on-congress-winning-both-lok-sabha-seats-in-manipur-101736869391091.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:46:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[War of words on over national status of Gangasagar Mela on Makar Sankranti - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>War of Words Over National Status of Gangasagar Mela on Makar Sankranti</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/tst96e/article69098924.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/80717_14_1_2025_21_46_37_3_140125GANGASAGAR13.JPG" alt="A crowd of pilgrims assemble at Kapil Muni temple at Gangasagar Mela" title="A crowd of pilgrims assemble at Kapil Muni temple at Gangasagar Mela on the occasion of Makar Sankranti on Tuesday, January 14, 2025"><figcaption>A crowd of pilgrims assemble at Kapil Muni temple at Gangasagar Mela on the occasion of Makar Sankranti on Tuesday, January 14, 2025 | Photo Credit: Debasish Bhaduri</figcaption><p>As lakhs of devotees took a dip at the confluence of river Hooghly with the sea at Gangasagar Mela, a political war of words erupted between the West Bengal government and the State BJP leadership regarding the status and funding of the event.</p><ul><li>West Bengal government claims the Centre has not supported the Gangasagar Mela financially.</li><li>Minister Aroop Biswas announced that 85 lakh pilgrims participated in the holy dip this year.</li><li>BJP leader Sukanta Majumdar criticized the state arrangements compared to those at Kumbh Mela.</li><li>Security measures include deployment of 12,000 policemen and establishment of 152 help desks.</li><li>A report indicated several casualties and illnesses among attendees during the Mela.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Centre has always deprived the State and not paid us a single penny for organising this mela.” - Aroop Biswas</blockquote><p>The ongoing debates over the political implications and the support for Gangasagar Mela show the tensions between state and central authorities, affecting public perception and engagement with the event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/west-bengal/war-of-words-on-over-national-status-of-gangasagar-mela-on-makar-sankranti/article69098883.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/west-bengal/war-of-words-on-over-national-status-of-gangasagar-mela-on-makar-sankranti/article69098883.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As Mrs Steve Jobs has a VIP Kumbh experience, for ordinary Kalpvasis, this year’s event is more expensive – and expansive - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/steve-jobs-wife-vip-maha-kumbh-laurene-powell-experience-kalpvasis-9778226/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/steve-jobs-wife-vip-maha-kumbh-laurene-powell-experience-kalpvasis-9778226/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AAP faces FIR for posting AI-generated videos of Modi, Shah on X - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AAP faces FIR for AI-Generated Videos of Modi and Shah</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250110122722_Arvind-Kejriwal-Delhi-Election-2025.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="The alleged videos were posted by AAP on January 10 and January 13." /><figcaption>The alleged videos were posted by AAP on January 10 and January 13.</figcaption><p>Delhi Police has registered an FIR against the Aam Aadmi Party ​(AAP) for allegedly posting AI-generated photos and videos of Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Union Home Minister Amit Shah on the party's official X handle.</p><ul><li>The case was lodged at the North Avenue police station.</li><li>The FIR was based on a complaint regarding objectionable content.</li><li>The videos were posted by AAP on January 10 and 13.</li></ul><blockquote>The alleged videos have sparked controversy around content posting on social media.</blockquote><p>This incident raises questions about the use of AI-generated content in political discourse and its implications for responsible communication.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/aap-faces-fir-for-posting-ai-generated-videos-of-modi-shah-on-x-12910637.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/aap-faces-fir-for-posting-ai-generated-videos-of-modi-shah-on-x-12910637.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:18:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Haryana BJP chief among 2 booked for alleged gangrape in Himachal's Kasauli - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/haryana-bjp-chief-among-2-booked-for-alleged-gangrape-in-himachals-kasauli-101736868916238.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/haryana-bjp-chief-among-2-booked-for-alleged-gangrape-in-himachals-kasauli-101736868916238.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:17:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SCBA, SCAORA file joint petition in Supreme Court over directions on marking appearance of lawyers - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SCBA and SCAORA Petition Supreme Court for Appearance Marking Guidelines</h1><p><strong>Published on: </strong><time datetime='2025-01-14T16:01:57.961Z' title='2025-01-14 16:01'>14 Jan 2025, 4:01 pm</time></p><p>The Supreme Court Bar Association (SCBA) and the Supreme Court Advocate on Record Association (SCAORA) have jointly filed a petition before the Supreme Court regarding the marking of appearance by lawyers in cases.</p><ul><li>The petition seeks to declare that all lawyers present in a case should be allowed to mark their appearance through their advocate-on-record (AoR).</li><li>It challenges a September 2024 order that restricted AoRs to marking appearances only for authorized lawyers.</li><li>The petition argues that the current practice direction contradicts earlier administrative directives from the Supreme Court.</li><li>The petition highlights the comprehensive role of advocates in Supreme Court proceedings beyond mere submissions.</li></ul><blockquote>"by no stretch of imagination can overrule the law laid down by this Hon’ble Court through its various pronouncements which have time and again emphasised on the importance and requirement of appearances of advocates before the top court."</blockquote><p>The petition was filed through AoR Astha Sharma, SCBA Honorary Secretary Vikrant Yadav, and SCAORA Honorary Secretary Nikhil Jain.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/scba-scaora-file-joint-petition-supreme-court-directions-marking-appearance-lawyers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/scba-scaora-file-joint-petition-supreme-court-directions-marking-appearance-lawyers</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 16:01:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bus fire in Vrindavan claims life of Maha Kumbh pilgrim - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bus Fire in Vrindavan Claims Life of Maha Kumbh Pilgrim</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Tuesday evening | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117242948,imgsize-1206548,width-400,resizemode-4/117242948.jpg" alt="Bus fire in Vrindavan claims life of Maha Kumbh pilgrim"><figcaption>Bus fire in Vrindavan</figcaption><p>A tragedy struck when an elderly pilgrim lost his life in a bus fire while traveling to the Maha Kumbh in Prayagraj.</p><ul><li>The bus was carrying around 50 pilgrims from Telangana.</li><li>The fire started while the bus was parked at a tourist center in Vrindavan.</li><li>Witnesses reported sparks coming from the vehicle before it engulfed in flames.</li><li>Emergency services were unable to reach in time to save the trapped passenger.</li><li>The deceased was identified as Dhrupati, who chose to stay inside the bus.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dhrupati was smoking a beedi and opted to remain inside while others stepped out,” said a fellow passenger.</blockquote><p>The incident is currently under investigation to determine the cause of the fire.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/bus-fire-in-vrindavan-claims-life-of-maha-kumbh-pilgrim/articleshow/117242856.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/bus-fire-in-vrindavan-claims-life-of-maha-kumbh-pilgrim/articleshow/117242856.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New claimant to Panth vote enters fray as radical Sikh preacher Amritpal floats political outfit - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amritpal Singh Launches New Political Party in Punjab</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Tuesday, on the occasion of the Maghi Mela<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Print</p><p>The new party, Shiromani Akali Dal (Waris Punjab De), was announced by Amritpal Singh and Sarabjit Singh. The party aims to compete in the upcoming SGPC elections and the 2027 Punjab election. Amritpal has been appointed as its President.</p><ul><li>The formation of the new political party coincides with the Maghi Mela, a significant religious event for Sikhs.</li><li>Amritpal Singh is currently detained under the National Security Act.</li><li>A five-member committee will manage the party until elections for the president are held.</li><li>Fifteen resolutions were passed during the conference, focusing on injustices faced by all communities.</li><li>No mention of Khalistan in the resolutions despite the pro-independence sentiment associated with Amritpal.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are not fighting for one community but for injustice to every community.” – Tarsem Singh</blockquote><p>The establishment of this party shows a shift in the political landscape of Punjab, as traditional parties face decline and new leadership emerges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/politics/new-claimant-to-panth-vote-enters-fray-as-radical-sikh-preacher-amritpal-floats-political-outfit/2445114/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/politics/new-claimant-to-panth-vote-enters-fray-as-radical-sikh-preacher-amritpal-floats-political-outfit/2445114/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:24:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Schools In Prayagraj To Remain Closed Tomorrow For Grades 1 To 8, Classes To Be Held Online - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/education-career/up-schools-to-remain-closed-tomorrow-for-grades-1-to-8-classes-to-be-held-online-9188824.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/education-career/up-schools-to-remain-closed-tomorrow-for-grades-1-to-8-classes-to-be-held-online-9188824.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:15:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vision Document 2047: IMD aims for zero-error forecast up to 3 days - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vision Document 2047: IMD aims for zero-error forecast up to 3 days</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent news</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p>
<p>The India Meteorological Department (IMD) has set ambitious goals for its weather forecasting abilities, aiming for zero-error forecasts for up to three days and 90% accuracy for five days by 2047.</p>
<ul>
    <li>IMD celebrates its 150th anniversary with new targets for weather forecasting.</li>
    <li>Aims for zero loss of life during severe weather by enhancing early warning systems.</li>
    <li>Targets include 80% accuracy for seven-day forecasts and 70% for ten-day forecasts by 2047.</li>
    <li>Plans to improve meteorological observational systems at the village level through advanced technology.</li>
    <li>The Vision Document emphasizes the importance of modern meteorology in disaster management.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Meteorology offers the most important support for disaster management capability of any country. To minimise the impact of natural disasters, we need to maximise the efficiency of meteorology," - Narendra Modi.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the IMD's Vision Document outlines a strategic shift towards enhancing weather forecast accuracy and disaster management efficiency, significantly impacting public safety and economic resilience in the years ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/imd-aims-at-zero-error-forecast-up-to-3-days-zero-disaster-deaths-by-2047-125011401023_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/imd-aims-at-zero-error-forecast-up-to-3-days-zero-disaster-deaths-by-2047-125011401023_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:13:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Apologise To Indians': Parliamentary Panel To Summon Meta Over Zuckerberg's Poll Loss Remark - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/mark-zukerberg-india-elections-remark-bjp-parliamentary-committee-meta-summons-9188318.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/mark-zukerberg-india-elections-remark-bjp-parliamentary-committee-meta-summons-9188318.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:13:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heavy-duty military drone of Israeli-origin crashes into the sea off Porbandar - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israeli-Origin Military Drone Crashes into Sea Off Porbandar</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117242086,imgsize-674510,width-400,resizemode-4/117242086.jpg" alt="Heavy-duty military drone of Israeli-origin crashes into the sea off Porbandar" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Heavy-duty military drone crashes during trials</figcaption><p>A heavy-duty drone, the Drishti-10, crashed into the sea during its pre-acceptance trials off Porbandar in Gujarat. Assembled in India under a license from Israel, the drone was being operated when it ditched into the water.</p><ul><li>The Drishti-10 drone is based on the Hermes 900 Starliner from Israeli firm Elbit Systems.</li><li>It is designed for long-range ISR missions and can operate at altitudes of up to 30,000 feet with an endurance of 36 hours.</li><li>The vendor has retrieved the drone for analysis, and the incident has no financial implications for the Navy, as the drone had not been delivered yet.</li><li>In 2023, each armed force ordered two of these drones, costing around Rs 120 crore each.</li><li>This incident highlights India’s increasing use of Israeli drones for surveillance and reconnaissance.</li></ul><blockquote>“The vendor has retrieved the drone and will analyse what went wrong.”</blockquote><p>This incident reflects the ongoing developments in India's defense capabilities, particularly in remotely-piloted aircraft systems.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/heavy-duty-military-drone-of-israeli-origin-crashes-into-the-sea-off-porbandar/articleshow/117242099.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/heavy-duty-military-drone-of-israeli-origin-crashes-into-the-sea-off-porbandar/articleshow/117242099.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UPSC cheating case: Puja Khedkar seeks pre-arrest bail, moves SC - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxPR0o4cG9GaGNIai16MUJ6TnpDX0Z6dDFTd1BkSlRENmZWR2pZTEdCWUlVamJrLWtHVXM1NEE2dHZNdEFndDBzZ295N0FQdUE5R0lzVS0tTnJWeldDY3IzOW5rVFVpMVgzQ0t4WEd6SV92ekk5STZoSlIyQnp0ZFJic3I3dHRfQ0txNFN6czhZOTYyRUloYmk4NlczbjA0UFNvRGxBbjR5OVlqcEZNNXUwazVxTmc3dzDSAbwBQVVfeXFMUHJsWnBrb2JaNnpvREZIZ0lUQ2M3LWhjUUZpMHF4bkIyWTBkd0hCaTdxQlhkQnRnYmIzS2lSWnBQaUpGa0pidDctaW5ZbGR4TDNWdmdVWkZRWFFiLWxHdTBqZEh5dUlBTGE1dXBMSDZVcDE4TXA2XzZYTkRuZ3RzVVZsNWhySWdUc3M2UVI1YzRaVFNiT2RGcGxxZTcwTkt5dGZJa2lWdmU4R2JNbnMtaWs5X3JrMmJyUFlFNGI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxPR0o4cG9GaGNIai16MUJ6TnpDX0Z6dDFTd1BkSlRENmZWR2pZTEdCWUlVamJrLWtHVXM1NEE2dHZNdEFndDBzZ295N0FQdUE5R0lzVS0tTnJWeldDY3IzOW5rVFVpMVgzQ0t4WEd6SV92ekk5STZoSlIyQnp0ZFJic3I3dHRfQ0txNFN6czhZOTYyRUloYmk4NlczbjA0UFNvRGxBbjR5OVlqcEZNNXUwazVxTmc3dzDSAbwBQVVfeXFMUHJsWnBrb2JaNnpvREZIZ0lUQ2M3LWhjUUZpMHF4bkIyWTBkd0hCaTdxQlhkQnRnYmIzS2lSWnBQaUpGa0pidDctaW5ZbGR4TDNWdmdVWkZRWFFiLWxHdTBqZEh5dUlBTGE1dXBMSDZVcDE4TXA2XzZYTkRuZ3RzVVZsNWhySWdUc3M2UVI1YzRaVFNiT2RGcGxxZTcwTkt5dGZJa2lWdmU4R2JNbnMtaWs5X3JrMmJyUFlFNGI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:08:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India summons envoy: Why Bangladesh has objected to fencing along the border - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India summons envoy: Why Bangladesh has objected to fencing along the border</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/indo-bangla-border.jpeg?resize=600,338" alt="indo bangla border fencing"><figcaption>The BSF says fencing is important to curb trans-border crimes.</figcaption><p>India's Ministry of External Affairs asserts its compliance with all agreements regarding border security amidst renewed tensions with Bangladesh over fencing activities along their shared border.</p><ul><li>Bangladesh raised concerns over violations of a bilateral agreement regarding border fencing.</li><li>The Border Guards Bangladesh (BGB) attempted to stop the construction of a barbed wire fence in West Bengal.</li><li>Fencing along the India-Bangladesh border has been a contentious issue, with historical disputes regarding the construction protocols.</li><li>India has completed a substantial portion of the border fencing, yet challenges remain due to terrain and local objections.</li></ul><blockquote>“The SRF is erected mainly to stop animal movement and check trans-border crimes.” – Surjeet Singh Guleria, Inspector General (Retd), BSF</blockquote><p>The ongoing negotiations and rising tensions highlight the complexity and sensitivity surrounding border security measures between India and Bangladesh.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/india-summons-envoy-bangladesh-border-fencing-row-9778190/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/india-summons-envoy-bangladesh-border-fencing-row-9778190/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Haryana BJP chief Mohan Lal Badoli, singer Rocky Mittal booked for gang-rape of Delhi resident in Himachal - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/haryana-bjp-chief-mohal-lal-badoli-singer-rocky-mittal-gang-rape-9778621/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/haryana-bjp-chief-mohal-lal-badoli-singer-rocky-mittal-gang-rape-9778621/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-IAS trainee Puja Khedkar moves to Supreme Court after Delhi HC rejects anticipatory bail - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Puja Khedkar Appeals to Supreme Court After Bail Rejection</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/Puja-Khedkar--File-Photo_1736862180981_1736862181236.jpg" alt="IAS trainee Pooja Khedkar approached SC" title="IAS trainee Pooja Khedkar approached SC"><figcaption>IAS trainee Pooja Khedkar approached SC</figcaption></figure><p>Puja Khedkar, a former IAS trainee, has moved to the Supreme Court after the Delhi High Court denied her anticipatory bail. She is accused of forging documents to gain eligibility for the 2022 UPSC exam.</p><ul><li>Khedkar allegedly exploited benefits for OBC and disability categories.</li><li>The Delhi High Court described her actions as a "glaring example of fraud".</li><li>Public trust in competitive exams could be severely impacted if the allegations are substantiated.</li><li>Khedkar has been banned from UPSC and removed from IAS after her appointment was denied.</li><li>She claims to be targeted due to her accusations of sexual harassment against a senior official.</li></ul><blockquote>“The public's trust in competitive exams and their credibility would be severely damaged if such charges were proven true.” - Delhi High Court</blockquote><p>This case raises significant concerns about meritocracy within public service and could have broader implications for the integrity of civil service examinations in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/exias-trainee-puja-khedkar-moves-to-supreme-court-after-delhi-hc-rejects-anticipatory-bail-101736861033433.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/exias-trainee-puja-khedkar-moves-to-supreme-court-after-delhi-hc-rejects-anticipatory-bail-101736861033433.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>