<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 04:26:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 04:26:48 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Sunny Leone' Got Rs 1000/Month Under Chhattisgarh Scheme For Married Women - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPc1FBUDE2SGxFYm10T3MwZHFPWC1abmF4RlVsdUZZM2VsWms0WWdvREtGRlRHd0J4R2NDTkpUcWlfTTlYcmMyNG1CeXZmZTFaSWNENzNzMV9ySTlVd0FyRENMZEZQTU9zdlBUNFdxVVdpdnVYUXVxWFYtNmdVYjdROUllN0hlNjAxYVhuOVZSUUo3SEpfUzZ1MTZ3ZTNkMlRETVRhOW4yNDk5blBiT0Z5NnlSck9zdXpMdmhkVXBFLUhqZlJOSzJtd1RRMFFzT29W?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPc1FBUDE2SGxFYm10T3MwZHFPWC1abmF4RlVsdUZZM2VsWms0WWdvREtGRlRHd0J4R2NDTkpUcWlfTTlYcmMyNG1CeXZmZTFaSWNENzNzMV9ySTlVd0FyRENMZEZQTU9zdlBUNFdxVVdpdnVYUXVxWFYtNmdVYjdROUllN0hlNjAxYVhuOVZSUUo3SEpfUzZ1MTZ3ZTNkMlRETVRhOW4yNDk5blBiT0Z5NnlSck9zdXpMdmhkVXBFLUhqZlJOSzJtd1RRMFFzT29W?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:13:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 pro-Khalistan terrorists killed in police encounter in UP's Pilibhit - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>3 Pro-Khalistan Terrorists Killed in Police Encounter in UP's Pilibhit</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 20, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>A recent police encounter in Pilibhit, Uttar Pradesh, resulted in the death of three individuals linked to the pro-Khalistan movement during an operation aimed at curbing extremist activities in the region.</p><ul><li>The terrorists were reportedly involved in planning violent acts targeting various establishments.</li><li>Authorities noted that the operation was part of a larger initiative to enhance security and prevent the spread of extremism in Uttar Pradesh.</li><li>The encounter involved heavy gunfire and was conducted after extensive intelligence gathering.</li></ul><blockquote>"Our forces are committed to ensuring the safety of the public and will take strict action against those promoting violence and disruption." - Police spokesperson</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the operation serves as a reminder of ongoing security challenges posed by extremist groups and the need for vigilant actions by law enforcement to maintain peace.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/3-pro-khalistan-terrorists-killed-in-police-encounter-in-ups-pilibhit/articleshow/116583310.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/3-pro-khalistan-terrorists-killed-in-police-encounter-in-ups-pilibhit/articleshow/116583310.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pune: Three Dead, Six Injured in Wagholi as Drunken Driver’s Dumper Crushes People On Footpath - Punekar News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.punekarnews.in/pune-three-dead-six-injured-in-wagholi-as-drunken-drivers-dumper-crushes-people-on-footpath/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.punekarnews.in/pune-three-dead-six-injured-in-wagholi-as-drunken-drivers-dumper-crushes-people-on-footpath/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 03:06:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rain Brings The Chill To Delhi, But Air Quality Remains "Severe" - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxONUVqdmtGNTVGdndlekY3bElLZXhaaWtjMmEzb3pMenFyc09Ia2RLbTlNN2VrX1g3a1BtdWZrMmdacjc2STR4Uk9Dd1JSalNiWTJlQW9JNk9oYjdjZ2VYVTR6bW9NS1hNZGY1RklQWG1FM1VER0lvZHFlTGpnQTFDR2tjV3k5c2NJZ2R2a1hWUGpPalZGNU1UNmlaSnVXaFRmS3lua0szQXFwVEJqcWIxNzV0dVc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxONUVqdmtGNTVGdndlekY3bElLZXhaaWtjMmEzb3pMenFyc09Ia2RLbTlNN2VrX1g3a1BtdWZrMmdacjc2STR4Uk9Dd1JSalNiWTJlQW9JNk9oYjdjZ2VYVTR6bW9NS1hNZGY1RklQWG1FM1VER0lvZHFlTGpnQTFDR2tjV3k5c2NJZ2R2a1hWUGpPalZGNU1UNmlaSnVXaFRmS3lua0szQXFwVEJqcWIxNzV0dVc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 02:21:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atul Subhash: A man's suicide leads to clamour around India's dowry law - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Atul Subhash: A man's suicide leads to clamour around India's dowry law</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> BBC News</p>
<img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/c4fe/live/233005c0-bee6-11ef-9880-bd78436cd924.jpg.webp" alt="BBC Atul Subhash with his parents and brother in happier times">
<figcaption>Atul Subhash's suicide has galvanised men's rights activists and started a wider debate around India's tough dowry law</figcaption>
<p>On December 9, Atul Subhash, a 34-year-old software engineer, took his own life, leaving behind a note that accused his estranged wife and her family of harassment. His death has ignited discussions surrounding India's controversial dowry law and its implications.</p>
<ul>
<li>Subhash left a 24-page suicide note and an 81-minute video detailing his struggles.</li>
<li>He accused his estranged wife, Nikita Singhania, and her family of harassment, which they denied.</li>
<li>His suicide has led to protests demanding justice and calls for changes to the dowry law.</li>
<li>The law has been criticized for being misused by women, yet women's rights activists point to the ongoing issues of dowry-related violence.</li>
<li>India's Supreme Court has noted the potential misuse of the law, calling for caution in its application.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The law had come after a long and hard fight” - Sukriti Chauhan</blockquote>
<p>The tragic incident has opened a dialogue about the complexities of marriage, harassment, and the law in contemporary India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c33d6161z3yo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c33d6161z3yo</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 01:14:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Hindu Morning Digest, December 23, 2024 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hyderabad Police release video detailing events leading to stampede at Sandhya Theatre</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<p>The Hyderabad Police released a video outlining the events leading to a tragic stampede at Sandhya Theatre, where one individual died, and another was critically injured. Simultaneously, Congress criticized the government's complex GST tax system over differing popcorn tax slabs.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The video by Hyderabad Police details the timeline of the December 4 stampede.</li>
  <li>Revathi died, and her son Sritej was critically injured in the incident.</li>
  <li>Congress demanded a reform of the GST regime, pointing out tax loopholes.</li>
  <li>Half of the MGNREGS sites inspected in Bengal showed irregularities.</li>
  <li>Kuwait honored PM Modi with the 'Order of Mubarak Al Kabeer'.</li>
  <li>Farmer leader Dallewal's health condition worsens as his fast continues.</li>
  <li>West Bengal and Bihar are highly affected by arsenic contamination.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>'The current complexities in the system had thrown open several loopholes leading to tax evasion.'</blockquote>
<p>These developments highlight ongoing issues in public safety, economic policy, and health controversies while emphasizing the need for accountability and reforms in various areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/morning-digest-december-23-2024/article69016574.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/morning-digest-december-23-2024/article69016574.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building collapse: Mohali toll rises to 2, rescue ops called off - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohali Building Collapse: Death Toll Rises to Two, Rescue Operations Terminated</h1><p><strong>Published on: </strong>Sunday, <strong>Source: </strong>The Tribune</p><img src='https://example.com/mohali-building-collapse' alt='Mohali Building Collapse' /><figcaption>Rescue operations at the site of the collapsed building in Mohali.</figcaption><p>The toll in the Mohali building collapse has risen to two with the recovery of the body of a 30-year-old man, Abhishek Dhanwal, from the rubble on Sunday. Dhanwal worked with an IT firm. Earlier, the body of Drishti Verma (20) was recovered. The multi-storey building collapsed on Saturday evening at Sohana village in Mohali district.</p><ul><li>Two building owners arrested on charges of culpable homicide</li><li>Digging work was being carried out on the adjoining plot when the structure collapsed</li><li>No permission was taken for the digging work</li></ul><p>The 23-hour-long rescue operations were called off after officials confirmed no one else was trapped. A magisterial probe has been ordered, with the SDM to submit the report within three weeks. The building had a gym and PG accommodation, and digging work was being carried out on the adjoining plot.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/punjab/building-collapse-mohali-toll-rises-to-2-rescue-ops-called-off/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/punjab/building-collapse-mohali-toll-rises-to-2-rescue-ops-called-off/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:21:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India getting into 'offensive' play after Trump check - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India getting into 'offensive' play after Trump check</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><img src="https://img.etimg.com/photo/msid-116575936/screenshot-2024-12-23-011924.jpg" alt="Screenshot 2024-12-23 011924"><figcaption>India's strategic position on trade ahead of Donald Trump's policies.</figcaption><p>As Donald Trump prepares to take office, India is proactively engaging with industry stakeholders to outline their trade demands from the US. This initiative is crucial as Trump has hinted at imposing reciprocal taxes.</p><ul><li>India is soliciting 'offensive asks' from industry to evaluate trade impacts.</li><li>The US, a significant trade partner, had $53 billion in goods exports from India in the past financial year.</li><li>There are ongoing preparations regarding a mini trade deal discussed during Trump's previous term.</li><li>Global Trade Research Initiative suggests strategies for India to navigate potential tariffs.</li><li>India and the US are part of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, with three pillars operational.</li></ul><blockquote>"Negotiations, discussions, retaliation, dispute or mini trade deal, nothing is off or on the cards," said an official.</blockquote><p>India's approach signifies an important position in managing trade relations with the US amid evolving policies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/foreign-trade/india-getting-into-offensive-play-after-trump-check/articleshow/116575382.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/foreign-trade/india-getting-into-offensive-play-after-trump-check/articleshow/116575382.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Under Rozgar Mela, Modi to distribute over 71,000 appointment letters to recruits in govt. departments - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Modi to Distribute Over 71,000 Appointment Letters at Rozgar Mela</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/pgns2o/article69016791.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_17_2024_000115B.jpg" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi. File." /><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi. File. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will distribute more than 71,000 appointment letters to new recruits in various Union government departments on December 23, 2024, via videoconferencing.</p><ul><li>The Rozgar Mela aims to prioritize employment generation.</li><li>Distribution of appointment letters will begin at approximately 10:30 am.</li><li>Mr. Modi will also address attendees during the event.</li><li>The event will take place at 45 locations across the country.</li><li>Recruitment includes roles in ministries such as Home Affairs, Health, and Higher Education.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Rozgar Mela will provide meaningful opportunities to youngsters for their participation in nation-building and self-empowerment.”</blockquote><p>This initiative reflects the government's commitment to boosting employment opportunities for the youth across the nation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/under-rozgar-mela-modi-to-distribute-over-71000-appointment-letters-to-recruits-in-govt-departments/article69016007.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/under-rozgar-mela-modi-to-distribute-over-71000-appointment-letters-to-recruits-in-govt-departments/article69016007.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kashmir’s coldest winter in years - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxNTzh5NTFCdXFnbFU3dlI4bUV1WHdqSUxWTERITVUtUTUtNGlHYWtfZFBSTXV4dXRDZGkxYnZydHEzSmhMRHVJYlZaUzZuSllIYVpDWV9KU2k2QmJIdlozYjZWNUZXUi0tLWZfTmRrZS1VUFpyOTlkeVJZVmNQQ0pXV21TSdIBhwFBVV95cUxPb0lzMDIwSWtlQVNiOUlqMlY1WVBoUWM5dnJ2aFQ4bUl1R1ZYLWUwejB4UGNvUDZlYS1VamgybzI5SUROVkdPYVQyOHE1QzBJTFJ0ODRqdS1uU2U2aTAtWlZHRDhtRHphd0puR0I2Zi1IUGY2VEJlQWV6Yk5QRkhIY3l2V0ZxT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxNTzh5NTFCdXFnbFU3dlI4bUV1WHdqSUxWTERITVUtUTUtNGlHYWtfZFBSTXV4dXRDZGkxYnZydHEzSmhMRHVJYlZaUzZuSllIYVpDWV9KU2k2QmJIdlozYjZWNUZXUi0tLWZfTmRrZS1VUFpyOTlkeVJZVmNQQ0pXV21TSdIBhwFBVV95cUxPb0lzMDIwSWtlQVNiOUlqMlY1WVBoUWM5dnJ2aFQ4bUl1R1ZYLWUwejB4UGNvUDZlYS1VamgybzI5SUROVkdPYVQyOHE1QzBJTFJ0ODRqdS1uU2U2aTAtWlZHRDhtRHphd0puR0I2Zi1IUGY2VEJlQWV6Yk5QRkhIY3l2V0ZxT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:12:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wrong understanding of dharma leads to atrocities in its name across the world: Bhagwat - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wrong understanding of dharma leads to atrocities in its name across the world: Bhagwat</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>In a recent statement, Bhagwat emphasized that a flawed interpretation of dharma is causing atrocities globally, urging for a clearer understanding of its true essence.</p><ul><li>Bhagwat criticizes the misuse of the concept of dharma.</li><li>He calls for an enlightened understanding to prevent violence and injustices.</li><li>The discussion touches on historical and contemporary examples of dharma misinterpretations.</li></ul><blockquote>“A wrong understanding of dharma has led to confusion and violence,” Bhagwat stated.</blockquote><p>It is imperative for societies to reflect on the true teachings of dharma to foster peace and unity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/nagpur/wrong-understanding-of-dharma-leads-to-atrocities-in-its-name-across-the-world-bhagwat/articleshow/116575292.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/nagpur/wrong-understanding-of-dharma-leads-to-atrocities-in-its-name-across-the-world-bhagwat/articleshow/116575292.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Receives Kuwait's Highest Civilian Honour, His 20th International Award - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Receives Kuwait's Highest Civilian Honour, His 20th International Award</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The emir of Kuwait, Sheikh Meshal Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al Sabah, conferred Prime Minister Narendra Modi with the West Asian nation’s highest civilian award 'The Order of Mubarak the Great'. (IMAGE: NARENDRA MODI/X)" title="The emir of Kuwait, Sheikh Meshal Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al Sabah, conferred Prime Minister Narendra Modi with the West Asian nation’s highest civilian award 'The Order of Mubarak the Great'. (IMAGE: NARENDRA MODI/X)"><figcaption>The emir of Kuwait, Sheikh Meshal Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al Sabah, conferred Prime Minister Narendra Modi with the West Asian nation’s highest civilian award 'The Order of Mubarak the Great'. (IMAGE: NARENDRA MODI/X)</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi was conferred with Kuwait’s highest civilian honour, the ‘Mubarak Al-Kabeer Order’, in a ceremony held today at Bayan Palace by Kuwaiti Emir Sheikh Meshal Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al-Sabah. The award is traditionally conferred upon Heads of State and dignitaries as a gesture of friendship.</p><ul><li>PM Modi has received over 20 international honours to date.</li><li>Previous recipients of this award include US Presidents Bill Clinton and George Bush, and UK royal King Charles III.</li><li>The award recognizes contributions to strengthening ties between India and Kuwait.</li><li>PM Modi’s visit marks the first by an Indian prime minister to Kuwait in 43 years.</li></ul><blockquote><p>I am honoured to be conferred the Mubarak Al-Kabeer Order by His Highness the Amir of Kuwait, Sheikh Meshal Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al Sabah. I dedicate this honour to the people of India and to the strong friendship between India and Kuwait. — Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) December 22, 2024</p></blockquote><p>PM Modi expressed his hope that the friendship between India and Kuwait will continue to grow stronger in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/kuwait-bestows-its-highest-honour-mubarak-al-kabeer-order-on-pm-modi-9164786.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/kuwait-bestows-its-highest-honour-mubarak-al-kabeer-order-on-pm-modi-9164786.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 18:58:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Farmers push for SC’s help after parliamentary standing committee backs MSP law - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Farmers Urge Supreme Court to Implement MSP Law After Committee's Support</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Farmers-have-been-protesting-for-months-over-sever_1734893419204.jpg" alt="Farmers have been protesting for months over several demands, including a legal guarantee of MSP, on the borders of Delhi. (PTI)">
<figcaption>Farmers have been protesting for months over several demands, including a legal guarantee of MSP, on the borders of Delhi. (PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Farmers, led by Jagjit Singh Dallewal, are calling on the Supreme Court to enforce the parliamentary committee's recommendation for a legally guaranteed minimum support price (MSP) for farm produce.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Dallewal is on a fast-unto-death to push for the implementation of the MSP law.</li>
  <li>The parliamentary standing committee has emphasized the need for legally guaranteed MSPs for farmers.</li>
  <li>The report suggests the agriculture ministry should create a roadmap for implementing MSP.</li>
  <li>MSPs are intended to provide a minimum price to prevent distress sales among farmers.</li>
  <li>The committee's report discusses the advantages of implementing MSP as a legal guarantee to enhance rural economic growth.</li>
  <li>If not implemented, the government must provide a formal explanation to the committee.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Implementing a legally binding MSP in India is essential not only for safeguarding farmers’ livelihoods but also for promoting rural economic growth.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the farmers' plea, supported by the parliamentary committee, highlights the critical need for legal guarantees to ensure fair compensation for farmers’ produce, which could lead to sustainable farming practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/farmers-push-for-sc-s-help-to-bring-msplaw-101734893426395.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/farmers-push-for-sc-s-help-to-bring-msplaw-101734893426395.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 18:50:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi's Air Quality Turns 'Severe' Despite GRAP-4 Restrictions - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi's Air Quality Turns 'Severe' Despite GRAP-4 Restrictions</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 24 December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Delhi's Air Quality Turns 'Severe' Despite GRAP-4 Restrictions" alt="Delhi's Air Quality Turns 'Severe' Despite GRAP-4 Restrictions" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mvqfkt9g_delhi-pollution_625x300_22_December_24.jpeg"><figcaption>Delhi's air quality has worsened to severe levels.</figcaption><p>The air quality in Delhi has sharply deteriorated, reaching severe levels despite existing pollution control measures.</p><ul><li>The 24-hour average Air Quality Index (AQI) peaked at 409, indicating 'severe' pollution levels.</li><li>On the previous day, the AQI was recorded at 370, classified as 'very poor'.</li><li>PM2.5 particles remain the primary pollutant, with 37 out of 39 stations reporting severe conditions.</li><li>Areas reported alarming AQI readings as high as 474.</li><li>Delhi is currently under Stage IV of the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP), enacting strict anti-pollution measures.</li></ul><blockquote>“PM2.5 particles, which are 2.5 micrometres or smaller in diameter, can penetrate deep into the lungs, posing significant health risks.”</blockquote><p>The ongoing severe air quality raises serious health concerns, despite measures being in place to control pollution levels in the capital.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/delhis-air-quality-turns-severe-despite-grap-4-restrictions-7309926</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/delhis-air-quality-turns-severe-despite-grap-4-restrictions-7309926</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 18:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Risk of cardiac arrest, condition critical’: Doctors on farmer leader Dallewal as fast-unto-death enters Day 27 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Doctors Warn of Cardiac Arrest Risk as Farmer Leader Dallewal Enters Day 27 of Hunger Strike</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 22, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Veteran-farmer-leader-Jagjit-Singh-Dallewal--who-i_1734886329450_1734886337400.jpeg" alt="Veteran farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal, who is fast-unto-death, being checked by doctors. (HT photo)(HT_PRINT)" /><figcaption>Veteran farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal, who is fast-unto-death, being checked by doctors. (HT photo)(HT_PRINT)</figcaption><p>Farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal, currently on a hunger strike for 27 days, is in critical condition at the Khanauri border protest site.</p><ul><li>Dallewal is 70 years old and is demanding a legal guarantee for Minimum Support Price (MSP) on crops.</li><li>Doctors have stated he is at risk of cardiac arrest and multi-organ failure due to his prolonged fasting.</li><li>His condition shows signs of severe weakness, with symptoms affecting his nervous system and vital organs.</li><li>On December 26, symbolic hunger strikes will be organized at various levels to support his cause.</li><li>The farmers continue to protest at border points following failed attempts to march to Delhi.</li></ul><blockquote>“He is hemodynamically unstable... He is at risk of cardiac arrest and his condition is critical,” the doctor said.</blockquote><p>This situation raises concerns for the safety and wellbeing of Dallewal and highlights ongoing issues related to farmer rights and agricultural policies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/farmer-leader-jagjit-singh-dallewal-health-update-day-27-doctors-say-condition-critical-101734886140368.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/farmer-leader-jagjit-singh-dallewal-health-update-day-27-doctors-say-condition-critical-101734886140368.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:28:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Adani's big move, to set up Rs 20000 crore ultra-super critical... - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxOYTJneGo0X1V4YndsaERxR2MwRU4wYkRDNjFmNmdMeC1xUHRNWEdvekQ1WU0zUHgySHpVYkRibWNjQ3ZlTU95cXlpODhNYVBzODFBTVVBNGphVTNXN0RWbWpWb2U3V1NsRHRXQUFkaWVvRlRlMXE2Nk1YWk1DenZwVE9KeHlONGpVZ1FIbGcyak4xM2tPVENmdDZ1dXV4QTZIeDhzLUlRTUtxcE1GQ0N5TWluTWU3WUV2UTVmMjM0dnh0alRiUnVjTjZGc0xfc0VmdHRCUEpn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxOYTJneGo0X1V4YndsaERxR2MwRU4wYkRDNjFmNmdMeC1xUHRNWEdvekQ1WU0zUHgySHpVYkRibWNjQ3ZlTU95cXlpODhNYVBzODFBTVVBNGphVTNXN0RWbWpWb2U3V1NsRHRXQUFkaWVvRlRlMXE2Nk1YWk1DenZwVE9KeHlONGpVZ1FIbGcyak4xM2tPVENmdDZ1dXV4QTZIeDhzLUlRTUtxcE1GQ0N5TWluTWU3WUV2UTVmMjM0dnh0alRiUnVjTjZGc0xfc0VmdHRCUEpn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Couple Tied To Pole, Thrashed By Mob In Bihar - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/couple-tied-to-pole-thrashed-by-mob-in-bihar-video-viral-7309603</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/couple-tied-to-pole-thrashed-by-mob-in-bihar-video-viral-7309603</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:12:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NC MP to join protest on reservation issue outside CM’s residence - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/nc-mp-to-join-protest-on-reservation-issue-outside-cms-residence/article69016213.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/nc-mp-to-join-protest-on-reservation-issue-outside-cms-residence/article69016213.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi's special food recommendation as he enjoys family lunch at Delhi restaurant - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rahul Gandhi's special food recommendation as he enjoys family lunch at Delhi restaurant</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Rahul Gandhi Family Lunch" />
<figcaption>Rahul Gandhi dines at a popular Delhi restaurant.</figcaption>
<p>Rahul Gandhi was spotted enjoying a family lunch at a restaurant in Delhi, where he shared his food recommendations with fans and reporters.</p>
<ul>
<li>Rahul Gandhi praised the local cuisine and made specific recommendations to patrons.</li>
<li>The outing showcased his personal side, connecting with family and the public.</li>
<li>Photos of the event went viral on social media, sparking discussions among supporters and critics alike.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Good food brings people together.” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote>
<p>This event reflects Rahul Gandhi's efforts to remain relatable to the public amid political challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/rahul-gandhis-special-food-recommendation-as-he-enjoys-family-lunch-at-delhi-restaurant-priyanka-sonia-gandhi-robert-vadra/articleshow/116571018.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/rahul-gandhis-special-food-recommendation-as-he-enjoys-family-lunch-at-delhi-restaurant-priyanka-sonia-gandhi-robert-vadra/articleshow/116571018.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15-Year-Old Boy Dies By Suicide After Mother Refuses To Buy Him New Phone In Maharashtra - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>15-Year-Old Boy Dies By Suicide After Mother Refuses To Buy Him New Phone in Maharashtra</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/0htt5beg_india-police-generic_625x300_23_December_22.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="15-Year-Old Boy Dies By Suicide After Mother Refuses To Buy Him New Phone In Maharashtra"><figcaption>A 15-year-old boy tragically dies by suicide after being denied a mobile phone from his mother.</figcaption><p>A 15-year-old boy in Maharashtra's Sangli district reportedly dies by suicide after his mother denied his request for a mobile phone on his birthday due to financial constraints.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred in Miraj city on a Saturday night.</li><li>The boy was found hanging by his family the following day.</li><li>An accidental death report (ADR) has been registered and further investigation is in progress.</li></ul><blockquote>“The official added an accidental death report (ADR) has been registered.”</blockquote><p>This tragic event underscores the severe consequences that mental health issues can have on young individuals and highlights the need for open communication within families.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/15-year-old-boy-dies-by-suicide-after-mother-refuses-to-buy-him-new-phone-in-maharashtra-7308993</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/15-year-old-boy-dies-by-suicide-after-mother-refuses-to-buy-him-new-phone-in-maharashtra-7308993</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:18:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As Rahul Gandhi plans to visit Parbhani, BJP, Sena leaders call it ‘drama’ - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rahul Gandhi's Planned Visit to Parbhani Criticized as 'Drama' by BJP and Sena Leaders</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/3lcor6/article69016799.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/VIS_5814.JPG" alt="Maharashtra Police personnel keep vigil near Dr. Bhimrao Ambedkar Statue at Station Road in Parbhani, Maharashtra on December 14, 2024." title="Maharashtra Police personnel keep vigil near Dr. Bhimrao Ambedkar Statue at Station Road in Parbhani, Maharashtra on December 14, 2024."><figcaption>Maharashtra Police personnel keep vigil near Dr. Bhimrao Ambedkar Statue at Station Road in Parbhani, Maharashtra on December 14, 2024. | Photo Credit: Vijay Soneji</figcaption><p>Rahul Gandhi's upcoming visit to Parbhani has drawn sharp criticism from BJP and Shiv Sena leaders, who label it as an act of political 'drama' rather than genuine concern.</p><ul><li>Gandhi plans to meet the families of victims of recent violence in Parbhani.</li><li>Shiv Sena's Shaina N.C. accuses Gandhi of hypocrisy for politically capitalizing on the tragedy.</li><li>BJP chief Chandrashekar Bawankule also condemns Gandhi, suggesting his motives are self-serving.</li><li>The recent violence was instigated by an alleged desecration of a Constitution replica, causing significant property damage and arrests.</li></ul><blockquote>“Rahul Gandhi has been performing drama for his entire life... With such politics, the Congress would not find its feet in the State.” - Chandrashekar Bawankule, BJP Chief</blockquote><p>The political climate surrounding Gandhi's visit raises questions about the authenticity of political gestures in times of crisis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/bjp-sena-leaders-call-it-drama-as-rahul-gandhi-plans-to-visit-parbhani/article69016209.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/bjp-sena-leaders-call-it-drama-as-rahul-gandhi-plans-to-visit-parbhani/article69016209.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi's AQI turns ‘severe’ at 409 amid GRAP 4 restrictions - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi's Air Quality Index Reaches Severe Levels Amid GRAP 4 Restrictions</h1>
<p><strong>Published on: December 22, 2024</strong><br><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/delhi_air_pollution_1734879208282_1734879208579.jpg" alt="Delhi AQI severe conditions" title="Delhi AQI severe conditions">
<figcaption>On Saturday, the capital's AQI was recorded in the ‘very poor’ category at 370. (Arvind Yadav/HT PHOTO)</figcaption>
<p>The air quality in Delhi worsened to 'severe' with an AQI reading of 409 as the city continued to face restrictions under GRAP 4 due to deteriorating air conditions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The AQI rose from 370 (very poor) to 409 (severe) in 24 hours.</li>
  <li>Humidity levels were reported between 68% and 97% amidst foggy conditions.</li>
  <li>IMD forecasts light rain and cloudy skies for the following day.</li>
  <li>GRAP 4 restrictions include a ban on construction activities and entry of polluting trucks.</li>
  <li>Schools are required to shift classes for grades VI-IX and XI to hybrid mode.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“On December 16, the Centre's air quality panel imposed the GRAP IV curbs under the winter air pollution control plan.”</blockquote>
<p>This severe air pollution event not only affects health but also disrupts educational systems and daily life in Delhi.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhis-aqi-turns-severe-at-409-amid-grap-4-restrictions-101734878950592.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhis-aqi-turns-severe-at-409-amid-grap-4-restrictions-101734878950592.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:04:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dallewals condition critical, say doctors as farmer leaders fast enters 27th day - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQT0xYNi1BeEZCbU9xdlBZb09XQjFtLUpVdjdqNEh6NjlkZHBpcF9WM0s4LTJ3ay1WVUNrMVRybnQ2bFQzeVBibk1YcENyWjBJUWlRVlZoMC1mQTYtZFVDRTFQeHpPWnBGMmpudXZmR1dFUlk4UFhlbDdDeE9NcGNXUHp5cnJaTmtEMzE1a1EySjJRZF9ldXlQZUtLR2p1VTl6cUk2emxLdVNQWkllXzU0X3NOTVF5a1pzRG9KT1JR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQT0xYNi1BeEZCbU9xdlBZb09XQjFtLUpVdjdqNEh6NjlkZHBpcF9WM0s4LTJ3ay1WVUNrMVRybnQ2bFQzeVBibk1YcENyWjBJUWlRVlZoMC1mQTYtZFVDRTFQeHpPWnBGMmpudXZmR1dFUlk4UFhlbDdDeE9NcGNXUHp5cnJaTmtEMzE1a1EySjJRZF9ldXlQZUtLR2p1VTl6cUk2emxLdVNQWkllXzU0X3NOTVF5a1pzRG9KT1JR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:04:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In special gesture, Kuwait’s PM personally sees off PM Modi at airport as he leaves for India - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kuwait’s Prime Minister Bids Farewell to PM Modi at Airport</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>The Prime Minister of Kuwait personally escorted Prime Minister Modi at the airport as he departed for India, marking a significant diplomatic gesture.</p>
<ul>
<li>Kuwait's PM emphasized the strong ties between India and Kuwait.</li>
<li>The gesture reflects the growing relationship and cooperation between the two nations.</li>
<li>PM Modi expressed gratitude for the warm hospitality received during his visit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This is a testament to our flourishing relationship," said PM Modi during his departure.</blockquote>
<p>This personal send-off from Kuwait’s Prime Minister highlights the importance of diplomatic relationships and is a positive reflection of international cooperation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/in-special-gesture-kuwaits-pm-personally-sees-off-pm-modi-at-airport-as-he-leaves-for-india/articleshow/116570369.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/in-special-gesture-kuwaits-pm-personally-sees-off-pm-modi-at-airport-as-he-leaves-for-india/articleshow/116570369.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Leave India where they will even tax your popcorn ...': Startup founder to Indians with high salaries - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Leave India where they will even tax your popcorn ...': Startup founder to Indians with high salaries</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Publication Date Here]</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name Here]</p><p>This article discusses the challenges faced by Indians with high salaries, including taxation policies that influence their choices about where to live and work.</p><ul><li>The startup founder highlights the financial burdens imposed on high-income individuals in India.</li><li>Suggestions are made regarding the potential benefits of relocating to countries with more favorable taxation.</li><li>The commentary reflects broader sentiments among professionals regarding India's economic environment.</li></ul><blockquote>“In India, even popcorn is taxed heavily, making it hard for professionals to manage their finances.”</blockquote><p>The discussion raises significant points about the current economic climate in India and its impact on the workforce.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/social/leave-india-where-they-will-even-tax-your-popcorn-startup-founder-to-indians-with-high-salaries/articleshow/116570559.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/social/leave-india-where-they-will-even-tax-your-popcorn-startup-founder-to-indians-with-high-salaries/articleshow/116570559.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi's Sunday family lunch & a food recommendation amid Parliament scuffle row - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rahul Gandhi's Family Lunch and Food Recommendation Amid Parliament Scuffle Row</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 22, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/PTI12-22-2024-000193B-0_1734875564284_1734875591078.jpg" alt="LoP in the Lok Sabha and Congress leader Rahul Gandhi with his family at Kwality restaurant." title="LoP in the Lok Sabha and Congress leader Rahul Gandhi with his family at Kwality restaurant."><figcaption>LoP in the Lok Sabha and Congress leader Rahul Gandhi with his mother Sonia Gandhi, sister and MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra and brother-in-law Robert Vadra has lunch at Kwality restaurant.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Amid the ongoing row in Parliament, Congress leader Rahul Gandhi shared a glimpse of his Sunday family lunch at New Delhi's iconic Kwality Restaurant, recommending Chole Bhature, a North Indian delicacy, to his followers.</p><ul><li>Rahul Gandhi celebrated a family lunch alongside his mother Sonia Gandhi, sister Priyanka Gandhi, brother-in-law Robert Vadra, and his niece.</li><li>He posted recommendations for the restaurant's famous Chole Bhature on his Instagram.</li><li>The lunch takes place during a turbulent period of political conflict in Parliament.</li><li>An FIR has been lodged against Rahul Gandhi in connection with a scuffle involving BJP MPs.</li><li>Two BJP MPs were injured during the altercation following protests staged by NDA and INDIA bloc MPs.</li></ul><blockquote>“Family lunch at the iconic Kwality Restaurant. Try the Chole Bhature if you go,” he captioned the post.</blockquote><p>The shared images and his food recommendation come at a time when political tensions are high, reflecting the dual public and personal facets of Gandhi's current life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rahul-gandhis-sunday-family-lunch-a-food-recommendation-amid-parliament-scuffle-row-101734875017751.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rahul-gandhis-sunday-family-lunch-a-food-recommendation-amid-parliament-scuffle-row-101734875017751.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:42:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Leave India! It's high time': Startup founder's controversial post on Reddit goes viral | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>’Leave India! It’s high time’: Startup founder’s controversial post on Reddit goes viral</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>A recent controversial post by an entrepreneur on Reddit advising high-salaried individuals to leave India due to high taxes and lack of innovation is gaining a lot of attention.</p><img src='URL_to_image' alt='Startup Founder' /><figcaption>Startup founder expressing his views on Reddit.</figcaption><p>The Indian entrepreneur and startup founder, who studied at premier engineering institutes in India and pursued post-graduate education in the USA, shared his frustrations regarding the regulatory landscape and civic issues in India.</p><ul><li>The post highlights discontent with India's bureaucratic hurdles and regional discrimination.</li><li>The entrepreneur warns of a potential economic collapse in India and advocates for relocating to countries like UAE or Thailand for innovators.</li><li>He expresses dissatisfaction with the social behavior and a lack of civic sense among the populace.</li></ul><blockquote>“In a nutshell...leave the country where they will even tax your popcorn because they are out of ideas to make it a 5 trillion dollar economy!”</blockquote><p>The controversial post has sparked numerous discussions among Reddit users, some of whom resonate with his views.</p><p>This discourse brings attention to the challenges faced by professionals in India and provokes reactions regarding the nation's investment climate and infrastructure issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/entrepreneur-controversial-post-reddit-high-salaried-individuals-innovators-to-leave-india-due-to-high-taxes-11734871425782.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/entrepreneur-controversial-post-reddit-high-salaried-individuals-innovators-to-leave-india-due-to-high-taxes-11734871425782.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:32:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fraudster opens online account in Sunny Leone’s name, gets Rs 1,000 monthly under govt scheme - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxPV2tKbkx4Uzh1dEJGSnJEWVZJdWdNbjZTd0JMWGlQSUE1UVVjWWpaYjdyRFBack9nblVsQ1JBQ0hSa05lVFc5dXpaMENLTHprSXZlRVh6WXhJMHRobjY2NDFUcGw3dTE2dVhjbFYwaG12dzZkcjFuNTZEUTczQ09xbVI4a3XSAYsBQVVfeXFMUDVMcEVLM2dfeVd2MjZ2VDc2cWlXOC1raXp2b0ZVb0lPb3k5Yll2cFNnU3lUNjlaUDJQc2p6MnpyWWJEd3ZUaU9RS1JWcDM1SnRfbWRGWTFuMnNkQWNIVjBqRGVBeFBuWmdMOWRySmotaE9telozeW1LNTNxTENjNElMOGhOc0Q0ZGs4QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxPV2tKbkx4Uzh1dEJGSnJEWVZJdWdNbjZTd0JMWGlQSUE1UVVjWWpaYjdyRFBack9nblVsQ1JBQ0hSa05lVFc5dXpaMENLTHprSXZlRVh6WXhJMHRobjY2NDFUcGw3dTE2dVhjbFYwaG12dzZkcjFuNTZEUTczQ09xbVI4a3XSAYsBQVVfeXFMUDVMcEVLM2dfeVd2MjZ2VDc2cWlXOC1raXp2b0ZVb0lPb3k5Yll2cFNnU3lUNjlaUDJQc2p6MnpyWWJEd3ZUaU9RS1JWcDM1SnRfbWRGWTFuMnNkQWNIVjBqRGVBeFBuWmdMOWRySmotaE9telozeW1LNTNxTENjNElMOGhOc0Q0ZGs4QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:30:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pics: Rahul Gandhi's Family Lunch At Iconic Delhi Restaurant - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rahul Gandhi Enjoys Family Lunch at Iconic Delhi Restaurant</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/635v077o_rahul-gandhi-family_625x300_22_December_24.jpeg" alt="Pics: Rahul Gandhi's Family Lunch At Iconic Delhi Restaurant" /><figcaption>Rahul Gandhi and family at a Delhi restaurant</figcaption><p>After months of intensive election campaigns, the Gandhi family took a break to enjoy quality time together at the iconic Kwality restaurant in Delhi.</p><ul><li>Rahul, Priyanka, and family enjoyed popular dishes like chole-bhature.</li><li>They were joined by family members including Sonia Gandhi and Robert Vadra.</li><li>Photos of the lunch were shared on WhatsApp by Rahul, receiving a warm response on social media.</li><li>The gathering showcased three influential members of the Gandhi family, represented in one snapshot.</li></ul><blockquote>“Family lunch at the iconic Kwality Restaurant. Try the Chole Bhature if you go.” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote><p>This gathering highlights the importance of family time amidst busy political schedules and continues the legacy of a beloved restaurant known for its historic patronage.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhis-family-lunch-at-iconic-delhi-restaurant-7308649</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rahul-gandhis-family-lunch-at-iconic-delhi-restaurant-7308649</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:13:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three coastal Tamil Nadu districts brace for heavy rain on December 24 and 25 - DTNEXT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOQmQtTVI1anFDUjdmVm02OHBRSnE0S1NlRS1uWTJjbTB5RmhXam5KS0libEd1RUdmM3JZSmIzamIwMy1mUkk1ZGZIaWpiRHRZR0JJYUs4amhqOTc1NzA0Q3E1NFczS0NodUpuckZsTXcwUWFDcGlUMGZJWjVYX1gwVGpEZ3pKSTlGUHY0a296S001S2tNUzZVeVg1aWxfZW1XeHJKUGtsdl80NmlFYzhKWmVPUdIBuAFBVV95cUxPY0h5MGpaQ1NQdzJtVkJ1RHMxdWhOVkt1TWFVV2kya21QeUppS3lEb0NyR3plNk1iOEdOeUljaVRjTTNwdC1rWlVjT0NIRndVTXdpQ2JpOXpMTmxfZ1loaS0tbzBKZEl3a3RXMERwMXRfc1paaEtuVVRLM2RkaVlFWkxlVkszOXVUcTFVT1U3RGVtd1F4cnctX1p0Qkt0OVU3Y2JLNC1SUUFEMllkMFRYOFFuY1AzNlF5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOQmQtTVI1anFDUjdmVm02OHBRSnE0S1NlRS1uWTJjbTB5RmhXam5KS0libEd1RUdmM3JZSmIzamIwMy1mUkk1ZGZIaWpiRHRZR0JJYUs4amhqOTc1NzA0Q3E1NFczS0NodUpuckZsTXcwUWFDcGlUMGZJWjVYX1gwVGpEZ3pKSTlGUHY0a296S001S2tNUzZVeVg1aWxfZW1XeHJKUGtsdl80NmlFYzhKWmVPUdIBuAFBVV95cUxPY0h5MGpaQ1NQdzJtVkJ1RHMxdWhOVkt1TWFVV2kya21QeUppS3lEb0NyR3plNk1iOEdOeUljaVRjTTNwdC1rWlVjT0NIRndVTXdpQ2JpOXpMTmxfZ1loaS0tbzBKZEl3a3RXMERwMXRfc1paaEtuVVRLM2RkaVlFWkxlVkszOXVUcTFVT1U3RGVtd1F4cnctX1p0Qkt0OVU3Y2JLNC1SUUFEMllkMFRYOFFuY1AzNlF5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:13:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>