<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:25:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:25:36 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bihar Civil Court Clerk Answer Key 2024 Out, Direct Link To PDF - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid0FVX3lxTE1WaFh0d3NUOGFSam1fQ19WRkJyVi1zMFVJcXJiN0RWQ3FESXNyU1NKMVU1bGFaV0NjUUFRUGxqVUZZX2M1cFNsQ1lPc1lsSnQxb0VhbnRZTFlITWNTNU5vTWxFVXVqYmhqVjhkaGJsclB6Z3E5ejBJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid0FVX3lxTE1WaFh0d3NUOGFSam1fQ19WRkJyVi1zMFVJcXJiN0RWQ3FESXNyU1NKMVU1bGFaV0NjUUFRUGxqVUZZX2M1cFNsQ1lPc1lsSnQxb0VhbnRZTFlITWNTNU5vTWxFVXVqYmhqVjhkaGJsclB6Z3E5ejBJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 05:37:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explained: Centre scraps ‘no-detention policy’. Will Classes 5, 8 students fail now? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Scraps No-Detention Policy for Classes 5 and 8: What This Means for Students</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/no_detention_policy_1735016417039_1735016417555.jpg" alt="Severeal states and UTs have already scrapped the no-detention policy.(HT_PRINT/File image)" title="Severeal states and UTs have already scrapped the no-detention policy.(HT_PRINT/File image)">
<figcaption>Severeal states and UTs have already scrapped the no-detention policy.(HT_PRINT/File image)</figcaption>
<p>The Centre has ended the no-detention policy for students in Classes 5 and 8, meaning students who fail their year-end exams will no longer be automatically promoted. The policy revision allows for re-examination opportunities for those who do not meet promotion criteria.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The no-detention policy has been scrapped as part of the amendments to the Right to Education Act.</li>
  <li>18 states and Union Territories previously discontinued the no-detention policy.</li>
  <li>Students failing their exams will receive additional instruction and a chance for re-examination within two months.</li>
  <li>Teachers will assist students in identifying learning gaps during the holding period.</li>
  <li>No student can be expelled from school before completing elementary education.</li>
  <li>This change affects over 3,000 schools run by the central government, including Kendriya Vidyalayas.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"If the child appearing in the re-examination fails to fulfil the promotion criteria again, he shall be held back in fifth class or eighth class, as the case may be."</blockquote>
<p>This significant educational policy shift focuses on improving student performance and understanding rather than rote memorization.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/explained-centre-scraps-no-detention-policy-will-classes-5-8-students-fail-now-101735013777843.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/explained-centre-scraps-no-detention-policy-will-classes-5-8-students-fail-now-101735013777843.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 05:14:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Invited To Birthday, UP Boy Stripped, Beaten, Urinated Upon, Dies By Suicide - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/cities/invited-to-birthday-up-boy-stripped-beaten-urinated-upon-dies-by-suicide-7319243</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/cities/invited-to-birthday-up-boy-stripped-beaten-urinated-upon-dies-by-suicide-7319243</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 05:00:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Cheap Trolls": Manish Sisodia vs Manoj Tiwari Over Arvind Kejriwal Video - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6wFBVV95cUxNdTVxWUlMNktRalcxcl94S1g2ZFpxX3JabGpvZDBSZnF2cXYycUEzOVplbFJHMXlWd1NhUUR3aE5QZU0tbjFNT2RmSk1pSXAzSGw2RlAzYmE2VnhiaU44NVZmTjFUR2FJUGFPLWJHejJpdjg3OGFNZHNMV0xaMzZ5R0RVRWFhR3FuT1l6YlM1U092QnhzN3MyQXlCWlpJc2h1M0J3WU5MTTNGUFpmcjJ5NkU3Q2tsMTVyZW1tR2UzaHFEbDVSbHZrdXJFSFFGWmE4bDloZ0VsWmpManNpT0pvS3AwMDNGYm1hdS1n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6wFBVV95cUxNdTVxWUlMNktRalcxcl94S1g2ZFpxX3JabGpvZDBSZnF2cXYycUEzOVplbFJHMXlWd1NhUUR3aE5QZU0tbjFNT2RmSk1pSXAzSGw2RlAzYmE2VnhiaU44NVZmTjFUR2FJUGFPLWJHejJpdjg3OGFNZHNMV0xaMzZ5R0RVRWFhR3FuT1l6YlM1U092QnhzN3MyQXlCWlpJc2h1M0J3WU5MTTNGUFpmcjJ5NkU3Q2tsMTVyZW1tR2UzaHFEbDVSbHZrdXJFSFFGWmE4bDloZ0VsWmpManNpT0pvS3AwMDNGYm1hdS1n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:59:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[International drug smuggler Sunil Yadav gunned down in California by Lawrence Bishnoi's gang - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>International Drug Smuggler Sunil Yadav Gunned Down in California</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 16, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> News Agency</p><p>Sunil Yadav, a notorious drug smuggler, has been killed in California by members of Lawrence Bishnoi's gang. The incident highlights increasing violence associated with drug trafficking activities.</p><ul><li>Sunil Yadav was a prominent figure in the drug smuggling network.</li><li>Lawrence Bishnoi is known for orchestrating multiple violent acts against rival gangs.</li><li>The shooting occurred in a public area, raising safety concerns.</li><li>This event reflects the ongoing issue of gang violence related to drug trafficking in the U.S.</li></ul><blockquote>“This incident marks a significant escalation in the ongoing gang wars.” - Local Law Enforcement</blockquote><p>The killing of Sunil Yadav serves as a stark reminder of the dangers posed by organized crime involved in the drug trade.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/international-drug-smuggler-sunil-yadav-gunned-down-in-california-by-lawrence-bishnois-gang/articleshow/116616680.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/delhi/international-drug-smuggler-sunil-yadav-gunned-down-in-california-by-lawrence-bishnois-gang/articleshow/116616680.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Selection Process Flawed": Congress On Appointment Of Rights Panel Chief - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Critiques Flawed Selection Process for NHRC Chairperson</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/evtgdo08_rahul-gandhi-mallikarjun-kharge-ani-_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg" alt="Selection Process Flawed: Congress On Appointment Of Rights Panel Chief" title="Selection Process Flawed: Congress On Appointment Of Rights Panel Chief"><figcaption>Congress leaders Rahul Gandhi and Mallikarjun Kharge express dissent over NHRC chairperson appointment.</figcaption><p>The Congress party has raised concerns over the appointment of Justice V Ramasubramanian as the chairperson of the NHRC, labeling the selection process as fundamentally flawed.</p><ul><li>President Droupadi Murmu appointed Justice V Ramasubramanian as NHRC chairperson.</li><li>Congress leaders Rahul Gandhi and Mallikarjun Kharge issued a dissent note regarding the selection process.</li><li>They criticized the process as a pre-determined exercise lacking mutual consultation and consensus.</li><li>The dissent highlighted the NHRC's role in safeguarding human rights, particularly for marginalized communities.</li><li>Congress proposed alternative candidates, emphasizing the need for inclusivity and diversity in leadership.</li><li>Concerns were raised over the impact of leadership representation on the NHRC's effectiveness.</li></ul><blockquote>“The NHRC's credibility and effectiveness depend on its ability to embody the diversity and inclusiveness that define India's constitutional ethos.”</blockquote><p>This critique underscores the importance of a fair and inclusive selection process in ensuring the NHRC's mandate to protect human rights is upheld.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/process-wasnt-followed-congress-letter-of-dissent-over-rights-panel-chief-appointment-7319378</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/process-wasnt-followed-congress-letter-of-dissent-over-rights-panel-chief-appointment-7319378</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:05:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pre-determined exercise': Kharge, Rahul's dissent at NHRC selection panel meet - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kharge and Rahul Gandhi Express Dissent at NHRC Selection Process</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><p>This article discusses the dissent expressed by Opposition leaders Mallikarjun Kharge and Rahul Gandhi regarding the selection process of the new chairperson and members of the National Human Rights Commission (NHRC), which they claim was fundamentally flawed.</p><ul><li>Kharge and Gandhi recorded their dissent over the NHRC selection, labeling it as a "pre-determined" exercise.</li><li>They proposed Justice Rohinton Fali Nariman and Justice Kuttiyil Mathew Joseph for chairperson, but V. Ramasubramanian was appointed instead.</li><li>The NHRC chairperson position had been vacant since June 1.</li><li>The dissent highlights a departure from mutual consultation critical for fairness and credibility.</li><li>They emphasized the necessity of diversity in NHRC leadership to safeguard human rights effectively.</li><li>The NHRC is crucial for protecting the rights of marginalized and oppressed groups in society.</li></ul><blockquote>"A diverse leadership ensures that the NHRC remains sensitive to the unique challenges faced by various communities."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Kharge and Gandhi's dissent underscores the importance of an inclusive and fair selection process for the NHRC leadership to maintain public trust.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/pre-determined-exercise-kharge-rahuls-dissent-at-nhrc-selection-panel-meet/article69021472.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/pre-determined-exercise-kharge-rahuls-dissent-at-nhrc-selection-panel-meet/article69021472.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Second-Hand Cars No Longer Affordable? Here's How An 18% GST Will Impact Pre-Owned Car Market - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/business-economy/economy/second-hand-cars-no-longer-affordable-heres-how-an-18-gst-will-impact-pre-owned-car-market-article-116614987</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/business-economy/economy/second-hand-cars-no-longer-affordable-heres-how-an-18-gst-will-impact-pre-owned-car-market-article-116614987</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:41:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IIM Bangalore MBA Admission: Check eligibility, documents required and the selection process - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxNNWRjZ2dCWUVKc1RlenRncERaYnNNY1dnM0hQdGdzOTJvMUhOVUNzRTA2MTlySV9yRU5RT1ZDVVpsNzRWVVBKQ2tzTjJ0a3B6N3NEemVZX0VQaDBDNFk5aVBhaEJlZjBYNDltaEVWUW9UNUwxVmE4bFVkNDlQZE1LVVZsbk83WVpRbU9CNlFwcjN4NUx3Ukh2WDAwdmFNZE1XQWc5dTM4Rl9FbEFFYWg5WlA0QWxwdUVYa3RJVTdCVEoyYTdaXzBYZjhSZzFnZ2E2V1p0UzNSVDBFb3BBY19fLWpZdVFDbzVhWm90NTQzc1ByZzRoTEHSAfsBQVVfeXFMTnBNOWJITU1HcnpjazE2aHhkRGNUVWFZci1wYk14amVVbFpHTEV5dzFKWkpDVXhuS0t2VWROUzdhV3BRTk9MSXVLUWsxSU83TXRnMGIyRng5a0E3OHAydFhkM2Rta21oNGRGXzRuVzYzYV82YUJMRFBjWTVMVHBiV0hzbU9mOHRJUzU4SFBnTUlURll1cEszUExFODBOSlhsRl9ZNncyNHZpaGJuZTVHd1NQNWVkcnd1QTBTNU5zNGVHRllmNXNqcjhkWFIzZUc5azNpZ1EzWGxjb3RNVjllb0V1d3E5aFhGNmlfbVhiRjRpd0N3U2F3WEd5WFk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxNNWRjZ2dCWUVKc1RlenRncERaYnNNY1dnM0hQdGdzOTJvMUhOVUNzRTA2MTlySV9yRU5RT1ZDVVpsNzRWVVBKQ2tzTjJ0a3B6N3NEemVZX0VQaDBDNFk5aVBhaEJlZjBYNDltaEVWUW9UNUwxVmE4bFVkNDlQZE1LVVZsbk83WVpRbU9CNlFwcjN4NUx3Ukh2WDAwdmFNZE1XQWc5dTM4Rl9FbEFFYWg5WlA0QWxwdUVYa3RJVTdCVEoyYTdaXzBYZjhSZzFnZ2E2V1p0UzNSVDBFb3BBY19fLWpZdVFDbzVhWm90NTQzc1ByZzRoTEHSAfsBQVVfeXFMTnBNOWJITU1HcnpjazE2aHhkRGNUVWFZci1wYk14amVVbFpHTEV5dzFKWkpDVXhuS0t2VWROUzdhV3BRTk9MSXVLUWsxSU83TXRnMGIyRng5a0E3OHAydFhkM2Rta21oNGRGXzRuVzYzYV82YUJMRFBjWTVMVHBiV0hzbU9mOHRJUzU4SFBnTUlURll1cEszUExFODBOSlhsRl9ZNncyNHZpaGJuZTVHd1NQNWVkcnd1QTBTNU5zNGVHRllmNXNqcjhkWFIzZUc5azNpZ1EzWGxjb3RNVjllb0V1d3E5aFhGNmlfbVhiRjRpd0N3U2F3WEd5WFk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun Shares FIRST Post Since His Home Was Vandalised, Pushpa 2 Star Says 'I Am...' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun Shares FIRST Post Since His Home Was Vandalised</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2024/12/fotojet-2024-12-13t143139.840-2024-12-295dc1481c56adb28d596464964fc835.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Allu Arjun was arrested in connection with the stampede during Pushpa 2 premiere." title="Allu Arjun was arrested in connection with the stampede during Pushpa 2 premiere." loading="eager"><figcaption>Allu Arjun was arrested in connection with the stampede during Pushpa 2 premiere.</figcaption></figure><p>Allu Arjun shared his first social media post after his house was vandalised. The actor, involved in legal troubles since the release of his film Pushpa 2, faced a protest where a woman died in a stampede during the premiere.</p><ul><li>Allu Arjun's house was vandalised by protesters demanding justice for the woman who died in the stampede.</li><li>Allu Arjun was arrested related to the stampede incident but has not publicly commented on the vandalism.</li><li>He expressed gratitude to Yash Raj Films for supporting Pushpa 2, which broke several box office records.</li><li>His father, Allu Aravind, condemned the vandalism and stated the importance of restraint in their reaction.</li></ul><blockquote>“Thank you … so graceful. Humbled by your wishes. Thank you, I am touched. May this record soon be broken by a heart-melting #YRF film, and may we all collectively move towards excellence.” — Allu Arjun (@alluarjun) December 23, 2024</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Allu Arjun's situation highlights the controversies surrounding the release of Pushpa 2 and the emotional reactions from the public, alongside legal issues impacting his personal life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjun-shares-first-post-since-his-home-was-vandalised-pushpa-2-star-says-i-am-9166307.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/allu-arjun-shares-first-post-since-his-home-was-vandalised-pushpa-2-star-says-i-am-9166307.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:45:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Over 1,000 Vehicles Stuck Amid Heavy Snowfall In Himachal's Manali - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Over 1,000 Vehicles Stuck Amid Heavy Snowfall In Himachal's Manali</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/bd6b7e68_manali-traffic_625x300_24_December_24.jpeg" alt="Over 1,000 Vehicles Stuck Amid Heavy Snowfall In Himachal's Manali"><figcaption>Heavy snowfall has caused significant traffic disruptions in Manali.</figcaption><p>A recent snowfall in Manali, Himachal Pradesh, has resulted in over 1,000 vehicles getting stuck between Solang and the Atal Tunnel, leading to a rescue operation by police for stranded tourists.</p><ul><li>Around 1,000 vehicles are immobilized due to heavy snowfall.</li><li>Police have started rescue operations, shifting approximately 700 tourists to safety.</li><li>The influx of tourists for Christmas and New Year celebrations has exacerbated the situation.</li><li>Local businesses in the tourism sector are optimistic about an extended season due to the snowfall.</li></ul><blockquote>“The snowfall is such a beautiful sight. The weather is amazing. We didn't expect this at all…” - Hemant, a visitor from Rewari, Haryana.</blockquote><p>The unexpected snowfall has brought joy to tourists and locals alike, reviving the tourism industry struggling since the pandemic.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/over-1-000-vehicles-stuck-amid-heavy-snowfall-in-himachals-manali-7318801</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/over-1-000-vehicles-stuck-amid-heavy-snowfall-in-himachals-manali-7318801</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:36:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress moves to douse Pushpa fire, says CM Revanth Reddy not against film industry or Allu Arjun - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Moves to Address Pushpa Controversy, CM Revanth Reddy Clarifies Stance on Film Industry</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>The article discusses the recent statements made by CM Revanth Reddy regarding the controversy surrounding the film 'Pushpa'. Reddy emphasizes that he is not against the film industry or actor Allu Arjun amid rising concerns.</p><ul><li>CM Reddy addresses the reactions surrounding the film 'Pushpa'.</li><li>Cautions against misunderstanding his comments related to the film industry.</li><li>Highlights the importance of the film industry in the region.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am not against any individual or the film industry,” said CM Reddy.</blockquote><p>The article concludes by highlighting the positive role of films in the culture and economy of the region, and the need for constructive dialogue within the industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/hyderabad/congress-moves-to-douse-pushpa-fire-says-telangana-cm-revanth-reddy-not-against-telugu-film-industry/articleshow/116613843.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/hyderabad/congress-moves-to-douse-pushpa-fire-says-telangana-cm-revanth-reddy-not-against-telugu-film-industry/articleshow/116613843.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hospitals cannot refuse free medical treatment to rape, acid attack victims: Delhi High Court - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi High Court Mandates Free Medical Treatment for Rape and Acid Attack Victims</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> December 24, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/t52f9p/article69021352.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/IMG_INDEX_DELHI_HIGH_COU_2_1_OUDHSU0R.jpg" alt="Delhi High Court ruling image"><figcaption>The Delhi High Court said not providing such victims/survivors with required medical treatment is a criminal offence.</figcaption><p>The Delhi High Court has ruled that all hospitals must provide free medical treatment to survivors of sexual violence and acid attacks, emphasizing that refusal to do so is a criminal offense.</p><ul><li>Survivors must receive necessary medical treatment including first aid and diagnostic tests.</li><li>Complaints will be registered against medical professionals refusing treatment under Section 200 of BNS, 2023.</li><li>The court ordered awareness and compliance from all healthcare facilities regarding these rules.</li><li>A board stating that free treatment is available for such victims must be displayed in all medical facilities.</li><li>Those failing to comply could face up to one year in prison.</li></ul><blockquote>“Free out-patient and in-patient medical treatment is available for victims/ survivors of sexual assault, rape, gang rape, acid attacks, etc.”</blockquote><p>This directive highlights the ongoing challenges faced by survivors in accessing medical care and the court's commitment to ensuring their rights are protected.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/hospitals-cannot-refuse-free-medical-treatment-to-rape-acid-attack-victims-delhi-high-court/article69018454.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/hospitals-cannot-refuse-free-medical-treatment-to-rape-acid-attack-victims-delhi-high-court/article69018454.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Himachal Pradesh: Over 1,000 vehicles stuck in Solang-Rohtang after heavy snowfall in Manali, 700 tourists rescued - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Heavy Snowfall Causes Traffic Chaos in Manali, 700 Tourists Rescued</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/PTI12-09-2024-000087A-0_1734999663209_1734999685990.jpg" alt="A biker falls on a slippery road after fresh snowfall in Shimla, Himachal Pradesh,(PTI)"><figcaption>A biker falls on a slippery road after fresh snowfall in Shimla, Himachal Pradesh,(PTI)</figcaption><p>A fresh spell of heavy snowfall in Manali has trapped around 1,000 vehicles, with police coordinating efforts to rescue approximately 700 stranded tourists.</p><ul><li>Around 1,000 vehicles stuck between Solang and Atal Tunnel due to heavy snowfall.</li><li>Rescue operations successfully assisted 700 tourists to safe locations.</li><li>The influx of tourists for the holiday season contributed to the chaos.</li><li>In contrast, Shimla enjoys a festive atmosphere with tourism thriving from the snowfall.</li><li>Local businesses optimistic about a boost in tourism due to extended stays of visitors.</li></ul><blockquote>“The snowfall is such a beautiful sight. The weather is amazing. We didn't expect this at all… it’s a once-in-a-lifetime experience,” said a tourist from Haryana.</blockquote><p>This heavy snowfall has created both challenges and opportunities in Himachal Pradesh, affecting travel while also providing a much-needed boost to the tourism industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/himachal-pradesh-over-1-000-vehicles-stuck-in-solang-rohtang-after-heavy-snowfall-in-manali-700-tourists-rescued-101734999195491.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/himachal-pradesh-over-1-000-vehicles-stuck-in-solang-rohtang-after-heavy-snowfall-in-manali-700-tourists-rescued-101734999195491.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:54:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Congress Should Be Ready...': Mani Shankar Aiyar's Big Remark On INDIA Bloc Leadership - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Congress Should Be Ready...': Mani Shankar Aiyar's Big Remark On INDIA Bloc Leadership</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Congress leader Mani Shankar Aiyar | File Image"><figcaption>Congress leader Mani Shankar Aiyar | File Image</figcaption></figure><p>Former Union Minister Mani Shankar Aiyar stated that the Congress party should be prepared to relinquish its leading position in the opposition's INDIA bloc and suggested backing Mamata Banerjee for the role, citing her competence.</p><ul><li>Aiyar emphasized the need for Congress to consider alternatives for leadership within the bloc.</li><li>He acknowledged that Rahul Gandhi would still command respect, irrespective of holding the leadership position.</li><li>The INDIA bloc has faced challenges following previously successful elections, highlighting the shifting dynamics within the alliance.</li><li>Many opposition leaders are rallying behind Banerjee for leadership due to recent electoral setbacks.</li></ul><blockquote>“I don’t think it’s a relevant question. I think the Congress should be ready to not be the leader of the bloc. Let whoever wants to be the leader be the leader.” - Mani Shankar Aiyar</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Aiyar's remarks signal a potential shift in leadership dynamics within the opposition alliance as they prepare for future electoral challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/politics/mani-shankar-aiyar-on-congress-india-bloc-leadership-rahul-gandhi-9165649.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/politics/mani-shankar-aiyar-on-congress-india-bloc-leadership-rahul-gandhi-9165649.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 23:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fire breaks out at singer Shaan's residential building in Mumbai - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fire breaks out at singer Shaan's residential building in Mumbai</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 5, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Fire incident at Shaan's residence"><figcaption>A depiction of the fire incident at singer Shaan's residential building.</figcaption><p>A fire broke out at the residential building of popular singer Shaan in Mumbai, causing chaos and worry among residents. The fire rapidly spread, prompting quick action from local fire departments.</p><ul><li>The fire erupted in the evening, with flames visible from several floors.</li><li>Emergency services responded promptly to the scene, working to contain the blaze.</li><li>Residents were evacuated safely, and there are no reported injuries at this time.</li></ul><blockquote>"I heard alarms and saw smoke spreading quickly. We didn't waste any time and got out immediately." - A resident of the building.</blockquote><p>The incident underscores the importance of fire safety measures in residential buildings, as swift action helped avoid potential harm to residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/fire-breaks-out-at-singer-shaans-residential-building-in-mumbai/articleshow/116612668.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/fire-breaks-out-at-singer-shaans-residential-building-in-mumbai/articleshow/116612668.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 23:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat’s mandir-masjid take draws major dissent from seers - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat’s mandir-masjid take draws major dissent from seers</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="RSS Chief Mohan Bhagwat" /><figcaption>RSS Chief Mohan Bhagwat during a public address.</figcaption><p>The recent comments by RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat regarding temples and mosques have led to significant backlash from various religious leaders and seers. His statements were perceived as divisive and sparked discussions around communal harmony.</p><ul><li>Bhagwat suggested that both temples and mosques should coexist peacefully.</li><li>His statements were met with criticism from several religious figures who argue it undermines historical grievances.</li><li>The controversy highlights ongoing tensions surrounding religious sites and communal relations in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“Unity in diversity is the strength of our nation, and we must respect each other's places of worship.” – Remark from a responding seer.</blockquote><p>The unfolding reactions to Bhagwat’s comments indicate a need for more dialogue and understanding among different religious communities in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/rss-chief-mohan-bhagwats-mandir-masjid-take-draws-major-dissent-from-seers/articleshow/116610356.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/rss-chief-mohan-bhagwats-mandir-masjid-take-draws-major-dissent-from-seers/articleshow/116610356.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 21:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Fraud With Country': Delhi HC Denies Puja Khedkar's Pre-Arrest Bail In UPSC Case - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi HC Denies Pre-Arrest Bail to Puja Khedkar in UPSC Case</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Puja Khedkar (File Photo)" title="Puja Khedkar (File Photo)"><figcaption>Puja Khedkar (FIle Photo)</figcaption></figure><p>The Delhi High Court has denied anticipatory bail to Puja Khedkar, a former IAS officer, accused of misrepresenting facts in her UPSC application.</p><ul><li>The court vacated the interim protection from arrest granted to Khedkar.</li><li>Justice Chandra Dhari Singh stated a strong case is made out against her.</li><li>Khedkar was noted to be unfit to avail benefits reserved for disadvantaged groups.</li><li>The court described her actions as part of a larger conspiracy to manipulate the system.</li><li>UPSC had previously cancelled her candidature and issued a lifetime ban from future examinations.</li></ul><blockquote>Khedkar claimed she would cooperate in the investigation, asserting that her custody was unnecessary as all evidence is documentary.</blockquote><p>The court's ruling emphasizes the seriousness of the case, which impacts the integrity of one of the world's most prestigious examinations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/large-conspiracy-delhi-high-court-denies-anticipatory-bail-to-puja-khedkar-9165626.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/large-conspiracy-delhi-high-court-denies-anticipatory-bail-to-puja-khedkar-9165626.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 21:03:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh writes diplomatic note to India seeking return of Sheikh Hasina - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh Demands Sheikh Hasina's Extradition from India for 'Judicial Process'</h1><p><strong>Date & Source: January 13, 2023, from The Indian Express</strong></p><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Sheikh Hasina' width='200' height='200'><figcaption>Former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina</figcaption><p>Bangladesh has officially requested India to send back former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina to face trial for 'crimes against humanity and genocide'. The International Crimes Tribunal in Dhaka has issued arrest warrants for Hasina and several of her associates. The Indian Ministry of External Affairs has confirmed receiving the extradition request.</p><ol><li>Bangladesh's interim government has sent a diplomatic note to India for Hasina's extradition.</li><li>The India-Bangladesh extradition treaty allows provisions for refusing requests based on certain grounds.</li><li>Hasina's presence and statements in India have strained bilateral ties with Bangladesh.</li></ol><blockquote>“We have sent a note verbale to the Indian government saying that Bangladesh wants her back here for the judicial process.” - Touhid Hossain, Foreign Affairs Advisor, Bangladesh</blockquote><p>Conclusion: The extradition request could impact India-Bangladesh relations and will require delicate diplomacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-writes-diplomatic-note-to-india-seeking-return-of-sheikh-hasina-9740649/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-writes-diplomatic-note-to-india-seeking-return-of-sheikh-hasina-9740649/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 20:40:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru Accident: Volvo XC90 Worth More Than 1 Cr Crushed by Truck, Claimed 6 Lives on Spot - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/auto/bengaluru-accident-volvo-xc90-worth-more-than-1-cr-crushed-by-truck-claimed-6-lives-on-spot-9165396.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/auto/bengaluru-accident-volvo-xc90-worth-more-than-1-cr-crushed-by-truck-claimed-6-lives-on-spot-9165396.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:22:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yogi Adityanath impresses delegation with nearly 2-minute opening remark in Japanese | Video - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yogi Adityanath Delivers Opening Remarks in Japanese, Signs MoU with Yamanashi Prefecture</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source: </strong>HT News</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/GfgDTI7WAAAN_y6_1734980500026_1734980510382.jpg" alt="UP CM Yogi Adityanath and Kotaro Nagasaki, Governor of Japan's Yamanashi Prefecture, during a meeting in Lucknow on Monday.(yogiadityanath/X)"><figcaption>UP CM Yogi Adityanath and Kotaro Nagasaki, Governor of Japan's Yamanashi Prefecture, during a meeting in Lucknow on Monday.(yogiadityanath/X)</figcaption><p>Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath impressed a Japanese delegation with his nearly two-minute opening remarks given in Japanese, which received wide applause.</p><ul><li>Yogi Adityanath welcomed Kotaro Nagasaki, Governor of Yamanashi Prefecture, and highlighted the cultural ties between India and Japan.</li><li>An MoU was signed to promote industrial development, tourism, and vocational education collaboration between Uttar Pradesh and Yamanashi.</li><li>Adityanath expressed hope for economic and cultural exchanges and emphasized the shared values strengthening India-Japan ties.</li></ul><blockquote>“Had a productive meeting and fruitful discussion with Mr. Kotaro Nagasaki... Looking forward to exploring new opportunities for economic and cultural exchange together,” said Yogi Adityanath.</blockquote><p>This meeting represents a significant step towards enhancing bilateral relations and collaboration between India and Japan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/yogi-adityanath-impresses-delegation-with-nearly-2-minute-statement-in-japanese-watch-101734978512308.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/yogi-adityanath-impresses-delegation-with-nearly-2-minute-statement-in-japanese-watch-101734978512308.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:04:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Khalistan Zindabad Force chief hails from J&K, is now in Pakistan - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Khalistan Zindabad Force Chief Connected to Jammu & Kashmir, Currently Residing in Pakistan</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Khalistan Zindabad Force Chief" /><figcaption>Khalistan Zindabad Force Chief</figcaption><p>This article discusses the connections of the Khalistan Zindabad Force chief to Jammu & Kashmir, highlighting his current status in Pakistan.</p><ul><li>The chief has links to several militant activities.</li><li>There are concerns regarding cross-border terrorism.</li><li>Authorities are monitoring the situation closely.</li></ul><blockquote>“The connections of such leaders can lead to significant security challenges.”</blockquote><p>This situation demands attention from security forces and policymakers due to the potential risks involved.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/khalistan-zindabad-force-chief-hails-from-jk-is-now-in-pakistan/articleshow/116609434.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/khalistan-zindabad-force-chief-hails-from-jk-is-now-in-pakistan/articleshow/116609434.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manipur's Naga Groups Allege "Kuki Volunteers" Assaulted Students' Body Members - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxPT1BEbnVmbDhmS0M5Mm5URGtvT1JocmcxcUtPU1dtejUtc092OVZJeVNwSXZtYkZUeVJ1T2s5T3hyb1dET2Z2czhWVVBBUURWc1pDTmZrSktUaDBwWURYZThNekUxczdoWURwNzF5V3JPOTJvVm82ODRuZzdRQU9ha295ckNTdUUzT1dKRG4wSzZPODFxVlV5ZjgwRm45ZWc5RlFPVXdtZjZUNHlpSENRY1JPcWN0UdIBvgFBVV95cUxPeExMNkR4STJ6TjB4QVNpaGN1MXNnb2ljWDVzYmFpX2lBckZUV3ZldHFaLUJPd0hicmZyVXFwTzhFTV9jMHZfTVUwQWxFM0pnOFN1WDVRNTZSamFwQjY3OTVMQmdwRFY0YnJ4WVhwTlJkM3FCUnc2Y0N1UUx0SGp3Q0otQ2RBZEtjQlFEWXcyYkRKZFBuYk5Lc2J0MkYwVkNpVEJYRE5rQTVQNTA2VGp4TVlPVklkRFdiTngyRnl3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxPT1BEbnVmbDhmS0M5Mm5URGtvT1JocmcxcUtPU1dtejUtc092OVZJeVNwSXZtYkZUeVJ1T2s5T3hyb1dET2Z2czhWVVBBUURWc1pDTmZrSktUaDBwWURYZThNekUxczdoWURwNzF5V3JPOTJvVm82ODRuZzdRQU9ha295ckNTdUUzT1dKRG4wSzZPODFxVlV5ZjgwRm45ZWc5RlFPVXdtZjZUNHlpSENRY1JPcWN0UdIBvgFBVV95cUxPeExMNkR4STJ6TjB4QVNpaGN1MXNnb2ljWDVzYmFpX2lBckZUV3ZldHFaLUJPd0hicmZyVXFwTzhFTV9jMHZfTVUwQWxFM0pnOFN1WDVRNTZSamFwQjY3OTVMQmdwRFY0YnJ4WVhwTlJkM3FCUnc2Y0N1UUx0SGp3Q0otQ2RBZEtjQlFEWXcyYkRKZFBuYk5Lc2J0MkYwVkNpVEJYRE5rQTVQNTA2VGp4TVlPVklkRFdiTngyRnl3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:42:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress Leader Files Complaint Against Allu Arjun Over Scene In 'Pushpa 2' - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxNWmlvNUZMM3JBeGg3ZUpxOHBxOEFVdUMyQTFOVnVnblU0OS1xSmFPVXB0cm90dEtrSEhDQ2RRVl9CSGNHUU9zVDFxX3ZZX0tJWnNXaHJNaWtSM2tuOGl1X21VZHlfbTV5cEpDSXdOM3dwNG1hb0hpWk92RW5EdkpVd0hRdnI3Wk40SmRhVG1yVkVPcjY4NFEtd2lsMHBlMU5hMjFGYUFvekxfVlVIcm0wcE1MM3JDS3BhdGxpYV8wM015UTDSAcsBQVVfeXFMT1ZTb1dDblZReDZ4LVVPOHFFZFFNMnNTb1dUczZ1WjZ5OU12enoySVBaaWZQSlEzNGQzRFdYeVBnRm1MUXplNk1STlF6RUt5ZVl3QXJqOFVaMWFhTzk0QkNSWlNzN3AxNWh4RF9VMUZudEhmUTVIMGtIaVRKbnk5cUY2OHRYSjJhUFpUd2kwbXhpeHBXOW93UjRUSEhPRXYtVVJvaUpZZjd5bUg1MEd4bWtCNHZOZUo4WDZ5WTZvdkNnVDB5VzRLUXJ3YVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxNWmlvNUZMM3JBeGg3ZUpxOHBxOEFVdUMyQTFOVnVnblU0OS1xSmFPVXB0cm90dEtrSEhDQ2RRVl9CSGNHUU9zVDFxX3ZZX0tJWnNXaHJNaWtSM2tuOGl1X21VZHlfbTV5cEpDSXdOM3dwNG1hb0hpWk92RW5EdkpVd0hRdnI3Wk40SmRhVG1yVkVPcjY4NFEtd2lsMHBlMU5hMjFGYUFvekxfVlVIcm0wcE1MM3JDS3BhdGxpYV8wM015UTDSAcsBQVVfeXFMT1ZTb1dDblZReDZ4LVVPOHFFZFFNMnNTb1dUczZ1WjZ5OU12enoySVBaaWZQSlEzNGQzRFdYeVBnRm1MUXplNk1STlF6RUt5ZVl3QXJqOFVaMWFhTzk0QkNSWlNzN3AxNWh4RF9VMUZudEhmUTVIMGtIaVRKbnk5cUY2OHRYSjJhUFpUd2kwbXhpeHBXOW93UjRUSEhPRXYtVVJvaUpZZjd5bUg1MEd4bWtCNHZOZUo4WDZ5WTZvdkNnVDB5VzRLUXJ3YVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:40:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chennai Weather Update: Heavy Rainfall Expected Across Tamil Nadu For Next Two Days - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chennai Weather Update: Heavy Rainfall Expected Across Tamil Nadu For Next Two Days</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Chennai and its suburbs can expect partly cloudy skies with the possibility of moderate rain in some areas. (Representative/PTI File)" title="Chennai and its suburbs can expect partly cloudy skies with the possibility of moderate rain in some areas. (Representative/PTI File)"><figcaption>Chennai and its suburbs can expect partly cloudy skies with the possibility of moderate rain in some areas. (Representative/PTI File)</figcaption></figure><p>The Chennai Meteorological Department has issued a heavy rain warning for Chengalpattu, Villupuram, and Cuddalore districts. A deep depression in the Bay of Bengal is moving toward the coasts of North Tamil Nadu and South Andhra Pradesh, bringing moderate rain to various regions.</p><ul><li>Heavy rain is forecast for Chengalpattu, Villupuram, and Cuddalore districts over the next two days.</li><li>Chennai expected to have partly cloudy skies with possible moderate rain.</li><li>Fishermen advised against venturing into the sea due to cyclonic storms.</li></ul><blockquote>“Heavy rain is likely in Chennai for 2 days; cyclonic storms may persist in coastal areas until December 25.”</blockquote><p>Residents are advised to stay alert and follow weather updates as conditions develop.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/chennai-weather-update-heavy-rainfall-expected-across-tamil-nadu-for-next-two-days-ws-ab-9165250.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/chennai-weather-update-heavy-rainfall-expected-across-tamil-nadu-for-next-two-days-ws-ab-9165250.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:11:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hit by airbag after accident, 6-year-old in car’s front seat dies - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hit by airbag after accident, 6-year-old in car’s front seat dies</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Missing] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Missing]</p><p>This heartbreaking incident involves a 6-year-old who tragically died after being struck by an airbag during a car accident while sitting in the front seat.</p><ul><li>The child was seated in the front seat of the vehicle.</li><li>The airbag deployment was a key factor in the fatality.</li><li>The incident highlights the importance of child safety regulations in vehicles.</li></ul><blockquote>“This tragic event serves as a reminder of the need for proper child seating arrangements in vehicles.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, this incident underscores the need for increased awareness and stricter regulations regarding child passenger safety in vehicles to prevent such tragedies in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/mumbai/hit-by-airbag-after-accident-boy-6-in-cars-front-seat-dies/articleshow/116608424.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/mumbai/hit-by-airbag-after-accident-boy-6-in-cars-front-seat-dies/articleshow/116608424.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun summoned to appear for questioning at Chikkadpally police station - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun Summoned for Questioning Over Pushpa 2 Premiere Incident</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/telangana/diqghh/article69020525.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241221328L.jpg" alt="File photo of Telugu film star Allu Arjun." /><figcaption>File photo of Telugu film star Allu Arjun. | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The Chikkadpally police have issued a notice to actor Allu Arjun, requesting his presence for questioning in connection with the stampede at Sandhya Theatre during the <i>Pushpa 2</i> premiere on December 4, which resulted in the death of a woman.</p><ul><li>Allu Arjun is named Accused No. 11 in the case.</li><li>The questioning is scheduled for 11 a.m. on December 24, 2024.</li><li>He previously spent a night in Chanchalguda Jail after being arrested by the police.</li></ul><blockquote>“The stampede at Sandhya Theatre resulted in the death of a woman.”</blockquote><p>The situation surrounding the actor raises significant questions regarding safety measures at public events and accountability of organizers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/allu-arjun-summoned-to-appear-for-questioning-at-chikkadpally-police-station/article69020435.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/allu-arjun-summoned-to-appear-for-questioning-at-chikkadpally-police-station/article69020435.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ammonia spike: Delhi water supply crisis worsens, more plants impacted - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Water Supply Crisis Worsens Due to Ammonia Spike</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/The-Yamuna-is-polluted-due-to-over-permissible-lim_1734975402188_1734994569409.jpg" alt="The Yamuna is polluted due to over-permissible limit of ammonia. (Vipin Kumar/HT Photo)"><figcaption>The Yamuna is polluted due to over-permissible limit of ammonia. (Vipin Kumar/HT Photo)</figcaption><p>An ongoing water supply disruption in Delhi’s northern and central regions has worsened due to elevated ammonia levels in the Yamuna River, affecting several water treatment plants.</p><ul><li>The Delhi Jal Board reports ammonia levels at Wazirabad Barrage exceeding the treatable limit.</li><li>Water supply disruptions have been reported from five of the city’s nine treatment plants.</li><li>Residents in affected areas are facing low water pressure and contamination.</li><li>Political blame games are emerging between AAP and BJP regarding the cause of the ammonia spike.</li></ul><blockquote>“Due to regular receipt of high pollutants (ammonia more than 5ppm) in Yamuna... the situation is being constantly reviewed.” - DJB statement</blockquote><p>The situation highlights a critical water crisis that needs urgent attention and solutions to prevent further disruptions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/delhi-news/ammonia-spike-delhi-water-supply-crisis-worsens-more-plants-impacted-101734975405171.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/delhi-news/ammonia-spike-delhi-water-supply-crisis-worsens-more-plants-impacted-101734975405171.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:36:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India News Live Today December 23, 2024: Shiv temple reopens in Muzaffarnagar after 32 years since 1992 Ayodhya incident; Muslims shower flowers - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxNU29iVWJMTDdkM3dGdG15clJWcDFfUjB1V0R5TzlMdmYzTDYwT0NXWnNOT2FrVzVfa3B5eTdTZktrZmhvYUtoSTk2eEpkMFVteS1lN1ZjZWllM1BORmZBWlNKRE1lUmd6X0ktR3F4c1FCVFVrTXRwNTJIZzVZaXc3ZUdvd2lfVjRUQ3oyWS1IQWRCTDh6djgtX0hSbTNGQnhtaFRoVXVSaWZwLUEtWWpkbGpHb2JCNHhCLWcwaHdGSG5zQTUtTnY0VS13bmxEN0pkWFNDM0NQNmh0dkhf0gHiAUFVX3lxTE5yamtBUDJuckNhVnY3LVlQd0Jza3VReU5Cb1hNcmhmaU5kZmJtOWxldDAyN2dJNUdQUHA1OFhLYzlySDBmWEdmRU9qZ1ctS1RnR0VPOG52S0NMM0VJUHhncHFybm1ZRGtVa2E5UnE5aVBHWHhncVRfRHpOYjg1N1RNSExWdXZraGlmR2pQOEwtUjdLUktGZWVueW5TclRsc1J5eUhmV0Z1TlBQQ3YzNDl4OHJrYVhRMGdTSGRGN05SVWZEYmVtUUhRdHJja2szdFR6NzN2bEpqZngyMkFBa1pSX0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxNU29iVWJMTDdkM3dGdG15clJWcDFfUjB1V0R5TzlMdmYzTDYwT0NXWnNOT2FrVzVfa3B5eTdTZktrZmhvYUtoSTk2eEpkMFVteS1lN1ZjZWllM1BORmZBWlNKRE1lUmd6X0ktR3F4c1FCVFVrTXRwNTJIZzVZaXc3ZUdvd2lfVjRUQ3oyWS1IQWRCTDh6djgtX0hSbTNGQnhtaFRoVXVSaWZwLUEtWWpkbGpHb2JCNHhCLWcwaHdGSG5zQTUtTnY0VS13bmxEN0pkWFNDM0NQNmh0dkhf0gHiAUFVX3lxTE5yamtBUDJuckNhVnY3LVlQd0Jza3VReU5Cb1hNcmhmaU5kZmJtOWxldDAyN2dJNUdQUHA1OFhLYzlySDBmWEdmRU9qZ1ctS1RnR0VPOG52S0NMM0VJUHhncHFybm1ZRGtVa2E5UnE5aVBHWHhncVRfRHpOYjg1N1RNSExWdXZraGlmR2pQOEwtUjdLUktGZWVueW5TclRsc1J5eUhmV0Z1TlBQQ3YzNDl4OHJrYVhRMGdTSGRGN05SVWZEYmVtUUhRdHJja2szdFR6NzN2bEpqZngyMkFBa1pSX0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:35:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atul Subhash: A man's suicide leads to clamour around India's dowry law - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Atul Subhash: A man's suicide leads to clamour around India's dowry law</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 9, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> BBC News</p><figure><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/c4fe/live/233005c0-bee6-11ef-9880-bd78436cd924.jpg.webp" alt="BBC Atul Subhash with his parents and brother in happier times"><figcaption>Atul Subhash's suicide has galvanised men's rights activists and started a wider debate around India's tough dowry law</figcaption></figure><p>On December 9, Atul Subhash, a 34-year-old software engineer from Bengaluru, committed suicide, leaving behind a note and video detailing his troubles stemming from his marriage. His death has sparked outrage and debate over India's dowry laws.</p><ul><li>Subhash's suicide note accused his estranged wife and her family of harassment.</li><li>He left behind a 24-page note and an 81-minute video that went viral, igniting conversations on social media.</li><li>The dowry law, which aims to protect women, is being scrutinized for its potential misuse against men.</li><li>Subhash's family and men's rights activists are calling for justice and revisions to the dowry laws.</li><li>Statistics reveal a high number of dowry-related deaths among brides in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“Legal terrorism” - Supreme Court Judge on the misuse of the dowry law.</blockquote><p>This tragic incident highlights the complexities of dowry laws in India, revealing the urgent need for a nuanced discussion around their application and the protection of both genders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c33d6161z3yo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c33d6161z3yo</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:19:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>