<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:20:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Defence ministry inks Rs 7,629 crore contract for 100 more K-9 Vajra-T artillery guns - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Defence ministry inks Rs 7,629 crore contract for 100 more K-9 Vajra-T artillery guns</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Friday</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116506245,imgsize-1573726,width-400,resizemode-4/116506245.jpg" alt="Defence ministry inks Rs 7,629 crore contract for 100 more K-9 Vajra-T artillery guns" /><figcaption>K-9 Vajra-T artillery guns</figcaption><p>The Indian defence ministry has signed a Rs 7,629 crore contract with L&T for 100 additional K-9 Vajra-T self-propelled artillery guns. These guns are intended for deployment in high-altitude regions along the China border.</p><ul><li>The new artillery systems have a strike range of 28-38 km.</li><li>They enhance the Army's existing arsenal of K-9 guns, originally procured for desert warfare.</li><li>The guns are designed to operate effectively in sub-zero temperatures.</li><li>The acquisition aims to modernize artillery capabilities and boost operational readiness.</li><li>The project is expected to create over 9 lakh man-days of employment and promote Indian industries.</li><li>Further contracts for additional artillery systems and munitions are in the pipeline.</li></ul><blockquote>“This versatile artillery gun, with its cross-country mobility, will play a pivotal role in enhancing the Army’s lethal firepower.”</blockquote><p>This new initiative marks a significant step in artillery modernization, with the expected delivery of the new guns planned over the next four to five years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/defence-ministry-inks-rs-7629-crore-contract-for-100-more-k-9-vajra-t-artillery-guns/articleshow/116506155.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/defence-ministry-inks-rs-7629-crore-contract-for-100-more-k-9-vajra-t-artillery-guns/articleshow/116506155.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament session LIVE: Rajya Sabha, Lok Sabha adjourned sine die - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament session LIVE: Rajya Sabha, Lok Sabha adjourned sine die</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 20, 2024 | Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/rahul_gandhi_parliament_live__1734665864458_1734665864683.jpg" alt="An FIR was registered against Rahul Gandhi on Thursday in connection with the scuffle that broke out in the Parliament." title="An FIR was registered against Rahul Gandhi on Thursday in connection with the scuffle that broke out in the Parliament.">
<figcaption>An FIR was registered against Rahul Gandhi on Thursday in connection with the scuffle that broke out in the Parliament.</figcaption>
<p>The tensions in Parliament escalated over a controversial remark by Union Home Minister Amit Shah regarding Dr. B.R. Ambedkar, resulting in clashes between ruling and opposition members, causing injuries and legal actions.</p>
<ul>
<li>The scuffle began after Amit Shah's remarks in the Rajya Sabha sparked outrage among opposition members.</li>
<li>Two BJP MPs were injured during the confrontation, leading to an FIR against Congress Leader Rahul Gandhi.</li>
<li>Opposition parties accused the BJP of disrespecting Ambedkar and demanded an apology from Shah.</li>
<li>Parliament was adjourned sine die after the scuffle overshadowed the proceedings.</li>
<li>Calls for inquiries and allegations of misconduct were exchanged between party leaders following the incident.</li>
<li>Political leaders expressed disappointment over the session's inability to address critical national issues due to interruptions and infighting.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This FIR is a diversionary tactic by the BJP,” claimed the Congress party.</blockquote>
<p>The adjournment came amid heated debates, indicating a growing rift in parliamentary proceedings and underscoring the need for political decorum.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-session-live-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-rahul-gandhi-congress-ambedkar-row-protest-latest-news-today-december-20-101734665093430.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/parliament-session-live-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-rahul-gandhi-congress-ambedkar-row-protest-latest-news-today-december-20-101734665093430.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:28:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INLD patriarch O P Chautala’s long journey: Five-time CM to 10-year jail and party’s fall - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>O P Chautala: The Rise and Fall of a Political Patriarch</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Friday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<p>Om Prakash Chautala, former Chief Minister of Haryana and INLD patriarch, passed away at the age of 89. His political journey spanned over five decades, marked by significant ups and downs, including a conviction and imprisonment.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Chautala served as Haryana's CM five times.</li>
  <li>He was part of a prominent political family; his father was a Deputy Prime Minister.</li>
  <li>First took office as CM in December 1989 but resigned amidst controversy.</li>
  <li>Convicted in a recruitment scandal in 2013, serving 10 years in prison.</li>
  <li>Post-release, his party, INLD, struggled politically, leading to a split with the formation of JJP.</li>
  <li>INLD’s influence declined significantly, securing only 2 seats in the 2024 Assembly polls.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"He was a dominant figure in Haryana politics for over five decades."</blockquote>
<p>The life of O P Chautala reflects both the rise of a powerful political legacy and the challenges faced by his party in recent years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/inld-patriarch-o-p-chautalas-journey-five-time-cm-to-10-year-jail-9736398/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/inld-patriarch-o-p-chautalas-journey-five-time-cm-to-10-year-jail-9736398/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:21:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Be mindful': India raps Bangladesh government over now-deleted 'annex' post by key aide of Muhammed Yunu - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/be-mindful-india-raps-bangladesh-government-over-now-deleted-annex-post-by-key-aide-of-muhammed-yunus/articleshow/116504132.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/be-mindful-india-raps-bangladesh-government-over-now-deleted-annex-post-by-key-aide-of-muhammed-yunus/articleshow/116504132.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telangana HC provides relief to K.T. Rama Rao; no arrest till December 30 in Formula E race case - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telangana HC Provides Relief to K.T. Rama Rao; No Arrest Till December 30 in Formula E Race Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/k20l38/article69009253.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/20241124213L.jpg" alt="Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) working president K.T. Rama Rao" title="Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) working president K.T. Rama Rao"><figcaption>Bharat Rashtra Samithi (BRS) working president K.T. Rama Rao | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The Telangana High Court has granted interim relief to former Minister K.T. Rama Rao, prohibiting his arrest until December 30 regarding a corruption case involving the release of funds for the Formula E race during his party's government.</p><ul><li>The High Court has ordered that the investigation should continue while Mr. Rama Rao cooperates with the authorities.</li><li>The next hearing for the case is scheduled for December 27.</li><li>Mr. Rama Rao has expressed his readiness to face the allegations legally and claims there is no corruption involved.</li></ul><blockquote>Mr. Rama Rao reiterated that the funds were allocated legally and are intended for development in Hyderabad.</blockquote><p>This decision allows K.T. Rama Rao to continue his work without the threat of arrest while the investigation is ongoing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/telangana-hc-provides-relief-to-kt-rama-rao-no-arrest-till-december-30-in-formula-e-race-case/article69009027.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/telangana/telangana-hc-provides-relief-to-kt-rama-rao-no-arrest-till-december-30-in-formula-e-race-case/article69009027.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RSMSSB Conductor Online Form 2025 - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib0FVX3lxTFBNQnFfZ1NlZzFGR2FCQXpQemd2c3VQaXRjSWhuTEV3Wi1JSkh4ZmxZUjhBQ0NJdGdweVR0SURUNmtmU3MtcWRKZ3hlQk9wN1JuUVdpMFJmS3U4dnNsZXpTSE1RZ1dTd0hQYXI5TFZoRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib0FVX3lxTFBNQnFfZ1NlZzFGR2FCQXpQemd2c3VQaXRjSWhuTEV3Wi1JSkh4ZmxZUjhBQ0NJdGdweVR0SURUNmtmU3MtcWRKZ3hlQk9wN1JuUVdpMFJmS3U4dnNsZXpTSE1RZ1dTd0hQYXI5TFZoRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:03:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Punjab Govt Would Be Responsible': Supreme Court's Direction On Farmer Leader Jagjit Dallewal's Health - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Directs Punjab Government to Ensure Farmer Leader Jagjit Dallewal's Health</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Jagjit Singh Dallewal had been protesting for farmers' rights for weeks now and his health has deteriorated sharply after his hunger strike. (PTI/File)" /><figcaption>Jagjit Singh Dallewal had been protesting for farmers' rights for weeks now and his health has deteriorated sharply after his hunger strike. (PTI/File)</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court has ordered the Punjab government to take immediate action to ensure the safety and health of farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal, who is on an indefinite hunger strike. His health has critically deteriorated recently.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court's directives come after Dallewal lost consciousness during his hunger strike.</li><li>The Punjab government is required to transfer him to a makeshift hospital for constant monitoring.</li><li>Dallewal has been on hunger strike for 24 days and his condition is described as critical.</li><li>Political leaders have urged the government to meet the farmers' demands to alleviate Dallewal's situation.</li></ul><blockquote>The court stated, "The Punjab government would be responsible for Dallewal’s health."</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the ongoing farmers' protests and their struggle for rights, particularly regarding the demands addressed to the Indian government.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/sc-directs-punjab-govt-to-ensure-fasting-farmer-leader-jagjit-singh-dallewals-safety-9162937.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/sc-directs-punjab-govt-to-ensure-fasting-farmer-leader-jagjit-singh-dallewals-safety-9162937.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Temples Destroyed Repeatedly, Says Yogi Adityanath, Hours After Mohan Bhagwat Discourages More Mandir-Masji - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Temples Destroyed Repeatedly, Says Yogi Adityanath, Hours After Mohan Bhagwat Discourages More Mandir-Masjid Disputes</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Mohan Bhagwat’s remarks seem at odds with what Uttar Pradesh chief minister Yogi Adityanath said later on Friday. File image/X" /><figcaption>Mohan Bhagwat’s remarks seem at odds with what Uttar Pradesh chief minister Yogi Adityanath said later on Friday. File image/X</figcaption><p>Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath emphasized the repeated destruction of Hindu temples in various locations, shortly after RSS Chief Mohan Bhagwat called for harmony and discouraged further mandir-masjid disputes. The timing of these statements is significant as the Supreme Court has put a stay on new petitions related to these disputes.</p><ul><li>Yogi Adityanath identified specific sites of destruction, including the Kashi Vishwanath Temple and Ram Janmabhoomi.</li><li>Baghwat stated that raising new disputes is unacceptable and emphasized the need for harmony.</li><li>The Supreme Court has placed a hold on any new surveys or petitions in temple-mosque disputes until February.</li><li>Critics in the Samajwadi Party commented on the contradictory nature of the leaders' statements.</li></ul><blockquote>“Every day, a new matter (dispute) is being raked up. How can this be allowed? This cannot continue,” said Mohan Bhagwat.</blockquote><p>These remarks come amidst rising tensions surrounding temple and mosque disputes in India, highlighting the need for unity and dialogue moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/temples-destroyed-repeatedly-says-up-cm-yogi-hours-after-rss-chief-discourages-more-mandir-masjid-disputes-9162898.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/temples-destroyed-repeatedly-says-up-cm-yogi-hours-after-rss-chief-discourages-more-mandir-masjid-disputes-9162898.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:00:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Rahul Gandhi Obsessed With Businessman, Stalled Parliament": Kiren Rijiju To NDTV - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxPNV90VThsYm9vZHlEU2c2RklLWFpWcEZJYUF0NUIwTUxRVFo3SzdyajRnOFZfclZTdlctbFJNcGRSeU0zbEFmMnN2ZEFDNnhrenlkcGtuVThkYmhrWlkwdVdIQVZaZm1HdFh1WVp5QWtlNDJ5dERyZldZV0RsZFhId3EwOFhldEFQM3FSYzE5NHE3VUpGcVNqTS1kRjRJVnJobjAzZjFIN2pGOTh5aVF5Y2JXRmcwOWZaOVHSAcIBQVVfeXFMUDRWZVdxMk8wQXlaMnhWMFhvN2dsSDFEZzU3SUZzb2U5eVJHdG81cktqSWpfenlSdERfSzBlckVtY1ktMlcyRXM0a3p4S3NzUGhCc0s3emhTWkQtZ0NOQTJjZEVNS0M2UmFqWllKNVJ1Uk1EcW5QZlpKQzFnYzNxLWF5eGRWa3pEZ18td295Mno3eGZEclBwWUZoMzFVR3R0UVdNZ3ZQTEQtT2dXSnU4QnJMaktZNHAxQ2ozUUZzYkhlOUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxPNV90VThsYm9vZHlEU2c2RklLWFpWcEZJYUF0NUIwTUxRVFo3SzdyajRnOFZfclZTdlctbFJNcGRSeU0zbEFmMnN2ZEFDNnhrenlkcGtuVThkYmhrWlkwdVdIQVZaZm1HdFh1WVp5QWtlNDJ5dERyZldZV0RsZFhId3EwOFhldEFQM3FSYzE5NHE3VUpGcVNqTS1kRjRJVnJobjAzZjFIN2pGOTh5aVF5Y2JXRmcwOWZaOVHSAcIBQVVfeXFMUDRWZVdxMk8wQXlaMnhWMFhvN2dsSDFEZzU3SUZzb2U5eVJHdG81cktqSWpfenlSdERfSzBlckVtY1ktMlcyRXM0a3p4S3NzUGhCc0s3emhTWkQtZ0NOQTJjZEVNS0M2UmFqWllKNVJ1Uk1EcW5QZlpKQzFnYzNxLWF5eGRWa3pEZ18td295Mno3eGZEclBwWUZoMzFVR3R0UVdNZ3ZQTEQtT2dXSnU4QnJMaktZNHAxQ2ozUUZzYkhlOUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:40:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[52 kg Gold, Rs 10 Crore Cash Found In Abandoned Innova In Bhopal Jungle - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>52 kg Gold and ₹10 Crore in Cash Seized in Bhopal Jungle</h1><p><strong>Date: December 20, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: NDTV</strong></p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jr9bpr1_bhopal-gold-seizure_625x300_20_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="52 kg Gold, Rs 10 Crore Cash Found In Abandoned Innova In Bhopal Jungle"><figcaption>52 kg Gold and ₹10 Crore in Cash Found In Abandoned Innova In Bhopal Jungle</figcaption><p>Gold and cash worth crores were seized in recent raids by the Income Tax department and Lokayukta Police in Bhopal, highlighting alleged ties between politicians, government officials, and real estate agents.</p><ul><li>52 kg of gold biscuits valued at over ₹40 crore discovered in an abandoned Innova vehicle.</li><li>₹10 crore in cash found during raids connected to an alleged scam.</li><li>The vehicle is linked to Chetan Gaur, associated with former RTO constable, Saurabh Sharma.</li><li>Investigations ongoing into additional seized assets and their sources.</li><li>Raids also targeted prominent builders suspected of ties to politicians.</li></ul><blockquote>“Sources suggest that builders under investigation have ties with prominent politicians and bureaucrats.”</blockquote><p>The discovery raises concern about corruption and potential criminal networks in Bhopal's real estate sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/bhopal-news/gold-worth-rs-40-crore-cash-found-in-abandoned-innova-in-bhopal-jungle-7292848</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/bhopal-news/gold-worth-rs-40-crore-cash-found-in-abandoned-innova-in-bhopal-jungle-7292848</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:28:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sambhal authorities demolish steps of SP MP Zia Ur Rehman's home - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Demolition of Steps at Sambhal MP Zia Ur Rehman's Home Amidst Anti-Encroachment Drive</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Security-personnel-during-a-crackdown-on-electrici_1734691477440_1734691560633.jpg" alt="Security personnel during a crackdown on electricity theft, in Sambhal on Saturday (PTI)(HT_PRINT)"><figcaption>Security personnel during a crackdown on electricity theft, in Sambhal on Saturday (PTI)(HT_PRINT)</figcaption><p>In a dramatic turn of events, steps leading into the house of Sambhal MP and Samajwadi Party leader Zia Ur Rehman Barq were demolished on Friday as part of the UP government's anti-encroachment drive.</p><ul><li>The demolition drive was part of a larger 15-day campaign to clear encroachments from public drains in the district.</li><li>The UP electricity department imposed a fine of ₹1.91 crore on the Sambhal MP for electricity theft.</li><li>Power supply to Rehman's residence was disconnected following an inspection that revealed illegal power usage.</li><li>Charges of electricity theft are linked to a police case under the Electricity Act, 2003.</li><li>Rehman is also involved in a separate case related to violence in Sambhal that resulted in four deaths.</li></ul><blockquote>"An electricity inspection drive is underway in Sambhal even today. A fine of ₹1.91 crore has been imposed on the MP by the Electricity department and the power supply to his residence has been disconnected," Sambhal Superintending Engineer Vinod Kumar told PTI.</blockquote><p>The demolition and the charges against MP Zia Ur Rehman highlight ongoing issues surrounding encroachment and electricity theft in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/sambhal-authorities-demolish-steps-of-sp-mp-zia-ur-rehmans-home-101734691108869.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/sambhal-authorities-demolish-steps-of-sp-mp-zia-ur-rehmans-home-101734691108869.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:24:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Descendants of Aurangzeb riding rickshaws in Kolkata: UP CM Yogi Adityanath continues tirade against 'temple destroyers' - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yogi Adityanath's Remarks on Aurangzeb's Descendants in Kolkata</h1><p><strong>Published: </strong>20 December 2024, 10:56 IST</p><p>Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath has made controversial remarks regarding the descendants of those who destroyed Hindu temples, claiming they now struggle in Kolkata.</p><ul><li>Adityanath stated that the descendants of temple destroyers, specifically referencing Aurangzeb's lineage, now drive rickshaws in Kolkata.</li><li>He suggested that their hardships stem from their ancestors' actions of demolishing temples.</li><li>The CM emphasized that only 'Sanatan Dharma' can establish peace and noted the historical context of temple demolitions in India.</li><li>His comments followed a discussion about recent communal violence in Sambhal, Uttar Pradesh.</li></ul><blockquote>“Their clan will be extinct… only Sanatan Dharma can establish peace in the world.”</blockquote><p>Adityanath's remarks have sparked discussions about historical grievances and their implications in contemporary society.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/uttar-pradesh/descendants-of-aurangzeb-riding-rickshaws-in-kolkata-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-continues-tirade-against-temple-destroyers-3326523</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/uttar-pradesh/descendants-of-aurangzeb-riding-rickshaws-in-kolkata-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-continues-tirade-against-temple-destroyers-3326523</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:56:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Acting like dictators': BJP leader CT Ravi slams Karnataka govt after arrest over 'derogatory' remarks - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Leader CT Ravi Criticizes Karnataka Government After Arrest Over Comments</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>An arrest of an individual over purported derogatory remarks has sparked criticism from BJP leader CT Ravi, who accused the Karnataka government of authoritarian behavior.</p><ul><li>CT Ravi condemned the Karnataka government's action, labeling it as undemocratic.</li><li>The arrest has raised concerns regarding freedom of speech in the region.</li><li>Ravi's comments were aimed at defending individual rights against perceived government overreach.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is not how a democratic government should behave."</blockquote><p>The incident highlights ongoing tensions related to political discourse and individual freedoms in Karnataka.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/acting-like-dictators-bjp-leader-ct-ravi-slams-karnataka-govt-after-arrest-over-derogatory-remarks/articleshow/116500818.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/acting-like-dictators-bjp-leader-ct-ravi-slams-karnataka-govt-after-arrest-over-derogatory-remarks/articleshow/116500818.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Untrue’: Former CJI Chandrachud on reports he was being considered for NHRC chairperson - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Former CJI Chandrachud Denies NHRC Chairperson Consideration</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/fmy5d6/article69008647.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/10018_6_12_2024_20_11_8_4_CHANDRACHOOD_04.JPG" alt="Former Chief Justice of India D.Y. Chandrachud." title="Former Chief Justice of India D.Y. Chandrachud."><figcaption>Former Chief Justice of India D.Y. Chandrachud. | Photo Credit: The Hindu</figcaption><p>Former Chief Justice of India D.Y. Chandrachud has refuted media reports suggesting he was under consideration for the chairperson position of the National Human Rights Commission (NHRC).</p><ul><li>Chandrachud stated the reports were "untrue" and mentioned he is currently enjoying retirement.</li><li>The NHRC chairperson position has been vacant since former Supreme Court Justice Arun Kumar Mishra’s term ended on June 1, 2024.</li><li>A high-powered committee led by Prime Minister Narendra Modi convened on December 18 to deliberate on the next NHRC chairperson.</li><li>Justice Mishra was the eighth chairperson of the NHRC and served from June 2021 until June 2024.</li><li>Vijaya Bharathi Sayani is currently the acting chairperson of NHRC.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is untrue. Presently, I am enjoying my retired life," - D.Y. Chandrachud</blockquote><p>The NHRC chairperson is appointed by the President upon the committee's recommendation, which includes several prominent political figures and leaders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/untrue-former-cji-chandrachud-on-reports-he-was-being-considered-for-nhrc-chairperson/article69008592.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/untrue-former-cji-chandrachud-on-reports-he-was-being-considered-for-nhrc-chairperson/article69008592.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Adjourned Sine Die, 'One Nation, One Election' Bills Referred to Joint Committee - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/parliament-winter-session-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-adjourned-nda-opposition-protest-ambedkar-row-bjp-mps-injured-9162588.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/parliament-winter-session-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-adjourned-nda-opposition-protest-ambedkar-row-bjp-mps-injured-9162588.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:14:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wife, in-laws of techie Atul Subhash seek bail in Bengaluru court following arrest in abetment of suicide case - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wife, In-Laws of Techie Atul Subhash Seek Bail in Bengaluru Court Following Arrest in Abetment of Suicide Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Untitled-design-2024-12-20T152022.938.jpg?w=640" alt="Atul Subhash suicide" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Atul Subhash was allegedly harassed by his wife and in-laws.</figcaption><p>Atul Subhash, a 34-year-old employee, died by suicide, leading to the arrest of his wife and in-laws for alleged abetment. This article discusses their bail plea and the circumstances surrounding the case.</p><ul><li>Atul Subhash was found dead on December 9, 2024.</li><li>His family filed a complaint against his wife, her mother, and brother alleging harassment and extortion.</li><li>The accused are alleged to have demanded ₹3 crore to withdraw cases against Subhash.</li><li>Nikita Singhania and her family were arrested in Delhi and Uttar Pradesh.</li><li>Atul had filed multiple cases against his wife and her family.</li><li>He left behind a death note and a video documenting his struggles.</li></ul><blockquote>“My brother has been mentally and physically drained since the court battles began. He was constantly mocked and told to die if he couldn’t meet their demands.” - Bikas Kumar</blockquote><p>This case highlights the tragic circumstances around domestic disputes and the serious consequences that can arise from them.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/atul-subhash-wife-in-laws-seek-bail-in-bengaluru-court-following-arrest-9736082/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/atul-subhash-wife-in-laws-seek-bail-in-bengaluru-court-following-arrest-9736082/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:03:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody" alt="Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1jhj1vd8_atul-subhash-_625x300_20_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>Atul Subhash's Mother Appeals for Custody</figcaption><p>In a poignant development, the mother of Atul Subhash, a Bengaluru engineer who died by suicide, has approached the Supreme Court for custody of her four-year-old grandson amidst allegations of harassment against Subhash's estranged wife and her family.</p><ul><li>The case revolves around multiple arrests linked to Subhash's suicide on December 9, which his family claims was prompted by harassment.</li><li>Anju Modi filed a habeas corpus petition for her grandson, whose whereabouts remain unknown despite claims he is in a boarding school.</li><li>The Supreme Court has asked the governments of Uttar Pradesh, Haryana, and Karnataka for clarity regarding the child’s location.</li><li>Nikita Singhania, Subhash's estranged wife, and her family members face charges related to abetment of suicide and are currently in custody.</li><li>Pawan Kumar, Subhash's father, demands to know the child's whereabouts and custody due to the family's concerns for his safety.</li><li>There is ongoing legal contention, including anticipatory bail requests concerning Nikita's uncle.</li></ul><blockquote>Bikas Kumar, Subhash's brother, stated, "Our fight will continue. We will not immerse the ashes of my brother till we get justice."</blockquote><p>The situation highlights serious familial disputes and legal battles regarding the welfare of a young child amidst tragic circumstances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/atul-subhash-nikita-singhania-techie-suicide-atul-subhashs-mother-moves-supreme-court-for-4-year-old-grandsons-custody-7293075</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/atul-subhash-nikita-singhania-techie-suicide-atul-subhashs-mother-moves-supreme-court-for-4-year-old-grandsons-custody-7293075</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:49:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atul Subhash's Mother Moves Supreme Court for 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody" alt="Atul Subhash's Mother Goes To Supreme Court For 4-Year-Old Grandson's Custody" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1jhj1vd8_atul-subhash-_625x300_20_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>Atul Subhash's Mother Appeals for Custody</figcaption><p>In a poignant development, the mother of Atul Subhash, a Bengaluru engineer who died by suicide, has approached the Supreme Court for custody of her four-year-old grandson amidst allegations of harassment against Subhash's estranged wife and her family.</p><ul><li>The case revolves around multiple arrests linked to Subhash's suicide on December 9, which his family claims was prompted by harassment.</li><li>Anju Modi filed a habeas corpus petition for her grandson, whose whereabouts remain unknown despite claims he is in a boarding school.</li><li>The Supreme Court has asked the governments of Uttar Pradesh, Haryana, and Karnataka for clarity regarding the child’s location.</li><li>Nikita Singhania, Subhash's estranged wife, and her family members face charges related to abetment of suicide and are currently in custody.</li><li>Pawan Kumar, Subhash's father, demands to know the child's whereabouts and custody due to the family's concerns for his safety.</li><li>There is ongoing legal contention, including anticipatory bail requests concerning Nikita's uncle.</li></ul><blockquote>Bikas Kumar, Subhash's brother, stated, "Our fight will continue. We will not immerse the ashes of my brother till we get justice."</blockquote><p>The situation highlights serious familial disputes and legal battles regarding the welfare of a young child amidst tragic circumstances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/atul-subhash-nikita-singhania-techie-suicide-atul-subhashs-mother-moves-supreme-court-for-4-year-old-grandsons-custody-7293075</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/atul-subhash-nikita-singhania-techie-suicide-atul-subhashs-mother-moves-supreme-court-for-4-year-old-grandsons-custody-7293075</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:49:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FIR filed against CT Ravi, will be presented before court: Karnataka Home Minister G Parameshwara - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FIR Filed Against BJP Leader CT Ravi Over Allegations of Derogatory Remarks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/CT-RAVI-0_1672639471697_1734685919406.jpg" alt="BJP leader CT Ravi." title="BJP leader CT Ravi."><figcaption>BJP leader CT Ravi.</figcaption><p>Karnataka Home Minister G Parameshwara announced that an FIR has been filed against BJP leader CT Ravi after he allegedly made derogatory remarks towards Congress Leader Laxmi Hebbalkar. Ravi is set to be presented before the court following these accusations.</p><ul><li>An FIR was filed against CT Ravi after he allegedly used obscene language towards Minister Laxmi Hebbalkar.</li><li>G Parameshwara affirmed that CT Ravi will be presented in court today.</li><li>The incident escalated after CT Ravi reportedly called Rahul Gandhi a drug addict.</li><li>Advocate MB Jiragi claimed that formal arrest procedures were not followed for CT Ravi.</li></ul><blockquote>“This incident all started after he allegedly called Rahul Gandhi a drug addict. It is wrong, being a senior politician no one should use such words, that too against a lady who is a minister.”</blockquote><p>This situation raises concerns regarding the treatment of political figures and the respect accorded to political discourse in Karnataka.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/bengaluru-news/fir-filed-against-ct-ravi-will-be-presented-before-court-karnataka-home-minister-g-parameshwara-101734685646879.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/bengaluru-news/fir-filed-against-ct-ravi-will-be-presented-before-court-karnataka-home-minister-g-parameshwara-101734685646879.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:21:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allahabad High Court grants interim protection from arrest to Mohammed Zubair - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allahabad High Court Grants Interim Protection to Journalist Mohammed Zubair</h1><p><strong>Published on: </strong><time datetime="2024-12-20T09:01:56.780Z">20 Dec 2024, 9:01 am</time></p><div><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justice Siddharth Varma and Justice Nalin Srivastava" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Justice Siddharth Varma and Justice Nalin Srivastava</figcaption></div><p>The Allahabad High Court has granted interim protection from arrest to Alt News journalist Mohammed Zubair, who was charged by the Uttar Pradesh Police for allegedly endangering national integrity through a critical tweet about a controversial priest's speech.</p><ul><li>Zubair's arrest was temporarily blocked until a court hearing scheduled for January 6, 2025.</li><li>He tweeted that a speech by priest Yati Narsinghanand was derogatory and hateful, leading to accusations against him.</li><li>The FIR against Zubair was lodged following a complaint from the priest's supporters.</li><li>Zubair claims the charges are a retaliation for exposing Narsinghanand's hateful remarks.</li><li>The case has drawn significant attention, reflective of ongoing tensions regarding freedom of speech and communal relations in India.</li></ul><blockquote>Zubair stated that the FIR against him is a malicious attempt to prevent him from exposing criminal activities.</blockquote><p>This interim ruling highlights the ongoing conflict between journalists and political or religious figures in India, particularly regarding freedom of expression and the safety of reporting on sensitive issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/allahabad-high-court-grants-interim-protection-from-arrest-mohammed-zubair</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/allahabad-high-court-grants-interim-protection-from-arrest-mohammed-zubair</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:01:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adani to invest ₹20,000 crore in proposed supercritical thermal power plant in Bihar | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxNU3F4cDNDMmRZR3VSVmpqa2MzX2dWem0yY1JqeUtMaVpFcWFwSGNyWk0zWW1lN3RCTGRfeHlyR3ZsRVd1Z01hS2FxYmRBUmJXdklkNTZfOGxhMERkaV9vUTg2bXJzVjlEU3NhcE5rZ3JjZ1RPTHAwT05wM1B6THkyWXpfNzNjMU5kMzF0Z3M0cGR3Q2tCZjQ1YzdaR2ZUdjB4TUhmYXFGaEU2VEdtb3V4c25Ma1FONVFfeUZ5aHAyU1BxY1U0TjhIVzdBS1A3V1ZIQ2RfMWhSaTF2eFHSAeABQVVfeXFMTzctWWxLaW5FeEQ3Z0tJMkgzTmZXZ19TemRaNUZTMDVlUjFiOEgtRnlXU3hLd20wLWFYbzQ4cUlOUzN2M0ZtRW91UVpENkJiR2tzMXBSZ2dfMUFuSHMwYXBnVm1Ud1RrNUprVF9KQmdUTEtTNDVpNVhlX3ZKV014UFg3ek5XSHV2RzFnZTFha3N1dXhPcFVEZTNxdU9ZLXVHRnc4ZC1VUWxZWDZsXzhnYWlwSHNPWkVsWFg4SGRSWV91QmZJM3I4bnp5dTNtbVFjVTBwaU5BMXJmeGlhdUNEb0Q?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxNU3F4cDNDMmRZR3VSVmpqa2MzX2dWem0yY1JqeUtMaVpFcWFwSGNyWk0zWW1lN3RCTGRfeHlyR3ZsRVd1Z01hS2FxYmRBUmJXdklkNTZfOGxhMERkaV9vUTg2bXJzVjlEU3NhcE5rZ3JjZ1RPTHAwT05wM1B6THkyWXpfNzNjMU5kMzF0Z3M0cGR3Q2tCZjQ1YzdaR2ZUdjB4TUhmYXFGaEU2VEdtb3V4c25Ma1FONVFfeUZ5aHAyU1BxY1U0TjhIVzdBS1A3V1ZIQ2RfMWhSaTF2eFHSAeABQVVfeXFMTzctWWxLaW5FeEQ3Z0tJMkgzTmZXZ19TemRaNUZTMDVlUjFiOEgtRnlXU3hLd20wLWFYbzQ4cUlOUzN2M0ZtRW91UVpENkJiR2tzMXBSZ2dfMUFuSHMwYXBnVm1Ud1RrNUprVF9KQmdUTEtTNDVpNVhlX3ZKV014UFg3ek5XSHV2RzFnZTFha3N1dXhPcFVEZTNxdU9ZLXVHRnc4ZC1VUWxZWDZsXzhnYWlwSHNPWkVsWFg4SGRSWV91QmZJM3I4bnp5dTNtbVFjVTBwaU5BMXJmeGlhdUNEb0Q?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:01:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Can't speak Kannada in Bengaluru? Come to Delhi': Cars24 CEO's hiring post is viral - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Can’t speak Kannada in Bengaluru? Come to Delhi’: Cars24 CEO’s hiring post is viral</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p>
<img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/cars24-ceo-vikram-chopras-hiring-post-is-viral-photo-vikram-choprax-204604837-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=9lLJtnbyMw3.KMsf5TBoq.ERI3LLNQCY&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="vikram chopra" title="Cars24 CEO Vikram Chopra’s hiring post is viral (Photo: Vikram Chopra/X)" height="388">
<figcaption>Cars24 CEO Vikram Chopra’s hiring post is viral (Photo: Vikram Chopra/X)</figcaption>
<p>Vikram Chopra, CEO of Cars24, has ignited debate on social media with a viral hiring post that plays on the longstanding rivalry between Delhi and Bengaluru.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Chopra shared a graphic highlighting the language debate in Bengaluru, stating, “Still can’t speak Kannada after years in Bengaluru? It’s OK. Aa jao Dilli. We are looking for engineers who wish to stay close to home.”</li>
    <li>The post gained over 400,000 views and inspired discussions about regional biases in job postings.</li>
    <li>Reactions varied, with some praising the lighthearted jab while others criticized it as insensitive.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>One user commented, “Delhi NCR has its charm, but before calling it ‘better,’ let’s take a moment to consider the reality. A look at the crime data might offer a different perspective.”</blockquote>
<p>Chopra’s approach has opened up broader conversations about messaging in professional contexts and the cultural dynamics within India’s metro cities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/trending-news/story/cars24-ceo-vikram-chopra-hiring-post-viral-cant-speak-kannada-in-bengaluru-come-to-delhi-2652861-2024-12-20</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/trending-news/story/cars24-ceo-vikram-chopra-hiring-post-viral-cant-speak-kannada-in-bengaluru-come-to-delhi-2652861-2024-12-20</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:56:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CCTV captures deadly gas tanker crash on Jaipur-Ajmer highway: 9 dead, 15 critical - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxQZVRFcXFablJDY3BLYkR4c205MGplQm1oR3lRWVV4N25wTXMxa1hwem9LQm9QaW1EMFItU0Q0azlQeUhWbk5nNFB3UU9PY0lZRVZsMjVta2RzV0xTMjFjVl96MU81dGx2OWg1WHVYNU11MGtNNkxTa2dhbnF5amxDR0F3eTYweExQVjFDQkRKU0VVS21yT3cyZzlIWmMxLUFqeUhJWHJoTTF5QUZXTlZsV0RqUUI3OTM0MnJJSkJhZmt4OHJkQUZUY0kxZE5ZRFZHZElKXy04YUhqb1Q5cFltSVdra1pIZWJJTVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxQZVRFcXFablJDY3BLYkR4c205MGplQm1oR3lRWVV4N25wTXMxa1hwem9LQm9QaW1EMFItU0Q0azlQeUhWbk5nNFB3UU9PY0lZRVZsMjVta2RzV0xTMjFjVl96MU81dGx2OWg1WHVYNU11MGtNNkxTa2dhbnF5amxDR0F3eTYweExQVjFDQkRKU0VVS21yT3cyZzlIWmMxLUFqeUhJWHJoTTF5QUZXTlZsV0RqUUI3OTM0MnJJSkJhZmt4OHJkQUZUY0kxZE5ZRFZHZElKXy04YUhqb1Q5cFltSVdra1pIZWJJTVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Haryana CM, INLD chief Om Prakash Chautala passes away - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Former Haryana CM Om Prakash Chautala Passes Away at 89</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Friday, December 15, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Om-Prakash-Chautala.jpg?w=640" alt="Om Prakash Chautala" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Former Haryana chief minister Om Prakash Chautala. (Express Archives)</figcaption><p>Former Haryana chief minister and Indian National Lok Dal (INLD) leader Om Prakash Chautala passed away at his Gurugram residence on Friday afternoon. He was 89 years old.</p><ul><li>Chautala served as the chief minister of Haryana for a record five terms.</li><li>He was the son of former deputy prime minister Devi Lal.</li><li>Chautala will be cremated in Teja Khera, Sirsa district, with public viewings scheduled for Saturday.</li><li>He is survived by two sons and three daughters, with his son Dushyant having served as Deputy Chief Minister of Haryana.</li><li>Chautala had faced legal troubles, having been convicted in a 2013 corruption case, which affected his political career significantly.</li></ul><blockquote>“A cardiac arrest took his life as he had hiccups before he took his last breath,” said INLD spokesperson Rakesh Sihag.</blockquote><p>Om Prakash Chautala's passing marks the loss of a significant figure in Haryana's political landscape, having attempted to forge a new political front after his release from jail.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/om-prakash-chautala-passes-away-9735821/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/om-prakash-chautala-passes-away-9735821/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:48:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jaipur gas tanker crash: CCTV shows fire sweeping nearby property moments after accident | Video - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jaipur Gas Tanker Crash: CCTV Captures Fire After Deadly Accident</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/jaipur_gas_tanker_blast_1734683181102_1734683181519.jpg" alt="Firefighters at the site of the accident after a truck loaded with a chemical collided with some other vehicles and caught fire on the Jaipur-Ajmer Highway.(PTI)">
<figcaption>Firefighters at the site of the accident after a truck loaded with a chemical collided with some other vehicles and caught fire on the Jaipur-Ajmer Highway.(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>The crash on the Jaipur-Ajmer highway resulted in at least seven fatalities and over 35 injuries, transforming the scene into an inferno as multiple vehicles ignited.</p>
<ul>
  <li>At least seven fatalities reported, with over 35 individuals injured.</li>
  <li>The collision involved a gas tanker and multiple vehicles, leading to a significant fire.</li>
  <li>CCTV footage shows flames engulfing a nearby property shortly after the accident.</li>
  <li>Witnesses described flames visible from approximately a kilometer away.</li>
  <li>The Rajasthan Chief Minister and Home Minister both responded to the incident.</li>
  <li>Critical conditions reported among many of the injured.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Deeply saddened to hear the news of casualties in the gas tanker fire incident on the Jaipur-Ajmer National Highway.” - Rajasthan Chief Minister Bhajan Lal Sharma</blockquote>
<p>The incident highlights the dangers associated with transport accidents involving hazardous materials and stresses the importance of safety regulations on highways.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jaipur-gas-tanker-blast-cctv-video-petrol-pump-bhankrota-jaipur-ajmer-road-101734682037514.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jaipur-gas-tanker-blast-cctv-video-petrol-pump-bhankrota-jaipur-ajmer-road-101734682037514.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:37:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rajya Sabha adopts motion to nominate 12 MPs to joint panel on simultaneous polls - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rajya Sabha adopts motion to nominate 12 MPs to joint panel on simultaneous polls</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/pser1m/article69008357.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_20_2024_000079A.jpg" alt="Rajya Sabha Chairman Jagdeep Dhankhar conducts proceedings during the Winter session of Parliament" title="Rajya Sabha Chairman Jagdeep Dhankhar arrives to conduct proceedings in the House during the Winter session of Parliament, in New Delhi on Friday (December 20, 2024)." />
<figcaption>Rajya Sabha Chairman Jagdeep Dhankhar conducts proceedings during the Winter session of Parliament. Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption>
<p>The Rajya Sabha has adopted a motion to nominate 12 MPs to a joint committee that will review bills for simultaneous elections, marking a significant step towards the proposed electoral reform.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The motion was passed via voice vote on December 20, 2024.</li>
  <li>Union Law Minister Arjun Ram Meghwal moved the motion in the Rajya Sabha.</li>
  <li>The nominated members include representatives from various parties such as BJP, Congress, JD(U), and others.</li>
  <li>The joint committee will comprise 39 members: 27 from the Lok Sabha and 12 from the Rajya Sabha.</li>
  <li>The two 'one nation one election' (ONOE) bills propose mechanisms for conducting simultaneous elections and require constitutional amendments.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Upper House of Parliament resolves to nominate 12 members to serve on the joint committee.” - Union Law Minister Arjun Ram Meghwal</blockquote>
<p>This decision aims to expedite discussions around electoral reforms, focusing on the efficiency of holding simultaneous elections in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rajya-sabha-adopts-motion-to-nominate-12-mps-to-joint-panel-on-simultaneous-polls/article69008341.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rajya-sabha-adopts-motion-to-nominate-12-mps-to-joint-panel-on-simultaneous-polls/article69008341.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Andhra woman orders home appliances, receives dead body in package with letter demanding ₹1.3 crore - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/andhra-woman-orders-home-appliances-receives-dead-body-in-package-with-letter-demanding-rs-1-3-crore-101734682242908.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/andhra-woman-orders-home-appliances-receives-dead-body-in-package-with-letter-demanding-rs-1-3-crore-101734682242908.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:15:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Chief Justice DY Chandrachud Denies news of Appointment as NHRC Chairperson - Law Trend]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxNYUNPNDd3THlVc3lYa1JZcmNCMmNHR3FIdnVhX3lyVVBMdGN4U3BXR0tJZURWMDV0OFd5ZXhybHkza1QyYndKZmxpbWQ4U25GSjBEeHBJelVtZ1FjVWtpLW5HTEZqa1lMTFdWUy1WRENDekVUVVNTbFd3X1F6ekF3MHRxZVJWQUtIMHdhWVpGeFFoT0Nlc3NRZFFCRWFHSE1GNlpDcXpR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxNYUNPNDd3THlVc3lYa1JZcmNCMmNHR3FIdnVhX3lyVVBMdGN4U3BXR0tJZURWMDV0OFd5ZXhybHkza1QyYndKZmxpbWQ4U25GSjBEeHBJelVtZ1FjVWtpLW5HTEZqa1lMTFdWUy1WRENDekVUVVNTbFd3X1F6ekF3MHRxZVJWQUtIMHdhWVpGeFFoT0Nlc3NRZFFCRWFHSE1GNlpDcXpR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:14:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session Day 21 Live Updates: On last day of Winter Session, both Houses adjourned ‘sine die’ amid Centre-Oppn uproar - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament Winter Session Day 21 Live Updates: On last day of Winter Session, both Houses adjourned ‘sine die’ amid Centre-Oppn uproar</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 21, 2024 | Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/parliament_03039a.jpg?w=640" alt="Parliament Winter Session Day 21 Live Updates: lok sabha, rajya sabha" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Parliament Winter Session Day 21 Live Updates: Members in the Lok Sabha during the Winter session of Parliament, in New Delhi. (PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>On the final day of the Winter Session of Parliament, both Houses were adjourned sine die shortly after reconvening amidst a faceoff between the Centre and Opposition MPs, related to protests over comments made about B R Ambedkar.</p><ul><li>The Lok Sabha adopted a resolution referring bills on simultaneous elections to a joint parliamentary committee.</li><li>Protests in Parliament led to a scuffle involving Opposition and BJP MPs.</li><li>Two BJP MPs were reportedly injured during the confrontations.</li></ul><blockquote>“In a decisive move aimed at maintaining decorum, Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla issued instructions that no political party or groups of MPs will be allowed to hold any protest at the gates of Parliament House.”</blockquote><p>This session's conclusion highlights ongoing tensions between political parties in India, particularly concerning the treatment of historical figures like Dr B R Ambedkar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/parliament-winter-session-day-21-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-bjp-congress-9735436/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/parliament-winter-session-day-21-live-updates-lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-bjp-congress-9735436/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:05:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament winter session comes to end amid BJP-INDIA bloc showdown - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliament winter session comes to end amid BJP-INDIA bloc showdown</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Parliament winter session" /><figcaption>Parliament winter session</figcaption><p>The winter session of Parliament has concluded, marked by intense confrontations between the ruling BJP and the opposition INDIA bloc. The session saw significant debates and discussions surrounding various key issues.</p><ul><li>The winter session addressed multiple legislative measures amidst ongoing political tensions.</li><li>Opposition parties criticized the BJP for its handling of crucial topics, raising questions about governance.</li><li>Key debates revolved around economic policies, social issues, and national security.</li></ul><blockquote>“The essence of democracy is the ability to debate and discuss,” stated a senior opposition leader during the sessions.</blockquote><p>The conclusion of this winter session reflects the polarized political landscape in India, with implications for future legislative actions and political strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/parliament-winter-session-comes-to-end-amid-bjp-india-bloc-showdown/articleshow/116491845.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/parliament-winter-session-comes-to-end-amid-bjp-india-bloc-showdown/articleshow/116491845.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>