<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:23:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:23:54 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UP Teen Hammers Best Friend To Death For Blackmailing Girlfriend With Her Video - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<html><body><h1>UP Teen Hammers Best Friend To Death For Blackmailing Girlfriend With Her Video</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Last Updated: December 30, 2024, 19:23 IST</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Abhinav was killed by his friend in UP's Meerut | Image/File" title="Abhinav was killed by his friend in UP's Meerut | Image/File" data-src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" loading="eager" srcset="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270"><figcaption>Abhinav was killed by his friend in UP's Meerut | Image/File</figcaption></img><p>Introduction: A 17-year-old boy in Meerut allegedly killed his best friend for stealing intimate videos of his girlfriend from his phone and blackmailing her.</p><ul><li>The accused confessed to the crime and told the police that the victim, Abhinav, had been using the videos to torture his girlfriend.</li><li>The victim and accused were neighbours and studying for engineering entrance exams.</li><li>The accused was initially suspected by the victim's father after he was missing for a day.</li><li>The accused confessed to murdering Abhinav after CCTV footage showed them together.</li><li>The accused claimed that Abhinav had started blackmailing his girlfriend after accessing the videos.</li></ul><blockquote>Notable Quote: The accused told the police that Abhinav had stolen some pictures as well as videos from his phone to torture his girlfriend.</blockquote><p>Conclusion: The Uttar Pradesh Police has detained the teenage boy who confessed to killing his best friend over a blackmail incident involving his girlfriend.</p></body></html>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/up-teen-hammers-best-friend-to-death-for-blackmailing-girlfriend-with-her-video-9172466.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/up-teen-hammers-best-friend-to-death-for-blackmailing-girlfriend-with-her-video-9172466.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:37:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MPESB Group 5 Online Form 2025 - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMic0FVX3lxTE5LLW81RnQ2OFZxc1dVR0pudFE1NVVVZEZOcmRCMi1QX2Q2a2lJYkU0MDNtUWdLSWl0UEpzRnFLU2U5al92VWI4WTZCQTlpdHhwaFEwY2pRaG9uUTBCUHhJRkgxb0YtcHVQV0pzQWppRmJneEU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMic0FVX3lxTE5LLW81RnQ2OFZxc1dVR0pudFE1NVVVZEZOcmRCMi1QX2Q2a2lJYkU0MDNtUWdLSWl0UEpzRnFLU2U5al92VWI4WTZCQTlpdHhwaFEwY2pRaG9uUTBCUHhJRkgxb0YtcHVQV0pzQWppRmJneEU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:26:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Law equal for all, I don't blame police: Pawan Kalyan on Allu Arjun's arrest - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pawan Kalyan's Stance on Allu Arjun's Arrest and Stampede Incident</h1>
<p><strong>Published on: Dec 30, 2024</strong></p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/pawan-kalyan-30443081-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=0Hb_dLWvZygL1FKO68vx01pKYUWyzWk2&size=690:388" width="690" height="388" alt="Pawan Kalyan">
<figcaption>Andhra Pradesh Deputy Chief Minister Pawan Kalyan (PTI photo/File)</figcaption>
<p>Andhra Pradesh Deputy Chief Minister and former actor Pawan Kalyan has spoken about the arrest of Telugu actor Allu Arjun in connection with a stampede at a theatre. Kalyan stated that he doesn't blame the police for their actions and that the law is equal for everyone.</p>
<p>Kalyan believes that the incident could have been resolved more easily but was grateful that the police handled it with dignity.</p>
<ul>
<li>Kalyan supports the police's actions in the incident.</li>
<li>He understands the excitement of fans but emphasizes the importance of security measures.</li>
<li>He praises Telangana Chief Minister Revanth Reddy for his policies.</li>
</ul>
<p>Kalyan also shares his thoughts on the way the incident was handled and the role of Allu Arjun in the matter.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/india/south/story/pawan-kalyan-on-allu-arjun-arrest-does-not-blame-telangana-police-law-equal-for-everyone-2657305-2024-12-30</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/india/south/story/pawan-kalyan-on-allu-arjun-arrest-does-not-blame-telangana-police-law-equal-for-everyone-2657305-2024-12-30</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:48:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Rahul Gandhi flew to Vietnam amid mourning': BJP alleges 'contempt' for Manmohan Singh - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Accuses Rahul Gandhi of Insulting Manmohan Singh by Traveling Abroad During Mourning</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/ANI-20241228376-0_1735554428433_1735554467411.jpg" alt="Leader of Opposition in Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi during Manmohan Singh's funeral.(ANI file photo)" title="Leader of Opposition in Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi during Manmohan Singh's funeral.(ANI file photo)"><figcaption>Leader of Opposition in Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi during Manmohan Singh's funeral.(ANI file photo)</figcaption><p>The BJP has criticized Rahul Gandhi for allegedly traveling to Vietnam to celebrate New Year's shortly after the death of former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, claiming it shows a lack of respect for Singh's memory.</p><ul><li>The BJP accused Rahul Gandhi of insensitivity for traveling abroad while the nation mourns Singh's passing.</li><li>BJP spokesperson Shehzad Poonawalla stated that Congress has historically disrespected Singh, including during his life.</li><li>Congress clarified that their leaders did not attend the ashes immersion to respect the family's privacy.</li><li>The BJP's Malviya claimed Gandhi exploited Singh's death for political gain.</li><li>Congress MP Manickam Tagore criticized BJP's tactics, defending Gandhi's private travel.</li></ul><blockquote>“While the country is mourning Prime Minister Manmohan Singh's demise, Rahul Gandhi has flown abroad to bring in the New Year.” - Shehzad Poonawalla</blockquote><p>This incident has sparked significant political debate, with accusations exchanged between the two parties regarding the legacy and treatment of Manmohan Singh.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-flew-to-vietnam-amid-mourning-bjp-alleges-contempt-for-manmohan-singh-101735553898941.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/rahul-gandhi-flew-to-vietnam-amid-mourning-bjp-alleges-contempt-for-manmohan-singh-101735553898941.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:30:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shalini Passi says she married at 20, had a son at 21 but had one important condition for husband: ‘He should not…’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shalini Passi: Marrying Young and Having a Child at 21, with No Regrets</h1><p><strong>Date: 2024-12-01, Source: Indian Express</strong></p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Shalini-Passi-3.jpg?w=640" alt="Shalini Passi on marrying young" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Shalini Passi shares marrying at 20 was the greatest move. (Photo: Shalini Passi/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Shalini Passi, known for her appearances in 'Fabulous Lives vs Bollywood Wives,' has shared her perspective on getting married at 20 and becoming a mother at 21. In an interview with Mojo Story, she expressed no regrets about her decision, describing it as a 'great move by the universe.'</p><ol><li>Shalini had an arranged marriage with Sanjay Passi, the owner of the PASCO group, after his family spotted her at a wedding.</li><li>She had a condition for her arranged marriage: her husband should not drink, smoke, or gamble.</li><li>Despite initial challenges, Shalini mastered the art of hosting and adapted to her new lifestyle.</li><li>She is known for her love for art and philanthropic work.</li></ol><blockquote>“It was a very good move by the universe because I had so much energy and enthusiasm back then. What happens with women is later in their life, the energy and recovery gets extremely different. When young, you recover early. I became a mom at 21. Because I was young, I used to get more excited than my son when I took him to a toy store. Its like I am almost living my life in reverse.”</blockquote><p>Shalini Passi reflects on her young marriage and motherhood, emphasizing her enthusiasm and energy during that period.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/web-series/shalini-passi-says-she-married-at-20-had-a-son-at-21-but-had-one-important-condition-for-husband-9751353/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/web-series/shalini-passi-says-she-married-at-20-had-a-son-at-21-but-had-one-important-condition-for-husband-9751353/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:29:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Army installs Shivaji statue on Pangong Lake, Ladakh councillor questions relevance - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Army installs Shivaji statue on Pangong Lake, Ladakh councillor questions relevance</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/hpbv7f/article69042969.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Gf4S8mFWkAAHglK.jpg" alt="Chhatrapati Shivaji statue installed on the banks of Pangong Tso at an altitude of 14,300 feet. Photo courtesy: X/Fire and Fury Corps, Indian Army" title="Chhatrapati Shivaji statue installed on the banks of Pangong Tso at an altitude of 14,300 feet. Photo courtesy: X/Fire and Fury Corps, Indian Army">
<figure><figcaption>Chhatrapati Shivaji statue installed on the banks of Pangong Tso at an altitude of 14,300 feet. Photo courtesy: X/Fire and Fury Corps, Indian Army</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Councillor of Chushul in Ladakh has raised concerns over the installation of a statue of Chhatrapati Shivaji by the Indian Army on Pangong Tso's banks, questioning its relevance to the region.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The statue, inaugurated on December 26, 2024, was built with contributions from serving and retired personnel of a Maratha unit.</li>
  <li>Local residents and veterans criticized the lack of consultation with the community regarding the statue's installation.</li>
  <li>Some veterans suggested that Zorawar Singh, a historical figure significant to Ladakh, would have been a more appropriate choice for the statue.</li>
  <li>The decision comes amidst a backdrop of recent controversies regarding military symbols and representations in the region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“As a local resident, I must voice my concerns about the Shivaji statue at Pangong. It was erected without local input, and I question its relevance to our unique environment and wildlife.” - Konchok Stanzin, Councillor of Chushul</blockquote>
<p>The installation has sparked a debate about cultural representation and the importance of preserving local history in context.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/ladakh/army-installs-shivaji-statue-on-pangong-lake-ladakh-councillor-questions-relevance/article69042960.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/ladakh/army-installs-shivaji-statue-on-pangong-lake-ladakh-councillor-questions-relevance/article69042960.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Manali, Solang Valley koi bhi mat aana': Traveller's warning amid snow chaos in Himachal - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manali, Solang Valley koi bhi mat aana: Traveller's warning amid snow chaos in Himachal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/ANI-20241229207-0_1735552449913_1735552471814.jpg" alt="Vehicles stuck in a traffic jam near Nehru Kund on the way to Solang Valley, in Manali on Sunday. (ANI)"><figcaption>Vehicles stuck in a traffic jam near Nehru Kund on the way to Solang Valley, in Manali on Sunday. (ANI)</figcaption><p>Himachal Pradesh’s Manali and Solang Valley are facing severe disruptions from heavy snowfall, with over 1,800 vehicles stranded. Travelers are warned to avoid the region as conditions worsen.</p><ul><li>Over 2,000 vehicles were stuck due to a snowstorm affecting the Solang Valley and Atal Tunnel routes.</li><li>Rescue operations have been initiated, evacuating nearly 1,800 vehicles, with around 200 heavy vehicles still stranded.</li><li>Officials warn that further snowfall is expected, exacerbating road conditions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Manali and Solang Valley, koi bhi mat aana! (Do not come!)” - Chlucky Tyagi, a stranded traveler.</blockquote><p>The heavy snowfall has led to significant delays and hazardous conditions, with ongoing weather alerts for travelers considering the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/manali-solang-valley-koi-bhi-mat-aana-travellers-warning-amid-snow-chaos-in-himachal-pradesh-101735552086361.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/manali-solang-valley-koi-bhi-mat-aana-travellers-warning-amid-snow-chaos-in-himachal-pradesh-101735552086361.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:15:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['You took blankets from us & ...': Prashant Kishor's verbal spat with protesting students goes viral - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘You took blankets from us & ...’: Prashant Kishor's verbal spat with protesting students goes viral</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>An incident involving political strategist Prashant Kishor engaging in a heated exchange with protesting students has gained significant attention online, sparking discussions about political accountability and student activism.</p><ul><li>Kishor confronted students protesting against government policies.</li><li>The exchange included pointed remarks regarding student demands.</li><li>Social media platforms buzzed with reactions to the confrontation.</li></ul><blockquote>“You took blankets from us!” - Prashant Kishor during the confrontation.</blockquote><p>The confrontation highlights growing tensions between political figures and student activists, reflecting broader societal concerns.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/you-took-blankets-from-us-prashant-kishors-verbal-spat-with-protesting-students-go-viral/articleshow/116796084.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/you-took-blankets-from-us-prashant-kishors-verbal-spat-with-protesting-students-go-viral/articleshow/116796084.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FYUGP Calicut University 1st semester result 2024 out at results.uoc.ac.in; link here - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxQVHBxc3BWUXl6OXFIUTJHZi1nWm5KVGQ4Z1luemdHZWVWQ29RXzd6MWx3VUVrbzhSRVpZQzRQUVl5OUhNNVM2NjFMSFZZdmNIYWZCNWI3OEI2bDVuYXluSDVzaF9XRGhHMzNXaUN5QU01ZmJqTlMwOEZuazFUaTBVdUJDZnpJemQyRHA5dmVTb09zMmRyQ0FDcnpyTTBRNTF1b2FVRGVyejd5aHFrV1lJaDFhR2lCUXdhZkc1UFNHSXhRd0liTUpQekVOVzliNEozVWpzcXZn0gHbAUFVX3lxTE9DbkZ2RklHQlM2R3BDbTRETDRJMW9wSi1KVWNzQ0lSSzVNWGxabDRxSHM1dmpTTGRvWGh2UUxIUlpNWFREMHl0SVNINHdwTjNuc21WeEZ3ZGNPOHE2dXRveG9KZzdHM3piTkJ6Sm5QQUs3NVg2bEYyTVAtdzdNV3BPTHVja0VBTEFqZzhKUWZhWmE5c2M2X3g1eGZWdmViUU9IOVZ0c1JwZlF4akVXWG8wYWpFZ1VkaW9rMUpQWmptdV9ON3dZallUcWp0VVB2Y09kVnFmbk04Yk9mVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxQVHBxc3BWUXl6OXFIUTJHZi1nWm5KVGQ4Z1luemdHZWVWQ29RXzd6MWx3VUVrbzhSRVpZQzRQUVl5OUhNNVM2NjFMSFZZdmNIYWZCNWI3OEI2bDVuYXluSDVzaF9XRGhHMzNXaUN5QU01ZmJqTlMwOEZuazFUaTBVdUJDZnpJemQyRHA5dmVTb09zMmRyQ0FDcnpyTTBRNTF1b2FVRGVyejd5aHFrV1lJaDFhR2lCUXdhZkc1UFNHSXhRd0liTUpQekVOVzliNEozVWpzcXZn0gHbAUFVX3lxTE9DbkZ2RklHQlM2R3BDbTRETDRJMW9wSi1KVWNzQ0lSSzVNWGxabDRxSHM1dmpTTGRvWGh2UUxIUlpNWFREMHl0SVNINHdwTjNuc21WeEZ3ZGNPOHE2dXRveG9KZzdHM3piTkJ6Sm5QQUs3NVg2bEYyTVAtdzdNV3BPTHVja0VBTEFqZzhKUWZhWmE5c2M2X3g1eGZWdmViUU9IOVZ0c1JwZlF4akVXWG8wYWpFZ1VkaW9rMUpQWmptdV9ON3dZallUcWp0VVB2Y09kVnFmbk04Yk9mVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:56:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Air Force Airmen Group ‘Y’ Bharti Rally 2025 - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE1wSFlOSEZsZ25wdU1kX1V5VUlrNWN6bGRiYVNGeDdPNHIyUS15Ym1fbmdMcTcxTVNXVnhLcjVGaUV5NEIyLTA4R1BLUTMtOE43U2VFbnJfR3p2SEtMN2xKSE5FNmdHTEpPOXJTaXhKNjdWcFFTOUozSFpn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE1wSFlOSEZsZ25wdU1kX1V5VUlrNWN6bGRiYVNGeDdPNHIyUS15Ym1fbmdMcTcxTVNXVnhLcjVGaUV5NEIyLTA4R1BLUTMtOE43U2VFbnJfR3p2SEtMN2xKSE5FNmdHTEpPOXJTaXhKNjdWcFFTOUozSFpn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:56:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi exploited Manmohan Singh’s death for his expedient politics: BJP - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Accuses Rahul Gandhi of Exploiting Manmohan Singh’s Death for Political Gain</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/todays-paper/hkdptw/article69021046.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/INSIDE4_INTLP1_G82DORSJB.3.jpg.jpg" alt="Rahul Gandhi. File" title="Rahul Gandhi. File"><figcaption>Rahul Gandhi. File | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>The Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) launched a strong criticism of Congress leader Rahul Gandhi, alleging he exploited the death of former Prime Minister Dr. Manmohan Singh for political purposes while vacationing in Vietnam.</p><ul><li>BJP claims Rahul Gandhi exploited Dr. Singh's death for his own political advantage.</li><li>Congress criticized the BJP for diverting attention from key issues of governance.</li><li>BJP's Amit Malviya accused Gandhi of showing contempt for Singh and recalled historical grievances.</li><li>Congress leader Manickam Tagore rebuked the BJP, highlighting the shameful treatment of Singh's family.</li></ul><blockquote>“Mr. Gandhi politicised and exploited Dr. Singh’s death for his expedient politics but his contempt for him is unmissable.” - Amit Malviya, BJP IT cell head</blockquote><p>The political confrontation underscores the contentious atmosphere surrounding the legacy of Dr. Singh in Indian politics and highlights ongoing party rivalries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rahul-gandhi-exploited-manmohan-singhs-death-for-his-expedient-politics-bjp/article69042840.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/rahul-gandhi-exploited-manmohan-singhs-death-for-his-expedient-politics-bjp/article69042840.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab Bandh LIVE updates: Farmers' call shows impact in Haryana, public transport impacted - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Punjab Bandh LIVE updates: Farmers' call shows impact in Haryana, public transport impacted</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/PTI12-30-2024-000038B-0_1735535809229_1735535828785.jpg" alt="Punjab Bandh Live Updates: Farmers raise slogans as they block a road during the statewide 'bandh' called as part their ongoing protest, near Golden Gate, in Amritsar on Monday." title="Punjab Bandh Live Updates: Farmers raise slogans as they block a road during the statewide 'bandh' called as part their ongoing protest, near Golden Gate, in Amritsar on Monday."><figcaption>Punjab Bandh Live Updates: Farmers raise slogans as they block a road during the statewide 'bandh' called as part their ongoing protest, near Golden Gate, in Amritsar on Monday.</figcaption></img><p>The farmers in Punjab are observing a bandh as part of their continuous agitation for increased MSP and other demands. The protests have severely affected traffic on both roads and railways, particularly impacting neighboring Haryana.</p><ul><li>Over 200 trains have been canceled or rescheduled due to the bandh.</li><li>The bandh is from 7 AM to 4 PM, with emergency services remaining operational.</li><li>Protestors have organized community meals for commuters affected by the disruptions.</li><li>Farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal is on a hunger strike, having entered the 35th day.</li><li>The bandh has led to significant blockades across Punjab, with more than 280 reported.</li></ul><blockquote>“Farming is not our profession as Punjabis, it is our religion…” - Amrinder Singh Raja Warring, Ludhiana MP.</blockquote><p>The ongoing protests highlight the farmers' demands for legal guarantees on crop MSP, debt waivers, pensions for agricultural workers, and various other issues that affect their livelihoods.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/punjab-bandh-today-live-updates-farmers-protest-skm-kisan-mazdoor-morcha-30th-december-traffic-hit-101735535362493.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/punjab-bandh-today-live-updates-farmers-protest-skm-kisan-mazdoor-morcha-30th-december-traffic-hit-101735535362493.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:41:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minor BTS fans stage their kidnapping to fulfil dream of travelling to South Korea and meeting group members - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Minor BTS Fans Stage Kidnapping to Meet K-Pop Idols</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/BTS_1735546655895_1735546656132.webp" alt="South Korea's biggest musical group, BTS" title="South Korea's biggest musical group, BTS"><figcaption>South Korea's biggest musical group, BTS</figcaption><p>Three minor girls from Maharashtra staged their own kidnapping to gather money for a trip to South Korea to meet BTS members.</p><ul><li>The girls, aged 11 and 13, planned to travel to Pune for work to fund their trip.</li><li>They were reported missing when a call to the police claimed they were forcibly taken in a school van.</li><li>Police tracked them down on a bus headed to Pune with the help of local informants.</li><li>The girls admitted to the plan to earn money for meeting BTS.</li></ul><blockquote>“We had a plan to go to Pune, work there and earn money to go to South Korea.”</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the lengths to which fans may go to pursue their dreams and meet their idols.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/minor-bts-fans-stage-their-kidnapping-to-fulfil-dream-of-travelling-to-south-korea-and-meeting-group-members-101735545207836.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/music/minor-bts-fans-stage-their-kidnapping-to-fulfil-dream-of-travelling-to-south-korea-and-meeting-group-members-101735545207836.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Odisha will extend damage compensation to non-paddy farmers: Revenue Minister - OTV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Odisha will extend damage compensation to non-paddy farmers: Revenue Minister</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> OTV News</p><img src="https://images.odishatv.in/uploadimage/library/16_9/16_9_0/recent_photo_1735545804.webp" alt="Odisha will extend damage compensation to non-paddy farmers: Revenue Minister" title="Odisha will extend damage compensation to non-paddy farmers: Revenue Minister" width="916" height="515"><figcaption>Photo: OTV</figcaption><p>Revenue Minister Suresh Pujari announced that compensation for crop losses due to recent heavy rainfall will be offered to all affected farmers, including those not growing paddy.</p><ul><li>Crops including vegetables, cotton, and groundnuts have been affected.</li><li>About 2 lakh farmers have filed claims with insurance companies.</li><li>The government warned insurers against taking advantage of farmers.</li><li>A district-level damage assessment report is expected soon.</li><li>No farmer will be excluded from receiving compensation.</li></ul><blockquote>“The state government will utilize every lawful tool at its disposal to ensure that no farmer suffers extreme losses.” – Suresh Pujari</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical as reports of farmers taking drastic actions due to crop loss have emerged, highlighting the urgent need for comprehensive support.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/odisha-will-extend-damage-compensation-to-non-paddy-farmer-revenue-minister-252281</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/odisha-will-extend-damage-compensation-to-non-paddy-farmer-revenue-minister-252281</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:05:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun stampede case: Decision on counter police affidavit opposing the bail pushed to January 3 - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun Stampede Case Update: Bail Decision Delayed to January 3</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116792657,imgsize-151344,width-400,resizemode-4/116792657.jpg" alt="Allu Arjun stampede case: Decision on counter police affidavit opposing the bail pushed to January 3" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Allu Arjun related to the stampede case.</figcaption><p>A Hyderabad court has postponed the verdict on the bail application of actor Allu Arjun in connection to the Pushpa 2 stampede case to January 3.</p><ul><li>Allu Arjun was involved in a stampede incident during the premiere of 'Pushpa-2' where a woman died and her son was injured.</li><li>The actor appeared via video conference as the hearing for his bail came up.</li><li>He was arrested on December 13 and granted interim bail on December 14.</li><li>The police sought time to oppose his bail, leading to a new hearing date set for December 30.</li></ul><blockquote>“A 35-year-old woman died and her eight-year-old son was injured on December 4 during a stampede-like situation.”</blockquote><p>The court's decision on this high-profile case is anticipated as it involves serious allegations and public interest.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/telugu/movies/news/allu-arjun-stampede-case-decision-on-counter-police-affidavit-opposing-the-bail-pushed-to-january-3/articleshow/116792667.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/telugu/movies/news/allu-arjun-stampede-case-decision-on-counter-police-affidavit-opposing-the-bail-pushed-to-january-3/articleshow/116792667.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi polls: Kejriwal announces scheme to give ₹18,000 per month to priests, granthis - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Introduces ₹18,000 Monthly Scheme for Priests Ahead of Delhi Elections</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p>
<img alt="Delhi polls: Kejriwal announces scheme to give ₹18,000 per month to priests, granthis" title="Delhi polls: Kejriwal announces scheme to give ₹18,000 per month to priests, granthis" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Kejriwal announces a scheme for priests and granthis in Delhi.</figcaption>
<p>Arvind Kejriwal has announced the Pujari Granthi Samman Yojana, promising ₹18,000 per month to priests and granthis if AAP wins the upcoming elections. This initiative is part of his broader Revdi Par Charcha campaign aimed at securing voter support.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The scheme aims to honor temple priests and granthis in Delhi.</li>
  <li>Kejriwal described the payment as a token of respect rather than a salary.</li>
  <li>Registration for the scheme starts on December 31 at Hanuman Temple, Connaught Place.</li>
  <li>Other promised initiatives include enhancements in welfare schemes, healthcare improvements, and assistance for the middle class.</li>
  <li>Kejriwal has announced free healthcare for seniors, increased financial aid for women, and various guarantees for rickshaw drivers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Kejriwal stated, "A priest is a part of all of our family occasions... happy or sad; they are the ones who have carried forward the rituals from generation to generation. However, they have never paid attention to their families... and neither have we."</blockquote>
<p>This announcement is part of AAP's strategy to maintain power in the upcoming Delhi Assembly elections, focusing on fulfilling basic needs of citizens.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/politics/delhi-polls-kejriwal-announces-scheme-to-give-rs-18000-per-month-to-priests-granthis-19531543.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/politics/delhi-polls-kejriwal-announces-scheme-to-give-rs-18000-per-month-to-priests-granthis-19531543.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘You take blankets from us and then show us attitude’: Heated exchange between Prashant Kishor and BPSC aspirants - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Heated Exchange Between Prashant Kishor and BPSC Aspirants</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: Dec 30, 2024</strong> <br> Source: Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/20241229-PAT-SK-MN---Protest--32-0_1735544871976_1735544882711.JPG" alt="Jan Suraj Party founder Prashant Kishore addressing BPSC candidates during blocking road at JP roundabout in Patna. (Santosh Kumar/ Hindustan Times)">
<figcaption>Jan Suraj Party founder Prashant Kishore addressing BPSC candidates during blocking road at JP roundabout in Patna. (Santosh Kumar/ Hindustan Times)</figcaption>
<p>BPSC aspirants protested at Gandhi Maidan, demanding a re-examination of the 70th BPSC preliminary exam and a meeting with Nitish Kumar. A heated exchange occurred between students and Prashant Kishor when aspirants accused him of being absent during police action against the protesters.</p>
<ul>
<li>Students accused Kishor of being absent when police used water cannons and batons against them.</li>
<li>Kishor arrived at the scene and faced angry protesters who demanded he step away.</li>
<li>Kishor's remark, "You take blankets from us and then show us attitude," escalated tensions.</li>
<li>The protest began on Dec 13, gaining support from politicians, educationists, and activists.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Protesters asked, "Where was Prashant Kishor during the lathicharge?"</blockquote>
<p>After his eviction, Kishor addressed a press conference, refuting allegations, reaffirming support for the students' cause, and condemning police action. He plans to file an FIR against Patna Police and join the protest if no resolution is reached.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/you-take-blankets-from-us-and-then-show-us-attitude-heated-exchange-between-prashant-kishor-and-bpsc-aspirants-101735543658502.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/you-take-blankets-from-us-and-then-show-us-attitude-heated-exchange-between-prashant-kishor-and-bpsc-aspirants-101735543658502.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:53:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra minister Nitesh Rane sparks controversy with 'Mini Pakistan' comment on Kerala - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitesh Rane labels Kerala 'Mini Pakistan', Congress questions induction in Maha cabinet</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p><figure><img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116791608,width-300,height-225,imgsize-184978,resizemode-75,rect-176_147_1216_912/maharashtra-minister-nitesh-rane.jpg" alt="Maharashtra minister Nitesh Rane"><figcaption>Maharashtra minister Nitesh Rane</figcaption></figure><p>Maharashtra minister Nitesh Rane made a controversial statement by comparing Kerala to 'Mini Pakistan', suggesting that Congress leaders Rahul Gandhi and Priyanka Gandhi Vadra garner support from terrorists.</p><ul><li>Nitesh Rane's comments were made during a rally in Purandar Taluka, Pune.</li><li>Rane claimed that terrorists vote for Rahul and Priyanka Gandhi, influencing their election to Parliament.</li><li>Congress spokesperson Atul Londhe Patil criticized Rane, questioning his position in the cabinet and accusing him of spreading communalism.</li><li>Rane is the minister for fisheries and ports following the recent Maharashtra assembly elections.</li></ul><blockquote>Rane stated, "Kerala is mini Pakistan that is why Rahul Gandhi and his sister are elected from there. All terrorists vote for them."</blockquote><p>The controversy highlights ongoing political tensions in Maharashtra and raises questions about rhetoric used by politicians.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/politics-and-nation/nitesh-rane-labels-kerala-mini-pakistan-congress-questions-induction-in-maha-cabinet/articleshow/116791446.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/politics-and-nation/nitesh-rane-labels-kerala-mini-pakistan-congress-questions-induction-in-maha-cabinet/articleshow/116791446.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:34:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chandigarh-Delhi airfare soars from Rs 3,000 to Rs 19,000 amid Punjab bandh - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxNdkwyaDZPMXpUTC1OckxUWHRGVlNaUDZEeDBGbVhneGVYbVVWNFB5QWxPQlpzLThTT2R1b25idzQwNFZzZEM4X3BPVldsMGJMd2pPRkZwTk1tVUxuTXIwN2NYaVZKNU9rOE13T0M1X3RPdWMzblFVOWxMcjhhSW9NVWU0YTVmTmwwa0dTOVlROGFqc1ZaMkp4NTl1bjFUVW0wcjR6dXl1N2liQ0FZbkQxWjVwTi1FelZXSTZN0gG_AUFVX3lxTE1IMGFSOHp5S0ZQMXRMODZGd01ocXNQXzNZSjlZLXJhdUp5anN0YkhaemV6SFJIZXI1Ml9nbmlVQnBpcTlNYWMtYnREQXpXNTd1cUZLWnhJdWZRYWx0RFNjZnZPVUpCZHNPamZPSUpoLWJRd2JjbXhDbXBRNkhqSE5hdTRHZUhHLXlab1h6cndWY2plLTVIM0JQRS1DNUY0dUdNdU9hY1ZMTW8taDVKbzdzSWJlOXR4T1NSUUhhREZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxNdkwyaDZPMXpUTC1OckxUWHRGVlNaUDZEeDBGbVhneGVYbVVWNFB5QWxPQlpzLThTT2R1b25idzQwNFZzZEM4X3BPVldsMGJMd2pPRkZwTk1tVUxuTXIwN2NYaVZKNU9rOE13T0M1X3RPdWMzblFVOWxMcjhhSW9NVWU0YTVmTmwwa0dTOVlROGFqc1ZaMkp4NTl1bjFUVW0wcjR6dXl1N2liQ0FZbkQxWjVwTi1FelZXSTZN0gG_AUFVX3lxTE1IMGFSOHp5S0ZQMXRMODZGd01ocXNQXzNZSjlZLXJhdUp5anN0YkhaemV6SFJIZXI1Ml9nbmlVQnBpcTlNYWMtYnREQXpXNTd1cUZLWnhJdWZRYWx0RFNjZnZPVUpCZHNPamZPSUpoLWJRd2JjbXhDbXBRNkhqSE5hdTRHZUhHLXlab1h6cndWY2plLTVIM0JQRS1DNUY0dUdNdU9hY1ZMTW8taDVKbzdzSWJlOXR4T1NSUUhhREZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:07:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Deference to privacy': Congress shares why Gandhi family didn't accompany Manmohan Singh’s kin for immer - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/deference-to-privacy-congress-shares-why-gandhi-family-didnt-accompany-manmohan-singhs-kin-for-immersion-of-ashes/articleshow/116789155.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/deference-to-privacy-congress-shares-why-gandhi-family-didnt-accompany-manmohan-singhs-kin-for-immersion-of-ashes/articleshow/116789155.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Deference to privacy': Congress shares why Gandhi family didn't accompany Manmohan Singh’s kin for immersion of ashes - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Explains Gandhi Family's Absence at Manmohan Singh’s Ashes Immersion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>The Congress party has addressed the absence of the Gandhi family during the immersion of the ashes of Manmohan Singh's kin, emphasizing their respect for privacy.</p><ul><li>The Gandhi family did not attend the ceremony to maintain privacy.</li><li>Congress leaders expressed their understanding of the situation and highlighted the importance of privacy in such personal matters.</li><li>The event raised questions about the family's involvement in significant political and social rituals.</li></ul><blockquote>“Respect for privacy is fundamental in times of personal loss.”</blockquote><p>This incident reinforces the need for privacy during sensitive family events, particularly within political families.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/deference-to-privacy-congress-shares-why-gandhi-family-didnt-accompany-manmohan-singhs-kin-for-immersion-of-ashes/articleshow/116789155.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/deference-to-privacy-congress-shares-why-gandhi-family-didnt-accompany-manmohan-singhs-kin-for-immersion-of-ashes/articleshow/116789155.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Row Over Schemes, Arvind Kejriwal Launches New 'Yojana' For Priests, To Give Rs 18,000 A Month - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arvind Kejriwal's New 'Yojana' Promises Rs 18k A Month To Priests Amid Women's Scheme Row</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Last Updated: December 30, 2024, 18:42 IST</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)" title="Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)"><figcaption>Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)</figcaption><p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal on Monday announced a new scheme, 'Pujari Granthi Samman Yojana', under which the priests of temples and the 'granthis' of the Gurudwara will be paid a monthly honorarium of nearly Rs 18,000. This announcement comes just two months before the Delhi Assembly polls, with the BJP reacting sharply and calling it a 'deception'.</p><ul><li>Kejriwal's new scheme aims to benefit priests and granthis.</li><li>The BJP has criticized the announcement, saying it is a pre-election stunt.</li><li>The 'Mahila Samman Yojana' row, involving allegations of data fraud and election interference, remains a contentious issue.</li></ul><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="hi">…</p></blockquote><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The announcement of the 'Pujari Granthi Samman Yojana' has sparked a political row in Delhi, with the BJP calling it a deceptive move by the AAP. The upcoming Assembly polls have brought various schemes and promises to the forefront, with both parties trying to gain an edge.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/elections/delhi-polls-arvind-kejriwal-announces-pujari-granthi-samman-yojana-benefits-rs-18000-as-monthly-honorarium-9172376.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/elections/delhi-polls-arvind-kejriwal-announces-pujari-granthi-samman-yojana-benefits-rs-18000-as-monthly-honorarium-9172376.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:59:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Row Over Schemes, Kejriwal Launches New 'Yojana' For Priests, To Give Rs 18,000 A Month - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arvind Kejriwal's 'Pujari Granthi Samman Yojana': Rs 18k Honorarium for Priests and Granthis</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Last Updated: December 30, 2024, 18:42 IST, <a href="https://www.news18.com/">News18</a></p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&width=360&height=270" alt="Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)" title="Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)">
<figcaption>Former Delhi CM Arvind Kejriwal (PTI Image)</figcaption>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Ahead of the upcoming Delhi Assembly polls, Arvind Kejriwal, the chief of Aam Aadmi Party (AAP), has announced the 'Pujari Granthi Samman Yojana', which promises a monthly honorarium of nearly Rs 18,000 to priests of temples and 'granthis' of the Gurudwara.</p>
<ul><li>Kejriwal's announcement comes amidst a row surrounding the 'Mahila Samman Yojana', another welfare scheme by AAP.</li><li>The BJP has criticized the new scheme, calling it 'deception'.</li></ul>
<blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="hi">... (Kejriwal's tweet on the scheme)</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The implementation of this scheme, if AAP wins the elections, would mark a significant step towards recognizing and rewarding the contributions of priests and granthis in Delhi's religious and cultural landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/elections/delhi-polls-arvind-kejriwal-announces-pujari-granthi-samman-yojana-benefits-rs-18000-as-monthly-honorarium-9172376.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/elections/delhi-polls-arvind-kejriwal-announces-pujari-granthi-samman-yojana-benefits-rs-18000-as-monthly-honorarium-9172376.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:59:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh funeral: Congress says party leaders did not accompany his family out of deference to their privacy - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxOMzg5a0NLeEU3RVZ6UE5hY0p6RHVoSjlOTTd4TVRjbG9GNHUtZ2pDdU80bEZYdmtZN1lpb0ItMGtWYm1hdFlSdEVNZE9oWnVHa2hNTThPOTRGNUZ6TkRienRHNkh2RnZuazlKczk3aTlQTVZlUURLaFoyNDBPN1ZfbGl1dFRXQzgtQlBFMXVad0s2cENjXzhQZERCTkl5UXQ5a1NXVENWQnJIRWFXbUtERkxJMFhlSGZUN0ZkMmVrblc4azVpWkHSAcwBQVVfeXFMTzItM0hsLWhnOVBLSFlVRzJyWk5GMEpHeWpqYzRhSkZwNHF3bC1yNUNKT3AxSFFpb0R6d2tCbjBpLUNNSWcwREJyUmE2a0R4WlJ6OGxaYXM3NmtJZzhpMm1DUjlpVzNfMll1eTB1UEdVeFBXcjBzNlZhNFlNckVxNEpMNEd3RkM5YUVOZDk1SkgzcUtuVFV6R2U3WEIxOVFhTDVIc2MzUjVQdFRPRUN5UGk5emJGbHY0c0VOLVZQZ0FYc3Y4OUxhRkU4dmNz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxOMzg5a0NLeEU3RVZ6UE5hY0p6RHVoSjlOTTd4TVRjbG9GNHUtZ2pDdU80bEZYdmtZN1lpb0ItMGtWYm1hdFlSdEVNZE9oWnVHa2hNTThPOTRGNUZ6TkRienRHNkh2RnZuazlKczk3aTlQTVZlUURLaFoyNDBPN1ZfbGl1dFRXQzgtQlBFMXVad0s2cENjXzhQZERCTkl5UXQ5a1NXVENWQnJIRWFXbUtERkxJMFhlSGZUN0ZkMmVrblc4azVpWkHSAcwBQVVfeXFMTzItM0hsLWhnOVBLSFlVRzJyWk5GMEpHeWpqYzRhSkZwNHF3bC1yNUNKT3AxSFFpb0R6d2tCbjBpLUNNSWcwREJyUmE2a0R4WlJ6OGxaYXM3NmtJZzhpMm1DUjlpVzNfMll1eTB1UEdVeFBXcjBzNlZhNFlNckVxNEpMNEd3RkM5YUVOZDk1SkgzcUtuVFV6R2U3WEIxOVFhTDVIc2MzUjVQdFRPRUN5UGk5emJGbHY0c0VOLVZQZ0FYc3Y4OUxhRkU4dmNz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uma Thomas MLA who sustained injuries in accidental fall to continue on ventilator support: Medical bulletin - Onmanorama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxOcy1SQUIyZFhkTEtxTnBtRXFvRlN4NGFWbnEwUlpja1A0SFFRb3dEWmxPazRVWmpSTTJXRDRUUFFhXzlmLUJycFZxRDAyUllISVJqYVVZYTE3R3BtTDBxLXJnMS1zeWVFNzgzQ3c3T3ZrRW1vdkk4dUhOSWFjc3JOS05LTmhtUHZOQTB2Y2F2bHB4QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxOcy1SQUIyZFhkTEtxTnBtRXFvRlN4NGFWbnEwUlpja1A0SFFRb3dEWmxPazRVWmpSTTJXRDRUUFFhXzlmLUJycFZxRDAyUllISVJqYVVZYTE3R3BtTDBxLXJnMS1zeWVFNzgzQ3c3T3ZrRW1vdkk4dUhOSWFjc3JOS05LTmhtUHZOQTB2Y2F2bHB4QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:24:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diljit Dosanjh dedicates Guwahati concert to Manmohan Singh - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNRU95X0VuM3V4cFlxS3RlQ004b1ZsdWdzZDQ2eGpVWFotd0hrNGdfamRZSWxyRXNVaXVSUHVYUDNMdjh0WXRFb1VaN2xZTmxyVHlvTXQ1bXdfc19QWGgweXNWTHJiMXBSS0NLYjlCaU9hVzlaS0Q4QkJMVXE2b2dFOFBkUVJWaHBpNmdneGVCNWVRU2p6ZXFHbC1SMTUyR3dsWFp1OUZhUy1faHJa0gGwAUFVX3lxTE1KU2tPV2h4anBJckJ3RXBWbHRIWDZscTZ3VDlRSUUwMGdqNm9sTnNPN2haZC1PVEExbU5Udk9PaFRtdnNteGJCVTJPTDNUNDZGSWJrV19pY0h2WUZwWVRRNUNEdTJyR0QtcFFnOVNfWlhPOGVxQ3Rsd1JnRzZzRndsdV9KUWxWeUdPYXZyZThaYUlrX2JkamFIOEFJY3ItcWlzR18xU2NtM0o0WmRQTXp6?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNRU95X0VuM3V4cFlxS3RlQ004b1ZsdWdzZDQ2eGpVWFotd0hrNGdfamRZSWxyRXNVaXVSUHVYUDNMdjh0WXRFb1VaN2xZTmxyVHlvTXQ1bXdfc19QWGgweXNWTHJiMXBSS0NLYjlCaU9hVzlaS0Q4QkJMVXE2b2dFOFBkUVJWaHBpNmdneGVCNWVRU2p6ZXFHbC1SMTUyR3dsWFp1OUZhUy1faHJa0gGwAUFVX3lxTE1KU2tPV2h4anBJckJ3RXBWbHRIWDZscTZ3VDlRSUUwMGdqNm9sTnNPN2haZC1PVEExbU5Udk9PaFRtdnNteGJCVTJPTDNUNDZGSWJrV19pY0h2WUZwWVRRNUNEdTJyR0QtcFFnOVNfWlhPOGVxQ3Rsd1JnRzZzRndsdV9KUWxWeUdPYXZyZThaYUlrX2JkamFIOEFJY3ItcWlzR18xU2NtM0o0WmRQTXp6?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:21:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moderate snowfall likely in J&K on Jan 4, 5: MeT - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxOVlBEOWNsbVljQW1sd3RJRXc1cXpUQ0xnOE04dTdfSXJfX1ZqTjVrcndkSEJXdXZIYTlucHRuQV9EZVo4cEVRRFJyU1JfdkhGalgwakV6WldranZwTllBeWw5NXBBY0w0Ri01UEpDdm1wLXU3SEQ5S1BQYk82RDVuV2dtOWVMS3Y4TmNMRnVWa1dKazF3TWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxOVlBEOWNsbVljQW1sd3RJRXc1cXpUQ0xnOE04dTdfSXJfX1ZqTjVrcndkSEJXdXZIYTlucHRuQV9EZVo4cEVRRFJyU1JfdkhGalgwakV6WldranZwTllBeWw5NXBBY0w0Ri01UEpDdm1wLXU3SEQ5S1BQYk82RDVuV2dtOWVMS3Y4TmNMRnVWa1dKazF3TWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:21:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In pictures, from Amritsar’s Golden Gate to Punjab villages, farmers bandh cripples life - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxQNF9hWEY3V1JYSmRUdDVtZDk5NGR4VjgxazZja21BNkE2M1Z3SmV1bC1WNHRwRDJYWHFITTVpS3p4X2RZcXNDaE9kN3pJdnRVRXBUSzNSTUtzUG9UY29WQ253aG5EX2UxbFc5SEJWRkdIbUFJVVJ1YTZZZGJlcWhycmpUS2ZFOFp4a2p0YWo1YlBtZ3BZRWNXbFplZjB5N3ZLVXRjbHQwb0NLNDZsZTJ5SHVCWV9sZ3NDR18wQzIzVGlRS3VtOWR4SERVY3o2c3VTWkFnNVZzVmtPd9IB3gFBVV95cUxPeGdtXzJpZVhXanVueElGZUVhTEZ6RUNjT0tscnk5MFhsQ3ZOcW1jYW94X20zWUwtWkx3Rkt6aTVTSXJTS01kaGx3REtzVXZjR1Rfd3ByelZma3BEbVJlNU1UWmFrTGRsMFJOZmd1QlJYUXJONjAxMlZkbm5YdVdDSkkxZ0FDWk01dko4OWl0YzlTOVEzTkVleTJFdGU2Qmozbkc1SG80YjQyWFRwOG8tOE1sTTYtYXRoaXdjZ3A1emVqMFlSVUVaOTRZNzRYX3ktYXhpaUlnYXJKSUFFVFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxQNF9hWEY3V1JYSmRUdDVtZDk5NGR4VjgxazZja21BNkE2M1Z3SmV1bC1WNHRwRDJYWHFITTVpS3p4X2RZcXNDaE9kN3pJdnRVRXBUSzNSTUtzUG9UY29WQ253aG5EX2UxbFc5SEJWRkdIbUFJVVJ1YTZZZGJlcWhycmpUS2ZFOFp4a2p0YWo1YlBtZ3BZRWNXbFplZjB5N3ZLVXRjbHQwb0NLNDZsZTJ5SHVCWV9sZ3NDR18wQzIzVGlRS3VtOWR4SERVY3o2c3VTWkFnNVZzVmtPd9IB3gFBVV95cUxPeGdtXzJpZVhXanVueElGZUVhTEZ6RUNjT0tscnk5MFhsQ3ZOcW1jYW94X20zWUwtWkx3Rkt6aTVTSXJTS01kaGx3REtzVXZjR1Rfd3ByelZma3BEbVJlNU1UWmFrTGRsMFJOZmd1QlJYUXJONjAxMlZkbm5YdVdDSkkxZ0FDWk01dko4OWl0YzlTOVEzTkVleTJFdGU2Qmozbkc1SG80YjQyWFRwOG8tOE1sTTYtYXRoaXdjZ3A1emVqMFlSVUVaOTRZNzRYX3ktYXhpaUlnYXJKSUFFVFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:19:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manipur violence: Security forces destroy four bunkers after gunfights - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manipur Violence: Security Forces Destroy Four Bunkers After Gunfights</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source: December 30, 2024, The Hindu</strong></p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/7feyfh/article69042296.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_CRPF_deployed_at_Gam_2_1_6FDO62K9.jpg" alt="Security forces deployed in Manipur">
<figcaption>A file image of CRPF personnel in Manipur | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption>
<p>Security forces have destroyed four bunkers and occupied three others in Manipur's Imphal East and Kangpokpi districts following gunfights with armed miscreants, police said on Monday. The operations were conducted in areas bordering Thamnapokpi and Sanasabi villages where gunfights took place.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Four illegal bunkers have been destroyed.</li>
  <li>Three bunkers have been occupied by security forces.</li>
  <li>The dominant areas in Uyok Ching in Kangpokpi district have also been occupied.</li>
</ul>
<p>On Friday, four persons, including police personnel and a woman, were injured in gun attacks in Thamnapokpi and Sanasabi villages. More than 250 people have been killed and thousands rendered homeless in ethnic violence between Meiteis and Kuki-Zo groups in Manipur since May last year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manipur/security-forces-destroy-four-bunkers-after-gunfights-in-manipur/article69042275.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manipur/security-forces-destroy-four-bunkers-after-gunfights-in-manipur/article69042275.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Security forces destroy four bunkers after gunfights in Manipur - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Security forces destroy four bunkers after gunfights in Manipur</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/7feyfh/article69042296.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_CRPF_deployed_at_Gam_2_1_6FDO62K9.jpg" alt="A file image of CRPF personnel in Manipur" title="A file image of CRPF personnel in Manipur"><figcaption>A file image of CRPF personnel in Manipur | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>Security forces in Manipur have successfully destroyed four bunkers used by gunmen following intense gunfights in the region. The operations took place in Imphal East and Kangpokpi districts, with authorities reporting major security advancements.</p><ul><li>Four gunman bunkers were destroyed, while three were occupied by security forces.</li><li>The operations were focused in Thamnapokpi and Sanasabi villages, where multiple gunfights occurred.</li><li>Injuries reported included four individuals, among them police personnel.</li><li>The conflict in the area has led to severe ethnic violence, with over 250 casualties since May 2023.</li></ul><blockquote>“All armed miscreants involved in recent firing incidents at Thamnapokpi and Sanasabi have been flushed out.”</blockquote><p>The ongoing military operations highlight the escalating situation in Manipur, stemming from ethnic violence that has left many dead and displaced. Continued efforts are crucial for restoring peace in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manipur/security-forces-destroy-four-bunkers-after-gunfights-in-manipur/article69042275.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manipur/security-forces-destroy-four-bunkers-after-gunfights-in-manipur/article69042275.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>