<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 01:48:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 01:48:44 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra portfolio allocation: Devendra Fadnavis keeps home, Ajit finance, Shinde urban development, g - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maharashtra portfolio allocation: Fadnavis retains home ministry, Ajit retains finance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The recent allocation of portfolios in Maharashtra sees Devendra Fadnavis retaining the important home ministry, while Ajit Pawar takes over the finance department. Eknath Shinde has been assigned urban development, and the housing portfolio is also a crucial part of the new allocations.</p><ul><li>Devendra Fadnavis remains the home minister.</li><li>Ajit Pawar has been given the finance portfolio.</li><li>Eknath Shinde is responsible for urban development.</li><li>The housing portfolio is now with Fadnavis.</li></ul><blockquote>“This allocation is essential for maintaining stability in the government and addressing the needs of the people.”</blockquote><p>This allocation is set to impact the governance and service delivery in Maharashtra as the state navigates various challenges ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/maharashtra-portfolio-allocation-devendra-fadnavis-keeps-home-ajit-finance-shinde-urban-development-gets-housing/articleshow/116548370.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/maharashtra-portfolio-allocation-devendra-fadnavis-keeps-home-ajit-finance-shinde-urban-development-gets-housing/articleshow/116548370.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 20:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra portfolio allocation: Fadnavis keeps home | Full list of ministers - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maharashtra Portfolio Allocation: CM Fadnavis Retains Home Department</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Saturday | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/ANI-20241221237-0_1734810222209_1734810290640.jpg' alt='Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis addresses the press conference on the last day of the Winter Session of State Assembly, in the presence of State Deputy Chief Minister Eknath Shinde, at Vidhan Bhavan, in Nagpur on Saturday. (ANI)' title='Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis addresses the press conference on the last day of the Winter Session of State Assembly, in the presence of State Deputy Chief Minister Eknath Shinde, at Vidhan Bhavan, in Nagpur on Saturday. (ANI)'><figcaption>Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis addresses the press conference on the last day of the Winter Session of State Assembly, in the presence of State Deputy Chief Minister Eknath Shinde, at Vidhan Bhavan, in Nagpur on Saturday. (ANI)</figcaption><p>Following more than two weeks since taking office, Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis announced the allocation of portfolios to his council of ministers. He has retained significant departments including Home, Energy, Law and Judiciary, and General Administration.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Devendra Fadnavis retains the Home Department.</li><li>Deputy Chief Minister Eknath Shinde receives Urban Development and Housing portfolios.</li><li>Ajit Pawar, NCP chief and Deputy Chief Minister, is assigned Finance and Planning.</li><li>Comprehensive list of ministers and their respective portfolios released.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics</h2><blockquote>“This allocation will ensure effective governance and service delivery in Maharashtra,” Fadnavis stated during the press conference.</blockquote><p>Overall, this portfolio allocation is essential in shaping the governance structure of Maharashtra under Fadnavis's leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maharashtra-portfolio-allocation-fadnavis-keeps-home-full-list-of-ministers-101734804550841.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maharashtra-portfolio-allocation-fadnavis-keeps-home-full-list-of-ministers-101734804550841.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 19:49:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delayed Exams, Holiday: Students Behind Bomb Threats To 3 Delhi Schools, Say Cops - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Students Behind Bomb Threats to Three Delhi Schools, Police Say</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/h6stfg18_police-in-school-ani_625x300_06_May_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="Delayed Exams, Holiday: Students Behind Bomb Threats To 3 Delhi Schools, Say Cops"><figcaption>Students are behind the bomb threats to the schools.</figcaption><p>The Delhi Police have identified that bomb threats sent to three schools were orchestrated by the students themselves, who sought to postpone exams. The police have conducted counseling and warned the parents of the involved students.</p><ul><li>Three Delhi schools received bomb threat emails linked to their own students.</li><li>The students sent the emails to postpone exams after a recent explosion in Rohini.</li><li>The police declared the threats as hoaxes after investigations.</li><li>Over 100 bomb threats have targeted Delhi schools in the past 11 days.</li></ul><blockquote>“The emails were sent through a VPN, making it difficult to trace the perpetrators.”</blockquote><p>This situation highlights a concerning trend of students resorting to bomb threats as a means of manipulating school schedules.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/delayed-exams-holiday-students-behind-bomb-threats-to-3-delhi-schools-say-cops-7303391</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/delayed-exams-holiday-students-behind-bomb-threats-to-3-delhi-schools-say-cops-7303391</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 18:13:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahayuti Portfolio Announcement Live Updates: CM Fadnavis retains Home, Ajit holds on to Finance, Shinde gets urban development - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxNRkJQYUVVZUxqcDY0dlBYTWJITHFOaWVsVEQ5c1Fwa2dUbWh3UU81WW51bExkRzRCeUpsQzQ0UUI2ZXpnOWdDQmZlbmNZV2dYVU5hbFYyaWJybklkQUNmQm4zZ3JZLUVsWF9MVGh3azllNHh0S1dicUh4TG1iV3ZSRWpRa0ZNUnYycVNNaXp1bkNRcHBURXV0NGdsM2RxQmhFSS1HZ3VRTEFacnFpNjFFbTRKZlcxbDNxQ2xzUG03RjhMNDZNNEVMOV84dHpIMzdZSmFITUVXM0phWUs0YXfSAeQBQVVfeXFMTjNBN0RuVzhLQzFjZzFmYkp3NFRlM1lVNE55eXMwLTBKSjVoNmYwWm5KTUlYeGM3cjVoVjVKLTFUN0YtWVNuUnAwRjdkd085a1BhUjdPaWxvOGE1T2pSNnFfMTFzcGNzQU1rLWtISkxSS3BvUVdHYzBEc2x4d0NVYUZRdDVuZ0g4Mm1oeW8tZ2laYTFudl9MWTdTOEhtajRFaHBWcEZwZDJncENXT0EyVEwtdDZVdmh5LXZCMFBzM203cHZzMkUwNXhNNFN4dmxmZUM1anlkdy1hc3VXOVktZ3hqdUM3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxNRkJQYUVVZUxqcDY0dlBYTWJITHFOaWVsVEQ5c1Fwa2dUbWh3UU81WW51bExkRzRCeUpsQzQ0UUI2ZXpnOWdDQmZlbmNZV2dYVU5hbFYyaWJybklkQUNmQm4zZ3JZLUVsWF9MVGh3azllNHh0S1dicUh4TG1iV3ZSRWpRa0ZNUnYycVNNaXp1bkNRcHBURXV0NGdsM2RxQmhFSS1HZ3VRTEFacnFpNjFFbTRKZlcxbDNxQ2xzUG03RjhMNDZNNEVMOV84dHpIMzdZSmFITUVXM0phWUs0YXfSAeQBQVVfeXFMTjNBN0RuVzhLQzFjZzFmYkp3NFRlM1lVNE55eXMwLTBKSjVoNmYwWm5KTUlYeGM3cjVoVjVKLTFUN0YtWVNuUnAwRjdkd085a1BhUjdPaWxvOGE1T2pSNnFfMTFzcGNzQU1rLWtISkxSS3BvUVdHYzBEc2x4d0NVYUZRdDVuZ0g4Mm1oeW8tZ2laYTFudl9MWTdTOEhtajRFaHBWcEZwZDJncENXT0EyVEwtdDZVdmh5LXZCMFBzM203cHZzMkUwNXhNNFN4dmxmZUM1anlkdy1hc3VXOVktZ3hqdUM3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 17:13:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15 Feared Trapped After Building Collapses In Punjab, Army Joins Rescue Op - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxPSHRTdzhQaWlCZ1JrUU1IMDFybGc3RGVzTW5EdFB3X3F6M1dkUWg4N0haUTQ3WVB0UlF6MXduaWVwWmFnZUFRbkZEdVlqOTRIdjNwX1JLUjg1RUJzUU9yclhhQ2RGZ2lqRzJ1TExaSE03bktldFhqZXVCM3cxVTR6Y2xVOUJWOVNoY01aTjlXNUdDQW40VHVCTUt0MFAwcGJ5UU1SV1FlX3AtLUViNUU5c3E2OExoUEIyYThSNWxqcjd4R1NJRmNqeWxHSmJLY0hPZUHSAdoBQVVfeXFMUGZFOWdsZVlFcktGUTE2QXZUVUJRR3RnbnpYbzJ1bXdTLTJ3NWRKNlQtNFVlWXk1UnRZZHlxVG1PbEwyS0ROVmxKN0MwWVppU3c2WmdtWWNJeXV1UGVsSkY0RUVQMXRXRG9mMXN6UzA2MmhZU0M5SXh3QTJJUnlMakNnWXRMYzlDWlItVHNfYVFITkFMRlowZzJSU3BJVGRKeWxCSzhSOWtvOGxFU2YwZmtEZTV3Q2oxZm5lcTlGcHpaSktPT09QU0VQUmlqZXRNOEE3bnlBLWRmN1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxPSHRTdzhQaWlCZ1JrUU1IMDFybGc3RGVzTW5EdFB3X3F6M1dkUWg4N0haUTQ3WVB0UlF6MXduaWVwWmFnZUFRbkZEdVlqOTRIdjNwX1JLUjg1RUJzUU9yclhhQ2RGZ2lqRzJ1TExaSE03bktldFhqZXVCM3cxVTR6Y2xVOUJWOVNoY01aTjlXNUdDQW40VHVCTUt0MFAwcGJ5UU1SV1FlX3AtLUViNUU5c3E2OExoUEIyYThSNWxqcjd4R1NJRmNqeWxHSmJLY0hPZUHSAdoBQVVfeXFMUGZFOWdsZVlFcktGUTE2QXZUVUJRR3RnbnpYbzJ1bXdTLTJ3NWRKNlQtNFVlWXk1UnRZZHlxVG1PbEwyS0ROVmxKN0MwWVppU3c2WmdtWWNJeXV1UGVsSkY0RUVQMXRXRG9mMXN6UzA2MmhZU0M5SXh3QTJJUnlMakNnWXRMYzlDWlItVHNfYVFITkFMRlowZzJSU3BJVGRKeWxCSzhSOWtvOGxFU2YwZmtEZTV3Q2oxZm5lcTlGcHpaSktPT09QU0VQUmlqZXRNOEE3bnlBLWRmN1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:54:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra portfolios: Fadnavis keeps Home, Shinde Urban Development; Ajit gets Finance - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maharashtra portfolios: Fadnavis keeps Home, Shinde Urban Development; Ajit gets Finance</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/todays-paper/tp-national/cuna0p/article68990107.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/15TH-ABHINAY-D-G0PDNLH2U.3.jpg.jpg" alt="Maharashtra Cabinet" width="100%" height="100%">
<figcaption>Cabinet portfolio allocation in Maharashtra</figcaption>
<p>Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis retains key portfolios while Deputy Chief Ministers Eknath Shinde and Ajit Pawar take on Urban Development and Finance, respectively.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Fadnavis retains Home, Law and Judiciary departments.</li>
  <li>Shinde gets Urban Development along with Housing and Public Works.</li>
  <li>Ajit Pawar continues with Finance and Planning, including State Excise.</li>
  <li>Ministers reshuffled, with new opportunities for younger leaders.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Young faces have been given an opportunity in this cabinet.”</blockquote>
<p>This cabinet reshuffle aims to balance power among coalition partners, maintaining crucial departments and preparing for the upcoming BMC elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/maharashtra/maharashtra-portfolios-fadnavis-keeps-home-shinde-urban-development-ajit-gets-finance/article69013705.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/maharashtra/maharashtra-portfolios-fadnavis-keeps-home-shinde-urban-development-ajit-gets-finance/article69013705.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GST council explains difference in tax rates between salted and caramel popcorn - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GST Council Clarifies Tax Rates for Salted and Caramel Popcorn</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/ANI-20241221325-0_1734797795521_1734797813522.jpg" alt="Union finance minister Nirmala Sitharaman speaks at the 55th meeting of the GST Council(ANI)"><figcaption>Union finance minister Nirmala Sitharaman speaks at the 55th meeting of the GST Council(ANI)</figcaption><p>The GST Council has issued a clarification on the tax rates applicable to different types of popcorn, specifying that pre-packed salted popcorn will incur a lower tax rate than caramelized popcorn.</p><ul><li>Pre-packed, labelled, ready-to-eat snacks are taxed at 12%.</li><li>Caramelized popcorn falls under a higher tax category at 18% due to its added sugar content.</li><li>The Central Board of Indirect Taxes and Customs (CBIC) will release a circular to clarify these rules further.</li><li>Ready-to-eat popcorn not pre-packed has a 5% GST rate.</li><li>Black pepper and raisins supplied directly by farmers are exempt from GST.</li></ul><blockquote>“Salted, caramelised, plain popcorn is being sold as namkeen in certain states. Caramelised popcorn comes with added sugar, so the treatment rate is different from namkeen.” - Nirmala Sitharaman</blockquote><p>The GST Council continues to review other tax issues without making definitive decisions, highlighting ongoing discussions about the applicability of GST on food delivery services.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/gst-council-explains-difference-in-tax-rates-for-salted-and-caramel-popcorn-101734797132186.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/gst-council-explains-difference-in-tax-rates-for-salted-and-caramel-popcorn-101734797132186.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:39:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi meets 101-year-old ex-IFS officer in Kuwait after granddaughter's request - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Meets 101-Year-Old Ex-IFS Officer in Kuwait Following Granddaughter's Request</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 21, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/Screenshot_2024-12-21_162839_1734778754027_1734778771362.png" alt="PM Modi met a 101-year-old ex-IFS officer in Kuwait" title="PM Modi met a 101-year-old ex-IFS officer in Kuwait">
<figcaption>PM Modi met a 101-year-old ex-IFS officer in Kuwait</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi met a 101-year-old former Indian Foreign Service (IFS) officer in Kuwait after a request from his granddaughter made on social media.</p>
<ul>
  <li>PM Modi responded to a request from Mangal Sain Handa's granddaughter on platform X for a meeting during his visit.</li>
  <li>This visit marks the first by an Indian PM to Kuwait in 43 years.</li>
  <li>Mangal Sain Handa's son expressed gratitude for the meeting, describing it as an "experience of a lifetime."</li>
  <li>Kuwait's Indian diaspora constitutes 21% of the population, with Indian workers making up 30% of the workforce.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We deeply value the historical connection with Kuwait that has been nurtured over generations.” - PM Modi</blockquote>
<p>This personal meeting highlights the relationship between India and Kuwait, especially within the context of a substantial Indian community in the Gulf state.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-meets-101-year-old-ex-ifs-officer-in-kuwait-at-granddaughters-request-101734776972325.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-meets-101-year-old-ex-ifs-officer-in-kuwait-at-granddaughters-request-101734776972325.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telangana not to allow benefit shows of movies.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telangana Bans Benefit Shows and Actor Theatre Visits Following Stampede Incident</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/Komatireddy-Venkat-Reddy31734797897.jpg" alt="Telangana not to allow benefit shows of movies" /><figcaption>Telangana Government Responds to Theatre Incident</figcaption><p>In response to a tragic stampede during the premiere of "Pushpa 2" in Hyderabad, the Telangana government has announced a ban on actor visits to theatres and benefit shows for upcoming movie releases.</p><ul><li>The government, led by Cinematography Minister Komatireddy Venkat Reddy, will not allow actor visits and benefit shows.</li><li>While they are suspending these events, they will continue to offer special incentives for the film industry.</li><li>After the incident that resulted in a death and injuries, the state will not increase cinema ticket prices but will consider them on a case-by-case basis.</li><li>Actor Allu Arjun did not meet the family of the deceased and was criticized for attending the event without police permission.</li><li>The government has pledged to pay Rs 25 lakh to the family of the deceased and continue to assist the injured child.</li><li>The Chief Minister condemned the lack of support from other film personalities for the victims.</li></ul><blockquote>“I assure that we will do everything possible to save the boy’s life,” said Minister Venkat Reddy regarding the injured child.</blockquote><p>The government's actions reflect concern for public safety and a commitment to support families affected by the incident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/telangana-news/telangana-not-to-allow-benefit-shows-of-movies-142907</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/telangana-news/telangana-not-to-allow-benefit-shows-of-movies-142907</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:18:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru Accident: CCTV Footage Shows Container Truck Toppling Over SUV Killing Family In Nelamangala Highway - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tragic Bengaluru Accident: Container Truck Topples Over SUV, Killing Family</h1><p><strong>Published: </strong> Saturday, December 21, 2024, 21:44 [IST] <strong>Source:</strong> Oneindia News</p><img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2024/12/bengaluru-accident-cctv-1734797057.jpg" alt="Bengaluru Accident CCTV Footage Shows Moment Container Truck Toppling Over SUV Killing Family In Nelamangala" width="600" height="338"><figcaption>Bengaluru Accident CCTV Footage Shows Moment Container Truck Toppling Over SUV Killing Family In Nelamangala</figcaption><p>A horrific accident on the Bengaluru-Tumakuru highway resulted in the death of six family members, including a notable tech industry leader, when a speeding container truck toppled over their SUV.</p><ul><li>The victims include Chandram Yegapagol, the Managing Director of IAST Software Solutions, and five family members.</li><li>The incident occurred near Nelamangala during their journey to Maharashtra for Christmas celebrations.</li><li>CCTV footage reveals the speeding container lorry losing control and crashing onto the SUV.</li><li>The tragedy has sparked an outpouring of grief within the tech community and raised concerns about road safety.</li></ul><blockquote>“The CCTV footage highlights the container lorry's high speed and sudden loss of control, showcasing the gravity of the incident.”</blockquote><p>This tragic event underscores the need for improved traffic safety measures and has left an indelible impact on the affected community.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/bengaluru/bengaluru-accident-cctv-footage-shows-moment-container-truck-toppling-over-suv-highway-nelamangala-4022835.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/bengaluru/bengaluru-accident-cctv-footage-shows-moment-container-truck-toppling-over-suv-highway-nelamangala-4022835.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:14:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gurugram Boy, 12, Wants Online Classes, Sends Bomb Threat To School - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/gurugram-boy-12-wants-online-classes-sends-bomb-threat-to-school-7303019</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/gurugram-boy-12-wants-online-classes-sends-bomb-threat-to-school-7303019</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 16:14:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra portfolio allocation: CM Fadnavis keeps home ministry, Ajit Pawar gets finance, Shinde gets u - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maharashtra portfolio allocation: CM Fadnavis keeps home ministry, Ajit Pawar gets finance, Shinde gets urban development</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>This article discusses the recent allocation of ministerial portfolios in Maharashtra, where Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis retains control of the Home Ministry while Ajit Pawar is assigned the Finance portfolio, and Deputy Chief Minister Eknath Shinde takes charge of Urban Development.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Devendra Fadnavis retains the Home Ministry.</li>
  <li>Ajit Pawar appointed as Finance Minister.</li>
  <li>Eknath Shinde to oversee Urban Development.</li>
  <li>The allocation reflects the power dynamics within the coalition government.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The allocation of portfolios is crucial for the functioning of the government and its future plans,” commented a political analyst.</blockquote>
<p>The announcement of the ministerial allocations marks a significant step in establishing the governance structure in Maharashtra following the recent political shifts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/maharashtra-portfolio-allocation-cm-fadnavis-keeps-home-ajit-pawar-gets-finance-shinde-gets-urban-development/articleshow/116542747.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/maharashtra-portfolio-allocation-cm-fadnavis-keeps-home-ajit-pawar-gets-finance-shinde-gets-urban-development/articleshow/116542747.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GST Council Exempts Gene Therapy, Cuts Tax Rate For Rice Kernels - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxONGtKbGRuVlRUZ3lIUWc2aWdROGlzenphbm9PcnFMbC1zVG5wREY2bVNtYUotcV9QRDlta1d0SVd1R2NyWWx6cUh3NTZ1aXBLOXVETVMwT0ZTZDk2aXNJTUFaaHpOZFZSRFFIVXVVUjBPMW4tYzkzX1p6Z2d1UjZic1N3cVpBU0dpa2hJMkl1UVpxM3lOSS1FYWFsVEU4eDNSdEc4WllPalVQSk5jcjgxLVI0NXJCWlNaRTQ1MUxNWVpKQ0XSAcsBQVVfeXFMT0QtZlM0aEIxRWhWN1Bta3ZGc3V4NjNtSEI3X25IbENhVjdxZHVidGp3d3FObnpfQmNwTk9kcGNEZDNWZC1JeGhiNDVoQmljZFEyeDBZUkdqc0l1X2RXelpMS1Ewa0xYSDk0c0ljUUt2TUdzajVkTndRb3lJQl9oS0JVOGw2Rno5M3FKbjJCRGtEVFo4b0l1elR3WE9GblB2aG8yRml5eFRZY0M1eW9lZm9JdVcySFBSaUh2bEFnakVUeURVaXladmtDN2M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxONGtKbGRuVlRUZ3lIUWc2aWdROGlzenphbm9PcnFMbC1zVG5wREY2bVNtYUotcV9QRDlta1d0SVd1R2NyWWx6cUh3NTZ1aXBLOXVETVMwT0ZTZDk2aXNJTUFaaHpOZFZSRFFIVXVVUjBPMW4tYzkzX1p6Z2d1UjZic1N3cVpBU0dpa2hJMkl1UVpxM3lOSS1FYWFsVEU4eDNSdEc4WllPalVQSk5jcjgxLVI0NXJCWlNaRTQ1MUxNWVpKQ0XSAcsBQVVfeXFMT0QtZlM0aEIxRWhWN1Bta3ZGc3V4NjNtSEI3X25IbENhVjdxZHVidGp3d3FObnpfQmNwTk9kcGNEZDNWZC1JeGhiNDVoQmljZFEyeDBZUkdqc0l1X2RXelpMS1Ewa0xYSDk0c0ljUUt2TUdzajVkTndRb3lJQl9oS0JVOGw2Rno5M3FKbjJCRGtEVFo4b0l1elR3WE9GblB2aG8yRml5eFRZY0M1eW9lZm9JdVcySFBSaUh2bEFnakVUeURVaXladmtDN2M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:52:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra portfolio allocation: Fadnavis keeps home ministry, Shinde gets urban development - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maharashtra portfolio allocation: Devendra Fadnavis keeps home, Eknath Shinde gets urban development</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/PTI12-21-2024-000353B-0_1734796342117_1734796372538.jpg" alt="Nagpur: Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis with deputy chief minister Eknath Shinde.(PTI)" title="Nagpur: Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis with deputy chief minister Eknath Shinde.(PTI)"><figcaption>Nagpur: Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis with deputy chief minister Eknath Shinde.(PTI)</figcaption><p>The Maharashtra government has officially announced the allocation of portfolios for its cabinet, following weeks of speculation. Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis retains the important home ministry, while Deputy Chief Minister Eknath Shinde takes charge of urban development and public works.</p><ul><li>Fadnavis keeps the coveted home ministry.</li><li>Eknath Shinde gets urban development and public works.</li><li>Ajit Pawar leads the finance department and holds the Excise portfolio.</li><li>Dadaji Bhuse is the new school education minister.</li><li>Industries minister Uday Samant continues in his role.</li><li>Health minister of state is Prakash Abitkar.</li><li>Chandrashekhar Bawankule is assigned the revenue department.</li></ul><blockquote>“The BJP-Shiv Sena-NCP's Mahayuti alliance scored a landslide victory in the Maharashtra assembly election.”</blockquote><p>This new cabinet structure follows negotiations where Eknath Shinde had initially demanded more significant roles, including the chief minister's position.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maharashtra-portfolio-allocation-fadnavis-gets-home-ministry-shinde-urban-development-101734796182424.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maharashtra-portfolio-allocation-fadnavis-gets-home-ministry-shinde-urban-development-101734796182424.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:50:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Higher Pension: Employers must submit wage details by January 2025 to get benefits | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Higher Pension: Employers Must Submit Wage Details by January 2025 to Get Benefits</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>The Employees' Provident Fund Organisation (EPFO) has extended the deadline for employers to submit wage details for higher pension benefits to January 31, 2025. This extension provides a final opportunity for compliance with recent regulations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The EPFO has highlighted the need for employers to process and upload pending applications for pension validation.</li>
  <li>Clarifications must be provided by January 15, 2025, for higher pension applications.</li>
  <li>Over 4.66 lakh cases require additional information to proceed.</li>
  <li>The deadline for employers was previously extended multiple times since February 2023.</li>
  <li>3.1 lakh applications are still pending with employers despite the extensions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A final opportunity is being given to the employers till 31.01.2025 to ensure that employers process and upload these pending Applications for Validation of Option / Joint Options.” - EPFO Statement</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the EPFO's extension aims to facilitate compliance among employers and ensure that eligible pensioners can benefit from the higher pension scheme.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/higher-eps-pension-employers-must-submit-wage-details-by-january-2025-to-get-benefits-11734781216503.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/higher-eps-pension-employers-must-submit-wage-details-by-january-2025-to-get-benefits-11734781216503.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:29:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GST Council Meeting Highlights: GST exemption for micro and small units renting from unregistered individuals under composition scheme - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxNV1hETWF5Y2ZiVkMwSk80bFdqdkR6MFBmQlYxV2F6RE1HbFBXUTMwWldETE4xZEdwVlctZ3FPYmVHN1dxYmdPdTlzeG9XUzhheWJRYUM0TW0zbzNUelhFQkN4NExwWGl3Y2NDOEFsc0FhSllMckVpZERVeS0tNzQ0VGx2ZkM4cHhldGt1VmFrN04xbGRYWHlXbFhlTllVVGh2eVk5TjhVbkw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxNV1hETWF5Y2ZiVkMwSk80bFdqdkR6MFBmQlYxV2F6RE1HbFBXUTMwWldETE4xZEdwVlctZ3FPYmVHN1dxYmdPdTlzeG9XUzhheWJRYUM0TW0zbzNUelhFQkN4NExwWGl3Y2NDOEFsc0FhSllMckVpZERVeS0tNzQ0VGx2ZkM4cHhldGt1VmFrN04xbGRYWHlXbFhlTllVVGh2eVk5TjhVbkw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:22:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Why is ECI afraid of transparency?': Jairam Ramesh questions Centre's move to restrict public access to - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Why is ECI afraid of transparency?': Jairam Ramesh questions Centre's move to restrict public access to electronic poll documents</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] - <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>Jairam Ramesh has raised concerns over the central government's decision to limit public access to electronic poll documents, questioning the motives behind such restrictions.</p><ul><li>Ramesh emphasizes the importance of transparency in electoral processes.</li><li>The Centre's move may undermine public trust in the electoral system.</li><li>Calls for an open dialogue regarding the accessibility of electoral documents.</li></ul><blockquote>“Transparency is the cornerstone of our democracy,” Ramesh stated during his address.</blockquote><p>This issue raises significant questions about democratic practices and accountability in the electoral process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/why-is-eci-afraid-of-transparency-jairam-ramesh-questions-centres-move-to-restrict-public-access-to-electronic-poll-documents/articleshow/116541909.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/why-is-eci-afraid-of-transparency-jairam-ramesh-questions-centres-move-to-restrict-public-access-to-electronic-poll-documents/articleshow/116541909.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Multi-storey Building Collapses In Punjab's Mohali, Several People Feared Trapped - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Multi-storey Building Collapses In Punjab's Mohali, Several People Feared Trapped</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Police personnel and others during a rescue operation after a multistorey building collapsed at Sohana village. (PTI)"><figcaption>Police personnel and others during a rescue operation after a multistorey building collapsed at Sohana village. (PTI)</figcaption><p>A multi-storey building collapsed in Punjab’s Mohali district, leaving several people feared trapped under the debris. Rescue operations are underway, featuring teams from the National Disaster Response Force and local authorities.</p><ul><li>A multi-storey building in Mohali collapsed, with reports of people trapped inside.</li><li>Rescue operations commenced promptly, involving local and NDRF teams.</li><li>Emergency services, including police and fire brigades, are at the scene.</li><li>The building collapse may be linked to nearby construction activities.</li><li>Punjab CM Bhagwant Mann is overseeing rescue operations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Sad news has been received that a multistorey building near Sohana in Sahibzada Ajit Singh Nagar (Mohali) has collapsed. The entire administration and other rescue teams have been deployed at the spot.” - Punjab CM Bhagwant Mann</blockquote><p>The building collapse has raised concerns about safety protocols in construction, and ongoing efforts are focused on locating and rescuing any individuals possibly trapped under the rubble.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/multistorey-building-collapses-in-punjabs-mohali-several-people-feared-trapped-9164232.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/multistorey-building-collapses-in-punjabs-mohali-several-people-feared-trapped-9164232.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 15:09:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi meets Indian migrant workers at Gulf Spic Labour Camp in Kuwait - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Meets Indian Migrant Workers at Gulf Spic Labour Camp in Kuwait</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>The article covers Prime Minister Modi's visit to Indian migrant workers residing at the Gulf Spic Labour Camp in Kuwait, focusing on his discussions and interactions with them.</p><ul><li>PM Modi met with Indian workers at the Gulf Spic Labour Camp.</li><li>The meeting aimed to address the concerns of the workers.</li><li>Modi reassured the workers of the government's support and initiatives for their welfare.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are committed to ensuring your welfare and addressing any issues you face abroad.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Prime Minister Modi's visit highlights the importance of supporting Indian migrant workers and addressing their needs abroad.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pm-modi-meets-indian-migrant-workers-at-kuwait-labour-camp/articleshow/116541587.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pm-modi-meets-indian-migrant-workers-at-kuwait-labour-camp/articleshow/116541587.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 14:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GST Council meet key decisions: No GST on bank penal charges, clarity on tax rate on popcorn & more - top - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GST Council Meet Key Decisions: No GST on Bank Penal Charges and More</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>This article outlines the key decisions made during the recent GST Council meeting, highlighting important updates on tax implications.</p>
<ul>
  <li>No GST to be levied on penal charges imposed by banks.</li>
  <li>Clarity provided regarding the tax rate on popcorn and its categorization.</li>
  <li>Additional announcements impacting various sectors and taxation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This decision is aimed at reducing the financial burden on consumers.”</blockquote>
<p>These announcements are expected to have a significant impact on both consumers and businesses, fostering clarity and reducing costs in certain areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/gst-council-meeting-key-decisions-highlights-goods-and-services-tax-nirmala-sitharaman-top-55th-gst-council-meet-takeaways/articleshow/116529340.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/gst-council-meeting-key-decisions-highlights-goods-and-services-tax-nirmala-sitharaman-top-55th-gst-council-meet-takeaways/articleshow/116529340.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 14:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[55th GST council meeting in Jaisalmer on December 21, 2024: Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman media briefing - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>55th GST Council Meeting Overview: Key Decisions and Updates</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/business/Economy/fvl7vd/article69013248.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_21_2024_000047A.jpg" alt="Union Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman chairs the 55th meeting of the GST Council, in Jaisalmer, on December 21, 2024." title="Union Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman chairs the 55th meeting of the GST Council, in Jaisalmer, on December 21, 2024."><figcaption>Union Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman chairs the 55th meeting of the GST Council in Jaisalmer. Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>The 55th meeting of the GST Council, chaired by Union Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman, was held on December 21, 2024, in Jaisalmer. Several significant discussions on GST changes, including those related to insurance levies, were tabled for future consideration.</p><ul><li>The review of GST levies on life and health insurance policies was postponed.</li><li>A Group of Ministers will re-examine the insurance levies prior to making recommendations to the Council.</li><li>Proposals for rate rationalisation involving about 150 items, such as packaged drinking water and bicycles under ₹10,000, were deferred.</li><li>The GST on gene therapy and long-range surface to air missiles has been exempted from tax.</li><li>Used car sales GST increased from 12% to 18%.</li><li>New tax rates were established for different types of popcorn based on packaging.</li><li>An examination of GST levies by states hit by natural disasters was initiated.</li></ul><blockquote>“Gene therapy that is now critical for dealing with life-threatening diseases, so have been totally exempted [from GST].” - Nirmala Sitharaman</blockquote><p>This meeting highlights ongoing efforts to adjust the GST framework to better address various economic needs and situations, while many discussions are still pending for clarity and consensus.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/business/Economy/55th-gst-council-meeting-in-jaisalmer-on-december-21-2024/article69013223.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/business/Economy/55th-gst-council-meeting-in-jaisalmer-on-december-21-2024/article69013223.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 14:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Multistorey building collapses in Punjab’s Mohali, several feared trapped - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Multistorey Building Collapse in Mohali Leaving Several Trapped</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/y1gxdj/article69013169.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_21_2024_000326B.jpg" alt="Police personnel and others during a rescue operation after a multistorey building collapsed at Sohana village, in Mohali district, Punjab, on December 21, 2024." title="Police personnel and others during a rescue operation after a multistorey building collapsed at Sohana village, in Mohali district, Punjab, on December 21, 2024."><figcaption>Police personnel and others during a rescue operation after the building collapse.</figcaption><p>Rescue operations are ongoing after a multistorey building collapsed in Sohana village, Mohali, with fears that people are trapped beneath the debris.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred on December 21, 2024, according to local sources.</li><li>District authorities have initiated rescue operations, employing two excavators and a National Disaster Response Team (NDRF) has been dispatched to the site.</li><li>Punjab Chief Minister Bhagwant Mann expressed concern and confirmed that rescue efforts are ongoing, urging cooperation from the public.</li><li>Preliminary reports suggest the building may have collapsed after excavation work was done nearby.</li><li>Senior police officials are monitoring the rescue operations, emphasizing the urgency of clearing the debris.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is an unfortunate incident. Rescue operation is in full swing.” - Kulwant Singh, Mohali MLA</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical as authorities work tirelessly to locate and rescue those potentially trapped under the rubble.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/multistorey-building-collapse-in-mohali-several-trapped/article69013152.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/multistorey-building-collapse-in-mohali-several-trapped/article69013152.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 14:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab Municipal Elections Live Updates: AAP wins in Patiala, Congress largest party in Phagwara; check all results here - PTC News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxPRmdaMm1MdzgtRUwtRGJpSm52YjBIQ3pqMnRCTjBtdjk0enFhendJZi1QQkdWVG1kdTk3c0lXc09SWWh4U1FnSEQ0eC15VmdxRHhFX2Y4RmRub1FtN3Z5MFBJRF96cFlfRXBpTTdUdlNOby1sUUpEYUVhS2hGb0Joa0V4em5mUE1tT0FKQnpNc2hXTzN1TFVnUjlTWW50d3ZWUmszMkJKUzV6QmtoR1FJeWlyTkxtTVRDWXlRb19pWdIBxAFBVV95cUxPa1ZJRXN2SEQyMmZhUldESWpkQkx3WDc1bUNTSUIxRjI3ZTVqQW5zX1dSVGppaHRuRFpWUzBhZm1NS3l0X3p0QkZSeGNTZkhxNzBSR1ZGTk14NUR4RE5lY1AxeF9jQXN3T3Q1LV9pT2FxZmFCdmU1MHVpMmZhUzQ4ZXU4MVlma0JWQ0NjWVNZY0E5d195eVNpYjlIYnNJcTcwdGxxM3JkZWtEcXYzeEw0U01EWnRUYWN2b0pUQWtSQ2ZQWi1H?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxPRmdaMm1MdzgtRUwtRGJpSm52YjBIQ3pqMnRCTjBtdjk0enFhendJZi1QQkdWVG1kdTk3c0lXc09SWWh4U1FnSEQ0eC15VmdxRHhFX2Y4RmRub1FtN3Z5MFBJRF96cFlfRXBpTTdUdlNOby1sUUpEYUVhS2hGb0Joa0V4em5mUE1tT0FKQnpNc2hXTzN1TFVnUjlTWW50d3ZWUmszMkJKUzV6QmtoR1FJeWlyTkxtTVRDWXlRb19pWdIBxAFBVV95cUxPa1ZJRXN2SEQyMmZhUldESWpkQkx3WDc1bUNTSUIxRjI3ZTVqQW5zX1dSVGppaHRuRFpWUzBhZm1NS3l0X3p0QkZSeGNTZkhxNzBSR1ZGTk14NUR4RE5lY1AxeF9jQXN3T3Q1LV9pT2FxZmFCdmU1MHVpMmZhUzQ4ZXU4MVlma0JWQ0NjWVNZY0E5d195eVNpYjlIYnNJcTcwdGxxM3JkZWtEcXYzeEw0U01EWnRUYWN2b0pUQWtSQ2ZQWi1H?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 14:01:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building collapses in Punjab's Mohali, several feared trapped - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Building Collapses in Punjab's Mohali, Several Feared Trapped</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 21, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/PTI12-21-2024-000326B-0_1734791639315_1734791678381.jpg" alt="Mohali: Police personnel and others during a rescue operation after a multistorey building collapsed at Sohana village.(PTI)"><figcaption>Mohali: Police personnel and others during a rescue operation after a multistorey building collapsed at Sohana village.(PTI)</figcaption><p>A multi-storey building collapsed in Mohali, Punjab, resulting in fears that several individuals may be trapped under the debris. The district authorities have initiated rescue operations with an NDRF team on-site.</p><ul><li>The building collapsed after a loud noise was reported, possibly linked to excavation work in the area.</li><li>Two excavators and a fire brigade team have been deployed for rescue efforts.</li><li>Senior Superintendent of Police Deepak Pareek confirmed the ongoing operation and stated that the cause of the collapse is under investigation.</li><li>Punjab Chief Minister Bhagwant Mann is coordinating with the administration and urged locals to assist the rescue teams.</li></ul><blockquote>“We pray that there is no loss of life, we will also take action against the culprits.” - Bhagwant Mann</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical as rescue operations continue, with hopes for a safe recovery of those trapped.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/building-collapses-in-punjabs-mohali-several-feared-trapped-101734789353265.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/building-collapses-in-punjabs-mohali-several-feared-trapped-101734789353265.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 13:59:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GST council defers tax cut on insurance premiums as Nirmala Sitharaman awaits IRDAI feedback - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GST Council Defers Tax Cut on Insurance Premiums</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 21, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/PTI12-21-2024-000047A-0_1734788443234_1734788454793.jpg" alt="Union Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman chairs the 55th meeting of the GST Council.(PTI)" title="Union Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman chairs the 55th meeting of the GST Council.(PTI)">
<figcaption>Union Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman chairs the 55th meeting of the GST Council.(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>The Goods and Services Tax (GST) council deferred the decision to cut tax on insurance premiums as many inputs including IRDAI comments are awaited. Additionally, the council clarified taxi regulations on popcorn taxation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The GST council did not approve a tax cut on insurance premiums pending IRDAI feedback.</li>
  <li>Clarification issued that pre-packed ready-to-eat snacks will face a 12% tax.</li>
  <li>Tax on caramelised popcorn is set at 18% without changing the existing popcorn tax rate.</li>
  <li>A group of ministers (GoM) will be formed to address Andhra Pradesh’s demand for a calamity cess on luxury goods.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The cess will be on luxury items and state-specific levy," said Andhra Pradesh Finance Minister Payyavula Keshav.</blockquote>
<p>This decision reflects ongoing considerations in adapting taxation to address current needs while awaiting further input from key stakeholders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/gst-council-defers-tax-cut-on-insurance-premiums-as-nirmala-sitharaman-awaits-irdai-feedback-101734787729780.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/gst-council-defers-tax-cut-on-insurance-premiums-as-nirmala-sitharaman-awaits-irdai-feedback-101734787729780.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 13:37:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Six-storey building collapses in Punjab's Mohali, several feared trapped - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Six-storey building collapses in Punjab's Mohali, several feared trapped</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023-10-19 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This tragic incident occurred when a six-storey building in Mohali, Punjab collapsed, leading to fears that several individuals may be trapped under the rubble.</p><ul><li>The building collapse happened early in the morning.</li><li>Rescue operations are currently underway, with local authorities and emergency services on the site.</li><li>Eyewitnesses reported hearing a loud noise before the structure fell.</li><li>Authorities are investigating the cause of the collapse.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are doing everything possible to rescue those trapped under the debris,” stated a local official.</blockquote><p>The community is in shock over this event, and ongoing efforts are being made to ensure that all possible safety measures are taken in future constructions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/six-storey-building-collapses-in-punjabs-mohali-several-feared-trapped/articleshow/116539598.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/six-storey-building-collapses-in-punjabs-mohali-several-feared-trapped/articleshow/116539598.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 13:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll Rules Tweak Makes Electronic Records Harder To Get, Sparks Row - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Poll Rules Tweak Makes Electronic Records Harder To Get, Sparks Row</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Poll Rules Tweak Makes Electronic Records Harder To Get, Sparks Row" alt="Poll Rules Tweak Makes Electronic Records Harder To Get, Sparks Row" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/fpcf6j4s_evm-generic_625x300_10_May_23.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>Image showing the impact of the new polling rules.</figcaption><p>The government has amended election rules to limit public access to certain electronic records, which has raised concerns about transparency in the electoral process.</p><ul><li>The amendment prevents public inspection of electronic records like CCTV footage and webcasting from polling stations.</li><li>Officials argue the change is necessary to prevent misuse and protect voter secrecy.</li><li>Opposition parties claim the amendment erodes the integrity of the electoral process.</li><li>A court case prompted the amendment, emphasizing the need for clarity regarding what documents are available for public inspection.</li><li>The amendment only allows access to documents explicitly mentioned in election rules.</li></ul><blockquote>“If there was ever a vindication of our assertions regarding the rapidly eroding integrity of the electoral process managed by the Election Commission of India (ECI) in recent times, this is it.” - Jairam Ramesh</blockquote><p>This amendment has sparked considerable debate about the balance between election security and public transparency.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/poll-rules-tweak-makes-electronic-records-harder-to-get-sparks-row-7301963</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/poll-rules-tweak-makes-electronic-records-harder-to-get-sparks-row-7301963</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 13:30:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thankfully, it was not taken up: J-K CM on proposed GST hike on Kashmir Shawl - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxQWk1HdnJmd3NXcVdiam5veXdQeU1LNkJVZTY3UnpYeW41b3VyRTU5UDhSS2g2RHhrbkNvdHpBLUluMEZ3MGtwWVNUd0F0ajVjWF9uOXFleVRVdjhYNHNNUU9PY1dmSEFKNDdpOWRHQ0Z5ZHVha1ZlWlA2UUtWTUY3a1A0VWVaQjd4cTBFZkwtM1Rlbl9VbWZEb3VTRHVVM2F5NFMtM2haaE1ObWk3THEtWjNLNkVMbUHSAcABQVVfeXFMTUFpQ3lkU2R5cl9VS3ZqUXV2Tm43b0RNdFMxM0ttVzdBNmhuTWgxb3h5TzRtc3hrMnJFV0RhZ0ZvR01pYkpWX1lQc2JDOXNqWEtkdHYtQ1NJaEV0RXBJdjNEajkyN3RZZlRmQzR1TFZnM2dvdG5ycTJMNDFPa1IwcGdENHU4bG16LVVQTm1EN0h5RXh5RWtDdFN4RFVSQmlmSHp1MmlqeVJlRk51UjRKWExuaUhqUFpjMUJEbHVTQmJf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxQWk1HdnJmd3NXcVdiam5veXdQeU1LNkJVZTY3UnpYeW41b3VyRTU5UDhSS2g2RHhrbkNvdHpBLUluMEZ3MGtwWVNUd0F0ajVjWF9uOXFleVRVdjhYNHNNUU9PY1dmSEFKNDdpOWRHQ0Z5ZHVha1ZlWlA2UUtWTUY3a1A0VWVaQjd4cTBFZkwtM1Rlbl9VbWZEb3VTRHVVM2F5NFMtM2haaE1ObWk3THEtWjNLNkVMbUHSAcABQVVfeXFMTUFpQ3lkU2R5cl9VS3ZqUXV2Tm43b0RNdFMxM0ttVzdBNmhuTWgxb3h5TzRtc3hrMnJFV0RhZ0ZvR01pYkpWX1lQc2JDOXNqWEtkdHYtQ1NJaEV0RXBJdjNEajkyN3RZZlRmQzR1TFZnM2dvdG5ycTJMNDFPa1IwcGdENHU4bG16LVVQTm1EN0h5RXh5RWtDdFN4RFVSQmlmSHp1MmlqeVJlRk51UjRKWExuaUhqUFpjMUJEbHVTQmJf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 13:15:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai Ferry Accident: Missing 7-Year-Old Boy's Body Found Off City Coast; Death Toll Rises To 15 - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Ferry Accident: Missing 7-Year-Old Boy's Body Found, Death Toll Rises to 15</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The Neelkamal ferry was on way to Elephanta Islands, a popular tourist destination near Mumbai, when the speed boat crashed into it around 4 pm. (Image: PTI)"><figcaption>The Neelkamal ferry was on way to Elephanta Islands, a popular tourist destination near Mumbai, when the speed boat crashed into it around 4 pm. (Image: PTI)</figcaption><p>The body of a seven-year-old boy who went missing after a ferry capsized off the Mumbai coast was found after a three-day search operation, raising the death toll to 15.</p><ul><li>A Navy speedboat crashed into the ferry on December 18, leading to the accident.</li><li>The Navy and Coast Guard conducted extensive search operations for the missing.</li><li>Of the 113 people on board, 15 have died and 98 were rescued, including two injured.</li><li>The ferry was overloaded, violating safety regulations.</li><li>Investigations are underway into the cause of the accident, with a case registered against the driver of the Navy vehicle.</li></ul><blockquote>Officials stated, "The Navy has launched a probe into one of the deadliest crashes in the city’s coastal area." </blockquote><p>This incident has highlighted serious safety concerns regarding passenger ferries and the enforcement of maritime regulations in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/mumbai-ferry-accident-missing-7-year-old-boys-body-found-off-city-coast-death-toll-rises-to-15-9163796.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/mumbai-ferry-accident-missing-7-year-old-boys-body-found-off-city-coast-death-toll-rises-to-15-9163796.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 12:58:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Caught on CCTV: Car flips 8 times on Rajasthan highway, passengers escape unhurt, ask for tea - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Five Passengers Escape Unhurt After SUV Flips Eight Times in Rajasthan</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 21, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/21/550x309/Screenshot_2024-12-21_180057_1734784277802_1734784281404.png" alt="In Rajasthan, five passengers miraculously escaped unhurt after their SUV flipped 8 times(X/HateDetectors)"><figcaption>In Rajasthan, five passengers miraculously escaped unhurt after their SUV flipped 8 times(X/HateDetectors)</figcaption></figure><p>In a miraculous escape, five passengers walked away unscathed after their SUV flipped eight times in a freak accident on a highway in Rajasthan's Nagaur district.</p><ul><li>The SUV was speeding when the driver lost control, causing the vehicle to flip multiple times.</li><li>Remarkably, none of the passengers sustained injuries despite the severe crash.</li><li>The incident was captured on CCTV, showing the SUV spiraling out of control before hitting a showroom.</li><li>After the flip, the passengers calmly entered the showroom and asked for tea.</li><li>The group was traveling from Nagaur to Bikaner.</li></ul><blockquote>“No one was hurt...not even a single scratch. As soon as they entered, they asked for tea,” said an amused official from the showroom.</blockquote><p>This incredible incident highlights both the potential dangers of high-speed driving and the resilience of the passengers involved.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/caught-on-cctv-car-flips-8-times-on-rajasthan-highway-passengers-escape-unhurt-ask-for-tea-101734783606673.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/caught-on-cctv-car-flips-8-times-on-rajasthan-highway-passengers-escape-unhurt-ask-for-tea-101734783606673.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 12:38:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>