<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:51:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:51:08 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session LIVE: ‘Rahul clueless on pages in Constitution', says Thakur - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxQaW5tNFpNQ3d4Yk93a3M2QU95cms2M0RVbzNRV0VCbWpIbl85VjF2WU9WbE9YOWphdUlLQk83dzlZZjR2enpOT2RObFFFY2Q3dGlnSW4wcW1BRjgwaHVjRkdwOWYweUZMT3ctM2ZCVjE0VmR5cUJWR0pEM3dpTFJCWkJFbnpJT0FVLXlZeWRkaHZlalNDWWRrZFF1b0o2OURGRVRKVEZSM0xoSDl4SldjaHlvcm52aExmYjZyOHBLcGYwTHFsX3VwVGdiTDF0V2VRRGxqLWhvX3pWVVlyNzRVQV9xaUIyMXlwbFF3dFVPZVN4RWQ1djJMdTU0TDdsbmfSAYQCQVVfeXFMUDVyY3hPOWR6SFlCX3h5cm52cXRGaUZNdEwycHhwM2ZiVHVRZDlqMVRhbzlYUF9zeWUtS0FpcDE5bWZiVS0zUGR1elJyUUhNcnBvYUVCOW5fckpfTEUxLW1DZDluWVVQY1JrVnUtaUJGSjhJRVdTVEZUbUNDUnpyT1VnbkhmVHNqcl81aGpFb2t3Y2lHWk1neEZLZEhxdFFNNW5oOVU1TXZGM0ktb3VBMWVqNkNsMlJsYVprX1puQjIwd1dUaEh2emFlX3hwc19teWhsYTktQUpTZ2EwaGRqLWo2d2ZXNDVXRnp3YzBzR29oWFFUVDcwSmlnLXByOTFiVWkxYnA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxQaW5tNFpNQ3d4Yk93a3M2QU95cms2M0RVbzNRV0VCbWpIbl85VjF2WU9WbE9YOWphdUlLQk83dzlZZjR2enpOT2RObFFFY2Q3dGlnSW4wcW1BRjgwaHVjRkdwOWYweUZMT3ctM2ZCVjE0VmR5cUJWR0pEM3dpTFJCWkJFbnpJT0FVLXlZeWRkaHZlalNDWWRrZFF1b0o2OURGRVRKVEZSM0xoSDl4SldjaHlvcm52aExmYjZyOHBLcGYwTHFsX3VwVGdiTDF0V2VRRGxqLWhvX3pWVVlyNzRVQV9xaUIyMXlwbFF3dFVPZVN4RWQ1djJMdTU0TDdsbmfSAYQCQVVfeXFMUDVyY3hPOWR6SFlCX3h5cm52cXRGaUZNdEwycHhwM2ZiVHVRZDlqMVRhbzlYUF9zeWUtS0FpcDE5bWZiVS0zUGR1elJyUUhNcnBvYUVCOW5fckpfTEUxLW1DZDluWVVQY1JrVnUtaUJGSjhJRVdTVEZUbUNDUnpyT1VnbkhmVHNqcl81aGpFb2t3Y2lHWk1neEZLZEhxdFFNNW5oOVU1TXZGM0ktb3VBMWVqNkNsMlJsYVprX1puQjIwd1dUaEh2emFlX3hwc19teWhsYTktQUpTZ2EwaGRqLWo2d2ZXNDVXRnp3YzBzR29oWFFUVDcwSmlnLXByOTFiVWkxYnA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:29:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Dissolve govt today and hold elections': SP chief Akhilesh Yadav's challenge to PM Modi on 'one nation, - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/dissolve-govt-today-and-hold-elections-sp-chief-akhilesh-yadavs-challenge-to-pm-modi-on-one-nation-one-election/articleshow/116313655.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/dissolve-govt-today-and-hold-elections-sp-chief-akhilesh-yadavs-challenge-to-pm-modi-on-one-nation-one-election/articleshow/116313655.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bihar Teacher Kidnapped On Way To School, Forced To Marry Woman At Gunpoint - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bihar-teacher-kidnapped-on-way-to-school-forced-to-marry-woman-at-gunpoint-7246439</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bihar-teacher-kidnapped-on-way-to-school-forced-to-marry-woman-at-gunpoint-7246439</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:34:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Political Updates | 'Indian farmers being treated like it's Pak border', says Bajrang Punia on use of tear gas, water cannon - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Political Updates | 17-18 people injured in police action at Sambhu border, says farmer leader Sarwan Singh</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 14 December 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p>

<!-- Image section is excluded as none is provided -->

<p>A delegation of BJP leaders has accused the Aam Aadmi Party of manipulating votes, while farmers are in the midst of a 'Dilli Chalo' march facing police resistance at the Sambhu border, leading to injuries among protesters.</p>

<ul>
    <li>17-18 people injured due to police action during farmer protests at Sambhu border, according to farmer leader Sarwan Singh.</li>
    <li>Heavy police presence deployed to disperse the 'Dilli Chalo' march initiative by farmers.</li>
    <li>Police used tear gas and water cannons against protesting farmers.</li>
    <li>BJP discusses evidence of alleged fake votes ahead of upcoming Delhi Assembly polls.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
    <p>"Both the forums have decided to withdraw the 'jatha' today. We are hearing that 17-18 people have been injured. We will hold a PC after some time and inform about the further action." - Sarwan Singh Pandher</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The ongoing protests highlight significant tensions between farmer groups and law enforcement, reflecting broader political strains as elections approach. Observers are keenly watching how these events unfold.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/india-politics-news-live-updates-bjp-congress-aap-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-priyanka-gandhi-arvind-kejriwal-delhi-polls-one-nation-one-election-farmers-protest-dilli-chalo-shambhu-border-3317476</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/india-politics-news-live-updates-bjp-congress-aap-narendra-modi-rahul-gandhi-priyanka-gandhi-arvind-kejriwal-delhi-polls-one-nation-one-election-farmers-protest-dilli-chalo-shambhu-border-3317476</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:17:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BPSC 70th Prelims Exam 2024 Live Updates: Exam analysis, paper leak allegations - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BPSC 70th CCE Prelims Exam 2024 Live Updates: Exam analysis, paper leak allegations</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/BPSC-1.jpg?w=640" alt="BPSC 70th Prelims Exam 2024 Live Updates: The BPSC CCE 70th preliminary exam will be held in a single shift from 12 noon to 2 pm" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>BPSC 70th Prelims Exam 2024 Live Updates: The BPSC CCE 70th preliminary exam will be held in a single shift from 12 noon to 2 pm. (Representative image)</figcaption>
<p>In the BPSC 70th preliminary exam, conducted across 912 centers, negative marking will be implemented for incorrect answers. Only successful candidates will proceed to the main exam.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The exam took place in a single shift from 12 noon to 2 pm.</li>
    <li>Over 4.83 lakh aspirants registered for the exam.</li>
    <li>2,035 vacancies will be filled as part of this recruitment process.</li>
    <li>No normalization of marks will be conducted as the exam is in 'one shift, one paper' format.</li>
    <li>The dates for the BPSC CCE 70th main exam will be announced after the prelims results.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Negative markings will be applied for incorrect answers. Only those who pass the preliminary exam will be eligible to take the BPSC CCE main exam.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the BPSC 70th preliminary exam is a significant step for over 4.83 lakh aspirants, setting the stage for future recruitment opportunities in the state.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/education/bpsc-70th-cce-prelims-2024-live-updates-exam-guidelines-feedback-analysis-answer-key-cut-off-9722519/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/education/bpsc-70th-cce-prelims-2024-live-updates-exam-guidelines-feedback-analysis-answer-key-cut-off-9722519/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:06:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi now capital of crime, people worried: Arvind Kejriwal writes to Amit Shah - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi now capital of crime, people worried: Arvind Kejriwal writes to Amit Shah</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/PTI12-11-2024-000319A-0_1734159991007_1734160078553.jpg" alt="Arvind Kejriwal addresses the media in New Delhi.(PTI)">
    <figcaption>Arvind Kejriwal addresses the media in New Delhi.(PTI)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Arvind Kejriwal has expressed grave concerns about the escalating crime rates in Delhi, urging a meeting with Union Home Minister Amit Shah to address the issues related to law and order.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kejriwal's letter highlights Delhi's alarming status as the "crime capital" of India, particularly for crimes against women.</li>
    <li>Delhi ranks first in murder cases and experiences a rise in extortion and bomb threats.</li>
    <li>A 350% increase in drug-related crimes has been reported, raising security fears among residents.</li>
    <li>Kejriwal criticized the BJP's handling of law enforcement in the capital and called for unity among Delhi's citizens.</li>
    <li>The Delhi High Court has mandated a comprehensive action plan to address bomb threats, setting an eight-week deadline.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "Delhi's law and order is under the Central Government, but Delhi is now being known as the capital of crime." - Arvind Kejriwal
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
    "Amit Shah ji has ruined Delhi. He has turned Delhi into a jungle raj. People are living a life of terror everywhere." - Arvind Kejriwal
</blockquote>
<p>The crisis in Delhi’s law and order management has led to growing discontent among residents, prompting calls for urgent governmental action to restore safety and security in the capital.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-now-capital-of-crime-people-worried-arvind-kejriwal-writes-to-amit-shah-101734159945328.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-now-capital-of-crime-people-worried-arvind-kejriwal-writes-to-amit-shah-101734159945328.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 07:10:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rajasthan RPSC Assistant Professor Online Form 2025 - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxOUktMOTg3ZU8wcEY1cTZTRXp6dkpVQmtjTzRXWUVvNkphQVRYY1g2bUlwb0tsTmw5TmlYNW8xekpRV2tUOTJrUmxSMDJmakU2dkhkc2xVVFZfM2VvZ1VmLUZvRjhPX2twRGJHMHo4eUhWQ3VFNUlwblR4ZGo3MEYzYU9ZdFdacTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxOUktMOTg3ZU8wcEY1cTZTRXp6dkpVQmtjTzRXWUVvNkphQVRYY1g2bUlwb0tsTmw5TmlYNW8xekpRV2tUOTJrUmxSMDJmakU2dkhkc2xVVFZfM2VvZ1VmLUZvRjhPX2twRGJHMHo4eUhWQ3VFNUlwblR4ZGo3MEYzYU9ZdFdacTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:30:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Though S.52 TP Act Doesn't Make Pendente Lite Transfer Void, Court Can Invalidate Such Sale Exercising... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Though S.52 TP Act Doesn't Make Pendente Lite Transfer Void, Court Can Invalidate Such Sale Exercising Contempt Jurisdiction</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> September 21, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p>
<!-- Image section is excluded as there is no image provided -->
<p>The Supreme Court ruled that while a transfer during ongoing court proceedings is not automatically void, it can be invalidated if done in contempt of court orders.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The case involved a contempt petition filed by Celir LLP regarding a property auctioned under the SARFAESI Act.</li>
    <li>The Supreme Court ruled that even if Section 52 of the Transfer of Property Act does not make such transfers void, courts can reverse them to uphold judicial authority.</li>
    <li>The transaction in question occurred after a Supreme Court petition was filed, highlighting contempt of judicial directions.</li>
    <li>The Court emphasized the need for respect towards the court's authority and the judicial process.</li>
    <li>Senior Advocates represented the involved parties in the case.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>"The mere conduct of parties aimed at frustrating the court proceedings or circumventing its decisions, even without an explicit prohibitory order, constitutes contempt. Such actions interfere with the administration of justice." - Supreme Court</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The court's decision reinforces the importance of adhering to court directions and maintaining the integrity of the judicial system, even in the context of property transfers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/though-s52-tp-act-doesnt-make-pendente-lite-transfer-void-court-can-invalidate-such-sale-exercising-contempt-power-supreme-court-278337</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/though-s52-tp-act-doesnt-make-pendente-lite-transfer-void-court-can-invalidate-such-sale-exercising-contempt-power-supreme-court-278337</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:19:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[E.V.K.S. Elangovan, senior Congress leader and Erode (East) MLA, no more - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>E.V.K.S. Elangovan, senior Congress leader and Erode (East) MLA, no more</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/pohwxh/article68984563.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/9870_31_5_2024_12_35_21_2_ER01EVKS2.JPG" alt="Erode (East) MLA E.V.K.S. Elangovan. File photo." title="Erode (East) MLA E.V.K.S. Elangovan. File photo.">
<figcaption>Erode (East) MLA E.V.K.S. Elangovan. File photo. | Photo Credit: M. Govarthan</figcaption>
<p>Former chief of the Tamil Nadu Congress Committee (TNCC) and former Union Minister of State, E.V.K.S. Elangovan, passed away in Chennai on Saturday morning after a brief illness at the age of 73.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Mr. Elangovan was admitted to MIOT hospital on November 13.</li>
    <li>He is survived by his wife and a son.</li>
    <li>He represented Erode (East), a seat previously held by his deceased son, E. Thirumahan Everaa.</li>
    <li>He was a prominent figure in Tamil Nadu politics, serving as TNCC president twice.</li>
    <li>He was also a former Union Minister of State, with responsibilities in key sectors such as Petroleum and Commerce.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"He held the post of TNCC president twice - 2000 to 2002 and 2014 to 2016 when the party was increasingly getting marginalised in the State politics."</blockquote>
<p>With a notable political lineage, Mr. Elangovan's contributions to the Congress party and Tamil Nadu politics have left a lasting impact.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/tamil-nadu/evks-elangovan-senior-congress-leader-and-erode-east-mla-no-more/article68984569.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/tamil-nadu/evks-elangovan-senior-congress-leader-and-erode-east-mla-no-more/article68984569.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LK Advani, veteran BJP leader, admitted to Apollo Hospital in Delhi - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>LK Advani, veteran BJP leader, admitted to Apollo Hospital in Delhi</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/ANI-20240609060-0_1719481946989_1734152494571.jpg" alt="Bharat Ratna and veteran Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) leader LK Advani.(ANI File)" title="Bharat Ratna and veteran Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) leader LK Advani.(ANI File)">
<figcaption>Bharat Ratna and veteran Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) leader LK Advani.(ANI File)</figcaption>
<p>Veteran BJP leader Lal Krishna Advani has been admitted to Apollo Hospital in New Delhi, where he is currently in stable condition and under observation.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Advani, aged 96, is being treated by Dr. Vinit Suri, a senior neurology consultant.</li>
    <li>He was admitted two days ago, and this is not his first hospitalization at this facility this year.</li>
    <li>The specific reason for his recent admission has not yet been disclosed.</li>
    <li>Advani is a key figure in the BJP's rise to prominence and has had a long political career since joining the party in 1951.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Advani is widely recognized for guiding the BJP from a mere two seats in the 1984 general election to becoming a national force in the 1990s."</blockquote>
<p>Advani's contributions and leadership have significantly impacted Indian politics, especially through his role in the Ram Janmabhoomi movement, which strengthened the BJP's political position.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/lk-advani-veteran-bjp-leader-admitted-to-apollo-hospial-in-delhi-101734152437663.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/lk-advani-veteran-bjp-leader-admitted-to-apollo-hospial-in-delhi-101734152437663.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Our children are brave servants of Allah’, read Delhi schools' bomb threat email - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Our children are brave servants of Allah’, read Delhi schools' bomb threat email</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> HT News Desk</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Security-personnel-outside-DPS--RK-Puram-after-the_1734149953538_1734149963892.jpg" alt="Police officials, fire service department, dog squad and bomb detection teams are currently present at the schools.(Sanchit Khanna/HT photo)" title="Police officials, fire service department, dog squad and bomb detection teams are currently present at the schools.(Sanchit Khanna/HT photo)">
  <figcaption>Police officials, fire service department, dog squad and bomb detection teams are currently present at the schools.(Sanchit Khanna/HT photo)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Day after 30 schools in Delhi received bomb threats, several schools in the city were sent similar threats via email on Saturday, police said.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bomb threat emails were sent to several schools in Delhi, including Delhi Public School, RK Puram, and Ryan International School, Vasant Kunj.</li>
  <li>The email was sent from childrenofallah@outlook.com and signed under the name of Barry Allah.</li>
  <li>The email stated that "Our children are brave servants of Allah. They shall complete their task."</li>
  <li>Police and security teams are currently searching the school premises, with nothing suspicious found yet.</li>
  <li>Previous bomb threat emails on Monday demanded $30,000 and threatened to detonate small bombs hidden in the buildings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  "Our bomb vests are blessed by the Prophet Muhammad. They shall not fail their goal. Our children are brave servants of Allah. They shall complete their task."
</blockquote>
<p>The bomb threat emails have raised concerns among parents and school staff, with police assuring them that thorough investigations are ongoing and safety remains their top priority.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/our-children-brave-servants-of-allah-read-delhi-schools-bomb-threat-email-101734149367473.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/our-children-brave-servants-of-allah-read-delhi-schools-bomb-threat-email-101734149367473.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 04:23:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP announces Ram temple construction in Bengal amid row over TMC MLA's Babri Masjid remarks - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/bjp-announces-ram-temple-construction-in-bengal-amid-row-over-tmc-mlas-babri-masjid-remarks/articleshow/116305677.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/bjp-announces-ram-temple-construction-in-bengal-amid-row-over-tmc-mlas-babri-masjid-remarks/articleshow/116305677.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 03:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Terrible Tragedies": India As 3 Students Killed In Canada - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxPWm1hQzNUS3A1dzBQbWRVcE1NWG5qQW84b2Q1TEJtMnFWcF9BOXNJRllEQnBsSjJvWjE0RmY2eHZKU0lIbUkwYktEOF9ITXkzUXgzS0ZQaXZ2U3BnVFRwN21YbjV4UDZUMlN3TjBIT1JPOWltZjJVaG1YNVBDOE5Ja2dETnBRZlc0eU9fa1d6RDhUYWJ0c0dtc0RnbmhfckNjMTdaR9IBrAFBVV95cUxQb2tPMGpEWmVXcmFQYmk0OFNlUFRBZTBtTFVOTVUtSGJhSjdtT1B6RldSblRxaTdZaXVUa0QxZW40MU1oSWo2R2pQdGl6cm13VEF2cG1pc1V3YjBCZFdXcTVrYUdKM1JkRGlUXzFXcFNVRnZGRy1ndHc5RjdEYVgtWFpMdWVQalJsbjh5YkRQWFFZbnZzdlplUWdOUG1hLUg4QVRVN0NhT0cxd2VP?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxPWm1hQzNUS3A1dzBQbWRVcE1NWG5qQW84b2Q1TEJtMnFWcF9BOXNJRllEQnBsSjJvWjE0RmY2eHZKU0lIbUkwYktEOF9ITXkzUXgzS0ZQaXZ2U3BnVFRwN21YbjV4UDZUMlN3TjBIT1JPOWltZjJVaG1YNVBDOE5Ja2dETnBRZlc0eU9fa1d6RDhUYWJ0c0dtc0RnbmhfckNjMTdaR9IBrAFBVV95cUxQb2tPMGpEWmVXcmFQYmk0OFNlUFRBZTBtTFVOTVUtSGJhSjdtT1B6RldSblRxaTdZaXVUa0QxZW40MU1oSWo2R2pQdGl6cm13VEF2cG1pc1V3YjBCZFdXcTVrYUdKM1JkRGlUXzFXcFNVRnZGRy1ndHc5RjdEYVgtWFpMdWVQalJsbjh5YkRQWFFZbnZzdlplUWdOUG1hLUg4QVRVN0NhT0cxd2VP?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 02:57:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switzerland Suspends Most Favoured Nation Status To India Over Nestle Ruling - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Switzerland Suspends Most Favoured Nation Status To India Over Nestle Ruling</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Switzerland MFN Status Suspension">
    <figcaption>This means that Switzerland will tax dividends that Indian entities will earn in that country at 10 per cent from January 1, 2025.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The Swiss government has suspended the most favoured nation (MFN) status in the Double Taxation Avoidance Agreement (DTAA) with India, citing a recent Supreme Court ruling, potentially leading to increased taxes on Indian firms operating in Switzerland.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The decision follows a ruling by the Indian Supreme Court regarding the application of the MFN clause in tax treaties.</li>
    <li>From January 1, 2025, Switzerland will impose a 10% tax on dividends to Indian tax residents.</li>
    <li>This suspension could impact Swiss investments in India and raise tax liabilities for Indian companies.</li>
    <li>Experts warn that this move complicates international tax treaty navigation and may lead to inequities.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “This suspension may lead to increased tax liabilities for Indian entities operating in Switzerland, highlighting the complexities of navigating international tax treaties in an evolving global landscape." - Sandeep Jhunjhunwala, Nangia Andersen M&A Tax Partner.
</blockquote>
<p>In summary, the suspension of the MFN status marks a significant shift in the bilateral tax treaty dynamics between Switzerland and India, raising concerns over tax implications for involved entities.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/switzerland-suspends-most-favoured-nation-status-to-india-over-nestle-ruling-9155810.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/switzerland-suspends-most-favoured-nation-status-to-india-over-nestle-ruling-9155810.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 02:55:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Businessman under ED lens dies by suicide along with wife, alleges harassment because he worked for Congress, Rahul Gandhi - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Businessman under ED lens dies by suicide along with wife, alleges harassment because he worked for Congress, Rahul Gandhi</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 8, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<p>On Friday morning, a businessman and his wife were found dead in their home in Madhya Pradesh’s Sehore district, with the husband alleging harassment linked to his political affiliations in a suicide note.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Manoj Parmar and his wife Neha died by suicide at their residence; their children discovered them.</li>
    <li>Parmar left a note accusing the Enforcement Directorate (ED) of harassment related to the investigation he was under.</li>
    <li>He claimed that the ED targeted him due to his association with Congress and its leader Rahul Gandhi.</li>
    <li>Authorities, including Sehore Superintendent of Police, are investigating the circumstances surrounding their deaths and verifying the note's authenticity.</li>
    <li>The ED denied allegations regarding their conduct during recent raids on Parmar's properties.</li>
    <li>The case originates from CBI allegations of loan fraud involving approximately Rs 6 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“After my death, the responsibility of these children is yours and of the Congress, so a message goes out that the party stands with its workers.” - Manoj Parmar</blockquote>
<p>The situation has escalated into a political controversy, with claims of harassment and demands for an impartial investigation into the ED's actions.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/businessman-under-ed-lens-dies-by-suicide-along-with-wife-alleges-harassment-because-he-worked-for-congress-rahul-gandhi-9723872/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/businessman-under-ed-lens-dies-by-suicide-along-with-wife-alleges-harassment-because-he-worked-for-congress-rahul-gandhi-9723872/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 01:50:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Haryana Weather and AQI Today: Check weather forecast for December 14, 2024 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Haryana Weather and AQI Today: Check weather forecast for December 14, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/05/29/550x309/heatwave_1682126178495_1717001728091_1717001745747.jpg" alt="Haryana weather update on December 14, 2024" title="Haryana weather update on December 14, 2024">
<figcaption>Haryana weather update on December 14, 2024</figcaption>
<p>The weather forecast for Haryana today indicates a clear sky with moderate air quality, ideal for planning outdoor activities.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The current temperature in Haryana is 18.27 °C.</li>
    <li>Minimum and maximum temperatures are predicted to be 9.86 °C and 23.56 °C, respectively.</li>
    <li>Relative humidity is at 17% with a wind speed of 17 km/h.</li>
    <li>The Air Quality Index (AQI) stands at 141.0, classified as moderate.</li>
    <li>Tomorrow's forecast predicts a minimum and maximum temperature of 10.15 °C and 24.12 °C, respectively.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Children and people with respiratory diseases, such as asthma, should limit prolonged outdoor activity.”</blockquote>
<p>Plan accordingly to enjoy the weather while being mindful of air quality conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/haryana-weather-today-aqi-and-rain-forecast-updates-december-14-2024-101734139862314.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/haryana-weather-today-aqi-and-rain-forecast-updates-december-14-2024-101734139862314.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 01:31:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai Weather and AQI Today: Warm start at 22.99 °C, check weather forecast for December 14, 2024 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Weather and AQI Today: Warm start at 22.99 °C, check weather forecast for December 14, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/05/29/550x309/heatwave_1682126178495_1717001728091_1717001745747.jpg" alt="Mumbai weather update on December 14, 2024" title="Mumbai weather update on December 14, 2024">
<figcaption>Mumbai weather update on December 14, 2024</figcaption>
<p>The article provides a weather forecast and air quality index (AQI) update for Mumbai on December 14, 2024, highlighting current temperatures and upcoming predictions.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Current temperature in Mumbai is 26.06 °C, with a range of 22.99 °C (min) to 27.88 °C (max).</li>
    <li>Relative humidity stands at 40% and wind speed is 40 km/h.</li>
    <li>Tomorrow’s forecast predicts temperatures between 23.31 °C and 27.6 °C with 35% humidity.</li>
    <li>The AQI today is at 182, classified as moderate, suggesting limited outdoor activity for sensitive groups.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "Being aware of the AQI helps one make informed decisions regarding one's overall well-being."
</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, residents are advised to stay informed about the weather and AQI in order to plan their activities appropriately.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/mumbai-news/mumbai-weather-today-aqi-and-rain-forecast-updates-december-14-2024-101734139823642.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/mumbai-news/mumbai-weather-today-aqi-and-rain-forecast-updates-december-14-2024-101734139823642.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 01:30:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahua Moitra accuses Kiren Rijiju of 'threatening' her in Lok Sabha, writes to Inter-Parliamentary Union - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahua Moitra accuses Kiren Rijiju of 'threatening' her in Lok Sabha, writes to Inter-Parliamentary Union</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> 13 December 2024, 22:14 IST</p>
<p>Trinamool Congress Lok Sabha MP Mahua Moitra has accused Parliamentary Affairs Minister Kiren Rijiju of threatening her during a session in Lok Sabha and has formally reported the incident to the Inter-Parliamentary Union.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Moitra claimed that Rijiju threatened her in violation of parliamentary rules.</li>
    <li>She stated that Speaker Om Birla acknowledged the threat but took no action against Rijiju.</li>
    <li>Moitra has complained to the Inter-Parliamentary Union regarding ongoing gender harassment and intimidation.</li>
    <li>The controversy arose during a debate on the 75 years of the Indian Constitution, where Moitra referenced the controversial death of Judge B H Loya.</li>
    <li>Rijiju warned Moitra of "appropriate parliamentary action" for raising settled matters.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"So Kiren Rijiju openly threatens me in Lok Sabha today in complete violation of parliamentary rules & procedure," - Mahua Moitra</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights ongoing tensions and controversies within the Indian Parliament, particularly around issues of gender and freedom of speech.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/delhi/mahua-moitra-accuses-kiren-rijiju-of-threatening-her-in-lok-sabha-writes-to-inter-parliamentary-union-3317187</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/delhi/mahua-moitra-accuses-kiren-rijiju-of-threatening-her-in-lok-sabha-writes-to-inter-parliamentary-union-3317187</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 22:14:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RG Kar rape and murder trial: Ex-principal, cop get bail as CBI fails to file chargesheet on time - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[```html
<h1>RG Kar rape and murder trial: Ex-principal, cop get bail as CBI fails to file chargesheet on time</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/RG-Kar-1.jpg?w=640" alt="RG Kar bail" width="640" height="360">
  <figcaption>Sandip Ghosh, former principal of R G Kar Medical College and Hospital, and Abhijit Mondol former OC of Tala police. (File Photo)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A sessions court in Sealdah granted bail to the former principal of RG Kar hospital, Sandip Ghosh, and former officer-in-charge of Tala police station Abhijit Mondal after the CBI failed to submit a chargesheet within the mandatory 90-day period in connection with the rape and murder of a junior doctor at the state-run hospital.</p>
<ol>
  <li>The junior doctor was raped and murdered, and her body was found in the seminar room of the hospital in Kolkata on the morning of August 9.</li>
  <li>The CBI arrested Ghosh and Mondal on September 14 for alleged tampering of evidence and delay in filing the FIR.</li>
  <li>The CBI had already submitted its chargesheet against the prime accused, Sanjay Roy, a civic volunteer.</li>
  <li>The additional chief judicial magistrate (ACJM) granted bail to Ghosh and Mondal on furnishing bail bonds of Rs 2,000 each.</li>
  <li>Mondal is set to be released, while Ghosh is likely to stay in prison due to another case of alleged financial irregularities.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>“My client has suffered for more than 90 days. May he be released,” the suspended cop’s lawyer, Mohd Zakir, told the ACJM.</blockquote>
<p>The CBI’s failure to file the chargesheet within the statutory period led to the accused being granted bail, highlighting the importance of timely legal proceedings.</p>
```]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/r-g-kar-ex-principal-bail-rape-murder-junior-doctor-case-9723220/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/r-g-kar-ex-principal-bail-rape-murder-junior-doctor-case-9723220/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:30:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maha Kumbh will become a 'maha yagya of unity': PM Modi - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/maha-kumbh-will-become-a-maha-yagya-of-unity-pm-modi/articleshow/116301020.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/maha-kumbh-will-become-a-maha-yagya-of-unity-pm-modi/articleshow/116301020.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winter tightens grip on Kashmir - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNcUh2aWtmWjMwME5iUVdOS0lYT3EtNVVOdWk4UlFLbDZURTNRaTZnemtMTUtiNHpVNG5MYUtpb2RXRC1LcFJiM05fZXR6ZmpUbkoydWR6dzBVa1U4UF9tWmxlaldiVG9NQ21PNUlhREt3MG5hb0ZkdnRjSVZiZ1l0cDNn0gGGAUFVX3lxTE5CLTVkem9FMDVZeDlzRWFnc1dKdjRRSVRaTEVMQ1licU1NMDBNTjZiMGVHWXZwektmR1VMZkxUNkZsWGFNcXp1SFRtQ3UyRmYwMjU4UHpQd3pKaHJ0UFp2dFR1WUxTcHVfamo2blJoMU41dFRscWN5THFoVW80UXViT3NaaFN3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNcUh2aWtmWjMwME5iUVdOS0lYT3EtNVVOdWk4UlFLbDZURTNRaTZnemtMTUtiNHpVNG5MYUtpb2RXRC1LcFJiM05fZXR6ZmpUbkoydWR6dzBVa1U4UF9tWmxlaldiVG9NQ21PNUlhREt3MG5hb0ZkdnRjSVZiZ1l0cDNn0gGGAUFVX3lxTE5CLTVkem9FMDVZeDlzRWFnc1dKdjRRSVRaTEVMQ1licU1NMDBNTjZiMGVHWXZwektmR1VMZkxUNkZsWGFNcXp1SFRtQ3UyRmYwMjU4UHpQd3pKaHJ0UFp2dFR1WUxTcHVfamo2blJoMU41dFRscWN5THFoVW80UXViT3NaaFN3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 19:20:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Actor Darshan, Others Granted Bail In Renukaswamy Murder Case - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPNG1zczFzOURmOWNoWUZIQktaZnBYS2tLYnpNSGNsOUFSV1YxMW5YX2d5WVZQdllvcEw4b1BOT0JuRlpHN05oQ0dfU0lHTldRcF9TQWFrTEhWMGRXLVFVaVdvY25wcWZxVEZKNEEwMkZEdXVxLVh0RXRORjNwY1ZPMjM1aVhGS1ltQzYzSTZ1cTAxRVNMR21jR1llWFNwcEhYR0HSAaoBQVVfeXFMTjlJSEw5Q1h4aFZ2MkROM0dSTnZwTFdHOTRYT3lFZlBvdGZTdEZCU2t5c1F2SWFaU19DOVN6M3ZGTHB5QlFoaERiX1A1TUxoNXR3VUExM3RNaFVxWjgtS1dBOXBScU90Rko0dkJXd0dfSTg3SHJIVllxMVljaFdCZUtkRU5vVWdUd0FMejdZZlJFVThEUlVZMWlpWENiaklJZXowcWRpQkRxeWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPNG1zczFzOURmOWNoWUZIQktaZnBYS2tLYnpNSGNsOUFSV1YxMW5YX2d5WVZQdllvcEw4b1BOT0JuRlpHN05oQ0dfU0lHTldRcF9TQWFrTEhWMGRXLVFVaVdvY25wcWZxVEZKNEEwMkZEdXVxLVh0RXRORjNwY1ZPMjM1aVhGS1ltQzYzSTZ1cTAxRVNMR21jR1llWFNwcEhYR0HSAaoBQVVfeXFMTjlJSEw5Q1h4aFZ2MkROM0dSTnZwTFdHOTRYT3lFZlBvdGZTdEZCU2t5c1F2SWFaU19DOVN6M3ZGTHB5QlFoaERiX1A1TUxoNXR3VUExM3RNaFVxWjgtS1dBOXBScU90Rko0dkJXd0dfSTg3SHJIVllxMVljaFdCZUtkRU5vVWdUd0FMejdZZlJFVThEUlVZMWlpWENiaklJZXowcWRpQkRxeWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 18:23:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heavy Rain in Tamil Nadu, Puducherry trigger waterlogging in Chennai; IMD predicts more shower | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Heavy Rain in Tamil Nadu, Puducherry trigger waterlogging in Chennai; IMD predicts more shower</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Citing the extreme weather conditions associated with a low-pressure area over the Southeast Bay of Bengal that intensified into a depression, heavy rainfall has affected Tamil Nadu and Puducherry, leading to waterlogging in Chennai.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Extremely heavy rainfall observed in Tamil Nadu, Puducherry, and Karaikal.</li>
    <li>The India Meteorological Department (IMD) issued an orange alert for very heavy rainfall expected on December 17.</li>
    <li>Flood alerts have been issued for low-lying areas near the Adyar River due to the release of water from Chembarambakkam reservoir.</li>
    <li>14 cm of rainfall recorded in Chembarambakkam area on December 12, increasing inflow to the reservoir.</li>
    <li>The reservoir currently stands at 23.29 feet, close to its full capacity of 24 feet.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“IMD issued heavy rainfall warnings for Tamil Nadu, Puducherry, coastal Andhra Pradesh, Rayalaseema and Karaikal on December 16 and 18.” — India Meteorological Department</blockquote>
<p>With heavy rains continuing, authorities are taking precautionary measures to mitigate flooding and ensure public safety in affected areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/india/heavy-rain-in-tamil-nadu-puducherry-trigger-waterlogging-in-chennai-imd-predicts-more-shower-11734101344615.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/india/heavy-rain-in-tamil-nadu-puducherry-trigger-waterlogging-in-chennai-imd-predicts-more-shower-11734101344615.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 15:02:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court Issues Notice On PIL Raising Issue Of Snake Bites In India - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Issues Notice On PIL Raising Issue Of Snake Bites In India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 13, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p>
<p>The Supreme Court has issued notice on a public interest litigation regarding the lack of treatment and awareness for snake bites in India, seeking responses from government entities implicated in the case.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The PIL was filed by Advocate Shailendra Mani Tripathi, whose mother was a snake bite victim in 2019.</li>
    <li>Snakebite envenomation is a significant health emergency affecting 1.8-2.7 million individuals globally, with India contributing around 58,000 deaths annually.</li>
    <li>The implementation of standard treatment guidelines from 2017 for snake bites remains inadequate in Indian healthcare facilities.</li>
    <li>Under-reporting of snakebite incidents leads to a significant underestimation of the burden, with fatalities likely much higher than official figures.</li>
    <li>India is described as the "snakebite capital of the world," accounting for nearly half of global snakebite deaths.</li>
    <li>The petition requests improved access to anti-venom and establishment of dedicated treatment facilities and awareness campaigns.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“India is one of the world's most affected countries due to the large population engaged in agricultural activities, the presence of numerous venomous snakes, and lack of community awareness regarding prevention and control of snakebites.”</blockquote>
<blockquote>“A very large community level study of snakebite deaths in India gave a direct estimate of 45,900 deaths in 2005, which is over 30 times higher than the Government of India's official figure.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the Supreme Court's attention to this matter highlights the urgent need for systematic changes in how snakebites are managed and treated in India, advocating for better healthcare provision and public awareness to reduce fatalities associated with snake envenomation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-court-pil-non-availability-of-cure-awareness-snake-bites-notice-issued-278302</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-court-pil-non-availability-of-cure-awareness-snake-bites-notice-issued-278302</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 15:00:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India-Bangladesh relations: Bangladesh bends down before India, Yunus forced to buy... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India-Bangladesh relations: Bangladesh bends down before India, Yunus forced to buy...</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/India.com-2024-12-13T201901.256.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="India-Bangladesh relations: Bangladesh bends down before India, Yunus forced to buy...">
    <figcaption>Muhammad Yunus, the head of Bangladesh's interim government. (File)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Amidst rapidly deteriorating India-Bangladesh relations, Dhaka is facing a severe shortage of essential food items, prompting its interim government, led by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus, to seek assistance from India.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Bangladesh has imported 468 tonnes of potatoes from India amid food shortages.</li>
    <li>The shipment arrived at the Benapole railway station in Bangladesh's Jessore district.</li>
    <li>9,460 sacks of potatoes worth $1,007,640 were imported by Tata Traders from India.</li>
    <li>To reduce dependence on India, Bangladesh is also looking to import potatoes from Germany, Egypt, China, and Spain, and onions from China, Pakistan, and Turkey.</li>
    <li>Recent tensions include Bangladesh planning to import sugar from Pakistan, antagonizing India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "Bangladesh was mulling several options to control the price and supply of potatoes and onions." - Salim Uddin, Commerce Ministry Secretary
</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the relationship between India and Bangladesh has soured, especially with allegations of communal violence in Bangladesh and the current government's distancing from India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/india/india-bangladesh-relations-bangladesh-bends-down-before-india-muhammad-yunus-forced-to-buy-potatoes-dhaka-narendra-modi-pakistan-china-7463768/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/india/india-bangladesh-relations-bangladesh-bends-down-before-india-muhammad-yunus-forced-to-buy-potatoes-dhaka-narendra-modi-pakistan-china-7463768/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:52:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senthil Balaji Sabotaging Trial, Seeking Adjournments On Frivolous Grounds : ED Tells Supreme Court - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Senthil Balaji Sabotaging Trial, Seeking Adjournments On Frivolous Grounds: ED Tells Supreme Court</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p>

<p>The Enforcement Directorate (ED) has accused Tamil Nadu Minister Senthil Balaji of sabotaging his trial related to an alleged cash-for-jobs scam, claiming he is seeking adjournments for frivolous reasons.</p>

<ul>
    <li>The ED's Solicitor General Tushar Mehta stated that Balaji's actions demonstrate a deliberate attempt to delay the trial despite the Supreme Court's directives to expedite it.</li>
    <li>Balaji was reinstated as a Cabinet Minister shortly after his bail, raising concerns about witness intimidation.</li>
    <li>The Supreme Court has allowed the ED to file an affidavit regarding the matter, with a hearing scheduled for December 18, 2024.</li>
    <li>The affidavit details multiple adjournments related to Balaji's case and specific requests that caused further delays.</li>
    <li>Key witnesses in the case have been reportedly influenced by Balaji's ministerial position.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>“That despite this Hon'ble Court's directive to expedite the trial, Sh. V Senthil Balaji has drawn out the cross examination of PW-4 on one pretext or another for nearly two months." - ED's Affidavit</blockquote>

<p>The court highlighted concerns over how Balaji's appointment as a minister might affect the integrity of the trial, with Justice Oka remarking on the need for the same bench that granted bail to hear the matter.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/senthil-balaji-sabotaging-trial-seeking-adjournments-on-frivolous-grounds-ed-tells-supreme-court-278301</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/senthil-balaji-sabotaging-trial-seeking-adjournments-on-frivolous-grounds-ed-tells-supreme-court-278301</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:26:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru techie death: Wife and her family members abscond - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru techie death: Wife and her family members abscond</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/80ge4/article68984349.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_13_2024_000302B.jpg" alt="Police personnel in Jaunpur, Uttar Pradesh, on December 13, 2024, paste a notice at the residence of Nikita Singhania, wife of engineer Atul Subhash who ended his life in Bengaluru alleging harassment at the hands of his estranged wife and her family" title="Police personnel in Jaunpur, Uttar Pradesh, on December 13, 2024, paste a notice at the residence of Nikita Singhania, wife of engineer Atul Subhash who ended his life in Bengaluru alleging harassment at the hands of his estranged wife and her family">
<figcaption>Police personnel in Jaunpur, Uttar Pradesh, on December 13, 2024.</figcaption>
<p>A heartbreaking incident unfolds as Bengaluru techie Atul Subhash's wife and her family members evade police in connection with his suicide, marked by a death note alleging harassment.</p>
<ul>
    <li>A Bengaluru police team searched in Jaunpur, Uttar Pradesh for Atul Subhash's wife, Nikita Singhania, and her relatives.</li>
    <li>They are accused of abetting Atul's suicide, with a notice posted at their residence for questioning.</li>
    <li>Atul left a 40-page death note and an 81-minute video claiming harassment from his wife and family over false accusations and high alimony demands.</li>
    <li>Rumors of the family being detained have been denied by police, who continue their efforts to locate them.</li>
    <li>A campaign for justice for Atul has emerged among his friends.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "In his death note, Atul Subhash said that he had been pushed to end his life."
</blockquote>
<p>The case highlights serious issues of harassment and the need for accountability as the police intensify their search for the accused family members.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/techie-atul-subhash-suicide-wife-and-her-family-members-abscond/article68981703.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/techie-atul-subhash-suicide-wife-and-her-family-members-abscond/article68981703.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Priyanka Gandhi attacks BJP & RSS in debut speech. ‘It’s Samvidhaan, not Sangh-vidhaan’ - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Priyanka Gandhi attacks BJP & RSS in debut speech: 'It's Samvidhaan, not Sangh-vidhaan'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Print</p>

<p>In her debut speech in the Lok Sabha, Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra critiqued the ruling BJP for what she described as a shift away from the constitutional values of dialogue and discussion, asserting that the Constitution of India is not equivalent to the 'Sangh-vidhaan'.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Priyanka Gandhi delivered a nearly 40-minute speech, marking her first address in the Lok Sabha.</li>
    <li>She accused the BJP of creating a climate of fear, which she claimed has also affected the ruling party.</li>
    <li>She stated that the Constitution acts as a protective shield for justice and unity, warning that it is being undermined by the government.</li>
    <li>Gandhi referenced significant conversations with victims of violence to highlight the impact of current governance on marginalized communities.</li>
    <li>She criticized the Prime Minister's absence and discussed the government's failures while invoking historical political themes.</li>
    <li>Priyanka advocated for a nationwide caste census and called for the reinstatement of paper ballots in elections.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
    “The Constitution is a <em>‘suraksha kavach’</em> (protective shield) for the principles of justice, harmony, unity, equality, and freedom of speech. But the ruling side has been chipping away at that protective shield.”
</blockquote>

<p>Priyanka Gandhi's debut speech reflects her strategic political approach to connect with diverse voter bases and critiques the current government’s policies while emphasizing the relevance of the Constitution in contemporary India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/politics/priyanka-gandhi-attacks-bjp-rss-in-debut-speech-its-samvidhaan-not-sangh-vidhaan/2401247/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/politics/priyanka-gandhi-attacks-bjp-rss-in-debut-speech-its-samvidhaan-not-sangh-vidhaan/2401247/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:21:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bihar Civil Court Clerk Admit Card 2024- Out - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTFA5OUpzMW4wZEgwRnd0YmkwaVRnaDRkNEpjWUtYVU1KYUxxTVZING1paWxhN0tPdnNYdUtrZ3YxVlhzQU1lSkhBZXpuR3pzZWd4ZkRMSEZ1MEZVRWtaVFBDbVVpOUgzRHQ3YlljUE52Y0xIdm1mZ1FOcE9ZdHk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTFA5OUpzMW4wZEgwRnd0YmkwaVRnaDRkNEpjWUtYVU1KYUxxTVZING1paWxhN0tPdnNYdUtrZ3YxVlhzQU1lSkhBZXpuR3pzZWd4ZkRMSEZ1MEZVRWtaVFBDbVVpOUgzRHQ3YlljUE52Y0xIdm1mZ1FOcE9ZdHk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:47:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliament Winter Session Live Updates: Borders Shrinking, Minorities Targeted, Says Akhilesh Yadav - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxPV2lFd2UzZTI4TlFlLUpVWVdlOXpDMTROdFJkN3FuVmVocDU4bVdNRlRrRm9XUHlQX200STlZMWxtbFJNWTZxU2JXZ1NFR3BTenNFS0hjTU1WVm5XZ1ROZDNGbVdJZ2oxdlA2Vlk0WF96dEN0Ti02NEE4QmNuZWlMRmV6WElzY3NlS0hOMVFZRmY3aXNfd3lVQmtxU1U4ZEdZMXVtRThDR2hfUUM3ZVNKQ2ZnZ3c2TXkxa1NpX3QwcDJXcnhYcjlrUkZTaTljR1dZUzZHLWZYc0t4UkMyUkd3LVJoajFiaWNpcTZ3ZGZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxPV2lFd2UzZTI4TlFlLUpVWVdlOXpDMTROdFJkN3FuVmVocDU4bVdNRlRrRm9XUHlQX200STlZMWxtbFJNWTZxU2JXZ1NFR3BTenNFS0hjTU1WVm5XZ1ROZDNGbVdJZ2oxdlA2Vlk0WF96dEN0Ti02NEE4QmNuZWlMRmV6WElzY3NlS0hOMVFZRmY3aXNfd3lVQmtxU1U4ZEdZMXVtRThDR2hfUUM3ZVNKQ2ZnZ3c2TXkxa1NpX3QwcDJXcnhYcjlrUkZTaTljR1dZUzZHLWZYc0t4UkMyUkd3LVJoajFiaWNpcTZ3ZGZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:32:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>