<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 16:27:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 16:27:04 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Denied Cabinet Berth, Shiv Sena MLA Resigns From Party Post - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQWHRQTUtLNjBtb1ZBdUhpdVlSR2NMVFpQLVZPWUtJejRraUFKRS1BOVE5bFJPTmZhSmxPR2txVEZQYkU1UEJtVHlUeGFGaGVVMUlmSVVrVG9kNzRYTDJLRWxoZGVMTXBtMVl3MXNHY3prdklvVmRPa3lQZkFncmFIR3VCTy1KSlJrT2EtMUZJOEdhZkpYYk1fOWdCOWtmVGpmSjdjZGxNalg5RXQzS2podXgwN1lhUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQWHRQTUtLNjBtb1ZBdUhpdVlSR2NMVFpQLVZPWUtJejRraUFKRS1BOVE5bFJPTmZhSmxPR2txVEZQYkU1UEJtVHlUeGFGaGVVMUlmSVVrVG9kNzRYTDJLRWxoZGVMTXBtMVl3MXNHY3prdklvVmRPa3lQZkFncmFIR3VCTy1KSlJrT2EtMUZJOEdhZkpYYk1fOWdCOWtmVGpmSjdjZGxNalg5RXQzS2podXgwN1lhUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:12:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['When You Get 100 MPs, You Celebrate...' Omar Abdullah Slams Congress Over EVM Charge - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>When You Get 100 MPs, You Celebrate... Omar Abdullah Slams Congress Over EVM Charge</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024<strong> Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="He said parties should not contest elections if they do not trust the voting mechanism.(PTI photo file)"><figcaption>He said parties should not contest elections if they do not trust the voting mechanism.(PTI photo file)</figcaption><p>Omar Abdullah has criticized the Congress party for questioning the reliability of Electronic Voting Machines (EVMs) after its electoral losses, arguing that parties should not blame the voting mechanism when election results are unfavorable.</p><ul><li>Abdullah rebuffed Congress’s doubts about EVMs, emphasizing they can't question results only after losses.</li><li>He highlighted the need for consistency regarding trust in electoral mechanisms.</li><li>The Congress has called for a return to paper ballots following poor performance in recent state elections.</li><li>Abdullah drew on personal experience, stating he has faced defeat without blaming election systems.</li></ul><blockquote>“When you get a hundred plus members of Parliament using the same EVMs, and you celebrate that as sort of a victory for your party, you can’t then a few months later turn around and say… we don’t like these EVMs because now the election results aren’t going the way we would like them to.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Abdullah’s remarks reinforce the stance that political parties must own their electoral outcomes without shifting blame to the voting systems.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/politics/rift-in-india-bloc-widens-as-omar-abdullah-tells-ally-congress-to-stop-whining-about-evms-9156983.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/politics/rift-in-india-bloc-widens-as-omar-abdullah-tells-ally-congress-to-stop-whining-about-evms-9156983.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:02:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka President Anura Kumara Dissanayake arrives in New Delhi for three-day visit - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sri Lanka President Anura Kumara Dissanayake Arrives in New Delhi for Three-Day Visit</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/newsletter/the-evening-wrap/40wnl0/article68989050.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Ge1-OdVW0AAW33p.jpg" alt="Minister of State for Information and Broadcasting, Dr. S. Murugan and other diplomatic officials welcomed Mr. Dissanayake upon his arrival in India on Sunday (December 15, 2024).">
<figcaption>Minister of State for Information and Broadcasting, Dr. S. Murugan and other diplomatic officials welcomed Mr. Dissanayake upon his arrival in India on Sunday (December 15, 2024). | Photo Credit: X/@MEAIndia</figcaption>
<p>Sri Lanka President Anura Kumara Dissanayake arrived in New Delhi on December 15, 2024, for a three-day visit to strengthen bilateral relations with India.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Welcomed by Minister of State for Information and Broadcasting, Dr. S. Murugan, and other officials.</li>
  <li>First overseas visit after assuming the presidency.</li>
  <li>Plans to discuss bilateral matters with Minister of External Affairs Dr. S. Jaishankar and National Security Advisor Shri Ajit Doval.</li>
  <li>Visit follows an invitation from Dr. Jaishankar, who recently visited Colombo.</li>
  <li>His first official visit since NPP's historic victory in the parliamentary elections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Warm and special welcome! President <a href="https://twitter.com/anuradisanayake?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@anuradisanayake</a> of Sri Lanka was warmly received by MoS <a href="https://twitter.com/Murugan_MoS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Murugan_MoS</a> as he arrived in New Delhi. This is President Dissanayake's first bilateral visit to India since he assumed office.” — Randhir Jaiswal</blockquote>
<p>This visit marks a pivotal moment in strengthening India-Sri Lanka relations following a change in leadership in Sri Lanka.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/sri-lanka-president-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-arrives-in-new-delhi-for-three-day-visit/article68989051.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/sri-lanka-president-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-arrives-in-new-delhi-for-three-day-visit/article68989051.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UP Police Constable DV / PST Admit Card 2024 Out at uppbpb.gov.in - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTFBHTDJGc1dZclVlNUdlaUZzMHVVMlZfbkdJTHFvVDVHbzhFUm15SXNTVE9XaGlldzhOMVh0NUxCMV9QdGswUVZxdjNaTXYyeFZxSVRieUR5RnZaaVFuYnRJQVd2OTVIUVltOVY0R2FSOVNQbTRWNGV4c0xXdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTFBHTDJGc1dZclVlNUdlaUZzMHVVMlZfbkdJTHFvVDVHbzhFUm15SXNTVE9XaGlldzhOMVh0NUxCMV9QdGswUVZxdjNaTXYyeFZxSVRieUR5RnZaaVFuYnRJQVd2OTVIUVltOVY0R2FSOVNQbTRWNGV4c0xXdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:41:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra cabinet expansion: Ajit Pawar's message to NCP legislators not getting ministerial berths - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ajit Pawar's Message to NCP Legislators on Cabinet Expansion</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Ajit_Pawar_1734272258121_1734272258397.jpg" alt="Maharashtra deputy chief minister Ajit Pawar.(PTI file)" title="Maharashtra deputy chief minister Ajit Pawar.(PTI file)">
<figcaption>Maharashtra deputy chief minister Ajit Pawar.(PTI file)</figcaption>
<p>Maharashtra Deputy Chief Minister Ajit Pawar assured NCP legislators that those not appointed as Ministers in the recent cabinet expansion will have opportunities in the future during a gathering in Nagpur.</p>
<ul>
<li>39 ministers were sworn in, increasing cabinet strength to 42.</li>
<li>Pawar emphasized limited ministerial positions but expressed commitment to giving others a chance.</li>
<li>BJP received the largest share of ministerial posts with 19, followed by Shiv Sena with 11 and NCP with 9.</li>
<li>This cabinet expansion is part of a broader political landscape following the November assembly elections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Everybody wants to become a minister and deserves an opportunity, but the ministerial berths are limited.” - Ajit Pawar</blockquote>
<p>The cabinet expansion reflects ongoing political dynamics in Maharashtra, with significant implications for regional governance and party representation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maharashtra-cabinet-expansion-ajit-pawars-message-to-ncp-legislators-not-getting-ministerial-berths-101734270798623.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maharashtra-cabinet-expansion-ajit-pawars-message-to-ncp-legislators-not-getting-ministerial-berths-101734270798623.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:20:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abhishek Manu Singhvi: ‘One Nation, One Election will face serious Constitutional challenges … it violates the Basic Structure’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Abhishek Manu Singhvi: ‘One Nation, One Election will face serious Constitutional challenges … it violates the Basic Structure’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><p>The Centre is planning to introduce Bills for 'One Nation, One Election' in Parliament amid opposition concerns. Senior Congress leader Abhishek Manu Singhvi expresses legal and democratic objections to the proposed simultaneous elections.</p><ul><li>Singhvi argues that the plan undermines the democratic mandate and could lead to constitutional challenges.</li><li>He describes the concept as appealing but fundamentally flawed due to its imposition on the will of the people.</li><li>Reports suggest potential legal ramifications that could violate the Basic Structure of the Indian Constitution.</li><li>The Congress and many regional parties oppose the proposal, emphasizing the need for maintaining federalism.</li><li>Concerns are raised regarding the practicality of synchronizing elections and the alleged financial benefits claimed by the government.</li></ul><blockquote>“Democracy is a festival of diversity, uncertainty, spontaneous will.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Singhvi believes that while the initiative aims for uniformity, it risks undermining the essence of democracy in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/abhishek-manu-singhvi-interview-one-nation-one-election-9726522/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/abhishek-manu-singhvi-interview-one-nation-one-election-9726522/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Important MCQs Based On Latest Supreme Court Judgments For Law Examinations - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Important MCQs Based On Latest Supreme Court Judgments For Law Examinations</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [To be added] <strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p><p>The article provides multiple-choice questions based on recent Supreme Court judgments relevant to law examinations. Each question is followed by the correct answer and a brief explanation.</p><ul><li>Question 1 discusses the prosecution of a police officer without prior sanction under Section 197 Cr.P.C.</li><li>Question 2 addresses a breach of compromise in High Court proceedings.</li><li>Question 3 examines the necessity of a separate application for possession in specific performance cases.</li><li>Question 4 deals with the classification of mortgages based on conditions stipulated in a mortgage deed.</li><li>Question 5 focuses on the maintainability of a suit in light of the doctrine of constructive res-judicata.</li><li>Question 6 outlines the liability of a company's authorized officer in cheque dishonor cases.</li><li>Question 7 considers the arguments surrounding the intentionality of an accused in a murder case.</li><li>Question 8 questions the non-arbitrability of wages disputes under statutory jurisdiction.</li><li>Question 9 highlights the admissibility of disclosure statements made during transport to police custody.</li><li>Question 10 reviews the need for considering cross-examination in summoning applications under Section 319 Cr.P.C.</li></ul><p><strong>Notable Quotes or Statistics:</strong></p><blockquote>“The Supreme Court held that a police official who is accused of lodging a false case cannot claim that he cannot be prosecuted without sanction...”</blockquote><p>The article encapsulates recent developments in law through practical questions, making it an excellent study resource for law students preparing for examinations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/important-mcqs-based-on-latest-supreme-court-judgments-for-law-examinations-278403</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/important-mcqs-based-on-latest-supreme-court-judgments-for-law-examinations-278403</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:41:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[39 Maharashtra Ministers Join Devendra Fadnavis' Cabinet. Full List - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>39 Maharashtra Ministers Join Devendra Fadnavis' Cabinet</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Today | <strong>Source:</strong> Maharashtra Government</p><p>The much-awaited cabinet expansion of the Maharashtra government led by Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis took place, with 39 ministers taking their oaths in Nagpur.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>A total of 39 ministers were inducted into the cabinet.</li><li>19 ministers from the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP).</li><li>9 ministers from the Ajit Pawar-led Nationalist Congress Party (NCP).</li><li>11 ministers from the Eknath Shinde-led Shiv Sena.</li></ul><h3>Full List of Ministers:</h3><p><strong>Bharatiya Janata Party: 19</strong></p><ol><li>Chandrashekhar Bawankule</li><li>Radhakrishna Vikhe Patil</li><li>Chandrakant Patil</li><li>Girish Mahajan</li><li>Ganesh Naik</li><li>Mangalprabhat Lodha</li><li>Jaykumar Rawal</li><li>Pankaja Munde</li><li>Atul Save</li><li>Ashok Uike</li><li>Ashish Shelar</li><li>Shivendra Raje Bhosale</li><li>Jaykumar Gore</li><li>Sanjay Sawakare</li><li>Nitesh Rane</li><li>Akash Fundkar</li><li>Madhuri Misal (MoS)</li><li>Dr. Pankaj Bhoyar (MoS)</li><li>Meghana Bordikar Sakore (MoS)</li></ol><p><strong>Nationalist Congress Party: 9</strong></p><ol><li>Hasan Mushrif</li><li>Dhananjay Munde</li><li>Dattatraya Bharne</li><li>Aditi Tatkare</li><li>Manikrao Kokate</li><li>Narhari Zirwal</li><li>Makrand Jadhav Patil</li><li>Babasaheb Patil</li><li>Indranil Naik (MoS)</li></ol><p><strong>Shiv Sena: 11</strong></p><ol><li>Gulabrao Patil</li><li>Dada Bhuse</li><li>Sanjay Rathod</li><li>Uday Samant</li><li>Shambhuraje Desai</li><li>Sanjay Shirsat</li><li>Pratap Sarnaik</li><li>Bharat Gogawale</li><li>Prakash Abitkar</li><li>Ashish Jaiswal (MoS)</li><li>Yogesh Kadam (MoS)</li></ol>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/39-maharashtra-ministers-join-devendra-fadnavis-cabinet-full-list-7254571</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/39-maharashtra-ministers-join-devendra-fadnavis-cabinet-full-list-7254571</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:19:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['They wanted me dead': Bengaluru cop's note mirrors techie Subhash Atul's suicide case - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru Cop's Note Reflects Techie Subhash Atul's Suicide Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Bengaluru News Image" /><figcaption>Bengaluru cop's note sheds light on the tragic suicide case.</figcaption><p>The note from a Bengaluru police officer reveals deep connections to the distressing suicide case of techie Subhash Atul, highlighting issues related to mental health and social pressures.</p><ul><li>The note indicates the officer's personal struggles and pressures faced in the line of duty.</li><li>Subhash Atul's case has brought attention to mental health awareness, especially among tech professionals.</li><li>The broader implications point towards societal expectations and their impact on mental well-being.</li></ul><blockquote>“They wanted me dead,” the note poignantly states, reflecting the emotional turmoil faced.</blockquote><p>This tragic case underscores the urgent need for mental health support and awareness in high-pressure environments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/cop-dies-by-suicide-blames-wifeand-father-in-law-in-death-note/articleshow/116324971.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/cop-dies-by-suicide-blames-wifeand-father-in-law-in-death-note/articleshow/116324971.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My political career made and unmade by Gandhis: Mani Shankar Aiyar - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPVWJGaVJqYXRtRXJycHdUdWZtVTAyNU1VaU1EY0RhbnhmRnFlWTB2U2NLXy00SlZPUEk0cDVoLS13c3NtQng5OVRTMGpFbGlWdDIydzYyZEpNZkc3cHNCcHZiOV9aLUp6TUlySFJBa3lTSGd1ZGJnckFrS3FObDgxRE9zdERmWkFEUkdQcG5nbE9qeXFlTFhOaG1ncFFIb296ZTNMdWdGVnVhd9IBrgFBVV95cUxQZ0l3UzYyM1hGY2JkaXh4S05pZ0NyMzVCeG5MMFdjc3EybnExNl9wd2piRVY3TFdHNm1MenNIZ19PM040cVpzLVRoc3ZyS3Y0R0V6Z3o5MlQ0TmlWUTJ3UW9kcjh5LWoxeUFLaWM4LTNXbDhVMkZPNkU0MGxSYVUwa2hEZ0tBTGl2Zm85d2kwY09qblBLR0JYZWZmN0tfUUZDbV9QT1lxRzdKc3p4ZHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPVWJGaVJqYXRtRXJycHdUdWZtVTAyNU1VaU1EY0RhbnhmRnFlWTB2U2NLXy00SlZPUEk0cDVoLS13c3NtQng5OVRTMGpFbGlWdDIydzYyZEpNZkc3cHNCcHZiOV9aLUp6TUlySFJBa3lTSGd1ZGJnckFrS3FObDgxRE9zdERmWkFEUkdQcG5nbE9qeXFlTFhOaG1ncFFIb296ZTNMdWdGVnVhd9IBrgFBVV95cUxQZ0l3UzYyM1hGY2JkaXh4S05pZ0NyMzVCeG5MMFdjc3EybnExNl9wd2piRVY3TFdHNm1MenNIZ19PM040cVpzLVRoc3ZyS3Y0R0V6Z3o5MlQ0TmlWUTJ3UW9kcjh5LWoxeUFLaWM4LTNXbDhVMkZPNkU0MGxSYVUwa2hEZ0tBTGl2Zm85d2kwY09qblBLR0JYZWZmN0tfUUZDbV9QT1lxRzdKc3p4ZHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:23:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India is a player the world turns to, even if we're bashful at times, says EAM Jaishankar - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxPVF9tZENjbTRWazhDM0lOWTVZV3NjODlhYWYwM01ZN0Vfc1UxaEEtYUZxYU5ER1pfRG1lY01CUjRRZmN5UEYxV05Zdk5oUFBMV2ZsVlJYVEl1aGJrYU5RXzRlbG5yZ2k4UUYzQkhrc2I3aEw1Z1ljRDJBWjljRmZhTEJOQXZDUFMwTHZTejI1bWd3emdpMmQyYUdSUnE0MjlVVzZzeDU2ZVpEMmpzTDRoaUFBNUFnQms2amJCV29TeVJSVFA2QlFIN1RZczJPWl9jck4xelBzcmxpSnAzdmNYOC11ZWh5QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxPVF9tZENjbTRWazhDM0lOWTVZV3NjODlhYWYwM01ZN0Vfc1UxaEEtYUZxYU5ER1pfRG1lY01CUjRRZmN5UEYxV05Zdk5oUFBMV2ZsVlJYVEl1aGJrYU5RXzRlbG5yZ2k4UUYzQkhrc2I3aEw1Z1ljRDJBWjljRmZhTEJOQXZDUFMwTHZTejI1bWd3emdpMmQyYUdSUnE0MjlVVzZzeDU2ZVpEMmpzTDRoaUFBNUFnQms2amJCV29TeVJSVFA2QlFIN1RZczJPWl9jck4xelBzcmxpSnAzdmNYOC11ZWh5QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:43:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘She may not understand’: BJP on Priyanka Gandhi's barb on PM Modi's speech in Lok Sabha - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Responds to Priyanka Gandhi's Criticism of PM Modi's Speech</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/mixcollage-15-dec-2024-04-59-pm-3287_1734262336146_1734262482719.jpg" alt="Kiren Rijiju and Anurag Thakur have responded to Priyanka Gandhi's jibe at PM Modi. (PTI/ ANI)" /><figcaption>Kiren Rijiju and Anurag Thakur have responded to Priyanka Gandhi's jibe at PM Modi. (PTI/ ANI)</figcaption></figure><p>Priyanka Gandhi Vadra criticized PM Narendra Modi's speech in Lok Sabha, calling it boring and lacking in substance. The BJP retaliated with comments regarding her understanding of parliamentary discourse.</p><ul><li>BJP leaders Kiren Rijiju and Anurag Thakur responded to Priyanka Gandhi's remarks about PM Modi's speech.</li><li>Rijiju stated that Gandhi may not grasp the nuances of PM Modi's remarks, labeling them as factual statements.</li><li>Thakur accused Priyanka of not being serious during Parliament proceedings.</li><li>Priyanka called Modi's speech devoid of new or constructive content, highlighting dissatisfaction with the Prime Minister's approach.</li></ul><blockquote>“I thought he would say something significant, but he spoke about 11 hollow promises.” - Priyanka Gandhi Vadra</blockquote><p>The responses from the BJP underscore ongoing tensions between the two parties, particularly regarding the relevance and impact of parliamentary dialogue.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/she-may-not-understand-bjp-on-priyanka-gandhis-barb-on-pm-modis-speech-in-lok-sabha-101734260904300.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/she-may-not-understand-bjp-on-priyanka-gandhis-barb-on-pm-modis-speech-in-lok-sabha-101734260904300.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:37:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘My political career made, unmade by Gandhis’, says Congress veteran Mani Shankar Aiyar - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘My political career made, unmade by Gandhis’, says Congress veteran Mani Shankar Aiyar</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/mani-shankar-aiyar_1637720669574_1734260938316.jpg" alt="File photo of Congress leader Manishankar Aiyar.(HT Photo)" title="File photo of Congress leader Manishankar Aiyar.(HT Photo)"><figcaption>File photo of Congress leader Manishankar Aiyar.(HT Photo)</figcaption></figure><p>Senior Congress leader Mani Shankar Aiyar stated that his political career has been significantly influenced by the Gandhi family, citing his limited interactions with Sonia, Rahul, and Priyanka Gandhi. He emphasized the irony of being both made and unmade by them.</p><ul><li>Aiyar believes that if Pranab Mukherjee had been made Prime Minister in 2012, it could have mitigated the Congress party's losses in the 2014 Lok Sabha elections.</li><li>He discussed the challenges faced in 2012 due to health issues impacting Sonia Gandhi and Dr. Manmohan Singh.</li><li>Aiyar is set to publish his thoughts in a book titled 'A Maverick in Politics'.</li></ul><blockquote>“The irony of my life is that my political career was made by the Gandhis and unmade by the Gandhis.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Aiyar reflected on his experiences and the influence of the Gandhis on his political trajectory.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/my-political-career-made-unmade-by-gandhis-says-congress-veteran-mani-shankar-aiyar-101734260375108.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/my-political-career-made-unmade-by-gandhis-says-congress-veteran-mani-shankar-aiyar-101734260375108.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:16:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man In Bihar Dies After Mob Thrashes Him All Night On Suspicion Of Theft - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQVDFfR09CU0tIbDA1dDVNeGpDQ0JlMUlnVVg1c2c3RVVBX1h3bnlteERHUHpPQW02OGVSTWdsTDFzQWFLZnpWcWxKbWpaRGJrOE4tSy14SFFXN3E1T1NpY1NYOUJIQkp2SXB5aWRFNUhMWFBGZGJGaGJ1UVk5MkNiXzBoaE9EYWY5VkdCOXBFSnN3R0tmaXNxeDRnZWhWaHNBcm9oYnZoZVR1ckRWSU14SllR0gG6AUFVX3lxTE5adC00NzE5TURGX1ZMR0tpV3h0by1PTFgzVGowQ3NIZmVsendhZWdBaTBvWjBtOHp2cG14ek5YZ2l2bG9hOWd5T2lWWmJQTkVCSmwzTmJhOHl2QkVobDBLQkRYcGNYMW9KamVQbXlPZFNfUHdCRDdtMDJIbjRnVFJEZjZfaFFwX0hROE9vMng5WkRlQ0R1VzRsZ1RxN3ZlRzJFbF9pYXc1YmpPTDhqRUJsN25YdlZsYnNSUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQVDFfR09CU0tIbDA1dDVNeGpDQ0JlMUlnVVg1c2c3RVVBX1h3bnlteERHUHpPQW02OGVSTWdsTDFzQWFLZnpWcWxKbWpaRGJrOE4tSy14SFFXN3E1T1NpY1NYOUJIQkp2SXB5aWRFNUhMWFBGZGJGaGJ1UVk5MkNiXzBoaE9EYWY5VkdCOXBFSnN3R0tmaXNxeDRnZWhWaHNBcm9oYnZoZVR1ckRWSU14SllR0gG6AUFVX3lxTE5adC00NzE5TURGX1ZMR0tpV3h0by1PTFgzVGowQ3NIZmVsendhZWdBaTBvWjBtOHp2cG14ek5YZ2l2bG9hOWd5T2lWWmJQTkVCSmwzTmJhOHl2QkVobDBLQkRYcGNYMW9KamVQbXlPZFNfUHdCRDdtMDJIbjRnVFJEZjZfaFFwX0hROE9vMng5WkRlQ0R1VzRsZ1RxN3ZlRzJFbF9pYXc1YmpPTDhqRUJsN25YdlZsYnNSUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:06:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court Collegium summons Justice Shekhar Kumar Yadav over remarks on Muslims - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Collegium Summons Justice Yadav Over Controversial Remarks on Muslims</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 15 Dec 2024, 10:47 am</p><p>The Supreme Court Collegium has summoned Allahabad High Court's Justice Shekhar Kumar Yadav for a meeting next week regarding his recent remarks against the Muslim community.</p><ul><li>Justice Yadav made controversial statements during a speech at an event organized by the Vishva Hindu Parishad.</li><li>He asserted that "India will operate according to the wishes of the majority population" and used derogatory terms towards Muslims.</li><li>Following the outcry, there are demands for his impeachment and reassignment of his judicial duties.</li><li>The Campaign for Judicial Accountability and Reforms (CJAR) has filed a complaint seeking an enquiry.</li><li>Justice Yadav's roster has been altered to limit his cases starting December 16.</li><li>MPs led by Kapil Sibal have submitted an impeachment motion to the Rajya Sabha.</li></ul><blockquote>“The comments made by the sitting judge has led to demands that he be impeached and judicial work be withdrawn from him in the meantime.”</blockquote><p>This summoning and the surrounding controversy highlight increasing tensions over judicial conduct and communal sensitivities in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/supreme-court-collegium-summons-justice-shekhar-kumar-yadav-remarks-muslims</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/supreme-court-collegium-summons-justice-shekhar-kumar-yadav-remarks-muslims</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:47:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[24-page suicide note and a letter titled ... goes missing from the Google Drive shared by the Bengaluru t - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwJBVV95cUxNMHZIZGV0MmdlOU5lZjNkblF3S211N19GNkhuNEVrWjlqdDY1T0pQNFF0Wm1ySkxXRUxvRy1RRFZHVTI1VXZGeGJGQ21IQ3h6a2JpOTJTQzZrS1ZjclFib0d0UGx5UEdxN3otaUNzREVfTFo0RlB1Y1F0VHJBd195ZUZ3cUEzSGJtU2l3RFJhaGlOdmotVVZGU1NCWHJPcW91VHJadjA5SnRVOVU4OHFxXzlObWlPN1pRa29hZVg1QXJiZnEwN3VtS0pfajV3WUcyUklfYW9FVUtIMVJtUXhxSW5ZQ3dJNHBUeEdXUmFDUnprcDdybzBiMkxzLTR1Q1MzWTRZZG5JdVBRa2F0OFJiVkd6a0ZQWnA3dHllc2tSTTFyLTdZZXZQSU55Y9IBsAJBVV95cUxQUS1YNEVGWVJqNTVib190NFBicGdma0lSU2Q5S3NmY09waXdmLURqb2V2WXAzNkVKdl9ENXZlb3pDNVBJYl8tQ0thNWNPVmtRbzdNRnhuVlphbUU0ZzNiQWc0VE5LTWl4Vmt1TGRoaVRzMmJDbkVSeVphQ2NOUzlGMlBuR0Q2ODZ1TUQ0Q0U1WlpFbHNUaTdTMDhlVUxxOEpWTWI1WFNjVUZxRGdVUkZqM3JsMjRZcENoam9lTXVxT0R3aXM4VDRWWHlMSUZjcHUybFRQQVUxUUJTYWZFMjFFQkxDTTB2MUpWRlFodWNFYmx6UFh0b0pWOERtY0QzSkF3anFZQjJVb01WeTRIQWFoaV9KS1U1dHFkMjNkeXhhVFdXazJzZGVkWldlS1VqeXhK?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwJBVV95cUxNMHZIZGV0MmdlOU5lZjNkblF3S211N19GNkhuNEVrWjlqdDY1T0pQNFF0Wm1ySkxXRUxvRy1RRFZHVTI1VXZGeGJGQ21IQ3h6a2JpOTJTQzZrS1ZjclFib0d0UGx5UEdxN3otaUNzREVfTFo0RlB1Y1F0VHJBd195ZUZ3cUEzSGJtU2l3RFJhaGlOdmotVVZGU1NCWHJPcW91VHJadjA5SnRVOVU4OHFxXzlObWlPN1pRa29hZVg1QXJiZnEwN3VtS0pfajV3WUcyUklfYW9FVUtIMVJtUXhxSW5ZQ3dJNHBUeEdXUmFDUnprcDdybzBiMkxzLTR1Q1MzWTRZZG5JdVBRa2F0OFJiVkd6a0ZQWnA3dHllc2tSTTFyLTdZZXZQSU55Y9IBsAJBVV95cUxQUS1YNEVGWVJqNTVib190NFBicGdma0lSU2Q5S3NmY09waXdmLURqb2V2WXAzNkVKdl9ENXZlb3pDNVBJYl8tQ0thNWNPVmtRbzdNRnhuVlphbUU0ZzNiQWc0VE5LTWl4Vmt1TGRoaVRzMmJDbkVSeVphQ2NOUzlGMlBuR0Q2ODZ1TUQ0Q0U1WlpFbHNUaTdTMDhlVUxxOEpWTWI1WFNjVUZxRGdVUkZqM3JsMjRZcENoam9lTXVxT0R3aXM4VDRWWHlMSUZjcHUybFRQQVUxUUJTYWZFMjFFQkxDTTB2MUpWRlFodWNFYmx6UFh0b0pWOERtY0QzSkF3anFZQjJVb01WeTRIQWFoaV9KS1U1dHFkMjNkeXhhVFdXazJzZGVkWldlS1VqeXhK?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kolkata Mayor Firhad Hakim’s remark on ‘Muslim majority’ triggers controversy, BJP accuses him of inciting hatred - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kolkata Mayor's Comments on Muslim Majority Spark Controversy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/adhikari.jpg?w=640" alt="Firhad Hakim" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Bengal Leader of Opposition Suvendu Adhikari termed Hakim’s statement “dangerous”. (Image: X)</figcaption><p>Kolkata Mayor Firhad Hakim's remarks about the Muslim community being a majority have ignited a political backlash. His statement has been accused of inciting communal hatred by the opposition BJP.</p><ul><li>Firhad Hakim claimed, “We will soon be majority,” which provoked criticism from BJP leaders.</li><li>BJP president Sukanta Majumdar criticized Hakim's comments as a dangerous agenda, equating it to hate speech.</li><li>Hakim defended his statement by asserting his national identity and commitment to secularism.</li><li>Opposition leaders argued that while enhancing Muslim representation in judiciary is positive, framing it in terms of majority is risky.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pure venom from the Kolkata Mayor, TMC’s Firhad Hakim openly inciting communal hatred and pushing a dangerous agenda...” - Sukanta Majumdar</blockquote><p>This controversy has stirred discussions on communal identity and representation in Indian politics, raising questions on the balance between community aspirations and the broader national integrity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/kolkata-mayor-firhad-hakim-muslim-majority-controversy-bjp-9726030/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/kolkata/kolkata-mayor-firhad-hakim-muslim-majority-controversy-bjp-9726030/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:30:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dynasty politics not lifelong ticket to success, politicians remain glorified daily wagers: Omars advice to sons - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxNM2I1dF9wTVlsSHE2dG9rY0JKVGY1OXhvWnVSenpRVllVZ2tOTXVRdEZaU1RIekMwdDlpNG1rQjRJVmhWNXY2cXNmUlMzZ0Rad1NIVzk4NldCMDZ0UnUtbmhJQlNKUUx4ejdFSF96bTFSdnJCa0xmQkNIQVI4YU50cjlaS0p1MXIxS0phYTAtY1JmZzVTRTFtRzlJSEVNV1pDcDBhNGlVN1NpZnhUeGpLYU1BeVA0ODJTeE1KODFLSUpaZTlPZkVaZmZtRE9QdjBib1I2RVE4eGgyYlhXbDgtemgxWlphQ1JPTVBZcdIB7wFBVV95cUxQRXdWY2R2Y0FJVi0wTmZCSHN6anpvQUVEbTBab0ZLQmh2dFA3amc3SDF5b3NHRE9HVzNmZEU2TUs4SFFDNG5mZFNYaFB4eFVLdzNiNTZBNktwZEpCU19OUmMxM0tfdWwyUVJGLUFROHF4b2NkZTB0cDVoS0thWjNZMTQ5d0pyWExQN1F3Q0V2WHJpaG5JRTlMNzJjVGliUVluXzN3NjdpaGk2ZUo1Q2F3aU1yb1FGOWtNWjFZb1N5ekstV1YtNWpRSmh5dUhKQlh0LWhzeGpaUHhuZmFjcU1iNFZHZTU0Z0FST3pFRm0zaw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxNM2I1dF9wTVlsSHE2dG9rY0JKVGY1OXhvWnVSenpRVllVZ2tOTXVRdEZaU1RIekMwdDlpNG1rQjRJVmhWNXY2cXNmUlMzZ0Rad1NIVzk4NldCMDZ0UnUtbmhJQlNKUUx4ejdFSF96bTFSdnJCa0xmQkNIQVI4YU50cjlaS0p1MXIxS0phYTAtY1JmZzVTRTFtRzlJSEVNV1pDcDBhNGlVN1NpZnhUeGpLYU1BeVA0ODJTeE1KODFLSUpaZTlPZkVaZmZtRE9QdjBib1I2RVE4eGgyYlhXbDgtemgxWlphQ1JPTVBZcdIB7wFBVV95cUxQRXdWY2R2Y0FJVi0wTmZCSHN6anpvQUVEbTBab0ZLQmh2dFA3amc3SDF5b3NHRE9HVzNmZEU2TUs4SFFDNG5mZFNYaFB4eFVLdzNiNTZBNktwZEpCU19OUmMxM0tfdWwyUVJGLUFROHF4b2NkZTB0cDVoS0thWjNZMTQ5d0pyWExQN1F3Q0V2WHJpaG5JRTlMNzJjVGliUVluXzN3NjdpaGk2ZUo1Q2F3aU1yb1FGOWtNWjFZb1N5ekstV1YtNWpRSmh5dUhKQlh0LWhzeGpaUHhuZmFjcU1iNFZHZTU0Z0FST3pFRm0zaw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:26:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lok Sabha defeats Rajya Sabha in Tuberculosis-awareness friendly cricket match - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lok Sabha Wins Friendly Cricket Match to Raise TB Awareness</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ANI</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/2024-12/Match%20Gif.gif?VersionId=9Uelf2mzFL0kTfAcYeQakGj7qW9FYRCo" width="690" alt="MPs cricket match" title="Lok Sabha Speaker's XI beat Rajya Sabha Chairman's Xi by 73 runs in the anti-tuberculosis awareness match in New Delhi on Sunday, December 15, 2024. (Screengrab: X/@ANI)" height="388"><figcaption>Lok Sabha Speaker's XI beat Rajya Sabha Chairman's Xi by 73 runs in the anti-tuberculosis awareness match in New Delhi on Sunday, December 15, 2024. (Screengrab: X/@ANI)</figcaption><p>The Lok Sabha Speaker's XI triumphed over the Rajya Sabha Chairman's XI by 73 runs in a cricket match aimed at raising awareness for tuberculosis, held at Major Dhyan Chand National Stadium in New Delhi.</p><ul><li>The match featured MPs from both houses, with Lok Sabha Speaker's XI captained by Anurag Thakur and Rajya Sabha Chairman's XI led by Kiren Rijiju.</li><li>Anurag Thakur scored 111 runs, contributing significantly to his team's victory.</li><li>BJP MP Nishikant Dubey received the Best Fielder award, while Congress MP Deepender Singh Hooda was recognized as the Best Bowler.</li><li>Other notable MPs participated, promoting fitness and TB awareness.</li></ul><blockquote>“TB is a serious disease, and raising awareness is the most effective way to combat it. Spreading awareness about TB is a collective responsibility…” – Anurag Thakur</blockquote><p>This match not only showcased sportsmanship but also aimed at increasing public awareness about tuberculosis, highlighting the need for collective efforts in combating the disease.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-mps-tb-free-india-awareness-cricket-match-new-delhi-major-dhyan-chand-national-stadium-2650144-2024-12-15</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/lok-sabha-rajya-sabha-mps-tb-free-india-awareness-cricket-match-new-delhi-major-dhyan-chand-national-stadium-2650144-2024-12-15</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:13:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi polls: AAP unveils 38 candidates, Kejriwal to contest from New Delhi| Full list - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AAP Announces 38 Candidates for Delhi Assembly Elections</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/AAP-chief-Arvind-Kejriwal---HT-Photo-_1734196791635_1734256146242.jpg" alt="AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal. (Hindustan Times )">
<figcaption>AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal. (Hindustan Times )</figcaption>
<p>The Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) announced its fourth list of candidates for the upcoming Delhi assembly elections, with its leader Arvind Kejriwal contesting from New Delhi.</p>
<ul>
  <li>AAP has unveiled a total of 38 candidates for the elections.</li>
  <li>Arvind Kejriwal will compete against Sandeep Dikshit.</li>
  <li>Atishi will contest from Kalkaji, and other ministers will also run in different constituencies.</li>
  <li>Kejriwal emphasized the party's solid foundation of educated candidates.</li>
  <li>In the previous elections, AAP won 62 of 70 seats.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our party has a solid group of educated individuals to carry out its vision and strategy for the advancement of Delhiites.” - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote>
<p>Despite losing some current lawmakers, AAP is presenting a united front for the upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-polls-aap-unveils-38-candidates-kejriwal-to-contest-from-new-delhi-full-list-101734253358026.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-polls-aap-unveils-38-candidates-kejriwal-to-contest-from-new-delhi-full-list-101734253358026.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:11:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Assembly Elections 2025: Game on with Kejriwal re-contesting; Congress drops candidates' list while Smriti Irani meets BJP veterans - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAJBVV95cUxPakxUcmxucnB4SWc1VWNhbHNOM0N6dS1kVGd2dlRwUWhmLUN6enNYM0xPWUNuZjFNTXUwc0lVTTF6UE1PT1NMRTBmbWItNjdydV82cTZqeDV2REMzX3paYlhMN08ySFFCOHdNT0Vhd3FjZGtkOVY5SUVCeE1ibnNURGtEZWtGV1p5ajlhUUpUUHZ6Z0xJa3lWNmZIZk9aM2t4aVZuczZ0TlRWT0dNZll4ZDBSaHd4OTFOWkVVRGJ0Mm9WSFppbVozRVgxUUstUFhZczhmb0UzQjFsbXhaSzNFQXJTMGROVHJDbDBncmU0SmVZaFczNjZ0d1JVRzFrTWNFOG1xMmMxZmNLa2lSSmxwbg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAJBVV95cUxPakxUcmxucnB4SWc1VWNhbHNOM0N6dS1kVGd2dlRwUWhmLUN6enNYM0xPWUNuZjFNTXUwc0lVTTF6UE1PT1NMRTBmbWItNjdydV82cTZqeDV2REMzX3paYlhMN08ySFFCOHdNT0Vhd3FjZGtkOVY5SUVCeE1ibnNURGtEZWtGV1p5ajlhUUpUUHZ6Z0xJa3lWNmZIZk9aM2t4aVZuczZ0TlRWT0dNZll4ZDBSaHd4OTFOWkVVRGJ0Mm9WSFppbVozRVgxUUstUFhZczhmb0UzQjFsbXhaSzNFQXJTMGROVHJDbDBncmU0SmVZaFczNjZ0d1JVRzFrTWNFOG1xMmMxZmNLa2lSSmxwbg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:56:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MP couple's 'suicide' days after ED raid: Family says 'had we sided with BJP, this wouldn't have happened' - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MP couple's 'suicide' days after ED raid: Family says 'had we sided with BJP, this wouldn't have happened'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Print</p><p>In a tragic incident, Manoj and Neha Parmar reportedly took their own lives shortly after an Enforcement Directorate (ED) raid, with family members claiming political pressure led to their distress.</p><ul><li>The family alleged the ED raid was an attempt to coerce them into supporting the BJP.</li><li>A note found near their bodies accused ED officials of harassment and warned that aligning with BJP would mitigate their legal troubles.</li><li>The Congress party labeled the incident as a “political murder” and accused the BJP of using the ED as a political tool.</li><li>Manoj's family highlights ongoing harassment by multiple agencies as the reason for their despair.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is clear for the BJP—join the party and ED cases and everything goes away. If you don’t, you face the consequences.” - Dharam Singh Parmar, Manoj's father</blockquote><p>The ED and BJP spokespersons have dismissed the allegations, stating that the raid was conducted properly and denying any harassment.</p><p>The political fallout from this incident has sparked intense discussions regarding the misuse of investigative agencies in political conflicts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/india/mp-couples-suicide-days-after-ed-raid-family-says-had-we-sided-with-bjp-this-wouldnt-have-happened/2404010/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/india/mp-couples-suicide-days-after-ed-raid-family-says-had-we-sided-with-bjp-this-wouldnt-have-happened/2404010/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:55:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘If you have problems with EVMs…': Omar Abdullah's salvo at INDIA ally Congress - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Omar Abdullah Critiques Congress on EVM Accountability</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/PTI12-14-2024-000217A-0_1734255937782_1734255986267.jpg" alt="Omar Abdullah Interview" title="New Delhi: Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah during an interview with PTI" />
<figcaption>New Delhi: Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah during an interview with PTI.</figcaption>
<p>Jammu and Kashmir chief minister Omar Abdullah has criticized the Congress party for its inconsistent stance on Electronic Voting Machines (EVMs), suggesting that they cannot accept results they like and blame the EVMs for defeats.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Abdullah rebukes Congress for questioning EVMs after losing elections.</li>
  <li>He argues that parties should be consistent in their trust of the voting mechanism.</li>
  <li>Abdullah believes the Congress should have not relied solely on the National Conference during the recent campaign.</li>
  <li>He emphasizes the need for clarity and principle in political discourse.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"When you get a hundred plus members of Parliament using the same EVMs... you can't then... say we don't like these EVMs because now the election results aren't going the way we would like them to." - Omar Abdullah</blockquote>
<p>Abdullah emphasizes that electoral machines remain the same regardless of the outcomes and cautions against using them as excuses for electoral failure.</p>
<p>His remarks come amidst ongoing tensions between the National Conference and the Congress in the context of their alliance under the INDIA Bloc.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/omar-abdullah-fires-another-shot-at-ally-congress-if-you-have-problems-with-evms-101734255715415.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/omar-abdullah-fires-another-shot-at-ally-congress-if-you-have-problems-with-evms-101734255715415.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:50:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Aarti’ performed at reopened temple in Uttar Pradesh’s Sambhal - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aarti Performed at Reopened Temple in Sambhal, Uttar Pradesh</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> December 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/e9bwc9/article68988016.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241214200L.jpg" alt="A well has been found near the ancient Lord Shiva temple which has been reopened after 42 years during an anti-encroachment drive of the Sambhal administration, in Sambhal on Saturday." /><figcaption>A well has been found near the ancient Lord Shiva temple which has been reopened after 42 years during an anti-encroachment drive of the Sambhal administration, in Sambhal on Saturday.</figcaption><p>Aarti was performed on Sunday morning at the recently reopened Lord Shiva and Hanuman temple in Sambhal, which had been locked since 1978 due to communal riots. The temple, located near the Shahi Jama Masjid, was reopened following an anti-encroachment drive initiated by the Sambhal administration.</p><ul><li>The temple houses idols of Lord Hanuman and a Shivling.</li><li>Local authorities discovered the temple during an anti-encroachment inspection.</li><li>Residents have shared memories and highlighted the temple's significance in the community.</li><li>The temple had been closed for decades following communal violence that displaced Hindu families.</li></ul><blockquote>“We all came here together and decided to reopen the temple.” - SDM Vandana Mishra</blockquote><p>This reopening marks a significant moment for the local Hindu community, reconnecting them with a long-lost place of worship.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/uttar-pradesh/aarti-performed-at-reopened-temple-in-uttar-pradeshs-sambhal/article68988012.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/uttar-pradesh/aarti-performed-at-reopened-temple-in-uttar-pradeshs-sambhal/article68988012.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maggi prices likely to rise after January 1; here is why - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxPMTBtQ2M3TXhUWk9fekVtU1VSNWFHWXJ2bmNkT3FEWDZfbmc3cXJXSWl1QnZNdnNPQ1JnaWx2dnlkRFBpdHNibTJIVWVKT2FJczdyUUVuUGFjWWpOamRZcVl4czJ2RDdhSHlzQkFKd3JhOFdaUnlvc1dPYTNSYW5lWHVzaloyM0NpNk1hVWFYbm1naE04dDIxU3VhSjMwSjFt0gGkAUFVX3lxTE5Ud0h1V0p3M1UzdUpMQkhyRFc4cndOUzNNSlZkY3dGS3BrekFHUldnVmczZngtS3hReENBZmdBb2gtb0xhN1daU1RPMVJ2SklMNmxILTVtcE9fLVJub0JVVUlyeGFZZS1LZGZaTUFfYlBUSkJoRk05M2M4b3RBVDNiZzBLUzBKNURjUFU4YktNaXZfVDJ5LXZ1X1VwdVprRzgxRzdD?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxPMTBtQ2M3TXhUWk9fekVtU1VSNWFHWXJ2bmNkT3FEWDZfbmc3cXJXSWl1QnZNdnNPQ1JnaWx2dnlkRFBpdHNibTJIVWVKT2FJczdyUUVuUGFjWWpOamRZcVl4czJ2RDdhSHlzQkFKd3JhOFdaUnlvc1dPYTNSYW5lWHVzaloyM0NpNk1hVWFYbm1naE04dDIxU3VhSjMwSjFt0gGkAUFVX3lxTE5Ud0h1V0p3M1UzdUpMQkhyRFc4cndOUzNNSlZkY3dGS3BrekFHUldnVmczZngtS3hReENBZmdBb2gtb0xhN1daU1RPMVJ2SklMNmxILTVtcE9fLVJub0JVVUlyeGFZZS1LZGZaTUFfYlBUSkJoRk05M2M4b3RBVDNiZzBLUzBKNURjUFU4YktNaXZfVDJ5LXZ1X1VwdVprRzgxRzdD?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 08:31:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Complete Supreme Court Quarterly Digest 2024- [July To September] - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Complete Supreme Court Quarterly Digest 2024: July To September</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p><p>This digest covers notable Supreme Court rulings from July to September 2024, highlighting key legal principles and cases affecting various facets of law.</p><ul><li>Bar Councils cannot exceed fee limits set for enrolment.</li><li>Advocates must attend court in proper attire as per regulations.</li><li>Exorbitant enrolment fees violate rights related to profession and equality.</li><li>The Supreme Court prohibits online presence marking without actual participation in hearings.</li><li>Civilian killings due to lack of sanction under AFSPA have led to legal proceedings being quashed.</li><li>The Supreme Court allows final year law students to appear for the All India Bar Exam.</li></ul><blockquote>“Legal professionals are not immune from prosecution for criminal misdeeds.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the digest reflects ongoing reforms in the legal profession and the emphasis on procedural integrity by the Supreme Court.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/supreme-court/supreme-court-judgments-and-orders-quarterly-digest-2024-278396</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/supreme-court/supreme-court-judgments-and-orders-quarterly-digest-2024-278396</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 08:25:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[25-year-old biker killed after being hit by bus in Mumbai, days after deadly Kurla accident - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biker Killed in Mumbai After Bus Accident Days After Deadly Kurla Crash</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Mumbai--India--Dec-13--2024--BEST-bus-services-res_1734248575217_1734248644730.jpg" alt="Four days after the Kurla accident, BEST bus services had just resumed on Friday. (Raju Shinde/HT Photo)" title="Four days after the Kurla accident, BEST bus services had just resumed on Friday. (Raju Shinde/HT Photo)">
<figcaption>Four days after the Kurla accident, BEST bus services had just resumed on Friday. (Raju Shinde/HT Photo)</figcaption>
<p>A tragic motorcycle accident in Mumbai claimed the life of a 25-year-old man just days after another deadly bus crash in Kurla. The police have arrested the bus driver and conductor in connection with this recent accident.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The victim, Dikshit Vinod Rajput, was killed by a BEST electric bus in the Govandi area.</li>
  <li>The accident occurred at the Shivaji Nagar junction as the victim was riding his motorcycle.</li>
  <li>Police reported that the victim suffered severe head injuries and was pronounced dead at the hospital.</li>
  <li>The driver and conductor of the bus have been arrested under relevant sections of the law.</li>
  <li>Just days earlier, a separate bus accident in Kurla resulted in the deaths of seven people and injuries to 42 others.</li>
  <li>The police are conducting further investigations into both incidents.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The bus was a 12-metre-long electric vehicle manufactured by Hyderabad-based Olectra Greentech...”</blockquote>
<p>This recent incident raises serious concerns regarding the safety and operation of electric buses in Mumbai, particularly in light of the earlier Kurla accident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/25yearold-biker-killed-after-being-hit-by-bus-in-mumbai-days-after-deadly-kurla-accident-101734248190468.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/25yearold-biker-killed-after-being-hit-by-bus-in-mumbai-days-after-deadly-kurla-accident-101734248190468.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 08:21:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab DGP, MHA Director meet fasting farmer leader Dallewal; urge him to get medical aid - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Punjab DGP, Centres representative meet farm leader Dallewal; urge him to get medical aid</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Sunday, November 26<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p><p>The Punjab Director-General of Police and a senior Union Ministry of Home Affairs officer met farmer leader Jagjit Singh Dallewal, who has been on a fast for 20 days, to discuss his health and demands.</p><ul><li>DGP Gaurav Yadav and representative Mayank Mishra visited Dallewal at the Khanauri border.</li><li>Dallewal is a cancer patient seeking government acceptance of various farmers' demands, including the legal guarantee of MSP.</li><li>The Supreme Court of India ordered a meeting and medical assistance for Dallewal.</li><li>Government officials have assured medical facilities are in place.</li><li>Dallewal has remained firm on continuing his fast despite appeals from officials.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have appealed to farmers that Dallewal’s life is precious. Medical facilities have been provided here.” - DGP Gaurav Yadav</blockquote><p>Officials are working to facilitate communication between Dallewal and the government regarding farmers' demands while closely monitoring his health condition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/patiala/punjab-dgp-centres-representative-meet-farm-leader-dallewal-urge-him-to-get-medical-aid/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/patiala/punjab-dgp-centres-representative-meet-farm-leader-dallewal-urge-him-to-get-medical-aid/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 08:15:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Danish Chikna, Dawood Ibrahim's Drug Factory Manager, Arrested In Mumbai - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Danish Chikna, Dawood Ibrahim's Drug Factory Manager, Arrested In Mumbai</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>December 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1ukgnr88_danish-merchant-danish-chikna-_625x300_15_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400" alt="Danish Chikna, Dawood Ibrahim's Drug Factory Manager, Arrested In Mumbai"><figcaption>Danish Chikna, Dawood Ibrahim's Drug Factory Manager</figcaption><p>The Mumbai Police have arrested Danish Merchant, also known as Danish Chikna, who is a key associate of gangster Dawood Ibrahim, in connection with a drug operations case.</p><ul><li>The arrests were part of a larger operation that began on November 8.</li><li>Merchant was arrested alongside his associate, Kader Ghulam Sheikh.</li><li>Two previous arrests on November 8 led to discovering the drug supply chain linked to Merchant.</li><li>The police located both Merchant and his associate in the Dongri area on December 13.</li><li>Merchant's previous arrest in 2019 involved a major drug operation dismantled by the NCB.</li></ul><blockquote>“A carefully planned operation led to their arrest.”</blockquote><p>This operation underscores the ongoing efforts by law enforcement to combat drug trafficking linked to organized crime in Mumbai.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/danish-chikna-dawood-ibrahims-drug-factory-manager-arrested-in-mumbai-7252679</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/danish-chikna-dawood-ibrahims-drug-factory-manager-arrested-in-mumbai-7252679</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:40:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[E.V.K.S. Elangovan’s funeral will be done with State honours: State government - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>E.V.K.S. Elangovan’s funeral will be conducted with State honors: Tamil Nadu government</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Tamil Nadu government announcement</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/6okgna/article68987810.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/IMG_9870_2_3_2023_15_59__2_1_BGDNI09N.jpg" alt="E.V.K.S. Elangovan. File photo"><figcaption>E.V.K.S. Elangovan. File photo</figcaption><p>The Tamil Nadu government announced that the funeral of senior Congress leader E.V.K.S. Elangovan will be conducted with State honors following his passing on Saturday morning after a brief illness.</p><ul><li>E.V.K.S. Elangovan served as a significant figure in Tamil Nadu and Indian politics.</li><li>His death prompted condolences from the government, highlighting his candid nature and public service.</li><li>The funeral is set to honor his contributions to society.</li></ul><blockquote>“Mr. Elangovan spoke his mind and served the public well,” stated the government.</blockquote><p>This announcement reflects the state's respect and appreciation for E.V.K.S. Elangovan's lifetime of service.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/tamil-nadu/evks-elangovans-funeral-will-be-done-with-state-honours-state-government/article68987716.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/tamil-nadu/evks-elangovans-funeral-will-be-done-with-state-honours-state-government/article68987716.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>