<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:15:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:15:27 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: How cops cleared 1,000 vehicle jam in Himachal Pradesh - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How Police Rescued Tourists from a Major Traffic Jam in Himachal Pradesh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/PTI12-25-2024-000298A-0_1735360839981_1735360999213.jpg" alt="Vehicles stuck in a traffic jam as tourists arrive to celebrate Christmas, at Manali in Kullu district(PTI)"><figcaption>Vehicles stuck in a traffic jam as tourists arrive to celebrate Christmas, at Manali in Kullu district(PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>Himachal Pradesh faced severe traffic congestion with 1,000 vehicles stranded near Solang Nala due to heavy snowfall and an influx of tourists. Kullu police successfully rescued around 5,000 stranded tourists in a continuous operation.</p><ul><li>Heavy snowfall led to one of the worst traffic jams in Himachal Pradesh's history, impacting thousands.</li><li>The Kullu police coordinated a massive rescue operation to evacuate the stranded tourists.</li><li>Authorities are working to clear blocked roads amid ongoing snow and continue to face challenges due to severe weather conditions.</li><li>The India Meteorological Department issued alerts for heavy snowfall and cold waves across several districts.</li></ul><blockquote>“Due to fresh snowfall today on 27.12.2024, about 1,000 tourists and other vehicles were stuck in Solang Nala.” - Kullu Police</blockquote><p>This event highlights the challenges faced by local authorities during peak tourist seasons impacted by extreme weather conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/video-how-cops-cleared-1-000-vehicle-jam-in-himachal-pradesh-101735360570817.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/video-how-cops-cleared-1-000-vehicle-jam-in-himachal-pradesh-101735360570817.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 04:52:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Major power outage in Kashmir after snowfall, restoration expected by evening: Omar Abdullah - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxPZmgyWFM3aFVCNmUzd0NoUERTUVMzX3NPR285OE5xWGdwNzhkQmJWZmhDV3RuY0VLMHhvZUFlcmNhQ3g1dFNNdFBkdmNMa2N3WGFlTE9XclVIMU1sd3JzR1lBNGZ5VVUyM1ZaRGdNcHlzZTVYUThmX2ZScjU2VGJNaFNuYnpZaFNLOFhFRkFIYUJfSTlSbUNzc05fVDl0LTNjOVVMYTNaMWRMTmZwd2V5dnhmODdkQWZ2YmdCSjdLOHkwNUduMzlHdDZfQTctMEnSAdQBQVVfeXFMTU5PZTAtay1IdEFfM2J4clhwSC1vaGM3T05DOWpBYUhzOUpleGNzcHNNV25LQVlfTFhKc19QdjRMSWdrRkpkMlBJX3U0MUhHRHdzaWIxSDhRVUU5OGU0WVQ0eFFWc0NiZWNnS3dCLUk3UmtLLWlhMk1RQlZfcjd0cUJ4bmxTVEd4QkFEcGhDbnpkeGNZTWdNWXFETzZYNGtEOG1jaGV6OVF2ZDVMQjduSDRqTnBlZG5BaUVHZVhSYUdEQ3VFek9mUlczcDNOR283c3FjeEk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxPZmgyWFM3aFVCNmUzd0NoUERTUVMzX3NPR285OE5xWGdwNzhkQmJWZmhDV3RuY0VLMHhvZUFlcmNhQ3g1dFNNdFBkdmNMa2N3WGFlTE9XclVIMU1sd3JzR1lBNGZ5VVUyM1ZaRGdNcHlzZTVYUThmX2ZScjU2VGJNaFNuYnpZaFNLOFhFRkFIYUJfSTlSbUNzc05fVDl0LTNjOVVMYTNaMWRMTmZwd2V5dnhmODdkQWZ2YmdCSjdLOHkwNUduMzlHdDZfQTctMEnSAdQBQVVfeXFMTU5PZTAtay1IdEFfM2J4clhwSC1vaGM3T05DOWpBYUhzOUpleGNzcHNNV25LQVlfTFhKc19QdjRMSWdrRkpkMlBJX3U0MUhHRHdzaWIxSDhRVUU5OGU0WVQ0eFFWc0NiZWNnS3dCLUk3UmtLLWlhMk1RQlZfcjd0cUJ4bmxTVEd4QkFEcGhDbnpkeGNZTWdNWXFETzZYNGtEOG1jaGV6OVF2ZDVMQjduSDRqTnBlZG5BaUVHZVhSYUdEQ3VFek9mUlczcDNOR283c3FjeEk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 04:48:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BRS Leader KTR Summoned By Probe Agency In Formula E Racing Case - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BRS Leader KTR Summoned By Probe Agency In Formula E Racing Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> New Delhi</p><p>The Enforcement Directorate (ED) has summoned BRS leader and former Telangana minister KT Rama Rao regarding financial irregularities tied to the Formula E race in Hyderabad.</p><ul><li>KTR is scheduled to appear on January 7, with other officials on January 2 and 3.</li><li>Allegations involve unauthorized transfers totaling Rs 55 crore from the HMDA to Formula E Operations Limited.</li><li>Additional transfers of Rs 54.8 crore for future races are under investigation.</li><li>This is the second money laundering case related to the family of former Telangana Chief Minister K Chandrashekar Rao.</li></ul><blockquote>This marks another political and legal challenge for the BRS party.</blockquote><p>The unfolding events signal potential repercussions for the BRS party amidst ongoing scrutiny.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/brs-leader-ktr-summoned-by-probe-agency-in-formula-e-racing-case-7348485</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/brs-leader-ktr-summoned-by-probe-agency-in-formula-e-racing-case-7348485</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 04:25:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govt agreed to memorial for Manmohan Singh, Congress now playing politics: BJP - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Accuses Congress of Playing Politics Over Memorial for Manmohan Singh</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/d6vm1d/article69036038.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI12_28_2024_000029B.jpg" alt="Mortal remains of former prime minister Manmohan Singh being taken to AICC headquarters" title="Mortal remains of former prime minister Manmohan Singh being taken to AICC headquarters"><figcaption>Mortal remains of former prime minister Manmohan Singh being taken to AICC headquarters, in New Delhi, Saturday, December 28, 2024. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>The Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) has announced its decision to construct a memorial for former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh while accusing the Congress party of politicizing the issue.</p><ul><li>The BJP stated that it is committed to honoring Manmohan Singh’s contributions to India's economic development.</li><li>A memorial and mausoleum will be built in his memory, a decision that was communicated to Congress leadership prior.</li><li>The Congress has claimed it wanted Manmohan Singh's cremation to take place at a location suitable for a memorial, but the ceremony occurred at Nigambodh Ghat.</li><li>BJP spokesperson Sudhanshu Trivedi criticized Congress for their perceived lack of respect towards Singh.</li></ul><blockquote>“Congress party, who never respected Dr. Manmohan Singh in their lifetime, today even after his death, they are seen doing politics.” - Sudhanshu Trivedi</blockquote><p>The BJP insists that the memorial will be built following necessary legal protocols, reinforcing their commitment to respecting Singh's legacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/govt-agreed-to-memorial-for-manmohan-singh-congress-now-playing-politics-bjp/article69036029.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/govt-agreed-to-memorial-for-manmohan-singh-congress-now-playing-politics-bjp/article69036029.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 04:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Utter rubbish…’: Pranab Mukherjee's daughter Sharmistha slams Congress amid Manmohan Singh memorial row - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sharmistha Mukherjee Criticizes Congress Over Memorial Controversy for Manmohan Singh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/sharmistha-mukherjee_8a39bdf0-63b0-11e6-b372-5e31f535a023_1735353579757.jpg" alt="Sharmistha Mukherjee has slammed the Congress party.(Sonu Mehta/HT File Photo)" title="Sharmistha Mukherjee has slammed the Congress party.(Sonu Mehta/HT File Photo)"><figcaption>Sharmistha Mukherjee has slammed the Congress party.(Sonu Mehta/HT File Photo)</figcaption><p>Sharmistha Mukherjee, daughter of former president Pranab Mukherjee, criticized the Congress party for not convening a Congress Working Committee (CWC) meeting after her father’s death in 2020, while supporting a request for a memorial for former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh.</p><ul><li>Sharmistha stated the Congress didn’t hold a CWC meeting after Pranab Mukherjee's passing.</li><li>She referenced diary entries showing that a CWC meeting was held for K.R. Narayanan's passing.</li><li>Despite criticism, she supports a memorial for Manmohan Singh, who passed away at 92.</li></ul><blockquote>“When baba passed away, Congress didnt even bother 2 call CWC 4 condolence meeting. That’s utter rubbish...” - Sharmistha Mukherjee</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Sharmistha Mukherjee’s remarks highlight ongoing tensions within the Congress party regarding how it honors its leaders, contrasted with her support for a memorial for Manmohan Singh.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/utter-rubbish-pranab-mukherjees-daughter-sharmistha-slams-congress-amid-manmohan-singh-memorial-row-101735353223134.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/utter-rubbish-pranab-mukherjees-daughter-sharmistha-slams-congress-amid-manmohan-singh-memorial-row-101735353223134.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 03:27:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heavy snowfall paralyses life in south Kashmir - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxPd1RCcnhMZHpVVXBXRGlvSXpLbnk4MGRzQ3RyVHJUYm1sR3Q1UXM2cHU2YzdaTEw4NHVRRjFqdEVrSlh0VE92dy00Q2tEUV9pU2VvOW1ZSGwzWnhGUUVhN292ZUlZSVhWZk5oMDZJRVhrR2ltU3A0dkd1bXA4YkhXZjVrSjktVDctMFpVRHJNOVNmdFpz0gGaAUFVX3lxTE54ZW9wbmk4SDVmTXpvWjRrMFh0Q2dnemZXUXdFMWN5azB1cjRtakNrUDN0NlgtNlNKY1FHQUlNX2RUTG1WaDJNbGhHYWRJYWhLeUR5RnNPbW42Yk1hdmNYb1Y4MDlaV3hpS1JGWkhzSW9OZmstQ1dsVEtuemRVQjdLaW5ZSGNjbDFlM2t0YmF1RGItc3RLN2NMUVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxPd1RCcnhMZHpVVXBXRGlvSXpLbnk4MGRzQ3RyVHJUYm1sR3Q1UXM2cHU2YzdaTEw4NHVRRjFqdEVrSlh0VE92dy00Q2tEUV9pU2VvOW1ZSGwzWnhGUUVhN292ZUlZSVhWZk5oMDZJRVhrR2ltU3A0dkd1bXA4YkhXZjVrSjktVDctMFpVRHJNOVNmdFpz0gGaAUFVX3lxTE54ZW9wbmk4SDVmTXpvWjRrMFh0Q2dnemZXUXdFMWN5azB1cjRtakNrUDN0NlgtNlNKY1FHQUlNX2RUTG1WaDJNbGhHYWRJYWhLeUR5RnNPbW42Yk1hdmNYb1Y4MDlaV3hpS1JGWkhzSW9OZmstQ1dsVEtuemRVQjdLaW5ZSGNjbDFlM2t0YmF1RGItc3RLN2NMUVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 03:15:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Security rushed to the affected areas': Manipur CM Biren Singh condemns 'indiscriminate firing by Kuki m - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manipur CM Biren Singh Condemns Indiscriminate Firing by Kuki Militants</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p>
<p>In the wake of recent violence, Manipur Chief Minister Biren Singh has condemned the indiscriminate firing by Kuki militants that has affected several communities in the region.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Chief Minister stated that security has been rushed to the affected areas.</li>
  <li>Local communities are expressing outrage at the ongoing violence.</li>
  <li>There are calls for better protection for civilians and accountability for the militants.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Such violence cannot be tolerated in a civilized society,” said CM Singh.</blockquote>
<p>As tensions rise in the region, the response from the state government and security forces will be critical in determining the next steps for restoring peace.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/security-rushed-to-the-affected-areas-manipur-cm-biren-singh-condemns-indiscriminate-firing-by-kuki-militants/articleshow/116729203.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/security-rushed-to-the-affected-areas-manipur-cm-biren-singh-condemns-indiscriminate-firing-by-kuki-militants/articleshow/116729203.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 02:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allu Arjun appears before court virtually in Sandhya Theatre stampede case, cites security reasons - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Allu Arjun Appears Virtually in Sandhya Theatre Stampede Case</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/Actor-Allu-Arjun_1735352717299_1735352717677.jpg" alt="Actor Allu Arjun arrives at the Chikkadpally police station for questioning" title="Actor Allu Arjun arrives at the Chikkadpally police station for questioning"><figcaption>Actor Allu Arjun arrives at the Chikkadpally police station for questioning as part of an ongoing probe into the stampede during the screening of Pushpa-2 in Hyderabad, on Tuesday. (PTI)(HT_PRINT)</figcaption></figure><p>Actor Allu Arjun appeared virtually before a local court regarding his bail in the Sandhya Theatre stampede case, where a woman died due to a stampede at his film's premiere.</p><ul><li>Allu Arjun is accused in a case related to a stampede during the premiere of his film <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/pushpa-2-the-rule-box-office-collection-day-23-allu-arjun-film-brings-in-over-1127-crore-as-it-enters-4th-week-101735314756943.html">Pushpa 2: The Rule</a>.</li><li>The incident occurred on December 4, resulting in the death of a 35-year-old woman and injuries to her son.</li><li>The hearing for his bail plea has been postponed to December 30.</li><li>Allu Arjun had been arrested earlier and was granted interim bail.</li></ul><blockquote>“Allu Arjun appeared citing security reasons and to avoid public inconvenience.”</blockquote><p>The case continues to attract public and media attention as it raises questions about crowd management during film premieres.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/allu-arjun-appears-before-court-virtually-in-sandhya-theatre-stampede-case-cites-security-reasons-101735351971888.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/telugu-cinema/allu-arjun-appears-before-court-virtually-in-sandhya-theatre-stampede-case-cites-security-reasons-101735351971888.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 02:29:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh funeral LIVE updates: Former PM’s last rites at Nigambodh Ghat in Delhi - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manmohan Singh funeral LIVE updates: Former PM’s last rites at Nigambodh Ghat in Delhi</h1><p><strong>Date Published:</strong> December 28, 2024 - <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/gm5s8t/article69035921.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Manmohan%20Singh%20funeral.png" alt="Manmohan Singh funeral" /><figcaption>Manmohan Singh funeral</figcaption><p>Former Prime Minister Dr. Manmohan Singh will receive a State funeral at Nigambodh Ghat on Saturday, December 28, 2024.</p><ul><li>The funeral is scheduled to begin at 11:45 a.m.</li><li>Dr. Singh's body will be at the AICC headquarters for public viewing from 8:30 a.m. to 9:30 a.m.</li><li>A state-sanctioned memorial will be allocated for Dr. Singh in the future.</li><li>Several dignitaries, including the current Prime Minister and former officials, are expected to pay their respects.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dr. Singh’s final journey will commence from the headquarters to the cremation ground at 9:30 a.m.” - K. C. Venugopal</blockquote><p>The public and political figures are invited to gather and pay their last respects to a leader known for his economic policies and international diplomacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manmohan-singh-funeral-last-rites-nigambodh-ghat-congress-live-updates-december-28/article69035874.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manmohan-singh-funeral-last-rites-nigambodh-ghat-congress-live-updates-december-28/article69035874.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 01:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's development priorities were key to Manmohan Singh's foreign policy - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/indias-development-priorities-were-key-to-manmohan-singhs-foreign-policy/articleshow/116726639.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/indias-development-priorities-were-key-to-manmohan-singhs-foreign-policy/articleshow/116726639.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 22:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress demands memorial for Manmohan Singh; committed to building one: Government - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Demands Memorial for Manmohan Singh; Government Committed to Building One</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The Indian Congress party is advocating for the establishment of a memorial for former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, with the government indicating its commitment to fulfilling this demand.</p><ul><li>The Congress party believes a memorial would honor Singh's contributions to the nation.</li><li>The government has acknowledged the request and plans to take necessary steps toward its realization.</li><li>This initiative reflects Singh's legacy in Indian politics, particularly in economic reforms.</li></ul><blockquote>“A memorial for Manmohan Singh is essential to recognize his pivotal role in shaping modern India,” said a Congress leader.</blockquote><p>The effort to create a memorial highlights the ongoing reverence for Manmohan Singh's leadership and policies that have had lasting impacts on the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/congress-demands-memorial-for-manmohan-singh-committed-to-building-one-government/articleshow/116725340.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/congress-demands-memorial-for-manmohan-singh-committed-to-building-one-government/articleshow/116725340.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 21:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Snowfall paints Kashmir white - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Snowfall Paints Kashmir White</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2022</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Greater Kashmir</p>
<p>The recent snowfall in Kashmir has delighted locals and tourists alike, marking the end of a prolonged dry spell. However, it has also caused significant disruptions to traffic and air travel.</p>
<ul>
<li>Kashmir received its first snowfall of the season, affecting Srinagar and various districts.</li>
<li>Traffic disruptions were reported on major routes, including the Srinagar-Jammu National Highway.</li>
<li>Seven flights were cancelled at Srinagar International Airport due to heavy snow and low visibility.</li>
<li>The Meteorological Department predicted continued snowfall in higher altitudes.</li>
<li>Roads leading to the Chenab Valley and Pir Panjal regions are likely to remain closed for months due to heavy snow accumulation.</li>
<li>Local authorities are advising caution due to potential landslides and slippery conditions on roads.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I drove from Jammu to Srinagar today. It snowed continuously from Banihal to Srinagar. The conditions were quite treacherous.” - Omar Abdullah, Chief Minister</blockquote>
<p>This significant snowfall has not only brought joy for winter tourism but also presents challenges for infrastructure and safety on the roads.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/front-page-2/snowfall-paints-kashmir-white/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/front-page-2/snowfall-paints-kashmir-white/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 19:17:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Girl child raped in UP's Basti; 3 boys aged 6-7 booked - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/girl-child-raped-in-ups-basti-3-boys-aged-6-7-booked-101735320814755.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/girl-child-raped-in-ups-basti-3-boys-aged-6-7-booked-101735320814755.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:40:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Shocking & deliberate insult': Congress, SAD slam Centre over Manmohan Singh's last rites, memorial - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shocking & deliberate insult: Congress, SAD slam Centre over Manmohan Singh's last rites, memorial</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 25, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>An uproar has ensued as Congress and the Shiromani Akali Dal criticize the Central government for its handling of former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh's last rites and memorial.</p><ul><li>The article details the significant backlash against the Central government.</li><li>It highlights statements from key figures in Congress and SAD regarding the perceived neglect of Singh's contributions.</li><li>Public sentiment is heavily in favor of memorializing Singh appropriately.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a shocking and deliberate insult to a leader who served the nation.”</blockquote><p>The article concludes by emphasizing the need for the government to honor Singh’s legacy in a respectful and appropriate manner.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/shocking-deliberate-insult-congress-sad-slam-centre-over-manmohan-singhs-last-rites-memorial/articleshow/116721431.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/shocking-deliberate-insult-congress-sad-slam-centre-over-manmohan-singhs-last-rites-memorial/articleshow/116721431.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh’s funeral at Nigambodh ghat, Congress calls it deliberate insult to first Sikh PM - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manmohan Singh’s funeral at Nigambodh ghat, Congress calls it deliberate insult to first Sikh PM</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 27, 2024 - <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ogmcjb/article69034679.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241227232L.jpg" alt="Congress leaders paid their last respects to former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh, who passed away at the age of 92, at Bidhan Bhavan in Kolkata on Friday." title="Congress leaders paid their last respects to former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh, who passed away at the age of 92, at Bidhan Bhavan in Kolkata on Friday."><figcaption>Congress leaders paid their last respects to former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh.</figcaption><p>The Ministry of Home Affairs has ordered a State funeral for former Prime Minister Dr Manmohan Singh at Nigambodh Ghat, which has sparked controversy with the Congress party calling it a deliberate insult to Singh's legacy.</p><ul><li>Dr Manmohan Singh passed away at the age of 92.</li><li>The Congress demanded a funeral location suitable for a memorial.</li><li>The decision for Nigambodh Ghat was made after discussions between Congress leaders and government officials.</li><li>Senior Congress leaders expressed that the choice of location is viewed as disrespectful.</li><li>Dr Singh was a highly revered figure, recognized for his significant contributions to India.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is nothing but a deliberate insult to the first Sikh Prime Minister of India, Dr. Manmohan Singh,” said Congress communication chief Jairam Ramesh.</blockquote><p>The government's decision has sparked a broader discussion about how national leaders are honored in death and the significance of memorials for their contributions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manmohan-singhs-final-journey-on-december-28-cremation-at-nigambodh-ghat/article69034552.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/manmohan-singhs-final-journey-on-december-28-cremation-at-nigambodh-ghat/article69034552.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['No One Should Blame Girl For Being With Male Friend': Madras HC Orally Remarks In Plea For CBI Probe... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Madras High Court Emphasizes Victim's Rights in Anna University Sexual Assault Case</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p><p>The Madras High Court heard pleas for a CBI probe into the sexual assault of a student at Anna University, stressing that victims should not be blamed for the circumstances surrounding their assault.</p><ul><li>The court clarified that no one should blame the victim for being with her boyfriend during the incident.</li><li>It criticized the State Government for leaking the FIR and emphasized the need for privacy and respect for victims.</li><li>The court raised concerns about campus security, pointing out that many surveillance cameras were non-functional at the time of the incident.</li><li>There were questions regarding the legality of the police commissioner’s remarks about the investigation status.</li><li>The case has significant implications regarding the accountability of law enforcement and university authorities.</li></ul><blockquote>“Just because this incident has happened, no one should blame the girl for sitting with her boyfriend. It is her private right.”</blockquote><p>The court's remarks reflect a growing awareness of victim rights and the importance of privacy in legal proceedings, while also demanding higher accountability from law enforcement and educational institutions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/madras-high-court/madras-high-court-anna-university-no-blame-on-girl-govt-criticised-for-fir-leak-279535</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/madras-high-court/madras-high-court-anna-university-no-blame-on-girl-govt-criticised-for-fir-leak-279535</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:30:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DGCA suspends two top officials at Akasa Air over “training lapses” - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>DGCA Suspends Two Akasa Air Officials Over Training Lapses</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/iw7ov4/article69034466.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_FILE_PHOTO__An_Akasa_2_1_DODECEL2.jpg" alt="Photo used for representation purpose only." title="Photo used for representation purpose only." /><figcaption>Photo used for representation purpose only. | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>The Directorate General of Civil Aviation (DGCA) has suspended the head of operations and head of training at Akasa Air for six months due to training lapses related to the use of an uncertified simulator for pilot training.</p><ul><li>DGCA conducted a regulatory audit that revealed significant training violations.</li><li>Capt. Floyd Gracious and Neeraj Bhatia are suspended and must be replaced by suitable candidates.</li><li>Previous fines and penalties for Akasa Air indicate ongoing compliance issues.</li></ul><blockquote>The DGCA noted that the airline's response to earlier violations was unsatisfactory.</blockquote><p>This suspension highlights the ongoing scrutiny faced by Akasa Air concerning pilot training and operational compliance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/dgca-suspends-two-top-officials-at-akasa-air-over-training-lapses/article69034349.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/dgca-suspends-two-top-officials-at-akasa-air-over-training-lapses/article69034349.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi pollution: CAQM revokes GRAP 3 measures as rain improves air quality - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Pollution: CAQM Revokes GRAP 3 Measures as Rain Improves Air Quality</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/PTI12-27-2024-000298A-0_1735310726237_1735310749963.jpg" alt="People move amid rain at Vijay Chowk, in New Delhi.(PTI)"><figcaption>People move amid rain at Vijay Chowk, in New Delhi.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Delhi's air pollution levels showed a declining trend, prompting the Centre's anti-pollution panel to revoke Stage 3 curbs under the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) due to improved air quality brought on by rain.</p><ul><li>The 24-hour average air quality index (AQI) was 324 at 7 PM.</li><li>CAQM stated that air quality shifted from 'severe' to 'poor', allowing the withdrawal of Stage 3 measures.</li><li>Stage 1 and 2 measures will remain in effect to prevent further deterioration.</li><li>The significant impact of rain is expected to continue improving air quality in the city.</li><li>GRAP Stage 3 included bans on non-essential construction, hybrid schooling for younger students, and restrictions on certain vehicles.</li></ul><blockquote>"Delhi's air quality has shifted from the 'severe' category to the 'poor' range. As a result, measures under Stage III, implemented earlier, are now being withdrawn." - CAQM</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the recent rainfall in Delhi has led to a notable improvement in air quality, prompting authorities to ease certain pollution control measures while maintaining vigilance to ensure continued air quality management.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-pollution-caqm-revokes-grap-3-measures-as-rain-improves-air-quality-101735310373594.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-pollution-caqm-revokes-grap-3-measures-as-rain-improves-air-quality-101735310373594.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:44:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru founder drives his own cab at 3 am after driver falls asleep on the job. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxOMkVLenJWUWVSU1hIV1Y0Wk9nTDBQcFlTb3BDaVZhUzZNZXcxd2xrM3Z3LXlLbGFrcVZIc3NfV3Z1QTB4RUJ1VWhqUWd6aWpzTzJFRFl3cFVVY0RTazhCemJGVTM3Y0hoeFZrZGNYRUdWanF4THd1U21oaGdueXdsM0RtR1FVcUx5S3lnRnotZTR1WUc2ZEljNC0tMk1Pb0Jva3piRFoyYXdfelRnNnE1XzRYTkttTTJsNWNCRzZWY3Rld2hEQnRFR3B5dEg3NkFrakhvdDNZRl9HaVZCUlpUc3pB0gHnAUFVX3lxTE9MUzYyOVVONEVNSnNwaXhqUzRkUU1KSU91R2VYY2JQQmIwdDZkazM2TVFCRXUwYkVtX0wwcm5OZm1SZXNLZ2hYTHdHdk5NaFpNblM4Ukl1SDZ4QXdXZTMtV2ZuSm44SU5FYndwQVRMY191YmpwcXhrSEtQNk1idGcyZDMtTWREdTlfbEhLQTI2TmowQ04tOTAtZUVrbUVMVy04THlnVW1DRTFtUk8yOThCcGY4YUlxNjJxM0tWZ1dXdWh4VkJyWWdTQTQ5bHBuMXZIU2dvSjR1bFpCblVUZ3ZNZmEyWmFKRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxOMkVLenJWUWVSU1hIV1Y0Wk9nTDBQcFlTb3BDaVZhUzZNZXcxd2xrM3Z3LXlLbGFrcVZIc3NfV3Z1QTB4RUJ1VWhqUWd6aWpzTzJFRFl3cFVVY0RTazhCemJGVTM3Y0hoeFZrZGNYRUdWanF4THd1U21oaGdueXdsM0RtR1FVcUx5S3lnRnotZTR1WUc2ZEljNC0tMk1Pb0Jva3piRFoyYXdfelRnNnE1XzRYTkttTTJsNWNCRzZWY3Rld2hEQnRFR3B5dEg3NkFrakhvdDNZRl9HaVZCUlpUc3pB0gHnAUFVX3lxTE9MUzYyOVVONEVNSnNwaXhqUzRkUU1KSU91R2VYY2JQQmIwdDZkazM2TVFCRXUwYkVtX0wwcm5OZm1SZXNLZ2hYTHdHdk5NaFpNblM4Ukl1SDZ4QXdXZTMtV2ZuSm44SU5FYndwQVRMY191YmpwcXhrSEtQNk1idGcyZDMtTWREdTlfbEhLQTI2TmowQ04tOTAtZUVrbUVMVy04THlnVW1DRTFtUk8yOThCcGY4YUlxNjJxM0tWZ1dXdWh4VkJyWWdTQTQ5bHBuMXZIU2dvSjR1bFpCblVUZ3ZNZmEyWmFKRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Audit reveals lapses: DGCA suspends two senior Akasa pilots in-charge of operations & training - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Audit reveals lapses: DGCA suspends two senior Akasa pilots in-charge of operations & training</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Akasa Airlines"/><figcaption>Image of Akasa Airlines fleet</figcaption><p>The Directorate General of Civil Aviation (DGCA) has suspended two senior pilots from Akasa Airlines, following an audit that revealed significant operational and training lapses. This decision comes as the DGCA emphasizes the importance of safety in aviation operations.</p><ul><li>The pilots were in charge of critical operational responsibilities.</li><li>The audit indicated various compliance issues related to training and operational protocols.</li><li>DGCA has underlined its commitment to stringent safety regulations in the aviation sector.</li></ul><blockquote>“Safety is paramount in aviation, and immediate corrective actions are taken whenever discrepancies are found.” - DGCA Official</blockquote><p>This suspension is part of a broader effort by the DGCA to ensure that all airlines adhere strictly to safety regulations, highlighting their ongoing vigilance in safeguarding aviation standards.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/audit-reveals-lapses-dgca-suspends-two-senior-akasa-pilots-in-charge-of-operations-training/articleshow/116718537.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/audit-reveals-lapses-dgca-suspends-two-senior-akasa-pilots-in-charge-of-operations-training/articleshow/116718537.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manmohan Singh Death: Why Is The Funeral Not Today And What Does Protocol Say? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/manmohan-singh-death-why-is-the-funeral-not-today-and-what-does-protocol-say-ws-ab-9169651.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/manmohan-singh-death-why-is-the-funeral-not-today-and-what-does-protocol-say-ws-ab-9169651.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:24:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress Seeks Space For Memorial To Manmohan Singh, Writes To PM - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Seeks Space For Memorial To Manmohan Singh, Writes To PM</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Congress Party Statement</p>
<p>Following the passing of former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, Congress chief Mallikarjun Kharge has reached out to Prime Minister Narendra Modi to discuss the possibility of building a memorial at the site of his last rites.</p>
<ul>
<li>Manmohan Singh passed away at the age of 92 due to age-related issues.</li>
<li>He served two terms as Prime Minister from 2004 to 2014 under the UPA government.</li>
<li>The last rites are scheduled to take place on December 28, 2024, at Nigambodh Ghat in Delhi.</li>
<li>Kharge emphasized that this request aligns with traditions of memorializing leaders at their funeral sites.</li>
<li>Singh is credited with vital economic reforms that greatly improved India's economic stability.</li>
<li>He had a significant role in ushering in various landmark policies like the NREGS and the RTI.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When the nation was in the throes of grave economic crisis, it was Dr. Manmohan Singh who took India out of the crisis and also led the country towards prosperity.” — Mallikarjun Kharge</blockquote>
<p>This request seeks to honor Singh's legacy as a statesman and a national leader.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/manmohan-singhs-last-rites-should-be-held-at-a-place-where-a-memorial-can-be-built-m-kharge-writes-to-pm-modi-7345275</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/manmohan-singhs-last-rites-should-be-held-at-a-place-where-a-memorial-can-be-built-m-kharge-writes-to-pm-modi-7345275</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:22:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pollution Curbs Under GRAP-3 Revoked In Delhi As Air Quality Improves - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pollution Curbs Under GRAP-3 Revoked In Delhi As Air Quality Improves</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>The pollution curbs in Delhi under GRAP-3 have been lifted due to improvements in air quality following continuous rains. The AQI has shown a downward trend and is expected to remain in the 'poor' category for the next few days.</p><ul><li>Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) 3 curbs lifted as air quality improves.</li><li>Continuous rains have contributed to a decrease in the AQI levels.</li><li>Restrictions on diesel generators and construction activities are being eased, but some areas remain under closure orders.</li><li>Stage I & II of the revised GRAP will remain in effect to monitor air quality.</li></ul><blockquote>“Actions under Stage I & II of the revised GRAP shall remain invoked and be implemented, monitored and reviewed by all the agencies concerned in the entire NCR.”</blockquote><p>This move marks a shift in response to improved environmental conditions, as the seasonal pollution issues are still anticipated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pollution-curbs-under-grap-3-revoked-in-delhi-as-air-quality-improves-7345132</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pollution-curbs-under-grap-3-revoked-in-delhi-as-air-quality-improves-7345132</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:04:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madras High Court Takes Suo Motu Cognizance Of Alleged Sexual Assault Of Student At Anna University - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Madras High Court Takes Suo Motu Cognizance Of Alleged Sexual Assault Of Student At Anna University</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Madras High Court</p><p>The Madras High Court has taken cognizance of the alleged sexual assault of a second-year engineering student at Anna University in Chennai, following a letter from Advocate R Varalakshmi.</p><ul><li>The incident happened on December 23 when the accused allegedly recorded a video of the girl and her male friend before assaulting her.</li><li>The bench noted the need for procedural adherence before action can be taken and awaits formal orders from the Chief Justice.</li><li>The Advocate General assured the court that the state would file a status report on the investigation.</li><li>Concerns have been raised regarding campus safety and the history of the accused, who has previous sexual assault cases against him.</li><li>The National Commission for Women has also responded, calling for stricter punishments related to leakage of FIR details.</li></ul><blockquote>“We've made an attempt to get orders from the Chief Justice...There's a procedure to be followed. So we'll have to wait for the official orders,” said the court.</blockquote><p>The court's reaction highlights the ongoing issues surrounding campus security and the legal processes to ensure justice and safety for students.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/madras-high-court/madras-high-court-anna-university-sexual-harassment-case-suo-motu-cognisance-279528</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/high-court/madras-high-court/madras-high-court-anna-university-sexual-harassment-case-suo-motu-cognisance-279528</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:22:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Friend, Philosopher, Guide": Sonia Gandhi Remembers Manmohan Singh - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/he-was-my-friend-philosopher-and-guide-sonia-gandhi-remembers-manmohan-singh-7344810</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/he-was-my-friend-philosopher-and-guide-sonia-gandhi-remembers-manmohan-singh-7344810</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:18:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China defends plan to build world's largest dam over Brahmaputra River in Tibet - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Defends the Construction of the World's Largest Dam Over the Brahmaputra River</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/Dam_1735304527810_1735304534430.jpg" alt="China said it will continue to maintain communication with countries in the lower reaches. (Representational)" title="China said it will continue to maintain communication with countries in the lower reaches. (Representational)">
<figcaption>China said it will continue to maintain communication with countries in the lower reaches. (Representational)</figcaption>
<p>The Chinese foreign ministry announced plans for a $137 billion dam on the Brahmaputra River in Tibet, asserting that it will not adversely affect neighboring countries along the river.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The dam is part of a major infrastructure project in the ecologically sensitive Himalayan region.</li>
  <li>China claims it has conducted extensive studies to ensure the project's safety and environmental impact.</li>
  <li>Work on the dam aims to foster international cooperation on disaster prevention and relief.</li>
  <li>Construction will take at least a decade and will connect to the grid further east.</li>
  <li>Concerns have been raised about potential water flow reductions affecting downstream countries, especially India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Everybody downstream is going to be concerned about what it means if water flow is reduced. I know India is very anxious about it.” - David Fishman, energy consulting firm</blockquote>
<p>This ambitious project highlights the complexities of managing international rivers and the geopolitical implications for neighboring nations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/china-defends-plan-to-build-worlds-largest-dam-over-brahmaputra-river-in-tibet-101735304422074.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/china-defends-plan-to-build-worlds-largest-dam-over-brahmaputra-river-in-tibet-101735304422074.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madras High Court slams TN Police for leaking FIR copy of Anna University sexual assault - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Madras High Court Criticizes Police for FIR Leak in Anna University Assault Case</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2024-12-27T12:59:25.818Z" title="2024-12-27 12:59">27 Dec 2024, 12:59 pm</time></p><p>The Madras High Court has condemned the Chennai Police for leaking the identity of a 19-year-old student who was assaulted at Anna University, questioning the implications for the victim's family and the broader chilling effect on victims coming forward.</p><ul><li>The Court expressed concern over the police's failure to redact the victim's identity in the FIR.</li><li>Justice SM Subramaniam emphasized that the negligence could deter future victims from approaching law enforcement.</li><li>The incident involved the arrest of a biryani vendor accused of sexually assaulting the student on December 23.</li><li>The Court is demanding answers from the police regarding lapses and the portrayal of the investigation's status.</li><li>Concerns were raised over the operational capacity of CCTV cameras at the university during the incident.</li></ul><blockquote>“You can upload the FIR but you are supposed to redact identity details. The damage caused to the victim and her family can't be taken back by you.”</blockquote><p>The Court's remarks reflect a critical stance towards systemic issues in handling sexual assault cases, emphasizing the need for accountability and protective measures for victims.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/madras-high-court-slams-tn-police-for-leaking-fir-copy-of-anna-university-sexual-assault</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/litigation/madras-high-court-slams-tn-police-for-leaking-fir-copy-of-anna-university-sexual-assault</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:59:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 Dead, 26 hurt as bus plunges into drain in Punjab - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bus Accident in Punjab Leaves 8 Dead and 26 Injured</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 6, 2023<br><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<p>This tragic incident occurred when a bus plunged into a drain in Punjab, resulting in multiple fatalities and injuries.</p>
<ul>
  <li>8 people lost their lives in the accident.</li>
  <li>26 individuals sustained injuries, with varying degrees of severity.</li>
  <li>The accident has sparked significant concern over road safety standards in the region.</li>
  <li>Rescue operations were launched immediately to assist the victims.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This is a heartbreaking tragedy that could have been avoided with better road safety measures." - Local Official</blockquote>
<p>The accident highlights the need for improved infrastructure and safety precautions on roads to prevent such incidents in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/over-20-injured-as-bus-plunges-few-feet-down-from-bridge-in-punjabs-bathinda/articleshow/116713996.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/over-20-injured-as-bus-plunges-few-feet-down-from-bridge-in-punjabs-bathinda/articleshow/116713996.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heavy Rain In Delhi Causes Severe Waterlogging, 'Orange' Alert Issued: Latest Weather Updates - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Heavy Rain In Delhi Causes Severe Waterlogging, 'Orange' Alert Issued: Latest Weather Updates</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Delhi Weather Updates" loading="eager"><figcaption>Delhi Weather Updates: Temperature in Delhi stood at 13 degree Celsius at 7:23am as the weather department forecast heavy rain and strong winds for December 27th and 28th.</figcaption><p>Delhi experienced heavy rainfall and lightning today as the cold wave intensified. The India Meteorological Department (IMD) has predicted thunderstorms, hailstorms, and moderate rainfall across northwestern and central India on December 27 and 28 due to an active western disturbance.</p><ul><li>Temperature in Delhi stood at 13 degree Celsius at 7:23am.</li><li>The maximum temperature expected to reach 20 degrees Celsius, with a minimum of 12 degrees Celsius.</li><li>Heavy rain and strong winds forecasted for December 27th and 28th.</li><li>IMD issued warnings for hailstorms in several northern states.</li><li>Delhi’s air quality remains ‘very poor’, with some improvement expected.</li></ul><blockquote>“On December 27 and 28, Madhya Pradesh is likely to face similar conditions.”</blockquote><p>The weather department's warnings indicate serious impacts on daily life in Delhi and surrounding areas, highlighting the need for precautionary measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/cold-wave-intensifies-in-delhi-as-national-capital-wakes-up-to-rain-latest-updates-9169409.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/cold-wave-intensifies-in-delhi-as-national-capital-wakes-up-to-rain-latest-updates-9169409.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:39:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Manmohan Singh preferred Maruti 800 over BMW': UP minister shares anecdote about ex-PM - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manmohan Singh preferred Maruti 800 over BMW: UP minister shares anecdote about ex-PM</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Current Date | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="UP Minister anecdote" width="600" height="400">
<figcaption>UP Minister shares a humorous anecdote about Manmohan Singh.</figcaption>
<p>The Uttar Pradesh minister shared a light-hearted memory about former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh preferring a humble Maruti 800 over a luxurious BMW, highlighting his simplicity and down-to-earth nature.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The anecdote reflects the character of Manmohan Singh during his tenure as Prime Minister.</li>
  <li>It emphasizes Singh's preference for practicality over luxury.</li>
  <li>The minister's story aims to evoke nostalgia among many who admired Singh.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Manmohan Singh was a leader who valued simplicity above all.”</blockquote>
<p>This anecdote serves as a reminder of the leaders who prioritize accessibility and relatability in their public image.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/manmohan-singh-preferred-maruti-800-over-bmw-up-minister-shares-anecdote-about-ex-pm/articleshow/116702450.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/manmohan-singh-preferred-maruti-800-over-bmw-up-minister-shares-anecdote-about-ex-pm/articleshow/116702450.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>