<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:17:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:17:46 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nitin Gadkari announces nationwide cashless treatment scheme for road accident victims - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitin Gadkari announces nationwide cashless treatment scheme for road accident victims</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/uvuz6d/article68687703.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI09_26_2024_000152A.jpg" alt="Minister Nitin Gadkari addressing the seminar"/><figcaption>Bengaluru: Union Minister for Road Transport & Highways Nitin Gadkari addresses an international seminar on ‘Advances in Bridge Management’ organised by Indian Roads Congress, in Bengaluru, Karnataka, Thursday, Sept. 26, 2024. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>The Central government is set to implement a cashless treatment scheme for road accident victims, allowing up to ₹1.5 lakh per person for medical care.</p><ul><li>The scheme will be applicable for all road accidents involving motor vehicles.</li><li>The National Health Authority will coordinate the implementation with various agencies.</li><li>It will function via a new IT platform integrating existing applications for accident management.</li><li>The pilot programme previously launched in Chandigarh will be expanded nationwide by March 2025.</li><li>Additional discussions on driver fatigue and vehicle safety measures were highlighted during the recent workshop.</li></ul><blockquote>“The broad contours of the pilot programme are -- victims entitled to cashless treatment up to a maximum of ₹1.5 lakh per accident per person for a maximum period of 7 days from the date of the accident.” - Nitin Gadkari</blockquote><p>This initiative aims to provide timely medical assistance to accident victims across India, addressing critical needs in emergency response.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/nitin-gadkari-announces-modified-cashless-treatment-scheme-for-road-accident-victims-nationwide/article69075166.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/nitin-gadkari-announces-modified-cashless-treatment-scheme-for-road-accident-victims-nationwide/article69075166.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sale By Way Of Public Auction Can't Be Set Aside Unless There's Material Irregularity Or Fraud/Collusion... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sale By Way Of Public Auction Can't Be Set Aside Unless There's Material Irregularity Or Fraud/Collusion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p><p>The Supreme Court has reiterated that public auction sales cannot be set aside unless there is a material irregularity, illegality, fraud, or collusion involved in the auction process.</p><ul><li>The Court cited <i>V.S. Palanivel vs. P. Sriram</i> which established that without serious flaws in the conduct of the auction, it should not be set aside.</li><li>A recent ruling in <i>Celir LLP vs Ms Sumati Prasad Bafna and others</i> confirmed that mere procedural irregularities do not justify the annulment of confirmed sales unless they are fundamental.</li><li>Justice BV Nagaratna and Justice NK Singh emphasized the principle that without material irregularities, auctions should typically be upheld to avoid chaos in transactions.</li><li>The Supreme Court reversed a Delhi High Court decision that invalidated an auction under the SARFAESI Act 2002.</li><li>The borrower had several opportunities to redeem the mortgage, and an alleged possessory claim was dismissed due to lack of valid documentation.</li><li>The auction was conducted following statutory requirements, making it a valid sale.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is now a well-settled principle that a sale by way of public auction cannot be set aside until there is any material irregularity and/or illegality committed in holding the auction or if such auction was vitiated by any fraud or collusion.”</blockquote><p>The Supreme Court's ruling aims to uphold the integrity of auction sales and ensure that legitimate transactions are not disrupted due to minor irregularities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/sale-by-way-of-public-auction-cant-be-set-aside-unless-theres-material-irregularity-or-fraudcollusion-supreme-court-280276</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/sale-by-way-of-public-auction-cant-be-set-aside-unless-theres-material-irregularity-or-fraudcollusion-supreme-court-280276</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:26:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Railways unveils Vande Bharat, specially designed for winters in J-K, for Katra-Srinagar route - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQUFlXeVBmbmIzODZWX25jaHVIdTJRVHI3NzJrckU5QnBBTm9kY0ZUb29tX1RlUkN2SnNUdXRKbUZ6MzVJYWZ5Rm5iYTlzTDgzcmJGbTFsYjlaaGZORVFSMWRpT1RXZ3A0WXlvMkJyYlBhdmw0X0pPSHJVVkxHOW1aVnlZeVhndF9SYjl0NG9JX2gzeDd6SV9yUG1raWl3U0Vybl9wd2piVHZNSURWXzVBQm9ub0ZyME1IOTZtek5qbm9FdGJGMVVwWXRxLWUxQjZvVFHSAdcBQVVfeXFMT0d2LU1MckJ6V0xuaTBha29ENkJGUmhZUy11M0JaYVJjWWh2cFVwS0FzLUZGeHN1dmVjUUlNcnhGVHdmQUdmeUttUXdXN2RHa2JfVVVwUy1zdUJBbkhfRGlCQTZObWRNNWZGYi1TZEk0Ty1jX08zQkNFZ2xpUzZ4RnFxbXlodmVWNGpRMHZwSVpmYm1CYVQzZllrLWFFbkpGMVdlYXRjall1UzZNdURESkRWSW1Ea1VkckgzcVpBcjlHZGk1cmxBc2o1VGxMS0dzR3c2ZDEySzA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQUFlXeVBmbmIzODZWX25jaHVIdTJRVHI3NzJrckU5QnBBTm9kY0ZUb29tX1RlUkN2SnNUdXRKbUZ6MzVJYWZ5Rm5iYTlzTDgzcmJGbTFsYjlaaGZORVFSMWRpT1RXZ3A0WXlvMkJyYlBhdmw0X0pPSHJVVkxHOW1aVnlZeVhndF9SYjl0NG9JX2gzeDd6SV9yUG1raWl3U0Vybl9wd2piVHZNSURWXzVBQm9ub0ZyME1IOTZtek5qbm9FdGJGMVVwWXRxLWUxQjZvVFHSAdcBQVVfeXFMT0d2LU1MckJ6V0xuaTBha29ENkJGUmhZUy11M0JaYVJjWWh2cFVwS0FzLUZGeHN1dmVjUUlNcnhGVHdmQUdmeUttUXdXN2RHa2JfVVVwUy1zdUJBbkhfRGlCQTZObWRNNWZGYi1TZEk0Ty1jX08zQkNFZ2xpUzZ4RnFxbXlodmVWNGpRMHZwSVpmYm1CYVQzZllrLWFFbkpGMVdlYXRjall1UzZNdURESkRWSW1Ea1VkckgzcVpBcjlHZGk1cmxBc2o1VGxMS0dzR3c2ZDEySzA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:04:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP Candidates List for Delhi Assembly Election 2025, Including Constituencies and Districts​​​ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxQY0tpMFo5SGxqNF9hY2VNcnNzRC1DUHhaU3QyZDdMWktRS0pDNElQV2VPQjQyVWdJVVNkc1dMYm9DUDJKMS1qaUhaVkwwQXlaaTRkajJhWW9zRWhIV3BvbWJVd1lUNXVWeWJqWjJzdFItRzFJd2l1Q0VmaGtjUi1wOTI5ZGJDcGhFUmZGYTdwcHlyZTJsT3pxQ2Y5dEl1d2VxLTFZOWhVYzlsc0NydEVEeUJ4aEVkb0toVDhHSHlfc2kyY19GUGQwV05Sc21xRS01R3Nzb3A0cWlodURvZV8taUJKVEFnWmNJS05PY0MxcjF2LWFSRmY40gH8AUFVX3lxTE9BWl9GV2tGWjhJYWVDWk5hOV9wUy12TEdJYmJJTW9wV1dCdXdzYnZOaFY5UEh3NVh4M3drWUN0TXJHT0o0eFJpSEt6aWVTSG5DWHBtUEl6NUV6QlQ2TEJkWlpMM1JTM2c2MDR4ZnlhT0g0Z3RXd0F6ME9lbDlaYl9WdEU0ZnE2cEdOZThvdFJWNDlQb25GV00yRzQ1SnpxQ1RRajFYT1pmeGxVWkZ1Y0doTjVhU2RyU3FLdXZ4NjR1eEVnVndIdGtkN0NqLVRmZkZ4WlBYcW00TjR5aEdhMTVlNUx1Y0JmTS1DaE5TQXliUEd4Z1Y2cERWM3pxRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxQY0tpMFo5SGxqNF9hY2VNcnNzRC1DUHhaU3QyZDdMWktRS0pDNElQV2VPQjQyVWdJVVNkc1dMYm9DUDJKMS1qaUhaVkwwQXlaaTRkajJhWW9zRWhIV3BvbWJVd1lUNXVWeWJqWjJzdFItRzFJd2l1Q0VmaGtjUi1wOTI5ZGJDcGhFUmZGYTdwcHlyZTJsT3pxQ2Y5dEl1d2VxLTFZOWhVYzlsc0NydEVEeUJ4aEVkb0toVDhHSHlfc2kyY19GUGQwV05Sc21xRS01R3Nzb3A0cWlodURvZV8taUJKVEFnWmNJS05PY0MxcjF2LWFSRmY40gH8AUFVX3lxTE9BWl9GV2tGWjhJYWVDWk5hOV9wUy12TEdJYmJJTW9wV1dCdXdzYnZOaFY5UEh3NVh4M3drWUN0TXJHT0o0eFJpSEt6aWVTSG5DWHBtUEl6NUV6QlQ2TEJkWlpMM1JTM2c2MDR4ZnlhT0g0Z3RXd0F6ME9lbDlaYl9WdEU0ZnE2cEdOZThvdFJWNDlQb25GV00yRzQ1SnpxQ1RRajFYT1pmeGxVWkZ1Y0doTjVhU2RyU3FLdXZ4NjR1eEVnVndIdGtkN0NqLVRmZkZ4WlBYcW00TjR5aEdhMTVlNUx1Y0JmTS1DaE5TQXliUEd4Z1Y2cERWM3pxRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[V. Narayanan, who is set to take over as ISRO Chairman, terms his new assignment ‘a great responsibility’ - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>V. Narayanan Set to Lead ISRO with Great Responsibility</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/kerala/p9rmlm/article69075001.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/nara1.jpg" alt="V. Narayanan, who will take over as ISRO Chairman from January 14, poses near a model of the Chandrayaan-3 moon lander." title="V. Narayanan, who will take over as ISRO Chairman from January 14, poses near a model of the Chandrayaan-3 moon lander."><figcaption>V. Narayanan, who will take over as ISRO Chairman from January 14, poses near a model of the Chandrayaan-3 moon lander.</figcaption><p>V. Narayanan, a rocket propulsion expert, will take over as the Chairman of ISRO on January 14, 2025. He describes this new role as a significant responsibility and opportunity to lead ISRO during a transformative time in India's space sector.</p><ul><li>Succeeds S. Somanath as ISRO Chairman.</li><li>ISRO has several major projects lined up including Gaganyaan, Chandrayaan-4, and an Indian space station.</li><li>Dr. Narayanan emphasizes the importance of increasing India's presence in space and the role of private sector reforms in achieving this goal.</li><li>He has a substantial background in rocket propulsion, having been with ISRO since 1984.</li></ul><blockquote>“Towards January-end we have the GSLV Mk-II/IRNSS-1 K mission... we have our hands full.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Dr. Narayanan's extensive experience and vision for reform will be crucial as ISRO embarks on its ambitious future projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/v-narayanan-who-is-set-to-take-over-as-isro-chairman-terms-his-new-assignment-as-a-great-responsibility/article69075005.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/v-narayanan-who-is-set-to-take-over-as-isro-chairman-terms-his-new-assignment-as-a-great-responsibility/article69075005.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ramesh Bidhuri to be replaced? Unease in BJP ahead of Delhi election: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unease in BJP Over Ramesh Bidhuri's Controversial Remarks Ahead of Delhi Elections</h1><p><strong>January 08, 2025</strong> - <strong>Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Ramesh-Bidhuri---ANI-_1736303205780_1736303230986.jpg" alt="BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri. (ANI)(HT_PRINT)"><figcaption>BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri. (ANI)(HT_PRINT)</figcaption><p>BJP leader Ramesh Bidhuri’s recent controversial remarks about Delhi chief minister Atishi and Congress MP Priyanka Gandhi Vadra have sparked a backlash, leading to discussions within the party about replacing him with a woman candidate for the upcoming assembly election.</p><ul><li>There have been at least two organisational meetings regarding Bidhuri's candidacy.</li><li>His remarks led to a reprimand from BJP leader JP Nadda.</li><li>Potential women replacements for Bidhuri are being discussed.</li><li>Bidhuri commented on Atishi's family name change, which drew criticism.</li></ul><blockquote>“Not just against Atishi, Rameshji’s statement on Priyanka Gandhi Vadra led to his being reprimanded by Naddaji within minutes,” a BJP source stated.</blockquote><p>The situation highlights internal tensions in the BJP as it prepares for the February 5 assembly election.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ramesh-bidhuri-to-be-replaced-unease-in-bjp-ahead-of-delhi-election-report-101736299967107.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ramesh-bidhuri-to-be-replaced-unease-in-bjp-ahead-of-delhi-election-report-101736299967107.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:11:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1 body recovered as forces resume operation to rescue trapped coal miners in Assam - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>1 Body Recovered as Forces Resume Operation to Rescue Trapped Coal Miners in Assam</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The Economic Times</p><p>Rescue operations have resumed in Assam after the recovery of one body of a coal miner. Efforts continue to locate the remaining trapped miners.</p><ul><li>One body has been recovered while others remain missing.</li><li>Rescue teams are engaged in ongoing operations to find the trapped individuals.</li><li>The incident has highlighted safety concerns in coal mining operations.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are working diligently to ensure everyone's safety and get the missing miners out as soon as possible," a rescue official stated.</blockquote><p>The incident raises critical questions about mine safety and the need for improved regulations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/guwahati/1-body-recovered-as-forces-resume-operation-to-rescue-trapped-coal-miners-in-assam/articleshow/117039208.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/guwahati/1-body-recovered-as-forces-resume-operation-to-rescue-trapped-coal-miners-in-assam/articleshow/117039208.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India on alert regarding China's proposed dam on Brahmaputra: Rajnath Singh - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India on Alert Regarding China's Proposed Mega Dam on Brahmaputra</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/cishnd/article69074914.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241229176L.jpg" alt="File picture of Defence Minister Rajnath Singh"><figcaption>File picture of Defence Minister Rajnath Singh | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>Defence Minister Rajnath Singh announced that the Indian government is monitoring China's plan to build a mega dam on the Brahmaputra river, indicating potential concerns for downstream water flow and regional security.</p><ul><li>India is closely watching developments regarding China's planned mega dam on the Brahmaputra river.</li><li>The dam poses potential risks to water flow impacting downstream states, prompting the Indian government's alert stance.</li><li>Rajnath Singh emphasized, "The Indian government is on alert" regarding the construction.</li><li>Singh highlighted India's growing global presence and economic strength, aiming to rank among the top three economies in the near future.</li><li>He urged educators to play a pivotal role in shaping the future of students.</li></ul><blockquote>"Earlier, people did not take it seriously when India spoke at international forums, but now when India speaks, the world listens." - Rajnath Singh</blockquote><p>The Indian government remains vigilant on the matter, reinforcing the importance of international dialogue concerning regional water resources.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/india-on-alert-regarding-chinas-proposed-dam-on-brahmaputra-rajnath-singh/article69074912.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/india-on-alert-regarding-chinas-proposed-dam-on-brahmaputra-rajnath-singh/article69074912.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prashant Kishor's health stable, aides urge him to end fast - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prashant Kishor's Health Condition Remains Stable Amid Fast</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 08, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/q98uiq/article69074899.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20250106253L.jpg" alt="Jan Suraaj party Chief Prashant Kishor. File" title="Jan Suraaj party Chief Prashant Kishor. File"><figcaption>Jan Suraaj party Chief Prashant Kishor. File | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>The health of Jan Suraaj Party founder Prashant Kishor is stable as he remains hospitalized after starting a fast unto death to support protesting candidates. Party leaders urge him to end his fast for his well-being.</p><ul><li>Kishor was admitted to ICU after suffering from dehydration.</li><li>Leaders from his party urged him to begin eating normally to protect his health.</li><li>Doctors hope if his condition improves, he might be moved out of ICU soon.</li><li>Kishor was fasting in support of BPSC aspirants protesting the examination process.</li><li>His fast began on January 2, culminating in a hospital admission on January 7.</li></ul><blockquote>“His fight is commendable, but Bihar faces many problems and his well-being is necessary for a prolonged struggle.” - Pavan K Varma</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while Kishor's health is stable, the ongoing protests underline significant issues regarding governance and public service examinations in Bihar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/bihar/prashant-kishors-health-stable-aides-urge-him-to-end-fast/article69074893.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/bihar/prashant-kishors-health-stable-aides-urge-him-to-end-fast/article69074893.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dense fog engulfs Delhi as temperature drops to 9°C, air quality remains in ‘poor category’ - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi wakes up to dense fog amid sharp drop in temperature</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/4r01oh/article69074860.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20250107210L.jpg" alt="Shallow fog covers the roads of Vijay Chowk, in New Delhi." title="Shallow fog covers the roads of Vijay Chowk, in New Delhi."><figcaption>Shallow fog covers the roads of Vijay Chowk, in New Delhi. File | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>Dense fog enveloped Delhi with visibility dropping to zero early Wednesday, accompanied by a significant drop in temperature.</p><ul><li>Visibility in Palam dropped to 50 metres at midnight, returning to 500 metres by 2.30 am, and then falling to zero at 5.30 am.</li><li>The minimum temperature recorded was 7.4 degrees Celsius, slightly above normal.</li><li>The maximum temperature is projected to reach around 16 degrees Celsius on Wednesday.</li><li>The Air Quality Index (AQI) recorded was 334, categorizing it as 'very poor'.</li></ul><blockquote>“Palam’s visibility dropped to 50 metres at 12 midnight. It improved to 500 metres by 2.30 am, before dropping to zero at 5.30 am.” - India Meteorological Department (IMD)</blockquote><p>The stark drop in temperature and the dense fog are notable developments for Delhi's winter season, impacting visibility and air quality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/deather-weather-fog-engulfs-minimum-temperature-drops-updates-january-8/article69074857.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/deather-weather-fog-engulfs-minimum-temperature-drops-updates-january-8/article69074857.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After almost five decades, Congress to bid adieu to 24, Akbar Road, move into a new home - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Moves to New Headquarters After Decades at 24, Akbar Road</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>The Congress party is set to bid farewell to its long-standing headquarters at 24, Akbar Road in New Delhi as it prepares to inaugurate its new office, Indira Gandhi Bhawan, located at 9 A, Kotla Road. The shift marks the end of an era for the party, which has seen significant historical events unfold at the Akbar Road location.</p><ul><li>The new headquarters has been under construction for 15 years and will be inaugurated on January 15.</li><li>Top Congress leaders, including AICC president Mallikarjun Kharge and Rahul Gandhi, are expected to attend the inauguration.</li><li>24, Akbar Road has been the Congress headquarters since 1978, witnessing critical moments in Indian political history.</li><li>The party plans to retain the Akbar Road building for high-profile meetings.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is time for us to move ahead with the times and embrace the new.” - K C Venugopal, AICC General Secretary</blockquote><p>The transition to the Indira Gandhi Bhawan symbolizes a modernization effort for the Congress party, aiming to create a workspace that caters to contemporary administrative and strategic needs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/after-five-decades-congress-to-bid-adieu-to-24-akbar-road-move-into-new-home-9766092/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/after-five-decades-congress-to-bid-adieu-to-24-akbar-road-move-into-new-home-9766092/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[V Narayanan named new ISRO chief, succeeds S Somanath - Onmanorama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNMWY2RmtITHhKX2RYTVNnaHNNcHBxZnhVUVphZEdGeHVsTndWaGNUMHpwSEhBZ2dsNU9XRHgxTFFDVVo5cFhGT0RtamUwNU9nYWplUVNxRmlYZTFqelM2MVhEcUZUODRacHl0SGRWcmtMN0NKenBjRTFCTGEzeTI5bEdmM0JOeHhTVWJaZzRZRzYxZ0hOUjB1dy0weFlfSms?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNMWY2RmtITHhKX2RYTVNnaHNNcHBxZnhVUVphZEdGeHVsTndWaGNUMHpwSEhBZ2dsNU9XRHgxTFFDVVo5cFhGT0RtamUwNU9nYWplUVNxRmlYZTFqelM2MVhEcUZUODRacHl0SGRWcmtMN0NKenBjRTFCTGEzeTI5bEdmM0JOeHhTVWJaZzRZRzYxZ0hOUjB1dy0weFlfSms?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:20:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Congressman challenges Biden Admin’s decision to investigate Adani, says risks relations with India - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxPT0FMUFMtTkZGSUVkUjJjOVdvNXFmMTFpbE1JMno1dVdRTkRGVk1HdUNCdFZQUFB3SzFhMF81dlBqS3dqMjF0SzFNZXhmcG1PenJvaVo2N1NlVkdqQzdKWFladUpTRndiQjZhUUFweDM2MnB3SFRodVdTd1RadTBZamtJYmljQWpHU3lwMk4xYmE2dmNmTHhoVVpOQnV0cDJBUEJ5dHFySlNMSU9Pb2FnX3NnRVFtUTR2TnlfUmo4c1l3Mi1uRzl1cmxOS1NoWC1FWl9mQzQyT2dNVjA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxPT0FMUFMtTkZGSUVkUjJjOVdvNXFmMTFpbE1JMno1dVdRTkRGVk1HdUNCdFZQUFB3SzFhMF81dlBqS3dqMjF0SzFNZXhmcG1PenJvaVo2N1NlVkdqQzdKWFladUpTRndiQjZhUUFweDM2MnB3SFRodVdTd1RadTBZamtJYmljQWpHU3lwMk4xYmE2dmNmTHhoVVpOQnV0cDJBUEJ5dHFySlNMSU9Pb2FnX3NnRVFtUTR2TnlfUmo4c1l3Mi1uRzl1cmxOS1NoWC1FWl9mQzQyT2dNVjA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:06:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RTO suspends Rapido’s operations - Ahmedabad Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxOMjhzeUhORWVvR1QxUjN4TV9mUzdmQ3JKbVhpN1hENWpiUF91cXBWWHdsUkRIOTB2U1hPbFBCUWszdzNzd3VEX1lRN1gwUTI1U1JRaG4xNHl6WENLbmhrYzMwT0k4Qm10Ml9MRlpOdExXWGtuWXhvazBZdlhDWEpHS0FSbw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxOMjhzeUhORWVvR1QxUjN4TV9mUzdmQ3JKbVhpN1hENWpiUF91cXBWWHdsUkRIOTB2U1hPbFBCUWszdzNzd3VEX1lRN1gwUTI1U1JRaG4xNHl6WENLbmhrYzMwT0k4Qm10Ml9MRlpOdExXWGtuWXhvazBZdlhDWEpHS0FSbw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:03:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Hindu Morning Digest, January 8, 2024 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Hindu Morning Digest: Key Updates from January 8, 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/e55ind/article69073738.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20250107203L.jpg" alt="Sharmistha Mukherjee calls on Prime Minister Narendra Modi" title="Sharmistha Mukherjee, author and daughter of former President Pranab Mukherjee, calls on Prime Minister Narendra Modi, in New Delhi on Tuesday." fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Sharmistha Mukherjee, author and daughter of former President Pranab Mukherjee, calls on Prime Minister Narendra Modi, in New Delhi on Tuesday. | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption>
<p>This article provides a summary of significant events reported on January 8, 2024, including political actions, government decisions, and upcoming legal reviews.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>General Strike Warning:</strong> 10 trade unions threaten to call a general strike if the Centre notifies new labour codes.</li>
<li><strong>Pranab Mukherjee Memorial:</strong> The Centre has earmarked a site at Rajghat for erecting a memorial for former President Pranab Mukherjee.</li>
<li><strong>UGC Draft Regulation:</strong> Students' body and teachers question new UGC draft regulation on faculty appointments, criticizing it for centralizing power.</li>
<li><strong>Sri Lanka-China Relations:</strong> Sri Lankan President Dissanayake is set to visit China from January 14.</li>
<li><strong>Same-Sex Marriage Review:</strong> The Supreme Court will hear petitions on January 9 regarding the review of its previous ruling on same-sex marriage.</li>
<li><strong>New ISRO Chief:</strong> Dr. V. Narayanan has been appointed as the new Space Secretary and ISRO Chairman.</li>
<li><strong>AI Governance:</strong> An inter-ministerial committee is recommended to strengthen governance in AI by the Centre's IndiaAI Mission.</li>
<li><strong>Bangladesh Political Turmoil:</strong> Bangladesh revokes the passport of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and others linked to protests.</li>
<li><strong>IAF Chief Comments:</strong> IAF chief states that R&D loses relevance if it doesn't meet project timelines.</li>
<li><strong>Allahabad High Court Ruling:</strong> Court dismisses plea against the impeachment motion for Justice Shekhar Yadav.</li>
<li><strong>Supreme Court Recommendation:</strong> Collegium recommends Patna HC Chief Justice for appointment to the Supreme Court.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Research and Development loses relevance if it does not meet timelines," - Air Chief Marshal A.P. Singh.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the updates from January 8 demonstrate ongoing significant political discussions and actions affecting various sectors in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/morning-digest-january-8-2024/article69073986.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/morning-digest-january-8-2024/article69073986.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi cold wave to intensify with temperatures set to plummet to 5 degrees this week - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Cold Wave to Intensify with Temperatures Set to Plummet to 5 Degrees This Week</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Cold-22_1736296121503_1736296142259.jpg" alt="Delhi weather: People sitting around a bonfire to warm themselves by fire on cold winter morning at Ram Lila Maidan in New Delhi.(Hindustan Times)" title="Delhi weather: People sitting around a bonfire to warm themselves by fire on cold winter morning at Ram Lila Maidan in New Delhi.(Hindustan Times)">
<figcaption>Delhi weather: People sitting around a bonfire to warm themselves by fire on cold winter morning at Ram Lila Maidan in New Delhi.(Hindustan Times)</figcaption>
<p>The Indian Meteorological Department forecasts a significant temperature drop in Delhi, with a minimum expected temperature of 5 degrees Celsius by Friday amidst adverse weather conditions.</p>
<ul>
<li>Temperatures in Delhi are projected to decrease starting Wednesday.</li>
<li>The Safdarjung observatory recorded a maximum temperature of 16.2 degrees Celsius, above normal.</li>
<li>Air Quality Index (AQI) remains in the "very poor" category, measuring 335 on Monday.</li>
<li>Restrictions under Stage 1 and 2 of the Graded Response Action Plan (GRAP) still apply in Delhi-NCR.</li>
<li>Dense fog reduced visibility significantly, leading to the delay of 25 trains.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The IMD reported that minimum visibility was recorded at 500 meters at Safdarjung, and at Palam, visibility was as low as 150 meters.</blockquote>
<p>This severe cold wave and deteriorating air quality highlight ongoing challenges for residents in Delhi due to adverse weather conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-cold-wave-to-intensify-with-temperatures-set-to-plummet-to-5-degrees-this-week-fog-aqi-air-quality-101736295849881.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-cold-wave-to-intensify-with-temperatures-set-to-plummet-to-5-degrees-this-week-fog-aqi-air-quality-101736295849881.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:55:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet V Narayanan, who is set to succeed S Somanath as ISRO chief - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meet V Narayanan, who is set to succeed S Somanath as ISRO chief</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/isro_chief_1736293960673_1736293993585.jpg" alt="New ISRO chief V Narayanan.(ANI)" title="New ISRO chief V Narayanan.(ANI)"><figcaption>New ISRO chief V Narayanan.(ANI)</figcaption></figure><p>V Narayanan has been appointed as the new chairman of the Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO), succeeding S Somanath, effective from January 14, 2025.</p><ul><li>V Narayanan is a distinguished scientist with nearly four decades of experience in rocket and spacecraft propulsion.</li><li>He began his career at ISRO in 1984 and has since held various roles, including director of the Liquid Propulsion Systems Centre (LPSC).</li><li>Narayanan has made significant contributions in solid propulsion for sounding rockets and various launch vehicles.</li><li>He is currently the director of LPSC, with responsibilities for propelling India's space missions.</li><li>ISRO recently gained attention for launching SpaDex, an initiative that places India among countries with advanced space docking technology.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Appointments Committee of the Cabinet has approved the appointment of Shri V. Narayanan...for a period of two years with effect from 14.01.2025, or until further orders, whichever is earlier.”</blockquote><p>Narayanan's extensive experience is expected to guide ISRO through its upcoming ambitious projects, including Chandrayaan 4 and Gaganyaan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/v-narayanan-new-isro-chief-s-somanath-indian-space-research-organisation-101736292217772.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/v-narayanan-new-isro-chief-s-somanath-indian-space-research-organisation-101736292217772.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:30:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Claws out: Man catches leopard by its tail, saves villagers from jaws of death - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Claws out: Man catches leopard by its tail, saves villagers from jaws of death</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>A heroic act by a man saved a village from a potentially deadly leopard encounter.</p><ul><li>A man caught a leopard by its tail.</li><li>His actions prevented harm to the villagers.</li><li>This incident highlights the ongoing human-wildlife conflict in the region.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was a dangerous situation, but I knew I had to act.” - Local hero</blockquote><p>This event underscores the need for better wildlife management and community awareness to prevent such encounters in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/claws-out-man-catches-leopard-by-its-tail-saves-villagers-from-jaws-of-death/articleshow/117034901.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/claws-out-man-catches-leopard-by-its-tail-saves-villagers-from-jaws-of-death/articleshow/117034901.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 20:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘You Are Virtually A Stranger’: Supreme Court To Atul Subhash’s Mother Who Sought Kid’s Custody - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Denies Custody to Atul Subhash's Mother, Calls Her 'Virtually a Stranger'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Atul reportedly had Rs 44,000 remaining each month for his and his family's living expenses, including rent, in Bengaluru. (News18 Hindi)" title="Atul reportedly had Rs 44,000 remaining each month for his and his family's living expenses, including rent, in Bengaluru. (News18 Hindi)"><figcaption>Atul reportedly had Rs 44,000 remaining each month for his and his family's living expenses, including rent, in Bengaluru. (News18 Hindi)</figcaption><p>The Supreme Court has refused the plea of Atul Subhash's mother seeking custody of her grandson, stating she is virtually a stranger to the child. The court emphasized the necessity of following proper legal procedures for such matters.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court denied custody of Atul Subhash’s son to his mother.</li><li>Justice Sharma highlighted that there is a separate procedure for custody issues.</li><li>The court advised her to visit the child rather than label her daughter-in-law as guilty without proof.</li><li>Atul Subhash had committed suicide on December 9, alleging harassment from his estranged wife and her family.</li><li>The habeas corpus petition regarding this case is pending until January 20.</li></ul><blockquote>“You’re virtually a stranger to the child. If you wish, please visit the child.” - Supreme Court</blockquote><p>This case illustrates the complex interplay between family law and personal circumstances influenced by tragic events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/atul-subhash-suicide-bengaluru-techie-mother-child-custody-plea-supreme-court-karnataka-hc-wife-nikita-singhania-9180540.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/atul-subhash-suicide-bengaluru-techie-mother-child-custody-plea-supreme-court-karnataka-hc-wife-nikita-singhania-9180540.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 20:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We’ve lost everything: Father after death of only son at IIM Bangalore - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>We’ve lost everything: Father after death of only son at IIM Bangalore</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/IIMB-Nilay-Patel.jpg?w=640" alt="IIMB" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>The victim, Nilay Patel, was a second-year Post Graduate student. (Express)</figcaption><p>On January 5, Kailash Patel celebrated his son Nilay's 28th birthday, unaware that a tragic incident would leave him bereft hours later. Nilay, a second-year Post Graduate student at IIM Bangalore, was found dead beneath his hostel balcony shortly after his birthday celebration.</p><ul><li>Nilay Patel was celebrated for his academic achievements, including a top position in a competition among IIM students.</li><li>He was preparing for campus placements and had secured an internship before his untimely death.</li><li>The family questions the circumstances of his death, emphasizing that there was no apparent stress in his life.</li><li>The police have registered a case of accidental death, with an investigation underway.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have lost everything in the world that we saved for. We dreamt of a good education for him and then his marriage and later, to play with our grandchildren. All our dreams have vanished.”</blockquote><p>The father has urged college authorities to enhance safety measures at the hostel to prevent such tragic events in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/ahmedabad/accidental-death-case-registered-after-student-found-dead-on-iimb-campus-question-of-how-confounds-father-after-death-of-only-son-9765921/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/ahmedabad/accidental-death-case-registered-after-student-found-dead-on-iimb-campus-question-of-how-confounds-father-after-death-of-only-son-9765921/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 20:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Army, Navy, NDRF deployed to rescue 11 trapped in flooded Assam 'rat hole' mine - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Army, Navy, NDRF Deployed to Rescue 11 Trapped in Assam 'Rat Hole' Mine</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 13, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Rescue Operation" />
<figcaption>Rescue operations underway in Assam.</figcaption>
<p>In a desperate attempt to save 11 workers trapped inside a flooded 'rat hole' mine in Assam, the Army, Navy, and National Disaster Response Force (NDRF) have been deployed. These rescue operations come amidst severe flash floods that have affected the region for days.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The workers were conducting illegal coal mining when the mine became flooded.</li>
  <li>Rescue teams are utilizing high-powered pumps to drain water from the mine.</li>
  <li>Local authorities have ramped up efforts to reach the trapped individuals quickly.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We are working tirelessly to ensure the safety of those trapped in the mine,” said a rescue spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>The situation remains critical, as families of the trapped workers anxiously await updates on their loved ones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/army-navy-ndrf-deployed-to-rescue-11-trapped-in-flooded-assam-rat-hole-mine/articleshow/117034790.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/army-navy-ndrf-deployed-to-rescue-11-trapped-in-flooded-assam-rat-hole-mine/articleshow/117034790.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 20:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wife Runs Away With Beggar, Leaves Behind Husband And Six Children In UP - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/wife-runs-away-with-beggar-leaves-behind-husband-and-six-children-in-up-9180472.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/wife-runs-away-with-beggar-leaves-behind-husband-and-six-children-in-up-9180472.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 20:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amit Shah unveils BHARATPOL - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTFA2dERTTHB5SXBPV3RyaXhBazktT2U5RFg5VHBfNzlKVXJOMEZibjdJZ2pSZ3FSamlfQXZqMGE2TUZpOEtldkRCYlc2MGRETFhxbzNUcXBNZnVLOHhBNGdDTzFiSjFXZjBSU2NvWnVJUnpITjcybllHRVp3WUvSAYABQVVfeXFMUDBfSlVrV3docDB1VFhoREdKOWM0MFJKVDlhdy1NWUVfN21DZWEzNTNHakMwV2d3ekhmbVJOM0FockNRMkFzVzREYkROMlBhb29oeEROVVdSZE9FQmtjOXl6eTlSOWhzTnpyQTBpNjVqNVFlMjFFTlFQdU9YSDIxR1Q?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTFA2dERTTHB5SXBPV3RyaXhBazktT2U5RFg5VHBfNzlKVXJOMEZibjdJZ2pSZ3FSamlfQXZqMGE2TUZpOEtldkRCYlc2MGRETFhxbzNUcXBNZnVLOHhBNGdDTzFiSjFXZjBSU2NvWnVJUnpITjcybllHRVp3WUvSAYABQVVfeXFMUDBfSlVrV3docDB1VFhoREdKOWM0MFJKVDlhdy1NWUVfN21DZWEzNTNHakMwV2d3ekhmbVJOM0FockNRMkFzVzREYkROMlBhb29oeEROVVdSZE9FQmtjOXl6eTlSOWhzTnpyQTBpNjVqNVFlMjFFTlFQdU9YSDIxR1Q?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:47:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Account staffer of call centre atacked by colleague - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQRjM3U2xZcjJnUkdFeGsyQ0EtQkZsOGd2dmpPOFJXOTIteEl5VWtKZ08xYzdaNmdyZE9kbUw0SFl0LS1TVVdOczJWRlFFUWVRNDVfTzFJNmZfMUJ1QkFIZzFDRldaeFBLZV9VZWdVM1JGOE1zX1ZYUzBGTFgzWTBFdjZ0VFRtUHd5TTVYajRqQ0p2bk1qaGpFb185WWlfNjBlNzlyMlJnei1TX0MzcUZ0bk9fWnl5a2pfSGw2czN3NjnSAcYBQVVfeXFMT2NzSFkxd2pDSjhxdzJFZTlfS1NScVRMZEhLelp3Y0o3ZlcyWVdmVzNnbk1KRGtHLVd4WG5vbG5LeEx4RTdEYmptR2YybTVNNW04WDktN0lVMFRMeUtaWEZXV1ZCRHh4djRnei04aE9md080QnM3ZzRWRG83NktSNzl1RnZqNVhXQkZTQnl1ZTZlTVNGanlFUUkwY2FYNGpmUHFHUU9aTmo5Z3RtSnRHLUNEcEozRWlGSmF4aEp6cUl3VF9FVXd3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQRjM3U2xZcjJnUkdFeGsyQ0EtQkZsOGd2dmpPOFJXOTIteEl5VWtKZ08xYzdaNmdyZE9kbUw0SFl0LS1TVVdOczJWRlFFUWVRNDVfTzFJNmZfMUJ1QkFIZzFDRldaeFBLZV9VZWdVM1JGOE1zX1ZYUzBGTFgzWTBFdjZ0VFRtUHd5TTVYajRqQ0p2bk1qaGpFb185WWlfNjBlNzlyMlJnei1TX0MzcUZ0bk9fWnl5a2pfSGw2czN3NjnSAcYBQVVfeXFMT2NzSFkxd2pDSjhxdzJFZTlfS1NScVRMZEhLelp3Y0o3ZlcyWVdmVzNnbk1KRGtHLVd4WG5vbG5LeEx4RTdEYmptR2YybTVNNW04WDktN0lVMFRMeUtaWEZXV1ZCRHh4djRnei04aE9md080QnM3ZzRWRG83NktSNzl1RnZqNVhXQkZTQnl1ZTZlTVNGanlFUUkwY2FYNGpmUHFHUU9aTmo5Z3RtSnRHLUNEcEozRWlGSmF4aEp6cUl3VF9FVXd3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[V. Narayanan appointed new Space Secretary and ISRO chief - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dr. V. Narayanan appointed as new Space Secretary and ISRO Chairman</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/1nk0fl/article69073985.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/DSC_1019.JPG" alt="Dr. V. Narayanan, Director, Liquid Propulsion Systems Centre (LPSC), ISRO, Valiamala, during an interview with “The Hindu” in Thiruvananthapuram."/><figcaption>Dr. V. Narayanan, Director, Liquid Propulsion Systems Centre (LPSC), ISRO, Valiamala, during an interview with “The Hindu” in Thiruvananthapuram. Photo Credit: M. PERIASAMY</figcaption><p>Dr. V. Narayanan has been appointed the new Space Secretary and will also become the Chairman of ISRO, succeeding S. Somanath.</p><ul><li>Dr. Narayanan will take over from January 14, 2025, for a period of two years.</li><li>He has been with ISRO since 1984, serving in various capacities.</li><li>He is an expert in rocket and spacecraft propulsion.</li><li>Previously directed the Liquid Propulsion Systems Centre (LPSC).</li><li>Contributed significantly to ISRO's Geosynchronous launch vehicles.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Appointments Committee of the Cabinet has approved appointment of V. Narayanan, Director, Liquid Propulsion Systems Centre, Valiamala as Secretary, Department of Space, and Chairman, Space Commission for a period of two years with effect from 14.01.2025, or until further orders, whichever is earlier.”</blockquote><p>Dr. Narayanan takes over from Mr. Somanath, who oversaw major ISRO missions including Chandrayaan-3.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/v-narayanan-appointed-new-space-secretary-and-isro-chief/article69073962.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/v-narayanan-appointed-new-space-secretary-and-isro-chief/article69073962.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Assembly Elections 2025| We are opening 'Sheesh Mahal'; challenge BJP to open PM's 'Rajmahal', says AAP's Sanjay Singh - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Assembly Elections 2025: AAP's Sanjay Singh Challenges BJP on 'Sheesh Mahal' Claims</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 07 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p>
<p>AAP MP Sanjay Singh invited the media to tour Arvind Kejriwal's former official residence, challenging BJP's claims of it being a 'Sheesh Mahal'.</p>
<ul>
<li>Singh challenged BJP leaders to visit the CM's residence and prove their claims about its lavishness.</li>
<li>He alleged that PM Modi resides in a 'Rajmahal' worth Rs 2,700 crores and urged similar media scrutiny.</li>
<li>Singh accused BJP of running a propaganda campaign related to the allegations of luxury in Kejriwal's residence.</li>
<li>The BJP is making these claims a focal point of its election campaign.</li>
<li>Singh demanded evidence of extravagant features such as a swimming pool and a minibar that BJP claims exist in the residence.</li>
<li>Delhi BJP president claimed valuable items were missing after Kejriwal vacated the bungalow.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Show us where is the swimming pool, the minibar and the golden toilet. The people of Delhi and the country deserve to know the truth." - Sanjay Singh</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing dispute highlights the tension between AAP and BJP in the lead-up to the elections, with both parties aiming to influence public perception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/elections/delhi/delhi-assembly-elections-2025-we-are-opening-sheesh-mahal-challenge-bjp-to-open-pms-rajmahal-says-aaps-sanjay-singh-3345466</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/elections/delhi/delhi-assembly-elections-2025-we-are-opening-sheesh-mahal-challenge-bjp-to-open-pms-rajmahal-says-aaps-sanjay-singh-3345466</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:48:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jammu-Kashmir train aims to tackle sub-zero temp - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jammu-Kashmir Train Aims to Tackle Sub-Zero Temperatures</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/The-Vande-Bharat-Express-being-maintained-at-Shaku_1736275584104_1736283398516.jpg" alt="The Vande Bharat Express being maintained at Shakur Basti in New Delhi on Tuesday. (HT Photo)" title="The Vande Bharat Express being maintained at Shakur Basti in New Delhi on Tuesday. (HT Photo)">
<figcaption>The Vande Bharat Express being maintained at Shakur Basti in New Delhi on Tuesday. (HT Photo)</figcaption>
<p>The first-ever train linking Jammu with Kashmir, the tailor-made Vande Bharat Express, is set to tackle sub-zero temperatures and is ready for inauguration by Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</p>
<ul>
<li>Built to operate in extreme cold with advanced heating systems.</li>
<li>Journey time from Jammu to Srinagar reduced from 8-9 hours to 3 hours and 10 minutes.</li>
<li>Equipped with features to prevent freezing of water tanks and ensure safety.</li>
<li>Part of the Udhampur-Srinagar-Baramulla Rail Link project, enhancing regional rail connectivity.</li>
<li>Utilizes the Chenab Rail Bridge, the world's highest rail bridge.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This train will prevent freezing of water tanks and bio-toilet tanks, with overheat protection sensors for safety and reliability.” - Northern Railways Official</blockquote>
<p>This innovative train service is expected to significantly improve travel times and experiences for passengers in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jammukashmir-train-aims-to-tackle-sub-zero-temp-101736275592917.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/jammukashmir-train-aims-to-tackle-sub-zero-temp-101736275592917.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:46:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[V Narayanan Appointed New ISRO Chief, Will Take Over From S Somanath - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>V Narayanan Appointed New ISRO Chief, Will Take Over From S Somanath</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>New Delhi</p><p>The Centre has appointed V Narayanan as the new chairman of the Indian Space Research Organisation and Secretary, Department of Space. Mr Narayanan will take over from S Somanath, the current head of the organisation, on January 14.</p><ul><li>V Narayanan is currently the head of the Liquid Propulsion Systems Centre (LPSC).</li><li>He played a key role in the development of India's cryogenic engine technology.</li><li>Mr Narayanan aims to take ISRO to greater heights with a clear roadmap for the future.</li><li>He has been with ISRO since 1984 and has held various significant positions.</li><li>S Somanath, the outgoing chief, led ISRO during significant missions including the successful Moon landing.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have a clear roadmap for India and I hope to take ISRO to greater heights as we have great talent,” - V Narayanan</blockquote><p>In conclusion, V Narayanan's appointment marks a new chapter in ISRO's leadership, promising continued advancements in India's space exploration efforts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/v-narayanan-appointed-new-isro-chief-will-replace-s-somanath-7422942</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/v-narayanan-appointed-new-isro-chief-will-replace-s-somanath-7422942</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:41:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India extends ex-B’desh PM Sheikh Hasina’s visa amid extradition call by Dhaka - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Extends Visa for Ex-Bangladesh PM Sheikh Hasina Amid Extradition Calls</h1><p><strong>Date: January 08, 2025</strong><br/><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Bangladesh-s-deposed-Prime-Minister-Sheikh-Hasina-_1736274864057.jpg" alt="Bangladesh's deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina speaks during a press conference in Dhaka, Bangladesh, on January 6, 2014. (AP File)"/><figcaption>Bangladesh's deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina speaks during a press conference in Dhaka, Bangladesh, on January 6, 2014. (AP File)</figcaption><p>India has extended the visa of deposed Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, who fled to India amid protests. This decision comes despite growing calls from Dhaka for her extradition.</p><ul><li>Sheikh Hasina has been in India since August 2024, following her departure amid nationwide protests in Bangladesh.</li><li>The interim government in Dhaka formally requested her extradition on December 23, 2024.</li><li>India’s Home Ministry was involved in extending Hasina's visa through the Foreigners Regional Registration Office.</li><li>Bangladesh has cancelled passports of 97 individuals, including Hasina, related to enforced disappearances and killings during protests.</li><li>An arrest warrant for Hasina has been issued by Bangladesh's International Criminal Tribunal.</li></ul><blockquote>“The passports department cancelled passports of 75 people, including Sheikh Hasina, due to their involvement in the July killings,” - Abul Kalam Azad Majumder</blockquote><p>The situation surrounding Sheikh Hasina highlights the complexities of international relations and the legal ramifications of political asylum. The extension of her visa indicates India's current stance on the matter amidst diplomatic pressures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-extends-ex-b-desh-pm-sheikh-hasina-s-visa-amid-extradition-call-by-dhaka-101736274870894.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-extends-ex-b-desh-pm-sheikh-hasina-s-visa-amid-extradition-call-by-dhaka-101736274870894.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:34:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pune: Woman Dies After Attack by Colleague At WNS in Viman Nagar - Punekar News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQaGVRNEN0aTI1a1lRYWlVWEJHNUhuUGtSS3d0VWdEaHRmU0pjOS1icXR1bkdPZ2M0eExlbE9ZS1lZMmJiX0RMX2s5LURVRmZOTG13cUR0Zk9xZkQ3ZDlrZUx5XzVSd3hOdnppSFNVSnNsMU9yaFM4ZVVUUUkwOFRFODBGYThBQU1IQWREclBmcDJvQ2x2Znc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQaGVRNEN0aTI1a1lRYWlVWEJHNUhuUGtSS3d0VWdEaHRmU0pjOS1icXR1bkdPZ2M0eExlbE9ZS1lZMmJiX0RMX2s5LURVRmZOTG13cUR0Zk9xZkQ3ZDlrZUx5XzVSd3hOdnppSFNVSnNsMU9yaFM4ZVVUUUkwOFRFODBGYThBQU1IQWREclBmcDJvQ2x2Znc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:15:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>