<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 22:16:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 22:16:23 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Budget 2025: Revised Income Tax Slabs, Higher Standard Deduction, Section 80C Limit Increase – Know Key Exp - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Budget 2025: Key Expected Changes in Income Tax</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Budget 2025: In the upcoming budget, the government is likely to provide income tax relief."><figcaption>Budget 2025: In the upcoming budget, the government is likely to provide income tax relief.</figcaption></figure><p>This article outlines five major changes anticipated in the upcoming Budget 2025 concerning income tax reforms that could affect salaried individuals.</p><ul><li><strong>Increase in Standard Deduction:</strong> The standard deduction may be raised to a maximum of ₹1 lakh to support higher earners amid rising costs.</li><li><strong>Revised Income Tax Slabs:</strong> Expected updates to the tax slabs may include a 30% tax rate for incomes above ₹20 lakh.</li><li><strong>Tax Reforms for Senior Citizens:</strong> Consideration for raising the exemption limit and reducing tax rates for senior citizens.</li><li><strong>Increase in Section 80C Deduction Limit:</strong> Suggested increase to ₹3.5 lakh to address financial pressures on taxpayers.</li><li><strong>Possible Import Duty Hike on Gold:</strong> An anticipated increase in import tax on gold to curb imports and address trade imbalances.</li></ul><blockquote>Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman will present the Union Budget 2025-26 on February 1.</blockquote><p>The upcoming budget is expected to bring crucial reforms that could significantly impact taxpayers and the economy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/tax/budget-2025-revised-income-tax-slabs-higher-standard-deduction-section-80c-limit-increase-know-key-expectations-9186868.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/tax/budget-2025-revised-income-tax-slabs-higher-standard-deduction-section-80c-limit-increase-know-key-expectations-9186868.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:44:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real India is at Maha Kumbh, say visitors from abroad - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Real India is at Maha Kumbh, say visitors from abroad</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>This article showcases the experiences and impressions of foreign visitors attending the Maha Kumbh Mela, highlighting their perspective on Indian culture, spirituality, and the significance of the event.</p><ul><li>Foreign visitors share their insights about the cultural richness of India.</li><li>The Maha Kumbh Mela is depicted as a pivotal spiritual gathering.</li><li>Participants express awe at the scale and organization of the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is the real India that we came to witness.”</blockquote><p>The Maha Kumbh Mela not only showcases India's rich spiritual heritage but also attracts global attention, reinforcing the cultural dialogue between nations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/real-india-is-at-maha-kumbh-say-visitors-from-abroad/articleshow/117214633.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/real-india-is-at-maha-kumbh-say-visitors-from-abroad/articleshow/117214633.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘End Unequal Understanding On Border Issues’: India To Bangladesh Envoy - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Urges Bangladesh to Resolve Border Understanding Discrepancies</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Border Security Force (BSF) soldiers patrol along the fencing of the India-Bangladesh international border on the outskirts of Agartala, capital of Tripura, India. (IMAGE: REUTERS)" /><figcaption>Border Security Force (BSF) soldiers patrol along the fencing of the India-Bangladesh international border on the outskirts of Agartala, capital of Tripura, India. (IMAGE: REUTERS)</figcaption><p>India has called for clarity and cooperation regarding border security measures during a meeting with a Bangladeshi envoy. This follows a recent tension over fencing and security agreements along the border.</p><ul><li>India summoned Bangladesh's deputy high commissioner due to ongoing border tensions.</li><li>Both countries are discussing border security protocols and the issue of illegal crossings.</li><li>Bangladesh expressed concerns over India's fencing activities which they argue violate bilateral agreements.</li><li>India is committed to preventing cross-border crimes through enhanced security measures, including fencing.</li><li>Officials from both sides have previously accused each other of unauthorized actions along the border.</li></ul><blockquote>“India observed all protocols while putting fencing,” source stated.</blockquote><p>Both nations need to collaborate effectively to address border security challenges while ensuring peace and cooperation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/india-summons-bangladesh-deputy-high-commissioner-over-border-fencing-row-9187159.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/india-summons-bangladesh-deputy-high-commissioner-over-border-fencing-row-9187159.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:37:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['You kept your word': J&K CM Omar Abdullah thanks PM Modi for timely elections - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘You kept your word’: J&K CM Omar Abdullah thanks PM Modi for timely elections</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>Omar Abdullah, the Chief Minister of Jammu and Kashmir, publicly thanked Prime Minister Narendra Modi for holding elections in the region as promised. This gesture is seen as vital for restoring democratic processes in J&K.</p><ul><li>Abdullah expressed gratitude during a public address, highlighting the importance of timely elections.</li><li>He stressed the need for renewed political engagement in the region.</li><li>The elections are aimed at reinforcing local governance and community involvement.</li></ul><blockquote>“Your commitment to democracy has been reaffirmed with these timely elections.” - Omar Abdullah</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Abdullah's appreciation reflects a significant step towards empowering local governance in Jammu and Kashmir and restoring faith in the political process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/you-kept-your-words-jk-cm-omar-abdullah-thanks-pm-modi-for-timely-elections-z-morh-tunnel-inauguration/articleshow/117198404.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/you-kept-your-words-jk-cm-omar-abdullah-thanks-pm-modi-for-timely-elections-z-morh-tunnel-inauguration/articleshow/117198404.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi-Omar Abdullah bonhomie to an absent NC MP: 5 takeaways from Z-Morh tunnel inauguration in Sonamarg - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Key Highlights from the Inauguration of the Sonamarg Tunnel</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Monday<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/modi-tunnel.jpg" alt="Modi Z-Morh Tunnel" width="1600" height="900">
<figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the inauguration of the Z-Morh tunnel in J&amp;K. (PTI)</figcaption>
<p>The recent inauguration of the Sonamarg tunnel marked a moment of unity between Prime Minister Modi and Chief Minister Omar Abdullah, showcasing infrastructure developments and political dynamics in Jammu and Kashmir.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Modi and Abdullah displayed camaraderie during the tunnel's inauguration.</li>
  <li>Abdullah emphasized growing trust in Modi's promises among the people of Jammu and Kashmir.</li>
  <li>Modi praised Abdullah's initiatives, including participation in community events like marathons.</li>
  <li>Union Minister Gadkari highlighted the infrastructural push affecting connectivity and security.</li>
  <li>The absence of Srinagar MP Aga Ruhullah Mehdi raised questions about internal party dynamics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Everything has a time; the right things will happen at the right time.” - PM Modi</blockquote>
<p>The inauguration highlights the ongoing dialogue and relationship between local leadership and the central government, reflecting a pivotal moment in the region's political landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/pm-modi-omar-abdullah-bonhomie-z-morh-tunnel-9777044/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/pm-modi-omar-abdullah-bonhomie-z-morh-tunnel-9777044/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll Officer Responds To AAP's Voter List Manipulation Charge In Delhi - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxQX0ZqQlJnMUx6b3I3QzFpNzRJclJQSF9xMDZoeTUyZUJXR2ZDaHlpWGVwZG0wZ1hMUmduNTBuOWpuMnZGQXN0ZzcwX0pzTlZVVDN2Z3JtX1ZNZ3ZRdWlaN0RxY0dPNGVNVkNYeWZZaEpZdmQzTmd5SExxUmFCa05tTzVYZWN2ZExlczRZOHhXazRnQ1NMS2tIVndpQ0JQVDZzSHJmZnNRX0dnN2NRTWR2aUFYbVJsaS15LXJhdWJGcGl2VzVzemxsQllsVnFlX09vZ0NHSGtsRTk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxQX0ZqQlJnMUx6b3I3QzFpNzRJclJQSF9xMDZoeTUyZUJXR2ZDaHlpWGVwZG0wZ1hMUmduNTBuOWpuMnZGQXN0ZzcwX0pzTlZVVDN2Z3JtX1ZNZ3ZRdWlaN0RxY0dPNGVNVkNYeWZZaEpZdmQzTmd5SExxUmFCa05tTzVYZWN2ZExlczRZOHhXazRnQ1NMS2tIVndpQ0JQVDZzSHJmZnNRX0dnN2NRTWR2aUFYbVJsaS15LXJhdWJGcGl2VzVzemxsQllsVnFlX09vZ0NHSGtsRTk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:21:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Party bigger than govt: Congress tells Karnataka leaders amid camp war - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Leaders Warned Against Indiscipline Amid Political Tensions in Karnataka</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 13 January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In a recent meeting, Congress leaders were cautioned by the party's general secretary regarding indiscipline, as political tensions rise between Karnataka’s Chief Minister Siddaramaiah and his deputy DK Shivakumar.</p><ul><li>The Congress high command warned its Karnataka leaders against disruptive behaviors and emphasized that the party is more important than the government.</li><li>General secretary Randeep Singh Surjewala addressed a general body meeting, stating that indiscipline would not be tolerated.</li><li>Surjewala indicated that caste-based conventions would only be allowed if formally organized under the party.</li><li>Senior ministers G Parameshwara and KN Rajanna did not attend the meeting, indicating their protest against Surjewala's remarks.</li><li>Surjewala criticized the BJP for attempting to undermine Congress's initiatives.</li><li>Plans for expanding Congress's presence in Karnataka include the opening of 100 Gandhi Bharat offices.</li></ul><blockquote>“The party is the mother and the government its child. Some of our leaders aren’t disciplined. None should bulldoze the party.” - Randeep Singh Surjewala</blockquote><p>This meeting underscores the ongoing internal struggles within the Congress party in Karnataka and the critical balance of power as the party navigates its leadership dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/party-bigger-than-govt-congress-tells-karnataka-leaders-amid-camp-war-3353603</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/party-bigger-than-govt-congress-tells-karnataka-leaders-amid-camp-war-3353603</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:14:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal vs Rahul Gandhi in Delhi: 'Fighting to save Congress' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arvind Kejriwal vs Rahul Gandhi in Delhi: 'Fighting to save Congress'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/PTI01-12-2025-000116B-0_1736784835325_1736784845328.jpg" alt="Former Delhi CM and AAP national convener Arvind Kejriwal(PTI file photo)" title="Former Delhi CM and AAP national convener Arvind Kejriwal(PTI file photo)">
<figcaption>Former Delhi CM and AAP national convener Arvind Kejriwal(PTI file photo)</figcaption>
<p>Aam Aadmi Party chief Arvind Kejriwal recently responded to Rahul Gandhi's comments, asserting that Gandhi's focus is on preserving the Congress party rather than addressing national issues.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kejriwal claimed that Gandhi's fight is about saving Congress, while his own fight is for the country.</li>
  <li>Rahul Gandhi criticized Kejriwal, stating that he campaigns similarly to Prime Minister Modi, making false promises.</li>
  <li>Gandhi accused Kejriwal of failing to eliminate corruption in Delhi, despite his promises.</li>
  <li>He highlighted issues such as inflation and the lack of support for backward communities and minorities, linking this to both Modi and Kejriwal.</li>
  <li>The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled for February 5, with results on February 8.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Inflation is at its peak. Poor people are becoming poorer and rich people are becoming richer.” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing political rivalry highlights significant concerns regarding governance, promises made by political leaders, and the upcoming elections in Delhi.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/arvind-kejriwal-vs-rahul-gandhi-in-delhi-fight-to-save-congress-101736784138554.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/arvind-kejriwal-vs-rahul-gandhi-in-delhi-fight-to-save-congress-101736784138554.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:14:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘PM Modi, Kejriwal failed to reduce inflation': Rahul Gandhi at Delhi rally - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘PM Modi, Kejriwal failed to reduce inflation': Rahul Gandhi at Delhi rally</h1><p><strong>Date: January 13, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/Rahul_Gandhi__1736780042946_1736780043179.jpeg" alt="Leader of the Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi addresses the “Jai Bapu, Jai Bhim, Jai Samvidhan’ public meeting at Zero Pushta, in Seelampur area ahead of the Delhi Assembly elections. (Raj K Raj/HT Photo)" title="Leader of the Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi addresses the “Jai Bapu, Jai Bhim, Jai Samvidhan’ public meeting at Zero Pushta, in Seelampur area ahead of the Delhi Assembly elections. (Raj K Raj/HT Photo)"><figcaption>Leader of the Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi addresses the “Jai Bapu, Jai Bhim, Jai Samvidhan’ public meeting at Zero Pushta, in Seelampur area ahead of the Delhi Assembly elections. (Raj K Raj/HT Photo)</figcaption><p>Rahul Gandhi, Leader of the Opposition in the Lok Sabha, accused PM Narendra Modi and AAP leader Arvind Kejriwal of failing to address rising inflation during a rally in Delhi.</p><ul><li>Gandhi stated that inflation is at its peak, adversely affecting the poor.</li><li>He criticized Modi's relationship with industrialists Ambani and Adani, calling for a more equitable society.</li><li>Gandhi emphasized the need to protect the Constitution from perceived threats posed by the BJP and RSS.</li><li>Both the Congress and AAP are contesting upcoming Delhi elections separately.</li><li>The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled for February 5, with counting on February 8.</li></ul><blockquote>“Inflation is at its peak. Poor people are becoming poorer and rich people are becoming richer.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Gandhi’s remarks highlight significant discontent with current leadership's economic policies as both parties prepare for a competitive electoral battle.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-kejriwal-failed-to-reduce-inflation-rahul-gandhi-at-delhi-rally-101736779978313.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-kejriwal-failed-to-reduce-inflation-rahul-gandhi-at-delhi-rally-101736779978313.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi polls: Kejriwal claims shoes, jackets, spectacles distributed in Kidwai Nagar, moves EC - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Claims Shoes, Jackets, Spectacles Distributed in Kidwai Nagar, Moves EC</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/PTI01-13-2025-000403A-0_1736780989386_1736781021632.jpg" alt="AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal, Punjab CM Bhagwat Mann, AAP MP Sanjay Singh and leader Awadh Ojha leave the Election Commission office.(PTI)" /><figcaption>AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal, Punjab CM Bhagwant Mann, AAP MP Sanjay Singh and leader Awadh Ojha leave the Election Commission office.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Arvind Kejriwal, chief of the Aam Aadmi Party, has made serious allegations about the distribution of goods intended to influence voters in Delhi's Kidwai Nagar. He reported these claims to the Election Commission (EC) and called for the suspension of local authorities involved.</p><ul><li>Kejriwal accused some politicians of distributing items including blankets, shoes, jackets, and spectacles to sway voters.</li><li>He demanded action against the local district magistrate for allegedly turning a blind eye to the activities.</li><li>The Election Commission has assured Kejriwal that such distributions will be stopped.</li><li>Concerns were raised regarding rival candidate Parvesh Verma's alleged distribution of money to voters.</li><li>Delhi Assembly polls are set for February 5, with vote counting on February 8.</li></ul><blockquote>“Yesterday, blankets were distributed in Kidwai Nagar, shoes, jackets were distributed, money was distributed, spectacles were distributed. ... We requested that the DM should be suspended and this kind of activity should be stopped,” - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the ongoing concerns about election integrity as the Delhi Assembly polls approach.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-polls-kejriwal-claims-shoes-jackets-spectacles-distributed-in-kidwai-nagar-moves-ec-101736780799424.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-polls-kejriwal-claims-shoes-jackets-spectacles-distributed-in-kidwai-nagar-moves-ec-101736780799424.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:14:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pune Ranks 4th Globally for Average Travel Time, Traffic Congestion Remains a Major Concern - Punekar News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxNNzB5bmF0MHNEZ05TeTFpMTM4T182cnJtc1ZmS1pFY3hQeDZvTXlQZmxOYXRqMWQ3djRFMjU2ZFNVRHdXLWVhcWpxdFVDdUU1VFpqZllBcmxURVJQZ3JxYUlOVko0WG0zOXBmcnF6ajhIZm9pRlBZaHBULU5WOFBzd013dTk1clZZSmhlX19TdkY2MDFHa3plMkZRd0VmZ21INzB4V3lJN25BLWdyblFITExCa09lVWtxb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxNNzB5bmF0MHNEZ05TeTFpMTM4T182cnJtc1ZmS1pFY3hQeDZvTXlQZmxOYXRqMWQ3djRFMjU2ZFNVRHdXLWVhcWpxdFVDdUU1VFpqZllBcmxURVJQZ3JxYUlOVko0WG0zOXBmcnF6ajhIZm9pRlBZaHBULU5WOFBzd013dTk1clZZSmhlX19TdkY2MDFHa3plMkZRd0VmZ21INzB4V3lJN25BLWdyblFITExCa09lVWtxb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swami Vivekananda’s visit to Belagavi recalled - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Swami Vivekananda’s Visit to Belagavi Recalled</h1><p><strong>Published: January 13, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/az655e/article69093235.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/9727_12_1_2025_21_13_44_1_13BGMVIVEKNADIGE1.JPEG" alt="BJP members taking out Vivek Nadige Marathon to mark Swami Vivekananda Jayanti in Belagavi on Sunday." /><figcaption>BJP members taking out Vivek Nadige Marathon to mark Swami Vivekananda Jayanti in Belagavi on Sunday. | Photo Credit: P.K. Badiger</figcaption><p>Rich tributes were paid to Swami Vivekananda by various organisations, students unions, and academic institutions on his 163rd birth anniversary.</p><ul><li>Events were held in Dharwad, attended by students from schools, colleges, and Karnatak University.</li><li>At JSS college, JSS secretary Ajit Prasad highlighted Swami Vivekananda's teachings on willpower and self-conquest.</li><li>The importance of determination, concentration, and patience in achieving goals was emphasized.</li><li>In Belagavi, local MLA Balachandra Jarkiholi urged youth to draw inspiration from Vivekananda.</li><li>A Viveka Nadige Marathon was organized, starting from the Ramakrishna Mission Ashram.</li><li>BJP district president Subhash Patil spoke on Vivekananda's contributions and his historical visit to Belagavi in 1892.</li></ul><blockquote>“Swami Vivekananda dedicated his life for the upliftment of society. It should inspire us all.” - Subhash Patil</blockquote><p>The celebrations of Vivekananda’s legacy continue to inspire people, especially the youth, in their pursuits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/swami-vivekanandas-visit-to-belagavi-recalled/article69093019.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/karnataka/swami-vivekanandas-visit-to-belagavi-recalled/article69093019.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh Mela 2025 Live Updates: 1.5 crore people bathe at Sangam on 1st day, Yogi Adityanath congratulates seers, devotees - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh Mela 2025 Live Updates: 1.5 Crore People Bathe at Sangam on 1st Day</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source: </strong>The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Mahakumbh-1.jpg?w=640" alt="Mahakumbh 2025 Day 1:" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Devotees taking holy dip at the bank of Triveni Sangam during Maha Kumbh in Prayagraj.</figcaption><p>At the onset of the Maha Kumbh festival, approximately 1.5 crore devotees gathered to take a holy dip at Sangam on the auspicious occasion of Paush Purnima. Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath commended various organizations for their efforts in making the first day successful.</p><ul><li>The Kumbh fair runs until February 26, with 50 lakh participants planning to stay for the entire duration.</li><li>549 projects have been initiated for the event with a budget of Rs 6,990 crore.</li><li>Installation of 2,300 CCTV cameras for crowd management and safety purposes.</li></ul><blockquote>“I thank the Mela and Prayagraj administrations, state police, and local civic bodies for their support.” – Yogi Adityanath</blockquote><p>The Mahakumbh Mela is a significant cultural and spiritual gathering, marked by its ancient ties to Hindu mythology and history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-uttar-pradesh-yogi-adityanath-9774779/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-uttar-pradesh-yogi-adityanath-9774779/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:21:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Centre Notifies Appointment Of Justice K Vinod Chandran As Supreme Court Judge - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justice K Vinod Chandran Appointed as Supreme Court Judge</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recently notified by the Central Government</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Union Law Minister Arjun Ram Meghwal on 'X'</p><p>Justice K Vinod Chandran, previously the Chief Justice of the Patna High Court, has been appointed as a Judge of the Supreme Court of India following the recommendation of the Supreme Court Collegium.</p><ul><li>The appointment was made after considering the lack of representation from the High Court of Kerala in the Supreme Court.</li><li>Justice Chandran has a lengthy judicial career, having been appointed as a Judge of the High Court of Kerala on November 8, 2011, and elevated to Chief Justice of Patna High Court on March 29, 2023.</li><li>The Supreme Court Collegium acknowledged his extensive experience in various legal fields.</li></ul><blockquote>"In exercise of the powers conferred by the Constitution of India, the President, after consultation with Chief Justice of India, is pleased to appoint Shri Justice Krishnan Vinod Chandran, Chief Justice, Patna High Court as a Judge of the Supreme Court of India."</blockquote><p>Justice K Vinod Chandran's elevation helps restore representation from Kerala in the country’s apex court.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/centre-notifies-appointment-of-justice-k-vinod-chandran-as-supreme-court-judge-280825</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/centre-notifies-appointment-of-justice-k-vinod-chandran-as-supreme-court-judge-280825</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:17:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BREAKING| Centre Notifies Appointment Of Justice K Vinod Chandran As Supreme Court Judge - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justice K Vinod Chandran Appointed as Supreme Court Judge</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>The Central Government has officially appointed Justice K Vinod Chandran, the Chief Justice of the Patna High Court, as a Judge of the Supreme Court, following recommendations from the Supreme Court Collegium.</p><ul><li>Justice Chandran's appointment fills the vacancy left by Justice CT Ravikumar's retirement.</li><li>The Collegium highlighted the lack of representation from the High Court of Kerala in the Supreme Court.</li><li>Justice Chandran was previously a Judge of the Kerala High Court and became Chief Justice of the Patna High Court in March 2023.</li><li>His extensive experience in diverse legal fields was noted by the Chief Justice of India, Sanjiv Khanna.</li></ul><blockquote>“In exercise of the powers conferred by the Constitution of India, the President, after consultation with Chief Justice of India, is pleased to appoint Shri Justice Krishnan Vinod Chandran, Chief Justice, Patna High Court as a Judge of the Supreme Court of India.” - Union Law Minister Arjun Ram Meghwal</blockquote><p>This appointment signifies a step towards better representation in the Supreme Court and acknowledges Justice Chandran's proven track record in the judiciary.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/centre-notifies-appointment-of-justice-k-vinod-chandran-as-supreme-court-judge-280825</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/centre-notifies-appointment-of-justice-k-vinod-chandran-as-supreme-court-judge-280825</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:17:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025 live: Holy dip performed by 1.5 cr devotees on first day, says UP CM - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh 2025 Live: 1.5 Crore Devotees Take Holy Dip on Day One</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/prayagraj_maha_kumbh_1736743787205_1736772264252.jfif" alt="Mahakumbh 2025: Devotees at Mahakumbh on Day 1" />
<figcaption>Mahakumbh 2025 live: Devotees at Mahakumbh on Day 1. (Prayagraj District Administration via ANI)</figcaption>
</div>
<p>The Mahakumbh Mela 2025 has commenced in Prayagraj, attracting an estimated 1.5 crore (15 million) devotees on the first day. This 45-day event is expected to witness a total of over 40 crore attendees, celebrated for its spiritual richness and cultural heritage.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The event kicked off on Paush Purnima, which features significant bathing rituals.</li>
  <li>UP CM Yogi Adityanath greeted attendees, calling it a unique opportunity to experience cultural and spiritual heritage.</li>
  <li>Over 40,000 security personnel are deployed to ensure the safety of pilgrims.</li>
  <li>Various safety arrangements were established, including traffic management and health facilities.</li>
  <li>Upcoming major bathing dates include January 14 (Makar Sankranti) and January 29 (Mauni Amavasya).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Today, Mahakumbh has begun. I congratulate all devotees, pilgrims, and the saints. Everyone should take part in the holy 'snan' during the Mahakumbh and get rid of all sins,” - Uttarakhand CM Pushkar Singh Dhami.</blockquote>
<p>The event continues to draw worldwide attention, marking a significant cultural gathering with profound spiritual implications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-sangam-shahi-snan-paush-purnima-holy-dip-jan-13-2025-101736725472437.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/maha-kumbh-mela-2025-live-updates-prayagraj-up-cm-yogi-adityanath-sangam-shahi-snan-paush-purnima-holy-dip-jan-13-2025-101736725472437.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:44:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Properties in Srinagar, Jammu, Delhi, And Assets Worth Crores”: ACB Books Retired SE - Daily Excelsior]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxPdHJsV1M2cVNmNE1lTEo5N0MyOVlmOWhRcnduSWcwMHZkeFRHYTNER1pfaGJpemhaUm91VTFsNHpvdlRYM3VMb3BrRmlCNXZjaGVmbWtIR2k5NkJpbFYzd0pCMlJjUmIyWkJyckJHTWlpUk03YjV3OFJpWF9pSl94VG50TlQ2M1FXVzVqY1BiX1h5OGY2WUVZMlBzQUdjaHUwdnNteC1sbnpzMUhkYjZXQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxPdHJsV1M2cVNmNE1lTEo5N0MyOVlmOWhRcnduSWcwMHZkeFRHYTNER1pfaGJpemhaUm91VTFsNHpvdlRYM3VMb3BrRmlCNXZjaGVmbWtIR2k5NkJpbFYzd0pCMlJjUmIyWkJyckJHTWlpUk03YjV3OFJpWF9pSl94VG50TlQ2M1FXVzVqY1BiX1h5OGY2WUVZMlBzQUdjaHUwdnNteC1sbnpzMUhkYjZXQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:39:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vaishnaw trashes Zuckerberg’s claim on India election result - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vaishnaw counters Zuckerberg’s claim on India election result</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p><p>Union minister Ashwini Vaishnaw responded to Mark Zuckerberg's assertion regarding the outcome of the 2024 election in India, stating that it was factually incorrect.</p><p>In a post on X, Vaishnaw emphasized that India had a massive voter turnout of over 640 million in the recent elections.</p><ul><li>Vaishnaw highlighted that the Indian populace reaffirmed their support for the NDA led by PM Narendra Modi.</li><li>Zuckerberg's claims, made in a podcast, suggested most governments lost their elections post-COVID.</li><li>Vaishnaw attributed PM Modi's victory to effective governance and the trust of the public.</li><li>He called Zuckerberg's misinformation disappointing, urging for facts and credibility to be upheld.</li></ul><blockquote>“From free food for 800 million, 2.2 billion free vaccines, and aid to nations worldwide during COVID, to leading India as the fastest-growing major economy, PM Modi's decisive 3rd-term victory is a testament to good governance and public trust.”</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the ongoing dialogue surrounding misinformation and the political narratives in a post-pandemic world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/india/vaishnaw-counters-zuckerbergs-claim-on-india-election-result/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/india/vaishnaw-counters-zuckerbergs-claim-on-india-election-result/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:18:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[J&K ACB registers Disproportionate Assets case against retired Superintending Engineer - Cross Town News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>J&K ACB registers Disproportionate Assets case against retired Superintending Engineer</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Jammu and Kashmir Anti Corruption Bureau</p><img src="/Banner-Pics/IMG_1918.jpeg" alt="J&K ACB registers Disproportionate Assets case against retired Superintending Engineer"><figcaption>Jammu and Kashmir Anti Corruption Bureau investigates assets.</figcaption><p>The Jammu and Kashmir Anti Corruption Bureau has launched an investigation into retired Superintending Engineer Riyaz Ahmad Parray for allegedly amassing assets beyond his known income through corrupt practices.</p><ul><li>The Anti Corruption Bureau verified allegations against Parray, revealing disproportionate assets.</li><li>Properties acquired include multiple flats, houses, and land in Jammu, Delhi, and Baramulla.</li><li>An FIR No. 01/2025 under the Prevention of Corruption Act has been registered against him.</li><li>Searches were conducted at various locations, yielding incriminating documents.</li></ul><blockquote>“The expenditures incurred and the value of assets acquired by the accused during service period have been found prima facie disproportionate to his known sources of income.”</blockquote><p>Further investigations are ongoing as the Anti Corruption Bureau continues to explore the extent of the alleged corruption.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crosstownnews.in/post/137770/jk-acb-registers-disproportionate-assets-case-against-retired-superintending-engineer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crosstownnews.in/post/137770/jk-acb-registers-disproportionate-assets-case-against-retired-superintending-engineer.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:03:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tens of thousands take holy dip in India as Maha Kumbh festival begins - Reuters India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/india/tens-thousands-take-holy-dip-india-maha-kumbh-festival-begins-2025-01-13/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/india/tens-thousands-take-holy-dip-india-maha-kumbh-festival-begins-2025-01-13/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:02:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blow to NCP(SP), Sena (UBT) bids to warm up to Mahayuti as Amit Shah targets Sharad Pawar, Uddhav Thackeray - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amit Shah Criticizes Uddhav Thackeray and Sharad Pawar at BJP Meeting</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>In a significant statement during a BJP state executive meeting, Union Home Minister Amit Shah condemned Uddhav Thackeray’s Shiv Sena (UBT) and Sharad Pawar’s NCP (SP), reinforcing the legitimacy of rival factions within Maharashtra’s political landscape.</p><ul><li>Shah highlighted the BJP's resolve to oust Uddhav Thackeray's party from the Brihanmumbai Municipal Corporation (BMC).</li><li>The BJP is focusing on upcoming local body elections, emphasizing the need for continued dedication.</li><li>Shah's criticism pointed towards the NCP’s historical actions and Thackeray’s alliance with Congress as betrayals of Hindutva principles.</li><li>Political shifts in Maharashtra are apparent, with realignments reverberating through regional parties.</li></ul><blockquote>“The resounding mandate in the BJP’s favour has put an end to the politics of betrayal.” - Amit Shah</blockquote><p>This meeting underscores the BJP’s firm stance against former allies, signaling a potential shift in Maharashtra’s political alliances ahead of upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/amit-shah-targets-sharad-pawar-uddhav-thackeray-9776804/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/amit-shah-targets-sharad-pawar-uddhav-thackeray-9776804/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:00:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ashwini Vaishnaw fact-checks Mark Zuckerberg over India polls remark: 'Misinformation' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashwini Vaishnaw fact-checks Mark Zuckerberg over India polls remark: 'Misinformation'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/Union-Minister-Ashwini-Vaishnaw---PTI-_1736772952241_1736772971994.jpg" alt="Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw. (PTI)"><figcaption>Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw. (PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>Union minister Ashwini Vaishnaw criticized Mark Zuckerberg's remark that India's ruling party lost major elections, stressing the importance of factual accuracy during discussions.</p><ul><li>Vaishnaw refuted Zuckerberg's claim about India's elections, highlighting the victory of the BJP in the 2024 general elections.</li><li>Zuckerberg suggested a global trend of incumbent losses due to various factors, including economic policies and pandemic responses.</li><li>Vaishnaw stated that over 640 million voters reaffirmed their trust in PM Narendra Modi's leadership.</li><li>He called for maintaining facts and credibility in discussions, especially from influential figures like Zuckerberg.</li></ul><blockquote>"Let’s uphold facts and credibility," Vaishnaw stressed.</blockquote><p>The exchange emphasizes the impact of misinformation in the digital age, particularly from high-profile individuals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ashwini-vaishnaw-fact-checks-mark-zuckerberg-over-india-polls-remark-misinformation-101736772820372.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ashwini-vaishnaw-fact-checks-mark-zuckerberg-over-india-polls-remark-misinformation-101736772820372.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:57:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Union Budget 2025: Anirudh Garg of Invasset PMS highlights 6 measures that may boost Indian stock market sentiment | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Union Budget 2025: Key Measures to Boost Indian Stock Market Sentiment</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> February 1, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>The Indian stock market is under pressure due to various concerns including foreign capital outflows and a weakening macroeconomic outlook. As the Union Budget 2025 approaches, expectations are high for measures that will stimulate economic growth and support the stock market.</p><ul><li>Tax reforms to increase disposable income and business profitability.</li><li>Increased capital expenditure on infrastructure and green energy to boost economic demand.</li><li>Sectoral incentives to enhance manufacturing and promote start-ups.</li><li>Privatisation and disinvestment strategies to optimize resource allocation.</li><li>Maintaining fiscal responsibility to ensure debt sustainability.</li><li>Improvements in the ease of doing business to attract investment.</li></ul><blockquote>Anirudh Garg emphasized: "Measures such as broadening the tax base, reducing compliance burdens, and addressing litigation through dispute resolution schemes signal investor-friendly governance."</blockquote><p>This Union Budget could play a vital role in lifting market sentiment and ensuring sustainable growth across sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/union-budget-2025-anirudh-garg-of-invasset-pms-highlights-6-measures-that-may-boost-indian-stock-market-sentiment-11736771216794.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/union-budget-2025-anirudh-garg-of-invasset-pms-highlights-6-measures-that-may-boost-indian-stock-market-sentiment-11736771216794.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:39:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On India-China border situation, Army chief rules out ‘buffer zones’ along LAC - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Army Chief Discusses India-China Border Stability and Disengagement</h1><p><strong>Date: January 13, 2025</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/Depsang_and_Demchok_1729852593379_1736771364261.jpg" alt="Both the Indian and Chinese armies pulled back their forward-deployed troops and equipment from the two flashpoints along the contested LAC." title="Both the Indian and Chinese armies pulled back their forward-deployed troops and equipment from the two flashpoints along the contested LAC."><figcaption>Both the Indian and Chinese armies pulled back their forward-deployed troops and equipment from the two flashpoints along the contested LAC.</figcaption><p>Army Chief General Upendra Dwivedi stated that the border situation with China is stable but sensitive, denying the existence of buffer zones along the Line of Actual Control (LAC).</p><ul><li>Both Indian and Chinese armies completed disengagement at Depsang and Demchok in eastern Ladakh last October.</li><li>General Dwivedi emphasized the need for a broader understanding to rebuild trust.</li><li>Verification patrolling has been successfully conducted by both sides.</li></ul><blockquote>"It is stable but sensitive... overall, both sides will remain back and will not go to the common areas because we still feel that if we meet at those places, the violence level may go high." - General Upendra Dwivedi</blockquote><p>This ongoing dialogue and military disengagement are crucial for maintaining peace along the contentious border.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/on-india-china-border-situation-army-chief-rules-out-buffer-zones-along-lac-101736770328328.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/on-india-china-border-situation-army-chief-rules-out-buffer-zones-along-lac-101736770328328.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:36:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['PM Modi’s decisive 3rd term victory': Union minister Ashwini Vaishnaw fact-checks Mark Zuckerberg on 202 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi’s Decisive 3rd Term Victory: Fact-Check by Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw on Zuckerberg's Claims</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>An analysis of Mark Zuckerberg's statements regarding the upcoming 2024 Lok Sabha elections in India, clarified by Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw, highlighting the significance of PM Modi's electoral success.</p><ul><li>Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw responded to claims made by Mark Zuckerberg about PM Modi’s electoral prospects.</li><li>The article discusses the implications of Modi’s expected third term victory on Indian politics.</li><li>Vaishnaw emphasizes the unwavering support for Modi from the electorate.</li></ul><blockquote>“The people of India have shown their trust in PM Modi’s leadership.”</blockquote><p>This analysis reaffirms the strong political climate ahead of the 2024 elections, with notable confidence in PM Modi’s continued leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pm-modis-decisive-3rd-term-victory-union-minister-ashwini-vaishnaw-fact-checks-mark-zuckerberg-on-india-elections/articleshow/117206369.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pm-modis-decisive-3rd-term-victory-union-minister-ashwini-vaishnaw-fact-checks-mark-zuckerberg-on-india-elections/articleshow/117206369.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['PM Modi’s decisive 3rd term victory': Union minister Ashwini Vaishnaw fact checks Mark Zuckerberg on 202 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi’s decisive 3rd term victory</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Image related to the article"/><figcaption>Image caption can go here.</figcaption><p>Union Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw fact-checked the statements made by Mark Zuckerberg regarding the upcoming 2024 Lok Sabha elections, pointing out inaccuracies and emphasizing the electoral strength of PM Modi.</p><ul><li>Mark Zuckerberg commented on the political landscape post-election victory.</li><li>Vaishnaw highlighted the misconceptions regarding Modi's electoral influence.</li><li>The article discusses implications for political campaigns and social media influence on voters.</li></ul><blockquote>“Zuckerberg's comments do not reflect the ground reality of Indian politics,” said Vaishnaw.</blockquote><p>This article underscores the importance of accurate information in the political arena, particularly in the context of social media influence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pm-modis-decisive-3rd-term-victory-union-minister-ashwini-vaishnaw-fact-checks-mark-zuckerberg-on-india-elections/articleshow/117206369.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/pm-modis-decisive-3rd-term-victory-union-minister-ashwini-vaishnaw-fact-checks-mark-zuckerberg-on-india-elections/articleshow/117206369.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Disappointing to see misinformation from Mark Zuckerberg': Ashwini Vaishnaw hits back - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Disappointing to see misinformation from Mark Zuckerberg': Ashwini Vaishnaw hits back</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/10/20241024092150_Ashwini-Vaishnaw.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431' alt='Ashwini Vaishnaw' title='Ashwini Vaishnaw' width='770' height='431'>
<figcaption>Ashwini Vaishnaw</figcaption>
<p>BJP leader and Railway minister Ashwini Vaishnaw criticized Mark Zuckerberg’s remarks about the Indian Parliamentary elections of 2024, calling them disappointing and factually incorrect.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Vaishnaw responded to Zuckerberg's claim that incumbent governments lost post-COVID, citing India's 2024 election as a success.</li>
  <li>He emphasized that over 640 million voters participated in the elections, reaffirming trust in PM Narendra Modi and the NDA.</li>
  <li>Vaishnaw noted India’s achievements during the pandemic, such as free food and vaccines for a large population.</li>
  <li>He tweeted about the importance of facts and credibility, tagging Meta in his message.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It’s disappointing to see misinformation from Mr. Zuckerberg himself. Let’s uphold facts and credibility.”</blockquote>
<p>This exchange highlights the ongoing debate around misinformation and the importance of accurate reporting in media and politics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/disappointing-to-see-misinformation-from-mark-zuckerberg-ashwini-vaishnaw-hits-back-12909616.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/disappointing-to-see-misinformation-from-mark-zuckerberg-ashwini-vaishnaw-hits-back-12909616.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:28:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025 live: Holy dip performed by 1.6 crore people till 4 pm on first day - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxPTlhWMGwxdWJBTlZyYS1NcHVSWHFfQmtLTUUzUnpVVTFJSTVfaWhfUHNLcmpXS1FQMVRXQ1hvS3d3XzhrQ3pzM3Z1N0M4NUxIeUZtZktkUkhkby1jMFlsZm5Ic21ZT1hjMHpDU0lwZGJodEZlU1JVdkhQNXpyNkJvc2N1MWdDOFc1TEo1ajBLdTlKWFMwSENzZ1d1bjF2NnBQY3ZCUVRzZkpCbjlNZXhXeld0ajl5STljNFVzMFVBUnhObGNwNkxkLXhjYjNlSWZTR1YtS3RUV3kxcVhzSnExcmRRR2V2S0l0WE9ad1RheWRJR0c5ZzAyWHJSTU0wZzlRN1k0WkJTNnJqMTlkOEHSAZMCQVVfeXFMUGhKTjZCUE9Nejc0MEFKVDFYRmFSTEcwSzBVN3ZjMlBhckp5V05hNmNQWXl3TUN4dHRlWGhhVUM0OWhkbGNvNjJuTUFQNE9ZSWJFdUxRMjljcFh2UmtSUkY2MXZOTWVKQWVyVGptZnZhbE84SWpfcjJtMTdSUHR5ZDFJUkFvbDdUNDloQkVCN3ZxbWhUWmpzTExoVF9Wbm1GNVlrT0FILXZqMXUtWTRBMkpudWRyODZyZ3plVkFpZUlWZjVVbWMtWkswMkRURHg1eFV3dlNmYXNocW9TN3ZwVkpKWU1kNDJSWkx4NjFnMkgxcG1QQ0xVNFU2Y20xWnRYcGs5VWhicGE1Nng2ZEdEbzBFOG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgJBVV95cUxPTlhWMGwxdWJBTlZyYS1NcHVSWHFfQmtLTUUzUnpVVTFJSTVfaWhfUHNLcmpXS1FQMVRXQ1hvS3d3XzhrQ3pzM3Z1N0M4NUxIeUZtZktkUkhkby1jMFlsZm5Ic21ZT1hjMHpDU0lwZGJodEZlU1JVdkhQNXpyNkJvc2N1MWdDOFc1TEo1ajBLdTlKWFMwSENzZ1d1bjF2NnBQY3ZCUVRzZkpCbjlNZXhXeld0ajl5STljNFVzMFVBUnhObGNwNkxkLXhjYjNlSWZTR1YtS3RUV3kxcVhzSnExcmRRR2V2S0l0WE9ad1RheWRJR0c5ZzAyWHJSTU0wZzlRN1k0WkJTNnJqMTlkOEHSAZMCQVVfeXFMUGhKTjZCUE9Nejc0MEFKVDFYRmFSTEcwSzBVN3ZjMlBhckp5V05hNmNQWXl3TUN4dHRlWGhhVUM0OWhkbGNvNjJuTUFQNE9ZSWJFdUxRMjljcFh2UmtSUkY2MXZOTWVKQWVyVGptZnZhbE84SWpfcjJtMTdSUHR5ZDFJUkFvbDdUNDloQkVCN3ZxbWhUWmpzTExoVF9Wbm1GNVlrT0FILXZqMXUtWTRBMkpudWRyODZyZ3plVkFpZUlWZjVVbWMtWkswMkRURHg1eFV3dlNmYXNocW9TN3ZwVkpKWU1kNDJSWkx4NjFnMkgxcG1QQ0xVNFU2Y20xWnRYcGs5VWhicGE1Nng2ZEdEbzBFOG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:17:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kumbh Mela | At Prayagraj, an encounter with naga sadhus and tent stays - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Experiencing the Spiritual Splendor of Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 13, 2025 05:24 pm IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/entertainment/movies/r3zyvi/article69095092.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/IMG_20250110_134955.jpg" alt="Boats arriving at Triveni Sangam, Prayagraj" title="Boats arriving at Triveni Sangam, Prayagraj">
<figcaption>Boats arriving at Triveni Sangam, Prayagraj | Photo Credit: Srinivasa Ramanujam</figcaption>
<p>The Kumbh Mela, taking place in Prayagraj, is the largest religious gathering in the world, with over 40 crore people expected to attend this year due to a rare celestial alignment.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Triveni Sangam, the confluence of the Ganga, Yamuna, and mythical Saraswati, is a sacred dip site for pilgrims.</li>
<li>This year's Mahakumbh is particularly special as it occurs only once every 144 years.</li>
<li>Sadhus from various parts of India gather for the event, staying in tents along the riverbanks.</li>
<li>Economic boost for Prayagraj with accommodations and facilities for the surge in attendees.</li>
<li>Experts note the dual nature of attendees - spiritual seekers and those attending as spectators.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Now it’s more of a show than a <i>kumbh</i>,” says Mahamandeshwar Ji Maharaj of the Juna Akhada.</blockquote>
<p>Prayagraj is prepared for the influx, with transportation, security, and health services being enhanced for the event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kumbh-mela-at-prayagraj-an-encounter-with-naga-sadhus-and-tent-stays/article69094980.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kumbh-mela-at-prayagraj-an-encounter-with-naga-sadhus-and-tent-stays/article69094980.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AIBE 19 Result Expected To Be Declared Soon, Where And How To Check? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AIBE 19 Result Expected To Be Declared Soon, Where And How To Check?</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 13, 2025, 19:24 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="AIBE 19 Result: The exam was held on December 22, 2024. (Representative/File)"><figcaption>AIBE 19 Result: The exam was held on December 22, 2024. (Representative/File)</figcaption></figure><p>The Bar Council of India (BCI) is expected to release the All India Bar Examination (AIBE) 19 result soon. Candidates who took the exam can check the result on the official website at allindiabarexamination.com, using their registration ID and password.</p><h2>AIBE 19 Result: Key Points</h2><ul><li>The BCI will release the scorecards based on the answer key objections.</li><li>Results can be checked on the official website.</li><li>Correct answers are awarded one mark, with no negative marking.</li><li>Passing marks for general candidates range from 40% to 45%.</li><li>The pass rate for SC, ST, and PWD candidates has been raised to 40% from 35%.</li></ul><h2>AIBE 19 Result: Steps to Check</h2><ol><li>Visit the official BCI website.</li><li>Navigate to the ‘Results’ section.</li><li>Click on the AIBE 19 Result link.</li><li>Enter your login credentials.</li><li>Submit and review your result.</li><li>Download and print your result for future reference.</li></ol><h2>Notable Quote</h2><blockquote>“There is no need to worry about any mismatch between the QP booklet number and OMR answer sheet serial number,” the BCI has informed.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, candidates should stay tuned for the results and be prepared to check them as soon as they are released.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/education-career/aibe-19-result-expected-to-be-declared-soon-where-and-how-to-check-9186925.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/education-career/aibe-19-result-expected-to-be-declared-soon-where-and-how-to-check-9186925.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:49:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>