<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 23:17:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 23:17:50 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Roadmap Clear For Chandrayaan-4’: What Dr V Narayanan Said After Becoming New ISRO Chief - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Roadmap Clear For Chandrayaan-4: What Dr V Narayanan Said After Becoming New ISRO Chief</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="New ISRO Chief Dr V Narayanan speaks to reporters. (Photo: News18)"><figcaption>New ISRO Chief Dr V Narayanan speaks to reporters. (Photo: News18)</figcaption><p>Rocket Scientist Dr V Narayanan, recently appointed as the chief of ISRO, aims to leverage technology for enhancing the lives of Indians. His vision includes ambitious space missions such as Chandrayaan-4, Gaganyan, and Venus orbital missions.</p><ul><li>Dr Narayanan emphasizes the importance of his new role, describing it as a “great responsibility.”</li><li>He expressed confidence in India’s upcoming space missions during an interview with CNN-News18.</li><li>Narayanan will officially take charge on January 14.</li><li>He has nearly four decades of experience in ISRO and holds a strong belief in teamwork.</li><li>His wife and daughter expressed immense pride in his new position.</li></ul><blockquote>“Basically, the country needs a lot of things in terms of climate studies, disaster management system, communication requirements, satellites for communication, and earth observation.” - Dr V Narayanan</blockquote><p>Dr Narayanan's leadership is expected to continue pushing ISRO towards innovative solutions that benefit society, emphasizing quality of life for Indian citizens.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/roadmap-clear-for-chandrayaan-4-what-dr-v-narayanan-said-after-becoming-new-isro-chief-9181943.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/roadmap-clear-for-chandrayaan-4-what-dr-v-narayanan-said-after-becoming-new-isro-chief-9181943.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 21:42:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AP Inter First-year Exam 2025 Cancelled, Only Second-year Exams From Now On - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AP Inter First-Year Exam 2025 Cancelled, Only Second-Year Exams Moving Forward</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="AP board has meanwhile released the second-year inter exam 2025 date sheet (Representative/File)" title="AP board has meanwhile released the second-year inter exam 2025 date sheet (Representative/File)" loading="eager"><figcaption>AP board has meanwhile released the second-year inter exam 2025 date sheet (Representative/File)</figcaption></figure><p>The Board of Secondary Education, Andhra Pradesh (BSEAP) has made the significant decision to cancel the Intermediate first-year public examinations for 2025. This move is intended to alleviate the examination pressure on students, as only second-year public examinations will now be conducted.</p><ul><li>The first-year syllabus will be taught in Telugu-English medium.</li><li>NCERT syllabus for Math and Chemistry for first-year students will be reduced significantly.</li><li>Internal assessments of 20 marks will replace annual exams for each subject.</li><li>Feedback from students, teachers, and stakeholders can be submitted until January 26.</li><li>AP SSC exams will be conducted from March 17 to 31, 2025.</li><li>AP inter second-year exams are scheduled between March 3 to March 20, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“To clear the exam this year, students needed to score at least 35 per cent in both theory and practical examinations,”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, this significant change aims to reduce stress on students while adapting educational strategies to modern needs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/education-career/ap-inter-first-year-exam-2025-cancelled-only-second-year-exams-from-now-on-9181978.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/education-career/ap-inter-first-year-exam-2025-cancelled-only-second-year-exams-from-now-on-9181978.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 20:21:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 killed, 30 injured in stampede in queue for event tokens at Tirupati temple - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 killed, 30 injured in stampede in queue for event tokens at Tirupati temple</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>A tragic incident occurred at the Tirupati temple where a stampede resulted in the deaths of six individuals and injuries to thirty others while they were queuing for event tokens.</p><ul><li>The stampede took place during a busy pilgrimage event.</li><li>Authorities are investigating the circumstances that led to the stampede.</li><li>The temple has expressed condolences to the families of the victims.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a heartbreaking situation; our thoughts are with the families affected by this tragedy.” - Temple Official</blockquote><p>This incident raises concerns about crowd management at large religious gatherings and highlights the need for improved safety measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/6-killed-30-injured-in-stampede-in-queue-for-event-tokens-at-tirupati/articleshow/117064714.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/6-killed-30-injured-in-stampede-in-queue-for-event-tokens-at-tirupati/articleshow/117064714.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 20:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vegetable Vendor Exposes Mumbai Jeweller's Rs 13.5 Crore Ponzi Scheme - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vegetable Vendor Exposes Mumbai Jeweller's Rs 13.5 Crore Ponzi Scheme</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Torres Jewellery had promised high returns on the purchase of gold, silver and moissanite. (Representative/PTI File)" title="Torres Jewellery had promised high returns on the purchase of gold, silver and moissanite. (Representative/PTI File)"><figcaption>Torres Jewellery had promised high returns on the purchase of gold, silver and moissanite. (Representative/PTI File)</figcaption></figure><p>A jeweller in Mumbai has been exposed for running a Ponzi scheme that defrauded investors of over Rs 13.48 crore. The operation was uncovered by a local vegetable seller who lodged a police complaint against the jeweller.</p><ul><li>The jeweller promised high returns, up to 520% on investments in moissanite.</li><li>Payments to investors ceased abruptly after initial returns were made.</li><li>Thousands of investors gathered outside Torres Jewellers’ Dadar office demanding their money back.</li><li>The police have filed an FIR against the company's directors for fraud.</li></ul><blockquote>"The fraud occurred between June 21, 2024, and December 30, 2024. After that, all payments stopped." - Pradeep Kumar Vaishya, Complainant</blockquote><p>The investigation is ongoing, with authorities attempting to locate the company's owner, who may have fled abroad.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/vegetable-vendor-exposes-mumbai-jewellers-rs-13-5-crore-ponzi-scheme-ws-ab-9181967.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/vegetable-vendor-exposes-mumbai-jewellers-rs-13-5-crore-ponzi-scheme-ws-ab-9181967.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 19:03:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Woman Alleges Assault By Kuki "Tenants" Over Land, Naga Village Authority In Manipur Sends Warning - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Woman Alleges Assault By Kuki &quot;Tenants&quot; Over Land, Naga Village Authority In Manipur Sends Warning</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>January 25, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/lds4jse8_kuki-naga_625x300_08_January_25.jpg" alt="Assault Incident" />
<figcaption>Image depicting the conflict between Kuki tribes and Naga villagers.</figcaption>
<p>A village authority in Manipur has condemned an alleged attack by Kuki tribesmen on a woman who was attempting to build a house on disputed land, highlighting escalating tensions between the Naga and Kuki communities.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Konsakhul Village Authority has given a 15-day ultimatum for the Kuki tenants to vacate the land claimed by the Naga villagers.</li>
  <li>A woman was reportedly assaulted by 30 men from the Kuki tribes while trying to build a home, prompting civil society organizations to intervene.</li>
  <li>Video evidence emerged showing aggressive behavior towards the Naga villagers by Kuki individuals.</li>
  <li>Indigenous People's Forum has demanded immediate action for the safety of Naga villagers, launching a blockade at a key thoroughfare.</li>
  <li>This incident comes amid growing tensions and previous allegations of violence involving Kuki volunteers against Naga tribes in the region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I am the person who was assaulted... The Kukis said I can't build a house there. Some 10-20 of them came, attacked me.” - The woman who was allegedly assaulted.</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights the ongoing land disputes and ethnic tensions in Manipur, necessitating urgent dialogue and resolution to prevent further violence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/woman-alleges-assault-by-kuki-tenants-over-land-naga-village-authority-in-manipur-sends-warning-7430651</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/woman-alleges-assault-by-kuki-tenants-over-land-naga-village-authority-in-manipur-sends-warning-7430651</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:22:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In a first, foreign secretary engages Taliban; India may restart development projects - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/in-a-first-foreign-secretary-engages-taliban-india-may-restart-development-projects/articleshow/117063089.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/in-a-first-foreign-secretary-engages-taliban-india-may-restart-development-projects/articleshow/117063089.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In a first, foreign secretary engages Taliban; India may restart development projects - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/in-a-first-foreign-secretary-engages-taliban-india-may-restart-development-projects/articleshow/117063089.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/in-a-first-foreign-secretary-engages-taliban-india-may-restart-development-projects/articleshow/117063089.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Judging Can Be A Lonely Task": Ex-Chief Justice DY Chandrachud To NDTV - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Judging Can Be A Lonely Task: Ex-Chief Justice DY Chandrachud To NDTV</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p>
<p>Justice DY Chandrachud reflects on his extensive career as the former Chief Justice of India, covering his legal journey, landmark judgments, and personal anecdotes in a recent interview with NDTV.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Chandrachud practiced law for nearly 30 years and was the longest-serving Chief Justice of India.</li>
  <li>He discussed notable judgments on electoral bonds, Article 370, and same-sex marriage.</li>
  <li>The former Chief Justice emphasized the loneliness of judging, where reflection occurs after arguments are completed.</li>
  <li>He recalled how he initially desired to pursue economics, influenced by his father's support for his career choices.</li>
  <li>Chandrachud mentioned the significance of humility in the judiciary, particularly within the Supreme Court.</li>
  <li>He discussed the need for the Supreme Court to revisit past judgments based on evolving societal context, including overruling some of his father's decisions.</li>
  <li>The impact of social media criticism on judges' work was highlighted, stressing the importance of context in court discussions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Law was not my first choice, to be very honest.” - Justice DY Chandrachud</blockquote>
<p>The interview showcases Justice Chandrachud's reflections on the evolving nature of law, the principle of humility in judgment, and the consideration of social media's impact on public perception of the judiciary.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/ndtv-exclusive-dy-chandrachud-judging-can-be-a-lonely-task-ex-chief-justice-dy-chandrachud-to-ndtv-7430233</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/ndtv-exclusive-dy-chandrachud-judging-can-be-a-lonely-task-ex-chief-justice-dy-chandrachud-to-ndtv-7430233</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:09:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pune: Doctor Dies In Horrific Road Accident In Undri; Truck Driver Arrested - Punekar News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Doctor Dies In Horrific Road Accident In Undri; Truck Driver Arrested</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 8th January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Punekar News</p><p>The incident involved Dr. Pranali Tanmay Date, a 34-year-old female doctor, who was killed by a speeding truck in Undri, Pune. The accident raised concerns among local residents about road safety.</p><ul><li>Dr. Date was on her two-wheeler when she was hit by a truck around 12:30 pm.</li><li>The truck driver sped away but was arrested later after CCTV footage was reviewed.</li><li>Residents are alarmed by the frequency of accidents and have called the area a “death trap.”</li><li>Citizens are demanding better traffic control and safety measures to prevent future incidents.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have started keeping necessary medical supplies to treat at least one person every day.” - Local resident</blockquote><p>This tragic event has led to a call for immediate actions from authorities to improve traffic safety in the Undri area.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.punekarnews.in/pune-doctor-dies-in-horrific-road-accident-in-undri-truck-driver-arrested/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.punekarnews.in/pune-doctor-dies-in-horrific-road-accident-in-undri-truck-driver-arrested/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:53:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tirupati temple stampede: Six devotees killed during distribution of darshan tokens; CM Naidu reviews situation | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tirupati Temple Stampede Claims Six Lives During Darshan Token Distribution</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Press Trust of India</p><p>At least six devotees, including three women, died in a stampede at the Tirupati temple as crowds jostled for darshan tokens. Chief Minister Chandrababu Naidu is set to visit the injured and has called for better arrangements.</p><ul><li>The stampede occurred during the distribution of tickets for Vaikunta Dwara Darshanam.</li><li>CM Naidu expressed shock and questioned the lack of proper arrangements for the expected crowd.</li><li>Videos of police administering CPR to the injured have circulated widely.</li><li>This incident highlights safety concerns during large religious events, similar incidents have occurred in other states.</li></ul><blockquote>“No casualties were reported in the previous similar incidents, highlighting the severity of the current situation.”</blockquote><p>The recent tragedy underscores the need for improved crowd management and safety measures at religious events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/devotees-killed-stampede-ticketing-tirumala-srivari-vaikuntha-dwara-tirupati-11736354802181.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/devotees-killed-stampede-ticketing-tirumala-srivari-vaikuntha-dwara-tirupati-11736354802181.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:49:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 dead in stampede at Andhra Pradesh's Tirupati Temple; CM Naidu holds high-level meet - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 dead in stampede at Andhra Pradesh's Tirupati Temple; CM Naidu holds high-level meet</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>A tragic stampede at Tirupati Temple in Andhra Pradesh resulted in the deaths of six individuals, prompting Chief Minister N. Chandrababu Naidu to convene a high-level meeting to investigate the incident.</p><ul><li>The stampede occurred during a large gathering, causing chaos and panic.</li><li>Emergency services were dispatched to the scene to aid the victims.</li><li>CM Naidu expressed condolences and announced compensation for the victims' families.</li><li>Authorities are reviewing safety measures at the temple to prevent future incidents.</li></ul><blockquote>“We must ensure the safety of all devotees,” said CM Naidu.</blockquote><p>This incident raises concerns about crowd management at religious sites, highlighting the need for improved safety protocols.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/stampede-at-andhra-pradeshs-tirupati-temple-death-toll-injuries/articleshow/117061496.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/stampede-at-andhra-pradeshs-tirupati-temple-death-toll-injuries/articleshow/117061496.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Die In Stampede At Tirupati During Distribution Of Tokens To Offer Prayers - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>3 Die In Stampede At Tirupati During Distribution Of Tokens To Offer Prayers</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="3 Die In Stampede At Tirupati During Distribution Of Tokens To Offer Prayers" alt="3 Die In Stampede At Tirupati During Distribution Of Tokens To Offer Prayers" height="435" width="773" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/uc0q2m4g_tirupati-stampede_625x300_08_January_25.jpg?downsize=773:435"><figcaption>Three people died in a stampede at Vishnu Niwasam, Tirupati.</figcaption><p>Three individuals lost their lives in a tragic stampede that occurred during the distribution of Vaikunthadwara Sarvadarshanam tokens at Vishnu Niwasam in Tirupati. The incident happened due to a massive rush of devotees.</p><ul><li>Three deaths reported during the stampede.</li><li>Four additional injuries were documented, with victims taken to Ruia Hospital.</li><li>Heavy police presence at the scene for crowd management.</li><li>Devotees were attempting to secure tokens to offer prayers.</li></ul><blockquote>“A massive rush of devotees attempting to secure tokens resulted in the stampede.”</blockquote><p>This tragic incident highlights the critical need for improved crowd management at large religious gatherings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/3-die-in-stampede-at-tirupati-during-distribution-of-tokens-to-offer-prayers-7430018</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/3-die-in-stampede-at-tirupati-during-distribution-of-tokens-to-offer-prayers-7430018</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:38:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UPSC CDS I Final Merit List Released; 590 Candidates Selected, Check Toppers List - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UPSC CDS I Final Merit List Released; 590 Candidates Selected</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="UPSC CDS I final merit list now available at upsc.gov.in." title="UPSC CDS I final merit list now available at upsc.gov.in."><figcaption>UPSC CDS I final merit list now available at upsc.gov.in.</figcaption></figure><p>The Union Public Service Commission (UPSC) has released the CDS I final merit list for 2024. A total of 590 candidates have been shortlisted for the Combined Defence Services, with 470 selected for the men’s course and 120 for the women’s course.</p><ul><li>A total of 590 candidates selected.</li><li>Top three male candidates: Ranbir Negi, Archit Chauhan, Devendra Sharma.</li><li>Top three female candidates: Divya, Pranjal Nangare, Mansi Basera.</li><li>Results available on upsc.gov.in.</li><li>Verification of DOB and educational qualifications will be conducted by Army Headquarters.</li></ul><blockquote>“The candidature of all the candidates is Provisional.” - UPSC</blockquote><p>The release of the merit list marks a crucial step for candidates aspiring to join the Indian Armed Forces through the CDS examination.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/education-career/upsc-cds-i-final-merit-list-released-at-upsc-gov-in-590-candidates-selected-check-toppers-list-here-9181740.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/education-career/upsc-cds-i-final-merit-list-released-at-upsc-gov-in-590-candidates-selected-check-toppers-list-here-9181740.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:05:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaDeX satellites drift apart, docking pushed for 2nd time - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaDeX Satellites Drift Apart, Docking Delayed Again</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date unavailable] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source unavailable]</p>
<p>The SpaDeX satellites have drifted apart, causing their docking procedure to be postponed for the second time. This development raises concerns about the capabilities of the satellite systems.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The docking procedure was initially scheduled but has faced delays.</li>
  <li>Scientists are investigating the reasons for the drift.</li>
  <li>This could have implications for future space missions and operations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This is a setback for our planned operations in space." - [Quote unavailable]</blockquote>
<p>This situation underscores the technical challenges associated with satellite operations, particularly in maintaining synchronization for docking.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/spadex-satellites-drift-apart-docking-pushed-for-2nd-time/articleshow/117060624.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/spadex-satellites-drift-apart-docking-pushed-for-2nd-time/articleshow/117060624.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISRO's Experiment To Dock 2 Satellites In Space Postponed For 2nd Time - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ISRO's Experiment To Dock 2 Satellites In Space Postponed For 2nd Time</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Wednesday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO)</p><p>The Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) has postponed its space docking experiment of satellites for the second time due to excessive drift observed between the mission satellites.</p><ul><li>The mission was scheduled for Tuesday but was postponed to Thursday.</li><li>ISRO explained that the drift observed was higher than expected after a non-visibility period.</li><li>The Space Docking Experiment (SpaDeX) aims to develop critical docking technology for future missions.</li><li>Two satellites, a chaser and a target, will perform various maneuvers to achieve docking.</li><li>The operation is a significant step in enhancing India's capabilities in complex space operations.</li></ul><blockquote>S. Somanth, ISRO Chief: "They will do the docking exercise only when all sensors have been fully calibrated and tested to satisfaction before it is attempted."</blockquote><p>This delay highlights the complexities involved in satellite docking, a process mastered by only a few nations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isros-experiment-to-dock-2-satellites-in-space-postponed-for-2nd-time-7429713</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isros-experiment-to-dock-2-satellites-in-space-postponed-for-2nd-time-7429713</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naresh Balyan facilitator in organised crime syndicate: Delhi police to court - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Naresh Balyan facilitator in organised crime syndicate: Delhi police to court</h1><p><strong>Date: Jan 08, 2025</strong><br/><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/India_7_1734523831601_1734523847734.jpg" alt="Naresh Balyan facilitator in organised crime syndicate: Delhi police to court" title="Naresh Balyan facilitator in organised crime syndicate: Delhi police to court"/><figcaption>Naresh Balyan facilitator in organised crime syndicate: Delhi police to court</figcaption></figure><p>The Delhi police have objected to the bail plea of MLA Naresh Balyan, alleging his involvement as a facilitator in an organized crime syndicate under the Maharashtra Control of Organised Crime Act (MCOCA).</p><ul><li>Balyan is accused of being a facilitator in Kapil Sangwan's organized crime syndicate.</li><li>Police claim he provided financial assistance to a syndicate member to evade arrest.</li><li>There are 16 FIRs against the syndicate for various crimes.</li><li>Concerns were raised about potential witness tampering and destruction of evidence if bail is granted.</li><li>The court hearing concerning his bail application resumes on January 9.</li></ul><blockquote>"They have confessed that accused Naresh Balyan is facilitator/conspirator in the organised crime syndicate..." - Akhand Pratap Singh, Special Public Prosecutor</blockquote><p>The accusations against Balyan highlight serious concerns regarding the influence of individuals involved in organized crime within the political framework.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/naresh-balyan-facilitator-in-organised-crime-syndicate-delhi-police-to-court-101736350491129.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/naresh-balyan-facilitator-in-organised-crime-syndicate-delhi-police-to-court-101736350491129.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:34:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyderabad set to experience coldest winter night in Jan, says weatherman - The Siasat Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hyderabad Expected to Experience Coldest Winter Night This January</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Telangana Weatherman</p><figure><img src="https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Winter-in-Hyderabad-780x470.jpg" alt="Winter in Hyderabad" width="1200" height="900"><figcaption>Representational Image</figcaption></figure><p>Hyderabad is bracing for its coldest winter night this January, with temperatures dropping to between 5-7 degrees Celsius in parts of North and West Telangana, and 7-9 degrees Celsius in some areas of Hyderabad.</p><ul><li>The cold snap is expected to result in the chilliest morning of the month.</li><li>Misty or hazy conditions are forecasted in all zones of Hyderabad.</li><li>Health experts advise precautions, especially for vulnerable groups such as the elderly and children.</li><li>Risks include frostbite, trench foot, and hypothermia due to low temperatures.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tonight will be the coldest night of this January and get ready for the coldest morning tomorrow with temp up to 5-7°C in North, West TG and 7-9°C in few parts of Hyderabad.” — Telangana Weatherman (@balaji25_t)</blockquote><p>Residents are urged to take necessary precautions to protect against the cold and potential health risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.siasat.com/hyderabad-set-to-experience-coldest-winter-night-in-jan-says-weatherman-3161795/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.siasat.com/hyderabad-set-to-experience-coldest-winter-night-in-jan-says-weatherman-3161795/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ashok Gehlot's attack on AAP prompts Arvind Kejriwal's 'Congress-BJP together' charge - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashok Gehlot's Attack on AAP Leads to Kejriwal's Accusation of Congress-BJP Alliance</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/PTI01-07-2025-000051A-0_1736349430935_1736349464984.jpg" alt="Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) chief Arvind Kejriwal during campaigning for the Delhi assembly election.(PTI file photo)" title="Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) chief Arvind Kejriwal during campaigning for the Delhi assembly election.(PTI file photo)"><figcaption>Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) chief Arvind Kejriwal during campaigning for the Delhi assembly election.(PTI file photo)</figcaption><p>Former Rajasthan Chief Minister Ashok Gehlot labeled the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) as the Congress's primary opposition in the upcoming Delhi assembly elections, prompting AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal to suggest a secret alliance between the Congress and BJP.</p><ul><li>Gehlot stated that AAP is mistaken to believe they are the dominant party in Delhi.</li><li>Kejriwal accused Congress of working alongside BJP against AAP.</li><li>Gehlot defended Congress's campaign efforts and emphasized a shift in voting dynamics.</li><li>The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled for February 5, 2025, with results due on February 8.</li></ul><blockquote>"They (the AAP) are our opposition...The situation in Delhi has changed now." - Ashok Gehlot</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Gehlot's comments intensify the political landscape ahead of the crucial elections, highlighting the contentious relationships among the major parties in Delhi.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ashok-gehlots-attack-on-aap-prompts-arvind-kejriwals-congress-bjp-together-charge-101736349246165.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ashok-gehlots-attack-on-aap-prompts-arvind-kejriwals-congress-bjp-together-charge-101736349246165.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['One of the greatest men…': British journalist pens moving tribute to Manmohan Singh - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘One of the greatest men…’: British journalist pens moving tribute to Manmohan Singh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/--EDS--FILE-PHOTO---New-Delhi--In-this-Jan--17--20_1735354967714_1736348645160.jpg" alt="Former Indian prime minister Manmohan Singh died at the age of 92 in December 2024.(HT_PRINT)"><figcaption>Former Indian prime minister Manmohan Singh died at the age of 92 in December 2024.(HT_PRINT)</figcaption><p>British journalist Martin Wolf honored former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh with a touching tribute, highlighting his legacy as a pivotal leader and policymaker.</p><ul><li>Wolf described Singh as one of the most important policymakers of our era.</li><li>Singh served as India's Prime Minister until his passing at the age of 92 in December 2024.</li><li>The tribute praised Singh's integrity, stating he remained untainted by political corruption.</li><li>Wolf mentioned significant achievements during Singh's tenure, including the US nuclear deal and India's Aadhaar system.</li><li>Referencing Barack Obama, Wolf noted, “When the prime minister speaks, the world listens.”</li><li>The tribute emphasized Singh's belief in India's democracy and public service.</li></ul><blockquote>“Singh took ideas seriously, yet was unfailingly courteous and open to the ideas of others.” - Martin Wolf</blockquote><p>This heartfelt tribute reflects on the indelible mark Manmohan Singh left on India and the global community.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/one-of-the-greatest-men-british-journalist-pens-moving-tribute-to-manmohan-singh-101736348270684.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/one-of-the-greatest-men-british-journalist-pens-moving-tribute-to-manmohan-singh-101736348270684.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:17:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[52-Kg Suitcase Sparks Interest As MPs Weigh In On 'One Nation, One Election' At First JPC Meet - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/52-kg-suitcase-sparks-interest-as-mps-weigh-in-on-one-nation-one-election-at-first-jpc-meet-9182343.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/52-kg-suitcase-sparks-interest-as-mps-weigh-in-on-one-nation-one-election-at-first-jpc-meet-9182343.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:01:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Schools Remain Closed Tomorrow in Hubballi-Dharwad? Here’s All You Need to Know - Hubballi Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Will Schools Remain Closed Tomorrow in Hubballi-Dharwad? Here’s All You Need to Know</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hubballi Times</p>
<img src="https://hubballitimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/school-holiday-2024-780x470.jpg" alt="" width="780" height="470">
<figcaption>A school holiday announcement in Hubballi-Dharwad.</figcaption>
<p>The Dr. B. R. Ambedkar Fans Forum intends to hold a bandh on January 9, prompting local schools in Hubballi and Dharwad to close for safety reasons. The holiday will be compensated with full classes on the following Saturdays.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Deputy Director of Public Instruction has mandated a holiday for schools within the city limits of Hubballi and Dharwad.</li>
  <li>Schools in rural areas will remain open as usual.</li>
  <li>Protesters are calling for all businesses to close in solidarity with the bandh.</li>
  <li>Essential services like healthcare and transport will continue to operate despite potential disruptions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The safety of children is our priority,” said a spokesperson from the Deputy Director of Public Instruction.</blockquote>
<p>This decision reflects the ongoing societal considerations surrounding public safety amid protests.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://hubballitimes.com/will-schools-remain-closed-tomorrow-in-hubballi-dharwad-heres-all-you-need-to-know/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hubballitimes.com/will-schools-remain-closed-tomorrow-in-hubballi-dharwad-heres-all-you-need-to-know/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:59:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frame Cashless Treatment Scheme For Road Accident Victims During 'Golden Hour' By March 14 : Supreme... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Directs Cashless Treatment Scheme for Accident Victims by March 14, 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p><p>The Supreme Court of India has mandated the Central Government to create a scheme for cashless treatment for motor vehicle accident victims within the critical first hour of injury, referred to as the 'golden hour', by March 14, 2025. This initiative aims to save lives by ensuring immediate medical care.</p><ul><li>The Court emphasized the urgency in implementing the scheme which has been a statutory obligation since the Motor Vehicles Act was updated.</li><li>Concerns were raised about existing delays in medical treatment due to payment issues and police delays.</li><li>Section 162 of the Motor Vehicles Act mandates a cashless treatment scheme, yet no scheme has been established despite this legal requirement.</li><li>Issues surrounding the draft concept note submitted by the Central Government were highlighted, particularly limitations on treatment amounts and coverage duration.</li><li>The Court ordered the creation of a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund to provide financial support for treatment costs.</li></ul><blockquote>“Once the scheme is framed and its implementation starts, it will save the lives of several injured persons...” - Supreme Court</blockquote><p>Additionally, the Court reviewed the hit-and-run compensation scheme and noted the low claim rates despite the frequency of such accidents. They have directed improvements to expedite claims processing.</p><p>The Court's order aims to solidify the legal framework surrounding accident victim treatment and compensation, enhancing road safety and emergency care in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/frame-cashless-treatment-scheme-for-road-accident-victims-during-golden-hour-by-march-14-supreme-court-directs-centre-280355</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/frame-cashless-treatment-scheme-for-road-accident-victims-during-golden-hour-by-march-14-supreme-court-directs-centre-280355</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:54:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frame Cashless Treatment Scheme For Road Accident Victims During 'Golden Hour' By March 14 : Supreme Court Directs Centre - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Directs Cashless Treatment Scheme for Accident Victims by March 14, 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p><p>The Supreme Court of India has mandated the Central Government to create a scheme for cashless treatment for motor vehicle accident victims within the critical first hour of injury, referred to as the 'golden hour', by March 14, 2025. This initiative aims to save lives by ensuring immediate medical care.</p><ul><li>The Court emphasized the urgency in implementing the scheme which has been a statutory obligation since the Motor Vehicles Act was updated.</li><li>Concerns were raised about existing delays in medical treatment due to payment issues and police delays.</li><li>Section 162 of the Motor Vehicles Act mandates a cashless treatment scheme, yet no scheme has been established despite this legal requirement.</li><li>Issues surrounding the draft concept note submitted by the Central Government were highlighted, particularly limitations on treatment amounts and coverage duration.</li><li>The Court ordered the creation of a Motor Vehicle Accident Fund to provide financial support for treatment costs.</li></ul><blockquote>“Once the scheme is framed and its implementation starts, it will save the lives of several injured persons...” - Supreme Court</blockquote><p>Additionally, the Court reviewed the hit-and-run compensation scheme and noted the low claim rates despite the frequency of such accidents. They have directed improvements to expedite claims processing.</p><p>The Court's order aims to solidify the legal framework surrounding accident victim treatment and compensation, enhancing road safety and emergency care in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/frame-cashless-treatment-scheme-for-road-accident-victims-during-golden-hour-by-march-14-supreme-court-directs-centre-280355</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/frame-cashless-treatment-scheme-for-road-accident-victims-during-golden-hour-by-march-14-supreme-court-directs-centre-280355</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:54:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assam coal mine rescue: Indian Navy deployed with specialised equipment - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian Navy Deployed for Rescue Operations in Assam Coal Mine Incident</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/h77vbc/article69075868.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/PTI01_08_2025_000062A.jpg" alt="Rescue operation underway for labourers trapped inside a coal mine at Umrangso area, in Dima Hasao district, Assam on Jan. 8, 2025." title="Rescue operation underway for labourers trapped inside a coal mine at Umrangso area, in Dima Hasao district, Assam on Jan. 8, 2025."><figcaption>Rescue operation underway for labourers trapped inside a coal mine at Umrangso area, in Dima Hasao district, Assam on Jan. 8, 2025. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>The Indian Navy has launched a rescue operation utilizing specialized equipment to rescue miners trapped in a coal mine in Assam. The efforts include advanced diving gear and underwater ROVs.</p><ul><li>The Indian Navy has mobilized a specialized team for the rescue at Umrangso, Dima Hasao.</li><li>One deceased miner has been recovered while eight remain trapped.</li><li>Rescue efforts involve the National Disaster Response Force (NDRF), the Indian Army, and local disaster response teams.</li><li>Challenges include hazardous underground conditions affecting rescue operations.</li><li>Experts, including highly trained Clearance Divers, are part of the rescue team.</li></ul><blockquote>“Many attempts were made yesterday but we didn’t succeed... A joint team dived today (in the mine) and we have recovered one body.” - H.P.S. Kandari, Commandant of the 1st Battalion of the NDRF</blockquote><p>The joint efforts continue with hopes of rescuing all trapped miners amidst challenging conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/assam/assam-coal-mine-rescue-indian-navy-deployed-with-specialised-equipment/article69075782.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/assam/assam-coal-mine-rescue-indian-navy-deployed-with-specialised-equipment/article69075782.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Maps lands Assam Police in Nagaland, locals hold them captive mistaking them for criminals - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxPRUM0UlQ4Mmp0MDR5MlVmVDNvYnB2LWlGbWJXRTdwUFhtb3E1ZzgzXzhKTHZJcXhaazFka2h4aUt6NFNkdTViNndUT3kwZTB4UlJBc1pTdGlBVmw5NUJpR2VZU1RjZ2tOa1VtOERNT3RtT2hxQTFWY0F1UVFPM09FN2h4ay1majUzcms0bHY2aXp0QTk4eVd2LUlkdWRIT3JkbGhvMExOZDkwNXdVRHJ0TkRKOFV3Yk41Tk1HcWRaNmVoWGtEVGtjc1B3UVlJbTFLT0FaNnBCSTJ0Z2pTb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxPRUM0UlQ4Mmp0MDR5MlVmVDNvYnB2LWlGbWJXRTdwUFhtb3E1ZzgzXzhKTHZJcXhaazFka2h4aUt6NFNkdTViNndUT3kwZTB4UlJBc1pTdGlBVmw5NUJpR2VZU1RjZ2tOa1VtOERNT3RtT2hxQTFWY0F1UVFPM09FN2h4ay1majUzcms0bHY2aXp0QTk4eVd2LUlkdWRIT3JkbGhvMExOZDkwNXdVRHJ0TkRKOFV3Yk41Tk1HcWRaNmVoWGtEVGtjc1B3UVlJbTFLT0FaNnBCSTJ0Z2pTb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:30:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka: Married tuition teacher elopes with a minor student, arrested and charged with kidnapping and rape - OpIndia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.opindia.com/news-updates/karnataka-married-tuition-teacher-elopes-with-minor-student-arrested-charged-with-kidnapping-and-rape/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opindia.com/news-updates/karnataka-married-tuition-teacher-elopes-with-minor-student-arrested-charged-with-kidnapping-and-rape/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:27:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boby Chemmanur arrested, Honey Rose's statement recorded - Onmanorama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Boby Chemmanur Arrested Following Honey Rose's Complaint</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> January 08, 2025 07:45 PM IST</p>
<p><strong>Updated:</strong> January 08, 2025 07:55 PM IST</p>
<img src="https://img.onmanorama.com/content/dam/mm/en/kerala/top-news/images/2025/1/8/boby-chemannur-honey-rose.jpg?w=1120&amp;h=583" alt="boby-chemannur-honey-rose" title="boby-chemannur-honey-rose">
<figcaption>Boby Chemmanur, Honey Rose. Photo: Special arrangement</figcaption>
<p>Businessman Boby Chemmanur was arrested following actor Honey Rose's complaint of sexual harassment. Police confirmed his custody at the Ernakulam Central Police Station.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Boby Chemmanur arrested after allegations of sexual harassment by Honey Rose.</li>
  <li>Honey Rose's statement was recorded by the Judicial Magistrate for over two hours.</li>
  <li>Complaints detail incidents from a jewellery inauguration and public forums.</li>
  <li>Around 20 YouTube channels are also facing complaints from Rose for defamatory content.</li>
  <li>Chemmanur faces charges under IPC Section 75 and Section 67 of the IT Act.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The specifics of Honey Rose's statement remain undisclosed but are critical for further charges.”</blockquote>
<p>The investigation continues, with potential for additional charges against Chemmanur based on the findings regarding the allegations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.onmanorama.com/news/kerala/2025/01/08/boby-chemannur-arrest-honey-rose-statement.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.onmanorama.com/news/kerala/2025/01/08/boby-chemannur-arrest-honey-rose-statement.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:15:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India’s foreign secretary meets Taliban minister for first time in Dubai - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India’s foreign secretary meets Taliban minister for first time in Dubai</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>January 8, 2025 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Foreign-secretary-Vikram-Misri-meets-the-Taliban-s_1736345485716_1736348289481.jpg" alt="Foreign secretary Vikram Misri meets the Taliban’s acting foreign minister Amir Khan Muttaqi in Dubai on Wednesday. (Image posted on X by @MEAIndia)" title="Foreign secretary Vikram Misri meets the Taliban’s acting foreign minister Amir Khan Muttaqi in Dubai on Wednesday. (Image posted on X by @MEAIndia)"><figcaption>Foreign secretary Vikram Misri meets the Taliban’s acting foreign minister Amir Khan Muttaqi in Dubai on Wednesday. (Image posted on X by @MEAIndia)</figcaption><p>India has pledged support for Afghanistan in the health sector and for refugee rehabilitation during a significant meeting between Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri and Taliban’s Acting Foreign Minister Amir Khan Muttaqi in Dubai.</p><ul><li>First official meeting between an Indian Foreign Secretary and a senior Taliban official.</li><li>India to provide material support to healthcare and refugee rehabilitation following a request from the Taliban.</li><li>Discussion included promoting Chabahar port for humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan.</li><li>India highlighted its historic friendship and commitment to the Afghan people.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Afghan side underlined its sensitivities to India’s security concerns.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, this meeting marks a pivotal step in India's engagement with the Taliban regime, opening pathways for humanitarian assistance while emphasizing security concerns.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/indias-foreign-secretary-meets-taliban-minister-for-first-time-in-dubai-101736345492863.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/indias-foreign-secretary-meets-taliban-minister-for-first-time-in-dubai-101736345492863.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:11:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi holds roadshow, unveils projects worth 2 lakh crore in Andhra Pradesh's Visakhapatnam - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-holds-roadshow-unveils-projects-worth-rs-2-lakh-crore-in-andhra-pradeshs-visakhapatnam-101736338440544.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-holds-roadshow-unveils-projects-worth-rs-2-lakh-crore-in-andhra-pradeshs-visakhapatnam-101736338440544.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:53:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi holds roadshow, unveils projects worth ₹2 lakh crore in Andhra Pradesh's Visakhapatnam - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-holds-roadshow-unveils-projects-worth-rs-2-lakh-crore-in-andhra-pradeshs-visakhapatnam-101736338440544.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-holds-roadshow-unveils-projects-worth-rs-2-lakh-crore-in-andhra-pradeshs-visakhapatnam-101736338440544.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:53:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>