<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:21:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:21:55 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy Pongal 2025: Wishes, Images, WhatsApp status, Messages, Quotes and greetings, cards to share this Pongal - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Happy Pongal 2025: Wishes, Images, WhatsApp Status, Messages, Quotes, and Greetings to Share</h1><p><strong>Date: January 14, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Indian Express</strong></p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/happy-happy-Pongal.png?w=640" alt="Happy Pongal" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Happy Pongal 2025 Wishes Images: Share these best wishes and cards and put them on your WhatsApp status this Pongal!</figcaption><p>Pongal is an auspicious Hindu festival celebrated mostly in India’s southern states, particularly in Tamil Nadu. The four-day harvest festival honors the Sun God, starting on January 14, 2025, and concludes on January 17.</p><ul><li>Traditionally celebrated with music, dance, and the preparation of sweet rice dish called Pongal.</li><li>The festival emphasizes community, gratitude, and joy among families and friends.</li><li>Curated lists of wishes, greetings, and cards are available for sharing on WhatsApp and Facebook.</li></ul><blockquote>“May the blessings of Surya Dev bring light and warmth into your life. Happy Pongal!”</blockquote><p>This Pongal is not just a celebration of the harvest but a time to reflect on the positivity and sweetness that life can offer. Happy Pongal!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/life-style/happy-pongal-2025-best-wishes-greetings-cards-whatsapp-status-9776403/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/life-style/happy-pongal-2025-best-wishes-greetings-cards-whatsapp-status-9776403/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IITian Baba at Mahakumbh: He studied aerospace engineering at IIT Bombay, then turned to spirituality - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meet Abhay Singh, the IITian Baba who quit science for spirituality</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 14, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/GhOEdWTaYAAmQLi_1736822050078_1736822057680.jpg" alt="The grand religious festival of Mahakumbh attracts people from all walks of lives.(X/@MahaaKumbh)" /><figcaption>The grand religious festival of Mahakumbh attracts people from all walks of lives.(X/@MahaaKumbh)</figcaption><p>At the world’s largest religious festival, the Mahakumbh Mela in Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, millions of devotees gather. This year, an IITian Baba, Abhay Singh, is making headlines for choosing spirituality over his engineering career.</p><ul><li>Abhay Singh studied aerospace engineering at IIT Bombay.</li><li>He also pursued a Masters in Design after his engineering studies.</li><li>Singh was born in Haryana and has incorporated philosophy into his life pursuits.</li><li>His conversation with an interviewer has gone viral online.</li><li>Singh believes that pursuing knowledge leads to spiritual fulfillment.</li></ul><blockquote>“If you keep pursuing knowledge, where do you reach? This is where you reach.”</blockquote><p>The Maha Kumbh started on January 13 and continues until February 26, attracting participants from various backgrounds.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/iitian-baba-at-mahakumbh-meet-the-man-who-left-science-for-spirituality-101736821678264.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/iitian-baba-at-mahakumbh-meet-the-man-who-left-science-for-spirituality-101736821678264.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:35:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy Pongal 2025: Best wishes, greetings, cards, WhatsApp status, SMS, images to share this Pongal - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Happy Pongal 2025: Wishes, Images, WhatsApp Status, Messages, Quotes and Greetings</h1><p><strong>Date: January 14, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Indian Express</strong></p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/happy-happy-Pongal.png?w=640" alt="Happy Pongal" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Happy Pongal 2025 Wishes Images: Share these best wishes and cards and put them on your WhatsApp status this Pongal!</figcaption><p>Pongal is a significant Hindu festival celebrated mainly in Tamil Nadu, marking the gratitude for agricultural prosperity. It lasts for four days, beginning on January 14, 2025.</p><ul><li>Pongal, a harvest festival, honors the Sun God.</li><li>Traditional dishes, including sweet rice (Pongal), are prepared to celebrate.</li><li>The festival encourages community bonding and gratitude.</li><li>Various wishes and messages can be shared across social media.</li></ul><blockquote>“May your year be as sweet as the sugarcane on Pongal!”</blockquote><p>In summary, Pongal 2025 is an occasion for celebration, joy, and community spirit, emphasizing love and gratitude.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/life-style/happy-pongal-2025-best-wishes-greetings-cards-whatsapp-status-9776403/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/life-style/happy-pongal-2025-best-wishes-greetings-cards-whatsapp-status-9776403/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Army General Upendra Dwivedi calls out Pakistan over terrorism, says no troop cuts at LAC - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Army General Upendra Dwivedi calls out Pakistan over terrorism, says no troop cuts at LAC</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/Army-1_1736816576573_1736816592534.jpg" alt="Army Chief General Upendra Dwivedi during a press conference in New Delhi, India, on Monday, January 13.(Hindustan Times)" title="Army Chief General Upendra Dwivedi during a press conference in New Delhi, India, on Monday, January 13.(Hindustan Times)">
<figcaption>Army Chief General Upendra Dwivedi during a press conference in New Delhi, India, on Monday, January 13.(Hindustan Times)</figcaption>
<p>In a recent press conference, Indian Army chief General Upendra Dwivedi labeled Pakistan as the “epicentre” of terrorism, adding that a significant percentage of active militants in Jammu and Kashmir are of Pakistani origin. He emphasized that troop levels along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) will not be reduced this winter.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gen Dwivedi stated that 80% of terrorists in Jammu and Kashmir are from Pakistan.</li>
  <li>The Army has received emergency procurement powers for counter-terror operations amidst increasing infiltration attempts from Pakistan.</li>
  <li>There has been a rise in terrorist activities particularly in North Kashmir and the Doda-Kishtwar region.</li>
  <li>Despite the escalation in attacks, the 2021 ceasefire agreement with Pakistan remains intact.</li>
  <li>The situation with China at the LAC is described as sensitive but stable, with no troop cuts planned.</li>
  <li>Trust-building measures are ongoing, and troop deployment reviews can happen before summer.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In recent months, increased terrorist activities were seen in North Kashmir. Last year, 60% of the terrorists eliminated were of Pakistan origin.” - General Upendra Dwivedi</blockquote>
<p>The emphasis on a balanced military deployment along the LAC suggests a proactive stance by the Indian Army, maintaining readiness for any potential conflict while also addressing the challenges posed by terrorism.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/what-gen-upendra-dwivedi-said-on-pakistan-and-china-ahead-of-army-day-celebrations-101736814448790.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/what-gen-upendra-dwivedi-said-on-pakistan-and-china-ahead-of-army-day-celebrations-101736814448790.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 02:11:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy Magh Bihu 2025: Bhogali Bihu Wishes, Images, Messages, WhatsApp & Facebook Status - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Happy Magh Bihu 2025: Celebrations and Best Wishes</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Happy Bhogali Bihu 2025" title="Happy Bhogali Bihu 2025"><figcaption>Happy Bhogali Bihu 2025: Wishes, Images, and Messages to Share. (Image: Shutterstock)</figcaption></figure><p>This article celebrates Magh Bihu, also known as Bhogali Bihu, a harvest festival observed in Assam that highlights community, abundance, and gratitude. The festivities for this year are set for January 15, with the Sankranti Moment occurring on January 14 at 09:03 AM.</p><ul><li>Magh Bihu is a traditional Assamese harvest festival.</li><li>The festival brings people together through feasting and cultural practices.</li><li>Emphasis on the abundance of nature and community spirit.</li><li>Popular wishes include hopes for happiness, prosperity, and good health.</li><li>The importance of lighting Meji and enjoying traditional foods is highlighted.</li></ul><blockquote>“This Magh Bihu, I hope that you burn all the negativity of your life in the bonfire and welcome positive vibes.”</blockquote><p>Magh Bihu is a time for celebration, reflection, and community bonding, marking the end of the harvest season with joy and gratitude.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/happy-magh-bihu-2025-wishes-images-messages-sms-greetings-whatsapp-facebook-status-9182155.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/lifestyle/happy-magh-bihu-2025-wishes-images-messages-sms-greetings-whatsapp-facebook-status-9182155.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:45:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mahakumbh 2025: Over 1 crore take dip in Sangam on Day 1; first ‘Amrit Snan’ today as millions gather on Makar Sankranti - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mahakumbh Mela 2025 kicked off with an attendance of over 1 crore devotees taking a holy dip at Sangam.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/INDIA-RELIGION-HINDUISM-FESTIVAL-KUMBH-20_1736815297570_1736815312158.jpg" alt="pilgrims watch and cheer as Naga Sadhus or Hindu holy men take part in a procession before taking a dip in Sangam, the confluence of Ganges, Yamuna and Saraswati rivers, during Shahi Snan or 'royal bath', to mark the Maha Kumbh Mela festival, in Prayagraj on January 14, 2025. (AFP)" title="pilgrims watch and cheer as Naga Sadhus or Hindu holy men take part in a procession before taking a dip in Sangam, the confluence of Ganges, Yamuna and Saraswati rivers, during Shahi Snan or 'royal bath', to mark the Maha Kumbh Mela festival, in Prayagraj on January 14, 2025. (AFP)"><figcaption>pilgrims watch and cheer as Naga Sadhus or Hindu holy men take part in a procession before taking a dip in Sangam, the confluence of Ganges, Yamuna and Saraswati rivers, during Shahi Snan or 'royal bath', to mark the Maha Kumbh Mela festival, in Prayagraj on January 14, 2025. (AFP)</figcaption><p>A day after over 1 crore people took a dip in the sacred Sangam, a record number of devotees are expected to participate in the first ‘Amrit Snan’ today, January 14, during the Makar Sankranti festival in Prayagraj.</p><ul><li>The first Amrit Snan of Mahakumbh is scheduled to begin at 5.30am, following a major dip on Monday.</li><li>Akhara participation is significant, with high-profile seers and Naga Sadhus attending.</li><li>Authorities have made extensive preparations for this 45-day religious event, including sanitation and security measures.</li><li>Over 10,000 police personnel have been deployed to ensure safety for the millions attending.</li></ul><blockquote>“Nine police teams will take all 13 akhadas to take holy dip, one after another - and it will continue till evening.” - DIG Vaibhav Krishna</blockquote><p>The Mahakumbh 2025 is anticipated to draw enormous crowds and is a vital spiritual event marking this unique occasion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-2025-over-1-crore-take-holy-dip-in-sangam-first-amrit-snan-today-as-millions-gather-on-makar-sankranti-101736813425800.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/mahakumbh-2025-over-1-crore-take-holy-dip-in-sangam-first-amrit-snan-today-as-millions-gather-on-makar-sankranti-101736813425800.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:43:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy Pongal 2025: Wishes, images, status, quotes, messages, greetings, and photos to share - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Happy Pongal 2025: Wishes, Images, Status, Quotes, Messages, Greetings Card, and Photos to share</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/happy-happy-Pongal-2.png?w=640" alt="Happy Pongal" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Happy Pongal 2025 wishes and greetings to share.</figcaption>
<p>Pongal is a major Hindu festival celebrated in South India, particularly Tamil Nadu, recognizing the significance of agricultural prosperity and the Sun God.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Pongal will be celebrated from January 14 to January 17, 2025.</li>
    <li>The festival is marked by gatherings, traditional decorations, and sharing of wishes and greetings.</li>
    <li>Best wishes, quotes, and greeting cards for Pongal have been compiled for sharing with family and friends.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Wishing you a Pongal that is filled with moments of joy, laughter, and togetherness.”</blockquote>
<p>The festival fosters community and appreciation among families, celebrating joyful moments and shared agricultural heritage.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/life-style/happy-pongal-2025-wishes-images-status-quotes-cards-9776167/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/life-style/happy-pongal-2025-wishes-images-status-quotes-cards-9776167/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Army chief backs women officers after Lt General criticised their performance - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Army Chief Supports Women Officers Amid Criticism</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://example.com/path-to-image.jpg" alt="Women Officers" /><figcaption>Women officers in the army demonstrating leadership.</figcaption><p>The Army Chief has come forward to endorse women officers following criticisms regarding their performance made by Lt General. This shows a shift in support for gender equality within military ranks.</p><ul><li>The Army Chief emphasized the importance of women in military roles.</li><li>Lt General's comments sparked a debate about gender equality in the armed forces.</li><li>The army's stance is shifting towards greater inclusivity.</li></ul><blockquote>“Women officers are integral to our operations and performance.” - Army Chief</blockquote><p>This endorsement is expected to enhance support for women in military roles and may lead to policy changes regarding their responsibilities and opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/army-chief-backs-women-officers-after-lt-general-criticised-their-performance/articleshow/117217331.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/army-chief-backs-women-officers-after-lt-general-criticised-their-performance/articleshow/117217331.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nag Mark 2 aces field trial: Top 5 insights from India's anti-tank missile - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nag Mark 2 aces field trial: Top 5 insights from India's anti-tank missile</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 14, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/ANI-20250113443-0_1736801160473_1736801168471.jpg" alt="DRDO conducted a successful field evaluation trial of the Nag Mark 2 anti-tank guided missile in the Pokharan firing ranges, in Jaisalmer on Monday.(ANI )" title="DRDO conducted a successful field evaluation trial of the Nag Mark 2 anti-tank guided missile in the Pokharan firing ranges, in Jaisalmer on Monday.(ANI )"><figcaption>DRDO conducted a successful field evaluation trial of the Nag Mark 2 anti-tank guided missile in the Pokharan firing ranges, in Jaisalmer on Monday.(ANI )</figcaption><p>The Defence Research and Development Organisation (DRDO) successfully conducted field evaluations of the Nag Mark 2 missile, which is now ready for induction into the Indian Army.</p><ul><li>Nag Mark 2 is a third-generation fire-and-forget anti-tank guided missile.</li><li>The trials validated the missile's firing range, as it successfully destroyed all designated targets.</li><li>The Nag Mark 2 features advanced technology for increased accuracy in complex environments.</li><li>It is designed to neutralise modern armoured threats, including those with explosive reactive armour.</li><li>The successful trials were acknowledged by Defence Minister Rajnath Singh, emphasizing the collaboration between DRDO and the Indian Army.</li></ul><blockquote>"Field Evaluation Trials of indigenously developed Nag Mk 2... were successfully flight tested at Pokhran Field Range." - Rajnath Singh</blockquote><p>The successful trials of Nag Mark 2 represent a significant advancement in India's defense capabilities, affirming the country's commitment to enhancing its military technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/nag-mark-2-aces-field-trials-5-things-to-know-about-indias-homegrown-anti-tank-missile-101736800653636.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/nag-mark-2-aces-field-trials-5-things-to-know-about-indias-homegrown-anti-tank-missile-101736800653636.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 20:52:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India, China still locked in ‘degree of standoff’: Army chief Gen Upendra Dwivedi - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India and China Maintain Standoff, Army Chief Advocates Diplomacy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Monday, January 8, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Army Press Conference</p><p>General Upendra Dwivedi states India and China are in a continued standoff, calling for renewed diplomatic efforts to rebuild trust.</p><ul><li>General Dwivedi highlighted the need for a new definition of trust between India and China.</li><li>Diplomatic negotiations are being prioritized to resolve ongoing tensions.</li><li>The Army chief acknowledged both nations have made alterations to their territorial positions since April 2020.</li><li>Decision-making authority has been devolved to corps commanders to address minor issues promptly.</li><li>The situation in Eastern Ladakh remains stable but sensitive, according to General Dwivedi.</li></ul><blockquote>“The trust between the two countries has to have a new definition.” - General Upendra Dwivedi</blockquote><p>The Indian Army continues to navigate the complexities of the India-China standoff, emphasizing the importance of cooperation and gradual progress through diplomatic channels.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/army-chief-lac-jammu-kashmir-situation-stable-9776048/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/army-chief-lac-jammu-kashmir-situation-stable-9776048/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 20:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Budget 2025: Revised Income Tax Slabs, Higher Standard Deduction, Section 80C Limit Increase – Know Key Exp - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Budget 2025: Key Expected Changes in Income Tax</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Budget 2025: In the upcoming budget, the government is likely to provide income tax relief."><figcaption>Budget 2025: In the upcoming budget, the government is likely to provide income tax relief.</figcaption></figure><p>This article outlines five major changes anticipated in the upcoming Budget 2025 concerning income tax reforms that could affect salaried individuals.</p><ul><li><strong>Increase in Standard Deduction:</strong> The standard deduction may be raised to a maximum of ₹1 lakh to support higher earners amid rising costs.</li><li><strong>Revised Income Tax Slabs:</strong> Expected updates to the tax slabs may include a 30% tax rate for incomes above ₹20 lakh.</li><li><strong>Tax Reforms for Senior Citizens:</strong> Consideration for raising the exemption limit and reducing tax rates for senior citizens.</li><li><strong>Increase in Section 80C Deduction Limit:</strong> Suggested increase to ₹3.5 lakh to address financial pressures on taxpayers.</li><li><strong>Possible Import Duty Hike on Gold:</strong> An anticipated increase in import tax on gold to curb imports and address trade imbalances.</li></ul><blockquote>Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman will present the Union Budget 2025-26 on February 1.</blockquote><p>The upcoming budget is expected to bring crucial reforms that could significantly impact taxpayers and the economy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/business/tax/budget-2025-revised-income-tax-slabs-higher-standard-deduction-section-80c-limit-increase-know-key-expectations-9186868.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/business/tax/budget-2025-revised-income-tax-slabs-higher-standard-deduction-section-80c-limit-increase-know-key-expectations-9186868.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:44:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real India is at Maha Kumbh, say visitors from abroad - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Real India is at Maha Kumbh, say visitors from abroad</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>This article showcases the experiences and impressions of foreign visitors attending the Maha Kumbh Mela, highlighting their perspective on Indian culture, spirituality, and the significance of the event.</p><ul><li>Foreign visitors share their insights about the cultural richness of India.</li><li>The Maha Kumbh Mela is depicted as a pivotal spiritual gathering.</li><li>Participants express awe at the scale and organization of the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is the real India that we came to witness.”</blockquote><p>The Maha Kumbh Mela not only showcases India's rich spiritual heritage but also attracts global attention, reinforcing the cultural dialogue between nations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/real-india-is-at-maha-kumbh-say-visitors-from-abroad/articleshow/117214633.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/real-india-is-at-maha-kumbh-say-visitors-from-abroad/articleshow/117214633.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1.7cr devotees brave cold, freezing water to take holy dip as Maha Kumbh begins - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>1.7 crore devotees brave cold for holy dip as Maha Kumbh begins</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>On this auspicious day, 1.7 crore devotees have gathered to take a holy dip in freezing waters as the Maha Kumbh Mela kicks off. Despite the severe cold, the enthusiasm among the devotees is palpable as they partake in this spiritual event.</p><ul><li>The Maha Kumbh Mela has attracted millions of participants.</li><li>Devotees traveled from across the country to attend.</li><li>Authorities have made extensive arrangements for safety and convenience.</li><li>Various cultural and religious activities are scheduled throughout the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a moment of deep faith and connection to spirituality,” said a participant.</blockquote><p>The Maha Kumbh Mela, a significant religious gathering, showcases the enduring spirit of faith among millions, transcending the challenges posed by the elements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/1-7cr-devotees-brave-cold-freezing-water-to-take-holy-dip-as-maha-kumbh-begins/articleshow/117214550.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/1-7cr-devotees-brave-cold-freezing-water-to-take-holy-dip-as-maha-kumbh-begins/articleshow/117214550.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘End Unequal Understanding On Border Issues’: India To Bangladesh Envoy - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Urges Bangladesh to Resolve Border Understanding Discrepancies</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Border Security Force (BSF) soldiers patrol along the fencing of the India-Bangladesh international border on the outskirts of Agartala, capital of Tripura, India. (IMAGE: REUTERS)" /><figcaption>Border Security Force (BSF) soldiers patrol along the fencing of the India-Bangladesh international border on the outskirts of Agartala, capital of Tripura, India. (IMAGE: REUTERS)</figcaption><p>India has called for clarity and cooperation regarding border security measures during a meeting with a Bangladeshi envoy. This follows a recent tension over fencing and security agreements along the border.</p><ul><li>India summoned Bangladesh's deputy high commissioner due to ongoing border tensions.</li><li>Both countries are discussing border security protocols and the issue of illegal crossings.</li><li>Bangladesh expressed concerns over India's fencing activities which they argue violate bilateral agreements.</li><li>India is committed to preventing cross-border crimes through enhanced security measures, including fencing.</li><li>Officials from both sides have previously accused each other of unauthorized actions along the border.</li></ul><blockquote>“India observed all protocols while putting fencing,” source stated.</blockquote><p>Both nations need to collaborate effectively to address border security challenges while ensuring peace and cooperation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/india-summons-bangladesh-deputy-high-commissioner-over-border-fencing-row-9187159.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/india-summons-bangladesh-deputy-high-commissioner-over-border-fencing-row-9187159.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:37:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Makar Sankranti 2025: 60+ Heartfelt Quotes, Images, and Statuses for Celebrations - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Makar Sankranti 2025: 60+ Heartfelt Quotes, Images, and Statuses for Celebrations</h1><p><strong>Date: January 14, 2025</strong> / <strong>Source: Moneycontrol</strong></p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250113180822_makar.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Makar Sankranti 2025: 60+ Heartfelt Quotes, Images, and Statuses for Celebrations"><figcaption>Makar Sankranti 2025 Celebration Image</figcaption><p>Makar Sankranti is a widely celebrated festival that marks the transition of the sun into Capricorn, symbolizing positivity, hope, and new beginnings. Observed with great enthusiasm across India, the festival unites people through cultural traditions, kite flying, and delicious delicacies.</p><ul><li>Over 60 heartfelt quotes and messages for Makar Sankranti.</li><li>Encourages sharing joy and prosperity with loved ones.</li><li>Brings together traditions of kite flying and festive foods.</li><li>Celebrates new beginnings and cultural significance.</li><li>Promotes warmth, hope, and happiness during the harvest festival.</li></ul><blockquote>Let the festive spirit inspire you to spread love and kindness.</blockquote><p>This Makar Sankranti, let's cherish togetherness and the beauty of traditions while embracing new opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/religion/makar-sankranti-2025-60-heartfelt-quotes-images-and-statuses-for-celebrations-article-12909657.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/religion/makar-sankranti-2025-60-heartfelt-quotes-images-and-statuses-for-celebrations-article-12909657.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:30:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy Makar Sankranti 2025: Wishes, messages, images, WhatsApp and Facebook status to share with loved ones - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Happy Makar Sankranti 2025: Wishes, Messages, Images, WhatsApp and Facebook Status to Share with Loved Ones</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> India TV</p><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/happy-makar-1736780073.webp" alt="Happy Makar Sankranti 2025: Wishes and images"><figcaption>Happy Makar Sankranti 2025: Wishes and images</figcaption><p>Makar Sankranti celebrates the sun's transition into Capricorn and represents new beginnings, prosperity, and thankfulness. People across India celebrate this festival under various names, bringing together unique traditions and a spirit of togetherness.</p><p>This article provides a collection of wishes, messages, and images for sharing via social media, making the festival even more memorable.</p><h3><strong>Happy Makar Sankranti 2025: Wishes and Messages</strong></h3><ul><li>Let’s welcome this Makar Sankranti with open arms and a heart full of gratitude.</li><li>May the blessings of the harvest season bring you happiness and prosperity.</li><li>Celebrate the spirit of gratitude and hope this Makar Sankranti.</li><li>Wishing you a bountiful harvest of love, happiness, and good fortune this Makar Sankranti!</li><li>Let the spirit of Makar Sankranti fill your heart with joy and your life with positivity!</li><li>On this Makar Sankranti, may you soar to new heights like the kites in the sky.</li></ul><h3><strong>Happy Makar Sankranti 2025: WhatsApp and Facebook Status</strong></h3><ul><li>Makar Sankranti reminds us to rise above challenges, just like the sun rises to mark a new journey.</li><li>Let this Sankranti be the beginning of success and endless opportunities for you.</li><li>Just like the sun transitions to Capricorn, let’s transition to new opportunities and brighter days.</li><li>Wishing you a prosperous year ahead, full of new beginnings and opportunities.</li><li>Makar Sankranti is here! Let’s celebrate the festival of new beginnings and endless blessings.</li><li>Let’s welcome new beginnings and bid farewell to the past with a smile. Happy Makar Sankranti!</li></ul><p><strong>ALSO READ:</strong> <a href="https://www.indiatvnews.com/lifestyle/food/makar-sankranti-2025-from-khichdi-to-undhiyu-must-try-traditional-dishes-for-a-festive-feast-2025-01-13-971045" target="_blank">Makar Sankranti 2025: From Khichdi to Undhiyu, must-try traditional dishes for a festive feast</a></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/lifestyle/news/happy-makar-sankranti-2025-wishes-messages-images-whatsapp-and-facebook-status-to-share-with-loved-ones-2025-01-13-971095</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/lifestyle/news/happy-makar-sankranti-2025-wishes-messages-images-whatsapp-and-facebook-status-to-share-with-loved-ones-2025-01-13-971095</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:19:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['You kept your word': J&K CM Omar Abdullah thanks PM Modi for timely elections - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘You kept your word’: J&K CM Omar Abdullah thanks PM Modi for timely elections</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>Omar Abdullah, the Chief Minister of Jammu and Kashmir, publicly thanked Prime Minister Narendra Modi for holding elections in the region as promised. This gesture is seen as vital for restoring democratic processes in J&K.</p><ul><li>Abdullah expressed gratitude during a public address, highlighting the importance of timely elections.</li><li>He stressed the need for renewed political engagement in the region.</li><li>The elections are aimed at reinforcing local governance and community involvement.</li></ul><blockquote>“Your commitment to democracy has been reaffirmed with these timely elections.” - Omar Abdullah</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Abdullah's appreciation reflects a significant step towards empowering local governance in Jammu and Kashmir and restoring faith in the political process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/you-kept-your-words-jk-cm-omar-abdullah-thanks-pm-modi-for-timely-elections-z-morh-tunnel-inauguration/articleshow/117198404.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/you-kept-your-words-jk-cm-omar-abdullah-thanks-pm-modi-for-timely-elections-z-morh-tunnel-inauguration/articleshow/117198404.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Army chief rules out any troop cut along LAC, trust deficit & a 'degree of standoff' persists - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Army chief rules out any troop cut along LAC, trust deficit & a 'degree of standoff' persists</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='Army Chief' /><figcaption>Army Chief addressing media.</figcaption><p>The Indian Army chief has stated that there will be no reduction of troops along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) with China, emphasizing that a degree of standoff remains due to ongoing trust issues.</p><ul><li>Troop levels along the LAC will remain unchanged.</li><li>Trust deficit between India and China continues to affect relations.</li><li>Strategic military presence is crucial for national security.</li></ul><blockquote>"The situation at the LAC requires continued vigilance and preparedness from our forces."</blockquote><p>This decision reinforces India's stance on maintaining a strong defensive posture amidst uncertain geopolitical dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/army-chief-rules-out-any-troop-cut-along-lac-trust-deficit-a-degree-of-standoff-persists/articleshow/117213009.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/army-chief-rules-out-any-troop-cut-along-lac-trust-deficit-a-degree-of-standoff-persists/articleshow/117213009.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi-Omar Abdullah bonhomie to an absent NC MP: 5 takeaways from Z-Morh tunnel inauguration in Sonamarg - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Key Highlights from the Inauguration of the Sonamarg Tunnel</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Monday<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/modi-tunnel.jpg" alt="Modi Z-Morh Tunnel" width="1600" height="900">
<figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the inauguration of the Z-Morh tunnel in J&amp;K. (PTI)</figcaption>
<p>The recent inauguration of the Sonamarg tunnel marked a moment of unity between Prime Minister Modi and Chief Minister Omar Abdullah, showcasing infrastructure developments and political dynamics in Jammu and Kashmir.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Modi and Abdullah displayed camaraderie during the tunnel's inauguration.</li>
  <li>Abdullah emphasized growing trust in Modi's promises among the people of Jammu and Kashmir.</li>
  <li>Modi praised Abdullah's initiatives, including participation in community events like marathons.</li>
  <li>Union Minister Gadkari highlighted the infrastructural push affecting connectivity and security.</li>
  <li>The absence of Srinagar MP Aga Ruhullah Mehdi raised questions about internal party dynamics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Everything has a time; the right things will happen at the right time.” - PM Modi</blockquote>
<p>The inauguration highlights the ongoing dialogue and relationship between local leadership and the central government, reflecting a pivotal moment in the region's political landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/pm-modi-omar-abdullah-bonhomie-z-morh-tunnel-9777044/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/pm-modi-omar-abdullah-bonhomie-z-morh-tunnel-9777044/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rahul fighting to save Cong, Im fighting for country: Kejriwal - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxNVFNIa21sZ09kTVdlVElJWWRrcmV3N3FkX1BFQ3BLbWhkWGlUaHRzSWJwdVRnMU9adDJKRE5RN3RTSWNSeERDTzhDYUtobDUyWFdiN2J2ZUZvRk0zcDdybUo2NC10QmpWVy1rUGh0OFVFYVBqeHZ6VHFZXzRQWFFzNEZXb2Y3eHhiUTFfN1RESWs4R1JMLXNtc0R3VkVyMC1XVkww0gGnAUFVX3lxTE5qMmhWaTd1UG1QZkNtQWRYSnNXblc3WHQwV2hIS01Qa2tLM0V0TExqWVNyeXNDSzJrNkFXQm1PbTBnaVkzMzFteFR0NE5RT0xXVVFvNnFYM0FLT1V2bl9VQ1h3YktlMFVLWDlFTFFJZVhCeXhlVmRUck5OazBsOVVqekhIc0RNRXVQelhUT2VmRVJmMTdjcUt1WVJWWDBjZE8tUGF4c1hB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxNVFNIa21sZ09kTVdlVElJWWRrcmV3N3FkX1BFQ3BLbWhkWGlUaHRzSWJwdVRnMU9adDJKRE5RN3RTSWNSeERDTzhDYUtobDUyWFdiN2J2ZUZvRk0zcDdybUo2NC10QmpWVy1rUGh0OFVFYVBqeHZ6VHFZXzRQWFFzNEZXb2Y3eHhiUTFfN1RESWs4R1JMLXNtc0R3VkVyMC1XVkww0gGnAUFVX3lxTE5qMmhWaTd1UG1QZkNtQWRYSnNXblc3WHQwV2hIS01Qa2tLM0V0TExqWVNyeXNDSzJrNkFXQm1PbTBnaVkzMzFteFR0NE5RT0xXVVFvNnFYM0FLT1V2bl9VQ1h3YktlMFVLWDlFTFFJZVhCeXhlVmRUck5OazBsOVVqekhIc0RNRXVQelhUT2VmRVJmMTdjcUt1WVJWWDBjZE8tUGF4c1hB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:37:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[National Conference mobilises local people to attend PM Modi rally in Kashmir - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>National Conference Mobilizes Locals for PM Modi's Rally in Kashmir</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/a0c7qp/article69097245.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI01_13_2025_000322B.jpg" alt="Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah greets Prime Minister Narendra Modi during a public meeting at Sonamarg in J&K’s Ganderbal district on January 13, 2025. Photo: PMO via PTI" />
<figcaption>Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah greets Prime Minister Narendra Modi during a public meeting at Sonamarg in J&K’s Ganderbal district on January 13, 2025. Photo: PMO via PTI</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi addressed a public function in Kashmir after the inauguration of the Z-Morh tunnel, with over 5,000 locals attending despite harsh weather conditions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Unlike previous events, government employees were not instructed to attend; over 5,000 local residents showed up.</li>
  <li>Locals traveled from far-off areas, demonstrating enthusiasm to hear Modi speak.</li>
  <li>MLA Mian Mehar Ali stated that locals were prepared for the Prime Minister's visit for days.</li>
  <li>MLA Ali expressed disappointment over the lack of announcement regarding the restoration of Statehood for J&K.</li>
  <li>Residents expect the new tunnel to significantly benefit the local community, particularly in tourism.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We pressed around 500 vehicles to ferry locals from far-off and snow-bound villages. People were eager to listen to what the PM had to offer.” – MLA Mian Mehar Ali</blockquote>
<p>This event marked a shift from previous rallies, showing local enthusiasm and the anticipation surrounding infrastructure developments in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/jammu-and-kashmir/nc-mobilises-locals-to-attend-pm-rally-in-kashmir/article69096536.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/jammu-and-kashmir/nc-mobilises-locals-to-attend-pm-rally-in-kashmir/article69096536.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll Officer Responds To AAP's Voter List Manipulation Charge In Delhi - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxQX0ZqQlJnMUx6b3I3QzFpNzRJclJQSF9xMDZoeTUyZUJXR2ZDaHlpWGVwZG0wZ1hMUmduNTBuOWpuMnZGQXN0ZzcwX0pzTlZVVDN2Z3JtX1ZNZ3ZRdWlaN0RxY0dPNGVNVkNYeWZZaEpZdmQzTmd5SExxUmFCa05tTzVYZWN2ZExlczRZOHhXazRnQ1NMS2tIVndpQ0JQVDZzSHJmZnNRX0dnN2NRTWR2aUFYbVJsaS15LXJhdWJGcGl2VzVzemxsQllsVnFlX09vZ0NHSGtsRTk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxQX0ZqQlJnMUx6b3I3QzFpNzRJclJQSF9xMDZoeTUyZUJXR2ZDaHlpWGVwZG0wZ1hMUmduNTBuOWpuMnZGQXN0ZzcwX0pzTlZVVDN2Z3JtX1ZNZ3ZRdWlaN0RxY0dPNGVNVkNYeWZZaEpZdmQzTmd5SExxUmFCa05tTzVYZWN2ZExlczRZOHhXazRnQ1NMS2tIVndpQ0JQVDZzSHJmZnNRX0dnN2NRTWR2aUFYbVJsaS15LXJhdWJGcGl2VzVzemxsQllsVnFlX09vZ0NHSGtsRTk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:21:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Party bigger than govt: Congress tells Karnataka leaders amid camp war - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress Leaders Warned Against Indiscipline Amid Political Tensions in Karnataka</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 13 January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In a recent meeting, Congress leaders were cautioned by the party's general secretary regarding indiscipline, as political tensions rise between Karnataka’s Chief Minister Siddaramaiah and his deputy DK Shivakumar.</p><ul><li>The Congress high command warned its Karnataka leaders against disruptive behaviors and emphasized that the party is more important than the government.</li><li>General secretary Randeep Singh Surjewala addressed a general body meeting, stating that indiscipline would not be tolerated.</li><li>Surjewala indicated that caste-based conventions would only be allowed if formally organized under the party.</li><li>Senior ministers G Parameshwara and KN Rajanna did not attend the meeting, indicating their protest against Surjewala's remarks.</li><li>Surjewala criticized the BJP for attempting to undermine Congress's initiatives.</li><li>Plans for expanding Congress's presence in Karnataka include the opening of 100 Gandhi Bharat offices.</li></ul><blockquote>“The party is the mother and the government its child. Some of our leaders aren’t disciplined. None should bulldoze the party.” - Randeep Singh Surjewala</blockquote><p>This meeting underscores the ongoing internal struggles within the Congress party in Karnataka and the critical balance of power as the party navigates its leadership dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/party-bigger-than-govt-congress-tells-karnataka-leaders-amid-camp-war-3353603</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/karnataka/party-bigger-than-govt-congress-tells-karnataka-leaders-amid-camp-war-3353603</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:14:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal vs Rahul Gandhi in Delhi: 'Fighting to save Congress' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arvind Kejriwal vs Rahul Gandhi in Delhi: 'Fighting to save Congress'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/PTI01-12-2025-000116B-0_1736784835325_1736784845328.jpg" alt="Former Delhi CM and AAP national convener Arvind Kejriwal(PTI file photo)" title="Former Delhi CM and AAP national convener Arvind Kejriwal(PTI file photo)">
<figcaption>Former Delhi CM and AAP national convener Arvind Kejriwal(PTI file photo)</figcaption>
<p>Aam Aadmi Party chief Arvind Kejriwal recently responded to Rahul Gandhi's comments, asserting that Gandhi's focus is on preserving the Congress party rather than addressing national issues.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kejriwal claimed that Gandhi's fight is about saving Congress, while his own fight is for the country.</li>
  <li>Rahul Gandhi criticized Kejriwal, stating that he campaigns similarly to Prime Minister Modi, making false promises.</li>
  <li>Gandhi accused Kejriwal of failing to eliminate corruption in Delhi, despite his promises.</li>
  <li>He highlighted issues such as inflation and the lack of support for backward communities and minorities, linking this to both Modi and Kejriwal.</li>
  <li>The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled for February 5, with results on February 8.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Inflation is at its peak. Poor people are becoming poorer and rich people are becoming richer.” - Rahul Gandhi</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing political rivalry highlights significant concerns regarding governance, promises made by political leaders, and the upcoming elections in Delhi.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/arvind-kejriwal-vs-rahul-gandhi-in-delhi-fight-to-save-congress-101736784138554.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/arvind-kejriwal-vs-rahul-gandhi-in-delhi-fight-to-save-congress-101736784138554.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:14:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pathanamthitta sexual abuse case: 42 arrested in 29 cases across 4 police stations - Onmanorama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQTkkydWlUbTFUVHdnODh1NDIyQVRJc1RuVFRhREJRQXVPR2hpQlVkdlduV3AxRVdIMVAydU1xRXNRcWhuV243QjFncHBiV0FDenc5eGVXY3NsdzZ5QmQtWmxrWW1QRVlhZm9sN3dsQU9yN2NqOTYycWRSMUx1S3I4UU0tRlp4b0w1TGtnV3AtUC1ub1NaWTdubnJOM0xBWXZMb0NSeF82TXBjbGQ0TWZyRHpSdFE5UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQTkkydWlUbTFUVHdnODh1NDIyQVRJc1RuVFRhREJRQXVPR2hpQlVkdlduV3AxRVdIMVAydU1xRXNRcWhuV243QjFncHBiV0FDenc5eGVXY3NsdzZ5QmQtWmxrWW1QRVlhZm9sN3dsQU9yN2NqOTYycWRSMUx1S3I4UU0tRlp4b0w1TGtnV3AtUC1ub1NaWTdubnJOM0xBWXZMb0NSeF82TXBjbGQ0TWZyRHpSdFE5UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘PM Modi, Kejriwal failed to reduce inflation': Rahul Gandhi at Delhi rally - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘PM Modi, Kejriwal failed to reduce inflation': Rahul Gandhi at Delhi rally</h1><p><strong>Date: January 13, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/Rahul_Gandhi__1736780042946_1736780043179.jpeg" alt="Leader of the Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi addresses the “Jai Bapu, Jai Bhim, Jai Samvidhan’ public meeting at Zero Pushta, in Seelampur area ahead of the Delhi Assembly elections. (Raj K Raj/HT Photo)" title="Leader of the Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi addresses the “Jai Bapu, Jai Bhim, Jai Samvidhan’ public meeting at Zero Pushta, in Seelampur area ahead of the Delhi Assembly elections. (Raj K Raj/HT Photo)"><figcaption>Leader of the Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi addresses the “Jai Bapu, Jai Bhim, Jai Samvidhan’ public meeting at Zero Pushta, in Seelampur area ahead of the Delhi Assembly elections. (Raj K Raj/HT Photo)</figcaption><p>Rahul Gandhi, Leader of the Opposition in the Lok Sabha, accused PM Narendra Modi and AAP leader Arvind Kejriwal of failing to address rising inflation during a rally in Delhi.</p><ul><li>Gandhi stated that inflation is at its peak, adversely affecting the poor.</li><li>He criticized Modi's relationship with industrialists Ambani and Adani, calling for a more equitable society.</li><li>Gandhi emphasized the need to protect the Constitution from perceived threats posed by the BJP and RSS.</li><li>Both the Congress and AAP are contesting upcoming Delhi elections separately.</li><li>The Delhi assembly elections are scheduled for February 5, with counting on February 8.</li></ul><blockquote>“Inflation is at its peak. Poor people are becoming poorer and rich people are becoming richer.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Gandhi’s remarks highlight significant discontent with current leadership's economic policies as both parties prepare for a competitive electoral battle.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-kejriwal-failed-to-reduce-inflation-rahul-gandhi-at-delhi-rally-101736779978313.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-kejriwal-failed-to-reduce-inflation-rahul-gandhi-at-delhi-rally-101736779978313.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi polls: Kejriwal claims shoes, jackets, spectacles distributed in Kidwai Nagar, moves EC - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Claims Shoes, Jackets, Spectacles Distributed in Kidwai Nagar, Moves EC</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/PTI01-13-2025-000403A-0_1736780989386_1736781021632.jpg" alt="AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal, Punjab CM Bhagwat Mann, AAP MP Sanjay Singh and leader Awadh Ojha leave the Election Commission office.(PTI)" /><figcaption>AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal, Punjab CM Bhagwant Mann, AAP MP Sanjay Singh and leader Awadh Ojha leave the Election Commission office.(PTI)</figcaption><p>Arvind Kejriwal, chief of the Aam Aadmi Party, has made serious allegations about the distribution of goods intended to influence voters in Delhi's Kidwai Nagar. He reported these claims to the Election Commission (EC) and called for the suspension of local authorities involved.</p><ul><li>Kejriwal accused some politicians of distributing items including blankets, shoes, jackets, and spectacles to sway voters.</li><li>He demanded action against the local district magistrate for allegedly turning a blind eye to the activities.</li><li>The Election Commission has assured Kejriwal that such distributions will be stopped.</li><li>Concerns were raised regarding rival candidate Parvesh Verma's alleged distribution of money to voters.</li><li>Delhi Assembly polls are set for February 5, with vote counting on February 8.</li></ul><blockquote>“Yesterday, blankets were distributed in Kidwai Nagar, shoes, jackets were distributed, money was distributed, spectacles were distributed. ... We requested that the DM should be suspended and this kind of activity should be stopped,” - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the ongoing concerns about election integrity as the Delhi Assembly polls approach.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-polls-kejriwal-claims-shoes-jackets-spectacles-distributed-in-kidwai-nagar-moves-ec-101736780799424.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-polls-kejriwal-claims-shoes-jackets-spectacles-distributed-in-kidwai-nagar-moves-ec-101736780799424.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:14:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pune Ranks 4th Globally for Average Travel Time, Traffic Congestion Remains a Major Concern - Punekar News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxNNzB5bmF0MHNEZ05TeTFpMTM4T182cnJtc1ZmS1pFY3hQeDZvTXlQZmxOYXRqMWQ3djRFMjU2ZFNVRHdXLWVhcWpxdFVDdUU1VFpqZllBcmxURVJQZ3JxYUlOVko0WG0zOXBmcnF6ajhIZm9pRlBZaHBULU5WOFBzd013dTk1clZZSmhlX19TdkY2MDFHa3plMkZRd0VmZ21INzB4V3lJN25BLWdyblFITExCa09lVWtxb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxNNzB5bmF0MHNEZ05TeTFpMTM4T182cnJtc1ZmS1pFY3hQeDZvTXlQZmxOYXRqMWQ3djRFMjU2ZFNVRHdXLWVhcWpxdFVDdUU1VFpqZllBcmxURVJQZ3JxYUlOVko0WG0zOXBmcnF6ajhIZm9pRlBZaHBULU5WOFBzd013dTk1clZZSmhlX19TdkY2MDFHa3plMkZRd0VmZ21INzB4V3lJN25BLWdyblFITExCa09lVWtxb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Megastar and Teja Sajja attend Sankranthi Celebrations at Kishan Reddy’s Residence - Telugu360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxQaGMyT1hRYVhuVmhERmNYdDdneWxueHl4bkJvbl9NRThjTVc4eDdBdU5WNnAyOE1sbjFxdkxtWnJNdUF0RnZRTld1b1JnTWo1dmxSTDM2Qnd0Uzd2eUFkazBzMGdDVy1tU2JRUDA0WWlucWJNci1TWHl4Slh0WDRNcEdXQ29aYXBidGJkd295QzFBOVlsOGV0RzhMcHF0d1RYTXEzUDk1cXlJR1No?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxQaGMyT1hRYVhuVmhERmNYdDdneWxueHl4bkJvbl9NRThjTVc4eDdBdU5WNnAyOE1sbjFxdkxtWnJNdUF0RnZRTld1b1JnTWo1dmxSTDM2Qnd0Uzd2eUFkazBzMGdDVy1tU2JRUDA0WWlucWJNci1TWHl4Slh0WDRNcEdXQ29aYXBidGJkd295QzFBOVlsOGV0RzhMcHF0d1RYTXEzUDk1cXlJR1No?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:41:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UGC-NET exam on January 15 postponed - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UGC-NET Exam on January 15 Postponed</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/wy655/article69082153.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_FL_-_UNIVERSITY_GRAN_2_1_H5DEMA51.jpg" alt="UGC-NET Postponement Photo" title="UGC-NET Postponement Photo"><figcaption>“Examination scheduled on 16th January 2025 will be conducted as per earlier schedule,” the NTA said. File | Photo Credit: The Hindu</figcaption><p>The National Testing Agency (NTA) has announced the postponement of the UGC-NET exam originally scheduled for January 15 due to the celebration of Pongal, Makar Sankranti, and other festivals.</p><ul><li>The new date for the exam will be announced later.</li><li>The decision was made following requests from students regarding the date coinciding with major festivals.</li><li>The exam is important for students seeking Junior Research Fellowships and Assistant Professor positions.</li></ul><blockquote>“We strongly urge the UGC to take into account the cultural and practical implications for students from these regions,” said SFI leaders.</blockquote><p>This postponement aims to accommodate the cultural significance of the festivals and facilitate better participation from students.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/education/nta-postpones-ugc-net-exam-on-january-15-due-to-festivals-new-date-to-be-announced-later/article69096525.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/education/nta-postpones-ugc-net-exam-on-january-15-due-to-festivals-new-date-to-be-announced-later/article69096525.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>