<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 14:16:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 14:16:18 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prashant Kishor reacts to ' ₹2 crore vanity van' charge at BPSC protest: 'To relieve myself...' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/prashant-kishor-reacts-to-rs-2-crore-vanity-van-charge-at-bpsc-protest-to-relieve-myself-101735996377006.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/prashant-kishor-reacts-to-rs-2-crore-vanity-van-charge-at-bpsc-protest-to-relieve-myself-101735996377006.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 13:24:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wife, her mother and brother get bail in case of abetting Bengaluru techie Atul Subhash's suicide - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru Techie Atul Subhash's Family Granted Bail in Suicide Case</h1><p><strong>Date: Today</strong> | <strong>Source: Bengaluru Court</strong></p><p>The wife and in-laws of Bengaluru techie Atul Subhash have been granted bail by a Bengaluru court in the abetment of suicide case against them following Subhash's suicide on December 9.</p><ul><li>Subhash's wife Nikita Singhania and her family were accused of harassment leading to his death.</li><li>They had previously appealed to the Karnataka High Court for expedited bail proceedings.</li><li>Subhash left a video and a detailed note accusing his wife and her relatives of torturing him.</li><li>Nikita was arrested in Gurugram; her family members were arrested in Prayagraj.</li><li>The parents of Subhash are seeking custody of their grandson.</li></ul><blockquote>“My son was broken from inside... His suicide note mentioned that his parents be given custody of his child,” said Pawan Kumar, Subhash's father.</blockquote><p>This case raises serious concerns about marital harassment and the mental health of individuals facing familial pressures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/wife-her-mother-and-brother-get-bail-in-case-of-abetting-bengaluru-techie-atul-subhashs-suicide-7399133</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/wife-her-mother-and-brother-get-bail-in-case-of-abetting-bengaluru-techie-atul-subhashs-suicide-7399133</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 12:58:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bengaluru Techie Atul Subhash's Wife, In-Laws Get Bail In Abetment Of Suicide Case - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bengaluru Court Grants Bail to Atul Subhash's Wife and In-Laws in Suicide Case</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today <strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>The wife and in-laws of Bengaluru techie Atul Subhash have been granted bail by a Bengaluru court in an abetment of suicide case.</p><ul><li>Atul Subhash died by suicide on December 9, citing harassment from his wife and her family.</li><li>His wife Nikita, her mother Nisha, and brother Anurag were granted bail after an appeal to the session court.</li><li>On December 14, the wife and in-laws were arrested in connection with the case.</li><li>Subhash left behind a video and note detailing harassment, extortion, and allegations against his wife and her relatives.</li><li>His parents are seeking custody of their four-year-old grandson, expressing concerns for his welfare.</li></ul><blockquote>“My son was broken from inside... His suicide note also mentioned that his parents be given custody of his child,” - Pawan Kumar, father of Atul Subhash.</blockquote><p>This case highlights the serious issues surrounding domestic violence and mental health, prompting public discussion on the responsibilities of family members in such scenarios.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/wife-her-mother-and-brother-get-bail-in-case-of-abetting-bengaluru-techie-atul-subhashs-suicide-7399133</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/wife-her-mother-and-brother-get-bail-in-case-of-abetting-bengaluru-techie-atul-subhashs-suicide-7399133</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 12:50:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kejriwal promises to waive 'inflated' water bills, if AAP wins Delhi polls - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kejriwal Promises to Waive 'Inflated' Water Bills If AAP Wins Delhi Polls</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><div><p>Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal has vowed to waive off what he calls 'inflated' water bills if the Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) retains power in the upcoming elections. This promise is part of the party's campaign strategy aimed at addressing the grievances of Delhi residents regarding high water charges.</p><ul><li>Kejriwal's assurance targets the issue of inflated water bills in Delhi.</li><li>The waiver proposal is positioned as a key aspect of AAP's electoral campaign.</li><li>The party aims to garner support from voters affected by rising utility costs.</li></ul><blockquote>“If AAP wins, we will cancel all unnecessary water charges and ensure that residents pay only for the actual water consumed,” stated Kejriwal.</blockquote><p>The AAP aims to strengthen its hold in the Delhi assembly by emphasizing issues of utility affordability and civic welfare.</p></div>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/kejriwal-promises-to-waive-inflated-water-bills-if-aap-wins-delhi-polls/articleshow/116941997.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/kejriwal-promises-to-waive-inflated-water-bills-if-aap-wins-delhi-polls/articleshow/116941997.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 12:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab Protesters At His Doors, Kejriwal Makes New Poll Promise & Big Claim On Congress, BJP 'Tie-Up' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/politics/arvind-kejriwal-news-congress-bjp-fighting-delhi-elections-2025-together-punjab-protest-9177091.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/politics/arvind-kejriwal-news-congress-bjp-fighting-delhi-elections-2025-together-punjab-protest-9177091.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 12:28:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shillong Teer Results Today, January 4, 2025 LIVE: Winning Numbers For Shillong Teer, Morning Teer, Juwai T - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shillong Teer Results Today, January 4, 2025 LIVE: Winning Numbers</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> <time>January 04, 2025</time> <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Shillong Teer is a legal archery-based lottery played in Meghalaya." title="Shillong Teer is a legal archery-based lottery played in Meghalaya."><figcaption>Shillong Teer is a legal archery-based lottery played in Meghalaya. (Image: Shutterstock)</figcaption></figure><p>The Shillong Teer lottery offers cash rewards and supports local archery sports. Live updates on the winning numbers for various games, including Shillong and Juwai Teers, can be found here.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Shillong Teer First Round Winning Number: 89</li><li>Shillong Teer Second Round Winning Number: 15</li><li>Khanapara Teer First Round Winning Number: 66</li><li>Khanapara Teer Second Round Winning Number: 23</li><li>Juwai Teer First Round Winning Number: 17</li><li>Juwai Teer Second Round Winning Number: 64</li><li>Shillong Morning Teer results available</li><li>Shillong Night Teer results pending</li></ul><blockquote>“Accurately predicting the first round with a Rs 1 bet earns Rs 80, while the same bet in the second round yields Rs 60.”</blockquote><p>This lottery not only provides financial rewards but also promotes archery in Meghalaya.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/shillong-teer-result-today-4-1-2025-first-and-second-round-lottery-result-check-winning-numbers-full-list-9175428.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/shillong-teer-result-today-4-1-2025-first-and-second-round-lottery-result-check-winning-numbers-full-list-9175428.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 12:24:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CISF jawan kills himself with service weapon at Surat International airport - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CISF Jawan Dies by Suicide at Surat International Airport</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 04, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src='https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ud5cn5/article69061278.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/WhatsApp%20Image%202025-01-04%20at%204.51.00%20PM.jpeg' alt='CISF jawan' /><figcaption>File image is used for representational purpose.</figcaption><p>A 32-year-old jawan from the Central Industrial Security Force (CISF) committed suicide at Surat International Airport by shooting himself with his service weapon. The incident occurred on January 4, 2025, around 2:10 PM.</p><ul><li>The deceased, identified as Kisan Singh, was from Jaipur and was on duty at the airport.</li><li>Police reported that he died in a washroom and was pronounced dead shortly after being taken to a hospital.</li><li>The motive behind the suicide is currently unknown and is under investigation.</li></ul><blockquote>The reason for the extreme step taken by the jawan was not immediately clear.</blockquote><p>This tragic event raises concerns regarding the mental health and well-being of personnel in high-stress roles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/gujarat/cisf-jawan-kills-himself-with-service-weapon-at-surat-international-airport/article69061254.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/gujarat/cisf-jawan-kills-himself-with-service-weapon-at-surat-international-airport/article69061254.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 11:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Modi govt 3.0 is maintaining an arm’s length from protesting farmers - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why Modi govt 3.0 is maintaining an arm’s length from protesting farmers</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<p>Union Agriculture Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan has indicated a distant approach from the ongoing farmers' protests led by the Samyukta Kisan Morcha and Kisan Mazdoor Morcha, unlike the proactive measures taken during Modi's previous term.</p>
<ul>
<li>Farmers have been protesting since February 2024 at the Punjab-Haryana borders, demanding legal status for Minimum Support Price (MSP) and a farm debt waiver.</li>
<li>Chouhan has extended an open invitation for talks, yet has not engaged directly with the protesting farmers.</li>
<li>The government's previous attempts to resolve farmer grievances, particularly in 2020-21, led to escalated tensions and prolonged protests.</li>
<li>Current protests are more localized and lack the broad unity seen in earlier movements.</li>
<li>Jagjit Singh Dallewal, president of BKU Sidhupur, is on a hunger strike demanding response to farmers' issues from the government.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Currently, the Supreme Court is looking into this issue. Whatever directives the Supreme Court gives, will be followed.” - Shivraj Singh Chouhan</blockquote>
<p>This current strategy marks a significant shift in the government's handling of farmer-related issues, emphasizing a more detached stance in contrast to previous direct engagements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/modi-govt-protesting-farmers-msp-demands-farm-laws-9759720/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/political-pulse/modi-govt-protesting-farmers-msp-demands-farm-laws-9759720/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 11:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi man cons 700 woman on dating apps using pics of Brazilian model - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxPcWR1cE9OUzNUM0RDOW9tdG5DUW1zZWUxN2hPN21nZTF4MHk5MW9rdVljQ3V3OElENHlJanBxcnNicEM5Tl9EcnNraDgtZG5TZExhLUo1Sll0dmRQTzE1ZlIyVTdRb2N1Zkk2SjFaclVBaGsxRHZDdUZtNl9xNmF2SHpLUFRNS0NqUFpUSW42REZpZkJ5cEhsT2s3d1lGVy1MTF9yanhMcUpmc18tMnVVaHVhVdIBuAFBVV95cUxPbEJPNlBlcWkyTWhFTk1UTFl4VDVWUzVGa0lsVlVrcVhNdnVUdmhBVFNycUVyc2VqMFdOQVJJRXVjUFpVeS1HN0hKcTdSM1J6bjhNOXBFNTlxTEtrTG9kaHlQc0d4VDhyQnNQOWdIeGpjUnpDOVUzVXNGVFZHMUZqc2NBb3JTM1M2REowQ2ZCX1lZaFdwNU5OZHRCRFFwMGxKcWUxbTg0Wk1QZ1c5MlJZZld6d0p6TjE4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxPcWR1cE9OUzNUM0RDOW9tdG5DUW1zZWUxN2hPN21nZTF4MHk5MW9rdVljQ3V3OElENHlJanBxcnNicEM5Tl9EcnNraDgtZG5TZExhLUo1Sll0dmRQTzE1ZlIyVTdRb2N1Zkk2SjFaclVBaGsxRHZDdUZtNl9xNmF2SHpLUFRNS0NqUFpUSW42REZpZkJ5cEhsT2s3d1lGVy1MTF9yanhMcUpmc18tMnVVaHVhVdIBuAFBVV95cUxPbEJPNlBlcWkyTWhFTk1UTFl4VDVWUzVGa0lsVlVrcVhNdnVUdmhBVFNycUVyc2VqMFdOQVJJRXVjUFpVeS1HN0hKcTdSM1J6bjhNOXBFNTlxTEtrTG9kaHlQc0d4VDhyQnNQOWdIeGpjUnpDOVUzVXNGVFZHMUZqc2NBb3JTM1M2REowQ2ZCX1lZaFdwNU5OZHRCRFFwMGxKcWUxbTg0Wk1QZ1c5MlJZZld6d0p6TjE4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 11:14:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life sprouts in space: Isro successfully germinates cowpea seeds in just four days under microgravity con - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Life sprouts in space: Isro successfully germinates cowpea seeds in just four days under microgravity conditions</h1><p><strong>Published on: </strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source: </strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116941234,imgsize-793393,width-400,resizemode-4/116941234.jpg" alt="Life sprouts in space: Isro successfully germinates cowpea seeds in just four days under microgravity conditions" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Isro's achievement in growing cowpea seeds in space</figcaption><p>Isro has made a significant breakthrough by germinating cowpea seeds in microgravity conditions during their PSLV-C60 POEM-4 mission.</p><ul><li>The experiment used the Compact Research Module for Orbital Plant Studies (CROPS).</li><li>CROPS was developed to research seed germination in space.</li><li>Eight cowpea seeds were placed in a regulated environment with precise temperature control.</li><li>The germination occurred in just four days, with further leaf development expected.</li><li>This experiment lays the groundwork for future agricultural studies in space.</li><li>The mission included 24 sophisticated payloads developed in collaboration with academic institutions.</li></ul><blockquote>This development presents significant potential for future space expeditions, particularly for extended missions and establishing human settlements on other celestial bodies.</blockquote><p>The success of this initiative is a major step towards sustainable space agriculture, crucial for life on future space missions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/life-sprouts-in-space-isro-successfully-germinates-cowpea-seeds-in-just-four-days-under-microgravity-conditions/articleshow/116941156.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/life-sprouts-in-space-isro-successfully-germinates-cowpea-seeds-in-just-four-days-under-microgravity-conditions/articleshow/116941156.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 11:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CISF jawan shoots himself dead at Surat Airport - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CISF jawan shoots himself dead at Surat Airport</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Available; <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Surat Airport" /><figcaption>CISF Personnel at Surat Airport</figcaption><p>A Central Industrial Security Force (CISF) jawan tragically took his own life at Surat Airport. This incident has raised concerns regarding mental health among security personnel.</p><ul><li>The incident took place in the early hours.</li><li>Immediate investigations have been launched to ascertain the reasons behind this extreme decision.</li><li>Peers expressed shock over the incident, highlighting mental stress faced by security personnel.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a tragic incident; we need to address the mental health issues faced by our forces.”</blockquote><p>In light of this event, there is a growing call for improved mental health support for armed forces personnel.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/cisf-jawan-shoots-himself-dead-at-surat-airport/articleshow/116941346.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/cisf-jawan-shoots-himself-dead-at-surat-airport/articleshow/116941346.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 11:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Soldiers Die As Army Vehicle Falls Into Gorge In Jammu And Kashmir - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Three Soldiers Die in Army Vehicle Accident in Jammu and Kashmir</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> Saturday <strong>Source:</strong> Srinagar</p> <p>Three soldiers died after an Army truck skidded off the road and plunged into a gorge in Jammu and Kashmir's Bandipora district. Bad weather contributed to the accident.</p> <ul> <li>Incident occurred near the SK Payen area at around 2.30 pm.</li> <li>The Army expressed gratitude towards Kashmiri locals for their assistance in evacuating injured soldiers.</li> <li>Heartfelt condolences were offered to the bereaved families by the Army.</li> <li>This incident follows another vehicle accident last month in which five soldiers died.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“Tragically three bravehearts lost their lives in the unfortunate accident. Indian Army extends heartfelt condolences to the bereaved families.”</blockquote> <p>The tragic loss of these soldiers highlights the dangers faced by military personnel in challenging weather conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/2-soldiers-die-2-injured-as-army-vehicle-falls-into-gorge-in-j-k-7398017</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/2-soldiers-die-2-injured-as-army-vehicle-falls-into-gorge-in-j-k-7398017</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 11:03:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dense fog engulfs Delhi; flight operations hit at IGI airport - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQZVVISW9XVld1SWF5TXhQUXpNRmthNjdmR3pPUnRreTctNHRDWEMwSVRMaTBoajFvRi0zVHo3LUFCakFqaDMteXlhcXd3WkxJVlF1UDVsSWdKbk00Z3lQQnlidjVzb2drOER4OTdaalRHS3BmNnRYV0VNUkYwVFZuZHAyRTFpcmZDSFJZQkdhTG5XOFo0U3M3VGtxaWlsQUp4a0tXaWt6OXhGUWFteEVGYnN5RzUtMGtVWGw0NURXa3HSAccBQVVfeXFMTkdJX0ZDaGluRENya0tmeVZkdnZrLUlHZ0NzYXRmWGJ1UndobDlncmo0RTJIRE96cjItM1czV21OYUt4TGVRZUcwY2xxTjdPZVcxTk1vZThrMW40QldqQ0FVeHpIRmw2SzRBVnh3WEV6NWVOV1NxWHZURmlyQmhadHJ6Qng1WHdzc1JwaXR6LXVENE9RclJMdGtXWTBTQnhtVENyNEEwWk9RZW56Q0pVb1JxQ0dPYXNnZ1djbzdGZXBYaG5BcDRSNA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQZVVISW9XVld1SWF5TXhQUXpNRmthNjdmR3pPUnRreTctNHRDWEMwSVRMaTBoajFvRi0zVHo3LUFCakFqaDMteXlhcXd3WkxJVlF1UDVsSWdKbk00Z3lQQnlidjVzb2drOER4OTdaalRHS3BmNnRYV0VNUkYwVFZuZHAyRTFpcmZDSFJZQkdhTG5XOFo0U3M3VGtxaWlsQUp4a0tXaWt6OXhGUWFteEVGYnN5RzUtMGtVWGw0NURXa3HSAccBQVVfeXFMTkdJX0ZDaGluRENya0tmeVZkdnZrLUlHZ0NzYXRmWGJ1UndobDlncmo0RTJIRE96cjItM1czV21OYUt4TGVRZUcwY2xxTjdPZVcxTk1vZThrMW40QldqQ0FVeHpIRmw2SzRBVnh3WEV6NWVOV1NxWHZURmlyQmhadHJ6Qng1WHdzc1JwaXR6LXVENE9RclJMdGtXWTBTQnhtVENyNEEwWk9RZW56Q0pVb1JxQ0dPYXNnZ1djbzdGZXBYaG5BcDRSNA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 11:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who was R Chidambaram, scientist involved in 1974 'Op Smiling Buddha', Pokhran tests? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who was R Chidambaram, scientist involved in 1974 'Op Smiling Buddha', Pokhran tests?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 04, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/r_chidambaram_1735984845874_1735984863311.jfif" alt="Chidambaram breathed his last in Jaslok Hospital of Maharashtra's Mumbai at 3:20 am on Saturday.(X/@DAEIndia)"><figcaption>Chidambaram breathed his last in Jaslok Hospital of Maharashtra's Mumbai at 3:20 am on Saturday.(X/@DAEIndia)</figcaption><p>Rajagopala Chidambaram, a prominent physicist and leader in India's nuclear program, passed away at age 88 on January 4, 2025. He is celebrated for his roles in both the 1974 'Smiling Buddha' and the 1998 Pokhran-II tests, which confirmed India's status as a nuclear power.</p><ul><li>Chidambaram served as Principal Scientific Adviser (2001–2018) and director of Bhabha Atomic Research Centre (1990-1993).</li><li>His contributions helped advance India's nuclear capabilities and scientific research, impacting sectors like energy and healthcare.</li><li>He was recognised with honors such as the Padma Shri (1975) and Padma Vibhushan (1999) for his work.</li><li>Chidambaram's research greatly influenced materials science and high-pressure physics in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“His unparalleled contributions to India's scientific and strategic capabilities and his visionary leadership in science and technology will forever be remembered.” - Department of Atomic Energy</blockquote><p>R. Chidambaram's legacy is marked by his dedication to scientific excellence and national progress in nuclear technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/who-was-r-chidambaram-scientist-involved-in-1974-op-smiling-buddha-pokhran-tests-101735982786589.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/who-was-r-chidambaram-scientist-involved-in-1974-op-smiling-buddha-pokhran-tests-101735982786589.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 10:44:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weather news live: Normal operations resume at Delhi airport; 19 flights diverted - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Weather news live: Normal operations resume at Delhi airport; 19 flights diverted</h1><p><strong>Date: January 4, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/flight_delays_airport_indigo_1721389508033_1735966700792.jpg" alt="Passengers at Delhi Airport amid fog" loading="lazy" decoding="async"><figcaption>Passengers look at screens, some of them showing Blue Screen errors, at T3 Terminal of the Indira Gandhi International Airport amid Microsoft outage, in New Delhi, Friday, July 19, 2024.</figcaption><p>Flight and train operations have been severely impacted in Delhi due to dense fog, leading to flight diversions and delays.</p><ul><li>Normal operations have resumed at Delhi airport after interruptions.</li><li>A total of 19 flights were diverted due to adverse weather conditions early Saturday.</li><li>IndiGo and Air India reported temporary halts in operations due to extremely low visibility.</li><li>81 trains were delayed at New Delhi station also owing to the fog.</li><li>Cold wave conditions affected several regions, including Punjab, Haryana, and Rajasthan.</li></ul><blockquote>“Due to adverse weather conditions in Delhi, 19 flight diversions were reported between 0015 hours and 0130 hours. Operations have now returned to normal.” - Delhi International Airport Limited</blockquote><p>The recovery of operations signifies a return to normalcy at Delhi airport, but the impact of the weather has disrupted travel significantly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/weather-live-updates-fog-cold-wave-delhi-airport-haryana-uttar-pradesh-january-4-2024-101735943715851.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/weather-live-updates-fog-cold-wave-delhi-airport-haryana-uttar-pradesh-january-4-2024-101735943715851.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 09:42:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arvind Kejriwal's Delhi poll rival Parvesh Verma's big dare: 'Hope he doesn't run away' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxNaWhya1U0SHNfVUQ3MGxzdlZ6Y0xjeHJRWWVJNVluRDFUTm9kUzdjNGtfdUh3UDZDazVZS1ZSbk82OUJEQ01DWXBtelJvS0pOWEY1MEtLOTFJbUlvZms2Qk5HZW5IWEtIY0pybTVmMEpDT3hGem1PMmx6eVNxYzBkZkllSFRLV25UbjVVNU1EWldOTTVRVWVvbGdhWU8ydDJqaHBFR3MzRUdwWHhtTjF1azV2RVZSNjh3SFdpRC1WUFBkcHF5TDhkRlE0enFwcjBFdlVwU242SUpfMlM30gHiAUFVX3lxTE5aNVVrXzQtMnlBa2NUZlpEajRlOW0tMF9CajFndFA0cWludWxHWkJobmQ3dnpIZi1UUUFpR00tMG5pb0VtaWMyZFk0RmNjOUVPRWpJemFRSm4wcFhGSGI4dHRIbEIzZXBPLUN1MDl2NnlUYkt5UXpQRFNCd0ZBazh3QnZ1U1ZtRFpvYU53XzJidnBZVXV0ZDQ2WDVuMVhUT1FlQURUSWlqdlRQSjV4NDItTzBfTTR1OWdaMTM2UkpwZDdOd0dLcDAya3ZWZVVMUEhpcEVNalVfTGxMZWxGUTJfelE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxNaWhya1U0SHNfVUQ3MGxzdlZ6Y0xjeHJRWWVJNVluRDFUTm9kUzdjNGtfdUh3UDZDazVZS1ZSbk82OUJEQ01DWXBtelJvS0pOWEY1MEtLOTFJbUlvZms2Qk5HZW5IWEtIY0pybTVmMEpDT3hGem1PMmx6eVNxYzBkZkllSFRLV25UbjVVNU1EWldOTTVRVWVvbGdhWU8ydDJqaHBFR3MzRUdwWHhtTjF1azV2RVZSNjh3SFdpRC1WUFBkcHF5TDhkRlE0enFwcjBFdlVwU242SUpfMlM30gHiAUFVX3lxTE5aNVVrXzQtMnlBa2NUZlpEajRlOW0tMF9CajFndFA0cWludWxHWkJobmQ3dnpIZi1UUUFpR00tMG5pb0VtaWMyZFk0RmNjOUVPRWpJemFRSm4wcFhGSGI4dHRIbEIzZXBPLUN1MDl2NnlUYkt5UXpQRFNCd0ZBazh3QnZ1U1ZtRFpvYU53XzJidnBZVXV0ZDQ2WDVuMVhUT1FlQURUSWlqdlRQSjV4NDItTzBfTTR1OWdaMTM2UkpwZDdOd0dLcDAya3ZWZVVMUEhpcEVNalVfTGxMZWxGUTJfelE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 09:39:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Govt's Intentions, Policies, Decisions Filling Rural India With New Energy': PM Modi - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Govt's Intentions, Policies, Decisions Filling Rural India With New Energy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 04, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi. (Image: PTI/File)"><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi. (Image: PTI/File)</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi emphasized that the Indian government's initiatives are energizing rural India, aiming to empower communities and transform villages into hubs of growth.</p><ul><li>PM Modi spoke at the Grameen Bharat Mahotsav 2025, celebrating rural India's resilience.</li><li>He highlighted increasing accessibility to healthcare services in rural areas.</li><li>An approximate Rs. 3 lakh crore in financial assistance has been provided to farmers under the PM-KISAN scheme.</li></ul><blockquote>“During the COVID pandemic, the world doubted how Indian villages would tackle the crisis, but we ensured vaccines reached the last person in every village.” – PM Modi</blockquote><p>The Prime Minister's remarks reflect ongoing government efforts to enhance rural infrastructure and economic stability, aiming for a 'Viksit Bharat' (Developed India) by 2047.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/govts-intentions-policies-decisions-filling-rural-india-with-new-energy-pm-modi-9176876.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/govts-intentions-policies-decisions-filling-rural-india-with-new-energy-pm-modi-9176876.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 09:24:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[S.354 IPC | To Establish Mens Rea, Something More Than Vague Statements Must Be Produced : Supreme Court... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Emphasizes Clarity in Establishing Mens Rea for IPC Section 354</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> LiveLaw</p><p>The Supreme Court has ruled that for Section 354 IPC to apply, there must be a clear demonstration of criminal force along with intent to outrage a woman’s modesty. Vague statements are insufficient to establish mens rea.</p><ul><li>The court found that mere assertions of discomfort do not meet the legal requirements for establishing mens rea.</li><li>In this case, the complaint against the appellant was quashed due to lack of substantial evidence.</li><li>The court underscored that definitions of criminal force exist, but modesty lacks a clear legal definition.</li><li>Citing precedents, the court stressed the necessity of intention to support allegations of criminal intimidation.</li><li>The proceedings against the appellant were set aside, reflecting on the misuse of legal processes.</li></ul><blockquote>“To establish mens rea, something better than vague statements must be produced before the court.”</blockquote><p>The ruling highlights the need for clear evidence in legal cases related to IPC Section 354, reinforcing the principle that any claims must be substantiated beyond mere assertions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/supreme-court/supreme-court-clarifies-section-354-ipc-criminal-force-and-intent-to-outrage-woman-modesty-279986</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/supreme-court/supreme-court-clarifies-section-354-ipc-criminal-force-and-intent-to-outrage-woman-modesty-279986</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 09:23:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Army vehicle falls into gorge in J&K's Bandipora, 3 soldiers dead - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Army Vehicle Accident in Bandipora Claims Lives of Three Soldiers</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 04, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/bandipora_army_vehicle_accident_1735993044300_1735993082783.jpeg" alt="Army soldiers near the damaged army vehicle at Wular viewpoint in Bandipora district.(Waseem Andrabi /Hindustan Times)"><figcaption>Army soldiers near the damaged army vehicle at Wular viewpoint in Bandipora district.(Waseem Andrabi /Hindustan Times)</figcaption><p>At least three soldiers died and two others were injured after an Army vehicle skidded off the road in Jammu and Kashmir's Bandipora district and fell into a deep gorge near the Wular Viewpoint on Saturday.</p><ul><li>The Indian Army's Chinar Corps cited inclement weather and poor visibility as causes for the accident.</li><li>Rescue operations were aided by Kashmiri locals, thanking them for their swift assistance.</li><li>Three soldiers are reported in critical condition, while two were declared dead upon arrival at the hospital.</li><li>This incident follows a similar accident where five soldiers were killed a week prior in Poonch district.</li><li>Weather warnings are in place, including yellow and orange alerts for snowfall affecting travel and safety.</li></ul><blockquote>"Tragically three bravehearts lost their lives in the unfortunate accident. Indian Army extends heartfelt condolences to the bereaved families."</blockquote><p>The incident highlights ongoing safety concerns for military operations in adverse weather conditions and the need for caution amongst civilians as forecasts predict heavy snowfall.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/army-vehicle-skids-off-road-in-jammu-and-kashmir-bandipora-several-injuries-deaths-101735981693128.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/army-vehicle-skids-off-road-in-jammu-and-kashmir-bandipora-several-injuries-deaths-101735981693128.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 09:11:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three soldiers die in road accident in north Kashmirs Bandipora - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxOWTB1QUhxTkUyM1dKcWtSWkNJWFg0QmZSRHdsMU1uam1qVFRxZ2tJeENzYy1jeXNHQjM1VXdYMWduUEdRelNSNTBIaC1oaHI1bzlqcFBoX0o5dzczaHZhR040ZEZWVTJrUXhVMC1iX0Z3ckRZN2YxdEp6MnZGMEhoN2FuZ1ZuWkd3R202UGV6WGJLYlNIVGJVNnJqRThWZi01MEJaNlgxS2NpRTZfT3dZZVNIZWlGNzF2TllQUTdLT1FUeWhjU3IwX0tpYmU4YVVoNXF2ctIB2gFBVV95cUxQXzVwY0t2T0M1SFlWWk9rMlk5TDJ2a1lsVk5VR1g0YWw0YUJjOGVsWF9qMjNHWE96U1VCd3N5b1JydE01R19rMGVLaGR5WmZoUG05OUJ2ZkZjOUU4Ni0teVlfZVQ5MTZmdjBHellHY0pZUVR6bEloRnhIaFhrT2JFSXd6WUM2WmV4eHIxUUZhblMybVpnOTZzU3FCZ1lxbWFTU1k0Y0p4UmNzaTBjMmV5THhFNTY2dHZyZkRRN3BwVlpIUzN0RFBydTZFZnV2NmxINnJtV1lrdEhXUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxOWTB1QUhxTkUyM1dKcWtSWkNJWFg0QmZSRHdsMU1uam1qVFRxZ2tJeENzYy1jeXNHQjM1VXdYMWduUEdRelNSNTBIaC1oaHI1bzlqcFBoX0o5dzczaHZhR040ZEZWVTJrUXhVMC1iX0Z3ckRZN2YxdEp6MnZGMEhoN2FuZ1ZuWkd3R202UGV6WGJLYlNIVGJVNnJqRThWZi01MEJaNlgxS2NpRTZfT3dZZVNIZWlGNzF2TllQUTdLT1FUeWhjU3IwX0tpYmU4YVVoNXF2ctIB2gFBVV95cUxQXzVwY0t2T0M1SFlWWk9rMlk5TDJ2a1lsVk5VR1g0YWw0YUJjOGVsWF9qMjNHWE96U1VCd3N5b1JydE01R19rMGVLaGR5WmZoUG05OUJ2ZkZjOUU4Ni0teVlfZVQ5MTZmdjBHellHY0pZUVR6bEloRnhIaFhrT2JFSXd6WUM2WmV4eHIxUUZhblMybVpnOTZzU3FCZ1lxbWFTU1k0Y0p4UmNzaTBjMmV5THhFNTY2dHZyZkRRN3BwVlpIUzN0RFBydTZFZnV2NmxINnJtV1lrdEhXUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 09:06:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two army soldiers killed, three critically injured in road accident in north Kashmirs Bandipora - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxOWTB1QUhxTkUyM1dKcWtSWkNJWFg0QmZSRHdsMU1uam1qVFRxZ2tJeENzYy1jeXNHQjM1VXdYMWduUEdRelNSNTBIaC1oaHI1bzlqcFBoX0o5dzczaHZhR040ZEZWVTJrUXhVMC1iX0Z3ckRZN2YxdEp6MnZGMEhoN2FuZ1ZuWkd3R202UGV6WGJLYlNIVGJVNnJqRThWZi01MEJaNlgxS2NpRTZfT3dZZVNIZWlGNzF2TllQUTdLT1FUeWhjU3IwX0tpYmU4YVVoNXF2ctIB2gFBVV95cUxQXzVwY0t2T0M1SFlWWk9rMlk5TDJ2a1lsVk5VR1g0YWw0YUJjOGVsWF9qMjNHWE96U1VCd3N5b1JydE01R19rMGVLaGR5WmZoUG05OUJ2ZkZjOUU4Ni0teVlfZVQ5MTZmdjBHellHY0pZUVR6bEloRnhIaFhrT2JFSXd6WUM2WmV4eHIxUUZhblMybVpnOTZzU3FCZ1lxbWFTU1k0Y0p4UmNzaTBjMmV5THhFNTY2dHZyZkRRN3BwVlpIUzN0RFBydTZFZnV2NmxINnJtV1lrdEhXUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxOWTB1QUhxTkUyM1dKcWtSWkNJWFg0QmZSRHdsMU1uam1qVFRxZ2tJeENzYy1jeXNHQjM1VXdYMWduUEdRelNSNTBIaC1oaHI1bzlqcFBoX0o5dzczaHZhR040ZEZWVTJrUXhVMC1iX0Z3ckRZN2YxdEp6MnZGMEhoN2FuZ1ZuWkd3R202UGV6WGJLYlNIVGJVNnJqRThWZi01MEJaNlgxS2NpRTZfT3dZZVNIZWlGNzF2TllQUTdLT1FUeWhjU3IwX0tpYmU4YVVoNXF2ctIB2gFBVV95cUxQXzVwY0t2T0M1SFlWWk9rMlk5TDJ2a1lsVk5VR1g0YWw0YUJjOGVsWF9qMjNHWE96U1VCd3N5b1JydE01R19rMGVLaGR5WmZoUG05OUJ2ZkZjOUU4Ni0teVlfZVQ5MTZmdjBHellHY0pZUVR6bEloRnhIaFhrT2JFSXd6WUM2WmV4eHIxUUZhblMybVpnOTZzU3FCZ1lxbWFTU1k0Y0p4UmNzaTBjMmV5THhFNTY2dHZyZkRRN3BwVlpIUzN0RFBydTZFZnV2NmxINnJtV1lrdEhXUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 09:06:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka transport minister Ramalinga Reddy justifies bus fare hike - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka Transport Minister Ramalinga Reddy Justifies Bus Fare Hike</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 04, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/04/550x309/assignment-name-in-brief_4b6b4c64-f6c7-11e7-b42e-2d533d154b0f_1735980759875.jpg" alt="Karnataka home minister Ramalinga Reddy. (Arijit Sen/HT Photo)"><figcaption>Karnataka home minister Ramalinga Reddy. (Arijit Sen/HT Photo)</figcaption></figure><p>Karnataka Transport Minister Ramalinga Reddy has announced a 15% increase in government bus fares, citing rising operational costs and a need to revise staff salaries. He criticized the BJP for protesting against the fare hike, emphasizing the increased costs of fuel and daily operations.</p><ul><li>The daily operational cost for bus transportation rose from ₹12.85 crore in 2020 to ₹18.86 crore now.</li><li>The government approved the fare hike in a cabinet meeting after demands from four transport corporations.</li><li>Reddy highlighted past fare hikes and reductions based on diesel prices, noting the BJP's previous fare increases.</li><li>The minister criticized the BJP's blame of the fare hike on the Shakti scheme, emphasizing its benefit for women's empowerment.</li></ul><blockquote>"The most important thing is that when I took over as the transport minister in 2023, I found the BJP had left behind a debt of ₹5,900 crore towards Provident Fund, gratuity and pending bills."</blockquote><p>This fare increase is positioned as a necessary adjustment to ensure the sustainability of bus services amidst rising costs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/bengaluru-news/karnataka-transport-minister-ramalinga-reddy-justifies-bus-fare-hike-101735980565056.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cities/bengaluru-news/karnataka-transport-minister-ramalinga-reddy-justifies-bus-fare-hike-101735980565056.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:57:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BJP's First List For Delhi Polls In, Parvesh Verma To Contest Arvind Kejriwal - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Announces Candidates for Delhi Assembly Elections, Parvesh Verma to Challenge Kejriwal</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 4, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>The BJP has unveiled its first list of candidates for the upcoming Delhi Assembly elections, targeting 29 out of the 70 seats available. Former BJP MP Parvesh Verma is set to contest against AAP's Arvind Kejriwal in New Delhi.</p><ul><li>The elections are scheduled for February 2025.</li><li>Parvesh Verma expresses gratitude to the BJP leadership for their trust in him.</li><li>Other notable candidates include Kailash Gehlot, Ramesh Bidhuri, and Arvinder Singh Lovely, who have shifted parties.</li><li>The upcoming elections are anticipated to be a tightly contested battle between the BJP and AAP.</li><li>The Congress party has not won any Delhi seats in the last two Assembly elections.</li></ul><blockquote>“Delhi is suffering because of Arvind Kejriwal. The people of Kalkaji have also faced 'AAPda' under Chief Minister Atishi,” said Ramesh Bidhuri, expressing his commitment to reclaiming his seat.</blockquote><p>The rivalry between BJP and AAP is heating up as former allies in the Opposition bloc, Congress and AAP, prepare to face off in the elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bjp-releases-first-list-for-delhi-elections-parvesh-verma-to-contest-against-arvind-kejriwal-ramesh-bidhuri-to-fight-atishi-7397301</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bjp-releases-first-list-for-delhi-elections-parvesh-verma-to-contest-against-arvind-kejriwal-ramesh-bidhuri-to-fight-atishi-7397301</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:52:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On fast for 40 days in Punjabs Khanauri, farmer leader Dallewal says morcha will win - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxNcnNCZUNiNS16cmxUb3FtQ29GeFZldHpTWVNiVENub3pGWHlHMTE4cl9TUHhlcVJCVlBCdFBETnF4UmJpX29MWFkteU1wLUpRODh2Q3hNS1FxcnpKdjM3WmpuTzlKUEU4RE5LUzdON2pSUWJES1p1WUp1amJFdUZROTlZT1paM3JfR2FEZzVQeGFuaW9VS3dfazJXZGdVM1NXODN4a0E4bjJZQldOeGlNYXBzSEZtWWFSNWhiZDlVVGzSAcQBQVVfeXFMT0pYNTZRWW1VRHhkRW03ajFxZlBJeEtYRndzSzJyeXVCUm5IVlNPSHREeTF2YnlUdEZ5Z2ZVbGVaaWV4OXAxY19ZaTJWZDk4RDdvWGZaTUFWcENZMFM2MGVmNU5EeTNsQnJBVDZkX2o3QVBMbWRCUVhqbHNRMFlvZ0I5U1VYTkFleFJ3aUVkeU1YVno1ZUlSODBlZ0VHeWk4T3hRWFAxNjFNTmtPUmFwdFJPZEdhakJ4OFZka1o1OW95OUhuUw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxNcnNCZUNiNS16cmxUb3FtQ29GeFZldHpTWVNiVENub3pGWHlHMTE4cl9TUHhlcVJCVlBCdFBETnF4UmJpX29MWFkteU1wLUpRODh2Q3hNS1FxcnpKdjM3WmpuTzlKUEU4RE5LUzdON2pSUWJES1p1WUp1amJFdUZROTlZT1paM3JfR2FEZzVQeGFuaW9VS3dfazJXZGdVM1NXODN4a0E4bjJZQldOeGlNYXBzSEZtWWFSNWhiZDlVVGzSAcQBQVVfeXFMT0pYNTZRWW1VRHhkRW03ajFxZlBJeEtYRndzSzJyeXVCUm5IVlNPSHREeTF2YnlUdEZ5Z2ZVbGVaaWV4OXAxY19ZaTJWZDk4RDdvWGZaTUFWcENZMFM2MGVmNU5EeTNsQnJBVDZkX2o3QVBMbWRCUVhqbHNRMFlvZ0I5U1VYTkFleFJ3aUVkeU1YVno1ZUlSODBlZ0VHeWk4T3hRWFAxNjFNTmtPUmFwdFJPZEdhakJ4OFZka1o1OW95OUhuUw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:48:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nimisha Priya: Last hope for Indian nurse on death row in Yemen - pardon from victim's family - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgkx4e4knv8o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgkx4e4knv8o</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:37:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[28 sentenced to life imprisonment in Chandan Gupta murder case: Read details from court documents - OpIndia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxQM0x5c21talcwRkhyTDUyS01VVU1uWWhuaHV4SGdxVGVBNnJRQjhGcjVTa3JiWFZGWXBnQ3BRU05BUXJ6YWUzcTl0VjdzU29UYl9PUlZCVHB1bkpkU0xkV2tVQkxobzBFVWljYkxZQ0dOSWd1R1FqSVY5dFZycGEzekdUR09nWURWMFBGLXhsY0c4dUtpaFVuZXk1QjBGT2h2aUk5NV95ZUhWLVZUOEtFLTllWVFvUUFHME9nY1h5V2ctalU5a3RXag?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxQM0x5c21talcwRkhyTDUyS01VVU1uWWhuaHV4SGdxVGVBNnJRQjhGcjVTa3JiWFZGWXBnQ3BRU05BUXJ6YWUzcTl0VjdzU29UYl9PUlZCVHB1bkpkU0xkV2tVQkxobzBFVWljYkxZQ0dOSWd1R1FqSVY5dFZycGEzekdUR09nWURWMFBGLXhsY0c4dUtpaFVuZXk1QjBGT2h2aUk5NV95ZUhWLVZUOEtFLTllWVFvUUFHME9nY1h5V2ctalU5a3RXag?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:37:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BRO MSW Offline Form 2025 - SarkariExam.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTFBrOXI3TDJMZ1JNNjhOX1JsUHFSMUd4SnctVFAtRDVtM3lMWEJmR0xhemR4Z3NwcDQ5LWtObm82bS16MEFTcklVanBWekFVN2lPRzRJQS1fVGJqYzBzNl80amI1YmJlc0tIWWRDOVVycWRjR0c2?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTFBrOXI3TDJMZ1JNNjhOX1JsUHFSMUd4SnctVFAtRDVtM3lMWEJmR0xhemR4Z3NwcDQ5LWtObm82bS16MEFTcklVanBWekFVN2lPRzRJQS1fVGJqYzBzNl80amI1YmJlc0tIWWRDOVVycWRjR0c2?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:09:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Assembly elections 2025: BJP releases first list of 29 candiates - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BJP Unveils First List of Candidates for Delhi Assembly Elections 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 04, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/cities/Delhi/uvmu7d/article69060859.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/BJPList.jpg" alt="BJP released their first list of 29 candidates for the Delhi Assembly elections. While Parvesh Sahib Singh Verma is pitted against Arvind Kejriwal, Ramesh Bidhuri will be contesting against Delhi CM Atishi." title="BJP released their first list of 29 candidates for the Delhi Assembly elections. While Parvesh Sahib Singh Verma is pitted against Arvind Kejriwal, Ramesh Bidhuri will be contesting against Delhi CM Atishi."><figcaption>BJP released their first list of 29 candidates for the Delhi Assembly elections.</figcaption></p><p>The BJP released a list of 29 candidates for the upcoming Delhi Assembly elections scheduled for February 2025, featuring significant matchups such as Parvesh Sahib Singh Verma against Arvind Kejriwal and Ramesh Bidhuri against Atishi.</p><ul><li>The candidates include Vijender Gupta (Rohini), Ashish Sood (Janakpuri), and Kailash Gahlot (Bijwasan).</li><li>Ramesh Bidhuri will contest in Kalkaji against Delhi CM Atishi.</li><li>Dushyant Kumar Gautam is fielded from Karol Bagh (SC).</li><li>Sardar Tarvinder Singh Marwah will run against Manish Sisodia in Jangpura.</li></ul><blockquote>“BJP’s Ramesh Bidhuri will be contesting from Kalkaji constituency against AAP leader and Delhi Chief Minister Atishi.”</blockquote><p>The initiative by the BJP to announce its candidate list sets the stage for fierce political battles in the upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/delhi-assembly-elections-bjp-releases-first-list-of-candidates/article69060807.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/Delhi/delhi-assembly-elections-bjp-releases-first-list-of-candidates/article69060807.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why is Garmin banned in India? Athletes tracking sports activity with these popular devices may land in jail | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why is Garmin banned in India? Athletes tracking sports activity with these popular devices may land in jail</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Garmin devices are not entirely banned in India, but certain models that feature satellite communication can lead to legal trouble for users. Recent incidents involving foreigners have highlighted the risks associated with these gadgets.</p>
<h2>Key Points:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Garmin devices using satellite communication, such as the Garmin inReach, are illegal in India without permission.</li>
<li>A Scottish hiker was detained at Delhi Airport for carrying a Garmin inReach.</li>
<li>Another foreign national faced similar issues with a Garmin Edge 540 GPS device.</li>
<li>The Indian Wireless Telegraphy Act of 1933 makes the use of such devices without licensing illegal.</li>
<li>Travelers are warned not to bring satellite phones or devices to India without prior approval.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Garmin was illegal here and that they were handing me over to the Police.” - Scottish hiker</blockquote>
<p>This highlights the importance for travelers to understand local regulations regarding technology and devices. The consequences of ignoring these laws can lead to serious legal action.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/why-is-garmin-illegal-in-india-athletes-tracking-their-sports-activity-with-these-popular-devices-may-land-in-trouble-11735892924598.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/why-is-garmin-illegal-in-india-athletes-tracking-their-sports-activity-with-these-popular-devices-may-land-in-trouble-11735892924598.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parvesh Verma to take on Kejriwal in Delhi, BJP releases 1st list of 29 candidates - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPWC1zUHZ5SkpicDY2eUg3NWx4OXZUTHBFTGVxb0pNamt4eVk5MkZQWVk3UTQ5UUN1MHY2VEZSRXRORmIwczdxRk55QW5LX3FiNGNPY0lPTFN5eTk4OGU3SEJ3QWh5bnZNVndTdXg1ajBuVFFZTklna0RtVDI2Q3dDdXR0Q0RQZlhtcmx4aEFueXFNNk01blUtN1hHWDZIelFjYUxLWWxkYmc3RHlENTJCQ2FoXy00dWt6QnJhMNIBwAFBVV95cUxPSGNWcDB1R3BFcF9QelJiUThnVS1CV296QTFYTVNCQm10d3NXSFM0QldSelV0VEtlWEtodXpFVFczTktlbjZ3ZzA0LVl1dGpGaUZ0dUUxdVV4UmdNZDA5QWx3d2lLNW1jaXZlN2ozLUhEdjNJR01vOUVDTUwzMGktYUw1YnctVi10MDJKQkV5TUtnMEs3bUM4aHZ3ckJTZVU0TkszT1ZwMV82aWN4SVlGNDVvWVVUYmdzdW9vSDl1aE8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPWC1zUHZ5SkpicDY2eUg3NWx4OXZUTHBFTGVxb0pNamt4eVk5MkZQWVk3UTQ5UUN1MHY2VEZSRXRORmIwczdxRk55QW5LX3FiNGNPY0lPTFN5eTk4OGU3SEJ3QWh5bnZNVndTdXg1ajBuVFFZTklna0RtVDI2Q3dDdXR0Q0RQZlhtcmx4aEFueXFNNk01blUtN1hHWDZIelFjYUxLWWxkYmc3RHlENTJCQ2FoXy00dWt6QnJhMNIBwAFBVV95cUxPSGNWcDB1R3BFcF9QelJiUThnVS1CV296QTFYTVNCQm10d3NXSFM0QldSelV0VEtlWEtodXpFVFczTktlbjZ3ZzA0LVl1dGpGaUZ0dUUxdVV4UmdNZDA5QWx3d2lLNW1jaXZlN2ozLUhEdjNJR01vOUVDTUwzMGktYUw1YnctVi10MDJKQkV5TUtnMEs3bUM4aHZ3ckJTZVU0TkszT1ZwMV82aWN4SVlGNDVvWVVUYmdzdW9vSDl1aE8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 07:57:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>