<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nation Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:21:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Nation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:21:34 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘You Are Virtually A Stranger’: Supreme Court To Atul Subhash’s Mother Who Sought Kid’s Custody - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/atul-subhash-suicide-bengaluru-techie-mother-child-custody-plea-supreme-court-karnataka-hc-wife-nikita-singhania-9180540.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/atul-subhash-suicide-bengaluru-techie-mother-child-custody-plea-supreme-court-karnataka-hc-wife-nikita-singhania-9180540.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:16:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Elections 2025 Date Announcement Live: Delhi To Vote On February 5, Counting On February 8 - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Elections 2025 Date Announcement Live: Delhi To Vote On February 5, Counting On February 8</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 &nbsp;| &nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>The assembly elections in Delhi will occur in a single phase on February 5, with votes counted on February 8, as announced by the Election Commission.</p><ul><li>Election scheduled for February 5, 2025.</li><li>Counting of votes set for February 8, 2025.</li><li>The current 70-member Assembly's term ends on February 23, requiring elections to form a new House.</li><li>AAP aims for a third consecutive term, facing competition from BJP and Congress.</li><li>India to reach one billion voters soon, setting a new record.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are going to be a nation of one billion voters very soon, which will be another record in voting,” said Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar.</blockquote><p>This announcement sets the stage for the upcoming electoral battle, highlighting the contest among major political parties and the increasing voter population in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/delhi-news/delhi-elections-2025-date-announcement-live-updates-poll-body-to-release-assembly-election-schedule-as-aap-bjp-congress-pm-modi-arvind-kejriwal-fight-7417380</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/delhi-news/delhi-elections-2025-date-announcement-live-updates-poll-body-to-release-assembly-election-schedule-as-aap-bjp-congress-pm-modi-arvind-kejriwal-fight-7417380</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:26:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Assembly poll schedule LIVE updates: Election Commission to announce dates shortly - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Assembly Elections 2025 LIVE: Voting on February 5, counting on February 8</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 07, 2025 - The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/9f0ws4/article69071757.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/WhatsApp%20Image%202025-01-07%20at%202.35.36%20PM.jpeg" alt="Delhi Assembly Election 2025" /><figcaption>Chief Election Commissioner Rajiv Kumar addressed the media on Delhi Assembly Election at Vigyan Bhawan on January 7, 2025. | Photo Credit: Sushil Kumar Verma</figcaption><p>The announcement for the Delhi Assembly elections has been made, with voting scheduled for February 5, 2025, and counting of votes set for February 8, 2025.</p><ul><li>Single-phase elections will be conducted in Delhi.</li><li>The Delhi Chief Election Commissioner emphasized a crackdown on the use of money power during elections.</li><li>Easy access and provisions for senior citizens and persons with disabilities will be ensured.</li></ul><blockquote>“India has a gold standard of elections, it’s a shared legacy for all of us including all political parties,” - CEC Rajiv Kumar.</blockquote><p>This election is poised to influence the political landscape of Delhi significantly, highlighting key issues such as electoral integrity and participation rights.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/elections/delhi-assembly/delhi-assembly-election-schedule-election-commission-live-updates/article69070928.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/elections/delhi-assembly/delhi-assembly-election-schedule-election-commission-live-updates/article69070928.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Bahane nahi badlav chahiye': After AAP, BJP releases campaign song ahead of Delhi elections - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Bahane nahi badlav chahiye': After AAP, BJP releases campaign song ahead of Delhi elections</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 - <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="BJP campaign song" />
<figcaption>BJP releases a new campaign song ahead of the Delhi elections</figcaption>
<p>The BJP has launched a campaign song titled 'Bahane nahi badlav chahiye', aggressively positioning itself ahead of the upcoming Delhi elections. This move follows a similar tactic by the AAP, showcasing the competitive political landscape.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The song emphasizes the need for change rather than making excuses.</li>
  <li>BJP's strategy is to resonate with voters seeking tangible results.</li>
  <li>Focus on addressing local issues that matter to Delhi residents.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  “We want to push for real change, not just empty promises,” a BJP spokesperson stated.
</blockquote>
<p>This release marks a significant moment in the lead-up to the elections, indicating the BJP's commitment to addressing voter concerns and enhancing its appeal in Delhi.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/bahane-nahi-badlav-chahiye-after-aap-bjp-releases-campaign-song-ahead-of-delhi-elections/articleshow/117017695.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/bahane-nahi-badlav-chahiye-after-aap-bjp-releases-campaign-song-ahead-of-delhi-elections/articleshow/117017695.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where Is Atul Subhash's Son? Nikita Singhania's Lawyer Replies In Top Court - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Court's 'Stranger' Remark As Atul Subhash's Mother Seeks Grandson's Custody</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent, <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>In a custody battle concerning AI techie Atul Subhash's four-year-old son, his estranged wife, Nikita Singhania, revealed to the Supreme Court that the child is currently in a boarding school in Faridabad, Haryana. Following Atul's tragic suicide in December, his mother Anju Devi is seeking custody.</p><ul><li>Atul Subhash took his own life after accusing Nikita of harassment.</li><li>Nikita's family is facing abetment to suicide charges.</li><li>The Supreme Court directed that the child be produced in the next hearing.</li><li>Concerns raised about the child's unfamiliarity with his grandmother.</li><li>The custody issue is to be decided in the appropriate court.</li></ul><blockquote>“Sorry to say but the child is a stranger to the petitioner,” remarked Justice Nagaratna.</blockquote><p>The next hearing is scheduled for January 20.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/atul-subhash-suicide-case-nikita-singhania-bengaluru-techie-suicide-where-is-atul-subhashs-son-nikita-singhanias-lawyer-replies-in-top-court-7418358</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/atul-subhash-suicide-case-nikita-singhania-bengaluru-techie-suicide-where-is-atul-subhashs-son-nikita-singhanias-lawyer-replies-in-top-court-7418358</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:04:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Election Live Updates: Arvind Kejriwal launches campaign song for assembly polls - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Election Live Updates: Election Commission to announce Delhi polls schedule shortly</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent updates from the Election Commission.</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/PTI01-07-2025-000053B-0_1736236240483_1736236272369.jpg" alt="Delhi Chief Minister Atishi, AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal, and party leaders during the launch of the campaign song." title="Delhi Election Live Updates: Delhi Chief Minister Atishi, AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal and party leaders Manish Sisodia and Gopal Rai during the launch of the party's campaign song."><figcaption>Delhi Chief Minister Atishi, AAP chief Arvind Kejriwal, and party leaders during the launch of the campaign song.</figcaption><p>The Election Commission of India is set to announce the schedule for the General Election for the Legislative Assembly of Delhi. This announcement comes amidst a political row regarding the voter roll.</p><ul><li>The Election Commission's press briefing is scheduled for 2:00 PM.</li><li>The term of the 70-member Assembly ends on February 23.</li><li>The final electoral roll shows over 1.55 crore registered voters in Delhi.</li><li>First-time voters aged 18-19 have increased by 52,554 since the last electoral roll.</li><li>AAP’s campaign song was released, highlighting achievements in governance.</li><li>Allegations of voter list manipulations raised by both AAP and BJP.</li></ul><blockquote>"We celebrate our elections like festivals, and people wait for our song; now it's out, and people can dance to it." - Arvind Kejriwal</blockquote><p>The upcoming elections in Delhi are generating significant interest, with preparations underway from all political parties.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-election-live-updates-election-commission-to-announce-delhi-assembly-election-date-today-bjp-aap-congress-candida-101736230542111.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/delhi-election-live-updates-election-commission-to-announce-delhi-assembly-election-date-today-bjp-aap-congress-candida-101736230542111.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:59:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Godman Asaram Bapu bail: SC grants interim bail in 2013 rape case on medical grounds till March 31 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/2013-rape-case-sc-grants-interim-bail-to-asaram-on-medical-grounds-till-march-31/article69071578.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/2013-rape-case-sc-grants-interim-bail-to-asaram-on-medical-grounds-till-march-31/article69071578.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court Grants Interim Bail To Asaram Bapu In Rape Case For Medical Treatment - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supreme Court Grants Interim Bail To Asaram Bapu In Rape Case For Medical Treatment</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Law</p><p>The Supreme Court has granted interim bail to self-styled godman Asaram Bapu, who is serving a life sentence in a rape case, allowing him to seek medical treatment until March 31, 2025.</p><ul><li>The bail was granted by Justices M.M. Sundresh and Rajesh Bindal, with a condition that Asaram must not meet his followers while released.</li><li>Asaram's legal team argued his health condition justified the need for bail, citing his advanced age and history of heart problems.</li><li>The Solicitor General opposed the bail, stating Asaram has adequate medical care in jail.</li><li>The bail was issued on humanitarian grounds, with the court allowing for a reassessment of Asaram's medical status closer to the end of the bail period.</li><li>The original conviction involved multiple charges of rape and other serious offenses against a female disciple.</li></ul><blockquote>“The relief was granted solely on humanitarian grounds.”</blockquote><p>This decision allows Asaram to undergo necessary medical treatment while under specific conditions imposed by the court.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-cour-grants-interim-bail-to-asaram-bapu-in-rape-case-for-medical-treatment-280178</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livelaw.in/top-stories/supreme-cour-grants-interim-bail-to-asaram-bapu-in-rape-case-for-medical-treatment-280178</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:55:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rape Convict Asaram Bapu Gets Interim Bail, But Can't Meet His Followers - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Asaram Granted Interim Bail by Supreme Court Despite Rape Convictions</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Recent news from <strong>Source: NDTV</strong></p><p>A week after self-styled godman Asaram returned to jail from a previous parole, the Supreme Court has granted him interim bail on medical grounds in a 2013 rape case. However, he will remain incarcerated as he seeks bail in another case.</p><ul><li>Asaram, 83, was convicted for raping a teenager in his Jodhpur ashram in 2013.</li><li>He has been sentenced to life imprisonment for the crime.</li><li>The court granted bail until March 31, with restrictions on meeting followers.</li><li>Police are instructed to escort him only for medical treatment.</li><li>Asaram's lawyers cited serious medical ailments in their request for bail.</li></ul><blockquote>Asaram is suffering from serious medical ailments.</blockquote><p>The court's decision reflects ongoing legal proceedings amid his multiple convictions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rape-convict-asaram-bapu-gets-interim-bail-from-supreme-court-on-medical-grounds-7418065</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/rape-convict-asaram-bapu-gets-interim-bail-from-supreme-court-on-medical-grounds-7418065</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:22:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Budget 2025: Raise income tax exempt limit to Rs 10 lakh - RSS Unions tell FM Sitharaman - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RSS Unions Urge FM Sitharaman to Raise Income Tax Exempt Limit to Rs 10 Lakh in Budget 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The RSS unions have called on Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman to increase the income tax exemption limit to Rs 10 lakh in the upcoming Budget 2025, emphasizing the need for financial relief for middle-class taxpayers.</p><ul><li>The current income tax exemption limit is lower, causing financial strain on families.</li><li>RSS unions argue that raising the limit will stimulate consumer spending.</li><li>Increased exemption is viewed as a necessary step towards economic recovery.</li></ul><blockquote>"A revision of the exemption limit will enhance disposable income and spur economic activity," said a union representative.</blockquote><p>This request reflects the growing concerns of the middle class regarding rising living costs and the desire for more favorable tax provisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/budget-2025-raise-income-tax-exempt-limit-to-rs-10-lakh-rss-unions-tell-fm-sitharaman/articleshow/117014377.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/budget-2025-raise-income-tax-exempt-limit-to-rs-10-lakh-rss-unions-tell-fm-sitharaman/articleshow/117014377.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madhya Pradesh: Doctor arrested for raping colleague inside abandoned govt medical college hostel - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/madhya-pradesh-doctor-arrested-for-raping-colleague-inside-abandoned-govt-medical-college-hostel-101736230427959.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/madhya-pradesh-doctor-arrested-for-raping-colleague-inside-abandoned-govt-medical-college-hostel-101736230427959.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:09:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Allahabad High Court dismisses PIL challenging impeachment motion against Justice SK Yadav - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxPalVGS1I0N2U0aTdqZHotZ3ZzUzN1ZU83M0tOZGFnQTVweUxLR0hab3N3UFpmVFp6cEVha1Jpel8yV1MzQjhSc3JOTHZQdy1vM3NOSGZ2NUNhSmVrV3BTOUJwR1Q1WHBoaFJJUFJ5eWlqOXhNNENwZHNnM1ZSSlRqVU9taGYtaTl1T1B3b2JlcUwwXzRyV003Y0xQdXNKUy1aSEFTSzZic0txakZmSHJyLW0tdWrSAcIBQVVfeXFMTlA4TENjMEN5dVpydV9KWV8wbmxaeWdBS2NrbnVNNkJiQ3NVaWR3ek1yYTVianNBdlJNOGtLSWNXNXdORnBWVGJTV1h1S2dhdmxDLUljN3psRzdRMHVXRzdxX1lTOXg4YUNuS0ROMGxaQzJQeEdPS29reUcta3BndGhpNGozUWtlcUQzRUc3ZWxzcjhCeUpNTmg2TjZmal9xdXRUWjhRRUJCM2xRdkpyaXJtb2Z6MW9kdlJNamNMWUtLU2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxPalVGS1I0N2U0aTdqZHotZ3ZzUzN1ZU83M0tOZGFnQTVweUxLR0hab3N3UFpmVFp6cEVha1Jpel8yV1MzQjhSc3JOTHZQdy1vM3NOSGZ2NUNhSmVrV3BTOUJwR1Q1WHBoaFJJUFJ5eWlqOXhNNENwZHNnM1ZSSlRqVU9taGYtaTl1T1B3b2JlcUwwXzRyV003Y0xQdXNKUy1aSEFTSzZic0txakZmSHJyLW0tdWrSAcIBQVVfeXFMTlA4TENjMEN5dVpydV9KWV8wbmxaeWdBS2NrbnVNNkJiQ3NVaWR3ek1yYTVianNBdlJNOGtLSWNXNXdORnBWVGJTV1h1S2dhdmxDLUljN3psRzdRMHVXRzdxX1lTOXg4YUNuS0ROMGxaQzJQeEdPS29reUcta3BndGhpNGozUWtlcUQzRUc3ZWxzcjhCeUpNTmg2TjZmal9xdXRUWjhRRUJCM2xRdkpyaXJtb2Z6MW9kdlJNamNMWUtLU2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Naxalites are rattled': CM Vishnu Sai lifts coffins of jawan killed in Chhattisgarh IED blast - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Naxalites are rattled: CM Vishnu Sai lifts coffins of jawan killed in Chhattisgarh IED blast</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The article discusses a recent incident in Chhattisgarh where CM Vishnu Sai honored the jawans who lost their lives in an IED blast attributed to Naxal militants. It highlights the ongoing conflict in the region and the government's commitment to countering such threats.</p><ul><li>The incident took place in Chhattisgarh, a region affected by Naxalite violence.</li><li>CM Vishnu Sai attended the funerals, demonstrating respect and support for the families of the deceased jawans.</li><li>Local authorities are under pressure to improve security measures in light of the attack.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will not bow down to Naxal threats. Their activities will not deter our will to protect our state.” - CM Vishnu Sai</blockquote><p>This tragic event underscores the continuing conflict in Chhattisgarh and the sacrifices made by security forces in the fight against insurgency.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/naxalites-are-rattled-cm-vishnu-sai-lifts-coffins-of-jawan-killed-in-chhattisgarh-ied-blast/articleshow/117014668.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/naxalites-are-rattled-cm-vishnu-sai-lifts-coffins-of-jawan-killed-in-chhattisgarh-ied-blast/articleshow/117014668.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UGC proposes major overhaul in recruitment of Assistant Professors, Vice Chancellors - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxOOUlnZkIwVVZ5bWR2SlpNVXNPZl9qMlFTTXY3VXk0b1IwRkhGODFHZ2E4VV9ldVB4LVd4UEJSWlRyRUJTQTUwb3pnc2xqWHJsaWpSU3BtSGdoQWFWX2lpQjMyZ0VCQVJJbG9ZWjNYRFRhM1Q1QXNXLVJZNV9OcnhRbHFMbnhLSHBiR1lUUzRQYkNKa3Y0U00wN2Nsd0VCOUlRM25hTGZTMTFNdDY4UlI3Nm1mQy1icWhjakJwTUhIWFozLUXSAcsBQVVfeXFMTXVxQmZuZUFPOVBpXzUtVF9oWXBnUFBzT0U4UjV3Q3NmTU5JUnY1V1U5UzJ1LWpibUI5NmNWd3BDREZOZjZaVFVOWTduckIxdERCZEQzaEZad0VmZ2VCSW12TGJGbGZuR05mc19sZ29SRDBvQnlRdmhybjZMWVhyY1dSRkxoSmQ3VmNTVkltODdBMjlKcXFFZHBudTMzWmxrWC1VUHJOSHdKMVFhVW1KeHlkTGZwVkg5Q2pNX3pDUGk4Y2x2MEoxYkRCNjQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxOOUlnZkIwVVZ5bWR2SlpNVXNPZl9qMlFTTXY3VXk0b1IwRkhGODFHZ2E4VV9ldVB4LVd4UEJSWlRyRUJTQTUwb3pnc2xqWHJsaWpSU3BtSGdoQWFWX2lpQjMyZ0VCQVJJbG9ZWjNYRFRhM1Q1QXNXLVJZNV9OcnhRbHFMbnhLSHBiR1lUUzRQYkNKa3Y0U00wN2Nsd0VCOUlRM25hTGZTMTFNdDY4UlI3Nm1mQy1icWhjakJwTUhIWFozLUXSAcsBQVVfeXFMTXVxQmZuZUFPOVBpXzUtVF9oWXBnUFBzT0U4UjV3Q3NmTU5JUnY1V1U5UzJ1LWpibUI5NmNWd3BDREZOZjZaVFVOWTduckIxdERCZEQzaEZad0VmZ2VCSW12TGJGbGZuR05mc19sZ29SRDBvQnlRdmhybjZMWVhyY1dSRkxoSmQ3VmNTVkltODdBMjlKcXFFZHBudTMzWmxrWC1VUHJOSHdKMVFhVW1KeHlkTGZwVkg5Q2pNX3pDUGk4Y2x2MEoxYkRCNjQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:41:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases live: Centre, health experts appeal for calm after five test positive - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV cases live: Odisha begins testing at several places following Centre advisory</h1><p><strong>Date: January 6, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/INDIA-HEALTH-VIRUS-HMPV-1_1736229640384_1736229653380.jpg" alt="A woman wearing a face mask walks outside a hospital in Bengaluru amid concerns over HMPV." title="A woman wearing a face mask walks outside a hospital in Bengaluru on January 6, 2025, amid concerns and alleged media reports on the spread of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV)."><figcaption>A woman wearing a face mask walks outside a hospital in Bengaluru on January 6, 2025, amid concerns over HMPV.</figcaption><p>The article discusses the initiation of testing for Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) in Odisha following guidance from the Centre after isolated cases were reported. It emphasizes the health measures being undertaken across various states.</p><ul><li>Five cases of HMPV reported across India.</li><li>Odisha has started testing at several locations.</li><li>Symptoms include mild cold-like signs, with serious risks for young children and immunocompromised individuals.</li><li>No significant outbreak reported, and health officials urge calm.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no need to panic,” said Gujarat Health Minister Rushikesh Patel.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while HMPV cases are being monitored, officials stress preparedness and public awareness over alarm.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-cases-live-updates-centre-health-experts-appeal-for-calm-after-five-test-positive-101736216169211.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-cases-live-updates-centre-health-experts-appeal-for-calm-after-five-test-positive-101736216169211.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:26:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telangana High Court refuses to quash FIR against BRS MLA KT Rama Rao in Formula E Race case - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Telangana High Court Upholds FIR Against BRS MLA KT Rama Rao in Formula E Race Funding Case</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 07 Jan 2025, 6:22 am</p><figure><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="Justice K Lakshman" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Justice K Lakshman</figcaption></figure><p>The Telangana High Court has refused to quash an FIR against BRS MLA K.T. Rama Rao related to allegations of corruption in the Formula E race funding case. The ruling comes amid claims of political vendetta and serious charges against Rao.</p><ul><li>Justice K Lakshman dismissed the plea to quash the FIR.</li><li>The FIR involves charges of criminal breach of trust and violations of the Prevention of Corruption Act.</li><li>The allegations stem from irregularities in funding for the Formula E race, which was cancelled after the Congress took power.</li><li>Rao's counsel argued the case is politically motivated.</li><li>The State's Advocate General noted serious allegations against Rao, including alleged misappropriation of funds.</li></ul><blockquote>“Rao cannot be prosecuted simply on account of a policy decision taken in 2023.” - KTR's Senior Advocate C Aryama Sundaram</blockquote><p>The court's decision reinforces serious scrutiny over the financial dealings associated with significant events in Telangana.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/telangana-high-court-refuses-quash-fir-brs-mla-kt-rama-rao-formula-e-race-case</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/telangana-high-court-refuses-quash-fir-brs-mla-kt-rama-rao-formula-e-race-case</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:22:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court Enhances Compensation For B.Tech Student Who Got Disabled After Motor Accident To Rs. 48... - Live Law - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxNVllBMkJ1U093LVJkaDY1bk9pX2RxQmZBVlVOQjBoUFN5OXJyV0tSR0NpOHZyRHpHRHR1TFNDcFhKa204bUhMWXp3c0ppOGpyR19nMTJ5ZVM1SVN4R21rS3pqSVBGWlMzRm1YcmZqZTFJRVRzMWJsQU9TQnV4XzVjS1RNeTN4c25Vc0hmT0hSME9GV1dhVE1HVVowM3hRU2llUDY1bkhoLXI0UjFxWE5CLVVSNldTOERqczZURURDVVJrU1ZtejVHdjlrSEZXakV0M01TVkZ1V0pUN3R0LUcycnBR0gHnAUFVX3lxTFBMeHBMUnNhdUw4ZjlrbklFQ0FQVGp5TnpBVTM5RTJIMXViY29VVjl1NmVtNkx3VDlwdm9BQkVxMHloaV9LTi0wS2tTRTNFWUZibzhpTDhoRnQ0ZnIweXNqem9zb0V3VUROTWppcC1yVFJ4VEJvN0pTZ24wTk9Vbmcwejh2YmJSelFoVkJVZmdIUkpBSnlOcXFhQWk3N3d3ejBOV0ZvUDl2SWxyVnpfQUdKdGt4Tkdpb2xJX3R2TjZfd2V2OWJzbXVqTjJ2am10NTRhQTNHbGtzY0MwTGFpbjhTb0lEcHc2Yw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxNVllBMkJ1U093LVJkaDY1bk9pX2RxQmZBVlVOQjBoUFN5OXJyV0tSR0NpOHZyRHpHRHR1TFNDcFhKa204bUhMWXp3c0ppOGpyR19nMTJ5ZVM1SVN4R21rS3pqSVBGWlMzRm1YcmZqZTFJRVRzMWJsQU9TQnV4XzVjS1RNeTN4c25Vc0hmT0hSME9GV1dhVE1HVVowM3hRU2llUDY1bkhoLXI0UjFxWE5CLVVSNldTOERqczZURURDVVJrU1ZtejVHdjlrSEZXakV0M01TVkZ1V0pUN3R0LUcycnBR0gHnAUFVX3lxTFBMeHBMUnNhdUw4ZjlrbklFQ0FQVGp5TnpBVTM5RTJIMXViY29VVjl1NmVtNkx3VDlwdm9BQkVxMHloaV9LTi0wS2tTRTNFWUZibzhpTDhoRnQ0ZnIweXNqem9zb0V3VUROTWppcC1yVFJ4VEJvN0pTZ24wTk9Vbmcwejh2YmJSelFoVkJVZmdIUkpBSnlOcXFhQWk3N3d3ejBOV0ZvUDl2SWxyVnpfQUdKdGt4Tkdpb2xJX3R2TjZfd2V2OWJzbXVqTjJ2am10NTRhQTNHbGtzY0MwTGFpbjhTb0lEcHc2Yw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:13:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assam mine: Three feared dead as India deploys divers, helicopters to rescue trapped miners - CNN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Three Feared Dead as India Deploys Divers, Helicopters to Rescue Trapped Miners</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/2025-01-07t064841z-2059715318-rc2u4caxli0o-rtrmadp-3-india-mining-accident.jpg?c=original" alt="Divers use a pulley to enter a coal mine to rescue trapped miners in Umrangso, a remote area in the northeastern state of Assam, India, January 7, 2025."><figcaption>Divers use a pulley to enter a coal mine to rescue trapped miners in Umrangso, Assam.</figcaption><p>Three miners are feared dead inside a flooded coal mine in Assam, India, as rescue teams work overnight to reach nine men trapped inside the mine.</p><ul><li>Rescue teams reported spotting three bodies but have not yet recovered them.</li><li>The army has deployed divers, helicopters, and engineers for rescue operations.</li><li>The incident occurred due to flooding in the mine, likely caused by hitting a water channel.</li><li>Coal mining disasters are common in northeastern India, with past incidents resulting in significant casualties.</li></ul><blockquote>“The mine got flooded yesterday — the source was internal. They probably hit some water channel and water came out and flooded it,” Mayank Kumar, district police chief in Dima Hasao.</blockquote><p>The rescue operation is ongoing, with efforts focused on reaching the nine trapped miners and recovering the bodies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/07/india/india-trapped-miners-feared-death-intl-hnk/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/07/india/india-trapped-miners-feared-death-intl-hnk/index.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GATE 2025 Admit Card Released on gate2025.iitr.ac.in, Direct Link - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GATE 2025 Admit Card Released on gate2025.iitr.ac.in, Direct Link</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today. <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-117007286,thumbsize-459624,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/117007286.jpg" alt="GATE 2025 Admit Card Today at gate2025.iitr.ac.in, Exam From February 1" title="GATE 2025 Admit Card Today at gate2025.iitr.ac.in, Exam From February 1"/>
<figcaption>GATE 2025 Admit Card Today at gate2025.iitr.ac.in, Exam From February 1</figcaption>
<p>The Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering (GATE) admit card has been released today, serving as a crucial document for candidates.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Essential for admission to postgraduate programs in IITs and IISc.</li>
  <li>Must carry the admit card and a valid photo ID to the exam center.</li>
  <li>GATE scores are also used by PSUs for recruitment.</li>
  <li>Conducted jointly by IITs and IISc.</li>
</ul>
<h3>GATE 2025 Hall Ticket: Here's how to download admit card</h3>
<ol>
  <li>Visit the official website - <a href="https://gate2025.iitr.ac.in/">gate2025.iitr.ac.in</a></li>
  <li>Access the GOAPS portal and log in.</li>
  <li>Enter enrollment ID and password.</li>
  <li>Download the admit card.</li>
</ol>
<p>The GATE exam will occur on February 1, 2, 15, and 16, 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/education/gate-2025-admit-card-released-at-gate2025-iitr-ac-in-hall-ticket-direct-link-article-117007203</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/education/gate-2025-admit-card-released-at-gate2025-iitr-ac-in-hall-ticket-direct-link-article-117007203</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HMPV cases live: Centre advises states to strengthen awareness measures - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>HMPV cases live: Centre advises states to strengthen awareness measures</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/INDIA-HEALTH-VIRUS-HMPV-1_1736229640384_1736229653380.jpg" alt="A woman wearing a face mask walks outside a hospital in Bengaluru on January 6, 2025, amid concerns and alleged media reports on the spread of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV)." title="A woman wearing a face mask walks outside a hospital in Bengaluru on January 6, 2025, amid concerns and alleged media reports on the spread of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV)."><figcaption>A woman wearing a face mask walks outside a hospital in Bengaluru on January 6, 2025, amid concerns and alleged media reports on the spread of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV).</figcaption><p>Health authorities are advising states to increase public awareness and preparedness as five cases of Human Metapneumovirus (HMPV) infections have been reported in India. The Centre emphasizes that these infections are manageable and not a cause for panic.</p><ul><li>Five cases of HMPV reported in India, with no widespread outbreak.</li><li>Children under 3 and immunocompromised individuals advised to take precautions.</li><li>Health systems are being prepared to manage potential surges in cases.</li><li>Public health guidelines are being issued to strengthen awareness.</li><li>Health experts state that HMPV has been circulating globally since its identification in 2001.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no need to panic. The government is ready for any situation.” - Uttar Pradesh Deputy Chief Minister Brajesh Pathak</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while cases of HMPV have been identified, health experts reassure the public that it is not a new virus, and normal precautions should suffice to prevent serious illness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-cases-live-updates-centre-health-experts-appeal-for-calm-after-five-test-positive-101736216169211.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/hmpv-cases-live-updates-centre-health-experts-appeal-for-calm-after-five-test-positive-101736216169211.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:00:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Months After RG Kar Horror, Junior Doctor Raped By Colleague At Gwalior Hostel, Accused Arrested - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/months-after-rg-kar-horror-junior-doctor-raped-by-colleague-in-gwalior-hostel-accused-arrested-9180419.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/months-after-rg-kar-horror-junior-doctor-raped-by-colleague-in-gwalior-hostel-accused-arrested-9180419.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:49:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Months After RG Kar Horror, Junior Doctor Raped By Colleague At Gwalior Hostel, Accused Arrested - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/months-after-rg-kar-horror-junior-doctor-raped-by-colleague-in-gwalior-hostel-accused-arrested-9180419.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/months-after-rg-kar-horror-junior-doctor-raped-by-colleague-in-gwalior-hostel-accused-arrested-9180419.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:49:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three feared dead as India deploys divers, helicopters to rescue trapped miners - CNN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Three feared dead as India deploys divers, helicopters to rescue trapped miners</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p><p>Three miners are feared dead inside a flooded coal mine in Assam, India, while rescue teams are desperately trying to reach the trapped individuals.</p><ul><li>Three bodies have been spotted but not yet recovered.</li><li>A total of nine men have been trapped since Monday in the mine.</li><li>Rescue operations involve army teams deploying divers and helicopters.</li><li>The mine flooded due to an internal water channel that was likely hit by the miners.</li><li>Previous coal mine disasters in northeastern India highlight ongoing safety concerns.</li></ul><blockquote>“The mine got flooded yesterday — the source was internal. They (the miners) probably hit some water channel and water came out and flooded it,” - Mayank Kumar, district police chief in Dima Hasao.</blockquote><p>Efforts continue as local authorities and rescue teams strive to recover those trapped and prevent further loss of life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/07/india/india-trapped-miners-feared-death-intl-hnk/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/07/india/india-trapped-miners-feared-death-intl-hnk/index.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi Assembly poll schedule LIVE updates: Election Commission to announce dates at 2 p.m. - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Delhi Assembly poll schedule LIVE updates: Election Commission to announce dates at 2 p.m.</h1>
<p><strong>Date Published:</strong> January 07, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/elections/delhi-assembly/p3tjj7/article69070951.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/ELECTION%20COMMISSION%20PC%20JK%20HARYANA_16_08_22.jpg" alt="Chief Election Commssioner Rajiv Kumar during a press conference in New Delhi." />
<figcaption>Chief Election Commssioner Rajiv Kumar during a press conference in New Delhi. | Photo Credit: Sushil Kumar Verma</figcaption>
<p>The Election Commission of India is set to announce the schedule for the Delhi Assembly elections today at 2 p.m. Follow live updates on developments.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The upcoming elections will have a three-cornered contest between BJP, Congress, and AAP.</li>
  <li>AAP leader Arvind Kejriwal has announced ₹10 lakh insurance for auto drivers.</li>
  <li>The turnout for new voter registrations is unprecedented, with an increase of over 1.67 lakh names on the electoral roll.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I wrote to the Chief Election Commissioner, with all these details, on how the large scale voter scam is happening in the New Delhi Assembly constituency.” – Atishi, Delhi Chief Minister.</blockquote>
<p>This election is crucial, as it will shape political dynamics in Delhi.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/elections/delhi-assembly/delhi-assembly-election-schedule-election-commission-live-updates/article69070928.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/elections/delhi-assembly/delhi-assembly-election-schedule-election-commission-live-updates/article69070928.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar visits Konark Sun Temple in Odisha ahead of Pravasi Bharatiya Divas - OTV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>S Jaishankar Visits Konark Sun Temple Ahead of Pravasi Bharatiya Divas</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> OTV News</p><img src="https://images.odishatv.in/uploadimage/library/16_9/16_9_0/recent_photo_1736227667.webp" alt="External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar visits Konark Sun Temple" title="External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar visits Konark Sun Temple" width="916" height="515"><figcaption>Photo: OTV</figcaption><p>Ahead of the <a href="https://odishatv.in/tag/pravasi-bharatiya-divas" target="_blank">Pravasi Bharatiya Divas</a> in Odisha, Indian External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar visited the Konark Sun Temple and Interpretation Centre.</p><ul><li>Jaishankar commenced his visit at the Interpretation Centre, which showcases the cultural significance of Konark.</li><li>Non-Resident Indians (NRIs) gathered in Bhubaneswar for the Pravasi Bharatiya Divas celebrations.</li><li>Attendees visited the sacred Jagannath Temple in Puri, seeking blessings.</li><li>The event emphasizes the connection between India and its overseas citizens while showcasing Odisha’s cultural heritage.</li></ul><blockquote>Several visitors expressed their joy and appreciation for the spiritual experience at the Konark Sun Temple.</blockquote><p>This visit fosters a deeper connection for NRIs with their heritage, enriching their cultural experience in Odisha.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/external-affairs-minister-s-jaishankar-visits-konark-sun-temple-in-odisha-252881</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://odishatv.in/news/odisha/external-affairs-minister-s-jaishankar-visits-konark-sun-temple-in-odisha-252881</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:32:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Money Cannot Substitute Life Lost But Effort Has To Be Made For Granting Just Compensation: SC Enhances... - Verdictum]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Money Cannot Substitute Life Lost But Effort Has To Be Made For Granting Just Compensation: SC Enhances...</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>The Supreme Court enhanced the compensation awarded to a victim of a motor accident, emphasizing the need for just compensation despite the fact that money cannot replace a lost life.</p><ul><li>The Supreme Court allowed an appeal, increasing the compensation from the Motor Accident Claims Tribunal (MACT) to Rs. 48,00,000.</li><li>The High Court was found to have “utterly failed” to properly assess other compensation aspects aside from loss of income.</li><li>The Appellant, a B.Tech student, suffered 60% permanent disability due to a truck accident caused by negligent driving.</li><li>The Supreme Court noted the MACT’s inadequate compensation for non-pecuniary losses.</li><li>The court stated that an effort must be made to provide just compensation as financial restitution.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is well accepted norm that money cannot substitute a life lost but an effort has to be made for grant of just compensation so far as money can compensate.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Supreme Court's ruling bolsters the importance of comprehensive compensation assessments in personal injury cases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.verdictum.in/court-updates/supreme-court/atul-tiwari-v-regional-manager-oriental-insurance-co-ltd-2025-insc-29-money-cannot-substitute-life-lost-just-compensation-1563609</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.verdictum.in/court-updates/supreme-court/atul-tiwari-v-regional-manager-oriental-insurance-co-ltd-2025-insc-29-money-cannot-substitute-life-lost-just-compensation-1563609</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:30:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congress-AIMIM alliance: Revanth Reddy coins ‘Ayya-Miyan unity’ slogan - The Siasat Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Congress-AIMIM alliance: Revanth Reddy coins 'Ayya-Miyan unity' slogan</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Siasat Daily</p>
<img src="https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-38.jpg" alt="Telangana CM to visit hostels in Hyderabad, dine with students" width="1200" height="900">
<figcaption>Telangana CM Revanth Reddy</figcaption>
<p>Hyderabad: Telangana Chief Minister A. Revanth Reddy has officially announced an alliance between Congress and AIMIM to focus on Hyderabad’s development.</p>
<ul>
  <li>“When Ayya and Miyan unite, nothing can stop progress,” said the Chief Minister during the Aramghar flyover inauguration.</li>
  <li>He aims to replace the popular “Jai Meem Jai Bheem” slogan with a Telangana version.</li>
  <li>Key projects include a second cable bridge over Mir Alam Tank, new Osmania General Hospital building, and naming the Aramghar flyover after Manmohan Singh.</li>
  <li>A Congress-AIMIM meeting will take place to discuss future projects and funding.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I am ready to fight Narendra Modi and meet Asaduddin Owaisi for the progress of the state.” - Revanth Reddy</blockquote>
<p>This alliance aims for significant developmental strides in Hyderabad, uniting two major political parties for progress.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.siasat.com/congress-aimim-alliance-revanth-reddy-coins-ayya-miyan-unity-slogan-3160823/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.siasat.com/congress-aimim-alliance-revanth-reddy-coins-ayya-miyan-unity-slogan-3160823/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CRPF DG reaches Chhattisgarh day after deadly Naxal-triggered blast in Bijapur - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/crpf-dg-reaches-chhattisgarh-day-after-deadly-naxal-triggered-blast-in-bijapur-9764127/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/crpf-dg-reaches-chhattisgarh-day-after-deadly-naxal-triggered-blast-in-bijapur-9764127/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:57:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CRPF DG reaches Chhattisgarh day after deadly Naxal-triggered blast in Bijapur - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/crpf-dg-reaches-chhattisgarh-day-after-deadly-naxal-triggered-blast-in-bijapur-9764127/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/crpf-dg-reaches-chhattisgarh-day-after-deadly-naxal-triggered-blast-in-bijapur-9764127/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:57:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Junior Doctor Raped By Colleague In Gwalior Hostel, Accused Arrested - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/cities/junior-doctor-raped-by-colleague-in-gwalior-hostel-accused-arrested-7416570</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/cities/junior-doctor-raped-by-colleague-in-gwalior-hostel-accused-arrested-7416570</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>