<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 17:49:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 17:49:53 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[What Kamala Harris really thinks about Israel and Gaza]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris speaking from behind a lectern." data-caption="Then-Senator Kamala Harris addressing the 2017 American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC) Policy Conference in Washington, DC. | Michael Brochstein/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Michael Brochstein/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-878131632.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Then-Senator Kamala Harris addressing the 2017 American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC) Policy Conference in Washington, DC. | Michael Brochstein/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s war in Gaza created a rift between moderates and progressives in his party. Now that he has stepped aside in the 2024 presidential race, the question is whether Vice President Kamala Harris, the presumptive Democratic nominee, would chart a different path forward as president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One early signal that she might: Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is scheduled to address Congress on Wednesday, and Harris will not preside in her role as vice president due to a previously scheduled event she is attending in Indianapolis. A slew of congressional Democrats (not just progressives) have decided not to attend in <a href="https://rollcall.com/2024/07/23/netanyahu-address-creates-a-dilemma-for-democrats/">protest of Netanyahu’s strategy in Gaza</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris will meet with Netanyahu one-on-one on Wednesday, and the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/harriss-support-for-gaza-cease-fire-hints-at-foreign-policy-shift-bbe8dc2a">Wall Street Journal reported</a> that she is expected to tell him “it is time for the war to end in a way where Israel is secure, all hostages are released, the suffering of Palestinian civilians in Gaza ends, and the Palestinian people can enjoy their right to dignity, freedom, and self-determination.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Only days into her campaign, Harris has yet to articulate her Gaza policy, but the fact that she is not attending Netanyahu’s speech and privately communicating the urgency of a ceasefire signals that she might not follow Biden’s lead in giving the Israeli leader a “<a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/world/biden-netanyahu-bear-hug-disaster/">bear hug</a>.” Biden literally embraced Netanyahu on the tarmac when the president landed in Tel Aviv in November as a symbolic gesture of unequivocal support for Israel, and has since kept the prime minister close metaphorically, offering military and financial support. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Harris does change course, even slightly, that could alter the US-Israel relationship, but could also have important electoral consequences as well.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Does Harris give Democrats a better chance in 2024?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362043/kamala-harris-vice-running-mate-democratic-presidential-ticket" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Who could be Harris’s running mate?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Harris’s strengths and vulnerabilities as a presidential candidate</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What does Kamala Harris think about Israel and the war in Gaza?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris has longstanding ties to the American Jewish community and Israeli interest groups.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her husband, Second Gentleman Doug Emoff, is Jewish and has been at the forefront of the Biden administration’s <a href="https://jewishinsider.com/2024/01/world-economic-forum-davos-antisemitism-herzog-greenblatt-emhoff-rosen/">initiative against antisemitism</a> since Hamas’s October 7 attack on Israel.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She has a good working relationship with Israeli President Isaac Herzog, who <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/kamala-harris-has-long-embraced-jewish-ties-but-critics-take-issue-with-gaza-stance/">shares a passion for climate issues</a>. She has also been on every one of the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/harriss-support-for-gaza-cease-fire-hints-at-foreign-policy-shift-bbe8dc2a">more than 20 phone calls</a> that Biden has had with Netanyahu throughout the war. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In her presidential bid, she has <a href="https://jewishinsider.com/2024/07/kamala-harris-jewish-democrats-vice-president-presidential-race/">won the backing</a> of major Jewish interest groups, including Democratic Majority for Israel, J Street, and the Jewish Democratic Council of America. She also has connections to the <a href="https://x.com/VP/status/1110301531306409986">American Israel Public Affairs Committee</a> (AIPAC) and gave a speech at the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=McK8bPR8pzU">organization’s annual conference in 2017</a> soon after she was elected to the US Senate, saying that one of her first acts in office was to introduce a resolution opposing a United Nations Security Council resolution condemning Israel. At the time, she said, “I believe the bonds between the United States and Israel are unbreakable.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Concerning the war in Gaza, Harris has repeatedly upheld Israel’s “<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">right to defend itself</a>” against Hamas and emphasized that the threat posed by Hamas to Israel must be “<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">eliminated</a>.” This suggests she’s largely in agreement with Biden’s posture. Harris has, however, taken a sharper tone than Biden concerning Israel’s treatment of civilians in Gaza.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a high-profile <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">speech in March</a>, she became the first person in the Biden administration to call for an immediate ceasefire, albeit only a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">temporary</a> one. She also said that the Israeli government must do more to increase the flow of aid to Gaza, “no excuses,” and called the situation in Gaza a “humanitarian catastrophe.” The version of the speech that was ultimately delivered had reportedly <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/white-house/kamala-harris-gaza-speech-watered-down-cease-fire-rcna141750">been softened</a> from its original draft, which more directly criticized Israel for its obstruction of aid trucks into Gaza. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She also has expressed empathy for <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024/4/24/24138333/columbia-student-protests-gaza-nyu-divest-faculty">student protesters on college campuses</a> who are horrified by the death and destruction in Gaza and have attempted to pressure their schools into cutting ties with Israel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They are showing exactly what the human emotion should be, as a response to Gaza,” Harris <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/politics/kamala-harris-interview-profile-excerpt/">told the Nation</a>. “There are things some of the protesters are saying that I absolutely reject, so I don’t mean to wholesale endorse their points. But we have to navigate it. I understand the emotion behind it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If she becomes president, the Wall Street Journal reported that Harris is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/harriss-support-for-gaza-cease-fire-hints-at-foreign-policy-shift-bbe8dc2a">expected to replace</a> some of the chief architects of the Biden administration’s strategy in Gaza, including national security adviser Jake Sullivan, Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin. It’s to be expected that a new president would want their own team in place, but any changes would open up possibilities for taking a different tack.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s national security adviser, Philip Gordon, has emphasized diplomatic rather than military solutions in foreign policy and written extensively about the difficulties of regime change in the Middle East. That background may prove relevant as Israel seeks to root out Hamas and install a new government in Gaza.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this suggests that Harris might be somewhat to Biden’s left on Gaza — but by how much is an open question and one that she will have to clarify. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“She does have an opportunity. She’s using the right language in some instances. But we need a clearer explanation from her on where she stands,” said Abed Ayoub, national legal and policy director of the American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And — as with Joe Biden’s campaign promises to make Saudi Arabia a pariah state — there’s always a chance that what Harris does eventually say while campaigning may change once she’s in office.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Biden’s Gaza policy has been divisive&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Politically, Harris faces the quandary of determining if — and by how much — she should distance herself from Biden’s record on Gaza, which has fractured the Democratic base.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden at one point <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/05/08/congress/progressives-cheer-israel-weapon-pause-gop-fume-biden-00156857">paused shipments of large munitions</a> to Israel over concerns about how they would be potentially used against civilians in Gaza but has otherwise continued to offer material support for the war, even after Israeli operations in Gaza’s southernmost city of Rafah <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/07/middleeast/destruction-inside-rafa-gaza-israel-intl/index.html">wreaked widespread destruction</a>. Over <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-israeli-strikes-southern-gaza-palestinian-death-toll-112159613">39,000 Palestinians</a> have already died in the course of the conflict, according to the Gaza Health Ministry.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In May, Biden called for a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/05/31/politics/biden-middle-east-remarks/index.html">deal to end the war</a> and return the remaining Israeli hostages in Gaza, while continuing to advocate for a two-state solution to the decades-long Israeli-Palestinian conflict. But the Israeli parliament has since voted to <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/israels-knesset-votes-overwhelmingly-palestinian-statehood-netanyahu-p-rcna162466">reject a two-state solution</a> and ceasefire talks are still ongoing two months later.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Monday, Biden promised he would <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/07/22/biden-gaza-war-end-hostages-return-pledge">deliver a ceasefire</a> deal before he leaves office. He did not elaborate on how he plans to overcome the roadblocks that have stalled negotiations thus far.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Progressives have for months been calling on Biden to halt weapons shipments to Gaza and put more pressure on Israel to end the war. Over 650,000 Democrats <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/06/05/biden-uncommitted-primary-vote-00161700">voted “uncommitted”</a> in the primary to protest Biden’s policies, and the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/video/opinion/100000009565908/biden-voters-dearborn-michigan.html">scale of the opposition to Biden in the Midwest</a> appeared as though it could have tipped the election in Trump’s favor in swing states including Michigan and Wisconsin. Depending on how Harris positions herself, she could win back some of those voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think there is excitement that [Biden] is not at the top of the ticket,” said Layla Elabed, a Palestinian American organizer in Michigan who helped lead the uncommitted movement, and the sister of Rep. Rashida Tlaib (D-MI). “But we are also right now watching and listening to what Harris is going to do next.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Overall, however, Democrats and Republicans <a href="https://www.newsnationnow.com/world/war-in-israel/most-americans-support-israel-over-hamas-poll/">remain largely supportive</a> of Israel’s campaign. Since Israel’s establishment in 1948, the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/10/11/politics/presidents-israel-cnn/index.html">US has maintained a special relationship with the country</a>. It has been the largest cumulative recipient of American foreign aid since its founding, <a href="https://www.cfr.org/article/us-aid-israel-four-charts">totaling about $310 billion</a> (adjusted for inflation) in total economic and military assistance.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For these reasons, it’s unlikely that Harris will deviate substantially from Biden on Israel — and if there is any change in her policy, it would be only slight. The question will be whether any changes can win back voters that the president has alienated without losing the voters who embraced his stance.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This leaves Harris with a difficult political tightrope to walk. But unlike Biden, she isn’t weighed down with the direct responsibility for all that has happened so far.&nbsp;</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/362782/kamala-harris-gaza-israel-palestine-biden-netanyahu</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/362782/kamala-harris-gaza-israel-palestine-biden-netanyahu</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Narea]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 17:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump rally gunman used weapon with 'collapsible stock']]></title><description><![CDATA[FBI Director Christopher Wray told a congressional committee it likely made the rifle easier to conceal.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp9vp4mkjpdo</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp9vp4mkjpdo</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 17:12:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What one Moscow square says about Russia's worsening relations with West]]></title><description><![CDATA[Moscow Mayor Sergei Sobyanin has signed an order renaming Europe Square Eurasia Square. ]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4ng8e3j72yo</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4ng8e3j72yo</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 17:34:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[World Leaders React to Biden Campaign Decision]]></title><description><![CDATA[Foreign leaders did not wade into the turmoil of U.S. politics. Many opted instead for statements of empathy that lauded the president’s record.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/21/world/europe/biden-election-world-leaders-reaction.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/21/world/europe/biden-election-world-leaders-reaction.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 11:46:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hillary Clinton urges Americans to rally around Kamala Harris: ‘a fresh start’ - The Guardian US]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxOZkl0VG8zUzZUOVVOS2hmcWplRTBWYUtibUg2NVRZTzAyRnJDVTIwcHhIYWJIcGo5cC1XQkVabTZJdm9IenhiblZkMnVXbklvYlUteV9HbkJjYk4tX2NTdl93OGRWakN2QUd5TC05eHBiNzRyTXBXZk5GdzR3T2pFTVF6M05kSFlldXBaUGRFV1BSUXUzM1JGakFkaTZ4d9IBngFBVV95cUxPdVZVR21mN1hoNTZZcWZRWEZLTFQwX2htcTIyRWJsdzVHN3FHY0ZHdWpxeFp2dFNHa0JkeWRQUlp6SDZGWnp6UnpHQlBkNDBBelNTUWtlX1NxRnNwNlZrVl8tVGp4aUpCTlEweXNZS2t0M3pET2cwZl8yMTdJVlRjWjlEc3ZwclFpbUtxSFktbGtsSnpxVTJ4TVk0cWlCQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Hillary Clinton urges Americans to rally around Kamala Harris: ‘a fresh start’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2pzbFA3X0N4R3FEbUItSDlxZnZDZ0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxOZkl0VG8zUzZUOVVOS2hmcWplRTBWYUtibUg2NVRZTzAyRnJDVTIwcHhIYWJIcGo5cC1XQkVabTZJdm9IenhiblZkMnVXbklvYlUteV9HbkJjYk4tX2NTdl93OGRWakN2QUd5TC05eHBiNzRyTXBXZk5GdzR3T2pFTVF6M05kSFlldXBaUGRFV1BSUXUzM1JGakFkaTZ4d9IBngFBVV95cUxPdVZVR21mN1hoNTZZcWZRWEZLTFQwX2htcTIyRWJsdzVHN3FHY0ZHdWpxeFp2dFNHa0JkeWRQUlp6SDZGWnp6UnpHQlBkNDBBelNTUWtlX1NxRnNwNlZrVl8tVGp4aUpCTlEweXNZS2t0M3pET2cwZl8yMTdJVlRjWjlEc3ZwclFpbUtxSFktbGtsSnpxVTJ4TVk0cWlCQQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxOZkl0VG8zUzZUOVVOS2hmcWplRTBWYUtibUg2NVRZTzAyRnJDVTIwcHhIYWJIcGo5cC1XQkVabTZJdm9IenhiblZkMnVXbklvYlUteV9HbkJjYk4tX2NTdl93OGRWakN2QUd5TC05eHBiNzRyTXBXZk5GdzR3T2pFTVF6M05kSFlldXBaUGRFV1BSUXUzM1JGakFkaTZ4d9IBngFBVV95cUxPdVZVR21mN1hoNTZZcWZRWEZLTFQwX2htcTIyRWJsdzVHN3FHY0ZHdWpxeFp2dFNHa0JkeWRQUlp6SDZGWnp6UnpHQlBkNDBBelNTUWtlX1NxRnNwNlZrVl8tVGp4aUpCTlEweXNZS2t0M3pET2cwZl8yMTdJVlRjWjlEc3ZwclFpbUtxSFktbGtsSnpxVTJ4TVk0cWlCQQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Labour delays proposals to ban oppressive Slapps lawsuits]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Labour justice minister in Lords says there is ‘need to protect access to justice’ for legitimate claims</p><p>Labour has delayed proposals to tackle spurious lawsuits brought by oligarchs and others aimed at intimidating journalists, academics and campaigners.</p><p>Frederick Ponsonby, a Labour justice minister in the House of Lords, said he could not commit to bringing forward standalone legislation on strategic lawsuits against public participation, known as Slapps, or set out a timetable for tackling the issue.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/article/2024/jul/24/labour-delays-proposals-to-ban-slapps-lawsuits">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/article/2024/jul/24/labour-delays-proposals-to-ban-slapps-lawsuits</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/article/2024/jul/24/labour-delays-proposals-to-ban-slapps-lawsuits</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 17:37:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thousands of protesters near Capitol ahead of Netanyahu’s address to Congress – live]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Capitol Hill on high alert for protests from a broad coalition of groups voicing opposition to Benjamin Netanyahu, who will address Congress later today</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/24/netanyahu-congress-protests-security">Capitol Hill on alert over protests as Netanyahu due to address Congress</a></li></ul><p><strong>Kevin McCarthy</strong>, the former Republican House speaker, has described attacks by his former colleagues on <strong>Kamala Harris</strong> claiming that she was hired as part of diversity, equity and inclusion (DEI) initiatives are “stupid and dumb”.</p><p>McCarthy, speaking to NBC News’ Meet the Press NOW last night, said:</p><p>I disagree with DEI, but she is the vice-president of the United States, she is the former US senator. These congressmen saying it, they are wrong in their own instincts.</p><p>If President Biden is committed to passing the torch to his vice president, and wants to be able to seed her campaign with the current Biden for President campaign war chest, he’ll first have to become his party’s legal nominee. After shuffling through the Democratic National Committee’s planned roll call vote he’d be free to drop out. Ms Harris could seamlessly slip into the driver’s seat.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/jul/24/harris-biden-trump-vance-latest-us-election-news-updates">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/jul/24/harris-biden-trump-vance-latest-us-election-news-updates</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/jul/24/harris-biden-trump-vance-latest-us-election-news-updates</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 17:35:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pro-Palestinian activists protest TV show’s fake encampment in New York]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Demonstrators at Queens College called the film shoot for CBS drama FBI: Most Wanted ‘propaganda’</p><p>A fake protest encampment set up for a TV shoot on a New York City college campus sparked a real reaction from pro-Palestinian activists, who organized their own demonstration against the filming, a newspaper reported on Wednesday.</p><p>The scenario unfolded on Monday and Tuesday at Queens College, where the CBS drama FBI: Most Wanted was filming an upcoming episode involving a climate change protest, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/24/nyregion/queens-college-protest-encampment.html">the New York Times reported</a>.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/24/pro-palestine-protest-fbi-most-wanted">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/24/pro-palestine-protest-fbi-most-wanted</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/24/pro-palestine-protest-fbi-most-wanted</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 17:27:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Marjorie Taylor Greene's Attack On Secret Service Director Manages To Backfire]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/marjorie-taylor-greenes-attack-secret-000531157.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/marjorie-taylor-greenes-attack-secret-000531157.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:05:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>