<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:20:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:20:04 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump targeted in assassination attempt]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Donald Trump raises a fist, with blood running down his face, as Secret Service agents hurry him forward." data-caption="Republican presidential candidate former President Donald Trump pumps his fist as he is rushed offstage during a rally on July 13, 2024, in Butler, Pennsylvania. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161923146.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Republican presidential candidate former President Donald Trump pumps his fist as he is rushed offstage during a rally on July 13, 2024, in Butler, Pennsylvania. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Former President Donald Trump was whisked off stage at a campaign rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, on Saturday, July 13, after gunshots erupted, including one that he said pierced his right ear. Trump was quickly escorted by Secret Service agents to a local medical facility and is “fine,” his campaign said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The suspected gunman, identified <a href="https://www.fbi.gov/news/press-releases/fbi-statement-on-incident-in-butler-pennsylvania">by the FBI</a> as 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks from Bethel Park, Pennsylvania, is dead, as is one person who attended the rally.<strong> </strong>Two more attendees were critically injured.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I heard a whizzing sound, shots, and immediately felt the bullet ripping through the skin,” Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/112782066045321247">wrote</a> afterward on Truth Social. “Much bleeding took place, so I realized then what was happening.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a brief <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/donald-trump-rally-shooting-joe-biden-statement/">televised statement</a>, President Joe Biden condemned the violence as “sick,” urging Americans to condemn political violence. Biden spoke with Trump on the phone, and his reelection campaign is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/trump-rally-incident/card/biden-campaign-to-pull-down-television-ads-yWBcGSbQDl4lfoGSgXOk">reportedly</a> pulling down television ads in the wake of the shooting.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is a developing story. Follow here for the latest news and analysis.</p>
<ul>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360516/trump-assasination-attempt-democracy-threat-rhetoric-critics-violence-politics-biden">Heated rhetoric is dangerous, but honest disagreement is necessary for democracy</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360521/trump-shooting-polls-political-impact-2024-election-election">Will Trump’s shooting change everything? Or surprisingly little?</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360390/trump-shot-assassination-attempt-shooter-bullet-butler-pennsylvania-biden-secret-service-updates">Who shot Trump? What we know about the assassination attempt.</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360587/who-shot-trump-what-we-know-about-the-assassination-attempt">Who shot Trump? What we know about the assassination attempt.</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360428/trump-assassination-attempt-pennsylvania-shooting-politics">America is not ready for what comes next</a>
		</li>
	</ul>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/360489/trump-shot-thomas-matthew-crooks-secret-service-butler-rally</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/360489/trump-shot-thomas-matthew-crooks-secret-service-butler-rally</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Vox Staff]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:03:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Heated rhetoric is dangerous, but honest disagreement is necessary for democracy]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Republican presidential candidate former President Donald Trump is rushed offstage during a rally on July 13, 2024 in Butler, Pennsylvania. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161922289.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Republican presidential candidate former President Donald Trump is rushed offstage during a rally on July 13, 2024 in Butler, Pennsylvania. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Donald Trump was nearly <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360390/trump-shooting-butler-pa-pennsylvania-ear-secret-service">assassinated on Saturday</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The former president was addressing a crowd in Butler, Pennsylvania, when a 20-year-old carried a rifle onto a nearby roof. That gunman, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/pidgin/articles/cxe27v3gr2ro">Thomas Matthew Crooks</a>, proceeded to fire several bullets at Trump, injuring the Republican’s ear, killing a male rallygoer, and wounding another. Security forces then shot Crooks dead.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is a tragedy for those directly harmed. Crooks stole life from a person and thus, a loved one from many other people. And he almost certainly traumatized many others, not least the Republican standard-bearer himself.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Saturday’s events are also a nightmare for the country. While riven by increasingly bitter political conflict over the past two decades, the United States had managed to avoid deadly assassination attempts against presidential candidates. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Keeping America’s “culture war” purely metaphorical is not easy. Fights over questions as fundamental as “Who counts as an American?” and “When does human life begin?” are not easily contained within the bounds of the democratic process. Occasionally, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/06/24/1107244499/storycorps-remembering-a-murdered-doctor-who-performed-abortions">they get people killed</a>. Erode the taboo against resolving these disputes through force, and you clear a path to mass death.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is therefore vital for all of America’s political factions to forswear political violence. In the wake of this weekend’s assassination attempt, however, some have called on partisans to do more than this: They have suggested that we must not merely condemn violence, but also avoid rhetoric that could hypothetically inspire it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some of these calls are patently cynical. For example, Ohio Senator J.D. Vance <a href="https://x.com/JDVance1/status/1812280973628965109">argued</a> Saturday that the “central premise of the Biden campaign is that President Donald Trump is an authoritarian fascist who must be stopped at all costs” and that this “rhetoric led directly to President Trump&#8217;s attempted assassination.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the time of Vance’s statement, nothing was known about the shooter’s motives. Thus, the senator did not know whether what he was saying was true. As of this writing, there is still no evidence that Crooks was motivated by the belief that Trump was an authoritarian. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More fundamentally, though, it is absurd for an ardent supporter of Donald Trump to feign a principled opposition to incendiary rhetoric. The former president has likened his political enemies to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2023/11/12/trump-rally-vermin-political-opponents/">“vermin</a>,” accused Joe Biden of trying to “<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-says-bidens-border-policies-are-conspiracy-overthrow-us-2024-03-02/">overthrow the United States”</a> by orchestrating mass immigration, and said that if the Democrat wins, “our country doesn’t stand a chance.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, not all calls for cooler rhetoric were disingenuous. The great science writer Robert Wright, whose politics are decidedly left of center, <a href="https://x.com/robertwrighter/status/1812277878748299340">posted on X</a> Saturday, “Why don’t we just skip the argument about which side has used more extreme rhetoric about the other side, which side used it first, etc. There’s been way too much on both sides. If you agree, maybe the best thing to do is politely discourage people on your own side from using it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This sentiment is understandable but imprecise. It is wrong to say things that are untrue, and when dishonest rhetoric is also politically incendiary, it is especially irresponsible. But we cannot have an honest and open debate about our political disagreements without saying things that an unhinged person might construe as a rationale for violence. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Donald Trump really does present a threat to the norms of liberal democracy and the welfare of millions of US residents. Joe Biden truly supports the legality of medical procedures that some Christian conservatives believe to be murder. Rhetoric that describes in good faith our polity’s disputes will imply that our elections have life-or-death stakes — because they do. Political violence is not wrong because our conflicts aren’t profound. It’s wrong because it undermines democracy. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Biden’s most heated rhetoric about Trump is defensible</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is no question that Joe Biden has denounced Trump in explosive terms. In late June, the president <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1806745000971296833">posted on</a> X, “Donald Trump is a genuine threat to this nation. He’s a threat to our freedom. He’s a threat to our democracy. He’s literally a threat to everything America stands for.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s last sentence here was arguably hyperbolic, but the president’s other claims are defensible. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many Americans reasonably believe that people who are compelled to carry a pregnancy to term are not free. Through his Supreme Court appointments, Trump is personally responsible for the <a href="https://www.vox.com/explainers/356314/abortion-laws-roe-wade-dobbs-decision-mifepristone-supreme-court">curtailment of reproductive rights</a> in many parts of the United States. Although he has <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/04/10/politics/trump-says-he-wouldnt-sign-federal-abortion-ban/index.html">disavowed</a> all intentions of further restricting abortion at the federal level, he is nevertheless <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/4/8/24124454/trump-abortion-policy-video-truth-social">closely aligned</a> with a movement that aims to do so. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump has also promised to carry out “<a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/documents/2024-republican-party-platform">the largest deportation operation in American history</a>.” This policy would <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/11/us/politics/trump-2025-immigration-agenda.html">reportedly involve</a> rounding up longtime US residents, confining them to detention camps, and then deporting them. Many undocumented immigrants were brought to the US as children and know no other home. It seems reasonable to say that Trump presents a threat to their freedom. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That Trump poses a threat to democracy should go without saying. As president, he attempted to block the peaceful transfer of power by <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/trump-demands-georgia-secretary-state-find-votes-hand/story?id=75027350">manipulating vote counts</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23513019/january-6-committee-report-trump-2020-election-insurrection">instigating a riot on Capitol Hill</a>. He has also outlined <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/17/us/politics/trump-plans-2025.html">plans for undermining</a> the independence of federal law enforcement while vowing to enact “<a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/trumps-dark-retribution-pledge-center-2024-bid-make/story?id=108315702">retribution</a>” on his movement’s enemies. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is highly unlikely that a second Trump administration would lead to the death of American democracy, as our nation’s federated system of government makes establishing an authoritarian regime exceptionally difficult. But it’s reasonable to say that putting an insurrectionist back into the Oval Office — after he’s had four years to assemble <a href="https://www.axios.com/2023/11/13/trump-loyalists-2024-presidential-election">a cadre of loyalists</a> to staff the executive branch — would pose an intolerably high threat to US democracy, even if that threat is remote. Most of us would not engage in any activity that came with a 1 percent risk of death if we could help it. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Heated rhetoric is an inextricable feature of democratic life</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My point here is not to say that Democrats’ incendiary rhetoric is always legitimate while Republicans’ is not. What matters is whether a given statement is plausibly true. We cannot honestly debate our nation’s core political disagreements without saying things that could inspire intense passion in partisans. Political passion is the kindling for political violence, but public officials must not compound the unavoidable hazards of democratic life by saying explosive things that are untrue. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2018, Donald Trump suggested that Democrats were orchestrating an invasion of the United States by violent <a href="https://x.com/realdonaldtrump/status/1009071403918864385?lang=en">“illegal immigrants”</a> because they viewed such criminals as “potential voters.” Republican Rep. Matt Gaetz argued that the Jewish, Democratic megadonor George Soros might be paying immigrants to “<a href="https://twitter.com/repmattgaetz/status/1052629557826736129">storm the US border @ election time</a>.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Shortly thereafter, a neo-Nazi who believed that Jews were orchestrating an invasion of the United States by violent Central American migrants — as part of a broader plan to render the white race incapable of reclaiming power in the US — murdered <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/10/what-we-know-about-robert-bowers-alleged-synagogue-shooter.html">11 people in a Pittsburgh synagogue</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The fundamental problem with Trump&#8217;s and Gaetz’s claims was not that they were liable to inspire violent malcontents to commit such atrocities. The problem was that they were spreading baseless conspiracy theories. If it were true that Democrats were orchestrating an invasion of the United States as part of a plan to enact mass voter fraud, Trump and Gaetz would be right to say so, even though this could provoke acts of violence. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it wasn’t true. Falsely claiming that your political opponents are trying to steal an election through mass voter fraud is wildly irresponsible; implying that conservative Americans should see immigrants as threats to their democratic freedom is something even worse.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By contrast, if a Republican were to say that Biden posed a massive threat to human life as defined by conservative Christian theology, they would be telling the truth. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I do not believe that a fetus is a person, but many Americans subscribe to a worldview in which it is. There can be no simple, scientific truth about a question as philosophical as when human life begins. In a pluralistic democracy, conservative Christians must be allowed to articulate the implications of their theology, even if that means portraying Democratic supporters of abortion rights as would-be mass murderers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a democracy with polarized politics, many legitimate forms of advocacy will imply that preventing an adversarial politician from taking power is of life-or-death importance. In a country with more guns than people, such political speech presents genuine hazards. If we find those risks unacceptable, we should curtail gun ownership before we constrict honest debate.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/360516/trump-assasination-attempt-democracy-threat-rhetoric-critics-violence-politics-biden</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/360516/trump-assasination-attempt-democracy-threat-rhetoric-critics-violence-politics-biden</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Levitz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 20:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Will Trump’s shooting change everything? Or surprisingly little?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Republican presidential candidate former President Donald Trump is rushed offstage during a rally on July 13, 2024, in Butler, Pennsylvania. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2161925534.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Republican presidential candidate former President Donald Trump is rushed offstage during a rally on July 13, 2024, in Butler, Pennsylvania. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It didn’t take long after the <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360390/trump-shot-assassination-attempt-shooter-bullet-butler-pennsylvania-biden-secret-service-updates">attempted assassination of President Donald Trump</a>, the killing of one of his rally attendees, and the injury of two others, for the political world’s attention to turn to a crass but undeniably important topic: What will it mean for Trump politically?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Among commentators and social media posters, there have basically been two separate instinctive — and conflicting — reactions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first reaction: This is a political boon for Trump that makes him more likely to win in November. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The second reaction: Don’t get too carried away, it may not make much of a difference.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not knowing the future, we can’t really say for sure. But there are somewhat convincing points behind each of them. Here are the arguments being put forward.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will the shooting be a tremendous help to Trump?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">History is full of examples of leaders who use a near-miss assassination attempt as an excuse to centralize power and crack down on civil liberties. Since Trump is not in office, he can’t do that right now, and the main question is whether it will affect his ability to win. Many (including some <a href="https://x.com/SteveSchmidtSES/status/1812272029959373146">vocal Trump critics</a>) believe it will dramatically help his chances for some combination of the following reasons.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>It will activate the MAGA base:</strong> For much of this year, there has been low interest in political news on both sides of the aisle, but there have been questions about whether Trump’s base in particular was less mobilized than they were in years prior. Conservative news sites were seeing <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2024/04/conservative-digital-media-traffic/678055/">dismal traffic</a> numbers and Trump’s campaign <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/03/18/trump-campaign-cash-crunch-small-dollar-donor-fatigue-major-donor-nerves.html">was struggling </a>with small-donor fundraising. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That began to change after Trump’s criminal conviction on May 30, which <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/20/us/politics/trump-fundraising-biden-election.html">unleashed</a> a massive surge in donations to Trump’s campaign that erased Biden’s cash edge. Perhaps the assassination attempt on Trump will be a similar catalyst: a lightning shock of attention that makes his base rally to his side and ensures they’ll turn out at the polls.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>It could make him win sympathy from— or look tough to — a general electorate:</strong> Sometimes, if a leading politician is shot but survives, there is a wave of sympathy and support for them. When President Ronald Reagan was shot (and much more seriously injured) in 1981, his approval increased from about 60 percent to about 68 percent <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/11887/ronald-reagan-from-peoples-perspective-gallup-poll-review.aspx">in Gallup polls</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Trump, much digital ink was spilled analyzing the potential political value of photos taken of him just after the shooting, most notably <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/07/13/republicans-back-trump-by-sharing-a-bloody-photo-of-the-former-president-00167980">Evan Vucci’s Associated Press photo</a> showing a bloodied Trump raising his fist while the American flag is behind him. His fans <a href="https://x.com/LoganPaul/status/1812264550731043074">opined</a> on social media that it made him look “<a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1812260638569177510">tough</a>,” with many making the comparison to the 1912 incident when Theodore Roosevelt was shot during a campaign speech and finished his speech. (The comparison is not perfect: Trump did not finish his speech, and Roosevelt lost that election.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>It could help him among low-trust voters:</strong> Some commentators, like <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/351563/one-explanation-for-the-2024-elections-biggest-mystery">my colleague Eric Levitz</a>, have argued that a major trend in politics is that “voters with low levels of trust in society and the political system are shifting rightward.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless of the facts around the shooting, the conspiracy theories around it will inevitably be twisted to advance the narrative that “they” — Democrats, the media, shadowy powers that be — wanted this to happen and are in some way responsible for it. Some of Trump’s allies <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/07/13/trump-shooting-blame-biden-democrats/">are already publicly advancing</a> such arguments; if they resonate, they could further expand the GOP’s emerging advantage among low-trust voters.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Or will it not make much of a difference?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Often, when pundits are hyping a supposedly game-changing political moment, it’s useful to take a step back and skeptically ask: Will it actually change much of anything?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>The election is still nearly four months away:</strong> It is a long time between now and November 5, 2024. Many other events will consume the news between now and then; just last week, the biggest political story was whether Joe Biden could hold onto the nomination. It is very far from clear that this is the one event that will loom over the rest of a campaign that is still a ways off from concluding.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Polling in this race has long been static:</strong> Trump and Biden are two very well-known candidates and polling in this race <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/national/">hasn’t moved much</a> throughout the campaign. For instance, Biden’s bad debate — one of the most dramatic events of the cycle — only <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/national/">lowered his standing</a> in national polling averages by about 2 points.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It has been very difficult to budge the Trump/Biden polling. As shocking as this event was, the vast majority of voters have long made up their views about Trump and seem quite unlikely to change their minds because of his injury. And if there is a short-term “sympathy bounce” for Trump, it may not last.&nbsp; (Reagan’s approval bounce after he was shot <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/11887/ronald-reagan-from-peoples-perspective-gallup-poll-review.aspx">only lasted a few months</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>The shooter may not fit easy political narratives:</strong> We don’t yet know anything about 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks’s motive for shooting Trump, and conspiracy theorists won’t care too much about the facts. Depending on what we do learn about his background and motivations, arguments blaming Democrats or shadowy power brokers for his actions may not come off as convincing to many voters in the general public.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">We don’t yet know how Trump will respond</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another difficulty in predicting exactly what this will mean is that we don’t yet know exactly how Trump will respond.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One could imagine him trying to stay above the fray, sound presidential, and use broadly appealing rhetoric to bring the country together.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In reality, he is still Donald Trump, a politician frequently motivated by grievance and <a href="https://www.voanews.com/a/trump-s-vows-of-revenge-against-his-opponents-gain-volume-/7650528.html">revenge</a>. Being who he is, he could well overreach, turning off voters he might have a chance of winning to his side, and convincing them that restoring him to the office would mean yet more turmoil.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So nothing is set in stone. The assassination attempt on Trump did not guarantee his victory. It could help his chances. But the campaign will be about more than what happened on Saturday.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/360521/trump-shooting-polls-political-impact-2024-election-election</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/360521/trump-shooting-polls-political-impact-2024-election-election</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Prokop]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 20:42:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden, Trump Call For Unity After Assassination Attempt Stuns US]]></title><description><![CDATA[Rivals Joe Biden and Donald Trump urged Americans to show unity Sunday after an assassination attempt on the Republican put the nation on edge in the run-up to the presidential election.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-trump-call-for-unity-after-assassination-attempt-stuns-us-6106463</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-trump-call-for-unity-after-assassination-attempt-stuns-us-6106463</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 20:20:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[WATCH: Biden addresses the nation after receiving briefing on Trump rally shooting - PBS NewsHour]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvcG9saXRpY3Mvd2F0Y2gtbGl2ZS1iaWRlbi1hZGRyZXNzZXMtdGhlLW5hdGlvbi1hZnRlci1yZWNlaXZpbmctYnJpZWZpbmctb24tdHJ1bXAtcmFsbHktc2hvb3RpbmfSAYABaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cucGJzLm9yZy9uZXdzaG91ci9hbXAvcG9saXRpY3Mvd2F0Y2gtbGl2ZS1iaWRlbi1hZGRyZXNzZXMtdGhlLW5hdGlvbi1hZnRlci1yZWNlaXZpbmctYnJpZWZpbmctb24tdHJ1bXAtcmFsbHktc2hvb3Rpbmc?oc=5" target="_blank">WATCH: Biden addresses the nation after receiving briefing on Trump rally shooting</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">PBS NewsHour</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2prNUluLUN4RTFmOUxqOU94Z0RTZ0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvcG9saXRpY3Mvd2F0Y2gtbGl2ZS1iaWRlbi1hZGRyZXNzZXMtdGhlLW5hdGlvbi1hZnRlci1yZWNlaXZpbmctYnJpZWZpbmctb24tdHJ1bXAtcmFsbHktc2hvb3RpbmfSAYABaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cucGJzLm9yZy9uZXdzaG91ci9hbXAvcG9saXRpY3Mvd2F0Y2gtbGl2ZS1iaWRlbi1hZGRyZXNzZXMtdGhlLW5hdGlvbi1hZnRlci1yZWNlaXZpbmctYnJpZWZpbmctb24tdHJ1bXAtcmFsbHktc2hvb3Rpbmc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvcG9saXRpY3Mvd2F0Y2gtbGl2ZS1iaWRlbi1hZGRyZXNzZXMtdGhlLW5hdGlvbi1hZnRlci1yZWNlaXZpbmctYnJpZWZpbmctb24tdHJ1bXAtcmFsbHktc2hvb3RpbmfSAYABaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cucGJzLm9yZy9uZXdzaG91ci9hbXAvcG9saXRpY3Mvd2F0Y2gtbGl2ZS1iaWRlbi1hZGRyZXNzZXMtdGhlLW5hdGlvbi1hZnRlci1yZWNlaXZpbmctYnJpZWZpbmctb24tdHJ1bXAtcmFsbHktc2hvb3Rpbmc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 16:50:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA['This was a security breakdown from start to finish': Chris Swecker - Fox News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CCAiC3dQUVI2MDBOYXZvmAEB?oc=5" target="_blank">'This was a security breakdown from start to finish': Chris Swecker</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2kyNEtfLUN4RnI1VVFZR3pNazBTZ0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CCAiC3dQUVI2MDBOYXZvmAEB?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CCAiC3dQUVI2MDBOYXZvmAEB?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 12:45:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine has right to strike military targets within Russian territory, Stoltenberg says]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e3bo8f/ukraine_has_right_to_strike_military_targets/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/uZ58gNYJcMDvyZcrOUUdJ9bQ9DTrpiI1lfAd87qTeVo.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=59d68d9fc39dc8398d7c9c9837af34ad22a1b57e" alt="Ukraine has right to strike military targets within Russian territory, Stoltenberg says" title="Ukraine has right to strike military targets within Russian territory, Stoltenberg says" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/BlazeBoltBlitz"> /u/BlazeBoltBlitz </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://kyivindependent.com/ukraine-has-right-to-strike-military-targets-within-russian-territory-stoltenberg-says/?utm_source=flipboard&amp;utm_content=topic%2Fukrainecrisis">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e3bo8f/ukraine_has_right_to_strike_military_targets/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e3bo8f/ukraine_has_right_to_strike_military_targets/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e3bo8f/ukraine_has_right_to_strike_military_targets/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/BlazeBoltBlitz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 20:13:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scotland's former first minister Humza Yousaf faces probe after quarter-million donation to Gaza]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e3bwuu/scotlands_former_first_minister_humza_yousaf/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/QFQ1YFwQnnzkJnfJOgXoiUVshWjUq2bD7VaG52ZU_zc.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=3c313545eb363f7f7a484feeda795e916c8403f5" alt="Scotland's former first minister Humza Yousaf faces probe after quarter-million donation to Gaza" title="Scotland's former first minister Humza Yousaf faces probe after quarter-million donation to Gaza" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Ask4MD"> /u/Ask4MD </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.jpost.com/international/article-810318">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e3bwuu/scotlands_former_first_minister_humza_yousaf/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e3bwuu/scotlands_former_first_minister_humza_yousaf/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e3bwuu/scotlands_former_first_minister_humza_yousaf/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Ask4MD]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 20:26:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[China, Russia start joint naval drills, days after NATO allies called Beijing a Ukraine war enabler]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e38xpt/china_russia_start_joint_naval_drills_days_after/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/SdXxkiKJKZBtKvA16hteDk8Pz-awyWMlyThskWgsy-s.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=42718d84ddaee36df0ec34182429e2b62e31855b" alt="China, Russia start joint naval drills, days after NATO allies called Beijing a Ukraine war enabler" title="China, Russia start joint naval drills, days after NATO allies called Beijing a Ukraine war enabler" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/PoorIsTheNewSwag"> /u/PoorIsTheNewSwag </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://apnews.com/article/china-russia-joint-naval-drills-nato-ukraine-08590a566d76ae1ddc47dde7cea8ad1a">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e38xpt/china_russia_start_joint_naval_drills_days_after/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e38xpt/china_russia_start_joint_naval_drills_days_after/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1e38xpt/china_russia_start_joint_naval_drills_days_after/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/PoorIsTheNewSwag]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 18:11:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump rally shooting breeds social media lies and sick conspiracies. What's wrong with us?]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/trump-rally-shooting-breeds-social-012506275.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/trump-rally-shooting-breeds-social-012506275.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 01:25:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Neighbor speaks out amid investigation at Trump rally gunman's home]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/neighbor-speaks-amid-investigation-trump-152311710.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/neighbor-speaks-amid-investigation-trump-152311710.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 15:23:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Melania Trump Gives Rare Statement After Donald Trump's Rally Shooting]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/melania-trump-gives-rare-statement-145425591.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/melania-trump-gives-rare-statement-145425591.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 14:54:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gun in assassination attempt belonged to Trump shooter's father, sources say]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/gun-assassination-attempt-belonged-trump-192239292.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/gun-assassination-attempt-belonged-trump-192239292.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 19:22:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Suspect in Trump rally shooting had explosive materials in vehicle, source says]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/suspect-trump-rally-shooting-had-161555875.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/suspect-trump-rally-shooting-had-161555875.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 16:15:55 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>