<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:01:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:01:22 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[A GOP Supreme Court will now decide the fate of transgender Americans]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Protesters hold pro-LGBTQ signs and flags outside the Supreme Court building. | Erik McGregor/LightRocket via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Erik McGregor/LightRocket via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-1174752369.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Protesters hold pro-LGBTQ signs and flags outside the Supreme Court building. | Erik McGregor/LightRocket via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hard to imagine a worse time for the Supreme Court to hear <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/united-states-v-skrmetti/"><em>United States v. Skrmetti</em></a>, arguably the most important trans rights case the justices have ever heard. <em>Skrmetti</em> asks whether discrimination against transgender people can violate the Constitution, a question the Court has never answered.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A decision against the trans plaintiffs in <em>Skrmetti</em>, moreover, could potentially upend the entire legal framework protecting Americans from gender discrimination of all kinds.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A Court with a 6-3 Republican supermajority plans to hear <em>Skrmetti</em> in early December, less than a month after an election in which, according to the Washington Post, GOP campaigns “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2024/11/05/election-trans-sports-trump-campaign/">spent at least $215 million</a> on network ads that paint trans people as a menace to society.” President-elect Donald Trump made <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-harris-transgender-politics-61cff97a64fac581ffc5f762be4c57d3">anti-trans rhetoric a key part of his campaign</a>, promising, for example, that if elected, he would keep “transgender insanity the hell out of our schools, and we will keep men out of women’s sports.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That is to say: This case arrives at a moment in which the Republican Party is all in on animus toward transgender people. And, while there are strong legal arguments supporting the pro-trans rights position in <em>Skrmetti</em>, this panel of justices has shown <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/371361/supreme-court-call-republican-justices-republicans">great deference to the general mood of the Republican Party</a> in past decisions, like when they ruled that Trump may <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">use his official presidential powers to commit crimes once he returns to office</a>. If the Court’s Republican majority is determined to reach an anti-trans result, they likely won’t let something as trivial as “the law” discourage them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, at least two of the Court’s Republicans have shown unexpected sympathy toward LGBTQ litigants in the past. In <a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=15591206893890926746&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=6&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr"><em>Bostock v. Clayton County</em></a> (2020), the Court ruled that a longstanding ban on sex discrimination in employment prohibits discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity — declaring that “it is impossible to discriminate against a person for being homosexual or transgender without discriminating against that individual based on sex.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Bostock</em> was authored by Justice Neil Gorsuch, a Trump appointee, and joined by Chief Justice John Roberts, who is also a Republican. So, if Roberts and Gorsuch hold to the views they expressed in <em>Bostock</em>, the two of them plus the three Democratic justices should be enough to extend at least some constitutional protection to trans people.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What’s at stake in <em>Skrmetti</em>?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The specific issue in <em>Skrmetti </em>is a Tennessee law prohibiting trans youth from receiving medical treatments such as puberty blockers and hormone therapy. About <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/371341/supreme-court-new-term-transgender-ghost-guns-porn-vapes">half of states</a> have laws targeting transgender health care, but Tennessee’s is among the strictest.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While the Court has never held specifically that discrimination against transgender people violates the Constitution, it has long held that <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/9/18/20917757/justice-ginsburg-ruth-bader-ginsburg-dies">sex discrimination does violate the Constitution</a>, ruling that “<a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=1428365285620704265&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=6&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr">all gender-based classifications</a>” are presumptively unconstitutional in <em>United States v. Virginia</em> (1996).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tennessee’s law trips over itself to classify young patients based on their gender. It declares that the law’s purpose is to “<a href="https://casetext.com/statute/tennessee-code/title-68-health-safety-and-environmental-protection/health/chapter-33-health-and-welfare-of-minors/section-68-33-101-findings">encourag[e] minors to appreciate their sex</a>” and to prevent young people from becoming “disdainful of their sex.” The law also denies certain medical treatments to patients based solely on their sex. A patient who was assigned male at birth may have testosterone prescribed by a doctor, but someone assigned female at birth may not have that treatment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Again, the Supreme Court has already said that <em>all </em>gender-based classifications are constitutionally dubious. “All” means “all.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Will that be enough to persuade these justices to strike down Tennessee&#8217;s law? The honest answer is, “Who knows?” It’s not like legal texts and Supreme Court precedents play no role in these justices’ decision-making, and they sometimes even hand down a decision like <em>Bostock</em> that cuts strongly against the Republican Party’s policy preferences.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there are two reasons to be pessimistic about <em>Skrmetti</em>. One is that after the recent election, anti-trans voices within the Court are likely to be emboldened, and pro-trans voices may feel like they have limited political capital. The other is that, while Tennessee’s law clearly discriminates on the basis of sex, the Court has only held that laws that do so should be presumed to be unconstitutional unless — as the Court put it in <em>Virginia — </em>there’s an “exceedingly persuasive justification” for the law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is possible that this Court will hold that a ban on trans health care meets this bar.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What current law says about “sex” discrimination, explained</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many of federal law’s core safeguards against sex discrimination emerged in the 1960s and 1970s. Beginning in the ’60s, Congress started to pass laws banning sex discrimination in various venues — Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, for example, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/6/15/21291515/supreme-court-bostock-clayton-county-lgbtq-neil-gorsuch">prohibits such discrimination in employment</a>. Then, in the 1970s, the Court began to place constitutional limits on the government’s ability to discriminate on the basis of sex.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The most significant of these cases, <a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=2528522570594071994&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=6&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr"><em>Craig v. Boren</em></a> (1976), established that any government action that classifies people based on sex is presumptively unconstitutional. Again, in <em>Virginia, </em>the Court stated that “a party seeking to uphold government action based on sex must establish an ‘<a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=1428365285620704265&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=6&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr">exceedingly persuasive justification</a>’ for the classification.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The federal appeals court that heard <em>Skrmetti</em> attempted to get around <em>Craig</em> and <em>Virginia</em> by pointing to the Supreme Court’s decision in <a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=4447817874641898447&amp;q=geduldig+v.+aiello&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=6,47&amp;as_vis=1"><em>Geduldig v. Aiello</em></a> (1974). But that decision read <em>Geduldig </em>far too broadly.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Briefly, <em>Geduldig</em> concerned a state-run insurance program that provided benefits to some California workers with disabilities, but not to workers whose disabilities arose out of a pregnancy. The Supreme Court rejected the argument that this exclusion for pregnant workers discriminated on the basis of sex, even though the Court wrote that “only women can become pregnant.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Geduldig</em>, it should be noted, is not a particularly beloved decision. Four years after it was handed down, Congress enacted the <a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/statutes/pregnancy-discrimination-act-1978">Pregnancy Discrimination Act</a>, which repudiated <em>Geduldig</em> in the workplace and forbade employers from discriminating on the basis of pregnancy. Regardless, <em>Geduldig</em>’s holding was limited. It established that the government may set up public benefit programs that exclude medical procedures “<a href="https://casetext.com/case/l-w-v-skrmetti-3">that only one sex can undergo</a>.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Skrmetti</em>, by contrast, involves medical procedures that both sexes can undergo. Anyone can take puberty blockers, testosterone, or estrogen. It is not physically impossible to administer testosterone to someone assigned female at birth in the same way that it is physically impossible for a person without a uterus to become pregnant.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Not all sex discrimination is forbidden</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given the Court’s decisions in <em>Craig</em> and <em>Virginia</em>, it should be obvious that Tennessee&#8217;s law draws distinctions based on sex and thus can only survive if the state can offer an “exceedingly persuasive justification” for it. Indeed, if the Court were to reject that conclusion, it would do considerable violence to the legal principles governing all gender discrimination cases.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, even if the Court honors the <em>Craig</em>/<em>Virginia</em> framework, Tennessee’s law could potentially survive if five of the justices deem the state’s arguments for the law sufficiently persuasive.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The briefs in the <em>Skrmetti</em> case paint two very different pictures of why medical professionals treat transgender patients with puberty blockers or hormones. A <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/23/23-477/323551/20240827210326240_23-477tsUnitedStates.pdf">brief filed by the Biden administration</a>, for example, warns that the absence of these treatments can lead patients with gender dysphoria (the medical term for the distress that can result when someone’s gender identity does not match their sex assigned at birth) to “‘debilitating distress,’ ‘depression,’ ‘substance use,’ ‘self-injurious behaviors,’ and ‘even suicide.’” One <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/68/wr/mm6803a3.htm">survey</a> referenced in the brief found that more than one-third of transgender high school students attempted suicide in the last 12 months.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This view, which presents gender-affirming treatments as a way to prevent suicide and alleviate the harms of gender dysphoria, is supported by briefs filed by medical and mental health groups such as the <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/23/23-477/323885/20240903123631640_23-477%20Amicus%20Brief%20of%20American%20Psychological%20Association%20et%20al..pdf" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/23/23-477/323885/20240903123631640_23-477%20Amicus%20Brief%20of%20American%20Psychological%20Association%20et%20al..pdf">American Psychological Association</a>, the <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/23/23-477/323964/20240903155151548_23-477%20tsac%20Brief%20of%20Amici%20Curiae%20AAP%20et%20al..pdf">American Academy of Pediatrics, the World Professional Association for Transgender Health (WPATH), and the American Medical Association</a> — among other, similar professional organizations.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/23/23-477/327730/20241008130915048_23-477%20Respondents%20Brief.pdf">Tennessee’s brief</a>, meanwhile, presents a much more conspiratorial picture. At one point, for example, it claims that a transgender official within the Biden administration pressured the WPATH to issue inappropriately permissive guidelines on trans health care for physicians. At another point, it suggests that a major hospital in Tennessee started providing transgender health care because doing so would “make a lot of money” for the hospital.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Do Tennessee&#8217;s arguments meet the threshold of an “exceedingly persuasive justification”? It’s worth noting that the trial court which heard <em>Skrmetti</em>, the only court to closely examine the evidence on either side of the case, temporarily blocked Tennessee’s law during an early hearing in this case. Of course, it’s possible that a full trial will reveal that Tennessee&#8217;s more conspiratorial view of the facts is correct, but there’s good reason to be skeptical that all of the major professional organizations representing pediatricians, psychologists, trans health providers, and physicians generally are all engaged in a grand conspiracy to make more money by overmedicating transgender children.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">There’s some chance the Court will hit pause on this case</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is some chance that the Court will delay resolution of this case, although probably not for very long.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the lower courts, both the Biden administration and lawyers for a group of transgender plaintiffs argued the pro-trans position. After they lost in the appeals court, both the <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/united-states-v-skrmetti/">Justice Department</a> and the <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/l-w-v-skrmetti/">private plaintiffs</a> asked the justices to hear their case. Although these two petitions present similar questions, the Court decided only to grant the Justice Department’s request to hear the case — which is why the case is currently called <em>United States v. Skrmetti</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus far, the Court has taken no action on the private plaintiffs’ petition, which is known as <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/l-w-v-skrmetti/"><em>L.W. v. Skrmetti</em></a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ordinarily, the Court’s decision to grant one petition and not the other wouldn’t matter very much. But it is exceedingly likely that the Trump administration will reverse the Justice Department’s position on this case once it takes power in January and formally withdraw its request for the justices to hear this case. That means that if the justices want to hold on to the case past January, they will need to grant the <em>L.W.</em> petition.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Realistically, none of these procedural maneuvers are likely to change much. It’s possible that the Court will delay oral arguments until all of this is resolved. But, if the justices want to resolve the issue presented by <em>Skrmetti</em>, there’s no reason why the Court can’t decide this case in its current term (which means a decision is likely in late June), regardless of how the procedural drama shakes out.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/scotus/385198/supreme-court-transgender-united-states-skrmetti</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/scotus/385198/supreme-court-transgender-united-states-skrmetti</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian Millhiser]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump picks North Dakota Governor Burgum for interior secretary - Reuters]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxOMVlTcTkxdDJFcDUxRDlYYUgxbnRFamFqclpYNWJoVFJ5LWJ5UlU5Y2Y4S2ozdHA4cVFFQmRkc2wwczVBUmRBRS1HMDlwY2k3TktKaTJDc0ZjVDRKOEVmYzJ1LWZMSnV4c1ptUWNvaEZfdUxEZU5mOTRWX3BodVo0ejVLQzdxNWtDSkg5Zm5QdUR0MXZCZk5iTmtZbWVkczk3TWJVTWI5NzZ5QQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump picks North Dakota Governor Burgum for interior secretary</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPNWNzd0hOYmpDWkJEQmUycGdTQW4xYUhBOHNuUzJUbDJUVTU3amRIMnhSRGMxRWtidnhDeklrUkkySzJOU0NhWE9LT0FKUi1RWTlqT2RGLVpEQzlIMnVlQ2I2MU1fNXVmUzhReUVBMzZzQ3UxN2hUM1pqWWdUWXhxZzJRbVBoWkVWTXR0UmZnanJ4TWxsbU1CM056Tzgta2djaEHSAaIBQVVfeXFMTkJSSkN6bnUxY3diT0xBT3NBZTVjanZrRXFSMHdzSERKWEJ1WG1rbVJqWENtNE9VTjBQNnVqRDJuSXQ2NUNzT2NiRnpQTzJlMlpXWEJTVXI5VTVsMnBzUTR2bWQwTXhZRmVRZENxS3lxamp1b2l2a2pQdjRaRmtVdG9qeEVUN0xWZlJvbGdZMjh4WktPRWNoZTYtZ2lNam1SMWR3?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump’s RFK Jr nomination condemned as ‘public health catastrophe’ – US politics live</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOaDFiVmtna3VwLW0yQ3BSWFFETEczU0lxRWFMUF9DSGoxNUJvTTlRWU1WOUNsUXVmR0xVRnFWLWpTcEdsOUg3YXExa2h5MUZRUExxVU5Uc3l6SWUzYzVZMUlSbGxBa2I4VlBMZjdCa0dVcHQ4ZXJ3REZqT2NwU1h1YkhnVHVYaFZOMy01RzFOQmZJb2p0Nm81Q2pFa3REd3FMMThYS3dQeU14QjFfWUxoQtIBtgFBVV95cUxOQ2lxa2JvdmpsS1ZDWHBIU3JTY3VhZDJYVDVmQloxYkdZWDF3Y0FZSFZEN1BkZFVjU3BvRkpjN1N3eXZaSmhuOGVBQWFGSnRPRlhjMXB2NVdBMmo0aHFzQWxsdGZEaTd2VUFKM0xTLXRpWE9EaG9WQ2ZwTnJWRGNtY0NKREllQlV2MUlRWVU5ckNYWXJadGxjOEFfMHVhOTVhdWFibVI5UVBOU2trdU5jUWlhak91UQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump announces North Dakota Gov. Doug Burgum as Department of the Interior secretary</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxPSUs4aEJKRi0zaDZOTFFkUnNrTDBiQzk2THNOWFFUZXk3alF5RVlQOXR0a2t3NlRzQ1hacW42aVFLM2hucXFyMW9HdGFaY2pnMXBURzdlTnRuMXNFWUlqdWRhVUFPV19YMTRaNzRnVWJ6OW9DSUVwTzRXajVla1M3NW90U3pYa1QzUDJn?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump Picks Burgum for Interior Secretary</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxQRFlvdGFNX2JZMVEzc1ZGVkg0UGd3SkRGRFQtWFhwOG1VMnpQdjc3UlRxM3ByenhiRzJSZmRSbHVLS1JTWFhzQlZtUXFDbGh5M2tVRi0zVGxER2NINUw3WGU1RGhqc0RQTVdJVDJ1X01ZX1N4ZU9yLVNvYUZkeFE3MVA3SlhOU2EyVFFOTkFQcFVQYTBtdUxB?oc=5" target="_blank">Reporter: Trump announces Burgum's proposed role in the 'most Trumpian fashion'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxOMVlTcTkxdDJFcDUxRDlYYUgxbnRFamFqclpYNWJoVFJ5LWJ5UlU5Y2Y4S2ozdHA4cVFFQmRkc2wwczVBUmRBRS1HMDlwY2k3TktKaTJDc0ZjVDRKOEVmYzJ1LWZMSnV4c1ptUWNvaEZfdUxEZU5mOTRWX3BodVo0ejVLQzdxNWtDSkg5Zm5QdUR0MXZCZk5iTmtZbWVkczk3TWJVTWI5NzZ5QQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxOMVlTcTkxdDJFcDUxRDlYYUgxbnRFamFqclpYNWJoVFJ5LWJ5UlU5Y2Y4S2ozdHA4cVFFQmRkc2wwczVBUmRBRS1HMDlwY2k3TktKaTJDc0ZjVDRKOEVmYzJ1LWZMSnV4c1ptUWNvaEZfdUxEZU5mOTRWX3BodVo0ejVLQzdxNWtDSkg5Zm5QdUR0MXZCZk5iTmtZbWVkczk3TWJVTWI5NzZ5QQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 10:34:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Who is the Georgia judge who will decide fate of migrant accused of killing Laken Riley? - CNN]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNN2V0anNodVZWQThBai14TGk3UFgzUzhoZ1VCeUdFZ2tJUmhRRjE4LU1zbFVuSXZ4d09laDllR0tWNFBkNGZqTFZLb1ZFWldCdmRkWGVGZC1pM0dEMTBlTGlMbWNHUTBNNWtzWEZteFdTS0ZmMklNdGVjdngzZm1CWjA4REHSAXtBVV95cUxNZlRtTFBsWVZEc3pZZlAwZjU4dzRTNWFXSW1QLXZocTVxdzh0aWo4Rm5QOHVfUnBwc3BXS3F4MFlLRkJsd2g0cnFrb0gwYllFZEsybmFxMTZ2cDJDTHF6RlRyRDdaVThlTkNaNHVEdlVMUFZ6TW5iMmFHZUU?oc=5" target="_blank">Who is the Georgia judge who will decide fate of migrant accused of killing Laken Riley?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE9jeFBTSzlxWjR3OVh4b2VZSkVJS3Nwd2JUdE9kVGctSU11a2lMY05ZQm4xUVh6ZloxUWQ5WkJ4YzBpWXJsVHkxeng1MFhvRnN3YUhzMHZ2OXpPRmdPQWFsOXg1bEx0RGVuWHNscnpKaHpTRW55TWxDbtIBb0FVX3lxTE9vUEJRQVkzWnNibnI3Yi1kaEp0eHJ3b2V3T0VoMzdEQUdTWlpSRUJib1dxVzBSUmltSkNFYV9KY1R2QjU3RTRVWHA4OENhZE5XaWZfZU4tZGFYUkQ4OWYyT3JYNjJUc2R0V1NRSGVGdw?oc=5" target="_blank">Trial begins today for the undocumented migrant accused of murdering Laken Riley, whose death ignited a political firestorm</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQLWJiRlJfVElDWXB5RlpMUXNJYUxQZnpwOEt2ZFdPZGFmc1RqM2phM19YLUpya1Y2Qllyay1YTHRkZG9YOF92M2ZrT0hKMWpXMm1Kak1CMVFJbnhwWVprcmppTnNZUmNfeS14MWJYdEt6eVc3Z2d4NUwxLTlUMzJIa2FycTRHaHdGNHRHWi1tbnFZd2JKa2FqTXF3bHJ5cDZGTzVnNm5JU2kxVE80QXl3QXpR0gG3AUFVX3lxTFBsdjRJaXdQUjM3dXBpazJPRjh1RHd4LUNnVTFJeDM0UGVnMVRtUWpiRzdfc1Q0SkJfZHh4M25OdGJMbmVIRDNyZENtMXM5V2F6cHRPV2lQZXV4bENmVEVZMlhOSTdhUjlQSHRoQzd6aU1NVmxpZWk1b1JqelRuNEhqTldnMXB6ZjNlNVpHbGFKQkViRVV4dlgwNl9qVGRuUWVINkJGYVRwd0p0djBvRUxrSXFWdU1zbw?oc=5" target="_blank">Laken Riley murder: Illegal immigrant suspect's trial begins after last-minute legal maneuver</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxNVVVNV194Q1VwOXlKbndZOTFqNUJxZmJSbVlZLVM4dWtTYUhIUDYxVERxMkozZkkwZmMwMkw2OE9FeThUT1dOYXI1X05FU2tSbkExUFh3dk91bDhCRUtmaDhKMXAzaUZyWElzbE5TajFJUmRfeHdiX2ZTVE9iMW9ObUNXZ001LVhkMTB2Sm1YWmstNUdfZEtlWmNtUFJRZXhWYWc?oc=5" target="_blank">Trial to begin for the man accused of killing Georgia nursing student Laken Riley</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxNcXRGeUVOYk8zakMtb0xleHlqaV9td1ZpOU01LW1sUVBFcl9RZ0VuUmRUVkRVQTd6VFVmcGkzbkpGanN6a1NLUDJBaGFRLXN4bmNDd19DY2hwMHhIS3dlWmQ2eXpuY0kyX2xuNE10ZlZiUnRwb2hrWmlHQTJKYmtwZFV2Zk93LThOOVNLTl82ZTJYc3VkOGpNdtIBVkFVX3lxTE1HUFp1c0Y0QnJoc1hRaGs1d1J6emRQcFhSV29wS0N1Q3pILVk3YVRIOHFXaG9EN0Q5QjFhT2E5TlBNNjQyekFROUxLU2d6eUFwbXlwelB3?oc=5" target="_blank">Trial for suspect in Georgia nursing student Laken Riley’s death to begin</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNN2V0anNodVZWQThBai14TGk3UFgzUzhoZ1VCeUdFZ2tJUmhRRjE4LU1zbFVuSXZ4d09laDllR0tWNFBkNGZqTFZLb1ZFWldCdmRkWGVGZC1pM0dEMTBlTGlMbWNHUTBNNWtzWEZteFdTS0ZmMklNdGVjdngzZm1CWjA4REHSAXtBVV95cUxNZlRtTFBsWVZEc3pZZlAwZjU4dzRTNWFXSW1QLXZocTVxdzh0aWo4Rm5QOHVfUnBwc3BXS3F4MFlLRkJsd2g0cnFrb0gwYllFZEsybmFxMTZ2cDJDTHF6RlRyRDdaVThlTkNaNHVEdlVMUFZ6TW5iMmFHZUU?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNN2V0anNodVZWQThBai14TGk3UFgzUzhoZ1VCeUdFZ2tJUmhRRjE4LU1zbFVuSXZ4d09laDllR0tWNFBkNGZqTFZLb1ZFWldCdmRkWGVGZC1pM0dEMTBlTGlMbWNHUTBNNWtzWEZteFdTS0ZmMklNdGVjdngzZm1CWjA4REHSAXtBVV95cUxNZlRtTFBsWVZEc3pZZlAwZjU4dzRTNWFXSW1QLXZocTVxdzh0aWo4Rm5QOHVfUnBwc3BXS3F4MFlLRkJsd2g0cnFrb0gwYllFZEsybmFxMTZ2cDJDTHF6RlRyRDdaVThlTkNaNHVEdlVMUFZ6TW5iMmFHZUU?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tulsi Gabbard’s Ties to ‘Cult’ Could Cost Her Intel Job - The Daily Beast]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNNzBPVUVmRUNFbEJvdlkxaGREbWZrMDVaUVJEbU1fZklDb05meEF5czJEV0twWEFmNFhZeTEzZmFtWGZfUTlyUjRjcnFGR0FZNGJLdkJ5YVFJQ0dHU3hHV09mdUo3dGlZTGtzN2tYWEI0OGMwQ2ZnbVo3X2d5STVTLVdPaWluWkpLTTdn?oc=5" target="_blank">Tulsi Gabbard’s Ties to ‘Cult’ Could Cost Her Intel Job</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Daily Beast</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxORTR4R1VHYUlXaVF1RF84LVE3STA3cjJleFVmaHZDcjFhSmo0VzhxRzExSGN4VmE4aHkwMGtIN0NkdGt6QkRULUpCZlg0am5UX1h6OUpybTJBTHdPQ1JVRzMzZmp3czBtX0haQ24wUWdqWWQ4eFBzUW5jVlpEaU1wVkhzU0FGZjdLYV9VVkhiZ3hLd2ZnNU5J0gGcAUFVX3lxTE9BRkozUzNsazdJNWp4TjlVdkstSUN0YmtxWGdiQnNEb2poZ0w0ekQwVUFENGZRc3lSczMyWm5xS0d1YkNvdXdCbGo2Y3dxVjNTQ3FjU2dkbEdMSGgxaS14X19MbXBSTmFMSzlDS3o0bDR2WUkwd2VycDVQeUt3c3pySGNxRlUwZFhTSVU5dkFGLVliRk9FN2JYa0locw?oc=5" target="_blank">Democrats trash Tulsi Gabbard after Trump taps her for DNI post</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE1XajBVYTA1dzlZMFRuMGxqc29lSDllWENjenlnYTVnNEp0YTVGREFhYjBPQ3dZMGpNdlhiemNJQ1o2NmlQU213LU9WMEhvdFNweDB1dGtsYkdqWGVrdDlodkwzeG1jZ1BhcGh4ZWVEZEI3elNna2JMNkh3?oc=5" target="_blank">‘We Are Reeling’: Trump’s Pick of Tulsi Gabbard Alarms Intelligence Community</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">TIME</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxNRTg1TTdNQzJLdlRnU0txNWszanJRdUh3dTRrbWdkaEdiUTVaSnN2YUFCYlBncHpzRVFnQVJhWDcyY0IzOEtBM0FsTTR5WHlKMUN0TDR4YXhfMzBuT1lHb3BiT0YzZlA5XzBuWTlyMlZISnBvdGlqNVYxZGFYdElWOFpzemlmblFQU1pFLUdlazQ2VGpwajliVU9xeGx1aHN1eG94dHRTZVBqN3owalRZdE0xOUM4RVlWWWJ1bkRDQktEWl9CNmExdnJLTUrSAVZBVV95cUxOREc3RUFBaTRtQlhOTVU3blhpaWNsQ3dxdDhWOUV2YmtBNnJiV1NKbzZjdU1rS1hBTVJxcEpUVk5ULXo0VTdMUmNvT2t4bWVuLUFIVXpNZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump's pick for top intel job has been accused of 'traitorous' parroting of Russian propaganda</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNNldfc0Y1aG4xdm10aWhwN2xZYUNRSTJXSDVpYThxc3ZvYXNNN3VxRVRGZEpjYzNYTm5PaHNyYVVIdG9QUnR0MUduX183bzZOckwwbWQyNmpYRnp4SkR1c19kRDVILTRjSmNncWYyV183S015RlhhTmF3Y3Q1SnlsMFhnY2pzTTIxcTF6ZkdiYWFYa2ROdHc?oc=5" target="_blank">‘Left turn and off the bridge’: Trump’s spy pick stuns intel world</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNNzBPVUVmRUNFbEJvdlkxaGREbWZrMDVaUVJEbU1fZklDb05meEF5czJEV0twWEFmNFhZeTEzZmFtWGZfUTlyUjRjcnFGR0FZNGJLdkJ5YVFJQ0dHU3hHV09mdUo3dGlZTGtzN2tYWEI0OGMwQ2ZnbVo3X2d5STVTLVdPaWluWkpLTTdn?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNNzBPVUVmRUNFbEJvdlkxaGREbWZrMDVaUVJEbU1fZklDb05meEF5czJEV0twWEFmNFhZeTEzZmFtWGZfUTlyUjRjcnFGR0FZNGJLdkJ5YVFJQ0dHU3hHV09mdUo3dGlZTGtzN2tYWEI0OGMwQ2ZnbVo3X2d5STVTLVdPaWluWkpLTTdn?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 02:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Live Briefing: Israeli strikes pummel Beirut; enlistment notices sent to ultra-Orthodox Jews]]></title><description><![CDATA[Defense Minister Israel Katz gave the go-ahead for 7,000 draft notices to be sent to ultra-Orthodox Jews, for enlistment in the Israel Defense Forces. ]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/11/15/israel-war-news-hamas-gaza-palestine/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/11/15/israel-war-news-hamas-gaza-palestine/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:38:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Putin attempts whitewashing Russian atrocities in Africa]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1grug6c/putin_attempts_whitewashing_russian_atrocities_in/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/u6Rwy8_j4n40IzI63RkW1jHApSVOXpJ14luj-ZW7ifs.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=5836257c48984b4905651be96dfbc276b18665fd" alt="Putin attempts whitewashing Russian atrocities in Africa" title="Putin attempts whitewashing Russian atrocities in Africa" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/IntlDogOfMystery"> /u/IntlDogOfMystery </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.voanews.com/a/putin-attempts-whitewashing-russian-atrocities-in-africa-/7864339.html">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1grug6c/putin_attempts_whitewashing_russian_atrocities_in/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1grug6c/putin_attempts_whitewashing_russian_atrocities_in/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1grug6c/putin_attempts_whitewashing_russian_atrocities_in/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/IntlDogOfMystery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 11:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sylvester Stallone calls Donald Trump 'second George Washington': 'I mean it']]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/115334911.cms" />“And I'll just say this, and I mean it: When George Washington defended his country, he had no idea that he was going to change the world. ’cause without him, you could imagine what the world would look like. Guess what? We got the second George Washington,” Sylvester Stallone who never identified as a Republican and did not endorse Donald Trump said about Trump. ]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/sylvester-stallone-calls-donald-trump-second-george-washington-i-mean-it/articleshow/115334911.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/sylvester-stallone-calls-donald-trump-second-george-washington-i-mean-it/articleshow/115334911.cms</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:01:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Middle East crisis live: Hamas ‘ready’ for Gaza ceasefire, says senior official]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Senior official Bassem Naim says militant group ‘ready for ceasefire’ and urges Donald Trump to ‘pressure’ 'Israel to ‘end the aggression’</p><p>Wafa, the Palestinian news agency, is reporting that two Palestinian people were killed in an Israeli artillery attack in <strong>Beit Lahiya</strong> in northern Gaza. Three other Palestinians were killed in a separate Israeli airstrike near the general security junction in western <strong>Gaza City</strong>, <a href="https://english.wafa.ps/Pages/Details/151668">according to Wafa</a>. A renewed Israeli assault was launched on the northern part of the Gaza Strip last month, with the Israeli military claiming it was to stop Hamas fighters regrouping there. The <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c77x05l5ze4o">blockage of aid and food deliveries</a> and the targeting of civilian infrastructure, however, have led to accusations that Israel is committing the war crime of seeking to forcibly displace the remaining population. The entirety of northern Gaza has been under Israeli evacuation orders but it is unclear how many people remain.</p><p>We have some comments coming through from <strong>Ali Larijani</strong>, the senior advisor to Iranian supreme leader Ali Khamenei. <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/nov/15/middle-east-latest-lebanon-israel-gaza-hamas-hezbollah?page=with:block-67371cb48f08a588f0fa6f05#block-67371cb48f08a588f0fa6f05">He has been speaking with</a> Lebanese parliament speaker <strong>Nabih Berri</strong> and Lebanon’s caretaker prime minister, Najib Mikati, in Beiurt.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/nov/15/middle-east-latest-lebanon-israel-gaza-hamas-hezbollah">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/nov/15/middle-east-latest-lebanon-israel-gaza-hamas-hezbollah</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/nov/15/middle-east-latest-lebanon-israel-gaza-hamas-hezbollah</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:33:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Smog crisis: pollution envelops Indian capital as Pakistan province declares emergency]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Schools ordered to close in Delhi and Punjab province as neighbouring countries battle dangerous air pollution</p><p>India’s capital, Delhi, has ordered all primary schools to cease in-person classes until further notice while Pakistan’s Punjab province has declared a health emergency, banning construction, shutting schools for another week and moving universities online, as both countries battle an air pollution crisis.</p><p>Delhi and the surrounding metropolitan area, home to more than 30 million people, consistently <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/01/lahore-delhi-choked-smog-pollution-season-india-pakistan">tops world rankings for air pollution in winter</a>, which is estimated to reduce life expectancy for the capital’s residents by up to seven years.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/15/india-smog-delhi-taj-mahal-schools-close-pollution">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/15/india-smog-delhi-taj-mahal-schools-close-pollution</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/15/india-smog-delhi-taj-mahal-schools-close-pollution</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:56:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[December UK interest rate cut unlikely despite GDP slowdown; vaccine-maker shares hit by RFK Jr nomination – business live]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2024/nov/15/uk-gdp-report-growth-economy-labour-pound-ftse-stock-market-business-live-news?filterKeyEvents=false&amp;page=with%3Ablock-6736ec938f08a588f0fa6dc1#block-6736ec938f08a588f0fa6dc1">Latest UK GDP growth report</a> shows UK grew by just 0.1% in July-September, a slowdown on the first half of the year</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2024/nov/15/economy-gdp-uk-treasury-rachel-reeves-budget">Few expected Britain to boom but the GDP figures will worry the Treasury</a></li><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/14/trump-administration-rfk-criticisms">RFK Jr condemned as ‘clear and present danger’ after Trump nomination</a></li><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2024/nov/14/bank-of-england-governor-urges-ministers-to-rebuild-relations-with-eu">Bank of England governor says Brexit has undermined UK economy</a></li></ul><p><strong>Luke Bartholomew, </strong>deputy chief economist at investment group<strong> abrdn</strong>, also points the finger at the budget:</p><p><em> </em>“The economy was always going to slow from<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/article/2024/jun/06/uk-statistics-watchdog-to-investigate-sunaks-use-of-term-economy-going-gangbusters"> the famously “gangbusters” pace of the first half of this year</a>, but the extent of the slowdown is a bit more pronounced than expected.</p><p>With activity growth in September being reported as particularly weak, it is plausible that some of slowing is the result of elevated uncertainty at that time, as firms and households speculated about possible tax changes ahead of the Budget. That said, it is also possible that this just represents normal monthly volatility rather than anything more fundamental.</p><p>“The UK economy stalled over the third quarter. Uncertainty ahead of the Budget probably played a big part, with firms widely reporting a slow-down in decision making. Hopefully this will prove to be a blip. We still expect the economy to return to a path of modest growth in the year ahead. But downside risks to the outlook have increased.</p><p>“The Budget has set off warning lights for business. The hike in National Insurance Contributions alongside other increases to employers’ cost base will add to the burden on business. And it is expected to trigger a more cautious approach to pay, hiring and investment as companies work through what it means for their own budgets.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2024/nov/15/uk-gdp-report-growth-economy-labour-pound-ftse-stock-market-business-live-news">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2024/nov/15/uk-gdp-report-growth-economy-labour-pound-ftse-stock-market-business-live-news</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2024/nov/15/uk-gdp-report-growth-economy-labour-pound-ftse-stock-market-business-live-news</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:50:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[China faces crucial decisions on climate policy during second Trump term]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>After rare accord with Biden White House on climate, China may now be more wary of adopting robust policy measures</p><p>China is facing crucial decisions on its climate policies as its hard-won relationship with the US on tackling the crisis looks set to founder during Donald Trump’s second presidential term.</p><p>World leaders and heads of delegations from many countries gathered at the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/nov/08/cop29-baku-climate-talks-odour-of-oil-return-of-trump-finance">Cop29 UN climate summit</a> are trying to salvage commitments that China has made during Joe Biden’s term, which ends in January.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/nov/15/china-faces-crucial-decisions-on-climate-policy-during-second-trump-term">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/nov/15/china-faces-crucial-decisions-on-climate-policy-during-second-trump-term</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/nov/15/china-faces-crucial-decisions-on-climate-policy-during-second-trump-term</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:00:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pharma shares hit as Trump picks RFK Jr to lead health department]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Choice of vaccine critic knocks some of world’s biggest drugmakers including Moderna, AstraZeneca and GSK</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/14/who-is-rfk-jr-and-what-might-his-top-priorities-be">Who is RFK Jr and what are his likely top priorities?</a></li><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2024/nov/15/uk-gdp-report-growth-economy-labour-pound-ftse-stock-market-business-live-news">Business live – latest updates</a></li></ul><p>Investors in pharmaceutical companies are selling off stock after Donald Trump <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/14/trump-administration-rfk">nominated the anti-vaccine activist Robert F Kennedy Jr</a> to lead the US Department of Health and Human Services.</p><p>RFK Jr has <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/14/who-is-rfk-jr-and-what-might-his-top-priorities-be">embraced numerous health-related conspiracy theories,</a> and is one of the most persistent and influential vaccine deniers in the US.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2024/nov/15/pharma-shares-trump-rfk-jr-health-vaccine-drugmakers-moderna-astrazeneca-gsk">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2024/nov/15/pharma-shares-trump-rfk-jr-health-vaccine-drugmakers-moderna-astrazeneca-gsk</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/business/2024/nov/15/pharma-shares-trump-rfk-jr-health-vaccine-drugmakers-moderna-astrazeneca-gsk</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:21:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Justine Bateman feels like she can breathe again in 'new era' after Trump win]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/justine-bateman-feels-she-breathe-135914542.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/justine-bateman-feels-she-breathe-135914542.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 13:59:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The last actions the Biden administration will take before Trump takes over the White House]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/last-actions-biden-administration-trump-100124597.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/last-actions-biden-administration-trump-100124597.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 10:01:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>