<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:46:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:46:36 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Trump is targeting protections for almost 1 million legal immigrants]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="A crowd of demonstrators hold up flags and signs. A neon sign held up in the center of the crowd reads: TPS 4 Central America." data-caption="Demonstrators march to Capitol Hill to demand Temporary Protected Status for immigrants from Nicaragua, Honduras, Guatemala, and El Salvador on May 1, 2023, International Workers Day. | Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-1252487171.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Demonstrators march to Capitol Hill to demand Temporary Protected Status for immigrants from Nicaragua, Honduras, Guatemala, and El Salvador on May 1, 2023, International Workers Day. | Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">President-elect Donald Trump has long sought to end deportation protections for immigrants with Temporary Protected Status (TPS), a program that has significantly expanded under the Biden administration to cover over 860,000 people. He has shown no sign of relenting in a second term — and may try to either revoke those protections or let them expire soon after being sworn in.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">TPS allows people to temporarily live and work in the US and is currently granted to citizens of at least 16 countries suffering from natural disasters, armed conflict, or other extraordinary circumstances. The secretary of homeland security can grant TPS to each country for a renewable period of up to 18 months. Some countries’ TPS status is set to expire soon, including El Salvador’s, which expires <a href="https://immigrationforum.org/article/fact-sheet-temporary-protected-status/">in March</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Directing his homeland security secretary not to renew TPS for these countries could allow Trump to start reducing the population of TPS holders. Ending TPS, which has provided a lifeline for hundreds of thousands of immigrants for decades, would reshape families and communities across the US. It would also harm local economies and industries that rely on TPS recipients’ labor.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In an <a href="https://www.newsnationnow.com/politics/2024-election/trump-springfield-haitian-migrants-removed/">interview with News Nation</a> in October, Trump said he would end TPS protections for Haitians after <a href="https://www.vox.com/podcasts/372206/springfield-ohio-pets-haitian-immigrants-conspiracy">lying about immigrants eating pets</a> in Springfield, Ohio: “Absolutely I’d revoke it,” he said, adding that he would send them back to their home country, despite its <a href="https://www.hrw.org/world-report/2024/country-chapters/haiti">deepening political and humanitarian crises</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tom Homan, who Trump tapped as his “border czar,” was also an editor of <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce">Project 2025</a>, a <a href="https://static.project2025.org/2025_MandateForLeadership_FULL.pdf" rel="nofollow">900-page opus</a> of conservative policy recommendations published by the Heritage Foundation, a right-wing think tank. The document explicitly calls on Congress to repeal TPS and other temporary status programs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump previously sought to end TPS during his first term. The lawsuits that delayed his plans have yet to be fully resolved. Meanwhile, President Joe Biden has more than doubled the number of immigrants covered by TPS. Immigrant advocates are hoping that Biden will use his final months in office to extend those TPS protections that will soon expire. But if Trump tries to end TPS, advocates are gearing up for what could be another legal fight, perhaps more difficult than the last.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The potential impact of ending TPS</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The current population of TPS holders is diverse — it includes people from Venezuela, Honduras, El Salvador, Ukraine, and more. Some TPS holders have been living in the US for decades, meaning that forcing them to return home would likely result in family separations and impact the communities where they have laid roots, as well as the US industries that employ them. Despite the length of time many TPS recipients have been in the US, they have no means to convert their legal status to a green card.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Many of us have been here for decades in the United States. We have built a family, many of us with kids born in the United States,” said José Palma, a TPS holder from El Salvador and coordinator at the National TPS Alliance, an advocacy group for TPS holders. “This is their country.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Haitians were first granted TPS after a devastating 2010 earthquake from which the country never recovered, setting off a cascade of events that culminated in the collapse of its government. For Hondurans, the grant came in 1999 after Hurricane Mitch wreaked widespread destruction. For Salvadorans, it was granted in 1990 amid a civil war in their home country that lasted 12 years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Cecilia Menjívar, a sociology professor at the University of California, Los Angeles, has studied these populations of Honduran and Salvadoran TPS holders. In a <a href="https://latino.ucla.edu/research/temporary-protected-status/">2020 report</a>, she found that they were deeply integrated in their communities and employed at high rates.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of the more than 2,000 people she surveyed, she found that all had lived in the US for at least 20 years, about two-thirds had a US-born child, 88 percent of them were in the labor force, and about one-third owned their homes. They had a large presence in hospitality, construction, personal services, and transportation. In addition, she said they are “very civically active,” participating in church groups, neighborhood initiatives, school organizations, and more.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This is not a population that can be uprooted so easily,” Menjívar said. “It will be quite impactful for the rest of the community to pluck them up and send them home.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other TPS holders, however, have arrived more recently. Lebanese were only granted TPS in October amid the fighting between Israel and Hezbollah. The biggest population of recent arrivals are Venezuelans fleeing the Maduro regime, numbering <a href="https://immigrationforum.org/article/fact-sheet-temporary-protected-status/">more than 340,000 since they were granted TPS in 2021.</a>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Menjívar said she expected them to have similarly high levels of labor force participation. They have not had as much time to put down roots here, but that doesn’t mean it will necessarily be easier to return them to their home countries. Venezuela, for instance, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/11/12/trump-mass-deportation-venezuela-nicolas-maduro">does not currently accept deportees from the US</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What is true for most TPS holders is that ending protections wouldn’t just affect them. It would also affect their communities and even their family members who never left their home countries and rely on their remittances.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The majority of recipients send money to our countries to support our families,” Palma said.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Can Trump’s plans to end TPS be stopped?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump has the power to end TPS protections, but it would be unusual to do so well before they are set to expire.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The way that TPS decisions typically work and the way that the statute is designed is that new decisions with regard to TPS are supposed to be made in the period immediately before the end of the period of designation for TPS holders,” said Emi MacLean, senior staff attorney at the ACLU of Northern California.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That means that Palma and other immigrant advocates may be able to buy some time for TPS recipients whose status is set to expire soon if they can convince the Biden administration to renew their status for another 18 months. But even if they are successful, Trump may still try to revoke their protections prematurely.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I can&#8217;t say definitively that [the Trump administration is] not going to try to do something that is atypical,” MacLean said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The clearest path (and the one Trump followed in his first term) is to just not renew TPS protections when they expire. However, if Trump does decide to end TPS protections early, his decision will likely face legal challenges.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During Trump’s first term, he tried to terminate TPS protections for about 400,000 citizens of El Salvador, Honduras, and Haiti, among nationals of other countries. He argued that conditions in those countries had improved enough that their citizens could safely return. <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/11/7/20950689/trump-tps-temporary-protected-status-el-salvador-haiti-honduras-state-department-report-senate">Senior State Department officials disagreed</a>, arguing that ending TPS would destabilize the three countries and that any wind-down period should span several years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2018, immigrant advocates sued the Trump administration, alleging that the president’s decision to end TPS was motivated by racism and that it unlawfully forced the US-citizen children of TPS holders to either separate from their families or live in a foreign country. They also asserted that Trump didn’t follow the correct agency procedures in his efforts to end the benefit, which involve evaluating the current conditions in the countries covered by TPS.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A federal court temporarily blocked Trump from following through while legal battles played out, and cases continued well after Biden took office. In June 2023, Biden finally rescinded Trump’s terminations of TPS and extended it for the affected countries. The lawsuits were dismissed as a result, but immigrant advocates are preparing to go back to court if Trump tries to end TPS again.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">MacLean suggested that some of the same legal arguments may apply this time around. She pointed to Trump’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/371855/trump-vance-springfield-ohio-racist-conspiracy-theories-haitian-immigrants">racist comments about Haitians</a> on the campaign trail as evidence that any termination of their TPS status may be similarly racially motivated.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While the exact contours of their legal arguments may depend on what happens in the coming months and who is affected, MacLean said it is clear that “any sort of broad-based effort to terminate TPS would almost certainly face really serious legal hurdles.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The one other way Trump could try to end TPS would be to request congressional help: Congress could also repeal TPS entirely, as Project 2025 proposes. Given congressional gridlock on the issue of immigration and the narrow Republican margin in the House and Senate, however, that path seems unlikely.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/policy/388685/tps-trump-haiti-venezuela-el-salvador-deportation</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/policy/388685/tps-trump-haiti-venezuela-el-salvador-deportation</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Narea]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Are progressive groups sinking Democrats&#8217; electoral chances? ]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Vice President Kamala Harris speaking" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris speaks at Howard University in Washington, DC, on November 6, 2024. | Angela Weiss/AFP via Getty" data-portal-copyright="Angela Weiss/AFP via Getty" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/GettyImages-2182586892-1.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris speaks at Howard University in Washington, DC, on November 6, 2024. | Angela Weiss/AFP via Getty</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">What ails the Democratic Party? Since Kamala Harris’s defeat, several Democrats and center-left commentators have pointed the finger at one culprit: “the groups.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Specifically, they claim, progressive interest and activist groups have both moved too far left and grown far too influential in the Democratic coalition, pushing the party to adopt stances out of step with the median voter on a range of different issues. This, they say, has backfired electorally and will ultimately hurt the people the groups claim to want to help.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Many of today’s lawmakers and leaders have come up at a time when alienating the groups is seen as anathema, but they should start seeing it as both right and necessary,” former Democratic staffer <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/16/opinion/democrats-interest-groups-majority.html">Adam Jentleson wrote</a> in the New York Times in November.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other commentators — <a href="https://x.com/jonfavs/status/1860500811328917624">Jon Favreau</a>, <a href="https://x.com/mattyglesias/status/1860703589125034333">Matthew Yglesias</a>, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/13/opinion/obama-ezra-klein-podcast-michael-lind.html">Ezra Klein</a>, and <a href="https://www.liberalpatriot.com/p/the-democrats-progressive-organization">Ruy Teixeira</a> — have made similar points. Some, like <a href="https://www.slowboring.com/p/how-we-got-here-ce8">Yglesias</a> and <a href="https://www.liberalpatriot.com/p/the-democrats-progressive-organization">Teixeira</a>, have been criticizing the influence of such groups for years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet this critique has been met with an impassioned backlash from progressives and leftists. Some, like <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/politics/corporate-democrats-not-woke-activists-doomed-kamala-harris/">Waleed Shahid</a>, argue the blame is misplaced and the supposed power of these progressive groups has been exaggerated. “The Democratic Party has long been shaped by far more powerful forces — corporate interests, lobbyists, and consultants — whose influence has neglected the real crises facing everyday Americans,” Shahid wrote for The Nation. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Others argue that inflation — a global phenomenon — was the main reason for Harris&#8217;s defeat, so a groups-focused diagnosis misses the point. And yet others argue that progressive groups represent morally righteous causes that Democrats should not abandon — for instance, that moderation <a href="https://x.com/adamjohnsonCHI/status/1854873773167513714">would</a> <a href="https://x.com/treeaston/status/1858527304017760711">amount</a> to throwing marginalized groups “under the bus.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This debate is now in full swing. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’m quite comfortable — morally and politically — with the position that Dem presidential candidates shouldn’t let voters believe they want to defund the police, abolish ICE, decriminalize border crossings, or provide transition surgeries for undocumented immigrants in prison,” Favreau <a href="https://x.com/jonfavs/status/1860500811328917624">recently posted on X</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In some ways, it’s a continuation of the debate over social justice politics and “<a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/3/22/18259865/great-awokening-white-liberals-race-polling-trump-2020">wokeness</a>” that has been raging for years. But it extends well beyond that — on <a href="https://www.slowboring.com/p/climate-is-the-problem">climate change</a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/377170/kamala-harris-economic-policy-new-progressive-economics">economic policy</a>, <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2024/06/the-orthodoxy-that-doomed-democrats-border-policies/678644/">immigration</a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/22876643/democrats-voting-rights-senate-filibuster-manchin">voting reforms</a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/abortion/386228/abortion-ivf-roe-republicans-congress-bipartisan-ban-birth-control">reproductive rights</a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/375488/child-care-paid-leave-build-back-better-harris-ctc-preschool-biden-families">child care</a>, and many others, the influence of such nonprofit groups on Democrats’ strategic decisionmaking has been immense in recent years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And yet there’s more to the story than just the groups. The bigger picture is that Democrats are reckoning with the apparent <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/378644/progressives-left-backlash-retreat-kamala-harris-pivot-center">end of a years-long trend</a> in which liberal college graduates’ opinions kept moving further left, a trend that influenced all actors in the party. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The debate now is over whether and how Democrats should respond to electoral defeat — by moving to the center and trying to moderate their positions, sticking to their guns, or moving even further left.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But what happened, exactly, and how? And what are the implications for Democrats, as they search for a path back to electoral victory?</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What are “the groups”?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When critics talk about “the groups,” they’re talking about a vast and complex tapestry of progressive nonprofit organizations focusing on a variety of issues. Some, like the <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/2019/9/10/20847401/sunrise-movement-climate-change-activist-millennials-global-warming">Sunrise Movement</a>, are relatively young. But others — the ACLU, Planned Parenthood, the Human Rights Campaign — have been around for decades.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Critiques of “the groups” are typically about progressive groups specifically, even though there have long been centrist and non-ideological interest groups that also influence the Democratic Party. Because, the critics assert, it’s the progressive groups that grew far <em>more</em> influential within the Democratic Party in recent years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Back at the start of Barack Obama’s presidency, for instance, Democrats in both the White House and Congress had a sometimes-testy relationship with the activists his press secretary Robert Gibbs disparaged as being part of the “<a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/administration/168588-white-house-unloads-anger-over-criticism-from-professional-left/">professional left</a>.” On policy and political matters, Democrats took into account progressive groups’ demands, but they were typically guided by caution about what might be “too far” for the public to accept or what might alienate powerful business interests. (The <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2009/jul/16/obama-health-plan-ama-support">Affordable</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/id/wbna31485134">Care Act</a> and Democrats’ <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2010/10/11/as-the-world-burns">failed cap-and-trade bill</a> were both crafted in <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/biden-pass-climate-legislation-1140934/">close consultation with business interests</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But with the rise of new protest movements and social media, and with establishment Democrats’ approach seemingly being discredited by Donald Trump’s 2016 win, progressive groups got more emboldened. <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/inspired-life/wp/2016/11/30/its-unprecedented-in-our-history-after-trumps-election-millions-of-dollars-poured-into-nonprofits/">New money</a> from megadonors and flush foundations, as well as viral small donors, flowed into existing groups’ coffers and funded new ones. A new generation of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/06/us/aclu-free-speech.html">activist staffers</a> <a href="https://theintercept.com/2022/06/13/progressive-organizing-infighting-callout-culture/">demanded bold action</a>. The lines between groups focused on different causes started to blur as a practice of allyship emerged, particularly on <a href="https://prochoicewashington.org/2020/06/25/in-solidarity-with-black-lives-defund-the-police/">social justice issues</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democratic politicians responded in part by moving left. This was most on display in the 2020 presidential primary, when leading contenders — <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/harris-defends-shifting-positions-on-fracking-and-decriminalizing-illegal-border-crossings">including Harris</a> — endorsed positions that would have seemed unthinkably radical to Democrats just a few years earlier, like banning fracking and decriminalizing unauthorized border crossing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One example that’s become emblematic of this trend is an <a href="https://assets.aclu.org/live/uploads/2024/08/Harris-ACLU-Candidate-Questionnaire.pdf">ACLU questionnaire</a> to which Harris responded that she’d support “gender transition care” for federal inmates and immigration detainees, a position Trump <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/20/us/politics/presidential-campaign-transgender-rights.html">blasted in attack ads</a> this year. (When Elizabeth Warren first ran for office in 2012 and was asked about this, she <a href="https://www.washingtonblade.com/2019/01/09/warrens-newfound-support-for-surgery-for-trans-inmates-could-impact-2020-race/">quipped</a> that she didn’t think it would be a good use of taxpayer money — but by 2019, she announced her full-throated support of such surgeries, in what advocates interpreted as an attempt to <a href="https://www.washingtonblade.com/2019/01/09/warrens-newfound-support-for-surgery-for-trans-inmates-could-impact-2020-race/">box in Harris</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beyond the 2020 primary, there was a broader trend of Democrats starting to view progressive advocacy groups as central to the party’s policymaking and strategic calculations. By the 2020s, Klein <a href="https://t.co/B3aK0DqRDp">observed</a>, a “culture of how you make policy” and “who you listen to had emerged” inside the Democratic Party. On one issue he covered, permitting reform for clean energy projects, Hill staffers “would explain to me that if you couldn’t get” environmental justice groups on board, “they couldn’t move forward with this at all.” Klein continued:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">And I would say, “Well, what is the power of these groups — like, what is their leverage on you?” And there was never an answer. It was just a coalitional decision that had been made in the culture of the way the Democratic Party now made policy.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In my own reporting — on issues like <a href="https://www.vox.com/22876643/democrats-voting-rights-senate-filibuster-manchin">voting rights</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/377170/kamala-harris-economic-policy-new-progressive-economics">economic policy</a> — I have noticed a similar shift in how Democratic staffers now talk about “the groups” (a term such staffers <a href="https://x.com/mattyglesias/status/1860703589125034333">often use</a> in such vague fashion). On many issues, these nonprofits became arguably the key constituency the Democratic Party was focused on pleasing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition to inflation, polls showed that voters were particularly unhappy with the Biden administration’s record on unauthorized immigration — an issue where Democrats had moved significantly to the left in recent years after pressure from activists and <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/the-political-scene/the-disillusionment-of-a-young-biden-official">their own staffers</a>. Faced with public discontent amid surging border crossing numbers, Biden eventually advanced sharply <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/353835/asylum-border-biden-policy-trump-shutdown">restrictionist policies</a> through executive action — but not until 2024, when it was too late to <a href="https://www.monmouth.edu/polling-institute/reports/monmouthpoll_us_061224/">change voter perceptions</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, viewed from the perspective of progressive activists, this is nonsense: They think Democrats tell them no all the time. On certain issues — most notably the Biden administration’s support for Israel’s war in Gaza — they’re correct. Most Democrats never went so far as to back “defunding the police.” And the further left the group, the less likely it is that Democrats fully embraced their agenda.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet relative to the early Obama era baseline, the party has indeed <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/378644/progressives-left-backlash-retreat-kamala-harris-pivot-center">shifted left</a> on a whole range of economic and cultural issues. This was indeed partly due to the hard work and tireless advocacy of the groups — but not entirely.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Democratic Party’s transformation wasn’t just about the groups</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The broader reason why Democrats’ leftward shift happened remains somewhat mysterious.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yglesias <a href="https://x.com/mattyglesias/status/1855044436004143113">has argued</a> that the rise of the groups is mostly a story of “astroturf” — that big donors and foundations funded phony “grassroots” movement organizations that convinced both Democratic politicians and the media to take them seriously, even though they spoke for no one but their donors. But that doesn’t explain the leftward shift in long-established groups <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/06/us/aclu-free-speech.html">like the ACLU</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Klein discussed several possibilities for <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/13/opinion/obama-ezra-klein-podcast-michael-lind.html">why Democrats adopted a culture</a> of deference to the groups, including a mistaken belief that those groups could deliver them votes (for instance, the argument that Latino voters generally wanted the lenient policies toward unauthorized immigrants demanded by advocacy groups), a revolving door between progressive nonprofits and Democratic staff jobs, and the rise of social media (which made the perceived backlash when politicians defied the groups more intense).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of these may be part of the story, but I do think there’s a risk of overstating the groups’ actual power and centrality to events.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Benjy Sarlin <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/11/15/2024/the-groups-are-too-easy-a-scapegoat-for-democrats">wrote at Semafor,</a> in Democrats’ 2020 primary, it was often specific candidates who chose to box out their opponents by running to the left, and they were doing so because they believed it would be politically beneficial to them. Sarlin also reminds us that “Abolish ICE” briefly caught on not because of any “group” — the slogan was coined by an up-and-coming Democratic consultant who was chasing influence and social media clout. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the election, Rep. Seth Moulton (D-MA) and commentator <a href="https://x.com/atrupar/status/1859775933575520741?s=46">Aaron Rupar</a> have both opined that Democrats had gotten on the wrong side of public opinion on the issues of trans athletes or bathrooms. Both have gotten impassioned pushback; a top aide to Moulton <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/house/4981767-moulton-aide-resigns-transgender-athletes/amp/">resigned</a>, Rupar faced social media criticism and <a href="https://x.com/atrupar/status/1859775933575520741?s=46">apologized</a>. But this pushback wasn’t because of the groups. It was because of genuinely held beliefs in progressive circles that trans women are women, that that’s an issue of fundamental rights, and that any concession to public opinion on this matter is poor allyship and throwing a marginalized group under the bus.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The groups themselves were also responsive to social media pressure. One low-stakes but illustrative example: In 2017, the ACLU tweeted a picture of a (white) toddler with an American flag, captioned, “This is the future that ACLU members want.” Outraged respondents from progressive Twitter <a href="https://time.com/4915799/aclu-baby-viral-meme/">deemed that</a> a white supremacist image. The ACLU then praised the critics for reminding them “that white supremacy is everywhere.” Such incidents were quite common at that time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The larger dynamic is: In the second Obama term and the first Trump term, the groups moved left, but they were responding to donors who had <a href="https://www.insidephilanthropy.com/home/2020-10-7-the-uneasy-alliance-between-progressives-and-billionaire-donors">shifted left</a>. Those donors were trying to channel the energy and passion of activists who had shifted left. Those activists got favorable coverage from media outlets that had shifted left. Those media outlets were chasing traffic and ratings from an audience that seemed to have shifted left (while being sensitive to social media criticism from that audience). And Democratic politicians were gauging all this and shifting left.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So in my view, the best overarching explanation is simply that opinion among liberal college grads (who overwhelmingly populate the institutions listed above) shifted left in the 2010s. Every actor was chasing incentives that resulted from this leftward shift, whether it be money, clicks, or social approval. The groups are merely a part of this larger story — they may have helped exacerbate the leftward shift, but they also reflected it. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, that poses the larger question of why that leftward shift happened. There are various potential causes, including post-Great Recession disappointment, disillusionment with the Democratic establishment reflected in Bernie Sanders’s rise and deepening after Trump’s victory, social media exposing liberals to new ideas like the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/3/22/18259865/great-awokening-white-liberals-race-polling-trump-2020">Great Awokening</a> and making activists more influential, and the rise of “movement”-style thinking. There was a widespread belief that the old consensus had failed and bold new progressive ideas were necessary. And, while Trump was in power, there seemed to be no negative consequences to moving left — internal Democratic tensions and misgivings were subordinated to the task of stopping Trump.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What comes next?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What does seem clear is that, for the time being at least, the leftward shift <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/378644/progressives-left-backlash-retreat-kamala-harris-pivot-center">has stopped</a> since Biden took office. A backlash to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/25/upshot/democrats-trump-working-class.html">progressive activists’ preferred policies</a> on several issues, including <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/383079/california-prop-36-tough-on-crime-colorado-prop-128">criminal justice</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/351535/3-theories-for-americas-anti-immigrant-shift">immigration</a>, is in full swing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And, of course, Harris lost. How much blame, if any, “the groups” should get for that has become a matter of intense debate. Progressive group defenders point out that Harris tried to pivot to the center and that the Biden administration’s record on inflation and immigration were her two biggest vulnerabilities. The groups’ critics say Harris’s group-influenced positions from the 2020 primary weighed her down, and Democrats ran into political trouble on inflation and immigration in part because of the groups’ bad advice.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How the Democratic world — its groups, donors, activists, media outlets, staffers, and politicians — responds to all this is yet to be seen.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are past models. In the 1980s, after the landslide defeats of three successive Democratic presidential nominees, various reform factions <a href="https://www.progressivepolicy.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/Politics_of_Evasion.pdf">tried to moderate</a> the party, arguing that they’d gotten out of touch with the median voter and were too beholden to “special interests.” Some called for moderation on cultural issues, others for new pro-growth and pro-business policies. Bill Clinton became affiliated with these reformers, and won the presidency in 1992.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In contrast, the model of Democrats between 2004 (when John Kerry lost) to 2008 (when Obama won big) may suggest a sweeping overhaul of the party’s positions isn’t necessary. After all, Harris came pretty close to winning. Perhaps Trump will govern poorly and Democrats will return to power having changed little, avoiding a wrenching internal coalitional conflict. And perhaps the apparent end of the leftward opinion shift among liberal college graduates will be enough to effectively weaken the power of the groups.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another model, oddly enough, is Trump. Before his rise, the Republican Party was tethered to an unpopular “free market” economic agenda involving Medicare cuts and free trade pushed by donor-financed advocacy groups. In 2016, Trump distanced himself from that agenda, and in doing so revealed those groups had little actual power. However, Trump also hugged other groups in the GOP coalition even tighter — promising, for instance, to pick his Supreme Court appointees from a Federalist Society list. Then, in 2024, it was the anti-abortion groups that looked to be a political millstone for Trump — so he <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/01/politics/trump-federal-abortion-ban/index.html">distanced himself</a> from them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Democrats now, there are some nascent attempts to challenge the group-dominated status quo. Yglesias recently pitched a new agenda for “<a href="https://www.slowboring.com/p/a-common-sense-democrat-manifesto">Common Sense Democrats</a>” that involves moderating on several issues. Klein has been <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/22/opinion/ezra-klein-podcast-jennifer-pahlka-steven-teles.html">more focused</a> on how to make Democratic governance work better, and <a href="https://x.com/ezraklein/status/1860401118871711990">says his critique</a> is more about the party’s “broader culture of coalitional cowardice” rather than “an anti-left-wing view.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet others are skeptical of how much Democrats will — and should – change. “Democrats declaring independence from liberal and progressive interest groups can’t and likely won’t happen,” the commentator Michael A. Cohen (not Trump’s former lawyer) <a href="https://truthandcons.substack.com/p/looking-for-loss-in-all-the-wrong">wrote on Substack</a>. “For better or worse, these groups <em>are</em> the modern Democratic Party. If Democrats hope to retake political power in Washington, they must ensure that these groups are enthusiastic, mobilized, and remain firmly ensconced in the Democrats’ corner.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Indeed, the politics of the war in Gaza may be a cautionary tale in this regard. Biden and Harris ignored progressive groups by remaining supportive of Israel — but as a result, Harris faced regular criticism from activists and negative coverage throughout the campaign. The groups might not be so effective at winning Democrats votes — but they still might be able to drive some away.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/388752/democrats-groups-jentleson-favreau-klein-yglesias</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/388752/democrats-groups-jentleson-favreau-klein-yglesias</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Prokop]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[This obscure budget procedure could be Trump’s biggest weapon]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Donald Trump looking to the side over a black background" data-caption="Donald Trump speaks at the Faith and Freedom Road to Majority conference at the Washington Hilton on June 24, 2023, in Washington, DC. | Drew Angerer/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Drew Angerer/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/GettyImages-1259028789.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Donald Trump speaks at the Faith and Freedom Road to Majority conference at the Washington Hilton on June 24, 2023, in Washington, DC. | Drew Angerer/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Presidents have a lot of Constitutional powers: the power to wage war; the power to veto laws; the power to pardon criminals; the power to appoint Supreme Court members and other judges. But President-elect Donald Trump and his inner circle are hoping to add a new power to the repertoire, one which would constitute one of the largest expansions of presidential power in modern history: impoundment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Their theory is that the president has a constitutional authority to withhold, or “impound,” spending from projects after that spending has already been authorized by Congress. Advocates <a href="https://americarenewing.com/the-history-of-impoundments-before-the-impoundment-control-act-of-1974/">cite examples</a> of past presidents impounding various programs until Congress shut down the practice with 1974’s <a href="https://www.gao.gov/products/095406">Impoundment Control Act</a>, which Trump allies view as an unconstitutional law and a congressional power grab.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump himself attempted to use impoundment and related powers several times during his first term, most famously to <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/9/30/20883584/trump-impeachment-whistleblower-ukraine">delay paying aid to Ukraine</a> in an attempt to force a prosecution of Joe Biden’s family in that country; this act directly led to Trump’s first impeachment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s second term, though, could see a much more extensive use of the power. His nominee to run the Office on Management and Budget, Russ Vought, was on the frontlines <a href="https://rollcall.com/2021/01/19/trump-budget-office-slams-1974-impoundment-law-on-way-out/">fighting for broad impoundment power in the first term</a>, and has sought sweeping cuts to programs like <a href="https://ccf.georgetown.edu/2023/02/27/center-for-renewing-america-budget-plan-would-cut-federal-medicaid-spending-by-one-third-repeal-affordable-care-acts-coverage-expansions/">Medicaid</a> and <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/food-assistance/house-republicans-proposals-could-take-food-away-from-millions-of-low">food stamps</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If, as is likely, Congress <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/383186/trump-vance-medicaid-food-stamps-obamacare-poverty">resists these cuts</a>, Trump and Vought, as well as their flashy spending-cut consultants <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/384904/trumps-department-of-government-efficiency-sounds-like-a-joke-it-isnt">Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy</a>, could attempt to use impoundment power anyway, sending the fight into courts. There are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Train_v._City_of_New_York">multiple</a> Supreme Court <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinton_v._City_of_New_York">decisions</a> suggesting such an attempt would be illegal and unconstitutional — but today we have a court where Trump himself appointed a third of the members, and which <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">recently granted</a> him sweeping immunity from prosecution.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the Court sides with Trump in such a fight, it could set the precedent that presidents can effectively cut spending without Congress, which could have vast, far-reaching implications for everything from health care to defense to science.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Here is what impoundment power is, how it has historically worked, how Trump’s team wants it to work, and why Trump’s view of the power could set the stage for a massive executive power grab, altering fundamentally the relationship between Congress and the president.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Impoundment, explained</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The official definition of “impoundment,” per the <a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/gao-05-734sp.pdf#page=65">Government Accountability Office</a> (GAO) that oversees the practice, is “any action or inaction by an officer or employee of the federal government that precludes obligation or expenditure of budget authority.” In other words: any time someone in the federal government doesn’t spend money that Congress has ordered it to spend.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This takes two forms: <a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/gao-05-734sp.pdf#page=89">rescission</a>, and <a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/gao-05-734sp.pdf#page=47">deferral</a>. In rescission, the spending is simply canceled, while in deferral it is withheld temporarily, in theory to be spent in the future. Under the Impoundment Control Act, passed in 1974, both rescissions and deferrals can be passed by Congress at any time, and they can also be requested by the president. But any presidential requests have to be approved by Congress to take effect, and that has happened quite rarely.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From fiscal year 1974, when these provisions took effect, and 2018, the last year when a president invoked this provision, <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/pbaf.12372#page=5">presidents have proposed $92 billion in rescissions</a>, of which only $25 billion were approved by Congress. To put that in context, combined federal spending from 1974 to 2018 was <a href="https://www.cbo.gov/data/budget-economic-data#2">about $83.6 trillion</a>, and approved presidentially suggested rescissions amount to 0.07 percent of that. No Impoundment Control Act rescission has been approved since 2000, and George W. Bush and Barack Obama did not so much as propose any. The act is just not a very important part of the budget process, typically.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The GAO has also recognized a practice called “programmatic delay,” which it views as not technically impoundment but which is closely related. Programmatic delays occur when the government is trying to spend money Congress has instructed it to spend, but factors outside their control preclude this. The GAO has <a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/ogc-94-17.pdf#page=4">offered as an example</a> a program in which the government is supposed to provide a certain amount of money in loans, but where there are few applicants so the program simply cannot lend out the total amount Congress has set aside for this purpose.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another more recent example was Biden’s executive order upon taking office instructing a pause in the construction of border walls and fences with Mexico. While Congress had appropriated money specifically for border barriers, <a href="https://www.gao.gov/products/b-333110-0">the GAO ruled that the Biden administration was merely “programmatically delaying” the project</a>, because the delays were chalked up to environmental reviews and other hurdles that it was legally required to clear before continuing construction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Programmatic delay does offer the executive branch some flexibility in spending, but only a bit. Otherwise, the Impoundment Control Act is very clear: The president cannot refuse to spend money that Congress has told him to spend. The GAO is empowered to challenge the president if it sees this limitation being contradicted, <a href="https://www.gao.gov/products/b-331564">as it did when Trump withheld funds</a> from Ukraine in 2019. In that case, the funds were eventually <a href="https://www.defensenews.com/congress/2019/09/12/white-house-releases-250-million-in-ukraine-military-aid/">released</a> and the incident led to Trump’s impeachment.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The history of impoundment and impoundment control</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you read enough about impoundment, you&#8217;re going to hear about the gunboats.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 1803, Congress had appropriated $50,000 (about <a href="https://www.officialdata.org/us/inflation/1803?amount=50000">$1.4 million</a> in today’s dollars) for some gunboats on the Mississippi River, <a href="https://www.americanheritage.com/impoundment">provoked by France&#8217;s refusal to offer the US access to the Port of New Orleans</a> at the end of 1802. President Thomas Jefferson declined to purchase the gunboats, however, because he had enlisted Secretary of State James Madison to negotiate with Napoleon in secret with another goal in mind: simply buying all of France’s North American territories. In July 1803, the Louisiana Purchase was announced, rendering the gunboats unnecessary. All in all, it was a much better deal.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In October, <a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/documents/third-annual-message">Jefferson explained the decision</a> in his State of the Union message to Congress, telling representatives that, “The favorable and peaceable turn of affairs on the Mississippi rendered an immediate execution of that law unnecessary.” The historian <a href="https://www.americanheritage.com/impoundment">Allan Damon notes</a> that this was technically a deferral, not an impoundment, because Jefferson wound up buying the gunboats in 1804, as part of his more general efforts to build out the embryonic Navy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To advocates of impoundment — most notably Mark Paoletta, who served as general counsel for the Office on Management and Budget in Trump&#8217;s first term and has written extensively in defense of a broad impoundment power — this kind of history proves that impoundment is as American as apple pie. In a <a href="https://americarenewing.com/the-history-of-impoundments-before-the-impoundment-control-act-of-1974/">detailed report</a> with co-authors Daniel Shapiro and Brandon Stras, Paoletta observes, “The Jeffersonians recognized that Congress’s power of the purse was a power to set a ceiling on appropriations. The power of the purse did nothing to encroach the Executive’s inherent discretion to spend less than the amount appropriated.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Critics with a more mainstream view of the issue think this wildly misunderstands the history. <a href="https://www.yalejreg.com/nc/the-president-has-no-constitutional-power-of-impoundment-by-zachary-s-price/">Zachary Price, a professor at UC Law San Francisco</a>, notes that the underlying statute appropriating the $50,000 for the gunboats &#8220;authorized expenditure without requiring it.&#8221; The text of the law &#8220;authorized and empowered&#8221; Jefferson to order the construction of &#8220;a number not exceeding fifteen gun boats&#8221; with &#8220;a sum not exceeding fifty thousand dollars.&#8221; Through that wording, Congress was giving the president the discretion to spend as much as $50,000 on the boats, but also the discretion to decline.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More to the point, Congress and the president for most of the 19th and 20th centuries operated with a shared understanding that spending bills offered this kind of flexibility. &#8220;Both Congress and the executive branch …&nbsp;seem to have followed a default understanding that appropriations statutes conferred implicit authority to forego spending when it proved unnecessary or when statutory goals could be accomplished with a smaller expenditure,” Price writes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Most historical impoundments, according to Georgetown law professor Eloise Pasachoff, were also for efficiency rather than policy reasons: if Congress, say, instructed the government to build a bridge for $100 million, and the bridge wound up only costing $90 million, the president might decline to spend $10 million because he could accomplish the same goal at a lower cost. “If you look at these examples that they’re bringing out, they mostly fall in the category of ‘Congress has appropriated money for something but it turns out we don’t need the full extent of that money,’” Pasachoff told Vox.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So you can certainly find examples from Jefferson to LBJ of presidents declining to spend money that had been authorized. Paoletta sees this as evidence that the president has a broad power to impound funds. Price and Pasachoff see it as evidence that Congress intended this flexibility: Impoundment was a power that Congress granted to the president in specific, limited contexts, but not an inherent power of the president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This governing order, of Congress allowing impoundments on the understanding that the president would use the power responsibly, broke down in the 1970s under the Nixon administration. Both the Senate and House were solidly Democratic for Richard Nixon’s entire presidency, and he sought to use impoundment as a means of influencing spending without needing their approval. His <a href="https://goodauthority.org/news/good-to-know-what-is-impoundment/">attempts were far more sweeping than previous presidents</a>, including gambits like an effort to outright eliminate the Office of Economic Opportunity, a key agency of LBJ&#8217;s war on poverty, and simply refusing to spend money on anti-water pollution efforts even after Congress had appropriated money for the effort over his veto. He declared that this was an <a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/documents/the-presidents-news-conference-86">absolute Constitutional power of the presidency</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He was more or less alone in that. In 1969, Assistant Attorney General William Rehnquist (who two years later would be appointed to the Supreme Court and 15 years after that become chief justice) <a href="https://www.justice.gov/file/147706/dl?inline=">wrote a memo</a> concluding that there is no constitutional right to impoundment. This was a very conservative Nixon official, one who Nixon would himself promote to the highest court in the land a few years later, concluding that the constitutional argument was bunk.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 1975, after Nixon had already resigned in disgrace, the water pollution case made its way to the Supreme Court, which <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Train_v._City_of_New_York">ruled unanimously that Nixon&#8217;s Environmental Protection Agency had illegally withheld the funds</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 1974, Congress sought to clarify matters by passing the Impoundment Control Act as part of a legislative package that also set up the modern budget process and created the Congressional Budget Office. The law did not so much make impoundment illegal as it clarified that impoundment, when not explicitly authorized by Congress in spending laws, <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-budget/faqs-on-impoundment-presidential-actions-are-constrained-by-long-standing">was always illegal</a>, and set up a process through which presidents could seek to roll back spending in an orderly way, but only with Congress’s participation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s not like the Impoundment Control Act took away the legal ability of the president to do that,” <a href="https://spp.umd.edu/our-community/faculty-staff/philip-joyce">Philip Joyce</a>, a professor of public policy at the University of Maryland and an expert on the budget process, told me. “The courts had already found there was no legal authority for the president to impound funds.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Can Trump actually do this?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump, in his first term, sought to bring back impoundment power to a degree not seen since Nixon. In 2018, he <a href="https://rollcall.com/2018/06/25/from-a-scream-to-a-whisper-rescissions-push-goes-dark/">sought $15.2 billion in rescissions</a>, the bulk coming from the Children&#8217;s Health Insurance Program, which supports state programs to insure children, usually through Medicaid.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The House first shaved half a billion off the cuts before narrowly passing them, then two Senate Republicans (Richard Burr and Susan Collins) voted against the package, enough to doom it given the Republicans’ narrow majority in the Senate. Despite that setback, his team kept repeatedly considering rescission packages, especially against <a href="https://www.devex.com/news/trump-administration-resurrects-rescission-proposal-in-latest-attack-on-us-aid-spending-95437">foreign aid</a>, only to back down under pressure from Congress.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The most infamous invocation of this power came in 2019, when the Office on Management and Budget sought unilaterally to delay aid to Ukraine, without asking Congress. The GAO eventually ruled that while <a href="https://www.gao.gov/products/b-331564.1">the non-military aid delay was legal</a> (it was a &#8220;programmatic delay&#8221; necessitated by circumstances), withholding <a href="https://www.gao.gov/products/b-331564">$214 million in military assistance</a> was not.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Later in 2019, the public learned that Trump had, in a phone call with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy, stated, &#8220;I would like you to do us a favor&#8221; <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/9/25/20883420/full-transcript-trump-ukraine-zelensky-white-house">in exchange for the aid</a>, specifically investigating the Biden family for corruption as well as a conspiracy theory that a Ukrainian, not Russia, hacked Democrats in 2016. The revelation that the aid was withheld specifically in a move to leverage a foreign nation into attacking a political opponent led to <a href="https://www.vox.com/c/2020/2/6/20914280/impeachment-trump-explained">Trump’s first impeachment</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But while Trump’s rescissions became a background detail to a broader scandal, his team continued to insist upon the power. As Trump was leaving office, Office of Management and Budget director Russ Vought and his general counsel Mark Paoletta <a href="https://rollcall.com/2021/01/19/trump-budget-office-slams-1974-impoundment-law-on-way-out/">wrote a letter</a> to the House Budget Committee <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Response-to-House-Budget-Committee-Investigation.pdf">arguing</a> that the Impoundment Control Act &#8220;should be significantly reformed or repealed.&#8221; They <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/01/14/trump-billions-cut-covid-vaccine-distributor-459496">sent a final rescission package to Congress</a> in January 2021, despite knowing it was dead in the water, underlining their seriousness about the procedure. Vought and Paoletta have since gone further and now argue that the Impoundment Control Act and its limits on impoundment powers are not just unwise, but unconstitutional.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The least dramatic way that Trump could use impoundment is by submitting rescission packages to Congress and watching them be approved, by a simple majority vote of each house. Rescission packages cannot be filibustered, so in principle the narrow Republican majority in the House and Senate could simply rubber-stamp the measures.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The power becomes truly interesting, however, if Trump insists upon cuts that Congress will <em>not</em> approve. One could imagine a repeat of the 2017 fight to repeal Obamacare, except, when enough Republicans defect to doom the effort in Congress, Trump and Vought opt to simply impound funds for the Medicaid expansion and Affordable Care Act premium subsidies unilaterally. This would inevitably provoke a legal challenge that could make its way to the Supreme Court.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a fool’s errand to predict what the Court would say on the matter, but we know a few things. Court precedent is solidly against a presidential impoundment power. In 1838, the Court ruled in <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/37/524/"><em>Kendall v. United States ex Rel. Stokes</em></a> that the executive branch could not fail to pay a debt that Congress had instructed it to pay, writing, &#8220;that the obligation imposed on the President to see the laws faithfully executed, implies a power to forbid their execution, is a novel construction of the constitution, and entirely inadmissible.” <a href="https://americarenewing.com/the-history-of-impoundments-before-the-impoundment-control-act-of-1974/">Paoletta and co-authors</a> argue that because this was not technically an impoundment, it&#8217;s not a binding precedent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the 1975 Supreme Court case on the Nixon EPA dispute, <em>Train v. City of New York</em>, did directly speak to impoundments, and reached the same conclusion. <a href="https://americarenewing.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/The-Presidents-Constitutional-Power-of-Impoundment-1.pdf">Paoletta counters</a> that the opinion in that case was written narrowly and based on the reading of the statute authorizing the EPA’s spending; it &#8220;does not address the President&#8217;s constitutional impoundment power.&#8221; That feels somewhat unconvincing though; as <a href="https://goodauthority.org/news/good-to-know-what-is-impoundment/">Bowdoin College political scientist Andrew Rudalevige has noted</a>, “presumably, if the president had inherent impoundment authority grounded in the Constitution, statutory language could not have set it aside.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All that said, the current court famously set aside a 49-year-old precedent when it <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/24/23181720/supreme-court-dobbs-jackson-womens-health-samuel-alito-roe-wade-abortion-marriage-contraception">overruled <em>Roe v. Wade</em></a>, and a 40-year-old precedent when it <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/357900/supreme-court-loper-bright-raimondo-chevron-power-grab">overruled <em>Chevron v. NRDC</em></a>. It could surely overturn <em>Train</em> and <em>Kendall</em> too, should it so desire; it could also assert a presidential impoundment power and massage its ruling such that it does not have to technically overrule those precedents, perhaps by parsing the decisions narrowly the way that Paoletta does.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the Court were to agree with the Paoletta argument, we’d be in a whole new world in terms of federal spending. Presidents would suddenly have a significant power to make spending cuts without congressional buy-in. Importantly, the power would be asymmetrical, tilted toward slashing programs versus building them. President Bernie Sanders could not use this power to set up a Medicare-for-All program, but a Republican president could use it to end Medicare outright.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such a world feels so fantastical from the standpoint of the last half-century of budget battles that to imagine it almost feels like playing Dungeons &amp; Dragons. But Trump has assembled a team dedicated to bringing us into such a world, and it may encroach upon our reality sooner than we expect.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/388393/donald-trump-congress-impoundment-budget-supreme-court</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/388393/donald-trump-congress-impoundment-budget-supreme-court</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dylan Matthews]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The uncomfortable question about “Latino” voters]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="A Latinos Con Harris-Walz poster hangs on a sidepost in a Puerto Rican neighborhood in North Philadelphia along 5th Street on the eve of the 2024 election." data-caption="Views of the heart of the Puerto Rican neighborhood of North Philadelphia along 5th Street on the eve of the 2024 election. | Andrew Lichtenstein/Corbis via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Lichtenstein/Corbis via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-2182934585.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Views of the heart of the Puerto Rican neighborhood of North Philadelphia along 5th Street on the eve of the 2024 election. | Andrew Lichtenstein/Corbis via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">What does “Latino” mean? And is there still such a thing as the “Latino vote”?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At first glance, both questions are simple to answer. Latinos are simply any of the 65 million people of any race living in the United States with cultural or ancestral ties to Latin America (and Spain, if you consider the term “Hispanic”). Overwhelmingly of Mexican descent (about 60 percent), they live primarily in two states, California and Texas, and make up about a fifth of the American population.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The “Latino vote,” meanwhile, could simply be those Latino Americans who vote in elections. More than 30 million of these people living in the US are citizens who can, and more than <a href="https://unidosus.org/hispanicvote/">16 million turned out</a> in the 2020 election — the Latino electorate. These voters have tended to vote for Democrats in national elections, and, since 2004, have given near super-majorities of support to the Democratic presidential candidate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For a time, this vote remained pretty uniform in both its makeup and its support for one party. That stability fueled the idea that there was such a thing as a Latino voting bloc, leading parties to have “Latino strategies” aimed at winning these voters over. They could be thought of as Black voters tended to be: reached with appeals to racial and ethnic solidarity, reminders of discrimination and inequality, and in turn expected to behave like Black voters — who, along with LGBTQ voters, have been Democrats’ most loyal cohort.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By 2024, this assumption has been called into question. To say that Latinos are not a monolith is now a cliche — the basic starting point for conversations about how these Americans vote. But now, is even the term “Latino” itself an oversimplification?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many strategists, academics, and activists agree, saying the category of “Latino” is too vague and amorphous to capture its diversity of race, language, national origin, and immigrant experience. And when it comes to politics, it can flatten the political ideology, partisan loyalty, and changing vote preferences of millions of people across 50 states.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That idea is gaining momentum, but it’s not universal. There are those who think the term has value, pointing out that it’s still useful to have a broad and more visible descriptor for these people; its members are stronger together, and despite diversifying political views, still tend to behave in similar patterns.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The implications are big: For the last 40 years, political organizing, power building, and business interests have relied on there being such a thing as a Hispanic or Latino community to count, to mobilize, and to market to. In short: This quandary matters for anyone hoping to win the votes of tens of millions of people.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The case for specificity — and that “Latino” is too broad</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The best political example to stop thinking of Latinos as a bloc or collective is to see what has happened when campaigns have tried to appeal to them as a group. The outreach and persuasion operation that President Joe Biden’s 2020 primary and general election campaigns ran is a prime example.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, that was the focal point of criticism of Democrats’ Latino voter outreach. It was too generic, unsophisticated, and premised on outdated thinking about what matters to these voters: promises of immigration reform and humanitarian border policies for a community that was primarily native-born; reminders of Donald Trump’s racism when these voters didn’t necessarily think he was talking about them; and “<a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/codeswitch/2019/06/27/695299713/primary-season-is-here-and-hispandering-is-back">Hispandering</a>” with flourishes of Spanish and Latin celebrity endorsements when Spanish-language use rates were declining and those <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/14/us/politics/latino-voters-america-ferrera.html">celebrities weren’t necessarily relevant</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The most widely referenced example: When Biden campaigned in Florida with the Puerto Rican singer Luis Fonsi, and <a href="https://youtu.be/oXOlvWw8uXs?si=6ZB9y-TUoO9pgMkn">bopped along to the star’s hit song “Despacito.”</a> It went viral —&nbsp;for the wrong reasons: seeming like a cringey last-ditch attempt to get in the good graces of a community he hadn’t really been campaigning for.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That campaign continued to be a <a href="https://apnews.com/article/hispanic-voters-2024-biden-outreach-democrats-election-e184e6d0695368e4f59cb48d28ff22be">special target</a> of this <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/11/05/931378189/what-we-know-about-the-latino-vote-in-some-key-states">criticism for beginning outreach too late</a> in the cycle, for not investing enough resources in persuasion and turnout efforts, for leaning too much on <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/aug/04/joe-biden-latino-voters-unveils-plan-tackles-inequalities">immigrant-friendly appeals</a> in that pitch, and for missing just how damaging Republican attacks describing Democrats as “socialists” actually were. Biden still won a majority of these voters, but his results were a decline from the share of support Hillary Clinton and Barack Obama had gotten in previous presidential cycles.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These approaches still fit within the old model of talking to and about a “Latino vote”: one that assumed it could operate as a voting bloc, and it would remain monolithic. At one point in time, it was. But as rates of college education rise, as incomes grow, as the share of foreign-born Latinos declines, and as they vote differently, perhaps “Latino” <em>should</em> give way for more specific reference points, like “Mexican American,” “Cuban American,” “Southwestern voters,” or “Florida Latinos” —&nbsp;at least for the purposes of electoral politics.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since 2020, the conventional wisdom has settled on a more tailored, targeted approach — what some Democratic Latino strategists and aligned groups call “culturally competent” campaigning. In 2024, that became the bedrock of Biden and Harris’s early and improved Latino outreach — what New York Democratic Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez called&nbsp;a “diaspora strategy.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They care about the diasporas and looking at this from a diaspora strategy, as opposed to just an overall, monolithic strategy that we often hear discussed and unfortunately played out in a lot of different areas,” <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/22/harris-latino-voters-00180365">Ocasio-Cortez told Politico</a> in September. “So I think that as time goes on, we’re going to see the results of that more refined approach.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the ground, that looked like tailored ads and campaign contact for Puerto Rican and Dominican communities in Pennsylvania and Florida, for Mexican Americans in the Southwest, and for using different surrogates, accents, and vocabulary in different media markets. After all, the thinking goes, what might sound familiar and credible to a first-generation naturalized Mexican American voter in Las Vegas is different from what appeals to the third-generation Puerto Rican voter who did not have to go through the same immigrant experience, even if they both speak Spanish.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans performed their own version of this new identity politics between the 2020 and 2024 cycles&nbsp;—&nbsp;but it looked very different.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead of appealing to a broad “Latino” or “Hispanic” vote, they doubled down on specific segments of the electorate in an attempt to chip away at Democratic dominance. They played up the specter of “socialism,” “communism,” and “Marxism” in both Trump’s and other down-ballot candidates’ appeals to Cuban and Venezuelan American voters in Florida. It’s here where one 2020 jingle that was recycled for the 2024 cycle stands out: A Cuban band’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X6YX1x4tbII">“Latinos for Donald Trump” salsa song</a> that went viral four years ago was used by Trump’s campaign this year to double down on a segment of the Latino electorate they thought was already likely to surge for him at the polls.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="Latinos for Donald Trump - Campaign Ad" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HNYUs4q9Znc?rel=0" width="720" height="405" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They paired this with talk of the threat that illegal immigration posed to Mexican Americans and their safety in border communities in the Southwest in order to reach Trump-friendly working-class voters in Arizona, Nevada, and Texas —&nbsp;a mirror image of the traditional Democratic appeal to working-class, first- or second-generation Latinos.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These varying, hyper-specific approaches all demonstrated two things: Campaigning to “Latinos” was falling out of vogue —&nbsp;the preference now was for direct appeals to subset within the bloc. And the Latino electorate was now large, complex, and varied enough to be examined and treated with the same degree of sophistication as white voters are.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The case that “Latino” still serves a purpose</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Biden’s 2020 run suggested it was a mistake to think of Latinos as a broad, workable category, Trump’s 2024 victory suggests that <em>maybe</em> you can.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if the Latino category is too diverse, and doesn’t function as a monolithic voting bloc, reality suggests they still behave as a group. That’s the conclusion of early analysis conducted by the Latino research firm Equis, which found that the <a href="https://x.com/carlosodio/status/1856370229548286293">rightward shifts of these voters in the 2024 cycle</a> cut across geographical location, population size, and country of origin.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Broad-based shifts like these challenge the use of provincial theories to explain them,” Equis co-founder Carlos Odio wrote in sharing those results.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The implication? It might make theoretical and intellectual sense to think of and appeal to these voters with specificity and fragmentation. But as a whole, a broader category of people united by similar experiences as a minority in the US, primarily nonwhite, and which continues to assimilate, still exists on the ground.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those similar experiences, some shared language, and growth across the country do make this cohort of people distinct from non-Hispanic white, Asian, and Black people —&nbsp;and therefore it makes sense to organize, mobilize, and campaign for the votes of these communities. That’s the premise that led to the formation of specific Hispanic- and Latino-focused advocacy groups and political organizations, and which continues to warrant specific data collection, policy work, fundraising, investment, and political outreach from institutions, businesses, politicians, and campaigns.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In practice, across race, age, and gender, this group is still also mostly motivated by a similar set of priorities and concerns. When asked about issues that might affect their vote in 2024, the overwhelming majority of these voters described economic anxiety. Immigration tended to follow — and for similar reasons: They were upset by the status quo of the <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2024/10/01/migrant-encounters-at-u-s-mexico-border-have-fallen-sharply-in-2024/">post-pandemic migrant crisis</a>. Though they may be becoming more of a swing voter group, by most metrics they are still siding with Democrats at higher rates than white voters. And above all, a majority of these people still conceive of themselves as distinctly either “<a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/race-and-ethnicity/2024/09/12/latinx-awareness-has-doubled-among-u-s-hispanics-since-2019-but-only-4-percent-use-it/">Hispanic” or “Latino</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, we’re overcomplicating this question. Whether “Latino” is still useful in the political realm reminds me of something the sociologist G. Cristina Mora, who has traced the history of the “Hispanic” and “Latino” labels,” told me back in 2021.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Sometimes people want to [say] that <em>somehow</em> Latinos are so different, like,<em> </em>‘Oh my god, they&#8217;re too diverse!’ Like, ‘Latinos are not a thing.’ How is white a thing? How is Black a thing? How is Asian a thing? Somehow people think that there&#8217;s something really uniquely diverse and special and in many ways we&#8217;re the same as others,” she told me then. “We&#8217;ve never just had one term that everyone was into, we&#8217;ve never had one term that everyone&#8217;s happy with.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the never-Trump strategist Mike Madrid, the ambiguity is the point. “Latino” as a multiracial category distinct from the binary “white” and “Black” challenges both the nation’s political class and the greater American public to realize just how quickly the US is moving into a primarily multiracial, Latino-driven future. It might not be a label that is useful forever, but it’s useful now for carving out a distinct category of people who deserve attention.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“To talk about us as ‘Mestizo’ [someone of Spanish and indigenous ancestry in Latin America]&nbsp; is more appropriate maybe than ‘Latino,’ but we are multiracial and there has to be a new language for that that doesn’t necessarily fit in this black and white paradigm,” Madrid told me.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>How we should think of “Latino” in the future</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For now, the “Latino” label doesn’t face the prospect of sliding out of relevance or usage soon, even if talk about the “Latino vote” seems to be on the decline.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sure, as this category of voters continues to assimilate, enmesh itself into the fabric of the nation, and change the nation just as we are being changed, Hispanic and Latino identity itself will change. Labels don’t stick around forever.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And that’s where the challenge of defining “Latino” and “Latino voters” suggests something more uncomfortable too: The idea of Hispanic-ness, Latinidad, is likely to change quickly in the next two decades. Rates of interracial marriage continue to remain high; the role of Spanish continues to decline; US-born Latinos are driving the growth of this part of the population; and ideological sorting within this part of the <a href="https://goodauthority.org/news/election-2024-racial-realignment-us-politics/">electorate appears to be increasing</a>. That suggests to political parties, and those seeking power, that they can’t rest easy thinking alignments or realignments will stick around forever. But it also means “Latinoness” stands to lose its distinctiveness in the near future.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/387924/the-uncomfortable-question-about-latino-voters</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/387924/the-uncomfortable-question-about-latino-voters</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Paz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Musk busts through the UK political china shop]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk, the CEO of Tesla, SpaceX, and X (formerly known as Twitter) may detest the current Kier Starmer government due to clashes on topics like free speech and immigration, but Musk is playing the long game. He&#8217;s getting cosy with major figures from both sides of the aisle, advancing his particular beliefs on AI [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/02/musk-busts-through-the-uk-political-china-shop/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/02/musk-busts-through-the-uk-political-china-shop/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:34:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What did Hunter Biden do and what is a presidential pardon?]]></title><description><![CDATA[An act of clemency by Hunter Biden's father continues a tradition by American presidents.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c99x07ny8lro</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c99x07ny8lro</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:37:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA["Apocalyptic": UN Chief On Situation In Gaza Amid Israel-Hamas War]]></title><description><![CDATA[The United Nations chief said Monday the situation in war-torn Gaza was "appalling and apocalyptic", warning conditions faced by Palesti]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apocalyptic-un-chief-on-situation-in-gaza-amid-israel-hamas-war-7154882</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apocalyptic-un-chief-on-situation-in-gaza-amid-israel-hamas-war-7154882</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:20:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[At $126 Billion, Putin Allocated A 3rd Of Russia's Budget Solely To Defence]]></title><description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin approved the country's budget for 2025 on Sunday, which includes record-breaking spending on military needs amid Moscow's ongoing assault against Ukraine.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-126-billion-putin-allocated-a-3rd-of-russias-budget-solely-to-defence-7154140</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-126-billion-putin-allocated-a-3rd-of-russias-budget-solely-to-defence-7154140</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:45:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden Opens the Only Trip of His Presidency to Sub-Saharan Africa]]></title><description><![CDATA[The president stopped in Cape Verde on his way to Angola, where he will highlight American commitment to Africa in the economic competition against China.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/02/world/africa/biden-africa-trip-angola-cape-verde.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/02/world/africa/biden-africa-trip-angola-cape-verde.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:30:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Centrist Party Edges Out Far-Right Challengers in Romania]]></title><description><![CDATA[The center-left Social Democrats won the most votes in a parliamentary election but a strong nationalist showing could make it difficult to form a stable Western-oriented government.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/02/world/europe/romania-election-centrist-far-right.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/02/world/europe/romania-election-centrist-far-right.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:38:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scholz Pledges $680 Million in Aid From Germany to Ukraine During Visit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Chancellor Olaf Scholz visited Kyiv on Monday. Amid fears that U.S. support could dry up, Ukrainian officials had criticized him for a recent phone call with President Vladimir V. Putin.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/02/world/europe/scholz-germany-ukraine-aid.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/02/world/europe/scholz-germany-ukraine-aid.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:40:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[U.N. Suspends Aid Deliveries to Gaza via Kerem Shalom Crossing]]></title><description><![CDATA[The head of the United Nations agency for Palestinian refugees said it was pausing deliveries through the Kerem Shalom crossing because of safety concerns.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/02/world/middleeast/unrwa-aid-gaza.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/02/world/middleeast/unrwa-aid-gaza.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:02:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[We haven’t seen a pardon as sweeping as Hunter Biden’s in generations - POLITICO]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPQXJmcXc1ZEtEWE1UckR2M0FKNXNRZzl5NlRuMmtWVlp4RERudFprS3pEYU1CdjY3TGxXOEh0ZWRmOVdOUk5iODdMLWhtVkxwYlNsc21EWEZicDFhcnNlUlNyektteXBHMXplTHk0QVZETUhmdGpzbW9aSWlROEZ5Qw?oc=5" target="_blank">We haven’t seen a pardon as sweeping as Hunter Biden’s in generations</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPZmU1amJJY202NnJtNkhtVnduTkhaRFhWNmdfZTcwaFpTSndKRUlqa05vRUk2TEZYNmFuWGExTGpKYWhra2twUXdYZ3NBMU9vcnU4OG5hQWRmaEgxRUF1cS1KdzA1cy1Za2g4WmlBaHRHNkhhaEd3bThMakZxT2pXRUppNlhxejlpbUh3T0tYcXl2LTNxZkUyREt4ZzJJX0RCbkxPZWF30gGrAUFVX3lxTE1CZVpBUHBnMDNtWERkdGtVLU9kOVc5aDdURUdOLWxzZnRpTjNnbmIzazF4NnR4Uk0wRVFXZW9RV2piclBMalo4RzhaazZaS3FDZEx1ek5ya09iSjROc0ZBRDZfb1J6ZEhDUU9ISHgzZGVOOWd1aUtyM1RJVkNFTjhpTjVYQ1hyNm4yNl9MUGpJcDlRUTl2dG9MUzVrZEI4ZUR3WktSX2JYWEN2VQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Republicans hammer Biden's 'No one is above the law' claim following Hunter pardon: 'Aged like fine milk'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE5tbDRqX3dTMGRpckZ3Sy1rOWJXM08zcEd6ZEFsWWo0SURnckFFbDhQUmtmQ0ZuZFZPVnRTN1g0ZU9qQlJBSFpxR1hhSl9qaDl3TFpreW9JX2Z5QQ?oc=5" target="_blank">What did Hunter Biden do and what is a presidential pardon?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNbEtUUFFUVUt4NVVDNGpVY2UzWkw2VkktZXJLRjdKbWhhRGVrYzlLMHJIeU95M08xeFk1MXNsQzhCUjJ4ZnBQb0F2RFlnSUE0VkEySktxRHl2Yl9YeERyX0xxMDdWbG5YUWlRMDg0Z2pTWmVnUmtKSy1xeTdoM0tSWEw3QndqVURpem5aYU8zTXJwZ0RUUHo2Y1NhOWFVWTQ?oc=5" target="_blank">President Biden pardons his son Hunter despite previous pledges not to</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxQSm8tamhrTnYzWWFBOWhwQTVJLXpmRGc2cGw3VVkyaGliMzFxRXdhTUxnZXo0VlVqVFBSMW5wZDNEUDJZWkVXbkhtdWMxTmJBSWxpRkpfWkNSMlRaOVJjSFVBUFU1WkhHbUhOZTNnekdrcmxuMmFPemR1TVZwQnlWdEhaeDZPRk0?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden’s Unpardonable Hypocrisy</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Atlantic</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPQXJmcXc1ZEtEWE1UckR2M0FKNXNRZzl5NlRuMmtWVlp4RERudFprS3pEYU1CdjY3TGxXOEh0ZWRmOVdOUk5iODdMLWhtVkxwYlNsc21EWEZicDFhcnNlUlNyektteXBHMXplTHk0QVZETUhmdGpzbW9aSWlROEZ5Qw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPQXJmcXc1ZEtEWE1UckR2M0FKNXNRZzl5NlRuMmtWVlp4RERudFprS3pEYU1CdjY3TGxXOEh0ZWRmOVdOUk5iODdMLWhtVkxwYlNsc21EWEZicDFhcnNlUlNyektteXBHMXplTHk0QVZETUhmdGpzbW9aSWlROEZ5Qw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 05:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lawler says he has no reservations about Kash Patel for FBI chief - The Hill]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxQYTBYMko5d0NPdzdZS3ZGRlg3VElKb3dBekQ2bmVZTFhKRGVSc2JPanlBTzFla1RlazViWW1Cb0dmcnBtY1pjRFQ3dEt3X2VjcG82bnN3bzF4ejJzNTEta0t4cC1vcmI2RjdmT25yMkNVYVBQbVUxWlY4RXVaaW02aDlR0gGHAUFVX3lxTFBLUGhhUHRpa3VzUk1SWUN2ODVyYnJrdGM5bjc5WVN0bVVYYkRaeXN5dHJnckpMcW0yZi1Bc1BRX2lJbFlZX2ZyTlNlb3E5dFNWOWluRENCSXNXQlFlN185cGRFTGk3QjlsOWFteE4xUzVaNThiRHBYZUV0bmlLN2RHSjZaamU0aw?oc=5" target="_blank">Lawler says he has no reservations about Kash Patel for FBI chief</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxPTlVxTlRPRWRLRWFiLTNDc2huMDQxUksxcFhLTGZNQlIwY1hHNjV0QmdpbzFUalA0VmVrM282a2I1SmhrYkxiZVNCaF8tWHZjTjd5OUU5VmtqY0JhNUNPRFAtVFVEZEZER1lVeDBrRTM1VmloRnpyYjF5dEJBcWkwcWtfa2RkenJTbHgtcU5RWGnSAYcBQVVfeXFMTS15SjBmUENoZzcyT2E5bkEzVXBRenVIR0I5akQ0LXk2X0hEVmpsNXI0VHdBWU1SNTFuZUFSVXpHLV9Gd2sya1A3Z1hOdzAxc29lWklCUzBVcXJadEtKRmtxRkkteWtJTHd6ZDExc09fUnAzOUxCSGoyNGpqLVVSUFJNSnZIdjdZ?oc=5" target="_blank">Who is Kash Patel, Trump’s pick for FBI director?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxONzh3MHpicFIzcXBDN284aTUtbWo5R3ppWHFJZGpNVlZ5QVc5NjZzMHFVQmQ0eDlPLTRDRS10akVTc0JtMFo3MkNRVzY0SWI4WnBOT1ZmbWdpZ3J0MjZ0VkpNRV85cFJlZUFiS2ZrWVh6elF5WXJoZ0hQdDB0dlhJbUdicXp5Z25WMEg0ZTR5Ykd1UnhsU0s0bXpkemtoZ05GVFQycTlTaEhLZnNYSXowa0lCbnRvNzJqYnFHdkk0QlNLNTZxUmtKVG8ySW9iTmxBWVpZ0gHYAUFVX3lxTE9DMEpISzJGMnNDT1RSd09ueDBhUUFkZUwxbFFvUFdkWnluRzYzWm9ELVg5ejVhYkxIdXB5cUhpVHh6Y01oOHNaRmNLdWx1MDlTbWNibHNFY082WDBVakE0V091ZVFfcE51WDVra3pXT214b2kwNDZReEdNRFJndTVIdFhwbFJCUzVaNkpjVkR6b2o3M0dYaVc3Q1JzcW9sZGJxODlzem5RVGxkV1lGbUJEQ3ZkTGNqdzdUWGxJaDNQc1R1T1NXeC1WbXRiRkdLUDB1TUpjd1pjNg?oc=5" target="_blank">Tulsi, Kash, Vivek: Trump picks Hindu lawmakers for top cabinet roles</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of India</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxQVE12YWlYSXl5dVlPQjJoV1RrYW5vVE1xWEdBbTU4azQwYUc1blZTeHppdk5FRGliaTkyU09lVkFaRFdzYjdFNmotRlFCV21Gam5BTEtpb2lVREdPeUhscWlQQm5SZmxGWWlrYW1RcHNpTGVkYU8xemZzME14TEdmVGcwbGlmQUd0eUE?oc=5" target="_blank">A Constitutional Crisis Greater Than Watergate</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Atlantic</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxQclI3QkpTOHJBLVpBcE5xZ0pZY2NiekdycmNDbDBCcTlKLWk4RkY5NnU0RU82SGR2MDdUTHJCblAyUVhkdG1uampRNDV0Rll5TnRVcHpkZVFkdGpnVGJRcGExMXRVbE9iY0VlQjc0d2N0SzduXzZaMlcyLVdrbTd0Y2lB?oc=5" target="_blank">Lawmakers express doubt over Trump’s plan to replace FBI’s Christopher Wray</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxQYTBYMko5d0NPdzdZS3ZGRlg3VElKb3dBekQ2bmVZTFhKRGVSc2JPanlBTzFla1RlazViWW1Cb0dmcnBtY1pjRFQ3dEt3X2VjcG82bnN3bzF4ejJzNTEta0t4cC1vcmI2RjdmT25yMkNVYVBQbVUxWlY4RXVaaW02aDlR0gGHAUFVX3lxTFBLUGhhUHRpa3VzUk1SWUN2ODVyYnJrdGM5bjc5WVN0bVVYYkRaeXN5dHJnckpMcW0yZi1Bc1BRX2lJbFlZX2ZyTlNlb3E5dFNWOWluRENCSXNXQlFlN185cGRFTGk3QjlsOWFteE4xUzVaNThiRHBYZUV0bmlLN2RHSjZaamU0aw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxQYTBYMko5d0NPdzdZS3ZGRlg3VElKb3dBekQ2bmVZTFhKRGVSc2JPanlBTzFla1RlazViWW1Cb0dmcnBtY1pjRFQ3dEt3X2VjcG82bnN3bzF4ejJzNTEta0t4cC1vcmI2RjdmT25yMkNVYVBQbVUxWlY4RXVaaW02aDlR0gGHAUFVX3lxTFBLUGhhUHRpa3VzUk1SWUN2ODVyYnJrdGM5bjc5WVN0bVVYYkRaeXN5dHJnckpMcW0yZi1Bc1BRX2lJbFlZX2ZyTlNlb3E5dFNWOWluRENCSXNXQlFlN185cGRFTGk3QjlsOWFteE4xUzVaNThiRHBYZUV0bmlLN2RHSjZaamU0aw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 23:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Who are the rebels who have seized control of Aleppo, Syria? - NPR]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxOZGczNlUweWY2eFVFRVliZENIazBBcklMNzhraVJYRVllbzFkZm1mTmY2bWhHeEdDYXlSUWFpbE1PQWk1NC1TZHpONk1OUkRIa2NoVVNKRUZrRXNXTktWbS01Y2R2T0ttTGZ5RmM2Q3dlOFA0T25yMnpJcUlQYzhJa0JGeUVZcjBmLWd1Q1hvbURQa3NNblQxdUhTanBldw?oc=5" target="_blank">Who are the rebels who have seized control of Aleppo, Syria?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPdWJRTkNpeTg2a2N5U2lOVWs0aDhZWE1VVlR6VmpvYUdPemQwenRpSVRaTkNBVHh1ZlV2aVV0MWdVU0lKWkZ3UzQtdGVuQnljNlF3WmVHb3lrcHN6OGh4cTRIRnE2eHVRM19vVE5vU3g4TUEtT3BJVTRyTk1OUzZfcnQ4WUt6Q3FVRFpYaXBOVHl5WXJ2UmNSREdVYw?oc=5" target="_blank">A Dormant War in Syria Has Just Reignited</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Bloomberg</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxOb1lKbGFIbXZBTFl6RlMtV0FuY3M5d3Rma2VmSTh2MENpcW5VYmZHNm9EeWZtZVJYVUpETEtQZFQ4QzlQRHNsUHV2ODJycnBMTGowakFNSDZBdjRrcTR4OEhXVDQ1eTk5NVJDMW5WU3RiRXRHNWF6djkxRURyUFZGOExySU42VHJjYk45NzN0V2NLQ01xM3J3cjJydG1OeTFURW1VeDVDcVhmZjNTMlZfdlpMN0lMNU9tbDZOaUJWZnpKSUnSAWNBVV95cUxPV2Zhay1tWFUxUTlRTndpYWpxYl9UZjhrbWhSakdjYlhCNk44Q19RcC13R3I4QTFMdFNqSjNlbHZHTGFsQ2swRTE3Z05VOXBWN2NoTjZibjhkaE52NlBnczRIZlU?oc=5" target="_blank">Middle East conflict live updates: Syrian government counterattacks as rebels push forward</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxNUE5MejZueHZDOVRSMERMd1doMXFsdHJNd0F4SWZ3d011VkpYYmdYXzZycjFjRUdRVllaWDJ5TG5wRWRYQmlLMExlc2NMeHZ0VVN4VGNxRmluZmwtRVBJbTVzZVd6dEZwa2hkelBVQkZIU3pTV3htYjhzNllRQThhcGpjbHVWS1IxdmpYQjRtdG8xWmJY?oc=5" target="_blank">Live briefing: Rebels advance in Syria; UNRWA pauses Gaza aid at key crossing</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxOZy1fRnFTLUVjb0RQU2tGOFdWS0thVC1Pek5ZcjBWd085T01UN09zOVlzYjlGeDc0NlMwcWxCRFpTRVZFcTdCeUg0dXB5eDNWc3h2TWFVbzF2Z1hIc3hCa2pobl9LZTJhUHhOZkJKNm9JRGVJSDc3VmZLbTkyMy0xVF9kZ2NfV2tVcFZudG1tTzQ4eXRyOEQ2TTFjNGdOcnhQZ0tEVXMzek9xLU5NSVhiRFR5Z0szSERxWFV5QkctemoxWFBpYmlDb0FKM09vaC1JYkwtS0pGc3BKcHJKTnkzWk9xaTNWcWY3N282U3p5WkhGTHRMdUlfWnR0ak1Oem0zdFl6ctIBigJBVV95cUxPWVFDNWNqY1NaUV9FZlVvTFdMQ1RiU2dHbTRiSmxpcDI5amFpTXpSanVlTDdUUmxTMDlqSmtibG1CWENsRGJuQlBZUDZHVjFrSmtDakhTMEU3Nll2SmNZalduUEtmeGJkVEVKamFFQnJQcWFlaERoZnV0MXdFa2I3TTF2V3lxNHlmaUtVTjk5bVNnYzdoTlFQX2VsMFZ0MENDS1hKVi1tRDBvU1FxWUlZWm05MjFnTmFPeGhnUTc5OFRVeEl3eFBJN0FoTkNhenhKQXNreURKTzhqX3dIbzgtbXFpYUFrSi1QT0NKXzQyRll5X1F5MXF4ZUk3UmMwdkhjUHc3eWxaQjNXZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Fall of Aleppo: Who are Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, jihadist group behind resurgence of Syria conflict?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of India</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxOZGczNlUweWY2eFVFRVliZENIazBBcklMNzhraVJYRVllbzFkZm1mTmY2bWhHeEdDYXlSUWFpbE1PQWk1NC1TZHpONk1OUkRIa2NoVVNKRUZrRXNXTktWbS01Y2R2T0ttTGZ5RmM2Q3dlOFA0T25yMnpJcUlQYzhJa0JGeUVZcjBmLWd1Q1hvbURQa3NNblQxdUhTanBldw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxOZGczNlUweWY2eFVFRVliZENIazBBcklMNzhraVJYRVllbzFkZm1mTmY2bWhHeEdDYXlSUWFpbE1PQWk1NC1TZHpONk1OUkRIa2NoVVNKRUZrRXNXTktWbS01Y2R2T0ttTGZ5RmM2Q3dlOFA0T25yMnpJcUlQYzhJa0JGeUVZcjBmLWd1Q1hvbURQa3NNblQxdUhTanBldw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump threatens 100% tariff on Bric nations - BBC.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE5abmU2Sm1MZTRFUFRsbjVBQ3VOVWxFZ1JvWVc5a3d5M2N6U3JBWk8yUDdnYUZQQkpHV3dmSTNfN1BzY2lDTno0R3ptQk9tNFp5OTV6c0RMVExmUdIBX0FVX3lxTE5SbnZzdEE2YjNhTENOSFl1dFZENWt0OWNKZzRRZ1k1b0phdk9WZm85bWRTeDEzUVJzb3dPOUhkSzRzSmhBVlRKa1d4dnBES19QclBzRGJQcWFhNHdkbkxz?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump threatens 100% tariff on Bric nations</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxOVS1TVjRiOUZrN1JSa1Ruel9XekEzal9KdGpoeE5nWFRjVFVmRlpTWlN3VGlGSWs3QW14SERIR1VGVHQ5ZXZ0YlJzY1laS2F4aG54d1hfcmVjcDAwOUR0ZUY4LTl3SXJDVmtlN2pwQ0ZRYS1PWGVCSFdQRGNNelBuNzNFN2PSAXtBVV95cUxQYjJmZ3VVWXdHanhUR0REUnQwX3hTZ3BWa21GcG9SNTJWd2planR1YTFON1RUMzNDcGtiNUZWb0liZnN1b0NmNW5LUjM0RFRiVDJucDFINXMyeWpLdUkyYnB6Y1dSXzdkN1A2bWg5Q2RaRFZkOGFqNV95ZG8?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump threatens 100% tariff on BRICS countries if they pursue creating new currency</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTFB6Y0Uwc08xT1dYT2dScklLZEdTREJLN1RCOTdDSV9sZjcwYjZmZ3MwbWMtSW05Q05OYkFNQk9SbjdqeE5NaU1UcDNDc3M2TGltNHpyTXpfalc4MTh6OUVFTDVaSGdzalRYTVplMzMteks?oc=5" target="_blank">Greatest threat to Trump’s dollar is Trump himself</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Financial Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxPX1pkT0YzWHJhTUc5Z1BfNzNuX1c0T3lqUlRoeXo4NWh0ZTNaYUlBdW9MbS00cVBRZnBKaXVhSFU3VUxoZFpTM21ZaWIyRWhQMHFkNVBHN1hVT055S0hiR0dQeGx2aG96cFBGVHR4RUxYRWxHNnd3eUlxUGYxaTFjUG45TmxxZkpncU5QQkV6LWQ3b2huZkE?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump Threatens Putin’s Russia And Xi’s China With ‘100% Tariffs’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Daily Beast</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxNWmdudUFnU0VvcnRsVlZhYkluYnlvN3FYNEZBMTBOWW9RTWFFeXBDSGwzemtfLVBDTkZDQ1BhbFZacXN4SWR3QWJFQXRBTXZUUUxaZ2RNTjdMSnRwZ1VROEdiTE5sMlVSaTNFSDR1RHNQaVJTaGVsUktaM3JMYzRQbVRzWEJLMGhDM29vcWpZMnBoV0xraDR5a1lFdEQxa25QMW1mSk9lM1Y5XzUyQ2E2ck5kQUVPa0NXUTF6cm8wTjVudy1C0gFkQVVfeXFMTi1heENGTEx3N2Q0SkhOV1FvWHliTTFYS04yUGFjTmNDRFNrak9JOXNsbVNINXJ2Ynp3VDUzbWhlbFBhVjFPZnp5d2tUbE0yN2ZZN3hRZ3hfbUlRZXNqU3NqWXE4bg?oc=5" target="_blank">Ali Velshi: Trump’s new tariff threat ‘isn’t the way’ to change global trade</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MSNBC</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE5abmU2Sm1MZTRFUFRsbjVBQ3VOVWxFZ1JvWVc5a3d5M2N6U3JBWk8yUDdnYUZQQkpHV3dmSTNfN1BzY2lDTno0R3ptQk9tNFp5OTV6c0RMVExmUdIBX0FVX3lxTE5SbnZzdEE2YjNhTENOSFl1dFZENWt0OWNKZzRRZ1k1b0phdk9WZm85bWRTeDEzUVJzb3dPOUhkSzRzSmhBVlRKa1d4dnBES19QclBzRGJQcWFhNHdkbkxz?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE5abmU2Sm1MZTRFUFRsbjVBQ3VOVWxFZ1JvWVc5a3d5M2N6U3JBWk8yUDdnYUZQQkpHV3dmSTNfN1BzY2lDTno0R3ptQk9tNFp5OTV6c0RMVExmUdIBX0FVX3lxTE5SbnZzdEE2YjNhTENOSFl1dFZENWt0OWNKZzRRZ1k1b0phdk9WZm85bWRTeDEzUVJzb3dPOUhkSzRzSmhBVlRKa1d4dnBES19QclBzRGJQcWFhNHdkbkxz?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:15:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How RFK Jr. Transformed From Green Hero to Vaccine Skeptic - The Wall Street Journal]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQU1c2RE5sSlhCVV9UMk1QRlg1WkJlQXRpUDh6cDlfLVc1VjVpdVNCbTNVbVk0MlVYMWJ0MEhiSG03YXNYN3VYMENFQjJQSk5tYzQwS2YzaGU0N3llMUR6QnRVN1NRVnlrN0REaGxtZGRVZlZiek1xMDNtX1BpM0xnMk1hUHFuT1lWYllRSUl5Y3VLUlpGOTl6Zk0yVQ?oc=5" target="_blank">How RFK Jr. Transformed From Green Hero to Vaccine Skeptic</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Wall Street Journal</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxNdWU1d3puZkNHbnRockxERXN1M2RyazlMc3d5WWc2ZlE2U1RZbkN6N3NZaHpLYjNZZjVDT2lIRk5yOW9kT1l4QzF3NFc4TWxwNHc4ZUJ0LTVPMVJ0UVNxTzVvNjl5Q1RpTmljWGFvWnpvMFI2WUxlcWZWdnFXQUJnN0pScw?oc=5" target="_blank">Kennedy’s Inheritance: How Addiction and Trauma Shaped a Turbulent Life</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQaDkxTndFY0ExY3UwOHlaZEZodFB3cEt1Y19lREJKNXgwME52SXFkb0g3b3o0MG9yaThRMGJFR1ItNUNaeDlUTFJINlNOXy1NMDFRUEJpNVYtamtGaDdWUUlrTGJPM0x3ZmRHTHpsMXdpVXZwSE43SWItVFBsTHJjU0cwTDQ?oc=5" target="_blank">RFK Jr. nomination process heats up</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Axios</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxNMnpsVjB1cVEtdC1vRTdOLWJKZlY3alJWNVBsZ2dYMERhcjBTckVqX2FrdEtLNVJvOWlaYWdZeUpPMVQ5djlTRm00MXo4RWp0RlEzX0VlbWtSNWhWc3RMc0NNRDY4enJpeVpWWVRyTUtCRy1tWnhuTV92dDFwMktDNVBLSQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Opinion | Bobby Kennedy finally achieves escape velocity</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxPR3lfTEk4cXQ0ZkY0OERLLUVMVWVwcjN5c3U2NUFtRnYzNVh1YnJWbEQ2UXlFVXZLWFZvSTRTVlNFU21lN05CWWxiR3R6bERJSTY2R2dnSDltNm5JWmRNTkpRV1UtcFozTUFKTE1TajdubWY4aElySHV0NS1nU1JXU0Yzb3JRYk96WkpxbnRn?oc=5" target="_blank">How Robert F. Kennedy Jr. went from outsider to Cabinet pick</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Los Angeles Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQU1c2RE5sSlhCVV9UMk1QRlg1WkJlQXRpUDh6cDlfLVc1VjVpdVNCbTNVbVk0MlVYMWJ0MEhiSG03YXNYN3VYMENFQjJQSk5tYzQwS2YzaGU0N3llMUR6QnRVN1NRVnlrN0REaGxtZGRVZlZiek1xMDNtX1BpM0xnMk1hUHFuT1lWYllRSUl5Y3VLUlpGOTl6Zk0yVQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQU1c2RE5sSlhCVV9UMk1QRlg1WkJlQXRpUDh6cDlfLVc1VjVpdVNCbTNVbVk0MlVYMWJ0MEhiSG03YXNYN3VYMENFQjJQSk5tYzQwS2YzaGU0N3llMUR6QnRVN1NRVnlrN0REaGxtZGRVZlZiek1xMDNtX1BpM0xnMk1hUHFuT1lWYllRSUl5Y3VLUlpGOTl6Zk0yVQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Syria, Russia Conduct Deadly Strikes To Push Back Rebel Advance - The Moscow Times]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOMjlDcm5BX0F2ODNLN2NDVDNoR3lNV1pqTW9UbDZvRGNmZ3lNcHZoV0NUbEpvTHlLcWFUd29oX20wWEhsQklxMC1ObnRqb1hUcHpGMW1KNFVmRHBLWVVKOUdvcmpzRmZnTWRHZEh3OFF5LVlMSTBfLXdaenRNcHYzQ2I2MFBESjgzZGRsS2RZQVd2YVM3U0NKdUhtQ3ZWQnpJVmdlbDVrUFJzRHRUYUsybQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Syria, Russia Conduct Deadly Strikes To Push Back Rebel Advance</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Moscow Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxNd0syWk5qWUstbE9BSllWZG9vRmRxWUVMeHZ4Q2dsOGl4Tm1YZU5MTE9nR0RDcGxRTlhsakxmU1o0dnNkVjM3bWtYVzdlNW5yelNQcnpwRld2WUsxcnplU0VPYXdpLVF6bnVqdG5pOWRTR0p2QmlZQklpcWhOa1RQT19uckNSdXdDQngwb3JpV1DSAZYBQVVfeXFMTnR5LTlQSTMwSUJTMnlsTnNPUlI5MGFNektBenpjRWl1cUJsTHNSRUg1dkl3b09JaDlMRzBxUDQ3SWNLVXp1T0hYZlUyVnBtWEhHMWJnT0ItaUhRaG8zdzRISkJKN1BTOVJ5dTZ2bW9ESmVyUkFROVN0em9zSVlXNTdzVTFGNW5hR2NqR2FaaVhpNm5fUXBR?oc=5" target="_blank">Syria's civil war reignites in dramatic fashion as Russia joins airstrikes on rebels who seized Aleppo</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNazQ4LVlxREY3TGl3ZUhiT0dIb2lfb24yVmtSdWdSYlk0Nl83WkdIMnoxeVFGYzBqck4tQ3JkeFpQUmpQMFh3YXZpMXVYOEphd2w4aGFLVEJnQUpteTk0dDhGWUROaGJMaGFyZ2RyN2FvRXJWZlVqamVmUUlQb2hHVl9xeGNWc25zcTZyZFNSbFlpenRBRXQ2enpHMmZqTnNMOXp6Ml9XT1U2Mm1Z0gGyAUFVX3lxTE1XZkxGUHJRSnNVajFXYXFYT1htTU5SUjVIN3VHTFdaVTV5WHlaNW4xMi1uQURoMFBiOER3WkRkTnp2b2hzRjEzTDdPenk0RVpUR2R4MDZfb1JvZkxhSWphRFlQSUx4bU14bHg2RmFCcFpZVUl3NTRUeDJlOGM1aGZuOXlTYXJaVkE0Rnh4ZXVxaXFKbEZDS3N0VVByRHBETnNJTUtpQUd5cmhGek0wVmgxUWc?oc=5" target="_blank">Russian jets strike Syria after rebels seize Aleppo in shock offensive</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Sky News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiX0FVX3lxTE5jLWVtVEdfTGdkTW9iOF9ELUU4OVVkT3dNYVc2Q0JwUVVWaHlycTNoemhtVGFJS2l3ekhpM2lfVVN3bTZyUDdBTTl0REtvRjA5TmFYcHB0dlZLX0RCTFRF?oc=5" target="_blank">Airstrikes in northwestern Syria kill 25 people, says Syria's White Helmets</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Jerusalem Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxOU0N0VEp3Q0NlSHFKSTlaS3RLSWZrdG5COWZDTGJudTk3b1lNVkhfend4WlhxMkI4YWZIa3JOSy1DWHJRbTl4TVYzaVRRQk5wVFBEc0JaWnVoUzJabkp2S2daR1VLcm1RNlV5UTVvaEY2cVFCMDlXSjF2UXg5R2dNVQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Syrian Civil Defence teams rescue survivors as group says strikes hit Idlib City</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo! Voices</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOMjlDcm5BX0F2ODNLN2NDVDNoR3lNV1pqTW9UbDZvRGNmZ3lNcHZoV0NUbEpvTHlLcWFUd29oX20wWEhsQklxMC1ObnRqb1hUcHpGMW1KNFVmRHBLWVVKOUdvcmpzRmZnTWRHZEh3OFF5LVlMSTBfLXdaenRNcHYzQ2I2MFBESjgzZGRsS2RZQVd2YVM3U0NKdUhtQ3ZWQnpJVmdlbDVrUFJzRHRUYUsybQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOMjlDcm5BX0F2ODNLN2NDVDNoR3lNV1pqTW9UbDZvRGNmZ3lNcHZoV0NUbEpvTHlLcWFUd29oX20wWEhsQklxMC1ObnRqb1hUcHpGMW1KNFVmRHBLWVVKOUdvcmpzRmZnTWRHZEh3OFF5LVlMSTBfLXdaenRNcHYzQ2I2MFBESjgzZGRsS2RZQVd2YVM3U0NKdUhtQ3ZWQnpJVmdlbDVrUFJzRHRUYUsybQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 08:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iraqi militias deploy in Syria to back government’s counteroffensive against insurgents - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxPeUw3dE1VdUd5eEx6d2ZEb1czVDR0Uk1kdk5lT3phZjkyejZjU1VkZXIzSGFCV2tuQWVGbXdFZ0YwN3dzSjVMaFA5T1BuSlZZa1lzNlBnQ0k3WWdQWGhVSDJMeGlVblJRQ1ZLRFBZa3dKYjN4QmRyRlZLMVlMQ3FWMVlaUjFFZ2dfdWJRSTNXaGVnUThPWGJsNmMwZlNSZUV5THhJ?oc=5" target="_blank">Iraqi militias deploy in Syria to back government’s counteroffensive against insurgents</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxPSTNkeGEyUnJQR0FSQXZnZE8yNXRMMmluSnNMN2U0cDUyTkJHUF9VMlI4Tjl5TVpVVFI4Q0h6Qzl1WFhLSmpMdEhERmUwbng5U2ptQ05NdEtDeHJvQzJoNFEzWThpVTE0WXNFU2ItZ0E1U0FFMUd5T3NOMUlVNWEyR1A0eWh5WEtPNG1fb19EMHFKS3dYUkHSAZYBQVVfeXFMUE41NGRsdFRYVjlZWURqTWhYTlg3NUprbTdSVGUxMEVtWDl1NzBGOWJXVEl5VHB5X0p5V1BZZWxWR2piNGd1dzlBbnkydzRYX3pyOWlLc2RYWjRXSjhxMTBReGNXMWZLdGZFWXJLRVdxdGt3M3B2M0wtZFQtMTVuLUlmblpBV3MwZGpmZFNpMFZmNk1mV21n?oc=5" target="_blank">Middle East crisis live: Iranian-backed militias reportedly enter Syria to support Assad’s army</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQaTdfYlYyd0dxNHBXb1hjRm1Odkx3Zk05LS02R3RnZTRsUHd3UlRkYXNKT3pXLUJXX3N3SWpCRi1IclBoczhXNDBfOGtRWVZad0hHY3Mxd0xVdng1bElxLXRnd0xUWkUza3BuQl8zZE5XQkFXdXNuYW1UY0ptTkVWbkdGU2o?oc=5" target="_blank">Iraqi militias enter Syria to reinforce government forces, military sources say</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo! Voices</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxNUTZxeE5vNld4Q0VKaTJlTURibHYxY2M1WEw0TFFMbmY0ZUpEQWlleUVyMk4xTzJJQUcyY0lZdVNvVDZrMXhUeWtMZW1vZ0dVdElmTmZDUmVYMnNiakR0TU9fTnI1d21rR3VCTHlROVYxWjBzUV9zNnl6aWMwQjhPaHBXYVNkLVhjM2F3R3lTNjVsZlZMcURITHVDOA?oc=5" target="_blank">Exclusive—Syria War Escalates as Iran-Backed Iraq Militias Vow Intervention</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Newsweek</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNWE5iUWRXZ1p0UEtzTnpXTGU4Y0NvRmo5QW9td3FCal9CX1I1MjlER2ZNczFaUVRMeTdjLWtHUi1Ed0xoSDg4UXNrR0JONENhLVcwSnFuR0xZelBRZVp0cnJlR2VQM2pFN29Yd05CaXJUS0dteVZ0WVFZbmNoR0hwSGhLeWhEa05HQ1c40gGQAUFVX3lxTE11M1pFS1pEamlNX0dzb296ZE4wdWxCSjlPN2hZQk1lMTFJWVlSMG5hbFFGQ0dTN0NoeXFDZ3pib0tfM2kwSzlhSnVuVmdWQ1JfbkNIMklCNW8tMXZyOTJSdWkwYmpLZ1g1bC02aVZ1MGhGdHNjcHViS1ZTYzdzTklzRVA0TDN6M3JVWHFLNUM4VQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Iraqi factions prepare to send fighters to back Syria's Assad</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New Arab</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxPeUw3dE1VdUd5eEx6d2ZEb1czVDR0Uk1kdk5lT3phZjkyejZjU1VkZXIzSGFCV2tuQWVGbXdFZ0YwN3dzSjVMaFA5T1BuSlZZa1lzNlBnQ0k3WWdQWGhVSDJMeGlVblJRQ1ZLRFBZa3dKYjN4QmRyRlZLMVlMQ3FWMVlaUjFFZ2dfdWJRSTNXaGVnUThPWGJsNmMwZlNSZUV5THhJ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxPeUw3dE1VdUd5eEx6d2ZEb1czVDR0Uk1kdk5lT3phZjkyejZjU1VkZXIzSGFCV2tuQWVGbXdFZ0YwN3dzSjVMaFA5T1BuSlZZa1lzNlBnQ0k3WWdQWGhVSDJMeGlVblJRQ1ZLRFBZa3dKYjN4QmRyRlZLMVlMQ3FWMVlaUjFFZ2dfdWJRSTNXaGVnUThPWGJsNmMwZlNSZUV5THhJ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[From beer to barley: How Trump’s tariff threat could affect your wallet]]></title><description><![CDATA[Donald Trump’s threat to hit Mexico with tariffs could raise prices on a surprising number of foods and drinks Americans love — from beer to berries to broccoli.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/12/02/mexico-tariffs-beer-avocados-tomatoes-berries/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/12/02/mexico-tariffs-beer-avocados-tomatoes-berries/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:00:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What led to Syria’s 13-year civil war, and why has fighting surged again? ]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:50:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zelenskyy: Ukrainian Army Lacks Strength to Liberate All Occupied Territories, Diplomatic Solutions Needed]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4r5lr/zelenskyy_ukrainian_army_lacks_strength_to/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/ey6y0V4i1IWiQd39ERPpY88JH1TRI9-8vg4oaQRSL_k.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=3f8b922096d88459c1189f2e1ef923392904d811" alt="Zelenskyy: Ukrainian Army Lacks Strength to Liberate All Occupied Territories, Diplomatic Solutions Needed" title="Zelenskyy: Ukrainian Army Lacks Strength to Liberate All Occupied Territories, Diplomatic Solutions Needed" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Beautiful-Hat-8625"> /u/Beautiful-Hat-8625 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://united24media.com/latest-news/zelenskyy-ukraines-army-lacks-strength-to-liberate-all-occupied-territories-diplomatic-solutions-needed-4149">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4r5lr/zelenskyy_ukrainian_army_lacks_strength_to/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4r5lr/zelenskyy_ukrainian_army_lacks_strength_to/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4r5lr/zelenskyy_ukrainian_army_lacks_strength_to/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Beautiful-Hat-8625]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:23:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine strikes Russian air defense system in Crimea: Forbes reveals possible target]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4rxim/ukraine_strikes_russian_air_defense_system_in/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/M7kDLUttM96_P_AEQx_FyFzmFbbf9ZilzzaSGFgBzlc.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=68762c3fde6fabba5b2dac22d50d53e62980a50d" alt="Ukraine strikes Russian air defense system in Crimea: Forbes reveals possible target" title="Ukraine strikes Russian air defense system in Crimea: Forbes reveals possible target" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/eaglemaxie"> /u/eaglemaxie </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://newsukraine.rbc.ua/news/ukraine-strikes-russian-air-defense-system-1733133779.html">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4rxim/ukraine_strikes_russian_air_defense_system_in/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4rxim/ukraine_strikes_russian_air_defense_system_in/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4rxim/ukraine_strikes_russian_air_defense_system_in/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/eaglemaxie]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:22:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Romanian Social Democrats Win Vote Despite Far-Right Surge in Parliament (coverage)]]></title><description><![CDATA[&#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/kaosvision"> /u/kaosvision </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://symby.com/news?q=romania+election+democrats+parliamentary+ballots+leftists&amp;_cid=5870608">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4t6h8/romanian_social_democrats_win_vote_despite/">[comments]</a></span>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4t6h8/romanian_social_democrats_win_vote_despite/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4t6h8/romanian_social_democrats_win_vote_despite/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/kaosvision]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:48:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[At least 25 killed as Russian, Syrian jets intensify bombing of Syrian rebel territory]]></title><description><![CDATA[&#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/JarKachYn"> /u/JarKachYn </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/least-25-killed-russian-syrian-jets-intensify-bombing-syrian-rebel-territory-2024-12-02/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4pj8k/at_least_25_killed_as_russian_syrian_jets/">[comments]</a></span>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4pj8k/at_least_25_killed_as_russian_syrian_jets/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1h4pj8k/at_least_25_killed_as_russian_syrian_jets/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/JarKachYn]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 07:21:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[When Vivek Ramaswamy predicted Joe Biden would pardon son Hunter]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/115901530.cms" />In June, when Hunter Biden was convicted, Vivek Ramaswamy predicted that it was a farce and Joe Biden would definitely pardon him. At that time, Biden did not indicate that he would favor his son and save him from trial and following punishment. But on Sunday, in a surprising move, Biden pardoned his son Sunday saying that his son was treated differently as his political opponents pounced on him. ]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/when-vivek-ramaswamy-predicted-joe-biden-would-pardon-son-hunter/articleshow/115901530.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/when-vivek-ramaswamy-predicted-joe-biden-would-pardon-son-hunter/articleshow/115901530.cms</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:10:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Joe Biden pardoning his son Hunter is so controversial]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/115899974.cms" />President Joe Biden's pardon of his son, Hunter Biden, has led to significant controversy. It contradicts Biden's previous assurances against such a pardon, diverges from Justice Department clemency guidelines, raises ethical concerns regarding nepotism, and has sparked political backlash and renewed scrutiny of Biden's clemency record.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/why-joe-biden-pardoning-his-son-hunter-is-so-controversial/articleshow/115899974.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/why-joe-biden-pardoning-his-son-hunter-is-so-controversial/articleshow/115899974.cms</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:38:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Canada pulls refugee welcome mat, launches ads warning asylum claims hard]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/115900010.cms" />Canada, once a welcoming nation for refugees, is now cautioning asylum-seekers through a $250,000 global online ad campaign that making a claim is difficult and has strict guidelines. ]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/canada-pulls-refugee-welcome-mat-launches-ads-warning-asylum-claims-hard/articleshow/115900010.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/canada-pulls-refugee-welcome-mat-launches-ads-warning-asylum-claims-hard/articleshow/115900010.cms</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:15:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fall of Aleppo: Who are Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, jihadist group behind resurgence of Syria conflict?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/115897481.cms" />Recently, Syrian rebels launched a major offensive in Aleppo, seizing parts of the city and pushing south towards Hama. This prompted the first Russian airstrikes on Aleppo since 2016. The operation was led by Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS), reviving conflict amidst new geopolitical dynamics and challenges faced by Assad's allies.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/fall-of-aleppo-who-are-hayat-tahrir-al-sham-jihadist-group-behind-resurgence-of-syria-conflict/articleshow/115897481.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/fall-of-aleppo-who-are-hayat-tahrir-al-sham-jihadist-group-behind-resurgence-of-syria-conflict/articleshow/115897481.cms</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:44:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Countries call for binding targets to cut plastic production after talks fail]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Group of 85 countries and blocs press for ambition in plastic waste treaty after no agreement was reached in Busan</p><p>Binding global targets to cut plastic production must be at the centre of any continuing negotiations to secure the world’s first treaty to tackle plastic waste, a group of 85 countries has said.</p><p>Talks in Busan, South Korea, attempting to secure agreement between more than 200 countries on the details of a plastic pollution treaty <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/dec/01/international-talks-on-curbing-plastic-pollution-fail-to-reach-agreement-busan">ended in failure</a> over the weekend.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/dec/02/countries-call-for-binding-targets-to-cut-plastic-production-busan-talks">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/dec/02/countries-call-for-binding-targets-to-cut-plastic-production-busan-talks</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/dec/02/countries-call-for-binding-targets-to-cut-plastic-production-busan-talks</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:33:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Centre-right Fianna Fáil and Fine Gael set to retain power in Ireland]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Parties expected to hold talks as election results show incumbents closing in on majority needed to govern</p><p>The two main centre-right parties in Ireland are expected to start talks on returning to government as the general election put the incumbents within touching distance of forming the 34th Dáil.</p><p>All but 12 Teachta Dála (TD) seats were filled when counting resumed at 9am on Monday but the results so far and tallies for the remaining seats suggest Fianna Fáil, led by Micheál Martin, and Fine Gael, led by Simon Harris, will together get 86 seats, just two short of the 88 needed for a majority.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/dec/02/ireland-election-centre-right-fianna-fail-fine-gael-to-retain-power">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/dec/02/ireland-election-centre-right-fianna-fail-fine-gael-to-retain-power</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/dec/02/ireland-election-centre-right-fianna-fail-fine-gael-to-retain-power</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:28:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Romania election: Social Democrats on course to win most seats despite far-right surge]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Centre-left PSD looks to have held off far-right challenge, with 70% of Romanians voting for mainstream parties</p><p>Romania’s ruling Social Democrat party (PSD) was on course to win the most votes in Sunday’s parliamentary elections, holding off a strong far-right surge that could yet deliver the country’s presidency to a Moscow-friendly ultranationalist.</p><p>Amid uncertainty as to whether the constitutional court would on Monday order the first round of the separate presidential ballot to be rerun, officials said that with 99.5% of votes counted in the parliamentary election, the centre-left PSD was credited with 22.6% of the vote.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/dec/02/romania-social-democrats-on-course-to-win-parliamentary-majority">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/dec/02/romania-social-democrats-on-course-to-win-parliamentary-majority</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/dec/02/romania-social-democrats-on-course-to-win-parliamentary-majority</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:17:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Middle East crisis live: Iranian-backed militias reportedly enter Syria to support Assad’s army]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Move comes after Aleppo falls to Islamist rebels, Hayat Tahrir al-Sham</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/dec/02/who-are-syrian-rebels-hayat-tahrir-al-sham-hts-aleppo">Who are HTS and why are they advancing?</a></li></ul><p>Israeli media reports that prime minister <strong>Benjamin Netanyahu</strong> will give testimony in his corruption trial not in Jerusalem as originally planned, but in a fortified bunker in Tel Aviv.</p><p>Netanyahu’s lawyers have sought to delay him giving testimony, arguing that conducting the war has deprived him of the opportunity to prepare his defence, and the security implications of having him appear at a known time and public location.</p><p>We all have come to the conclusion that any sort of insecurity in Syria won’t be limited to Syria alone. We are all aware of the fact that terrorism would not be concentrated in a single place and spreads to other areas.</p><p>Our Turkish friends are as much concerned as we are about the course of developments in Syria. It is clear that one of the reasons for … terrorism in Syria has been the occupation by the American military forces.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/dec/02/middle-east-crisis-live-syria-iran-assad">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/dec/02/middle-east-crisis-live-syria-iran-assad</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/dec/02/middle-east-crisis-live-syria-iran-assad</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:32:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UK politics live: calls for tighter donation laws amid reports Musk could give Reform UK $100m]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Farage says he was unaware of possible move by US tech billionaire and says he doubts such a donation will take place</p><p><strong>Nigel Farage</strong>, the Reform UK leader, has said that he does not believe a story saying Elon Musk, the multi-billionaire Trump ally and owner of X, might give his party $100m.</p><p>The suggestion was contained in<a href="https://www.thetimes.com/uk/politics/article/elon-musk-pay-nigel-farage-prime-minister-xts720xsp"> a story published by the Sunday Times</a> yesterday. It did not feature an on-the-record source for the claim, but it said “leading businessmen and Conservative Party officials believe there is a credible prospect that Musk is preparing to give $100 million (£78 million) to Farage as a “f*** you Starmer payment” with a view to transforming British politics”.</p><p>I suspect this is not true. Legally, companies operating in the UK can give money to UK political parties, but I think we’re a very long way away from that.</p><p>Look, if it did happen, well, that’d be great, but I think it’s one of those really very good gossipy Sunday newspaper things. Let’s see. But I rather doubt it.</p><p>The craziest thing about this story is that it is all perfectly legal.</p><p>Musk is a South African-born billionaire who lives in the US. Our election laws are explicitly supposed to prevent foreign donations like this - but anyone, from anywhere, can get around the rules if they donate through a UK registered company. (A wheeze <a href="https://democracyforsale.substack.com/p/robert-jenrick-donations-loss-making-company-tory">Robert Jenrick knows well.</a>)</p><p>New targets on living standards will be unveiled by Keir Starmer on Thursday</p><p>Is being seen as a sidelining of his big economic pledge - getting the highest growth in the G7</p><p>The problem with the ‘highest sustained growth in G7’ target is Starmer of course doesn’t control the economies of US, Aus, Canada, Germany, France, Japan</p><p>US growing way faster now: 2.8% estimate for 2024 vs 1.1% for UK</p><p>For the new living standards target real household disposable income and GDP per capita have been considered.</p><p>The new promise will likely have the benefit of not being a pledge to beat other countries.</p><p>Note the nuance. The G7 target remains. It will likely be mentioned in the ‘Plan For Change’ document unveiled on Thurs and Starmer’s speech</p><p>But a new major economic pledge will now be unveiled which in the coming years is likely to be talked about much more than the G7 ambition</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/dec/02/uk-politics-live-keir-starmer-nhs-waiting-lists-housebuilding">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/dec/02/uk-politics-live-keir-starmer-nhs-waiting-lists-housebuilding</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/dec/02/uk-politics-live-keir-starmer-nhs-waiting-lists-housebuilding</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:01:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[NHS bosses reportedly worried about Starmer’s pledge to cut waiting lists]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>PM expected to set target to carry out 92% of routine operations and appointments within 18 weeks</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/dec/02/uk-politics-live-keir-starmer-nhs-waiting-lists-housebuilding">UK politics live – latest updates</a></li></ul><p>NHS bosses are said to be privately concerned about Keir Starmer’s <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2024/nov/30/starmer-to-pledge-cuts-to-nhs-waiting-lists-and-in-major-reset-for-labour">ambitious targets</a> to cut waiting lists for routine operations, set to be announced later this week, which will also include specific targets on living standards and housebuilding.</p><p>The prime minister is expected on Thursday to set a target for 92% of routine operations and appointments to be carried out within 18 weeks, one that has not been achieved in almost a decade, the Times has reported.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/dec/02/cut-nhs-waiting-lists-keir-starmer">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/dec/02/cut-nhs-waiting-lists-keir-starmer</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/dec/02/cut-nhs-waiting-lists-keir-starmer</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:30:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump allies begin attack on EPA and rules protecting US drinking water]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>With Biden soon to leave the White House, Republicans start an assault on the Environmental Protection Agency</p><p>Donald Trump’s allies have fired the opening salvoes of his coming administration’s attack on the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the federal agency that enforces and regulates laws on air, soil, and water quality among other crucial environmental and health issues.</p><p>In a <a href="https://peer.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/11_20_24_House_Oversight_EPA-Scientific-Integrity-Letter-11_15_24.pdf">letter from Republican House leadership</a> to EPA the administrator, Michael Regan, Republicans trained their sites on the agency’s scientific integrity policies that are designed to insulate scientists and research from political interference.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/dec/02/trump-allies-attack-epa-drinking-water-rules">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/dec/02/trump-allies-attack-epa-drinking-water-rules</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/dec/02/trump-allies-attack-epa-drinking-water-rules</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:00:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Anti-opioid groups are ‘optimistic’ about Trump’s tariffs. Will the move help tackle the fentanyl crisis?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Campaigners say imposing fee on Mexico, Canada and China till they address drug smuggling could be effective</p><p>Anti-opioid campaigners in the US have welcomed Donald Trump’s threat to hit Mexico, China and Canada with increased trade tariffs if they do not curb the smuggling of the powerful drug driving the US opioid epidemic.</p><p>Families and doctors grappling with a crisis that has claimed about 900,000 lives say the move may signal that a second Trump administration will finally get serious about tackling the flow of fentanyl into the US. But they also warn that much more needs to be done to reduce demand for opioids and to rein in the power of the pharmaceutical industry which created the epidemic.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/02/trump-tarrifs-anti-opioid-groups">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/02/trump-tarrifs-anti-opioid-groups</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/02/trump-tarrifs-anti-opioid-groups</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:00:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[First Thing: Biden issues ‘full and unconditional’ pardon to son Hunter]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The president reverses his pledge not to use his executive authority in this way, claiming that his son’s prosecution was politically motivated. Plus: scientists ask whether humans are hardwired to commit bad deeds</p><ul><li><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/info/2018/sep/17/guardian-us-morning-briefing-sign-up-to-stay-informed">Don’t already get First Thing in your inbox? Sign up here</a></strong></li></ul><p>Good morning.</p><p>Joe Biden has <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/01/joe-biden-pardons-hunter">granted “a full and unconditional” pardon</a> to his son Hunter Biden, days before he was due to be sentenced for convictions on federal gun and tax charges, the US president said in a statement released by the White House on Sunday.</p><p><strong>How did Republicans respond?</strong> Donald Trump called the decision “such an abuse and miscarriage of justice”. Trump, too, has used executive authority to help a relative – <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/dec/23/donald-trumps-latest-wave-of-pardons-includes-paul-manafort-and-charles-kunsher">he pardoned Charles Kushner</a>, the father of his son-in-law Jared Kushner in 2020.</p><p><strong>How will Canada secure its border?</strong> LeBlanc said Canada would procure more drones and police helicopters and redeploy personnel.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/02/first-thing-biden-issues-full-and-unconditional-pardon-to-son-hunter">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/02/first-thing-biden-issues-full-and-unconditional-pardon-to-son-hunter</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/02/first-thing-biden-issues-full-and-unconditional-pardon-to-son-hunter</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:11:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Washington DC reacts to President Biden pardoning son Hunter in shock decision]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/president-biden-pardons-son-hunter-021000547.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/president-biden-pardons-son-hunter-021000547.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 02:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Former Israeli defense minister Yaalon warns of ethnic cleansing in Gaza]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/former-israeli-defense-minister-yaalon-171618483.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/former-israeli-defense-minister-yaalon-171618483.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 17:16:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump Labor pick surprises unions, rattles business]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/trump-labor-pick-surprises-unions-220000191.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/trump-labor-pick-surprises-unions-220000191.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>