<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 14:49:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 14:49:49 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Who is Ryan Wesley Routh? The suspect in the Trump Florida assassination attempt, explained.]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="People in uniform stand on the side of a road strung with police tape." data-caption="Law enforcement gather at the crime scene outside the Trump International Golf Club in West Palm Beach, Florida, following a second apparent assassination attempt on former President Donald Trump on September 15, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2171585640.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Law enforcement gather at the crime scene outside the Trump International Golf Club in West Palm Beach, Florida, following a second apparent assassination attempt on former President Donald Trump on September 15, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Just two months after a man <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360489/trump-shot-thomas-matthew-crooks-secret-service-butler-rally">tried to assassinate</a> former President Donald Trump, the Secret Service says it stopped what appeared to be <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/09/15/us/harris-trump-election">a second assassination attempt</a> against the former president.&nbsp;Unlike the July 13 shooting at Trump’s rally, in which a member of the crowd was killed and Trump was injured, no one was harmed this time. But the incident has raised questions about the ability of the Secret Service to protect the former president and sparked new concerns about the risk of ongoing political violence this election cycle.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Sunday, law enforcement officials say, the former president was playing golf on his course in West Palm Beach, Florida, when Secret Service agents <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2W1Yi_Np64U">spotted a gun barrel in the bushes</a> on the perimeter of the course. Agents surrounded the former president and opened fire, prompting a man to flee the scene.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The suspected gunman was 300–500 yards from the former president, according to Palm Beach County Sheriff Ric Bradshaw in a press conference. (While close, the suspect was not as close as Trump’s July shooter, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/heres-what-we-know-about-thomas-matthew-crooks-suspected-trump-rally-shooter-2024-07-14/">who was within roughly 150 yards</a> of the president when he opened fire.) Police said they found an AK-47 style rifle with a scope, along with two backpacks and a camera, in the bushes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is still unclear whether the suspected gunman fired any shots before the Secret Service reacted. The former president — according to Fox News anchor Sean Hannity, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/15/us/politics/trump-reaction-golf-shooting.html">who spoke to</a> the president on Sunday after the attempted attack — was safe and in good spirits.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A witness saw someone fleeing the vicinity in a black Nissan immediately after the incident, according to Bradshaw, and law enforcement officials announced that they apprehended a suspect, 58-year-old <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/15/us-news/alleged-would-be-trump-assassin-ryan-routh-has-had-several-run-ins-with-law-including-conviction-of-possessing-a-weapon-of-mass-destruction/">Ryan Wesley Routh</a>, on Interstate 95 shortly after. Officials said that Routh was unarmed and appeared calm as he was arrested. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Who is Ryan Wesley Routh?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unlike <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/07/15/us/thomas-crooks-trump-rally-shooting-invs/index.html">the man who attempted to assassinate Trump in July</a>, Routh has a colorful public history. Routh had previously lived in North Carolina, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/ryan-routh-custody-trump-golf-club-incident-rcna171225" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">but had moved to Hawaii</a> in recent years and said he was building <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/09/15/politics/trump-attempted-assassination-man-detained/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">affordable housing</a> there.  He was interviewed by<em> </em>the New York Times in 2023 for an article <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/03/25/world/europe/volunteers-us-ukraine-lies.html">about Americans acting as freelance fighters for the war in Ukraine</a>, despite little or no qualifications to do so. Routh, who had no prior military experience, spoke with a Times<em> </em>reporter about his plans to recruit soldiers who had fled the Taliban in Afghanistan and transport them to Ukraine to join the war efforts.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“By the time I got off the phone with Mr. Routh some minutes later it was clear he was in way over his head,” the reporter, Thomas Gibbons-Neff <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/15/us/politics/trump-routh-ukraine-interview.html">wrote</a>. “He talked of buying off corrupt officials, forging passports and doing whatever it takes to get his Afghan cadre to Ukraine, but he had no real way to accomplish his goals.” In 2023, Routh <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/09/15/2024/alleged-trump-plotter-ryan-routh-complained-of-obstacles-to-getting-foreign-soldiers-to-ukraine">also spoke to Semafor</a> about his efforts.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Routh also appears to have a criminal history. In 2002, <a href="https://greensboro.com/article_3006b4f9-9370-5b08-a54e-46c87faf6cbe.html">he was arrested in Greensboro, North Carolina, following a three-hour standoff with police</a> in which he barricaded himself inside a roofing business. He was charged with possessing an illegal, fully-automatic machine gun. According to the News &amp; Observer<em>, </em>a newspaper based in Raleigh, North Carolina, Routh also <a href="https://www.newsobserver.com/news/politics-government/article292532509.html">had other convictions</a>, including a hit and run and possession of stolen goods.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Routh’s son spoke positively of his father <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/sep/15/trump-florida-shooter-suspect-son-ukraine">in an interview</a> with the Guardian this weekend and expressed surprise at the idea he had resorted to violence. Little else is known at this time about his other potential familial relationships.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">What are Routh’s political leanings?&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like Trump’s other would-be assassin, Thomas Matthew Crooks, Routh’s political stances appear not to fit neatly into a single political ideology — though it does seem he views Trump as a threat to American democracy.&nbsp;Routh <a href="https://www.newsobserver.com/news/politics-government/article292532509.html">was registered</a> in North Carolina as an “unaffiliated” voter and participated in this year’s Democratic primary. He had given money to Democratic causes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But on an X account that has since been deactivated, a user with Routh’s name <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/09/15/politics/trump-attempted-assassination-man-detained/index.html">said that he had supported Donald Trump in 2016</a> but had been disappointed by his presidency. In another post from the same account, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/09/16/trump-florida-assassination-attempt-suspect-ryan-routh">the author tried to encourage Nikki Haley and Vivek Ramaswamy</a>, both Republicans, to run for president and vice president together.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The same account <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/15/us-news/would-be-trump-assassin-idd-as-ryan-routh-58-of-hawaii-sources/">posted that</a> “democracy is on the ballot” in this election, along with other, <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/15/us-news/would-be-trump-assassin-idd-as-ryan-routh-58-of-hawaii-sources/">sometimes incoherent posts</a> about various subjects including Ukraine and China, suggesting that the author’s politics are not easily characterized by a single worldview.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As with July’s assassination attempt, online partisans on both sides are already drawing conclusions about Routh’s political leanings and its implications, with some Democrats <a href="https://x.com/search?q=Routh&amp;src=typeahead_click">downplaying</a> Routh’s support for liberal causes and Republicans <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/15/trump-second-assassination-attempt-republican-response-00179261" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/15/trump-second-assassination-attempt-republican-response-00179261">connecting Routh’s comment about democracy being on the ballot</a> to what Vice President Kamala Harris and other Democrats have said about the stakes for this election.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What about the gun?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The AK-47 Routh had on him, like the AR-15 used by Crooks, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/07/23/us/trump-shooting-gunman-snipers.html">is one of the preferred weapons of mass shooters</a> in recent years. Both are assault-style weapons — a phrase that has many possible meanings but generally refers to guns that are meant for rapid-fire use with large magazines of ammunition. An AK-47 style weapon <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2019/08/28/el-paso-shooting-gun-romania/">was used at a 2019 shooting in El Paso, Texas</a>, where 23 people were killed and 22 were injured.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris, who said in a statement that she was “deeply disturbed” by the reports of a second attempted attack on Trump, has called for <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-61621470">banning assault weapons</a>. The United States <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=220dREyLPus">had a federal assault weapons ban</a> in place from 1994—2004, and research suggests that assault weapons bans <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13504851.2014.939367?scroll=top&amp;needAccess=true">meaningfully reduce</a> mass shooting deaths.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://www.monmouth.edu/polling-institute/reports/monmouthpoll_us_042423/">public is divided</a> over the question of whether to ban assault weapons, though, and Republicans in Congress <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/senate/4345455-senate-republicans-block-assault-weapons-ban/">blocked</a> a bill to do so when it came up for a vote in 2023. Even after being targeted by a similar weapon in July, former president Trump <a href="https://www.vox.com/donald-trump/360742/someone-tried-to-assassinate-the-former-president-and-the-gop-still-wont-talk-about-guns">did not</a> call for an assault weapons ban.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>How did another assassination attempt happen so quickly?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Lawmakers are <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/15/us/politics/secret-service-trump-shooting.html">demanding to know</a> more about how another would-be assassin was able to get so close to the former president for a second time in a few months. At the press conference, law enforcement explained that Trump’s Secret Service detail did not have the resources to cover the entire perimeter of the golf course, but lawmakers are sure to ask for more details in the coming days.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The facts about a second incident certainly warrant very close attention and scrutiny,” Democratic Sen. Richard Blumenthal of Connecticut <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/15/us/politics/secret-service-trump-shooting.html">told </a>the New York Times.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though a second assassination attempt in such a short period of time seems shocking, it is in some ways not surprising. Current and former law enforcement officials I’ve spoken to in recent weeks have emphasized just how difficult the task of protecting elected officials in public has become. Following the expiration of the federal assault weapons ban, and after more than a decade of marketing of assault-style rifles, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/interactive/2023/history-of-ar-15-marketing/">more of these</a> weapons are circulating in the US <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/gunmakers-made-over-1-billion-in-assault-weapon-sales-in-the-past-decade-congressional-report-finds/">than ever before</a>. The number of deadly long-range guns held by the public makes it considerably more difficult to maintain a zone of safety around politicians.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Secret Service also noted Sunday that as a former president, Trump doesn’t have access to the same level of security that the current president does, and some <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/15/us/politics/secret-service-trump-shooting.html">former officials are now suggesting</a> that may need to change.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Guns aren’t the only problem, though. As Garen Wintemute, an expert in political violence and gun violence told me this summer, his research has revealed <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/369441/political-violence-2024-election" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/politics/369441/political-violence-2024-election">a small but worrying segment of the American population</a> is open to the idea that violence committed for political reasons is justifiable.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the time, Wintemute said, the conditions that made more violence likely were a closely contested race, with momentum swinging towards Democrats, and a race where political violence had already recently occurred.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think it will happen again. Whether it will involve an elected official as a target, I can’t say,” Wintemute <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/369441/political-violence-2024-election">told Vox</a>, in July. “But we’ve opened the door to political violence this election season, and there are still some leaders using rhetoric that enables violence. And we will all pay a price for that, I suspect.”</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/371981/trump-shooting-ryan-wesley-routh-golf-club</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/371981/trump-shooting-ryan-wesley-routh-golf-club</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Marin Cogan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 13:53:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 things to know about the apparent assassination attempt on Trump at one of his golf courses - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPLVphbS10U1ExMzBkLUhKVEJPZ0hwcXFESTJQOW9vVl9PT3ltVGdMbVoyM2dBZWU3M20wRHlkTk9sVzJ2RV9RN3AyNklUNG16NzR5WE01SVVSMG5BV0U0a2tJM0Q3ZkpKRU5JelAwUUtKSDVTQ3ZXajUyekVlb0h3d091Vk9yQUZPdVppRjhaZU5fd1RKWERfU0VYVF9ZZnZoOEE?oc=5" target="_blank">5 things to know about the apparent assassination attempt on Trump at one of his golf courses</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxQMEtoXy1DX0RnRlNyWFFJbTZhX1RHUlZNNmdkT1I3VzVtbjZNeFJERkkxcHRGTFA0NUx0Zk9udUR3NEY1WmpSZ0Y4bWdCZWhOelFoN0ZDUzB0ZnJHZnd3MGhPTGdfcGwydGhqNGxGUVVaVnBRLUw1S1RFQWVybnU3NU4yM3lGVlNQ?oc=5" target="_blank">A New York Times Reporter Revisits Earlier Interview With Suspect at Trump Golf Course</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE04SUcyVllXdjlxcVVuVFhVNDB1WkhmUFNKaW42TS1Xc1owMExoUE5CbVBJMTBKanJ0MHc1WkF1QTFMeHFCMlpNUF8zaERJdEk4X1A4em5GZG5RTlI2VWo3MmFVSVFsT2RmN2JoX19OVUFodHRJZ1FJVVJ30gF_QVVfeXFMUDI5cjl4Qi11cDZlaUlOM1VfMXZTQ09HUjVIZ25SY0U1cGVEbk9tNnA5dngyMWo0NURfVi1nZ0pDOXcwRlR2R25aTHY1UU1OZ1dnbDJNWGNxZGVyY3lnV29TaGtSbzV0bnIxTmpLNE15Y2taTmRqTF82ZWF1LThlVQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Suspect in apparent Trump assassination attempt to make first court appearance</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOdWp0YklfZ25pbXR2TEVHa2JxTVJjanphSGlabW9SM3dsV1FpZm00aVdMTTRtV1J2YXQtaEpFSVV6Mmt1WkdCaUNoYVNIWnZrUlBERnR3REVUTHd5OGEwbWVMM3VHbHBDYVk2MFUyRTFtZnZBeDZhNVhJazRRTnZ1UUdVVW9uenh3YUVmT1FmcU53VnVURmhfdnEydXZZYkdyWXdHRUhJM1dtVWdCeE4yMjQybkM0czI2X3N2VEJvY0NVNjRyNFhUetIBzgFBVV95cUxObUJ0RzEyeWhMUl9XZDdzQml0bGhkeDF6NE1EbzJtcGV2N25paWpKTGJ2eHhCcXhpdkFXclVIeVdPVnRvN0JwWlpKOEtVLWZ2cHpkZ3l1eU00OGhkMm5fZm00U0NBbi1DUFY0RnVvelNNdmdHYlNneUpwNkw3X1VTWE11eHIzSDZrNzgzcWdab05xd0hWeTYwNHdIMk9zUDJ5TUpMTThFS25Id0ZiN3RqVDZGeUtaVUg1VFRpMHUzcnpJU19OcDExNGFEaWdRdw?oc=5" target="_blank">Ex-NBA star Rex Chapman calls on media to divert attention from 2nd apparent Trump assassination attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxNTTB0VzNLTGJiMGhxaHR2NExyQll1UDRsQUNibkUyNkE1VEszQkQySjI2ajdnakgtUWxwbzB3SllGVGpoTVFNV09BZ1VLR3pmYzdfRm9rbndZcWh3cmdpNmNEYkM2RDJtM1QtUzRfLUZDVUN4d0xwVlMxTXBseEY4cW5PZmQzVnVydHpNc1h2dF9WdDBfUHFGYW50a01DdXdNODc3Qg?oc=5" target="_blank">Exclusive | Suspected Trump Gunman Had Rifle With Scratched-Off Serial Number</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Wall Street Journal</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPLVphbS10U1ExMzBkLUhKVEJPZ0hwcXFESTJQOW9vVl9PT3ltVGdMbVoyM2dBZWU3M20wRHlkTk9sVzJ2RV9RN3AyNklUNG16NzR5WE01SVVSMG5BV0U0a2tJM0Q3ZkpKRU5JelAwUUtKSDVTQ3ZXajUyekVlb0h3d091Vk9yQUZPdVppRjhaZU5fd1RKWERfU0VYVF9ZZnZoOEE?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPLVphbS10U1ExMzBkLUhKVEJPZ0hwcXFESTJQOW9vVl9PT3ltVGdMbVoyM2dBZWU3M20wRHlkTk9sVzJ2RV9RN3AyNklUNG16NzR5WE01SVVSMG5BV0U0a2tJM0Q3ZkpKRU5JelAwUUtKSDVTQ3ZXajUyekVlb0h3d091Vk9yQUZPdVppRjhaZU5fd1RKWERfU0VYVF9ZZnZoOEE?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 14:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zelenskyy: Ukraine can’t provide even 4 out of 14 brigades with weapons they need]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fi5hiu/zelenskyy_ukraine_cant_provide_even_4_out_of_14/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/GKkkwVD0XNW8o0cbZlCxJVUFiqMjaouCDLz8zEe6y1I.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=dc1e2347cd505babf2bb8a362c62f18eb5f1aef8" alt="Zelenskyy: Ukraine can’t provide even 4 out of 14 brigades with weapons they need" title="Zelenskyy: Ukraine can’t provide even 4 out of 14 brigades with weapons they need" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/murphystruggles"> /u/murphystruggles </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://gwaramedia.com/en/zelenskyy-ukraine-can-t-provide-even-4-out-of-14-brigades-with-weapons-they-need/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fi5hiu/zelenskyy_ukraine_cant_provide_even_4_out_of_14/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fi5hiu/zelenskyy_ukraine_cant_provide_even_4_out_of_14/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fi5hiu/zelenskyy_ukraine_cant_provide_even_4_out_of_14/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/murphystruggles]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 14:04:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mexico's violent Sinaloa state logs 19 homicides in five days]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/mexicos-violent-sinaloa-state-logs-202958499.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/mexicos-violent-sinaloa-state-logs-202958499.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 20:29:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Delhi's chief minister announces resignation two days after he was released on bail]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/delhis-chief-minister-announces-resignation-092540233.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/delhis-chief-minister-announces-resignation-092540233.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 09:25:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Man accused of trying to kill Trump wrote a book urging Iran to assassinate the ex-president]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/man-accused-trying-kill-trump-134644431.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/man-accused-trying-kill-trump-134644431.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 13:46:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[NATO military committee chair, others back Ukraine's use of long range weapons to hit Russia]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/nato-military-committee-chair-others-182654570.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/nato-military-committee-chair-others-182654570.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 18:26:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel targets southern Lebanon with heavy airstrikes as tensions continue]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/israel-targets-southern-lebanon-heavy-023758912.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/israel-targets-southern-lebanon-heavy-023758912.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 02:37:58 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>