<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 22:13:19 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 22:13:19 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Does RFK Jr. dropping out of the presidential race help Trump?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Robert F. Kennedy Jr. speaks during a campaign event on October 12, 2023 in Miami, Florida. | Eva Marie Uzcategui/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Eva Marie Uzcategui/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1720421711.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Robert F. Kennedy Jr. speaks during a campaign event on October 12, 2023 in Miami, Florida. | Eva Marie Uzcategui/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Arguably the weirdest candidate of the 2024 election is expected to drop out soon.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Following a controversy-filled campaign that included revelations that a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/08/us/rfk-jr-brain-health-memory-loss.html">worm had eaten part of his brain</a> and that he was <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365284/robert-f-kennedy-jr-bear-central-park">responsible for the bear carcass</a> that <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/newyork/news/bear-cub-found-dead-in-central-park-nypd-investigating-as-animal-cruelty/">mysteriously appeared</a> in Central Park in 2014, Robert F. Kennedy Jr., and his running mate Nicole Shanahan, are reportedly planning to suspend their presidential bid. He is <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/rfk-jr-plans-drop-presidential-race-end-week/story?id=113028999">considering endorsing</a> former President Donald Trump and reportedly hopeful that he might <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/rfk-jr-trump-health-secretary-anti-vaccine-rcna167588">secure the position of Trump’s health secretary</a> if he wins.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kennedy was an environmental lawyer <a href="https://www.eenews.net/articles/rfk-jr-green-hero-turned-anti-vaccine-activist-takes-on-biden/">known for</a> his work cleaning up the Hudson River with a storied last name who in recent years has become known for spreading conspiracy theories about medicine, including <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-68447223">vaccines</a> and <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/robert-f-kennedy-jr-conspiracy-theory-twitter-elon-musk-1234747479/">anti-depressants</a>. He used the popularity he gained as an <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/07/13/1187272781/rfk-jr-kennedy-conspiracy-theories-social-media-presidential-campaign">anti-vaxxer during the pandemic</a> to briefly challenge President Joe Biden in the Democratic primary before announcing an independent bid for president in October 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He had been seen as a potential spoiler for both candidates, given his connection to the Democratic Kennedy dynasty as well as his embrace of the anti-establishment and anti-vaccine views held by certain segments of the GOP. He was <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/22/rfk-jr-end-campaign-polls">polling around 10 percent</a> nationally for the better part of 2024, and even higher in some swing state polls.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/rfk-jr-map-on-the-ballot-states/">struggled to get on the ballot in many states</a>, though his campaign maintains that he has secured enough signatures to do so in all but Kentucky, Mississippi, Rhode Island, and Wyoming. And after Vice President Kamala Harris became the Democratic nominee, he seemed to hold less sway among voters who were turned off by Biden. His poll numbers <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/22/rfk-jr-end-campaign-polls">consequently cratered</a> to under 5 percent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite Kennedy’s flagging national numbers,&nbsp;polling suggests his exit from the race could still help Trump, with whom he’s become <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2024/7/17/is-rfk-jr-truly-independent">decidedly more cozy</a> in recent months. Trump wouldn’t have to win a lot of Kennedy’s potential voters to make a difference in key swing states; if the race is as close as it was in 2020, Trump gaining even a fraction of a percent from Kennedy could make the difference.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Kennedy’s exit may help Trump — possibly where it matters the most</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump probably has the most to gain from Kennedy dropping out. Kennedy has increasingly endeared himself to Republican voters while struggling to get the same support among Democrats and independents. And polls conducted in recent months, including since Biden dropped out of the race, suggest that Trump would pick up more of Kennedy’s supporters. Any margin would likely be small — but potentially significant.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans tend to see Kennedy more favorably than Democrats, and those with favorable views toward him tend to have more favorable opinions of Trump than of Harris, according to a <a href="https://apnorc.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/July-2024-W1-topline.pdf">July AP-NORC poll</a> conducted before Biden dropped out.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Several national polls conducted since Harris became the presumptive nominee have also tested a race between Harris, Trump, and Kennedy, as well as a two-way race between Harris and Trump. Trump tends to get a bigger bump than Harris when Kennedy is excluded.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In an <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/en-us/ipsos-2024-us-national-election-survey-august-2024">August Reuters/Ipsos poll of registered voters</a>, for instance, Harris received 42 percent support, Trump 37 percent, and Kennedy 4 percent, while 15 percent supported another candidate, weren’t sure who they would support, or weren’t sure if they would vote at all. But when voters were pushed to select either Trump or Harris, 49 percent backed Harris and 47 percent Trump — a 10 percentage point boost for Trump.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump had a similar edge with Kennedy voters in a <a href="https://harvardharrispoll.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/HHP_July2024_KeyResults.pdf">July Harvard CAPS/Harris Poll</a>. In a three-way contest, Harris earned 44 percent support, Trump 47 percent, and Kennedy 10 percent. In a head-to-head poll, Harris earned 48 percent and Trump 52 percent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It may seem like the advantage Trump gains when Kennedy is out of the picture is relatively small. But Biden won in 2020 by exceedingly <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/12/02/940689086/narrow-wins-in-these-key-states-powered-biden-to-the-presidency">narrow margins</a> in six key battleground states; in Arizona, it was by less than 11,000 votes. On the margin, Kennedy’s supporters could make a difference, depending on where they’re distributed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Arizona, for example, Kennedy is still polling at about 6 percent, according to <a href="https://elections2024.thehill.com/arizona/biden-trump-rfk-arizona/">The Hill’s polling average</a>. Of course, he might not actually win that large a vote share if he decides to stay in the race; third-party candidates tend to poll much better than they actually perform on Election Day, when their supporters are confronted with the reality that their preferred candidate won’t win. But that vote share would have been more than enough to have swung the 2020 results in the other direction.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The same is true in other swing states, where polling suggests a very tight race. An early <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/08/10/us/elections/times-siena-poll-registered-voter-crosstabs.html">August New York Times/Siena</a> survey of registered voters in Michigan, Pennsylvania, and Wisconsin found Harris leading Trump 46 percent to 43 percent when respondents were given all third-party candidates to choose from. When asked to pick between just Harris and Trump, the gap tightened to 48 and 46 percent, respectively. Those <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/16/kamala-harris-polls-key-states">states are likely to be key</a>, given their high electoral college vote count — and in most scenarios, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/election/2024/electoral-college-map?game-id=2024-PG-CNN-ratings&amp;game-view=map">Harris would need all three to win</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Harris’s entry into the race likely limits the impact of Kennedy’s exit</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Kennedy’s supporters may still be able to make an important impact on the margins, their power to drag the Democratic nominee’s polling down seems to have diminished substantially.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before Harris became the nominee, there was a much larger than usual number of disaffected voters who didn’t like either Biden or Trump and just wanted someone — anyone — as an alternative. A theoretical no-name candidate as an alternative to Biden and Trump got about 10 percent in <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24112624/rfk-jr-kennedy-shanahan-running-mate-2024-election">Ipsos polling</a> conducted earlier this year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kennedy provided an alternative for a while. But when Harris stepped up, that undermined his appeal — at least among Democrats.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There were some wavering Democratic voters who just thought Biden was too old, or they didn&#8217;t like him, and Harris is just a more appealing candidate for those kinds of people,” said Kyle Kondik, managing editor of Sabato’s Crystal Ball at the University of Virginia Center for Politics.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kondik said it’s possible that Biden may have ended up winning back those voters anyway if he had stayed in the race and had a <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/8/17/21371232/convention-polls-biden-trump-election">typical post-Democratic National Convention bump</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But at this point, Kondik said, he would not be surprised if the third-party vote share in the election ends up being about 2 percent of the electorate, as it was in 2012 and 2020. Before Harris became the nominee, political analysts were projecting that it would be closer to the nearly 6 percent share third parties got in 2016, which some analysts <a href="https://rollcall.com/2019/07/29/how-third-party-votes-sunk-clinton-what-they-mean-for-trump/">argued doomed</a> Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton’s candidacy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“For all the talk about third parties in this election, a combination of the most prominent third-party candidate dropping out, in addition to the increased favorability of the two major party nominees, means that there’s just going to be less of a market for third-party candidates,” he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kennedy could make more of an impact as a surrogate for Trump. He could help the former president with certain demographics, such as young men who listen to prominent personalities such as Joe Rogan, who has <a href="https://variety.com/2024/digital/news/joe-rogan-endorses-rfk-jr-president-1236101220/">praised Kennedy</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the Trump campaign might also be wary of attaching itself to Kennedy’s brand: If the brain worm and the bear incident weren’t enough, he has been disavowed by <a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2019/05/08/robert-kennedy-jr-measles-vaccines-226798/">members of his own famous family</a> and now peddles <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/06/us/politics/rfk-conspiracy-theories-fact-check.html">conspiracy theories</a> not just about the <a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19">Covid-19</a> vaccine, but <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/retropolis/wp/2018/05/26/who-killed-bobby-kennedy-his-son-rfk-jr-doesnt-believe-it-was-sirhan-sirhan/">his father’s killer</a>, <a href="https://time.com/6287001/rfk-jr-interview-2024-campaign/">5G cell phone transmission</a>, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2006/06/25/fashion/25bobby.html">fraud in the 2004 election</a>, and more.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The Democratic refrain against Trump and [his running mate JD] Vance is that they’re ‘weird,’” Kondik said. “Kennedy doesn’t make them less weird.”</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/368394/rfk-drop-out-2024-presidential-campaign-trump</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/368394/rfk-drop-out-2024-presidential-campaign-trump</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Narea]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 22:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Police hunt Arizona man who threatened to kill Trump]]></title><description><![CDATA[The search for a 66-year-old man who targeted Donald Trump in social media posts came as the ex-president visited the border state.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c86l4p583y6o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c86l4p583y6o</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 21:47:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Here's everything to expect from Fed Chair Powell's speech Friday in Jackson Hole]]></title><description><![CDATA[For all the attention being paid to the speech, the chances of it containing any new news seem remote.]]></description><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/22/heres-everything-to-expect-from-fed-chair-powells-speech-friday-in-jackson-hole.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/22/heres-everything-to-expect-from-fed-chair-powells-speech-friday-in-jackson-hole.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 19:08:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris to accept Democratic nomination on Day 4 of DNC. Here's who else is speaking]]></title><description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris became the Democratic nominee in the race against Republican Donald Trump after President Joe Biden dropped his reelection bid.]]></description><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/22/dnc-kamala-harris-nomination-president-trump.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/22/dnc-kamala-harris-nomination-president-trump.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 18:51:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Former FTX exec Ryan Salame's romantic partner indicted on campaign finance crimes]]></title><description><![CDATA[Michelle Bond was charged two months before her romantic partner, former FTX exec Ryan Salame, is due to surrender to being a prison sentence.]]></description><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/22/michelle-bond-romantic-partner-of-former-ftx-exec-salame-indicted.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/22/michelle-bond-romantic-partner-of-former-ftx-exec-salame-indicted.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 21:45:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris To Take The Stage On Last Day Of Democratic Convention]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Democratic National Convention, a four-day mega event which saw a tearful Joe Biden getting a farewell, and Kamala Harris making a surprise entry in a tan suit, will end today.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-take-the-stage-on-last-day-of-democratic-convention-6396362</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-take-the-stage-on-last-day-of-democratic-convention-6396362</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 21:50:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris to cap Democratic convention with historic speech - Reuters]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPN2MwUXBfRGRMN0pybjB4SWdTTFpWMWZURjR3N0d4LUY1bVFvMWVxeWlzcVJNLW11NExGUXl6NUJTZnVnMlhCeXNiMFNiUkl4a2FNWHkteEZ4ZzdLRlktZ0o1ZG93RTRnSmlLelVjaFp5S2xSWjJjc0dHcDF0cWNZUGxCdS05OGJ4d3VaNHE2WmdJVjdTTkFET01ISS1oV2tLM2t6WW1iQ0s?oc=5" target="_blank">Kamala Harris to cap Democratic convention with historic speech</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxOeVdFMXI3OGtlZ1VfYlZoYzdyM3FkZVg0VFJ5M3hhV3ZYcmNiUE84QnNtbWFDOGYtRW95MnZ6dTk0bmp5TXBqbThiTXRHUWl3bWNJUEl6VzA1cDVOOGk5ODJ2MnNkSXRNUlo2SkNmY3JoenczNm1td0ViSGZZNUFlVUFIcmttU0gyR05ZM2NhaVVfN25ZM2JRcnRjV2I0N2NwcU9pSVlpc3hsd0FGZjJ0YnJrVWE?oc=5" target="_blank">Yusef Salaam, a member of the ‘Central Park Five,’ will speak at the convention</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxPdkZaOGdTWWYwQU1kMV9ldFluOC1DMWFBbmpBczJKcjVpZkMyMzFJb0s0amdPRHVocWFHZXluMTg3Tm5TSEhQU0tiTHNkVTgzNmVseWdsQ2dMdm1yQUtNUHMybi1fYlUzSW1GajY2cVBDRkFVSnRaN2otU05qdjJWOW1FZFJaMVNjM2drRlNORTVvSFds0gGaAUFVX3lxTE5OTVc1RHZUYzFnYzlyMXJZOVQ1bFdFRGdwRldfNFk5aDZpOWE2ZW1BeUI0RTVQUks4Q09kbzJkV0hSeEhmZ2M5Wlo1UXdYdkdUd2x4N0c3U05YeUxhSVVxUTZPVkEwTUFITXBhSWE4d2RpQ2ppbEpjcTJaQVZWRVVTdzVRVmhzbHdudEMtMmdxeUlTYm1NVmJiMGc?oc=5" target="_blank">Live updates: Harris takes center stage on final night of DNC</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxQSW1KQjV5MmpoZ1JSakFJYnNybTNGSXNpUUtraXc4a0s4NUE0OUVwNV8xVlotQlN6TlZYb2xJSWJRWGUyRVVWWjF3MEl4M1ZJZU9rcDlnRGlWWTBwaWJPRjBXUnNReUN1dmlUWHcyMF9GOTQyclY1Z0xpWmY4QkF5N25fZFFuQVJR0gGOAUFVX3lxTE1aYjRDWjg4QWdPWTZCajF1bjNmNDJUR1IxWWxoemtsRzNKcEJXXy05SGJ2cTBYTkZ3dmhYdU03VkJuX1RaMkxGSFVxZzRRZlNvdS1HTHBSQ0FZVVlmRjZBS3F2NTByUGtxOERJSFhQc3AtaXNlRUdOZEVJTzUtdWJYZy1BRFg2M3ZvSjhpdEE?oc=5" target="_blank">Kamala Harris to accept Democratic nomination on Day 4 of DNC. Here's who else is speaking</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxOR2UzWE0zZkMxc0hTUkV6U1JrYU03NzV6ejNnNi0xOVAzdTdPdVFHYXYyb2UzMFY0YkZ0MnN6ajV1dEZleUxRamluNE5MYTkycjJaS2w0Uzd5QkhfdEFTLXlySUNYaGtsY2FEcnBYNGJLNVpmUC1QMzE5ZW5nSmtYc19nMFF0ZVhpUTFSRVVZM1ptWmhsYnItaXJsNXl1OEdUdkxLNDlzNzVYa3o1d3FiSnBDTk5XS2tTNXRQQ0d2MEY0R1h3QlNWVHlqdHXSAWZBVV95cUxOQlNWaFpqR3pDUkF0SlFHUllzT1A2NW8wMFdSVmhiSzZyem4zOFJQZTczNGNmMlNTdy03N0U4aUhtMVJ0bzAwNS03dUpEWTVWY3NyS2lTUXZ3SHc3QjNqaFVEaTFBZnc?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris campaign co-chair previews acceptance speech: ‘Freedom, future and joy’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPN2MwUXBfRGRMN0pybjB4SWdTTFpWMWZURjR3N0d4LUY1bVFvMWVxeWlzcVJNLW11NExGUXl6NUJTZnVnMlhCeXNiMFNiUkl4a2FNWHkteEZ4ZzdLRlktZ0o1ZG93RTRnSmlLelVjaFp5S2xSWjJjc0dHcDF0cWNZUGxCdS05OGJ4d3VaNHE2WmdJVjdTTkFET01ISS1oV2tLM2t6WW1iQ0s?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPN2MwUXBfRGRMN0pybjB4SWdTTFpWMWZURjR3N0d4LUY1bVFvMWVxeWlzcVJNLW11NExGUXl6NUJTZnVnMlhCeXNiMFNiUkl4a2FNWHkteEZ4ZzdLRlktZ0o1ZG93RTRnSmlLelVjaFp5S2xSWjJjc0dHcDF0cWNZUGxCdS05OGJ4d3VaNHE2WmdJVjdTTkFET01ISS1oV2tLM2t6WW1iQ0s?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 21:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Harris has South Asian American voters in swing state Georgia fired up - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxPQmhvOXVVNUhyZHNtblY3YU5Tbkp1V1c3OHpzTXNkT0FfRVVDamJLcTdLR3IyOHRpTGlIMGJpZ1ZRZVJjSHU3N2VzSWVYa3BzdEpDWU1YUE9wS2hMNWdRMmNxa2Y1QWhjWmFLeUx1cHJUeGxja3NXUDREQ2pSeVhKNlFNV2VsOTIyMTM2b0ZqcV96TWM1cmRHZVNJbU7SAVZBVV95cUxOMTg3MU5qVGNNM3k1NlBwTVZIYlAyNjJ3N0g3UTVZd0FsT1FwN1NKeWNhUVcxQzMzb2p0T1p0ZV9IMzZ2eEFKSGVaRUpLOVVWMkM2M1cxQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris has South Asian American voters in swing state Georgia fired up</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxPam1jTkdkU3RMYWY3cmlEa24zN1JXTFprSlB6dnBxNWNmTGgxQnM5ZnlsOFRIbTBFZGkwTWZWNU1yZF8ybVdPeFZrazBqS1pSUkl4SUFkTHRVNmZ4OF9LVHZ6cndzRjZwU0taS1U0dENKOU5QeVpnWUdIa3hLb1l6UEZmWFc2QQ?oc=5" target="_blank">In Kamala Harris' ancestral village in India, people cheer her U.S. presidential bid</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxOeEdHVmwtaldaRlFOWnRPRWM2R3Z3TjF5TjlSNEM5ZVJ3YzI5U0JSSUh6WnlGdjZmQlMtWkMwT2FJQWJDMlYxakd0cTRRSmdvZDZ1dVh6WUNGLWNDVjE5ZG4tbU9VSHNNTlpVeHU3TEMzak1BYWRBaDgzcTZBYVhkMW9QLVdqZDJpRU1ISGxobUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">‘Excited to show up for her’: mixed-race voters finally feel seen with Harris’s nomination</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNZjJaWmNlbTl4UFdiaDdFR1lxYWhXYVRjNVlEWnQ1c3R2clY5dUxic1VyeF9LYzF3UDFITVk4Mk5fZU9YZ2RmMmpFWl95SXYwX215SDR6VGtoVC0tYW9EVThqZUNsVDhUUzJUdzBPVC1DZk04VHdibEdJbEhqNFZmbEdB?oc=5" target="_blank">Opinion | The Black Identity in Kamala Harris’s Jamaican Roots</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxQVmRNR1ZIem53ejR6Wm5PbmxER25BY2NjcmFfeG9lVDBnWWFPY1ZSYzZ4OE5iMnNEVHFTRk9kZGFiczdhMFA4WlJNbTg1T3pUMEdqQkJVSmdYLUpfM2p4MlQ2M3ZvRWN1RHdNVTNJc0c4M0NoMm81WkRLa2lWRUZxYzRrOEphbFpvVHViMTBySmJMcXE2czg1cGQ2SEdCNW1R?oc=5" target="_blank">Kamala Harris' roots reflect changing US demographics</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxPQmhvOXVVNUhyZHNtblY3YU5Tbkp1V1c3OHpzTXNkT0FfRVVDamJLcTdLR3IyOHRpTGlIMGJpZ1ZRZVJjSHU3N2VzSWVYa3BzdEpDWU1YUE9wS2hMNWdRMmNxa2Y1QWhjWmFLeUx1cHJUeGxja3NXUDREQ2pSeVhKNlFNV2VsOTIyMTM2b0ZqcV96TWM1cmRHZVNJbU7SAVZBVV95cUxOMTg3MU5qVGNNM3k1NlBwTVZIYlAyNjJ3N0g3UTVZd0FsT1FwN1NKeWNhUVcxQzMzb2p0T1p0ZV9IMzZ2eEFKSGVaRUpLOVVWMkM2M1cxQQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxPQmhvOXVVNUhyZHNtblY3YU5Tbkp1V1c3OHpzTXNkT0FfRVVDamJLcTdLR3IyOHRpTGlIMGJpZ1ZRZVJjSHU3N2VzSWVYa3BzdEpDWU1YUE9wS2hMNWdRMmNxa2Y1QWhjWmFLeUx1cHJUeGxja3NXUDREQ2pSeVhKNlFNV2VsOTIyMTM2b0ZqcV96TWM1cmRHZVNJbU7SAVZBVV95cUxOMTg3MU5qVGNNM3k1NlBwTVZIYlAyNjJ3N0g3UTVZd0FsT1FwN1NKeWNhUVcxQzMzb2p0T1p0ZV9IMzZ2eEFKSGVaRUpLOVVWMkM2M1cxQQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 18:19:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Supreme Court partly grants GOP request to enforce Arizona’s proof-of-citizenship voting law - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQaEFmdTNLRmwtVVNWaHpOMk0wTTdoY0Z3VHY1X0JrSWMyS3NKeGVESWlJc3VCY2RlNGtydUF2eVlwZlpUdE4xRTlMNm1VZ0lDZmEtdDVnenc0QTZ1Mm1Ra3I0bnJxUDFkX1Zkc0hla0ZxM0U1NllJa3JGalZIMU8tNW5nb2lOTFpBRFp0dEVGUEQ1bmFteVdXUzJNbW9kTGh6WTNpaUE0VnN3MzFWai10Y2tUcFdZZ2FvdFI0WnBjUGhtVExqYWxB0gFWQVVfeXFMTUxWQWJnb1RqNy1qOVpYM25QM1didjJKaVh6dVl2alZlYTlQZ3RSNEM1TS1PMU04WFhzenhGalZmWmtSODRLdXp3aW1vY01SVmpGYms0UlE?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court partly grants GOP request to enforce Arizona’s proof-of-citizenship voting law</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxQSzVjZl8xYldhVEo5Qlgwa294M2dwWGp4eTZDRllmY2FqZzB4WjZCeU4zc0JIRVJjT3lLVndhSUxLRklCNFVnU0ZId2hWQ2FmRFNydVFFSHVzbmhpOE8tSXFXT0syYnNhVk9EZTBaaW9xR01GSmd6QV9YbVVrVFo0OHljV1NTcHhjT0J4di1qbkVvVEVRYTNHbGVxUzMxY21EOWZBLWEwSUd2T1AyUmc1Tw?oc=5" target="_blank">SCOTUS gives partial victory to GOP trying to enforce proof of citizenship to vote in Arizona</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxNM05nR19kbDRIYkE5SXJZUW81NHNYWGs2LXN0OWtNN1dWbkphYllwNkkyS09mWUdqRWdveUJEZEk5YjY3UWVnclF2NjVNWDJ4VlVIczFFbGppQ3ZFWTctUUZlX2ZmQkpjV1hwYXBjaE1HMnBJbkVQOHJzUEFLQnRhODVwclQwZDZDckpQVnBMcU9OdTlqUFpwUlFxSXJiQUc3c1E2bUI3Vm9RanllaC1yVHFqclNjQ0VJM2ZZbWdGMS1vZDBNdmZETkoyTQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court Takes Mixed Approach on Arizona Proof-of-Citizenship Requirements for Voting</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Wall Street Journal</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxNV1RaclVFd2w0X1dXcHV1b2czZEtjSzBCbHotRFhTRE5iXzA3aDl0c0VtUWM4NDBfVlB3LXFoeGJheUh3a056bHM0MHdKNGZBMjA1dFpXc1R6ZDVidnMyNzFLRk0tVkFpRHAxLW9TVVRiOG55TE1KRHphTnBtVzBOSy1wcjllZ25MT1FrRW1ES1VPWjNrdDhyQmJn?oc=5" target="_blank">Divided Supreme Court rejects GOP bid to prevent some Arizonans from voting in presidential election</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxOaWlieVdNdTVRczdWcGdHaXRCVkhfOUc0V05XdXlVU3pwUlNvWHdCWkNGYm51eVJraktnbUY0Q29EMFBVSEpfa2ZiNVI0YVZuZzgwcVRSTzBTOVlYOV9NYThwdWl3TGxMNklLU21PMWhxQzZMNWV3eUZMNlNLaE84YWpOTjV2enExbkMyMlVFNTBwbnNFV1prSVJPQkJGT3kzTko2NnpNaw?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court Hands Republicans a Huge Win in Crucial Swing State</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New Republic</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQaEFmdTNLRmwtVVNWaHpOMk0wTTdoY0Z3VHY1X0JrSWMyS3NKeGVESWlJc3VCY2RlNGtydUF2eVlwZlpUdE4xRTlMNm1VZ0lDZmEtdDVnenc0QTZ1Mm1Ra3I0bnJxUDFkX1Zkc0hla0ZxM0U1NllJa3JGalZIMU8tNW5nb2lOTFpBRFp0dEVGUEQ1bmFteVdXUzJNbW9kTGh6WTNpaUE0VnN3MzFWai10Y2tUcFdZZ2FvdFI0WnBjUGhtVExqYWxB0gFWQVVfeXFMTUxWQWJnb1RqNy1qOVpYM25QM1didjJKaVh6dVl2alZlYTlQZ3RSNEM1TS1PMU04WFhzenhGalZmWmtSODRLdXp3aW1vY01SVmpGYms0UlE?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxQaEFmdTNLRmwtVVNWaHpOMk0wTTdoY0Z3VHY1X0JrSWMyS3NKeGVESWlJc3VCY2RlNGtydUF2eVlwZlpUdE4xRTlMNm1VZ0lDZmEtdDVnenc0QTZ1Mm1Ra3I0bnJxUDFkX1Zkc0hla0ZxM0U1NllJa3JGalZIMU8tNW5nb2lOTFpBRFp0dEVGUEQ1bmFteVdXUzJNbW9kTGh6WTNpaUE0VnN3MzFWai10Y2tUcFdZZ2FvdFI0WnBjUGhtVExqYWxB0gFWQVVfeXFMTUxWQWJnb1RqNy1qOVpYM25QM1didjJKaVh6dVl2alZlYTlQZ3RSNEM1TS1PMU04WFhzenhGalZmWmtSODRLdXp3aW1vY01SVmpGYms0UlE?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 21:00:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump jabs ‘highly overrated Jewish Governor’ Josh Shapiro - The Hill]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNWThJSlFBSzZOYkVOaEg2ZlBjOWh2TWVJZGFqSlVfVTBoMll2WVpJMmRuSFp1M01MUXNpRjM5T1JpMDFOcUNteVZmUzRUd01DdDgwMlJxXzM2MFN2VjVEclNGUk1fTy1XNEwwOUs0WFlPT2hlMzJQcHdIWERpRWQ0WWJmaER4eU82bS1tNW1LdW9rblVhMTlaSElCVkhqTFpvVzdJX0dmZ1hFYjRw0gGyAUFVX3lxTE5WQ2kyV1NCZm9Vel8tMXZKcm1WcW13aTlkUHlMdXFvRmxQV3lqSEtzM1dLQXZFUjJSeGhwcUU0emRCaG95ZHZLOWh3ZWNrdTNvTU9EVkZUM25hbE1EekVwNnZxU2NJY3VEaG5mNUtld1hic3gzWVNvVlg2T2p2eGNUSnJrOFZTcTRNUm5NTEZQUkwzclNLNDBDQWI1b0dkNkwxbkZra21Jdm9lcnNMVzMwVWc?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump jabs ‘highly overrated Jewish Governor’ Josh Shapiro</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxNSkVPRWtvazYxZHFiYjIyZUc0c18xXzVGNzYtY2tEQmJEaW1nQTkwSG1qMVFDRmR5Z3ItQkNmaEI2bVhsM055cEI4LXJBRERRT0ZyMWR4WUNyTHVKXzRjWUtXOU53SjZBeW5QTlBVbXpQa1NEOF9JUHpJc1FEQVRtbGFSNzZycWE3VEFPeC13?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump Launches Antisemitic Attack on Josh Shapiro Over DNC Speech</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New Republic</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxOVk41cU8zSllhUUJHbmdSQ0RlTFA2bURLMWFxSWFOTU9KRkdqV01ITmFBTkFXWGV6WHhtM1pXWVhWWkswb1B2SEZYUDVJQm5RRU9rcE1FOGRYd21DU1owTlVaUVVrOW1mUUVueTVPSC03bUlVeVBFbjVvWlBtRlU2VVlRellNd9IBiwFBVV95cUxNSnByRTg0aTBHaE1GSTU0MTlrMzJKV1l0eGRMMnpidFljUzEzWWYxOTdscVNrMmZoX3Nqck5xQjBEeXpDcDJQSDNQaVpkZGNiLUdPOTAzT1k1bzk4MFpidC1NSGZFdXE3eTlVYWVBczh4dEF0R1pIMWxnYnVhekFBWjFCbnhLMm5xVXlJ?oc=5" target="_blank">Josh Shapiro blasts Trump for calling him 'overrated Jewish Governor'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxNT1J4dDluSHU4VGRENHV2c2lWeklVeFpxRU12QmlRYVk5T0pfS2ZQbDJuR2xKS2txT3ZENlF3Z0tNc0w4R3lpNkYycGl2RmZ3bHZUbzhhQ1VvdU94clRkanR1UzNTbkQ2YTdjazRIdHdmQlNNd2lsaVRZaGRzbVRIUkxERjhFQUdHcklNek96YmdSdVcwRjJWNlcyTzJtbXRnR0NIQlg5dGo0R1ZPTy0yemY0aFZQMV9DeTlVZVBMdmNXR3c?oc=5" target="_blank">White House condemns antisemitism after Trump attacks 'Jewish Governor' Shapiro</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTE9PTE1uNEswMnppeVhrVWV6X05TZzJXV255RXJrMjNOS2p1UXYwdVgxSUFqYkhsTE1UYnBRaGdXUmFfM0ludXprclUweldGRkhtcm5fZzRoTlFIZjNEeFdhRnhLWm92VUZwVG14THVDRHgwTUs3dGFoVmt6aw?oc=5" target="_blank">Shapiro fires back at Trump after post slamming convention speech</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo! Voices</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNWThJSlFBSzZOYkVOaEg2ZlBjOWh2TWVJZGFqSlVfVTBoMll2WVpJMmRuSFp1M01MUXNpRjM5T1JpMDFOcUNteVZmUzRUd01DdDgwMlJxXzM2MFN2VjVEclNGUk1fTy1XNEwwOUs0WFlPT2hlMzJQcHdIWERpRWQ0WWJmaER4eU82bS1tNW1LdW9rblVhMTlaSElCVkhqTFpvVzdJX0dmZ1hFYjRw0gGyAUFVX3lxTE5WQ2kyV1NCZm9Vel8tMXZKcm1WcW13aTlkUHlMdXFvRmxQV3lqSEtzM1dLQXZFUjJSeGhwcUU0emRCaG95ZHZLOWh3ZWNrdTNvTU9EVkZUM25hbE1EekVwNnZxU2NJY3VEaG5mNUtld1hic3gzWVNvVlg2T2p2eGNUSnJrOFZTcTRNUm5NTEZQUkwzclNLNDBDQWI1b0dkNkwxbkZra21Jdm9lcnNMVzMwVWc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNWThJSlFBSzZOYkVOaEg2ZlBjOWh2TWVJZGFqSlVfVTBoMll2WVpJMmRuSFp1M01MUXNpRjM5T1JpMDFOcUNteVZmUzRUd01DdDgwMlJxXzM2MFN2VjVEclNGUk1fTy1XNEwwOUs0WFlPT2hlMzJQcHdIWERpRWQ0WWJmaER4eU82bS1tNW1LdW9rblVhMTlaSElCVkhqTFpvVzdJX0dmZ1hFYjRw0gGyAUFVX3lxTE5WQ2kyV1NCZm9Vel8tMXZKcm1WcW13aTlkUHlMdXFvRmxQV3lqSEtzM1dLQXZFUjJSeGhwcUU0emRCaG95ZHZLOWh3ZWNrdTNvTU9EVkZUM25hbE1EekVwNnZxU2NJY3VEaG5mNUtld1hic3gzWVNvVlg2T2p2eGNUSnJrOFZTcTRNUm5NTEZQUkwzclNLNDBDQWI1b0dkNkwxbkZra21Jdm9lcnNMVzMwVWc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 11:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US tells UN Security Council Gaza ceasefire ‘in sight’ ahead of Cairo talks - Al Jazeera English]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxOcTdJWTJ3YllOMWV6LXZ2R3lwN1RTbHhUWGo2NW80Y2l6U0xiQXZjU19VTXRqaEYwbnpyT1d6THNUQXRJNUkyeUhhU2NjYVBiR195b1QwT0VoOVBsNXVCWG04QnhqU0x4U2VTdGdEZVhPOHpHUU9ycG9jU0VsUDUzR29GRmllR1AyQmN2OXVXemlYcFpzUHVXajhtVHhMQ21MRkhqaVhvQTlTTktJM1hsalVuUXDSAboBQVVfeXFMT294MERyX2pMVkQyb0tHT05ld1hDdVFBQ3ByWFpmdVpIWExIenVmeUlSbFg3SGNHRmZPcjI3YllTT05DckdNR09BTUtkNXVPUExubDNrNlA2czdEMGdINi1fUzdrQ0d1aHp5N3JsWTZvZ2NSZHU0eVVFeVhWNmpZdXg3SHlpMWlyNWpPREVnamMxMmdVRkh5d2RWQnU4OGpfYjlsR1VlTXh1WVhQTjR2dWl1UVJObWxHR0F3?oc=5" target="_blank">US tells UN Security Council Gaza ceasefire ‘in sight’ ahead of Cairo talks</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Al Jazeera English</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxOMzc2SzdRWnV1TU5Da2szYkZxSFFYOWl5T3o1ZFlvTmNEaVo0bV9aazlPdkt2WXRvcFhWcTNGTkVXdzVnbnE3RFlIRmxEMDMyOUFIZHltUm5uUTZJUWhoYjd6M0wxMm1kS0Z2c2tzZ2tDVXJmaHVHZXZNT1l0MmMteTRlb216TVFJcTRKNkJ3UTFUSFpZRUJOV04ta25EMUJTa29wdlNR?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden speaks with Netanyahu as US prods Israel and Hamas to come to agreement on cease-fire deal</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxOcTc1c24tUXY0bXo1MjV1NVdBQ2lfc1BNZ2JjRDFkc0k3THg3bXNzOWl1YmRkSHItZHpnc3N0b2F2akNHakNqcWxMeWhDM2NubmFMTWxRd2dfajkxak9BY2M5U2NsS25vZnVNdnJfN3ZWaGExeTRSZjlwOUVRRWNJQ0U1bGp4ZGpuZ0FQY1FuRQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Opinion | An eerie quiet as Biden races to silence the guns in Gaza</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiY0FVX3lxTE9yRmVlUFU3dFo1WDZKX2NUbXRTVFF5THk5WTFMcDMwSVc4WjhXbnJoOHEzM0lrU2s5WGotcC14TjJQV1hRa3NOdjczaXNlZTdWV3l5dnA2T1RYRmxrLWt3Y0t1Zw?oc=5" target="_blank">Israeli team in Cairo for hostage negotiations, Qatari PM to head to Iran next week</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Jerusalem Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQeDc1SkVXNEZ3WWdtRm9DNGVqbVhhNnJVZFduM3lhMVIySDQ2SmphV2d6VUE1NzJNY1ZJRVdocVkzQ3p0VDJiWjVjSWZ5SlNTb19sV3lPRWdLeEVJaVcycEpnVk9CWk5qNW1rcllXaDh2ZGZfckxlcTlKSnV3X1AydzZ6SnN5ZzhONHpIV0pmNG5hNmdJR0hmQVExUdIBoAFBVV95cUxNQS1hclVKX3RkM3RNLWRrSDE3emZSSVpnR2NiY0xUTjdmT1VmYzlZSFo4VEhfd085TFN2eFJGWXowMnp4U1VnUjZiY3JiMnRIT2tLMlh6MEFUMlc4ck9YZndRYzJZbkhVY1pIdDFRQjNpQmtRX3lybjhOSzNDZDA0TE8zWkJpNWZLSzZMeVlTd2E5ZkNIcDhJZ0F1SkEydXV6?oc=5" target="_blank">U.S. participates in renewed Israel-Gaza cease-fire talks in Cairo</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxOcTdJWTJ3YllOMWV6LXZ2R3lwN1RTbHhUWGo2NW80Y2l6U0xiQXZjU19VTXRqaEYwbnpyT1d6THNUQXRJNUkyeUhhU2NjYVBiR195b1QwT0VoOVBsNXVCWG04QnhqU0x4U2VTdGdEZVhPOHpHUU9ycG9jU0VsUDUzR29GRmllR1AyQmN2OXVXemlYcFpzUHVXajhtVHhMQ21MRkhqaVhvQTlTTktJM1hsalVuUXDSAboBQVVfeXFMT294MERyX2pMVkQyb0tHT05ld1hDdVFBQ3ByWFpmdVpIWExIenVmeUlSbFg3SGNHRmZPcjI3YllTT05DckdNR09BTUtkNXVPUExubDNrNlA2czdEMGdINi1fUzdrQ0d1aHp5N3JsWTZvZ2NSZHU0eVVFeVhWNmpZdXg3SHlpMWlyNWpPREVnamMxMmdVRkh5d2RWQnU4OGpfYjlsR1VlTXh1WVhQTjR2dWl1UVJObWxHR0F3?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxOcTdJWTJ3YllOMWV6LXZ2R3lwN1RTbHhUWGo2NW80Y2l6U0xiQXZjU19VTXRqaEYwbnpyT1d6THNUQXRJNUkyeUhhU2NjYVBiR195b1QwT0VoOVBsNXVCWG04QnhqU0x4U2VTdGdEZVhPOHpHUU9ycG9jU0VsUDUzR29GRmllR1AyQmN2OXVXemlYcFpzUHVXajhtVHhMQ21MRkhqaVhvQTlTTktJM1hsalVuUXDSAboBQVVfeXFMT294MERyX2pMVkQyb0tHT05ld1hDdVFBQ3ByWFpmdVpIWExIenVmeUlSbFg3SGNHRmZPcjI3YllTT05DckdNR09BTUtkNXVPUExubDNrNlA2czdEMGdINi1fUzdrQ0d1aHp5N3JsWTZvZ2NSZHU0eVVFeVhWNmpZdXg3SHlpMWlyNWpPREVnamMxMmdVRkh5d2RWQnU4OGpfYjlsR1VlTXh1WVhQTjR2dWl1UVJObWxHR0F3?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 19:24:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kyiv ups drone attacks as mass evacuations begin over Russia’s advancing troops - New York Post ]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxNQlRhV1lKVmdXemNmb0xsVFVwRW96WWh3NUFzeEVhbk9LRWh0ZlNNQlJjRmtsWG1oV3VLX2ppUXZqUnBza3JqWUw5UUtya2hDV2pBYUxoaEF3bklJb0VxRzZuUUpXcTNfVFF1a0tibERfaDd6SVZrc21BcUhIcUNvUjRuOEh6WndjQWhxRktRZXc5STJVV1htTGJINHY1dG4zTmhsOGhjTXhxWFR5MWc0aVFzcGlaNy1WaGVINg?oc=5" target="_blank">Kyiv ups drone attacks as mass evacuations begin over Russia’s advancing troops</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">New York Post </font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNWDVOYVlBMGNRZEVOUXZfX3VWTlVIODhMTjlfQk9vTF9aMHY5RG14THhZRjZicnBIMTFfbEEwNWU2LWZLcHF6V2VBUEM5cTVhdWF1TVhxS2VXdkRDcWw1Q0JnNzZpTUhtd3Rjd1p5ckFFUEZpQUJkOEljNDRsSC0tZDBLQ1lVbDZRdWdBUXRraXpKVm1lX2R4eTFYSWdjR0nSAVZBVV95cUxOSUtJdm42N0pIcDNTclNzUjBMb29RTWxUZmo2dTAzNXFybDdsa1BrOTdNRkk3eF9lVmhPZUoyc3dSUk43bHFwdnlHNE1Kdms1SjRyZDdIZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Video shows Ukrainian drone attack on Russian airbase Marinovka</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxNRDN4dHlIcDg3TUNyczBmNUxkcXFCQUhlLUJRV3VZXzAwVENWVFVVOU85MzdiTEhvNmF4M2s4VGdpWWlBMUlqTTlBM210SzBzbUpQb2FpREFLRF82VzExUFItSWwzRGt0bmRZY2p5QWNjazNYYUJLc2V6bWN1ZVhXdFRxTDVpWEx2RkY2ZHQ3SW9VamtWa2dOWEVfYXlpcjI5Z3Q0?oc=5" target="_blank">Ukraine says it destroyed glide bombs at a Russian air base that aircraft fly out of to bomb the front lines</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Business Insider</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxOZjkyVjVxZzVobVpweXdhTTdiMHktU1owYWFUQ1hmTHNBMkJwOHdRbWc0NEt2Qnd3Nm5iN3hiTF8zbTZ5Ujd0b3VzSHFXalBraWhpTDNHdHloRl9MaVcxQm1KdWpwNFM4Y1BWdkhRUTZOcXRUQ2ZPUjJ0dktNZ3VLUnd2czNmZHF4WEo2VE53akdwbENLUTY4N2VXbFR2M25BNG5aLXplWkczdHpfS2lwejR6WFp4elZx?oc=5" target="_blank">Ukrainian Drones Hit Russian Military Air Base as Kyiv Escalates Long-Range Strikes</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Wall Street Journal</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTFBDdEJ3UWFhMVN3eWdwMnRwWDRJODBQajRDTDlFblZ0N3E4VVctczVwSE9GLTJ2RDREZ1IwUVdRRnc1ekNpclFjQ01XVjZjWUoyWDFveTFoU0hEdzJSOHRvM1Zma0l2bElydldRd3BuX1V2UGRyWFJIaEJUONIBgAFBVV95cUxPcXJsRG1xc2EwX0pCLTFnakZSVUM0V2N2Y1BhR2hnYkstTXNhMm9GYTZJVUpUdDkxeEpjRXdxZThUcDJwUGhCWDFOYnE1RXFpMUN4WWJielpXYzFxdHNrVzlZWGFrMjJEcFY5dXpjSnU5akVWNFdGLU1hUUpVTExBWg?oc=5" target="_blank">Ukraine hits Moscow in major drone attack, Russia says</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxNQlRhV1lKVmdXemNmb0xsVFVwRW96WWh3NUFzeEVhbk9LRWh0ZlNNQlJjRmtsWG1oV3VLX2ppUXZqUnBza3JqWUw5UUtya2hDV2pBYUxoaEF3bklJb0VxRzZuUUpXcTNfVFF1a0tibERfaDd6SVZrc21BcUhIcUNvUjRuOEh6WndjQWhxRktRZXc5STJVV1htTGJINHY1dG4zTmhsOGhjTXhxWFR5MWc0aVFzcGlaNy1WaGVINg?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxNQlRhV1lKVmdXemNmb0xsVFVwRW96WWh3NUFzeEVhbk9LRWh0ZlNNQlJjRmtsWG1oV3VLX2ppUXZqUnBza3JqWUw5UUtya2hDV2pBYUxoaEF3bklJb0VxRzZuUUpXcTNfVFF1a0tibERfaDd6SVZrc21BcUhIcUNvUjRuOEh6WndjQWhxRktRZXc5STJVV1htTGJINHY1dG4zTmhsOGhjTXhxWFR5MWc0aVFzcGlaNy1WaGVINg?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 18:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Watch: MyPillow CEO Loses Fight With 12-Year-Old Child at DNC]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/watch-mypillow-ceo-loses-fight-142603693.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/watch-mypillow-ceo-loses-fight-142603693.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 14:26:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Putin's slow response to the Kursk attack could test the patience of some of his backers in Russia]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/putins-slow-response-kursk-attack-041035733.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/putins-slow-response-kursk-attack-041035733.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 04:10:35 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>