<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 21:37:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 21:37:26 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[How Tim Walz actually handled the George Floyd protests in Minnesota]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Gov. Tim Walz, center, is flanked by Sens. Amy Klobuchar and Tina Smith, all in masks, looking at buildings along a Minneapolis street, surrounded by residents." data-caption="Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz, Sen. Amy Klobuchar, and Sen. Tina Smith met with business owners affected by the looting and riots following the George Floyd protests in Minneapolis. | Anthony Souffle/Star Tribune via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anthony Souffle/Star Tribune via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1246555849.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz, Sen. Amy Klobuchar, and Sen. Tina Smith met with business owners affected by the looting and riots following the George Floyd protests in Minneapolis. | Anthony Souffle/Star Tribune via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Tim Walz was just over a year into his first term as Minnesota governor when a Minneapolis police officer murdered George Floyd in May 2020, touching off a generation-defining summer of global protests against police brutality and racial inequality.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Four years later, Walz’s handling of the demonstrations — which included mass unrest in Minnesota’s largest cities — is under new scrutiny after Vice President Kamala Harris tapped the governor <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365437/tim-walz-kamala-harris-vice-president-live-news-updates">to be her running mate</a> on Tuesday.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At least two people died during the violence in Minnesota’s Twin Cities, more than <a href="https://x.com/MnDPS_DPS/status/1267890735564668929">600 arrests</a> were made in the initial days of unrest, and the whole span of rioting and law enforcement response made it one of the most <a href="https://www.startribune.com/twin-cities-rebuilding-begins-with-donations-pressure-on-government/571075592">costly and destructive periods of civil unrest</a> in US history. Minneapolis and Saint Paul sustained hundreds of millions of dollars in damage during those riots, and hundreds of buildings were heavily damaged.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Conservatives have charged Walz with essentially <a href="https://x.com/TrumpWarRoom/status/1820810879484506388">allowing</a> rioters to “burn Minneapolis to the ground” and waffling on the deployment of National Guard troops to quell the violence. But even former President Donald Trump apparently <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/despite-new-criticism-trump-told-walz-2020-happy/story?id=112616502">acknowledged</a> the difficulty of the situation. Per a new audio recording obtained by ABC News, Trump told a call of governors in June 2020 that he “fully agree[d] with the way [Walz] handled it the last couple of days.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Walz wasn’t the main authority in charge of responding to the unrest — that was the task of local officials, including Minneapolis Mayor Jacob Frey. But the task eventually passed to him once it was too much for local officials to handle. Both Walz and Frey’s governments have traded blame and presented their own versions of the events of those days of rage, but the full story of what happened is still not completely known.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What did Walz do during the unrest?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The main line of criticism of Walz’s response to the late-spring riots hinges on the time it took for him to deploy the Minnesota National Guard and coordinate with other state and local officials in restoring order.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Floyd was killed on May 25, and large protests, with some vandalism and police violence, began the next day. By the evening of May 27, largely peaceful protests grew more violent, with looting and arson around the city. Frey, the mayor, <a href="https://www.startribune.com/mayor-frey-gov-walz-hesitated-to-deploy-national-guard-during-minneapolis-riots/571999292">reportedly contacted</a> Walz that evening and asked for help from the Minnesota National Guard. The city’s police chief then sent Walz’s office a <a href="https://www.startribune.com/mayor-frey-gov-walz-hesitated-to-deploy-national-guard-during-minneapolis-riots/571999292">written request for 600 troops</a>, in addition to some other logistical notes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Walz and his office did not sign an executive order authorizing National Guard deployments <a href="https://mn.gov/governor/newsroom/press-releases/?id=1055-433799">until the following afternoon</a>, May 28, at which point much of the city had shut down, businesses were closed and boarded up to prevent looting, and buildings were smoldering after overnight arsons. That night saw some of the worst rioting, violence, and arson, as well as one of the indelible scenes of the protests: the breach and burning of the Minneapolis police’s <a href="https://www.mprnews.org/story/2020/06/30/the-precinct-is-on-fire-what-happened-at-minneapolis-3rd-precinct-and-what-it-means">Third Precinct police station</a>. A few hundred National Guard and Minnesota State Patrol officers had been deployed to Minneapolis by then, but <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/03/us/minneapolis-government-george-floyd.html">were charged</a> with protecting federal buildings and downtown areas of the city, as well as escorting first responders, instead of immediately going to hot spots.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Walz would later say that the city had not specified where the troops should go — and state and local officials later <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/03/31/us/minnesota-george-floyd-protests-state-police-review/index.html">reflected</a> that there was a breakdown in communication, coordination, and understanding of just how long it would take to get National Guard troops prepped.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The next morning, once National Guard troops and the state patrol had taken control of the area around the station, another lasting moment occurred: the arrest of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ftLzQefpBvM">CNN correspondent Omar Jimenez and his crew</a> while reporting live near the police station.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At a press conference on May 29, Walz would take responsibility for the state patrol’s mishandling of the news crew, saying, “There is absolutely no reason something like this should happen. Calls were made immediately … I failed you last night in that.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That press conference was also the first time Walz acknowledged that local officials’ response had been an “abject failure” and that he would now be leading the response. He said he had spoken with President Donald Trump and said that his tweets about <a href="https://www.vox.com/identities/2020/5/29/21274754/racist-history-trump-when-the-looting-starts-the-shooting-starts">“shooting” starting after looting</a> were “unhelpful.” He deployed more National Guard troops and instituted a curfew. Still, more violence and vandalism occurred.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The following day, Saturday, May 30, Walz would fully mobilize the National Guard, speak with Secretary of Defense Mark Esper and Chair of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Mark Milley, and acknowledge that the situation had gotten worse because “outside agitators” had entered the region. The protests and riots wouldn’t be fully tamped down in the Twin Cities until June 7.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The aftermath was both a blame game, and a humbling process</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Throughout the protests, local and state officials sparred with each other over a lack of communication and a misunderstanding of the gravity of the situation. Frey, the mayor, would go on to say Walz had <a href="https://www.startribune.com/mayor-frey-gov-walz-hesitated-to-deploy-national-guard-during-minneapolis-riots/571999292">hesitated</a> to step in and take leadership after Frey asked for help.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Through an extremely difficult situation, I told the truth,” Frey <a href="https://www.startribune.com/mayor-frey-gov-walz-hesitated-to-deploy-national-guard-during-minneapolis-riots/571999292">told the Star Tribune</a> a few months later. “I relayed information as best I could to state partners. And we did what was demanded for the sake of our city.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.startribune.com/mayor-frey-gov-walz-hesitated-to-deploy-national-guard-during-minneapolis-riots/571999292">A Star Tribune investigation</a> found that Frey and his city government had been trying to give Walz and the state Department of Public Safety “what they said they needed to move forward” with deploying the National Guard to Minneapolis’s Third Precinct, where the unrest was concentrated.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Star Tribune examined timestamped email and text logs and <a href="https://www.startribune.com/mayor-frey-gov-walz-hesitated-to-deploy-national-guard-during-minneapolis-riots/571999292">found plenty of correspondence that backed up the city officials’ sequence of events</a>: that they asked for help from the state government repeatedly, provided specifics, and did not get a prompt response. “He did not say yes,” Frey said of Walz. “He said he would consider it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The governor’s office, meanwhile, contested many of the mayor’s assertions. Contrary to the documents reviewed by the Star Tribune, Walz’s team argued Frey did not immediately provide an official request and had not specified where the focus of the National Guard should be. The governor’s office also contended Walz acted quickly once the request was received.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“As a 24-year veteran of the Minnesota National Guard, Governor Walz knows how much planning goes into a successful mission,” a Walz spokesperson told the Star Tribune in 2020. “That’s why he pushed the City of Minneapolis for details and a strategy. He ordered the Minnesota National Guard to start preparing Thursday morning which allowed them to deploy to both St. Paul and Minneapolis that evening, per the Mayors’ requests.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By that point in the riots, state Republicans like then-state Senate Majority Leader Paul Gazelka had also criticized Walz’s response, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/05/30/politics/tim-walz-minnesota-george-floyd-killing/index.html">saying</a> it was “a failure of leadership” because “the governor didn’t take the right action.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Republicans are attacking the governor’s response now that he’s on the VP ticket</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the Walz announcement, Republicans have assailed him as “weak, failed, and dangerously liberal,” and zeroed in specifically on his response to the Floyd protests and their aftermath. But at the time, Trump <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/despite-new-criticism-trump-told-walz-2020-happy/story?id=112616502">apparently praised Walz</a>, saying he felt “very happy with the last couple of days … You called up big numbers and the big numbers knocked them out so fast it was like bowling pins.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given that the racial reckoning that the Floyd murder kicked off included the rise to prominence of the “Defund the Police” slogan and movement, some conservatives have also claimed that Walz was being “soft on crime” for <a href="https://mn.gov/governor/newsroom/press-releases/?id=1055-441356">supporting</a> police <a href="https://www.courthousenews.com/minnesota-governor-signs-floyd-inspired-police-reform-bill/">reforms</a> in the state that banned chokeholds, created new mental health resources for police and first responders, and required excessive-force trainings. And others in right-wing media have <a href="https://x.com/RNCResearch/status/1820825378547720226">conflated</a> his response to George Floyd’s murder specifically, which he connected to “<a href="https://www.c-span.org/video/?472637-1/minnesota-governor-walz-news-conference-protests-riots-police-violence">systemic issues</a>” with policing and “<a href="https://x.com/TPostMillennial/status/1820819691599757429">institutional racism</a>,” with Walz offering excuses for the violence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the run-up to his selection as Harris’s potential VP, Walz hasn’t faced too many questions about his response to the 2020 unrest. But he may now face more scrutiny for that time. In response to questions from <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/06/us/tim-walz-george-floyd-criticism.html">the New York Times</a> on Tuesday, a Walz spokesperson acknowledged that the riots were “a tragic time” but said that Walz “took action” to keep the city safe.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Decisions were made in a situation that is what it is,” Walz said of the riots at a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/1a_cmYLXrZw?si=acr05CZSR2njsAR5&amp;t=2001">press conference</a> earlier this month. “And I simply believe that we tried to do the best we can in each of those.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, August 7, 5:30 pm: </em></strong><em>This story was originally published on August 6 and has been updated to include news about a new recording of Donald Trump praising Tim Walz’s response to the Minneapolis riots.</em></p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/365535/tim-walz-minneapolis-burning-riot-george-floyd-minnesota-2020-protest</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/365535/tim-walz-minneapolis-burning-riot-george-floyd-minnesota-2020-protest</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Paz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 21:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Who is Gwen Walz? Meet the teacher and wife of Harris's VP pick - BBC.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE50eGp2cVFDaWs5RkZRN3Z6eWcwdFZUWEgwdHRnUG9ncmJTZ3RVLVhQN3lOZFppNEl0dmtScG51R1g0dXdONG8yRWJCVGxKZnk4Q25YZWVDM2RhQdIBX0FVX3lxTE45My13SWM5R3ZGU2xaSEtfUVdxRzlLVlQ0M3dKb1VpMUJmMDNUMHZoZm1xbkpzc18xbmdPaTRvVFJ1cnBIbkY3VnBMVUFtYXZhcW9nd1VwYmozM2VROEZF?oc=5" target="_blank">Who is Gwen Walz? Meet the teacher and wife of Harris's VP pick</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNYU13azZoZzItNmNhMXIxRzljRmpLMnlURTFrV0hoY3EzdERJc0NWYUJfT25jZ0VWM09lZWluOFpPSzZ0OWdGcFM0XzNlS3NlYW16QWJ2SXlqbkpFTUpsOTJUN1QxSVdEMS1iZENZdlE3cGR2QzdNMGJ4Rml6dk1wOGUtZl9oNEpJa2djQk10M3lzQdIBiAFBVV95cUxPMUdlWm1VMlB1V2d1UjZnNHVkWXJpS0FWckJkQVZ1aGNlVjhkS0hINE5NRmRaVVB4ZTFfdWd6N3U0V3pZSW5mVnBjT3RhLXZwY2czV2RUa2IxOFM2NFZzdlhOMlo2UG9OUW5DR0xFTTFVX3RuOXNvbVRfRWVtT0l2RGRUVG5Ob05V?oc=5" target="_blank">Vance reopens line of attack into Walz’s military record as two veterans now vie to be vice president</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE9TVnJ4enYwMmxTRUx3Nk9sdHBTU2hiWm95LUlkcVU5U0FaeTBiemJheGYzVlB6OEZkd09RaENrNndNbmVqeGxYd2JvQ1FHa0YwVlZHYUJUVnpuQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Walz has history with China - it's more hawkish than critics claim</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxOQTRRVWZ4MXZ1dXdWZ2J4NkREZk9NSzRBWERZMlRPWkkwVGxwZlRLZ1dmaktSeGhpekNkUzFfTWxJcnNwWkJfSkRUVDFUenVGbXZmeEZGZlJqR0U5S1JiX2Jfa0NSYjh4TGpVdnRfeVZkaGpwaGs1dlQ0ZnJybHBudlVjamkwbFJHSWZvcTJUMmJDLVhwTGpZam9oVlNNdUswbU5Va3RRRzJ4dw?oc=5" target="_blank">Having a Chance Has Changed the Democrats</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Atlantic</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNWkN1Q1drbnFJcEM0QktXVk1LZHg3bERjLUVVb29WVW8xcDE0a1ljeW9PVWRXWWFYenBpdzJRcnpTcUNmUkRRSkFfZExYUktUMUl5WTBiYWt4MXlPNDlHOGNzalFLTU9YbnUzM2VabXJ6TGViN0FDaWFsYzNUZjBJZmE5eXZjOHFOVWJFWGZ5Z0Y4R2swTmtMZGVUdUhVU3JaM0t1b3ZfMHlEMk1MYkFv0gFUQVVfeXFMTXA1NlhySHc2aDBscFN6Z3prcmYzbDRhV09iQko2RUJySjlFSWRldlJTUWsteWNmemRXdWRYX1Bub25wSlAzcXNRc2JnMXVkVldnMXky?oc=5" target="_blank">Kamala Harris choice of Tim Walz for VP disappoints anti-Trump Republicans</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MSNBC</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE50eGp2cVFDaWs5RkZRN3Z6eWcwdFZUWEgwdHRnUG9ncmJTZ3RVLVhQN3lOZFppNEl0dmtScG51R1g0dXdONG8yRWJCVGxKZnk4Q25YZWVDM2RhQdIBX0FVX3lxTE45My13SWM5R3ZGU2xaSEtfUVdxRzlLVlQ0M3dKb1VpMUJmMDNUMHZoZm1xbkpzc18xbmdPaTRvVFJ1cnBIbkY3VnBMVUFtYXZhcW9nd1VwYmozM2VROEZF?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE50eGp2cVFDaWs5RkZRN3Z6eWcwdFZUWEgwdHRnUG9ncmJTZ3RVLVhQN3lOZFppNEl0dmtScG51R1g0dXdONG8yRWJCVGxKZnk4Q25YZWVDM2RhQdIBX0FVX3lxTE45My13SWM5R3ZGU2xaSEtfUVdxRzlLVlQ0M3dKb1VpMUJmMDNUMHZoZm1xbkpzc18xbmdPaTRvVFJ1cnBIbkY3VnBMVUFtYXZhcW9nd1VwYmozM2VROEZF?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 20:44:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Illinois governor calls for resignation of sheriff whose deputy fatally shot Black woman in her home - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPSlhxdHBHN0J1dTlQRWRCNzl5RVRMQ040NFEyNTZtQkQ3cE00d3l5M0pfanNSaEZSTFI1RjAybWxGZGU3dVNpM3Zwb1Y1a1hMLURGQi1jSkxJMmpnVFExX290RkFmWHg1NHZjempZMVpYU0t6OWV0ZlBQV0pTbElnTGctUkhGRUxwNzIwci1iWlVZRkpoUXAzelV3?oc=5" target="_blank">Illinois governor calls for resignation of sheriff whose deputy fatally shot Black woman in her home</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxOUFhaaUpDcEVsTk1qMVNvQjVHdXJSd2ZvU21VcnpCaGlhNkxLeExhNHBtMzg1enUwcEVOUGdCT2w4S3U1T0ExTjVvZUlsXzlLY05YQndZNF9WbEowZl9USVlLcHNFc3l0SEVLME1lb1VQdENUV2tRRjFxWGxHMmREdDA1clg5WWFWc2s2TW1ISDNMUG9VNG1aRW5MWnVGcmh0NFQyeHhqX1lFWXBzakE00gGvAUFVX3lxTFBWRW0wcW5CaFU3S2VQSXYyanRUdlNxUWplYkVmUkViMm9oeGpDUDNCaG1FN0g4S1VYYjF3TnRUYWhJRFBPUU9DNUloYldLYXZXa0pHa2VNZUZTc0t0M1ZvRkkza3ZmVGp0MnR6bDR3RjFBNWZJX2hOOFctTXVoejV5YTN5RkdaQ2tONVhhQkdFck5BM0NIS21LTnNnb0l5Sl9BdllsdWVBS1hlQXQ4RVk?oc=5" target="_blank">Illinois governor calls for sheriff, whose deputy killed Sonya Massey, to resign</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPT2ZMMnI5SVZuV0tpM2otNnV3V3RuTVJfd1pKYVg2TG5TM2lTbFVNWFRfLTF6WUNMMk52X2FuVy1JUXl0VV8zdGNqQ24wQXpEOU5BempCZVdVWWY2blBIc2gwX0VGamdueEg3a2RNM3JjUDFTZkZpMjlicDk5a2g2SzdzVWI2VTQwcThaNGZRM0UxNTdLektYSnhDdTh5dmd0cVI5SUVsblNkTm5yWHhLdHh3?oc=5" target="_blank">Illinois Gov. Pritzker calls for sheriff to resign after Sonya Massey shooting</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">USA TODAY</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxQbEhUaHIzQnZoT3UxRW5xcndIUDBRZEZzS2FJbzlSd0ptMlhVMjN4eTZZLW82RlVRdWxQLTNzZEZTTVpmUk1fbGpOOEdJZWoxTXZ2WlNpaHdSMGd2Y0RwZ21mNVdtZkZYZzBheFNCNFotekx5ZFRvZjR0akdyaXNOdGFXRQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Deputy charged in killing unarmed Sonya Massey claimed to fear for his life</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPTC1VSVFOTTl5bjFxMlVTcDI4UlpROUM4anRWR0dvdE9yMDQ4NnlHQXZOYlUyREJiT3gxM2huTDJ5elQyTmhYMG5WdF9SQXRLWGdWRW9oWEQ1bWUzeEx2anVMd1JCX01Ga2ZrNFJmLWJKVW1aSGdrOEJLU2pzRHpPblVoUGRrcG1yV2ViMy00dWFFM0U?oc=5" target="_blank">Deputy’s fatal shooting of Sonya Massey highlights risky practice of hiring America’s legion of ‘wandering officers’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPSlhxdHBHN0J1dTlQRWRCNzl5RVRMQ040NFEyNTZtQkQ3cE00d3l5M0pfanNSaEZSTFI1RjAybWxGZGU3dVNpM3Zwb1Y1a1hMLURGQi1jSkxJMmpnVFExX290RkFmWHg1NHZjempZMVpYU0t6OWV0ZlBQV0pTbElnTGctUkhGRUxwNzIwci1iWlVZRkpoUXAzelV3?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPSlhxdHBHN0J1dTlQRWRCNzl5RVRMQ040NFEyNTZtQkQ3cE00d3l5M0pfanNSaEZSTFI1RjAybWxGZGU3dVNpM3Zwb1Y1a1hMLURGQi1jSkxJMmpnVFExX290RkFmWHg1NHZjempZMVpYU0t6OWV0ZlBQV0pTbElnTGctUkhGRUxwNzIwci1iWlVZRkpoUXAzelV3?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 18:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Egypt asks its airlines to avoid Iran airspace for three hours on Thursday - Reuters.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQZWlILXR1UzlrdXpQcDdSY2ZaNFlVTWNDXzRnOGhJTTdGOU1QU3pHVDc5WDNKakd3N0R4eW9HWVVQekJpUWtVUWVGZ05VcWxVOURPTkFiX2E3VHFCUkZBSEFKWFRLZzNCckNqQVU0MUdPOUxVMnBXZnMyNFVob2I0YTRxakpHNnpaRzl4SjE5QnFHM2VSS2RNU2Q3cFh0VnZFRm1pV3ZESDNrMlA0LXBBemRoQ014NGxIdVZJ?oc=5" target="_blank">Egypt asks its airlines to avoid Iran airspace for three hours on Thursday</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxNeTFfTElySV9oMk5ZVy1lS2pNRWhaenREWVFpR29nZXNqa3UycThzdEtmQ2tuVnB0YS1ncnRQeWM4Y2ZaQ3VUTzhfbVJOUVl0al9DWThqeDVqM1haQjIyZnVLelZlSld2NTBBNkpEemdyMXh1dGRlWl83dHczaTN0UVMxNHROeWZRQ255d0FPb2lnamhhdTljYUZMU2pnX1NxSXphcUc3eFVtdjN4QnF5ei1ZTXBCNWl2UjB1dmtuU09oZXdMaXBhZmpR?oc=5" target="_blank">Egyptian official says airlines asked to avoid Iran’s airspace due to military drills</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of Israel</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQbXhpWjItS2Q2clZmcHg3SnNXSXdxZmI4VUdRTUkxeVZsN2s4blQ2NDNQNkV5QU40ckVwSFluYV9qczBZN2h6S1o0VXJKcFBXc09PVHpzTDcycXRBQzdfWXB6ZjYyaWk0aDdsamRqWU1zT1JMSG9fYjZkTjNmZldrTkdDM1BENkVvY0pMTS15NXlpMWZwajhya0cwMWNYeDdCcTY1bG9WT3hROGlLM1Z1RlNrNDFtdw?oc=5" target="_blank">Egypt asks its airlines to avoid Iranian airspace for three hours on Thursday</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Globe and Mail</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXkFVX3lxTE9nVllmREdHbzZzLUlnbFM5M3pJNXgzdmRQSl96cy1jMmFMdXJSN3kzU2hGMnhCV3ZoY3lLQXpCLUpqenRGVUFGQ2FmRUJ3eWZaY2xiOXF3Zy0tTmt4Mnc?oc=5" target="_blank">Egypt asks its airlines to avoid Tehran airspace for three hours on Thursday</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Arab News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQY2lzQlQzV25rRHdRdGJrTVpiVDJjeDY5b194RDBmZmk3S0MzQlN4bzJ1S2ZGRjJvV1FzTkszdzVweWFZTEhzQVp1RjE0a3VPWTk1Y29odDk1OGNNMl9HTFlKdlRfZm9ESEpYWmd2Sk5qaFRRbDJaX3U3RVpCSmFTQXFvYWdXN2NvWFpxZnFnZV9KREJSRENqeDJYQVhSa2VZN1RTS3F6eHdDZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Egypt declares three-hour no-fly zone over Iran amid fears of attack</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Telegraph</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQZWlILXR1UzlrdXpQcDdSY2ZaNFlVTWNDXzRnOGhJTTdGOU1QU3pHVDc5WDNKakd3N0R4eW9HWVVQekJpUWtVUWVGZ05VcWxVOURPTkFiX2E3VHFCUkZBSEFKWFRLZzNCckNqQVU0MUdPOUxVMnBXZnMyNFVob2I0YTRxakpHNnpaRzl4SjE5QnFHM2VSS2RNU2Q3cFh0VnZFRm1pV3ZESDNrMlA0LXBBemRoQ014NGxIdVZJ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQZWlILXR1UzlrdXpQcDdSY2ZaNFlVTWNDXzRnOGhJTTdGOU1QU3pHVDc5WDNKakd3N0R4eW9HWVVQekJpUWtVUWVGZ05VcWxVOURPTkFiX2E3VHFCUkZBSEFKWFRLZzNCckNqQVU0MUdPOUxVMnBXZnMyNFVob2I0YTRxakpHNnpaRzl4SjE5QnFHM2VSS2RNU2Q3cFh0VnZFRm1pV3ZESDNrMlA0LXBBemRoQ014NGxIdVZJ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 19:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Harris’ blue-collar pitch: New candidate, same pro-labor policies - POLITICO]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxONEJSQ2FxSGRYRlFVdWVLZHQ3QWZmM0Z2dzVoczN0ZlVtdlhQWjRqNE9jdUxZV1RpRTVLUl9hVktrcVQ1aTdZRW9ScXk5SFpLN2pleEVQaERwcnpSZExaTUd2MjVxYmJiX1VZbEJENGxsemNyWnl1NW5WYnNxOEpjRFZLNnE1LXhzdHc?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris’ blue-collar pitch: New candidate, same pro-labor policies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2locE1xS0RCRzlpd0lIazQtdnFpZ0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxONEJSQ2FxSGRYRlFVdWVLZHQ3QWZmM0Z2dzVoczN0ZlVtdlhQWjRqNE9jdUxZV1RpRTVLUl9hVktrcVQ1aTdZRW9ScXk5SFpLN2pleEVQaERwcnpSZExaTUd2MjVxYmJiX1VZbEJENGxsemNyWnl1NW5WYnNxOEpjRFZLNnE1LXhzdHc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxONEJSQ2FxSGRYRlFVdWVLZHQ3QWZmM0Z2dzVoczN0ZlVtdlhQWjRqNE9jdUxZV1RpRTVLUl9hVktrcVQ1aTdZRW9ScXk5SFpLN2pleEVQaERwcnpSZExaTUd2MjVxYmJiX1VZbEJENGxsemNyWnl1NW5WYnNxOEpjRFZLNnE1LXhzdHc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 20:12:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cori Bush loses race, Michigan showdown is set: 4 takeaways from Tuesday's pivotal 2024 primaries - USA TODAY]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxQb1haQkJnZHdNYlB2N0lNcFdvVzN3czQwdDBaaWh4RkNjYm9wUUdPdmU3MUZleGJUOG1mQWVxS0tXSlJQOVNwdFc3Y0sxUjVWSk8zY1dmY0pmZDJRMHI4SG5iR1J3MHdCSzBVNVExTDlrVFd4WXRIYzhoX1J3OUx6ZzFCVDdoSnRXZHBudnVGTW5mVjdmVWlTMXNMRHlYZkZSSWJ6Wmp4akEzb2tBd2ptS2YxSDRkakF0UHc?oc=5" target="_blank">Cori Bush loses race, Michigan showdown is set: 4 takeaways from Tuesday's pivotal 2024 primaries</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">USA TODAY</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxNRUxBQUVqakE0aF9MX2lXcTk5eU1RWnJuRnYtdDVsenlRd2thWE1hczdYU2xCOGlWamZZbTEzNXQ5YVotaGM1RWdSVmFnck5vc3ZQLTRuM0xQX1hQc1RSUnhnMWs0TFF0ZXBEOUNGbmF5OHptN1V5RFR0SEdhdTQwMFotRHVYYzhRXzdvXw?oc=5" target="_blank">AIPAC Demonstrates Its Clout With Defeat of a Second ‘Squad’ Member</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxPdk5kbGNBRkxCMnlYT2tGelFZTktLWEhUVmJuYXVKY2RCTUVqakxod2o1LXdKZTdvczdyZ3pUZloxcVRBdi1IRjJocXdBUTQ1VWRybFlVSzdET0w4MTdaYU0wR21NWEhVbkRwSWhDQXp0eHBqTjZCNnpOaVJjNjNtWmF2ellmUDNQcEhmU0N4QXh3VW9ZUVcxSmwxVlZUQ1NPNnJsejZfQjMzTWM?oc=5" target="_blank">Progressives have a win in Walz and a loss in Cori Bush, so what now?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Independent</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQbGcwUHp1YTRJY1VIVGZmd0h1QzBCWm5sZERITjlXZkg1TnN3UEI3aTlCMk9UQzNac1NpYW9ROEwwMnBqLTNfNU03N2RWblk4NFJOWU9iUzZfWTdiTDBKQ3lNTlhKWUx1VncwRDB6dXJDc1BhSEo1Y3lxdEZYZllqc3BwQ2Q0Vm1DSmxxaXBR?oc=5" target="_blank">3 big takeaways from Tuesday’s primaries: An incumbent loss, Trump’s endorsement power and more</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxQRm03bUFlbGVfaTByUy1RTE12YXAzT3hZN0xKRXIxOVcyeVVHQVp4QlBWeHMxTEJYYnlfOElrTWNrcElHYWhTNkltOTRkeHp1TGtDLTVwc0FiUmpCVll2cWRwSjZVV2I5QnctM1ozdHI3SVBQYnUzVFRCS3EyeHVnX0VkY1FaMm8wUDlpMl9PbG1CekVvVVZsaGtWa3pXZUdEOThuQWR6VlZXT083eEhV?oc=5" target="_blank">'Be afraid': Bush threatens pro-Israel group in bizarre rant after wide-margin loss</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxQb1haQkJnZHdNYlB2N0lNcFdvVzN3czQwdDBaaWh4RkNjYm9wUUdPdmU3MUZleGJUOG1mQWVxS0tXSlJQOVNwdFc3Y0sxUjVWSk8zY1dmY0pmZDJRMHI4SG5iR1J3MHdCSzBVNVExTDlrVFd4WXRIYzhoX1J3OUx6ZzFCVDdoSnRXZHBudnVGTW5mVjdmVWlTMXNMRHlYZkZSSWJ6Wmp4akEzb2tBd2ptS2YxSDRkakF0UHc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxQb1haQkJnZHdNYlB2N0lNcFdvVzN3czQwdDBaaWh4RkNjYm9wUUdPdmU3MUZleGJUOG1mQWVxS0tXSlJQOVNwdFc3Y0sxUjVWSk8zY1dmY0pmZDJRMHI4SG5iR1J3MHdCSzBVNVExTDlrVFd4WXRIYzhoX1J3OUx6ZzFCVDdoSnRXZHBudnVGTW5mVjdmVWlTMXNMRHlYZkZSSWJ6Wmp4akEzb2tBd2ptS2YxSDRkakF0UHc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 15:14:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[London was on high alert, but few far right demonstrators came to the capital - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxOUGhIMlVCN1J6TF92VjR1SEJYak53MWZPN1NPYUNCRmczQXo1SEdSUTFpbnUybWd3SlhnYlZzMkczcU93S3A1UE9OSHR6LWVmWWpvdmZ4aGpsSXEtVzFUYXRyWnJjWFNtb3hJanNPNGVlMmdiRlNnVDRsRnh0VTVsUldfWEU1b1BEMjVrTlhHT1pfZ01ZSFVRS0lGUjhSdlNUZXRZ0gFWQVVfeXFMUDdzZWRBRUtSS3lKVlQzaFQxUXVfQW5KNjdieHhPbWdYdVJVTTRzQzMxUU4ydDlfVmoxdUIyS1F5ZExMaE51emtZNUFFWHpyY191V0lBUmc?oc=5" target="_blank">London was on high alert, but few far right demonstrators came to the capital</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxQaDJQSjhwWm1LTTZ3OWdhUEJfRVZVai1Vand5dUhpek5TbmVIR1F2Y1Y0TDRUYXp3NHZDYVU1TFNVZHBYQWI2R3ZTMk9kclVBcURCVkdYYmhfT3I5cGZxamdXZ3BodzVHdHdTZ1JlemUwbzE2MnVQbVFMTUZFVnNacnlCSXVCQlhxcjZ1TnNtNzhEYkxwaEhDeVhoYzE2QV84QzFaM2x4UkJWY3gyZTNMZmlPRnR0RmQxWVhZMHhuVk9HakoxZng2OXNkajdQVlk2aHc?oc=5" target="_blank">Thousands of anti-racism protesters take to streets to counter far-right rallies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTFBJRW9YM2psSGRsdFh3Qnlib0NDeGg3WlMzZUcteTAwZFQyaGJZNDFNRzA0YlJodC1aQkxyQVdLUkU5U195VmVJRFkyc2hiWVlmVVJxRmlkYjBndw?oc=5" target="_blank">Anti-racism protesters gather in London to show 'unity'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOekR4SVhZQ01ZV19MQ1BZb2hMVnlNUVdWYzJJc2VCSDVZLXM5MXhwRENqNFJrM0lHZmNqN2JDSG9aSEpTQnhNVHVxak9JMjNxODdNWXdOQVlQeE1CUEpWT1VlSTZ1aU5JOF9WcTE1TFZIYVhwQXFOdm5GUXJjM21TMU5WRzdTRUpoQVlySDB6Z0hGc0hjYlZSM2NSNFB4cjNGTWpGR1M3ZGk4Y2h6ZG5IUHJUNNIBuAFBVV95cUxQa0pJWW1lV19aLV9QTTNfSVhpbTN3Vkd6MGw4aHgxdHYzal8tdGxyVnhuV1JmeTFvdnBBWEdUX0tKbGVPOTd0MzJmSEw5Wm5NekI3dUIwNTV6c0lfZFlHVTBwclhOVUlQeUJsQ1BOWTl3elZPbmlOemFrLXNKUldxYzJHb09na3F2UnRlMmYtTFJ2U21Bc1BpM3d3eU9Jem9tYTVBM25wMjNUUDdFS0xNZzhWdzhfQ2sz?oc=5" target="_blank">UK riots live news: Anti-racist counter-protesters gather</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Al Jazeera English</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxPM2ptdkdRcG1yLVRtbUxaNjg5Z1BTYW9ZRHlJUHlGa3JSS2NnZ3dkQ2JrOG9jT0FjVktpM3RuN05SNUpXSElPWGpGeHR6ak55OEFDZ3IyVzh1azZyQm5zdWFpMnNpM2gxSzVTR05tY0NwZWxYRFY0ZUtUUFA0YUhXWGVld3d1bXRsNTJNcTdKbUFpRHV1SzRVa0trX2EwTkRHWjJ0YzhSRlgySnloNnNXdjBmZllGV003?oc=5" target="_blank">UK riots live: Up to 25,000 counter-protesters march in clear message to far-right after 100 rallies planned</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Independent</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxOUGhIMlVCN1J6TF92VjR1SEJYak53MWZPN1NPYUNCRmczQXo1SEdSUTFpbnUybWd3SlhnYlZzMkczcU93S3A1UE9OSHR6LWVmWWpvdmZ4aGpsSXEtVzFUYXRyWnJjWFNtb3hJanNPNGVlMmdiRlNnVDRsRnh0VTVsUldfWEU1b1BEMjVrTlhHT1pfZ01ZSFVRS0lGUjhSdlNUZXRZ0gFWQVVfeXFMUDdzZWRBRUtSS3lKVlQzaFQxUXVfQW5KNjdieHhPbWdYdVJVTTRzQzMxUU4ydDlfVmoxdUIyS1F5ZExMaE51emtZNUFFWHpyY191V0lBUmc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxOUGhIMlVCN1J6TF92VjR1SEJYak53MWZPN1NPYUNCRmczQXo1SEdSUTFpbnUybWd3SlhnYlZzMkczcU93S3A1UE9OSHR6LWVmWWpvdmZ4aGpsSXEtVzFUYXRyWnJjWFNtb3hJanNPNGVlMmdiRlNnVDRsRnh0VTVsUldfWEU1b1BEMjVrTlhHT1pfZ01ZSFVRS0lGUjhSdlNUZXRZ0gFWQVVfeXFMUDdzZWRBRUtSS3lKVlQzaFQxUXVfQW5KNjdieHhPbWdYdVJVTTRzQzMxUU4ydDlfVmoxdUIyS1F5ZExMaE51emtZNUFFWHpyY191V0lBUmc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 21:18:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thai court bans a popular political party for proposing to amend lèse-majesté law - NPR]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxNY0plSFp5VE8tQ3ZHcDlyejBMeDlrUjNDckt6a0NqbFIwTkhsUDJZQ29fbXA4ZHJ4Z1daM2JYR3FwdXBNTTU5WnNCSlNsaThwcmQ0bU9uT1A3T2VMUm1SbEN4eVBBcjNnem5MRDdNVTZGVTJfS0lxVEhIQmFKdnpWSGRucVhLRGRhZF9PeVZSbw?oc=5" target="_blank">Thai court bans a popular political party for proposing to amend lèse-majesté law</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxQdElVUndORHM4amYxTmFFRkJKS0lzUjZBa2pSY0ZLa3hJN1lLQlI0dUp3Ynl4WUQxRm1UaWgzSk90WWdSTWVSSVJIOXBJUFU4T0d2RWJMeUJKeXZKWnlBTFV1dkk4VVhtNmMzUjJsaWNnOEMzaG9mbTFxQmlwM09SallVZzJ2TjY1c0ZlY3VBR1h5aFFMRndiZFdRc1Ixa21XMGxFSXpLRTRET1BVblhTdGlMeWJsbVpFUGRjb2RJcTNfcmVpSktUN3U3RkliWG5BNXBUUDUxRng0aEhEQ2ptQ1hheGkwQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Thai court dissolves progressive party that won elections but was blocked from power</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Los Angeles Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxNcVB3Qnk5UnNHalVuQl9pOTBzQ0gyRmR6cUVyVEtKRXdQUFJhX1RxR2JEXzBqUC1uOUh6Mzl3SDdCRWxPWVlSQlV5SzBRek93SzU4MW1zUmxmUkQtUEJld0pzSE9qSnRxUno1QlpoLWJSczFZVmQxUTNzRDUtYThJZjE4V0lDRTVrcjk3emZBYjdwYnlTUWxDWHA1VUt2R2tzTHhIS2NrZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Banning the opposition won’t save Thailand’s unpopular regime</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Economist</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxNR0NqWkxaN0ZkWFlNbTBpcVRjX0Z6bG5QWWJYeUdMZF9KUlpJdHJ6dzFFYjBmVGstX1RqU08tUU1aM1hjUXJKT1lXN0h5MEYxZmc3TGdyeU8wU2xaM0lyd1JYM1FWVllJYkFqMzNmSlgyU2VKZWM5eHZESy1Qc2lWMDRzOExHR1VjLV9fVkdzTdIBhgFBVV95cUxPYXk5ZjdNSTNaVmdTVGRoTkRmZXRzVHRNMmtoU1Vidlk0WExfUXF6dmJkNmIyWGQ0ekZtOFVvTVFUWjhXdzhtc0JZZ211OWNBNXRKdDA1SFQydXZqNm9uVnhGR25GaTZ0MU9CUWlMZ3FhdGw5OUtXTE55ZlZxa1l5ZnN5VExaZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Thai court orders election-winning party to dissolve in major blow to kingdom’s popular progressive movement</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxQQWRYQWZQWkhHZC1sX18wOWo0QjJ4X0hBeGEyZzY0UWwwdENoSnVqMzd6OW1XOWpnNDlRell4UXpfaGVwbTBRcnRfMWxPRHc2SW41eVpHTGNwOXVxMHFUVi1UWkx3LURaX0tsdmY5TV9JYU5iMlJtYUlCZXdTd1F1N1MxdVd3WFR4NlE?oc=5" target="_blank">Court Disbands Thailand’s Most Popular Political Party</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxNY0plSFp5VE8tQ3ZHcDlyejBMeDlrUjNDckt6a0NqbFIwTkhsUDJZQ29fbXA4ZHJ4Z1daM2JYR3FwdXBNTTU5WnNCSlNsaThwcmQ0bU9uT1A3T2VMUm1SbEN4eVBBcjNnem5MRDdNVTZGVTJfS0lxVEhIQmFKdnpWSGRucVhLRGRhZF9PeVZSbw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxNY0plSFp5VE8tQ3ZHcDlyejBMeDlrUjNDckt6a0NqbFIwTkhsUDJZQ29fbXA4ZHJ4Z1daM2JYR3FwdXBNTTU5WnNCSlNsaThwcmQ0bU9uT1A3T2VMUm1SbEN4eVBBcjNnem5MRDdNVTZGVTJfS0lxVEhIQmFKdnpWSGRucVhLRGRhZF9PeVZSbw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 15:20:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[As war looms and flights dwindle, Lebanese grapple with whether to flee]]></title><description><![CDATA[The exodus from Lebanon began last week after back-to-back assassinations targeted a Hezbollah commander near Beirut and Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/07/lebanon-israel-hezbollah-flights-war/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/07/lebanon-israel-hezbollah-flights-war/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 21:34:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iran's president tells Macron aggression will not be tolerated]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/irans-president-tells-macron-aggression-141823827.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/irans-president-tells-macron-aggression-141823827.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:18:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[As A Paramedic, I Treated Women Who Had Illegal Abortions. Here’s A Dangerous Truth JD Vance Isn’t Going To Like.]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/paramedic-treated-women-had-illegal-115656911.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/paramedic-treated-women-had-illegal-115656911.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:56:56 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>