<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:40:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:40:29 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Do other Democrats actually do better against Trump than Biden?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="DETROIT, MI - OCTOBER 15: Vice President Kamala Harris tours a FOCUS: HOPE facility with Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer on Saturday, Oct. 15, 2022 in Detroit, MI. The Vice President is in Michigan for events to highlight the administrations work ahead of the midterm election. (Kent Nishimura / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-1243996385.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>DETROIT, MI - OCTOBER 15: Vice President Kamala Harris tours a FOCUS: HOPE facility with Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer on Saturday, Oct. 15, 2022 in Detroit, MI. The Vice President is in Michigan for events to highlight the administrations work ahead of the midterm election. (Kent Nishimura / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">If the goal of national Democrats is to keep Donald Trump out of the White House to protect democracy — and <a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter/358061/democrats-biden-trump-existential-threat-democracy-debate">they’ve largely framed the 2024 election in just those existential terms</a> — who is best equipped to do it? And after a dismal debate performance by President Joe Biden last week, is it possible that there is <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024">another Democrat</a> better equipped to beat Trump than the sitting president?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Polling gives us one way to answer that question. But it’s not as simple as looking at the topline numbers and deciding that it’s time to dump Biden. The only timeline for which we know anything, solidly, is the one we’re living in: anything else is purely hypothetical, and requires some suspension of belief, some scrutiny in looking at numbers, and some skepticism in how we might expect the public to react.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What we know: The data shows a wash</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are a few different ways to judge how a hypothetical non-Biden candidate might fare against Trump:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Head-to-head polling, which asks voters who they would vote for: Trump or [insert Democrat here]?&nbsp;</strong></li>
</ol>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Polls taken before Thursday all largely deliver the same answer: any Biden alternative — <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/357948/url-harris-replace-biden-trump-debate-reaction-polling-vice-presidency">Vice President Kamala Harris</a>, Govs. Gretchen Whitmer of Michigan, Gavin Newsom of California, Josh Shapiro of Pennsylvania, Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg — performed about the same, or worse, than Biden against Trump when voters were asked how they’d vote in head-to-head matchups.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In averages of national polls fielded between February 2023 and January of this year, for example, Harris underperformed Biden by <a href="https://x.com/admcrlsn/status/1755963760173289503/photo/1">about 2.3 percentage points</a>, per tracking by the former Democratic pollster Adam Carlson.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More recently, a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/03/05/us/elections/times-siena-poll-likely-electorate-crosstabs.html">New York Times/Siena College poll</a> asked this question of likely voters. Harris received the support of about 42 percent of respondents against the 48 percent who said they’d back Trump, trailing by 6 points. Biden, by comparison, received the support of 44 percent of respondents against Trump’s 48, trailing by 4 points. The 2-point gap is within the margin of error, so there’s little daylight between Biden and his vice president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Less polling data exists for non-Harris alternatives. Back in February, Carlson <a href="https://x.com/admcrlsn/status/1756003253190357282/photo/1">also compiled</a> the results of different polls in that same period that asked voters to choose between Trump and Whitmer, Newsom, Buttigieg, or Sens. Joe Manchin of West Virginia and Bernie Sanders of Vermont. All those polls were conducted at various points in those 11 months, by different pollsters, about different hypothetical matchups.&nbsp;He found that only Manchin did better than Biden — but based on just one poll.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Buttigieg, Newsom, and Sanders did worse than Biden against Trump (Newsom, for example, trailed Biden’s margin against Trump in every poll in which he was included, by about 3 percentage points on average). Whitmer did roughly the same as Biden, but that’s also based on only two polls.</p>

<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Who’s better-liked?</strong></li>
</ol>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another way to ask this question is to look at the favorability ratings of Biden, Biden alternatives, and Trump. Biden and Trump are both historically disliked political figures —&nbsp; Biden himself is the most unpopular modern president since … Trump. The latest source of information we have here that compares alternatives is also from before the debate: the Economist/YouGov’s poll <a href="https://d3nkl3psvxxpe9.cloudfront.net/documents/econTabReport_DqmBE9q.pdf">from the last week of June</a> asked about approval ratings for Trump, Biden, and Harris.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The poll found that Trump is disliked by 57 percent of Americans and liked by 39 percent, putting him at -18 percent. Biden is viewed similarly: disliked by 58 percent of the public and liked by 39 percent, placing him at -19 percent.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris does slightly better: disliked by 54 percent, and liked by 37 percent, placing her at -17 percent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, Harris is viewed slightly less negatively than Biden is, but she isn’t significantly more popular.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Polling aggregates of favorability ratings show something similar. In the Real Clear Politics average, <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/favorability/kamala-harris">Harris</a> holds a -14.8 point rating; <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/favorability/joe-biden">Biden</a> stands at -15.3; <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/favorability/donald-trump">Trump</a> stands at -11. Biden and Harris are viewed roughly the same.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the debate, we really only have one clear source on how Americans view these figures: a <a href="https://www.dataforprogress.org/blog/2024/6/29/in-post-debate-poll-voters-think-biden-is-too-old-to-be-president-yet-alternative-candidates-perform-similarly-against-trump">Data for Progress flash poll</a> fielded the day after the debate. This one poll of about 1,000 likely voters has been <em>the </em>key evidence used by Biden defenders and Biden critics to <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358461/replace-joe-biden-drop-out-kamala-harris">make their cases</a>, but it shows pretty much what we saw before the debate: no alternative candidate does better than Biden against Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In terms of vote share, Harris performs roughly the same as Biden, garnering the support of 45 percent of likely voters against Trump’s 48 percent. Other Democrats, like Buttigieg, Newsom, Whitmer, and Shapiro, win slightly smaller shares of the electorate — anywhere from 44 to 43 percent of likely voters. But at the same time, in those matchups, the share of undecided voters grows. Trump’s support, meanwhile, stays steadily between 46 and 47.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“What we&#8217;re seeing pretty frequently is that Trump&#8217;s numbers are pretty solid. Trump doesn&#8217;t move much,” <a href="https://www.gqrr.com/team/natalie-jackson/">Natalie Jackson</a>, a pollster and vice president at the GQR public opinion research firm, told me. “He stays pretty steady right around where he was in 2020.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And these are all national polls — if you’re wondering who might do better in the specific battleground states crucial to winning the Electoral College vote, we simply don’t have data.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What we don’t know</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, it’s too soon to tell just what the American people are thinking about replacing Biden with an alternative.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Plenty of political developments and newsworthy events are still unfolding, influencing how people think about Thursday night.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And even the one poll everyone has been referencing since Thursday should be viewed with a grain of salt, Jackson told me, since it was put together and fielded quickly, opening it up to some bias, since it’s taking stock of the type of people who would be willing to answer questions about the debate almost immediately.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We won’t know for two or three weeks how all of this bakes into the numbers, and now we have <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">the immunity case</a> stacked on top of it, so it’s possible that we’re not ever going to really know how this one event played out,” she told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Next, we are dealing in hypotheticals. Any talk about how a Biden alternative would fare against Trump is purely imaginary at this point: we don’t really know how well any of these candidates would do among specific kinds of voters or in different states or regions. How would Whitmer do in the Sun Belt? How would Newsom do in the Midwest? Those questions are crucial to winning the Electoral College, and the polls we have don’t come close to answering them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nor do we know how any of these candidates would get to the top of the ticket, and how their path would influence their popularity (or lack thereof). Would the nomination flow to Harris, who seems like the logical successor despite years of negative coverage? Would she be passed up in favor of Newsom, Whitmer, or Shapiro — and if so, how would the Democratic base, especially Black voters, respond to the first Black female vice president being sidelined so publicly? Would this all be fought out at the floor of an open convention in Chicago? And would all that chaos end up dealing the eventual nominee the same kind of damage that Biden’s age is dealing him right now?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there are, broadly speaking, two ways to look at the data we do have.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first is that the polls show hypothetical Biden alternatives would do no better than Biden (generally what Biden defenders say). The second is that they are doing just as well as Biden without even running as actual presidential candidates — and could do better still (what Biden critics say).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But neither side can fully claim to be right, and there are strong counterarguments to both sides. The <a href="https://www.dataforprogress.org/blog/2024/6/29/in-post-debate-poll-voters-think-biden-is-too-old-to-be-president-yet-alternative-candidates-perform-similarly-against-trump">DFP poll</a>, for example, shows that Harris, post-debate, still has a better favorability score than Biden, and is doing better than the president with women, Latino voters, and young voters — groups that Biden has <a href="https://split-ticket.org/2024/06/30/the-case-for-and-against-joe-biden/">struggled with overall</a>. Philip Bump at the Washington Post <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/06/28/kamala-harris-trump-matchup/">did some digging</a> on this question last week as well, comparing Harris and Biden’s favorability ratings among subgroups before the debate, and found Harris seems to be viewed more favorably by younger voters, women, and non-white voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, respondents are likely still not seeing Harris or alternatives as actual options, instead seeing these names as stand-ins for a “generic Democrat” — anyone who is not Joe Biden. Each of these alternatives is less well known than Biden in DFP’s poll; unless you’re super plugged into political news or from the Midwest, you probably don’t know who Gretchen Whitmer is; if you know of Gavin Newsom, you probably have strong feelings about him.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whitmer, Shapiro, and Buttigieg, for example, all have better net favorability ratings than Biden or Harris in the DFP poll, but many <a href="https://www.dataforprogress.org/blog/2024/6/29/in-post-debate-poll-voters-think-biden-is-too-old-to-be-president-yet-alternative-candidates-perform-similarly-against-trump#:~:text=Voters%E2%80%99%20Perceptions%20of%20Biden%20and%20Alternative%20Democratic%20Candidates">respondents say</a> they haven’t heard enough about these people to form an opinion. For Shapiro, Whitmer, and Buttigieg, the share of respondents who haven’t heard of them is much larger than the share who can form a positive or negative opinion. Newsom is the best-known of these alternatives, but he’s also disliked nearly as much as Biden, and more than Harris.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Being little-known isn’t necessarily a bad thing. To optimists about the alterna-Bidens, it means that there is more room for these candidates to grow, for the public to get to know them, and to put forward a new, positive message.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there’s also a pessimistic side: You’re less publicly vetted and more vulnerable to skeletons in the closet. Many would also be trying a first national campaign on the highest-stakes platform possible.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In short, we don’t know much. These are all hypotheticals we’re trying to game out from a very limited set of data. And we’re likely to get a bunch more data as we move further from the debate. As that happens, Jackson urged a word of caution.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think we&#8217;re in a position where there&#8217;s so much going on that we haven&#8217;t seen before that we should treat polling skeptically and as what it is: a snapshot of what opinion looks like in the moment that could change.”</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/358559/biden-harris-whitmer-newsom-shapiro-buttigieg-alternative-nomination-candidate-2024</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/358559/biden-harris-whitmer-newsom-shapiro-buttigieg-alternative-nomination-candidate-2024</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Paz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:27:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump sentencing in hush money case could be delayed]]></title><description><![CDATA[The ex-president's lawyers cite a new Supreme Court ruling that granted him partial immunity from prosecution.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cw4yp9g7ynwo</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cw4yp9g7ynwo</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 16:34:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rudy Giuliani disbarred over 'false and misleading' statements on 2020 election - ABC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibmh0dHBzOi8vYWJjbmV3cy5nby5jb20vVVMvcnVkeS1naXVsaWFuaS1kaXNiYXJyZWQtZmFsc2UtbWlzbGVhZGluZy1zdGF0ZW1lbnRzLTIwMjAtZWxlY3Rpb24vc3Rvcnk_aWQ9MTExNjExOTE10gFyaHR0cHM6Ly9hYmNuZXdzLmdvLmNvbS9hbXAvVVMvcnVkeS1naXVsaWFuaS1kaXNiYXJyZWQtZmFsc2UtbWlzbGVhZGluZy1zdGF0ZW1lbnRzLTIwMjAtZWxlY3Rpb24vc3Rvcnk_aWQ9MTExNjExOTE1?oc=5" target="_blank">Rudy Giuliani disbarred over 'false and misleading' statements on 2020 election</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiYGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMDIvbnlyZWdpb24vZ2l1bGlhbmktYmFycmVkLWZyb20tcHJhY3RpY2luZy1sYXctaW4tbmV3LXlvcmsuaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Giuliani Disbarred From the Practice of Law in New York</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiYWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMi9wb2xpdGljcy9ydWR5LWdpdWxpYW5pLW9mZmljaWFsbHktZGlzYmFycmVkLWluLW5ldy15b3JrL2luZGV4Lmh0bWzSAVpodHRwczovL2FtcC5jbm4uY29tL2Nubi8yMDI0LzA3LzAyL3BvbGl0aWNzL3J1ZHktZ2l1bGlhbmktb2ZmaWNpYWxseS1kaXNiYXJyZWQtaW4tbmV3LXlvcms?oc=5" target="_blank">Rudy Giuliani officially disbarred in New York for Trump election interference efforts</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiT2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndhc2hpbmd0b25wb3N0LmNvbS9wb2xpdGljcy8yMDI0LzA3LzAyL2dpdWxpYW5pLWRpc2JhcnJlZC1uZXcteW9yay_SAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Giuliani disbarred in N.Y. over false statements about 2020 election</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiV2h0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL2dpdWxpYW5pLW5ldy15b3JrLWRpc2JhcnJlZC04MWIzMjdmOWFiMWY5ODU0OGNiODg4ZjhlNjUyYzlhONIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Giuliani disbarred in NY as court finds he repeatedly lied about Trump's 2020 election loss</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibmh0dHBzOi8vYWJjbmV3cy5nby5jb20vVVMvcnVkeS1naXVsaWFuaS1kaXNiYXJyZWQtZmFsc2UtbWlzbGVhZGluZy1zdGF0ZW1lbnRzLTIwMjAtZWxlY3Rpb24vc3Rvcnk_aWQ9MTExNjExOTE10gFyaHR0cHM6Ly9hYmNuZXdzLmdvLmNvbS9hbXAvVVMvcnVkeS1naXVsaWFuaS1kaXNiYXJyZWQtZmFsc2UtbWlzbGVhZGluZy1zdGF0ZW1lbnRzLTIwMjAtZWxlY3Rpb24vc3Rvcnk_aWQ9MTExNjExOTE1?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibmh0dHBzOi8vYWJjbmV3cy5nby5jb20vVVMvcnVkeS1naXVsaWFuaS1kaXNiYXJyZWQtZmFsc2UtbWlzbGVhZGluZy1zdGF0ZW1lbnRzLTIwMjAtZWxlY3Rpb24vc3Rvcnk_aWQ9MTExNjExOTE10gFyaHR0cHM6Ly9hYmNuZXdzLmdvLmNvbS9hbXAvVVMvcnVkeS1naXVsaWFuaS1kaXNiYXJyZWQtZmFsc2UtbWlzbGVhZGluZy1zdGF0ZW1lbnRzLTIwMjAtZWxlY3Rpb24vc3Rvcnk_aWQ9MTExNjExOTE1?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:20:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bill Barr responds to Bannon’s threats: ‘I don’t lose any sleep over it’ - The Hill]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZ2h0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vcmVndWxhdGlvbi9jb3VydC1iYXR0bGVzLzQ3NTEzNzgtYmlsbC1iYXJyLXN0ZXZlLWJhbm5vbi1kb25hbGQtdHJ1bXAtamFuLTYtdGhyZWF0cy_SAWtodHRwczovL3RoZWhpbGwuY29tL3JlZ3VsYXRpb24vY291cnQtYmF0dGxlcy80NzUxMzc4LWJpbGwtYmFyci1zdGV2ZS1iYW5ub24tZG9uYWxkLXRydW1wLWphbi02LXRocmVhdHMvYW1wLw?oc=5" target="_blank">Bill Barr responds to Bannon’s threats: ‘I don’t lose any sleep over it’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaWh0dHBzOi8vYWJjbmV3cy5nby5jb20vUG9saXRpY3MvdHJ1bXAtYmlkZW4tcGF5LWJpZy1wcmljZS13ZWFwb25pemF0aW9uLWp1c3RpY2Utc3lzdGVtL3N0b3J5P2lkPTExMTU5NjI0MNIBbWh0dHBzOi8vYWJjbmV3cy5nby5jb20vYW1wL1BvbGl0aWNzL3RydW1wLWJpZGVuLXBheS1iaWctcHJpY2Utd2VhcG9uaXphdGlvbi1qdXN0aWNlLXN5c3RlbS9zdG9yeT9pZD0xMTE1OTYyNDA?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump says Biden will 'pay a very big price' for 'weaponization' of justice system as Bannon heads to prison</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnlhaG9vLmNvbS9uZXdzL3dhdGNoLWJpbGwtYmFyci1wcmljZWxlc3MtcmVhY3Rpb24tMTQyMDEzNDQ4Lmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Watch: Bill Barr's Priceless Reaction as Steve Bannon Heads to Prison</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo! Voices</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMS9wb2xpdGljcy92aWRlby9zdGV2ZS1iYW5ub24tcmVwb3J0cy10by1wcmlzb24tbXVycmF5LW5yLWRpZ3ZpZNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Hear Bannon address supporters before going to prison</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMDEvbnlyZWdpb24vc3RldmUtYmFubm9uLXByaXNvbi1qYW4tNi5odG1s0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Bannon Reports to Federal Prison After Conviction for Defying Congress</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZ2h0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vcmVndWxhdGlvbi9jb3VydC1iYXR0bGVzLzQ3NTEzNzgtYmlsbC1iYXJyLXN0ZXZlLWJhbm5vbi1kb25hbGQtdHJ1bXAtamFuLTYtdGhyZWF0cy_SAWtodHRwczovL3RoZWhpbGwuY29tL3JlZ3VsYXRpb24vY291cnQtYmF0dGxlcy80NzUxMzc4LWJpbGwtYmFyci1zdGV2ZS1iYW5ub24tZG9uYWxkLXRydW1wLWphbi02LXRocmVhdHMvYW1wLw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZ2h0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vcmVndWxhdGlvbi9jb3VydC1iYXR0bGVzLzQ3NTEzNzgtYmlsbC1iYXJyLXN0ZXZlLWJhbm5vbi1kb25hbGQtdHJ1bXAtamFuLTYtdGhyZWF0cy_SAWtodHRwczovL3RoZWhpbGwuY29tL3JlZ3VsYXRpb24vY291cnQtYmF0dGxlcy80NzUxMzc4LWJpbGwtYmFyci1zdGV2ZS1iYW5ub24tZG9uYWxkLXRydW1wLWphbi02LXRocmVhdHMvYW1wLw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 13:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rep. Quigley on Biden's debate performance: 'It wasn't just a horrible night' - POLITICO]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmNvbS9uZXdzLzIwMjQvMDcvMDIvZGVtb2NyYXRzLWJpZGVuLWRlYmF0ZS1mYWxsb3V0LTAwMTY2MjA40gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Rep. Quigley on Biden's debate performance: 'It wasn't just a horrible night'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZ2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMi9wb2xpdGljcy92aWRlby9taWtlLXF1aWdsZXktaW50ZXJ2aWV3LWJpZGVuLXJlcGxhY2VtZW50LWNubnRtLWxkbi1kaWd2aWTSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Democratic Rep. signals openness to Biden’s replacement as party’s nominee</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFodHRwczovL3d3dy5tc25iYy5jb20vYW5hLWNhYnJlcmEtcmVwb3J0cy93YXRjaC8tZXZlcnlvbmUtanVzdC1uZWVkcy10by1icmVhdGhlLWJpZGVuLWNhbXBhaWduLXRyaWVzLXRvLXJlYXNzdXJlLXRvcC1kb25vcnMtMjE0MDc1NDYxOTU00gE2aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubXNuYmMuY29tL21zbmJjL2FtcC12aWRlby9tbXZvMjE0MDc1NDYxOTU0?oc=5" target="_blank">‘Everyone just needs to breathe’: Biden campaign tries to reassure top donors</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MSNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigQFodHRwczovL3d3dy5mb3huZXdzLmNvbS9wb2xpdGljcy9sb25ndGltZS1iaWRlbi1zZW5hdGUtY29sbGVhZ3VlLWNhbGxzLWZvci1uZXctY2FuZGlkYXRlLWFmdGVyLWJpZGVuLWRlYmF0ZS1wZXJmb3JtYW5jZS1zdGFydGxpbmfSAYUBaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZm94bmV3cy5jb20vcG9saXRpY3MvbG9uZ3RpbWUtYmlkZW4tc2VuYXRlLWNvbGxlYWd1ZS1jYWxscy1mb3ItbmV3LWNhbmRpZGF0ZS1hZnRlci1iaWRlbi1kZWJhdGUtcGVyZm9ybWFuY2Utc3RhcnRsaW5nLmFtcA?oc=5" target="_blank">Longtime Biden Senate colleague calls for 'new candidate' after Biden debate performance: 'Disaster'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiV2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndhc2hpbmd0b25wb3N0LmNvbS9wb2xpdGljcy8yMDI0LzA3LzAxL2JpZGVuLXNraXR0aXNoLWRlbW9jcmF0cy1kZWZlY3Rpb25zL9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden team courts skittish Democrats as path to replace him narrows</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmNvbS9uZXdzLzIwMjQvMDcvMDIvZGVtb2NyYXRzLWJpZGVuLWRlYmF0ZS1mYWxsb3V0LTAwMTY2MjA40gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmNvbS9uZXdzLzIwMjQvMDcvMDIvZGVtb2NyYXRzLWJpZGVuLWRlYmF0ZS1mYWxsb3V0LTAwMTY2MjA40gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 13:10:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden team weighs July town hall, interviews to reassure voters - Reuters]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL3VzL2JpZGVuLXRlYW0td2VpZ2hzLWp1bHktdG93bi1oYWxsLWludGVydmlld3MtcmVhc3N1cmUtdm90ZXJzLTIwMjQtMDctMDEv0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden team weighs July town hall, interviews to reassure voters</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMi9wb2xpdGljcy9kZW1vY3JhdGljLWdvdmVybm9ycy1qb2UtYmlkZW4vaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBSmh0dHBzOi8vYW1wLmNubi5jb20vY25uLzIwMjQvMDcvMDIvcG9saXRpY3MvZGVtb2NyYXRpYy1nb3Zlcm5vcnMtam9lLWJpZGVu?oc=5" target="_blank">Democratic governors seek meeting with White House after poor debate performance</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnRoZWd1YXJkaWFuLmNvbS91cy1uZXdzL2FydGljbGUvMjAyNC9qdWwvMDEvcmVwbGFjZS1iaWRlbi1kZW1vY3JhdGljLWdvdmVybm9yc9IBWmh0dHBzOi8vYW1wLnRoZWd1YXJkaWFuLmNvbS91cy1uZXdzL2FydGljbGUvMjAyNC9qdWwvMDEvcmVwbGFjZS1iaWRlbi1kZW1vY3JhdGljLWdvdmVybm9ycw?oc=5" target="_blank">Democratic governors reportedly waiting in wings after dire Biden debate</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5qLmNvbS9wb2xpdGljcy8yMDI0LzA3L2RlbS1nb3ZzLXdhbnQtd2hpdGUtaG91c2UtbWVldGluZy13aXRoLWJpZGVuLXRvLWhlYXItZnJvbS10aGUtcHJlc2lkZW50LWRpcmVjdGx5Lmh0bWzSAYgBaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmouY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzLzIwMjQvMDcvZGVtLWdvdnMtd2FudC13aGl0ZS1ob3VzZS1tZWV0aW5nLXdpdGgtYmlkZW4tdG8taGVhci1mcm9tLXRoZS1wcmVzaWRlbnQtZGlyZWN0bHkuaHRtbD9vdXRwdXRUeXBlPWFtcA?oc=5" target="_blank">Before getting back on Biden bandwagon vs. Trump, Dem govs have a demand</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NJ.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiS2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMDIvdXMvcG9saXRpY3MvYmlkZW4tZ292ZXJub3JzLW1lZXRpbmcuaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden's Team Plans Meeting With Governors to Shore Up Support</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL3VzL2JpZGVuLXRlYW0td2VpZ2hzLWp1bHktdG93bi1oYWxsLWludGVydmlld3MtcmVhc3N1cmUtdm90ZXJzLTIwMjQtMDctMDEv0gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL3VzL2JpZGVuLXRlYW0td2VpZ2hzLWp1bHktdG93bi1oYWxsLWludGVydmlld3MtcmVhc3N1cmUtdm90ZXJzLTIwMjQtMDctMDEv0gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hungary's Orban, in Kyiv, proposes ceasefire to speed up peace talks - Reuters]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL2V1cm9wZS9odW5nYXJ5LXBtLW9yYmFuLWFycml2ZXMta3lpdi10YWxrcy13aXRoLXVrcmFpbmVzLXplbGVuc2tpeS0yMDI0LTA3LTAyL9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Hungary's Orban, in Kyiv, proposes ceasefire to speed up peace talks</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiU2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMDIvd29ybGQvZXVyb3BlL29yYmFuLWh1bmdhcnktdWtyYWluZS16ZWxlbnNreS5odG1s0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Prime Minister Viktor Orban of Hungary Visits Ukraine</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmluZGVwZW5kZW50LmNvLnVrL25ld3Mvd29ybGQvZXVyb3BlL3Zpa3Rvci1vcmJhbi1odW5nYXJ5LXVrcmFpbmUtZXUtcnVzc2lhLWIyNTcyNjI5Lmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Orban urges Ukraine 'to consider quick ceasefire' during first trip to war-torn Kyiv</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Independent</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnRoZWd1YXJkaWFuLmNvbS93b3JsZC9hcnRpY2xlLzIwMjQvanVsLzAyL3Zpa3Rvci1vcmJhbi12aXNpdHMta3lpdi10YWxrcy12b2xvZHlteXItemVsZW5za2l50gFoaHR0cHM6Ly9hbXAudGhlZ3VhcmRpYW4uY29tL3dvcmxkL2FydGljbGUvMjAyNC9qdWwvMDIvdmlrdG9yLW9yYmFuLXZpc2l0cy1reWl2LXRhbGtzLXZvbG9keW15ci16ZWxlbnNraXk?oc=5" target="_blank">Viktor Orbán visits Kyiv for surprise talks with Volodymyr Zelenskiy</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmFsamF6ZWVyYS5jb20vbmV3cy8yMDI0LzcvMi9odW5nYXJ5cy1vcmJhbi11cmdlcy1ydXNzaWEtdWtyYWluZS1jZWFzZWZpcmUtb24tc3VycHJpc2UtdmlzaXQtdG8ta3lpdtIBc2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmFsamF6ZWVyYS5jb20vYW1wL25ld3MvMjAyNC83LzIvaHVuZ2FyeXMtb3JiYW4tdXJnZXMtcnVzc2lhLXVrcmFpbmUtY2Vhc2VmaXJlLW9uLXN1cnByaXNlLXZpc2l0LXRvLWt5aXY?oc=5" target="_blank">Hungary’s Orban urges Russia-Ukraine ceasefire on surprise visit to Kyiv</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Al Jazeera English</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL2V1cm9wZS9odW5nYXJ5LXBtLW9yYmFuLWFycml2ZXMta3lpdi10YWxrcy13aXRoLXVrcmFpbmVzLXplbGVuc2tpeS0yMDI0LTA3LTAyL9IBAA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL2V1cm9wZS9odW5nYXJ5LXBtLW9yYmFuLWFycml2ZXMta3lpdi10YWxrcy13aXRoLXVrcmFpbmVzLXplbGVuc2tpeS0yMDI0LTA3LTAyL9IBAA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Investors have found peace in another Trump presidency - Yahoo Finance]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZGh0dHBzOi8vZmluYW5jZS55YWhvby5jb20vbmV3cy9pbnZlc3RvcnMtaGF2ZS1mb3VuZC1wZWFjZS1pbi1hbm90aGVyLXRydW1wLXByZXNpZGVuY3ktMTU0NzAzMTUwLmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Investors have found peace in another Trump presidency</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo Finance</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFodHRwczovL3d3dy5ibG9vbWJlcmcuY29tL25ld3MvbmV3c2xldHRlcnMvMjAyNC0wNy0wMS93YWxsLXN0cmVldC1zZWVzLXByZXNpZGVudGlhbC1kZWJhdGUtYXMtZ2FtZS1jaGFuZ2VyLXNlZXMtaGl0LXRvLWJvbmQteWllbGRz0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Wall Street Sees Presidential Debate as a Game Changer</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Bloomberg</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmJhcnJvbnMuY29tL2FydGljbGVzL3RydW1wLWJpZGVuLXN0b2NrLW1hcmtldHMtd2hhdC10by1rbm93LXRvZGF5LTBiMmUzZDE00gFaaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuYmFycm9ucy5jb20vYW1wL2FydGljbGVzL3RydW1wLWJpZGVuLXN0b2NrLW1hcmtldHMtd2hhdC10by1rbm93LXRvZGF5LTBiMmUzZDE0?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump, Biden Are Market Movers. Why They May Eclipse Fed Minutes, Jobs Data.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Barron's</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnRoZWdsb2JlYW5kbWFpbC5jb20vaW52ZXN0aW5nL2FydGljbGUtd2FsbC1zdHJlZXQtd2FudHMtZHJhbWEtZnJlZS1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtZGViYXRlLXdhdGNoaW5nLWNvbXBvcnRtZW50L9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Wall Street wants drama-free presidential debate, watching comportment as much as policy</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Globe and Mail</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUmh0dHBzOi8vZmluYW5jZS55YWhvby5jb20vdmlkZW8vbWFya2V0LXRyZW5kcy1wcmVzaWRlbnQtZGViYXRlLWJhbmstMjIxODMzMTYwLmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Market trends, presidential debate, bank dividends: Asking for a Trend</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo Finance</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZGh0dHBzOi8vZmluYW5jZS55YWhvby5jb20vbmV3cy9pbnZlc3RvcnMtaGF2ZS1mb3VuZC1wZWFjZS1pbi1hbm90aGVyLXRydW1wLXByZXNpZGVuY3ktMTU0NzAzMTUwLmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZGh0dHBzOi8vZmluYW5jZS55YWhvby5jb20vbmV3cy9pbnZlc3RvcnMtaGF2ZS1mb3VuZC1wZWFjZS1pbi1hbm90aGVyLXRydW1wLXByZXNpZGVuY3ktMTU0NzAzMTUwLmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:47:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Voters kick all the Republican women out of the South Carolina Senate]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/voters-kick-republican-women-south-114230340.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/voters-kick-republican-women-south-114230340.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 11:42:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Opinion: What Trump said during the debate that has many Black Americans and Palestinians outraged]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/opinion-most-despicable-things-trump-232825251.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/opinion-most-despicable-things-trump-232825251.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 02:47:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thanks to Gov. DeSantis, Floridians face continued risk of swimming in contaminated waters | Opinion]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/thanks-gov-desantis-floridians-face-203358247.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/thanks-gov-desantis-floridians-face-203358247.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 20:33:58 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>