<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 18:31:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 18:31:46 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Does Kamala Harris give Democrats a better chance to win?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Biden, in a navy suit and blue shirt, and Harris, in a white jacket and navy blouse, clasp hands held high between them, both smiling and standing on a balcony." data-caption="President Joe Biden, left, and Vice President Kamala Harris, on the Truman Balcony of the White House, on July 4, 2024. | Tierney L. Cross/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Tierney L. Cross/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2159971779.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>President Joe Biden, left, and Vice President Kamala Harris, on the Truman Balcony of the White House, on July 4, 2024. | Tierney L. Cross/Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Presidential candidates, and their campaigns, are the sum of all in which they exist and what came before them.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Just after he announced he was withdrawing from the 2024 presidential race, President Joe Biden <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1815087772216303933">endorsed</a> his vice president, Kamala Harris, as the nominee in his place — giving her a huge leg up in whatever process could follow from here. But there are still many unknowns about the future of the Democratic ticket. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the past weeks, amid speculation about Biden&#8217;s future on the ticket, two debates have played out. The first big question is whether Harris will be President Joe Biden’s replacement, or if <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024">another Democratic politician</a>, like Govs. Gretchen Whitmer (MI), Josh Shapiro (PA), or Gavin Newsom (CA) would do better. The <em>other</em> question circulating among pundits, pollsters, journalists, strategists, and regular folks is whether Harris would be a stronger presidential contender than Biden.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We can answer this question in a few ways: looking at data on her prospects, her recent performance on the campaign trail, and her past candidacies. Each of these paths give us limited answers, but to borrow a phrase from former Defense Secretary <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/style/rumsfeld-dead-words-known-unknowns/2021/07/01/831175c2-d9df-11eb-bb9e-70fda8c37057_story.html">Donald Rumsfeld</a>, we can still identify a few “known unknowns” that make the future a bit more divinable.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Coconut-pilled</a> backers of a Kamala Harris presidential campaign argue that Harris runs about even or even better than Biden does against former President Donald Trump <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/">in polling</a>; they point to Harris’s performance on the campaign trail so far, making the case against Trump and the American right’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce">plans in Project 2025</a>; and at a base level, they argue that she has been tested on the national stage, while other alternative candidates have not.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Critics of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/7/25/20697783/khive-twitter-kamala-harris-2020-candidate-doug-hive">KHive</a> — as the online superfans of the vice president call themselves — and the VP argue that Harris is still really unpopular with the American public. They argue that the polls don’t actually show that much of an advantage for Harris in battleground states or with the popular vote; they point to her failed 2019 presidential campaign and her tepid vice presidential tenure as proof she’s not a particularly good candidate or politician and would likely run an uneven campaign.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They also argue that Biden’s flaws and foibles are already built into the electorate’s mind, while the chaos and uncertainty of swapping in Harris would expose the Democrats to even more risks (like how voters react to a woman of color as a nominee).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The debate was the roiling undercurrent of the will-he-or-won’t-he <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361597/biden-drop-out-democrats-obama-pelosi-schumer">drama over Biden</a> these last few weeks. How it resolves now that he is off the ticket could have enduring ramifications for both the Democratic Party and the country. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The upsides to swapping in Harris</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris backers have plenty to point to in the aftermath of June’s presidential debate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s the obvious stuff: Harris is younger, can actually string sentences together, and has already been campaigning against Trump this year. These points were once again demonstrated this week —&nbsp;while Biden was forced to recover from Covid at his home in Delaware during the week of the Republican National Convention, Harris was on the trail with North Carolina Democratic Gov. Roy Cooper.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What the data says: </strong>First, a caveat: comparing polling of reality to a hypothetical match-up is always a bit treacherous.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What we can say from head-to-head polling of Harris is that the general trend has gotten a lot better for her. A year ago <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/358559/biden-harris-whitmer-newsom-shapiro-buttigieg-alternative-nomination-candidate-2024">she was underperforming Biden in head-to-head polling against Trump</a> in a variety of surveys. Closer to the debate and right after, she began to perform about evenly. And more recently, in July, a few polls comparing Biden and Harris against Trump in battleground states and nationally have shown Harris even with Biden or slightly ahead of him.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first sign of this change came from <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/02/politics/cnn-poll-post-debate/index.html">CNN’s first post-debate poll</a>, finding the vice president trailing Trump by 2 percentage points (within the margin of error) while Biden trailed by 6 points. And in <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/538/kamala-harris-stronger-candidate-biden/story?id=111656941">FiveThirtyEight’s</a> polls-only post-debate comparison of Harris and Biden vs. Trump, Harris performs slightly better than the president in battleground states <em>— </em>though not in all of them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Recent polling from Pennsylvania and Virginia also shows more positive signs for the vice president: <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/15/us/politics/pennsylvania-virginia-polls-biden-trump.html">New York Times/Siena College</a> polls this month show that while Harris still trails Trump by 1 point in Pennsylvania, that’s a smaller gap than the 3 points that put Trump ahead of Biden there. Both of these results are within the polling’s margin of error, making the race in the state essentially tied. In Virginia, meanwhile, Harris’s lead over Trump is 2 points larger than the lead Biden has over the former president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And a post-assassination attempt <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/en-us/race-presidency-remains-unchanged-wake-assassination-attempt-trump">national poll from Reuters/Ipsos</a> shows a statistically tied presidential contest for either Biden or Harris against Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Under the hood, however, Harris backers can find an additional data point in their column: <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/sites/default/files/ct/news/documents/2024-07/Reuters%20Ipsos%20Post%20Trump%20Assasionation%20Attempt%20Poll%20Topline.pdf">69 percent of respondents think Biden is too old</a>; Harris doesn’t face that concern. And Biden is more unpopular than Harris, something that is consistently true: As of July 18, Biden has a net -17.7 <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/biden-approval-rating/">approval</a> rating in the FiveThirtyEight aggregate. Harris’s <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/approval/kamala-harris/">disapproval</a> is at 11.8. And in RealClearPolitics’ average of favorability ratings, Biden (<a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/favorability/joe-biden">-16.3</a>) is also more unpopular than Harris (<a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/favorability/kamala-harris">-14.9</a>)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What the campaign trail shows: </strong>Harris backers can point to the vice president’s performance on the road this year and argue that she has evolved as a politician since her presidential run in 2019, and especially since the overturning of <em>Roe v. Wade</em> in 2022 —&nbsp;when she became the White House’s go-to surrogate and messenger on reproductive rights.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She has dominated that issue, both in official visits to states where abortion and reproductive rights have been under threat, and also during campaign swings this year that have seen her become more willing to talk about the <a href="https://abc7.com/kamala-harris-friend-high-school-canada/7846815/">personal experiences</a> that pushed her to become a sex crimes prosecutor and be able to connect with voters in a way Biden can’t.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, she has been playing up that past as a prosecutor — something she was not able to do during her last national campaign against fellow Democrats. “Prosecuting the case against Donald Trump” is now a go-to part of her stump speeches, both in talking about his and his party’s record on abortion and in talking about Trump’s convictions and indictments.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the top of the ticket, she would be able to zero in on this approach against an unpopular Republican candidate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What history tells us: </strong>Before her doomed 2020 presidential bid, Harris had a successful electoral record in California: winning statewide races by tacking to the center or simply pointing out how weird or abnormal her opponents were.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Running as a center-left politician was part of her bid during her first statewide race in California — for attorney general —&nbsp;since she was facing a popular moderate Republican during a red-wave year in 2010, and she was viewed as a liberal Bay Area district attorney. She opposed right-wing positions on gay marriage and immigration enforcement, and cast her opponent as an extremist, while also attacking him for not prosecuting more cases, including sex crimes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her 2016 Senate campaign, meanwhile, showed how she’s able to remain on message and be disciplined —&nbsp;winning support from the Democratic establishment, consistently holding a fundraising advantage, and showing that her Democrat opponent was not a serious candidate. There wasn’t much of a policy difference between Harris and her opponent, former Los Angeles District Attorney Steve Cooley, but she was still able to deliver a landslide win.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even her 2020 campaign shows that she’s a pragmatic thinker — not necessarily tied to a specific ideology that influences the way she would approach issues. She fumbled on policy, and couldn’t make a distinctive, proactive case to the Democratic base in the primary, but she doesn’t have to do that now. Even during this cycle, she has shown moments of pragmatism, too — her position on the war in Gaza, for example, put her to the left of Biden on the issue —&nbsp;but she has found ways to speak to young progressives and voters critical of Israel’s approach while still representing the president.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The risks of swapping in Harris</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What the data says: </strong>The major problem in comparing these Harris figures to Biden’s actual standing against Trump is that Biden’s numbers factor in every negative thing that he and his campaign have endured so far. Biden backers would point to the fact that opinions of Harris could still change for the worse as her theoretical campaign becomes not so theoretical anymore, and that her performing about as evenly as Biden against Trump is not that great of a sign when there is more uncertainty about how Harris would even campaign.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On that front, they point to the fact that Harris’s favorability numbers are not that different from Biden’s, and could still get worse. In recent polls, she performs worse than Biden in battleground states like <a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/west-wing-playbook/2024/07/18/so-you-wanted-some-harris-polling-00169524">Michigan</a>, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/kamala-harris-swing-state-poll-donald-trump-1927199">Arizona, and Nevada</a> — losing those states would likely doom a Democratic candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And she doesn’t necessarily do significantly better than Biden when looking at how subgroups of voters feel: She wins the same share of Black voters as Biden in head-to-head matchups with Trump in battleground states, <a href="https://split-ticket.org/2024/07/17/we-polled-black-voters-heres-what-we-found/">per Split-Ticket.org’s polling</a>, and does slightly worse than Biden <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/kamala-harris-biden-stronger-weaker-trump-nbc-news-poll-rcna161520">among white voters</a>, who still make up the majority of voters in swing states and nationally.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What the campaign trail shows: </strong>Taking the Kamala-critical position on the data as is — that there’s essentially no difference according to polls in how Harris performs against Trump than Biden — you are justified in being worried about what the campaign trail might look like.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris has only recently, since 2022, been active on the campaign trail, in part because she’s not the most naturally gifted campaigner or communicator. She has found the issues she excels at championing, but that’s only after going through a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/11/14/politics/kamala-harris-frustrating-start-vice-president/index.html">rocky</a> first <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-60061473">year</a> as <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/11/kamala-harris-first-six-months-vice-president-joe-biden">vice president</a> when her office saw a variety of staff departures, infighting, and missteps in message.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She received media training during that first year in order to get better at talking about the president’s agenda, but still struggled to define her portfolio —&nbsp;facing intense criticism on immigration and the border when that <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361635/kamala-harris-border-czar-immigration-mexico-guatemala-rnc">wasn’t even her original assignment</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/05/opinion/ezra-klein-podcast-kamala-harris.html">Reporters</a> who have been <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/10/magazine/kamala-harris.html">covering</a> her tenure point out that she seems most at home when she’s having more roundtable-style conversations, not necessarily in one-on-one interviews or while giving stump speeches.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris critics also point out that she will struggle to convince voters to see her as a legitimate candidate given biases against her because of her race, her gender, and the general idea that she’s not that plugged into the White House inner circle or aware of the day-to-day business of running the country.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then come the memes. While the genre of <a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Kamala Harris memes</a> has been exploding in popularity recently because of the chaos over Biden’s own candidacy, those jokes start from a kernel of truth: Harris is an awkward communicator. She’s prone to gaffes, to awkward jokes, to tortured analogies or stories, and is generally perceived as easy to mock.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What history tells us</strong>: Harris critics also have plenty to point to when criticizing her electoral history. Her toughest race was her first race, for California attorney general, when she was the worst-performing statewide Democratic candidate on the ballot, winning her seat by about <a href="https://archive.nytimes.com/www.nytimes.com/elections/2010/results/california.html?ref=politics">1 percentage point</a>.<strong> </strong>Read that again. She nearly lost to a Republican in California.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s the context that this was a red-wave year — the 2020 midterm elections were terrible for Democrats. But in California, she essentially had united Democratic support for her campaign, and still came close to failure — while every other Democratic candidate on the ticket performed significantly better.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She cruised to victory during the 2016 Senate race in part because the whole contest was “<a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/11/2016-california-senate-harris-sanchez-jungle-open-primary-reform-214429/">uninspiring</a>,” and neither Harris nor her opponent were able to excite voters during most of the campaign because Harris’s victory was assumed from the start. She also faced an easy, flawed candidate in that race: a wacky US representative <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1uuyTggFWYc">who famously “dabbed”</a> on stage during a debate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And her 2020 presidential contest showed what happens when a candidate lacks clarity about her campaign and reasons for running. She struggled to define herself, and her position on the ideological spectrum, relative to her Democratic rivals. She could not run a disciplined campaign — two rival camps within her operation <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson">pulled the campaign in different directions</a> for much of the primary.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This record shows the legitimate reasons to question whether Harris would be able to make a proactive case for herself —&nbsp;not just a negative case against Trump. She faces the struggle of convincing voters not to blame her for the unpopular results of the Biden-Harris administration, while still thinking of her as presidential material.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s one edge the governors and senators who have been talked about as potential alternatives to Biden have: They wouldn’t carry the same baggage from the Biden administration. Harris will likely be seen as tied to Biden’s legacy,&nbsp;which stands as another reason to look elsewhere.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/risk-opportunity-democrat-kamala-harris-joe-biden-alternative-candidate-nomination-beat-trump</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/risk-opportunity-democrat-kamala-harris-joe-biden-alternative-candidate-nomination-beat-trump</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Paz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 18:27:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden drops out, backs Harris in 2024 race]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2161483504.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden announced on Sunday that he will be stepping down as the Democratic presidential nominee for the 2024 race and will not pursue a second term in the White House. He is set to address the nation later this week.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The news comes after top Democrats, including former President Barack Obama, Nancy Pelosi, and Sen. Chuck Schumer called on Biden to step aside, with <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4774563-donald-trump-joe-biden-2024-election-swing-states/">polls</a> showing Trump leading Biden in major swing states. In recent days, Biden has been off the campaign trail as he has been isolating amid a Covid-19 infection.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Follow here for the latest news, explainers, and analysis.</p>
<ul>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/risk-opportunity-democrat-kamala-harris-joe-biden-alternative-candidate-nomination-beat-trump">Does Kamala Harris give Democrats a better chance to win?</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">Biden just quit the race and endorsed Kamala Harris. What happens now?</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee">Kamala Harris’s strengths — and vulnerabilities — explained</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson">Is Kamala Harris a better candidate now than she was four years ago?</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/358559/biden-harris-whitmer-newsom-shapiro-buttigieg-alternative-nomination-candidate-2024">Do other Democrats actually poll better against Trump than Biden?</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358084/biden-drop-out-lbj-harry-truman">LBJ and Truman knew when to quit. Will Biden?</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357955/biden-age-democrats-nominee-kamala-harris">How Democrats got here</a>
		</li>
	</ul>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/361888/biden-drops-out-kamala-harris-endorsement-dnc-democratic-nominee</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/361888/biden-drops-out-kamala-harris-endorsement-dnc-democratic-nominee</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Shira Tarlo]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 18:04:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden just quit the race and endorsed Kamala Harris. What happens now?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="President Joe Biden, in a navy suit and blue tie, speaks into a pair of microphones from a podium, looking down, with a US flag behind him." data-caption="President Joe Biden is pictured at the  NATO Summit in Washington DC in July, nearly two weeks after his disastrous debate performance set in motion efforts to get him to end his campaign for a second term. | Kent Nishimura/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Kent Nishimura/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2161687527.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>President Joe Biden is pictured at the  NATO Summit in Washington DC in July, nearly two weeks after his disastrous debate performance set in motion efforts to get him to end his campaign for a second term. | Kent Nishimura/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">After weeks of pressure, conjecture, and handwringing at the highest levels of the Democratic Party, President Joe Biden has decided to step aside from the 2024 presidential race.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The president issued a <a href="https://x.com/joebiden/status/1815080881981190320?s=46&amp;t=WDV3NvpmCLI-fO5R13Teug">written statement Sunday afternoon</a>, saying he believes it is in the country&#8217;s best interest for him to step down, adding that he will address the nation later in the week about his decision. Biden’s decision comes after weeks of public and private entreaties from Democrats who have concluded that he is unlikely to defeat former President Donald Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Moments later, Biden released <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1815087772216303933">another statement endorsing Vice President Kamala Harris</a> to take his spot atop the ticket.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&#8220;My very first decision as the party nominee in 2020 was to pick Kamala Harris as my Vice President. And it’s been the best decision I’ve made,&#8221; the statement said. &#8220;Today I want to offer my full support and endorsement for Kamala to be the nominee of our party this year. Democrats — it’s time to come together and beat Trump. Let’s do this.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What is clear is that the presidential contest is entering uncharted territory for the modern era. Since the rise of the modern nomination process in the 1970s, no winner of the primaries has quit the race before the convention. And no major-party nominee has entered the race so close to November.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s worth pausing to appreciate just what a dramatic turn of events this has been. It was just a few short months ago that President Biden <a href="https://6abc.com/2024-super-tuesday-states-primary-results/14492343/">sailed through</a> the primary season with barely any opposition. But now, his party support has collapsed under him to the point where he effectively can’t continue his campaign.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The catalyst for this collapse was Biden’s June 27 debate performance, which will surely now go down as the most catastrophic general election debate in US presidential history. But what the debate actually did was supercharge concerns about Biden’s electoral prospects, stamina, health, and capacity that have long simmered below the surface of Democratic politics.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The doubts about Biden did not begin with the debate, but the debate suddenly made them impossible to ignore — and spurred the party to take action.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What will happen next, though, is far from clear. Some Democrats profess to believe that Biden was a uniquely flawed nominee because of his age, and that a different nominee could perform much better against the <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/favorability/donald-trump/">unpopular Trump</a>. But others are more pessimistic, suspecting that the party faces deeper electoral problems and that any replacement nominee is going to have a very tough road ahead.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Biden plowed ahead with his campaign despite party doubts. The debate made those doubts impossible to ignore.</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the start of Biden’s first term, many in the political world questioned whether he would run for a second, for two reasons: One is his age, since he’s already the oldest US president ever and would be 82 by Inauguration Day. The other is his bad polling numbers; his job approval has been dismal <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/biden-approval-rating/">since late 2021</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Biden doesn’t ever appear to have seriously considered not running. He said <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/biden-reelection-2024/2021/11/20/0779469c-4947-11ec-95dc-5f2a96e00fa3_story.html">from the start</a> of his term that he intended to run again, and when Democrats’ midterm election performance was better than many expected, it seemed to bolster his case that he could. So he made his reelection campaign official <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/04/25/1145679856/biden-president-announcement-2024-running-reelection">in April 2023</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All the party’s rising stars opted against launching a risky primary challenge to an incumbent president — doing otherwise would have earned them intense criticism in the party for dividing Democrats and damaging Biden’s chances in the general election. So Biden easily fended off challenges from the likes of Rep. Dean Phillips (D-MN) and author Marianne Williamson.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But doubts remained. Biden skeptics raised eyebrows at his <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/02/06/media/biden-skipping-super-bowl-interview/index.html">skipping the president’s</a> traditional pre-Super Bowl interview, at his <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/04/21/us/politics/biden-public-appearances-media.html">reluctance</a> to do press conferences, and at a special counsel report’s claims that he <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/2/8/24066529/biden-special-counsel-report-memory">seemed to have</a> a poor memory. In February, New York Times columnist (and Vox co-founder) <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/16/opinion/ezra-klein-biden-audio-essay.html">Ezra Klein caused a stir</a> by writing that Democrats should choose a different nominee at the convention, because Biden did not seem up for the rigors of the campaign.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then, Biden gave a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/03/07/biden-state-of-the-union-2024/">reasonably spirited performance</a> at his State of the Union address in March, temporarily putting those concerns to rest. But it did not improve his polls — by then, he’d consistently trailed Trump nationally and in almost every swing state <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-biden">for months</a>. He looked on track for defeat.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/15/us/politics/trump-biden-debate-june.html">reportedly why</a> Biden’s team made the surprising proposal to debate Trump so early, a very unusual move. The hope was that Biden could, with a vigorous performance, reset the race, refocus attention on Trump, and address concerns about his age again.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The opposite happened: Biden’s halting performance put a spotlight on his capacity to campaign (and serve another four years) that never went away.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He lost the media first.&nbsp;In the hours after the debate, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357746/biden-trump-debate-democrats-replace-dnc">various</a> liberal <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/25/opinion/joe-biden-drop-out.html">commentators</a> called on him <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/28/opinion/joe-biden-tom-friedman.html">to quit</a> the race. Mainstream journalists, sensing scandal and a cover-up, intensely focused on reporting out <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/359024/biden-age-leaks-lapses-polls">Biden’s true condition</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, Biden hoped that he could keep the party on board by doing a flurry of interviews and public events, showing the debate was a one-off. Some of these went <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360124/biden-dropout-defections-obama-pelosi">reasonably well</a>, others <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/17/politics/video/biden-youtube-complex-interview-tapper-lead-digvid">less so</a>. But his <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/18/us/politics/biden-fundraising.html">fundraising plummeted</a>, and the public and private pressure from Democrats urging him to step aside <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/19/us/politics/biden-democrats-campaign.html?partner=slack&amp;smid=sl-share">just kept increasing</a> — until Biden finally saw the writing on the wall.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The big question going forward: Are Democrats’ electoral problems just about Biden?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what happens next?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Obviously, much will depend on who the nominee is, and so far, we don&#8217;t know how that will be determined. The Democratic convention will take place the week of August 19.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there’s another big underlying question that we don’t yet know the answer to. Namely, how much are Democrats’ electoral woes about Joe Biden himself — and how much reflect deeper problems for the party as a whole?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some argue that Democrats are doing fine, and that it’s only Biden that’s been the problem; that voters have soured on the president because of his age or perceived incapacity to serve another four years, and because Trump remains flawed and unpopular, and another Democratic nominee would likely beat him. For instance, Democratic Senate incumbents <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/17/briefing/biden-vs-the-democratic-party.html">are polling significantly better</a> than Biden. That implies to some that with a different name at the top of the ticket, the party would be in great shape.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Others argue that Democrats’ problems will likely outlast Biden. Unhappiness with inflation under Biden, as well as unfolding foreign tumult<strong>,</strong> may have convinced voters that Trump wasn’t so bad after all. Public opinion on <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/07/the-changes-in-vibes-why-did-they-happen.html">key issues</a> has moved right. And there <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-whitmer">isn’t</a> much <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-newsom">polling</a> showing any possible Democratic <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-harris">alternative</a> beating Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some of these pessimists still believe it was worth pushing out Biden since he had little prospect of turning things around, but they emphasize that any replacement would be the underdog and face a very tough road ahead.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All we know for sure now is that Democrats have decided to roll the dice, ditching their unpopular nominee in hopes of improving their odds in a contest they were on track to lose.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Prokop]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 18:02:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden drops reelection bid and endorses Kamala Harris for president]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="Photo illustration of President Joe Biden." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f106pPZLG4fFIBLoSmPAhekIJKk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73473412/STK174_PRES_BIDEN_B.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Cath Virginia / The Verge | Photos from Getty Images, Anna Moneymaker</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="X7xKVh">President Joseph R. Biden has dropped his re-election bid. Biden announced his decision with a <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1815080881981190320">letter posted to social media</a> after a growing movement among Democrats and the media called for him to step aside. Biden is endorsing Vice President Kamala Harris as his replacement, <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1815087772216303933">writing</a>, “Today I want to offer my full support and endorsement for Kamala to be the nominee of our party this year.”</p>
<p id="Ed4FvH"> Here is the text from Biden’s letter about declining the nomination:</p>
<blockquote>
<p id="jir456">My Fellow Americans,</p>
<p id="T1P8n6">Over the past three and a half years, we have made great progress as a Nation.</p>
<p id="P6Ywqt">Today, America has the strongest economy in the world. We’ve made historic investments in rebuilding our Nation, in lowering prescription drug costs for seniors, and in expanding...</p>
</blockquote>
  <p>
    <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/21/24195289/biden-drops-out-presidential-election-race">Continue reading&hellip;</a>
  </p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/21/24195289/biden-drops-out-presidential-election-race</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/21/24195289/biden-drops-out-presidential-election-race</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gaby Del Valle]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 17:56:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden drops out of 2024 presidential election, endorses Kamala Harris as Democratic nominee]]></title><description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden made the decision to quit the election race against Donald Trump after weeks of pressure by a growing number of Democrats.]]></description><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/07/21/biden-to-drop-out-of-2024-presidential-race.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/07/21/biden-to-drop-out-of-2024-presidential-race.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 18:28:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden drops out of 2024 presidential election, endorses Kamala Harris as Democratic nominee - CNBC]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNuYmMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMjEvYmlkZW4tdG8tZHJvcC1vdXQtb2YtMjAyNC1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtcmFjZS5odG1s0gFUaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuY25iYy5jb20vYW1wLzIwMjQvMDcvMjEvYmlkZW4tdG8tZHJvcC1vdXQtb2YtMjAyNC1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtcmFjZS5odG1s?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden drops out of 2024 presidential election, endorses Kamala Harris as Democratic nominee</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiamh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzLzIwMjQtZWxlY3Rpb24vcHJlc2lkZW50LWpvZS1iaWRlbi1kcm9wcy0yMDI0LXByZXNpZGVudGlhbC1yYWNlLXJjbmExNTk4NjfSAStodHRwczovL3d3dy5uYmNuZXdzLmNvbS9uZXdzL2FtcC9yY25hMTU5ODY3?oc=5" target="_blank">President Joe Biden drops out of 2024 presidential race</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndhc2hpbmd0b25wb3N0LmNvbS9wb2xpdGljcy8yMDI0LzA3LzIxL2JpZGVuLW1hbmNoaW4tcGVsb3NpLWRyb3Atb3V0L9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden’s crisis deepens as both parties plan for his potential exit</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMia2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL2JpZGVuLWVuZHMtYmlkLXNlY29uZC10ZXJtLXdoaXRlLWhvdXNlLWhlLWRyb3BzLW91dC1oaXMtMjAyNC1yZW1hdGNoLXRydW1w0gFvaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZm94bmV3cy5jb20vcG9saXRpY3MvYmlkZW4tZW5kcy1iaWQtc2Vjb25kLXRlcm0td2hpdGUtaG91c2UtaGUtZHJvcHMtb3V0LWhpcy0yMDI0LXJlbWF0Y2gtdHJ1bXAuYW1w?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden ends bid for second term in White House as he drops out of his 2024 rematch with Trump</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiQ2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMjEvdXMvcG9saXRpY3MvYmlkZW4tZHJvcHMtb3V0Lmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden Drops Out of Race, Scrambling the Campaign for the White House</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNuYmMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMjEvYmlkZW4tdG8tZHJvcC1vdXQtb2YtMjAyNC1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtcmFjZS5odG1s0gFUaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuY25iYy5jb20vYW1wLzIwMjQvMDcvMjEvYmlkZW4tdG8tZHJvcC1vdXQtb2YtMjAyNC1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtcmFjZS5odG1s?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNuYmMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMjEvYmlkZW4tdG8tZHJvcC1vdXQtb2YtMjAyNC1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtcmFjZS5odG1s0gFUaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuY25iYy5jb20vYW1wLzIwMjQvMDcvMjEvYmlkZW4tdG8tZHJvcC1vdXQtb2YtMjAyNC1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtcmFjZS5odG1s?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 17:53:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel shoots down a missile fired from Yemen hours after a deadly Israeli strike on Houthi rebels - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3Mvd29ybGQvaXNyYWVsLXNob290cy1kb3duLW1pc3NpbGUtZmlyZWQtZnJvbS15ZW1lbi1yY25hMTYyOTA10gEraHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmJjbmV3cy5jb20vbmV3cy9hbXAvcmNuYTE2MjkwNQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel shoots down a missile fired from Yemen hours after a deadly Israeli strike on Houthi rebels</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2lDOGRTQkRCRmNmcnktOTgyeVlDZ0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3Mvd29ybGQvaXNyYWVsLXNob290cy1kb3duLW1pc3NpbGUtZmlyZWQtZnJvbS15ZW1lbi1yY25hMTYyOTA10gEraHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmJjbmV3cy5jb20vbmV3cy9hbXAvcmNuYTE2MjkwNQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3Mvd29ybGQvaXNyYWVsLXNob290cy1kb3duLW1pc3NpbGUtZmlyZWQtZnJvbS15ZW1lbi1yY25hMTYyOTA10gEraHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmJjbmV3cy5jb20vbmV3cy9hbXAvcmNuYTE2MjkwNQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 15:42:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Secret Service chief noted a ‘zero fail mission.’ After Trump rally, she’s facing calls to resign - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidGh0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL3RydW1wLWFzc2Fzc2luYXRpb24tYXR0ZW1wdC1zZWNyZXQtc2VydmljZS1jaGVhdGxlLWJpZGVuLTQ4ZDM4NDA1N2E4OTRiNzE4NTlmOTQ1MDM0MDkyOTAy0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service chief noted a ‘zero fail mission.’ After Trump rally, she’s facing calls to resign</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMjAvdXMvcG9saXRpY3Mvc2VjcmV0LXNlcnZpY2UtdHJ1bXAtc2hvb3RpbmcuaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service Says It Denied Earlier Trump Requests for More Federal Resources</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiamh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnRlbGVncmFwaC5jby51ay93b3JsZC1uZXdzLzIwMjQvMDcvMjEvc2VjcmV0LXNlcnZpY2UtcmVmdXNlZC1pbmNyZWFzZS10cnVtcC1zZWN1cml0eS1zaG9vdGluZy_SAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service admits it refused requests to increase Donald Trump's security before shooting</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Telegraph</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMic2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3NlY3JldC1zZXJ2aWNlLWV4cGxhbmF0aW9uLWNvbnRpbnVlcy1ldm9sdmUtb25lLXdlZWstYWZ0ZXItYXR0ZW1wdGVkLWFzc2Fzc2luYXRpb27SAXdodHRwczovL3d3dy5mb3huZXdzLmNvbS9wb2xpdGljcy9zZWNyZXQtc2VydmljZS1leHBsYW5hdGlvbi1jb250aW51ZXMtZXZvbHZlLW9uZS13ZWVrLWFmdGVyLWF0dGVtcHRlZC1hc3Nhc3NpbmF0aW9uLmFtcA?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service explanation continues to evolve one week after attempted assassination</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNuYmMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMjEvdHJ1bXAtc2hvb3Rpbmctc2VjcmV0LXNlcnZpY2UtZGVuaWVkLXNlY3VyaXR5Lmh0bWzSAVZodHRwczovL3d3dy5jbmJjLmNvbS9hbXAvMjAyNC8wNy8yMS90cnVtcC1zaG9vdGluZy1zZWNyZXQtc2VydmljZS1kZW5pZWQtc2VjdXJpdHkuaHRtbA?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service says it denied some Trump requests for more security, walking back previous story</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidGh0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL3RydW1wLWFzc2Fzc2luYXRpb24tYXR0ZW1wdC1zZWNyZXQtc2VydmljZS1jaGVhdGxlLWJpZGVuLTQ4ZDM4NDA1N2E4OTRiNzE4NTlmOTQ1MDM0MDkyOTAy0gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidGh0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL3RydW1wLWFzc2Fzc2luYXRpb24tYXR0ZW1wdC1zZWNyZXQtc2VydmljZS1jaGVhdGxlLWJpZGVuLTQ4ZDM4NDA1N2E4OTRiNzE4NTlmOTQ1MDM0MDkyOTAy0gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 16:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Democratic consensus solidifies around Harris, should Biden step aside - CNN]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8yMC9wb2xpdGljcy9kZW1vY3JhdGljLWNvbnNlbnN1cy1oYXJyaXMtc2hvdWxkLWJpZGVuLXN0ZXAtYXNpZGUvaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Democratic consensus solidifies around Harris, should Biden step aside</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL3VzL3dpdGgta2FtYWxhLWhhcnJpcy1kZW1vY3JhdHMtd291bGQtYmV0LWFnYWluc3QtdXMtaGlzdG9yeS1zZXhpc20tcmFjaXNtLTIwMjQtMDctMjEv0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">With Kamala Harris, Democrats would bet against US history of sexism, racism</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnVzYXRvZGF5LmNvbS9zdG9yeS9uZXdzL3BvbGl0aWNzL2VsZWN0aW9ucy8yMDI0LzA3LzIwL2thbWFsYS1oYXJyaXMtYmlkZW4tYmlvLWFtZXJpY2EtcmVhZHkvNzQ0NzE2NTEwMDcv0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">As President Joe Biden steps aside, would America be ready for President Kamala Harris?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">USA TODAY</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZ2h0dHBzOi8vbmV3cy5za3kuY29tL3N0b3J5L3doby1pcy1rYW1hbGEtaGFycmlzLXVzLXZpY2UtcHJlc2lkZW50LWFuZC1mYXZvdXJlZC1iaWRlbi1zdWNjZXNzb3ItMTMxODEwMTfSAWtodHRwczovL25ld3Muc2t5LmNvbS9zdG9yeS9hbXAvd2hvLWlzLWthbWFsYS1oYXJyaXMtdXMtdmljZS1wcmVzaWRlbnQtYW5kLWZhdm91cmVkLWJpZGVuLXN1Y2Nlc3Nvci0xMzE4MTAxNw?oc=5" target="_blank">Kamala Harris - US vice president and favoured Biden successor</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Sky News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiK2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL3ZpZGVvLzYzNTg3NTI3NDUxMTLSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Skipping over Kamala Harris would be a ‘catastrophic mistake’: Lindy Li</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8yMC9wb2xpdGljcy9kZW1vY3JhdGljLWNvbnNlbnN1cy1oYXJyaXMtc2hvdWxkLWJpZGVuLXN0ZXAtYXNpZGUvaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8yMC9wb2xpdGljcy9kZW1vY3JhdGljLWNvbnNlbnN1cy1oYXJyaXMtc2hvdWxkLWJpZGVuLXN0ZXAtYXNpZGUvaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[In his first campaign rally with Vance, Trump says he took 'a bullet for democracy' - NPR]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5wci5vcmcvMjAyNC8wNy8yMS9ueC1zMS01MDQ3ODI1L2RvbmFsZC10cnVtcC1qZC12YW5jZS1taWNoaWdhbi1yYWxsedIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">In his first campaign rally with Vance, Trump says he took 'a bullet for democracy'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiYmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm1saXZlLmNvbS9wb2xpdGljcy8yMDI0LzA3LzUtdGFrZWF3YXlzLWZyb20tdHJ1bXBzLXJhbGx5LWluLWdyYW5kLXJhcGlkcy1taWNoaWdhbi5odG1s0gFxaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubWxpdmUuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzLzIwMjQvMDcvNS10YWtlYXdheXMtZnJvbS10cnVtcHMtcmFsbHktaW4tZ3JhbmQtcmFwaWRzLW1pY2hpZ2FuLmh0bWw_b3V0cHV0VHlwZT1hbXA?oc=5" target="_blank">5 takeaways from Trump’s rally in Grand Rapids, Michigan</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MLive.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiV2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8yMC93b3JsZC92aWRlby9kYW5pZWwtZGFsZS1mYWN0LWNoZWNrLXRydW1wLXJhbGx5LW5yLWRpZ3ZpZNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Daniel Dale fact checks Trump’s claim crime rate in the US is on the rise</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFodHRwczovL3d3dy5mb3gxN29ubGluZS5jb20vbmV3cy9uYXRpb25hbC1wb2xpdGljcy9hbWVyaWNhLXZvdGVzL21vdG9yY2FkZS1wcmVwLXJldGlyZWQtbXNwLWRldGVjdGl2ZS1zZWNyZXQtc2VydmljZS1saWFpc29uLWxheXMtaXQtYWxsLW91dNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">MOTORCADE PREP: Retired MSP Detective, Secret Service liaison lays it all out</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">FOX 17 West Michigan News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnZhbml0eWZhaXIuY29tL25ld3Mvc3RvcnkvdHJ1bXAtdG9vay1hLWJ1bGxldC1mb3ItZGVtb2NyYWN5LWluLWZpcnN0LXJhbGx5LXNpbmNlLWFzc2Fzc2luYXRpb24tYXR0ZW1wdNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Donald Trump Says He “Took a Bullet for Democracy” In First Rally Since Assassination Attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Vanity Fair</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5wci5vcmcvMjAyNC8wNy8yMS9ueC1zMS01MDQ3ODI1L2RvbmFsZC10cnVtcC1qZC12YW5jZS1taWNoaWdhbi1yYWxsedIBAA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5wci5vcmcvMjAyNC8wNy8yMS9ueC1zMS01MDQ3ODI1L2RvbmFsZC10cnVtcC1qZC12YW5jZS1taWNoaWdhbi1yYWxsedIBAA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 16:05:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netanyahu comes to Washington as Biden reels and Trump soars - The Washington Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndhc2hpbmd0b25wb3N0LmNvbS93b3JsZC8yMDI0LzA3LzIxL2lzcmFlbC1uZXRhbnlhaHUtZGMtdmlzaXQtYmlkZW4tdHJ1bXAv0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Netanyahu comes to Washington as Biden reels and Trump soars</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFodHRwczovL3d3dy5oaW5kdXN0YW50aW1lcy5jb20vdmlkZW9zL3dvcmxkLW5ld3MvbmV0YW55YWh1LWZsZWVpbmctdG8tdXNhLWFzLWhvdXRoaXMtZmlyZS1taXNzaWxlcy1hdC1pc3JhZWwtYXBwb2ludHMtYWN0aW5nLXBtLWFtaWQtd2FyLXRocmVhdC0xMDE3MjE1ODI2NzgwNzYuaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Netanyahu 'Fleeing' To USA As Houthis Fire Missiles At Israel, Appoints 'Acting PM' Amid War Threat</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Hindustan Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFodHRwczovL3d3dy5oYWFyZXR6LmNvbS9pc3JhZWwtbmV3cy9oYWFyZXR6LXRvZGF5LzIwMjQtMDctMjEvdHktYXJ0aWNsZS8uaGlnaGxpZ2h0L2hvdy10aHJlZS1kZW1vY3JhdHMtcGF2ZWQtdGhlLXdheS1mb3ItbmV0YW55YWh1cy10b3RhbC12aWN0b3J5LWluLXdhc2hpbmd0b24vMDAwMDAxOTAtZDVjNS1kNTQ4LWEzYmEtZmZjZmJjODMwMDAw0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">How Three Democrats Paved the Way for Netanyahu's 'Total Victory' in Washington</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Haaretz</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiamh0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vb3Bpbmlvbi9pbnRlcm5hdGlvbmFsLzQ3ODE5OTktNS10aGluZ3MtY29uZ3Jlc3MtbWF5LW5vdC1rbm93LWFib3V0LWJlbmphbWluLW5ldGFueWFodS_SAW5odHRwczovL3RoZWhpbGwuY29tL29waW5pb24vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC80NzgxOTk5LTUtdGhpbmdzLWNvbmdyZXNzLW1heS1ub3Qta25vdy1hYm91dC1iZW5qYW1pbi1uZXRhbnlhaHUvYW1wLw?oc=5" target="_blank">5 things Congress may not know about Benjamin Netanyahu</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnlhaG9vLmNvbS9uZXdzL21pa2Utam9obnNvbi1tYWtlcy13aWxkLXRocmVhdC0xNjMyNDgzMjUuaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Mike Johnson Makes Wild Threat Against Democrats Over Netanyahu Visit</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo! Voices</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndhc2hpbmd0b25wb3N0LmNvbS93b3JsZC8yMDI0LzA3LzIxL2lzcmFlbC1uZXRhbnlhaHUtZGMtdmlzaXQtYmlkZW4tdHJ1bXAv0gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndhc2hpbmd0b25wb3N0LmNvbS93b3JsZC8yMDI0LzA3LzIxL2lzcmFlbC1uZXRhbnlhaHUtZGMtdmlzaXQtYmlkZW4tdHJ1bXAv0gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 18:06:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fighting in southern Gaza, Israeli strikes hit central areas - Reuters]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL21pZGRsZS1lYXN0L2ZpZ2h0aW5nLXJhZ2VzLXNvdXRoZXJuLWdhemEtaXNyYWVsaS1zdHJpa2VzLWhpdC1jZW50cmFsLWFyZWFzLTIwMjQtMDctMjEv0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Fighting in southern Gaza, Israeli strikes hit central areas</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiNWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lmpwb3N0LmNvbS9pc3JhZWwtaGFtYXMtd2FyL2FydGljbGUtODExMjc00gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">IDF sheds new light on IAF activity, intelligence before Deif strike</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Jerusalem Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiemh0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vaG9tZW5ld3MvYXAvYXAtaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC9hcC1pc3JhZWxzLWxhdGVzdC1haXJzdHJpa2VzLWluLWdhemEta2lsbC1hdC1sZWFzdC0xNS1pbmNsdWRpbmctY2hpbGRyZW4v0gF-aHR0cHM6Ly90aGVoaWxsLmNvbS9ob21lbmV3cy9hcC9hcC1pbnRlcm5hdGlvbmFsL2FwLWlzcmFlbHMtbGF0ZXN0LWFpcnN0cmlrZXMtaW4tZ2F6YS1raWxsLWF0LWxlYXN0LTE1LWluY2x1ZGluZy1jaGlsZHJlbi9hbXAv?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel’s latest airstrikes in Gaza kill at least 15 including children</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnZvYW5ld3MuY29tL2EvcGFsZXN0aW5pYW5zLWRpZS1pbi1nYXphLXN0cmlrZXMtYXMtY2Vhc2UtZmlyZS10YWxrcy1ncmluZC1vbi83NzA1OTUzLmh0bWzSAWZodHRwczovL3d3dy52b2FuZXdzLmNvbS9hbXAvcGFsZXN0aW5pYW5zLWRpZS1pbi1nYXphLXN0cmlrZXMtYXMtY2Vhc2UtZmlyZS10YWxrcy1ncmluZC1vbi83NzA1OTUzLmh0bWw?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel kills dozens in Gaza bombardment, strikes in Lebanon</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Voice of America - VOA News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNic25ld3MuY29tL25ld3MvaXNyYWVsaS1haXJzdHJpa2VzLWdhemEtcmVmdWdlZS1jYW1wLWNlYXNlLWZpcmUtdGFsa3MtZ3JpbmQtb24v0gFgaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuY2JzbmV3cy5jb20vYW1wL25ld3MvaXNyYWVsaS1haXJzdHJpa2VzLWdhemEtcmVmdWdlZS1jYW1wLWNlYXNlLWZpcmUtdGFsa3MtZ3JpbmQtb24v?oc=5" target="_blank">Israeli airstrikes kill at least 13 people in Gaza refugee camps as cease-fire talks grind on</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL21pZGRsZS1lYXN0L2ZpZ2h0aW5nLXJhZ2VzLXNvdXRoZXJuLWdhemEtaXNyYWVsaS1zdHJpa2VzLWhpdC1jZW50cmFsLWFyZWFzLTIwMjQtMDctMjEv0gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL21pZGRsZS1lYXN0L2ZpZ2h0aW5nLXJhZ2VzLXNvdXRoZXJuLWdhemEtaXNyYWVsaS1zdHJpa2VzLWhpdC1jZW50cmFsLWFyZWFzLTIwMjQtMDctMjEv0gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 17:19:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan proposes document on principles of peace before full deal with Armenia]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/azerbaijan-proposes-document-principles-peace-102821683.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/azerbaijan-proposes-document-principles-peace-102821683.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 10:28:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Outside the RNC, small Milwaukee businesses and their regulars tried to salvage a sluggish week]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/outside-rnc-small-milwaukee-businesses-040724102.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/outside-rnc-small-milwaukee-businesses-040724102.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 04:07:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[As Georgia presses on with 'Russia-style' laws, its citizens describe a country on the brink]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/georgia-presses-russia-style-laws-040342340.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/georgia-presses-russia-style-laws-040342340.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 04:03:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>