<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 08:50:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 08:50:28 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Labor claims Aukus nuclear waste dumping issue just a Greens scare campaign]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Legislation before Australian parliament covers the way the country’s nuclear-powered submarine program will be regulated</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2024/sep/11/australia-politics-live-dutton-cut-green-tape-miners-mining-king-royal-visit-plans-asylum-seekers-universities-student-caps-vaping">Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates</a></li><li>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl">breaking news email</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></li></ul><p>The Albanese government has bowed to pressure to close an Aukus loophole, insisting newly revealed changes will ensure Australia will not become <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/apr/02/poison-portal-us-and-uk-could-send-nuclear-waste-to-australia-under-aukus-inquiry-told">a dumping ground</a> for nuclear waste from US and UK submarines.</p><p>The Greens argued the government’s latest amendments did not go far enough and it was becoming increasingly clear the Aukus security pact was “sinking”.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed">Sign up for Guardian Australia’s breaking news email</a></strong></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/sep/11/labor-aukus-nuclear-waste-loophole-greens">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/sep/11/labor-aukus-nuclear-waste-loophole-greens</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/sep/11/labor-aukus-nuclear-waste-loophole-greens</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 08:40:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rachel Reeves says steel is ‘vital part’ of economy before statement about Port Talbot’s Tata plant – UK politics live]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>British steel industry braced for 2,500 job cuts at the Port Talbot steelworks </p><p>At the briefing with Scottish lobby journalists yesterday, <strong>Keir Starmer</strong> also said he will lead a new council of the nations and regions, which will involve the first ministers of the three devolved administrations. The new body will replace the joint ministerial councils, which previously operated and brought ministers from Edinburgh, Cardiff and Belfast together with UK government ministers.</p><p>Starmer said that, under the old system, the PM “didn’t bother turning up” and the UK government (also, in effect, England) was represented by the chancellor of the duchy of Lancaster (Michael Gove). Starmer said the new body would be:</p><p>A proper council, where Scotland is properly represented by the first minister in a formal setting with me and the other first ministers, meeting on a regular basis, where we can look at challenges and opportunities together.</p><p>There is massive hope in this, what we want to do, the change we want to bring about is massive.</p><p>It is to make sure the economy is not only growing but growing across the whole of the United Kingdom, including in Scotland, which will be measured in living standards rising, people feeling better off in a material way.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/sep/11/pmqs-keir-starmer-labour-rishi-sunak-conservatives-latest-uk-politics-live-updates">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/sep/11/pmqs-keir-starmer-labour-rishi-sunak-conservatives-latest-uk-politics-live-updates</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/sep/11/pmqs-keir-starmer-labour-rishi-sunak-conservatives-latest-uk-politics-live-updates</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 08:41:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine targets Moscow in biggest drone attack yet]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/russia-destroys-ukraine-launched-drone-234940024.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/russia-destroys-ukraine-launched-drone-234940024.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 23:49:40 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>