<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 21:15:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 21:15:21 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[What the death of Hezbollah’s leader means for the Middle East]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="An Iranian woman wrapped in a flag holds a photo of a man with a gray beard, as well as the flags of Palestine and Iran." data-caption="An Iranian woman holds a photo of Hassan Nasrallah and the flags of Palestine and Iran on October 2, 2024, in Tehran, Iran. | Majid Saeedi/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Majid Saeedi/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2176219132.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,93.2,83.499742183472" />
	<figcaption>An Iranian woman holds a photo of Hassan Nasrallah and the flags of Palestine and Iran on October 2, 2024, in Tehran, Iran. | Majid Saeedi/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Israel successfully killed Hezbollah’s longtime leader with an airstrike in Beirut last week, part of a flurry of attacks in its ongoing offensive against Lebanon that has since <a href="https://www.vox.com/israel/375125/lebanon-hezbollah-israel-iran-invasion-gaza">escalated to an invasion</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hassan Nasrallah, 64, had led the militant organization for over three decades and oversaw its transformation from militia group to powerful political organization in Lebanon. His death, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/middle-east/israel-targeted-hassan-nasrallah-the-fierce-islamist-behind-hezbollahs-rise-3acf635b">according to Wall Street Journal reporter Jared Malsin</a>, leaves the group with a significant leadership void. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nasrallah was key to Hezbollah’s rise as the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/middle-east/israel-targeted-hassan-nasrallah-the-fierce-islamist-behind-hezbollahs-rise-3acf635b">world’s most powerful nonstate armed force</a>, a role it pursued with the backing of Iran. The group, which has been designated a foreign terrorist organization by the US, used suicide bombings, kidnappings, and missile strikes to challenge American and Israeli influence in the region, in addition to its political heft. Nasrallah was known for his charisma and fierce determination, and his speeches were followed closely throughout the Arab world, not just in Lebanon.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He was equally admired and detested in the region for Hezbollah’s role in standing up against — and at times becoming — an invading force.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Malsin, Middle East correspondent for the Wall Street Journal, talked with <em>Today, Explained</em> host Sean Rameswaram about Nasrallah’s rise to power and what his death means for the future of Hezbollah.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Below is an excerpt of their conversation, edited for length and clarity. There’s much more in the full podcast, so listen to <em>Today, Explained</em> wherever you get your podcasts, including <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/today-explained/id1346207297">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://podcasts.google.com/feed/aHR0cHM6Ly9yc3MuYXJ0MTkuY29tL3RvZGF5LWV4cGxhaW5lZA==">Google Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3pXx5SXzXwJxnf4A5pWN2A">Spotify</a>, and <a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/vox/today-explained">Stitcher</a>.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Jared Malsin</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hassan Nasrallah, the secretary general of Hezbollah, was one of the most important figures in the Middle East. He became the leader of Hezbollah in 1992 and since then has led this transformation of Hezbollah from a militia group into a powerful political organization that has elected MPs to the Lebanese Parliament, that has members of the cabinet, and is also the most important arm of Iranian influence in the region. On the one side, he was a charismatic leader who was seen as one of the few leaders in the Middle East who stood up to Israel militarily. On the other side, he was labeled a terrorist by the United States and Israel. So there&#8217;s going to be a lot of people celebrating his death and a lot of people mourning him.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Sean Rameswaram</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Can you tell us how he got to be that towering figure? Where does his story begin?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Jared Malsin</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">His story begins in the early 1980s with the formation of Hezbollah. Israel invaded Lebanon in 1982. At that time, this was a small group that was operating in cells and didn&#8217;t even announce its presence publicly for a few years. In 1978 and ’79, you have the Iranian Revolution where there was an uprising against the Shah of Iran that was just an earthquake that shook the region. Nasrallah studied in Iran, rubbed shoulders with a lot of people who were involved in that movement, and there was kind of this awakening of ordinary people protesting in Iran could overthrow the Shah of Iran. It was this idea of “We can do anything.” And he returned to Lebanon where he went into this guerrilla movement. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The other thing to explain why Nasrallah was so important is that he was a charismatic public speaker. Every time he went on TV, it was an event. I have seen this over the course of more than a decade of reporting in the Middle East — when he would get on TV here in Lebanon, Palestinians, people in Egypt and Jordan, listened to what he said.  He would give these speeches where everyone is hanging on his every word. He liked to crack jokes — [for instance] during the Bush administration, he&#8217;s talking about John Bolton, and he says, “This is the American ambassador, Bolton, or whatever his name is … He&#8217;s a very funny-looking guy with his mustache …” and so on. And then there&#8217;s uproarious laughter. In addition to being the leader of the world&#8217;s most heavily armed militia and one of the most powerful political parties in Lebanon, [Nasrallah] also had this ability to directly connect with the public that broadened his appeal.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Sean Rameswaram</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Can you tell us about some of his biggest wins in his time in power?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Jared Malsin</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s one main win and it&#8217;s the Israeli withdrawal from southern Lebanon in 2000, which was the culmination of this 18 years of insurgency that Hezbollah had been fighting against the Israelis. They launched these attacks on Israeli forces, there was an insurgency, and then the Israelis withdrew without a peace treaty. And no one else in the region was able to do that. Israel has a qualitative military edge over every other country around it. They have nuclear weapons, they have fighter jets. And here is a group of guerrillas who, with the help of Iran but fighting with small arms and so on, was able to achieve that. And that inspired a lot of people.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The other one is 2006 when Hezbollah captured some Israeli soldiers in a raid across the border and took them back into Lebanon. It bordered on military disaster for the Israelis because they went into Lebanon. Israeli military officials will tell you that they were unprepared at that time for what they found, which is that you had a group fighting for their own country. They know the terrain. They had anti-tank missiles and were able to pierce the armor of more than 20 tanks.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Sean Rameswaram</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That might be why Nasrallah will be missed in the coming months, years. But you also alluded to people celebrating his death. Why will people be celebrating, including not just Israelis, but Arabs in the region and around the world?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Jared Malsin</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Right, this is really important. You saw over the weekend, for example, people celebrating in rebel-held Syria. Nasrallah decided to send his troops into Syria to fight [alongside] the regime because they made a decision to side with these states that are backing [them] even if it meant siding with a brutal regime that was repressing its own people. It was a turning point, where instead of fighting as a guerrilla force against an invading army, they were acting as an invading army, fighting against the Syrian rebels. That&#8217;s why across the region it&#8217;s incredibly polarized. There&#8217;s going to be a lot of people celebrating his death and saying good riddance. Even here in Lebanon, for example, there are people who absolutely loved him. There are people who absolutely hated him. And I think there are a lot of people who feel genuinely mixed about it.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Sean Rameswaram</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Is there another Nasrallah waiting in the wings? Do we know what comes next for Hezbollah?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Jared Malsin</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We don&#8217;t know yet. They have not named a successor yet, but there have been a whole series of senior Hezbollah leaders who have been killed in the last few months. So we&#8217;re talking about close to a generation of senior leaders, founding members of the group that have already been killed.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Sean Rameswaram</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You know, we had a <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/0tB0OoPOCWd2ZvJ5UIankY">guest on the show last week</a> [Nick Paton Walsh], who said it&#8217;s important to remember that “destroying their adversary&#8217;s capabilities in the immediate future doesn&#8217;t leave you safe in the longer term, because dead men have sons who come back more angry.”&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Jared Malsin</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s no wiping out Hezbollah. We&#8217;ve seen this with the war in Gaza, with Hamas, which is a much smaller, much less well-armed, less well-trained group. It has been able to outlast a massive Israeli military operation in a tiny place, the Gaza Strip. Hezbollah is a larger group that is much more heavily armed, has many more advantages in terms of geography, in terms of its ability to re-arm itself, and that has a history of regenerating over the years. So over the long term, Hezbollah isn&#8217;t going to go anywhere, even if it is significantly weakened.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast/375510/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-airstrike-hassan-nasrallah</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast/375510/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-airstrike-hassan-nasrallah</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Peter.Balonon-Rosen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 21:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thursday Briefing: Israeli Troops Clashed with Hezbollah]]></title><description><![CDATA[Plus, what we learned from fashion month.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/02/briefing/israel-hezbollah-debate-ukraine.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/02/briefing/israel-hezbollah-debate-ukraine.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 21:02:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bombshell immunity filing details Trump's alleged 'increasingly desperate' bid to overturn 2020 election - ABC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNcDFhVVlaXzNEc3JuT0hBOUpxY1lnWmZNNURXSWNmXzNJNHJ6dW5XTFdkNC1hdzh4anpDdnliNGFfUUZfM2o1N2lQM2p0RzYzQVdoaDVOSmRlZVFhdG1ITlJBUnNxbVpFalpOMWliSThXWWRhQ1hvNGxzV1JZMV85Yy1jc3pYLUxhcXJoeEZ1VVBxVkktTjJESW5xZEQtak5RdG9VQklrYUZtQlFRTUHSAbMBQVVfeXFMUER1M3RSNi1WMzJwbldKY0ZwbFRGeWhtLVNDZzE5YU9lS0w3b181enUzZGhES2k2THc5TWg1MFBYZzhRWkZoZnlTMEpDWjFFUWJxa0tEM2JQYXpad2E1WGVOckRoTDJ4N1lqWFlkSk8tdmlvSEVRU09Ic3RfV1hva3F3b1E2MzYtZDBOajFyWUtPVzNVV2ozdHRZaldxY0NBNEFqdzVFYWlOSWNTMkVFVHExek0?oc=5" target="_blank">Bombshell immunity filing details Trump's alleged 'increasingly desperate' bid to overturn 2020 election</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxORUNaOUoxQjNuQzRWVjJEZVNNRFZFWlNSZk12NXFIa2tseF9VRVc3RVkzaXNsNWR0TWRmV0dmVlFsZDJNdzhxdUhLTWZBTm1vZjA1QjQ3bEJUTlpUbmVHMXFBU1NZZVdaSk5HRUJTbzR5Vl9uTDgycHFTZERObWlFQ0UtdTQ3Sms3aVMweExkMEo0UQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Judge Unseals New Evidence in Federal Election Case Against Trump</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxOUXRJbjdtM2E1eXlsU2dNal9nWjFMOWRLQVhETzg3am5kdlNObS1zc1hvaEh1MG9RZEdkQ1A0RFZ4dFBLbVRLc042RGVYdXdfVVpxeFdXclIyUHhHdThxRzNFNjZLbTRnVHo2UXQ3dURpbEZuOGpfLWRBMzNISm1MWmVTeUFGVlZq0gF_QVVfeXFMTjN3VGdaWjh1ZkJYSlNidDN0ODJIXzFlMHNYZkZ5cFFxOWRmeEs3LXJWU2Z5bzVaamhkYTBhdnZaSDZ1SXZkeWd3YnZIRmxPZVFUbHlsR1BxUUlnX05IandqV1NEVFZobVRJTTB3RlZvWjE4MmwtcXVLQVVOY1JuMA?oc=5" target="_blank">Special counsel Jack Smith provides fullest picture yet of his 2020 election case against Trump in new filing</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOdXZPci1YM3JJS3pzY2JReDRyWmVoZTFGcXVsWm5nRTBCc0RhRnVuM1EwZUN1VUNHVEtvVzdTTkVYVU9kRE1IN2NZUE1WX1V4X0VUYzRBb3IwNDFzMTVnSVRIZnFDTm1VczBJLS02WVF5VlliOWg0S2NoLUxiWVFyUFJFV1I4NXJaamEtVUlhcThscW9QdzF3ZWV1cDdHTHdR?oc=5" target="_blank">Prosecutors: Trump 'resorted to crimes' after losing 2020 election in failed bid to cling to power</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxOd2ZLaGRqcmJON25zcWxlUm94d0IzNVdCQVFCbTBqVEt0LU5zOEl6c2VWVGRObDNGd3A1d21nV0U3aDNBczVHTjdCbS1acnNpM0dSUTlGU1EwR1dncFJHdzZCVEFQQkg1ZE1iZGFNQ0JidzU3M21LRDYzU2ZhUXRoZGl6cXpZQmZtOVoxUmIxR184ZUhiUFd2eWVJZWFYZ1g4OS11S9IBqgFBVV95cUxNNTI4Mnlvbm81cVQ0LUI3OVY1eTBWanZiam1rQ1d5MGtZYk44eE1OU0h6TGNaMmRXRjE0NTRJR1JsV3VMaXAwSWxFU3RrMUNCSEhTXzI2MlB1RC1wWnAzdUlnN1hDMUdiZHIyMGc0VUJXSXpjNVA4VjdQbHNsVUtmc1YtZW82dlFSaVVKbzA2TFgwaEltdm5kdmhFRFB0T1k3dW8tZEtTWVIyUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Judge unseals key filing in special counsel's election case against Trump</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNcDFhVVlaXzNEc3JuT0hBOUpxY1lnWmZNNURXSWNmXzNJNHJ6dW5XTFdkNC1hdzh4anpDdnliNGFfUUZfM2o1N2lQM2p0RzYzQVdoaDVOSmRlZVFhdG1ITlJBUnNxbVpFalpOMWliSThXWWRhQ1hvNGxzV1JZMV85Yy1jc3pYLUxhcXJoeEZ1VVBxVkktTjJESW5xZEQtak5RdG9VQklrYUZtQlFRTUHSAbMBQVVfeXFMUER1M3RSNi1WMzJwbldKY0ZwbFRGeWhtLVNDZzE5YU9lS0w3b181enUzZGhES2k2THc5TWg1MFBYZzhRWkZoZnlTMEpDWjFFUWJxa0tEM2JQYXpad2E1WGVOckRoTDJ4N1lqWFlkSk8tdmlvSEVRU09Ic3RfV1hva3F3b1E2MzYtZDBOajFyWUtPVzNVV2ozdHRZaldxY0NBNEFqdzVFYWlOSWNTMkVFVHExek0?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNcDFhVVlaXzNEc3JuT0hBOUpxY1lnWmZNNURXSWNmXzNJNHJ6dW5XTFdkNC1hdzh4anpDdnliNGFfUUZfM2o1N2lQM2p0RzYzQVdoaDVOSmRlZVFhdG1ITlJBUnNxbVpFalpOMWliSThXWWRhQ1hvNGxzV1JZMV85Yy1jc3pYLUxhcXJoeEZ1VVBxVkktTjJESW5xZEQtak5RdG9VQklrYUZtQlFRTUHSAbMBQVVfeXFMUER1M3RSNi1WMzJwbldKY0ZwbFRGeWhtLVNDZzE5YU9lS0w3b181enUzZGhES2k2THc5TWg1MFBYZzhRWkZoZnlTMEpDWjFFUWJxa0tEM2JQYXpad2E1WGVOckRoTDJ4N1lqWFlkSk8tdmlvSEVRU09Ic3RfV1hva3F3b1E2MzYtZDBOajFyWUtPVzNVV2ozdHRZaldxY0NBNEFqdzVFYWlOSWNTMkVFVHExek0?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel presses forward on two fronts and reports 8 combat deaths as fears of a wider war mount - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxPNGhxdGZCMmFPOEJfaUZJcUVvS0R2RTNReEd5U3dfN01CQlZ2VUJkOWJLOFdUdkJOSC1QTEJ3d1RDSC1Ybm9Gdjd5UG1mZzJGT05Zcy1DZ2kzTEJYblZvS0JkY1BPUFA1QU5jc2xCRVlIMlI0Zkc0NHNkdFVpNU1aUUpfQ2QxX2xyTDlhaFoya0hhVmlueHlzQzZ1X3JXMXZJMm5semNYelpRT3RJNEhF?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel presses forward on two fronts and reports 8 combat deaths as fears of a wider war mount</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPUnZUMjRFMVpoYk1QNHY3QXZON0Z6elR2YWI3a194OWVpRUV6TUF2dHhMUGdLMVVEdTdaRHFIWWlTTGFsZzdPcFN6SkYxYWZCVVA0VGZ2N2QyZnFSMl9OWnlER2lvcDVUVFYyZnNXMUQ5RGdXWmxNMGJOOTk5TU1Zdg?oc=5" target="_blank">Israeli Troops Clash With Hezbollah in Southern Lebanon: Live Updates and News</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxOdlAySFF3bURJa0V3VnR0UmRMdTBha01rTWJaM2FXUWRrLUllVGFibEZ5a2lPTWJTTHlucnRsY1pNVzBiaVZxYWNEN3JyUUxVampZUXotS2NJekxzR3ppcm1rc3dmN2o0T2FvQ2pQbzc1dmd6RmZJYnRSYW1WSUdsVXNSWWZkYWRjcHo4UlE1Q1hUT2V2ZVFJMUJOWHdDZzljODJjZTZYY1AwTllN0gFSQVVfeXFMTUFNa3M5RF9PNUJmZWFsY2E4eWJIMG1wTXJlUE1mM0RnOHlVZ0c4OV9NSy12LUR3OWNoRnRUdGtTX05RTmJLV01lSXRGYi1sMVl6UQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel's military says eight soldiers killed in fighting against Hezbollah militants in Lebanon</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPcUR2aGoxdTdFbENDdEtHaUZ2c1d5RUhzcTc0X2Y4VmpoeGhFZUpuNVRYT2s4OF9KNmNSQjJIM0hScXZwZ3duVkRRRll1bWc3d2p3WWNZZ1VRQXloeDViVm5oYjIzd25qSDRSTEFmMG9BX19lRVFHSUc5UzY5dC1OSg?oc=5" target="_blank">Where Will Israel’s Multifront War End?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Foreign Affairs Magazine</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxPNGhxdGZCMmFPOEJfaUZJcUVvS0R2RTNReEd5U3dfN01CQlZ2VUJkOWJLOFdUdkJOSC1QTEJ3d1RDSC1Ybm9Gdjd5UG1mZzJGT05Zcy1DZ2kzTEJYblZvS0JkY1BPUFA1QU5jc2xCRVlIMlI0Zkc0NHNkdFVpNU1aUUpfQ2QxX2xyTDlhaFoya0hhVmlueHlzQzZ1X3JXMXZJMm5semNYelpRT3RJNEhF?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxPNGhxdGZCMmFPOEJfaUZJcUVvS0R2RTNReEd5U3dfN01CQlZ2VUJkOWJLOFdUdkJOSC1QTEJ3d1RDSC1Ybm9Gdjd5UG1mZzJGT05Zcy1DZ2kzTEJYblZvS0JkY1BPUFA1QU5jc2xCRVlIMlI0Zkc0NHNkdFVpNU1aUUpfQ2QxX2xyTDlhaFoya0hhVmlueHlzQzZ1X3JXMXZJMm5semNYelpRT3RJNEhF?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 20:36:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vance: GOP has to earn America's trust back on abortion - Axios]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTE1uNFhUaWJUR3RzaXZEdk1feEFnclBzOWRpV2hEaVVSemQ3a0dXei1mUTROZDY2bzYwN1lCNE9DSnMtMFB1V0dYc1JRZmpNb0NxR1RVVVZ4N2cyb3N3c3d6UUZfZXpKZVNjRkNVc0tXTXZla0dL?oc=5" target="_blank">Vance: GOP has to earn America's trust back on abortion</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Axios</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxQRG9ZQUJTZGdSdjNKZ044ZFRENDRWTjZDek1FNHhOd0dhNVNSbFFIX0VmeVNvbXVFdHFrZWxsVEFMdzdKazNIY2Z5UlNoc3lJVlBhQVU1emh3d3l0TkdTVy1wTW01VXNUWW1zUXJEcU1LdEFHRmkwZXF2UkxRTkxwMkVoNWp4RU1TUmowTVl5UW1NOHFlOEtIY21ZTktiREdxNFdUYlRuVC1CdU1E?oc=5" target="_blank">Vance says GOP needs to regain Americans' trust on abortion. Pelosi responds</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxOS2hDTUhCZ09Ub0NvS1pOYnpKMjEtUzhYbjFHQ21LZXBsYTN1VGxlUVZ4djNvNXpTZ0NFUmQwTmh5YkE2YTZrVVppOE9vdVFFbk11eXBwT3BaLVdZek4xZTFkTUdFRU5rU0wwUkVUcXluUTlRSE1HRTJkcDZiUWxjMUtWWlBHWGRnYkI4cmRfR1ktSDJwRnpuaVRR0gGfAUFVX3lxTE5qcmUzbWRMeXhMdXZaZVZTNHFocW1SbWR5czhkazRfcHExYjJGeUVMTnBfSUxURUhwRFA3R2Q1c0FtUTB5cUhnMHFzWnZ4SDdPVWtpY2psZ0Z6cHBKMjJ2YXdibDFNX1pHLVI5NUg2SFF5M00ybWVFZ21mcjhZWDlROW5fZ0M4RXVIbThtbWVvbXdUODdpWUJ4OHNzTXRZSQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Voters react to Gov. Tim Walz claiming abortion is a 'basic human right'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTFBnR2tHbWxTMlVWRmdRSjBsaTdmNnFRaWJzTDZIZ292R3FlRjdtY291WVlyNVgtRF9sb1VIc0Y0QTZ3LUpxZTVDNDhoYjY1NlV2bnVLSGVKeEFaa3l3dk5CTjR5amZvT1dsLTE1U2t1WU1FeEpxbGNMX0Ftamh5Zw?oc=5" target="_blank">The Most Disturbing Question CBS Asked in the Entire V.P. Debate</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New Republic</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTE1uNFhUaWJUR3RzaXZEdk1feEFnclBzOWRpV2hEaVVSemQ3a0dXei1mUTROZDY2bzYwN1lCNE9DSnMtMFB1V0dYc1JRZmpNb0NxR1RVVVZ4N2cyb3N3c3d6UUZfZXpKZVNjRkNVc0tXTXZla0dL?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTE1uNFhUaWJUR3RzaXZEdk1feEFnclBzOWRpV2hEaVVSemQ3a0dXei1mUTROZDY2bzYwN1lCNE9DSnMtMFB1V0dYc1JRZmpNb0NxR1RVVVZ4N2cyb3N3c3d6UUZfZXpKZVNjRkNVc0tXTXZla0dL?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 05:59:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Exclusive: Iran's Khamenei warned Nasrallah of Israeli plot to kill him, sources say - Reuters]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQZG9FYmhkZUk3UE1LMUZ3ajZvUGpvVzVTb2hjY1JDcHBxaDdyck4tbFNPbnp0aGlUU2NhbmpFanhwT0pMOHVsWjlUc1dOa0ZkWmR2dm1tMHlBSE9teEFZNUZ3RDdWNFhtT09QNWhWLVh1TzVHLVJfc2l2ekVsVS1ZQUFYdS1YLVVFVWNUemZMbU13VE1fLUkwNXhOdmtzTzduZEREM1B0TW9PN2FjTS1jaE0tdlJRa2pTMGU4?oc=5" target="_blank">Exclusive: Iran's Khamenei warned Nasrallah of Israeli plot to kill him, sources say</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQbzYxUFpwODZEYzNuSWJ3bE5VSkVBZjFLMU9QVlotcVZldktWUDNjYjRCaHpIQ0R5ZnVIaVY1RDg1UGFkWE1XbTFZTUM0dnd5VHpWNVNRd0cxSkwtR3hNWXp3YXJRZUFxZy1zdFhVTU9WTW5sUkt5RXQ5R1d1VHJjVW90V3pVcWI3bk9JdGFxS3B2WU11TnFXU3BOOGpadEZEamZYU3Frb1Jqd09sZVExUE9GNlJBOEczN0llTFMtc3J3c0FFcEg2MUVyUG9QMDAyN0lqX0dreXI5YUdDT3YtZWdPLTJBcGt5LXRTcE9RaUdRVDlJcW1tMw?oc=5" target="_blank">Iran's Supreme Leader Khamenei had warned Nasrallah of Israeli plot to kill him: Report</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of India</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPWHVjSFZaZG9OTXZlTE9VdDRJV0RDSmR5Wk84TktTWEhKclU2eV9RSzNoRDNLOFhqZ1dsSEdCVW1NUjB0cDJJdkJJcERkT0owS0haZ3Y4OTlVS3MyR2loLVFwZnpMbVNXbjE0d0RrSjY5MWJqY2JhZ1FyYVo4Mi04cE1zdlIyV3hWMVZwcUE1alFiNTRkOTdjMEFJZng3Z2Q4bVHSAacBQVVfeXFMTVhWOGhUNENQUlBIeExnSzRJZjlNLTNHZmoyS2VXaUhUeFpxWDBlYVZEVzB5RVlON0ZhcnZTX2gxcHhYSHZLSkVlMXdudE1EV0N3TWdia2lvZmlPT0Zad0R2SWxUY2xSTG5vemtLWUZQQzlockNtSHViX0MyUHI5ME1Sdlo2bk1jMG9hMmsxcF9HMmJBNkpjREdoNEpydTZxVUt1RkV0X1E?oc=5" target="_blank">Fear, jubilation, jokes: Iranians react after missile attack on Israel</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Al Jazeera English</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxPRzNOMW9wV0NCcENhYlpVVFp5dTIzdFFVcC1uS1pXTEdBT3ZRNnRuY2dkZkRvZlZxQlhCN2dONndYNGpBamJudlNkNU9oOWJ0OVAtbWYtUm5HTEJJb0dBMGRCNVFxcWNBNkhDRWUtVDBHaFVXYmdPbmVIN1NmNk9WOFlqSkE2WHZHQ2ltQlBiaEdaTHBwRTJqS2hJMExLbGQ2d2pHN2NlaV9OaGVsRFQw?oc=5" target="_blank">After the decapitation of Hizbullah, Iran could race for a nuclear bomb</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Economist</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQZG9FYmhkZUk3UE1LMUZ3ajZvUGpvVzVTb2hjY1JDcHBxaDdyck4tbFNPbnp0aGlUU2NhbmpFanhwT0pMOHVsWjlUc1dOa0ZkWmR2dm1tMHlBSE9teEFZNUZ3RDdWNFhtT09QNWhWLVh1TzVHLVJfc2l2ekVsVS1ZQUFYdS1YLVVFVWNUemZMbU13VE1fLUkwNXhOdmtzTzduZEREM1B0TW9PN2FjTS1jaE0tdlJRa2pTMGU4?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQZG9FYmhkZUk3UE1LMUZ3ajZvUGpvVzVTb2hjY1JDcHBxaDdyck4tbFNPbnp0aGlUU2NhbmpFanhwT0pMOHVsWjlUc1dOa0ZkWmR2dm1tMHlBSE9teEFZNUZ3RDdWNFhtT09QNWhWLVh1TzVHLVJfc2l2ekVsVS1ZQUFYdS1YLVVFVWNUemZMbU13VE1fLUkwNXhOdmtzTzduZEREM1B0TW9PN2FjTS1jaE0tdlJRa2pTMGU4?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 18:04:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel bans UN chief Guterres from entering the country - POLITICO Europe]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxOMksyNFIwUzhnTmJKU2F4a0R4N2FCT3ZHNmc2Wnc0d0psYzN1ZVN2MWJ4ekZ2R0lNbDRGeFVnSHI4WDByVVpXQ2QtVzdYRlppMzd0dm9HbjJMaGJaeXdXNmNtRXA3UzluUG9kbXJuQk13MG9yd0ozbG14ZjJjMW85WFYzOHlBVVFBdkhkWEZLZ191S09IWmxB?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel bans UN chief Guterres from entering the country</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO Europe</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxPRjFOUEF0LXMzWTZWRzF3VzA0VTJ6bHZVdGoxMU1GNGZBMGpBMThjODlfbjhaOEk4b3JNdGliNFJybkFLdU85TTJRMUZHU3lHcEpUN1VRV3BzMWJ1OWdmaUpGVlViWGhJU3ZaRTBRMGtBUi1mdWltcWd0NjVHSXlfcXppdkFjMGdMVmVUMVN4U0lqZlhjN3BZRzU0eW9xZlFVQ0c3d2tVT3ZIYUpteGUyQk9DQ1RacE50aGNv?oc=5" target="_blank">Video: UN secretary general calls for ceasefire. Former Israeli prime minister calls him a ‘coward’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxQQWVQeEtBMXgtcHl4OThUdW5DLUpEOGpYbUROQkFydV9WanRhQ0k1ZzVhd3NZZTRZZU90THF4R3Fza1d3ekctWXlSR1RmcWQ0SEFRczlBUEs0Nm5GVlNkZGszZGFObjVGOU01dkxkcUpJOEdfQWIzX2ktMWJxRXNxUWpsSmh5N0tmOU1ETk5WdXdySUpzUGhVUC1DRm84Uk8wOHNFeDhNY9IBrAFBVV95cUxQcEFoMkZmenlrNHFaTkk4cDJXVkNEaVpFVmtqV2l3TDJabHExVER1dmMtbTIwM3dneml4dWN2Q3FLcVEwamVvZlZVOEtRcW9SNmppeUJXX1M5SV9Qd1lqc2N2MUxuT0hkYnNOanJ4R0NhR3p6dWNsZFV0ZW5fUWo2YmRxTGlza3ppMlhobXpYTFpGT2dSaGNmLWtwNmQyaVozanBFdk84UW5JLUlQ?oc=5" target="_blank">‘Deadly cycle of tit for tat must stop’ says Guterres</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Al Jazeera English</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxNTUFZdkh5d3RRckdlNnd2NFl6ZmltWW5IWEE3dktCU3JXY0diY0hvNkpQNXBBVjk3RjIyQXVDVUhqZkNKSmo4cENDUDJFOGhEVHZXTDEtenFVOTc4YkZBbkdia2EyT1dkMFBSX3Q5WGdweWZVbVdZRWJmUktGVC1fRHAzRktNWW1odXNJYjFJR3UwaVU1S3ozOVJ4cVJibW5xTTdBRkdB?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel bars UN secretary-general from entering country</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxPNTRlMmFQVFM2Z1E2MVRZYXRQdXRZRGFMX0RLMGl3UERFZGFYSndDTk5DYmd6QU5PZHZJQmNMUkpocFplR2VsNUJVVFozNTZIbTk3dDhqQU16WUxXcGpzVHFIcTVvWWM1aEk4elpaQjdPaWNnbW5ISzRtU3NVbWNld2RtTzZMTzdiRzRyTm5hazF3ZDR3d3otN0djYzZqTFBJT2ZQYm5iSDAwUHBoeGNjc2NlcG9Pc200bUZ3dWFlX2FDUdIBxwFBVV95cUxNRW9vMHdjcnBzcDZfb3ZtOEV0R0FhOGF4QTctQVRpcG9xZzFWX2xCVlhYb2RteW5BQW9WXzI3dmo4YVVYNllGazNXbWgwdXczYjE2WVVaeVQ0eV82RTQtYlVEN3FCR2JjTmpSUktkVlVpbFppUWVmX0FFQjRpaFVWQ3pHc0ZxUVloUHFkRzh2T3FhMEg2ZF80eTc0TTNXOGtMUjVYSURYUEotdUpRXzhVMDh6TW51Uk1yM1VxNFU4MldEOHlEMThz?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel bans UN secretary-general over anti-Israel actions: 'Doesn't deserve to set foot on Israeli soil'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxOMksyNFIwUzhnTmJKU2F4a0R4N2FCT3ZHNmc2Wnc0d0psYzN1ZVN2MWJ4ekZ2R0lNbDRGeFVnSHI4WDByVVpXQ2QtVzdYRlppMzd0dm9HbjJMaGJaeXdXNmNtRXA3UzluUG9kbXJuQk13MG9yd0ozbG14ZjJjMW85WFYzOHlBVVFBdkhkWEZLZ191S09IWmxB?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxOMksyNFIwUzhnTmJKU2F4a0R4N2FCT3ZHNmc2Wnc0d0psYzN1ZVN2MWJ4ekZ2R0lNbDRGeFVnSHI4WDByVVpXQ2QtVzdYRlppMzd0dm9HbjJMaGJaeXdXNmNtRXA3UzluUG9kbXJuQk13MG9yd0ozbG14ZjJjMW85WFYzOHlBVVFBdkhkWEZLZ191S09IWmxB?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 13:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israeli military deaths in Lebanon raise questions over war’s scope ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Eight Israeli soldiers were killed Wednesday in Lebanon, deaths that could shape the depth and scope of an Israeli ground offensive against Hezbollah.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/02/israel-lebanon-invasion-hezbollah-war/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/02/israel-lebanon-invasion-hezbollah-war/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 21:02:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ground offensive preceded by year of secret raids in Lebanon, Israel says]]></title><description><![CDATA[Before sending troops into Lebanon Tuesday, Israel carried out more than 70 operations north of the border, an Israeli official said.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/02/israel-lebanon-raids/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/02/israel-lebanon-raids/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 20:48:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum vows 'it's time for women']]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fullfb/mexican_president_claudia_sheinbaum_vows_its_time/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/QTbuYQm_aw5DihodgljOKh0QBr0Mg4TgHvD1bXPK6pE.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=2ef3818f9c192494cba1c0fadf23da665e1e5fda" alt="Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum vows 'it's time for women' " title="Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum vows 'it's time for women' " /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/CookMotor"> /u/CookMotor </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce3z263453lo">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fullfb/mexican_president_claudia_sheinbaum_vows_its_time/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fullfb/mexican_president_claudia_sheinbaum_vows_its_time/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fullfb/mexican_president_claudia_sheinbaum_vows_its_time/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/CookMotor]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 17:16:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Middle East crisis live: Israeli military says it is carrying out airstrike in Beirut]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>IDF says it is carrying out ‘targeted’ airstrike in Lebanon’s capital as multiple blasts are reported</p><p><strong>Danish</strong> police said on Wednesday morning that they were investigating two blasts in the vicinity of <strong>Israel’s</strong> <strong>embassy</strong> in <strong>Copenhagen</strong>.</p><p>“No one has been injured, and we are carrying out initial investigations at the scene,” Copenhagen police said in a statement. They said a “possible connection” to the Israeli embassy, which is located in the area, was being investigated.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/02/israel-iran-attacks-latest-updates-live-hezbollah-lebanon-beirut-strikes">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/02/israel-iran-attacks-latest-updates-live-hezbollah-lebanon-beirut-strikes</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/02/israel-iran-attacks-latest-updates-live-hezbollah-lebanon-beirut-strikes</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 20:57:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Melania Trump passionately defends abortion rights in upcoming memoir]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Exclusive: ‘I have carried this belief with me throughout my entire adult life’, former first lady writes in memoir </p><p>Melania Trump made an extraordinary declaration in an eagerly awaited memoir to be published a month from election day: she is a passionate supporter of a woman’s right to control her own body – including the right to abortion.</p><p>“It is imperative to guarantee that women have autonomy in deciding their preference of having children, based on their own convictions, free from any intervention or pressure from the government,” the Republican nominee’s wife writes, amid a campaign in which Donald Trump’s threats to women’s reproductive rights have played a central role.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/02/melania-trump-memoir-defends-abortion-rights">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/02/melania-trump-memoir-defends-abortion-rights</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/02/melania-trump-memoir-defends-abortion-rights</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 21:01:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Walz says Vance was ‘gaslighting’ public about Trump’s record in debate]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Democratic vice-presidential candidate calls opponent a ‘slick talker’ in first comments on Tuesday’s televised clash</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/01/trump-vance-vp-debate-highlights">School shootings, childcare and cost of living: key takeaways from the Walz-Vance debate</a></li></ul><p>The day after the only vice-presidential debate this year, Democrat <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/tim-walz">Tim Walz</a> called his Republican challenger, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/jd-vance">JD Vance</a>, a “slick talker” who was trying to rewrite history and gaslight people about <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a>’s record.</p><p>During a rally in York, Pennsylvania, Walz made his first public comments on the debate, which polls show was essentially a tie between the two vice-presidential candidates. The Minnesota governor was on a tour through the swing state on Wednesday.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/02/walz-vance-debate-gaslighting-trump-record">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/02/walz-vance-debate-gaslighting-trump-record</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/02/walz-vance-debate-gaslighting-trump-record</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 20:49:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia plans emergency public warning tests on Wednesday]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/russia-plans-emergency-public-warning-042740999.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/russia-plans-emergency-public-warning-042740999.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 04:27:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bombshell immunity filing details Trump's alleged 'increasingly desperate' bid to overturn 2020 election]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/bombshell-special-counsel-filing-includes-193959558.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/bombshell-special-counsel-filing-includes-193959558.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 20:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Five Chinese nationals charged with covering up midnight visit to Michigan military site]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/five-chinese-nationals-charged-covering-195446124.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/five-chinese-nationals-charged-covering-195446124.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:54:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Mocks Jimmy Carter on His Milestone 100th Birthday]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/donald-trump-mocks-jimmy-carter-170529743.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/donald-trump-mocks-jimmy-carter-170529743.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 17:05:29 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>