<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 18:16:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 18:16:04 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[The Democrats who could replace Biden if he steps aside]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="US Vice President Kamala Harris speaks at the Constitutional Convention of the UNITE HERE hospitality union in New York on June 21, 2024. (Photo by ANGELA WEISS / AFP) (Photo by ANGELA WEISS/AFP via Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-2158015324.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>US Vice President Kamala Harris speaks at the Constitutional Convention of the UNITE HERE hospitality union in New York on June 21, 2024. (Photo by ANGELA WEISS / AFP) (Photo by ANGELA WEISS/AFP via Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Following a <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357788/biden-trump-debate-winners-losers">disastrous performance</a> in Thursday night’s presidential debate, President Joe Biden is <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/27/us/politics/biden-debate-democrats.html?unlocked_article_code=1.3E0.i8EQ.kxLuikzdSwiv&amp;smid=url-share">facing a flood of calls</a> from Democratic pundits and strategists to <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357746/biden-trump-debate-democrats-replace-dnc">step aside</a> and make way for a different Democratic nominee amid real doubts that he is fit to defeat former President Donald Trump in November.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s time at the debate was full of nonsequiturs, rhetorical errors, off-topic asides, and extended pauses to gather his thoughts. He spoke quietly and with a scratchy throat — his <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4744889-joe-biden-has-a-cold-debate/">aides say he had a cold</a>. Overall, his performance only added fuel to existing <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/en-us/majority-americans-think-both-biden-and-trump-are-too-old-serve-second-terms">concerns about his age</a> and <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/joe-biden-age-election-2024-8ee15246">ability to perform his duties</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear, Trump’s performance was a horror too; it was full of outright lies and rambling incoherence as well. He once again made clear that he poses a grave threat to US democracy — which is, in part, why some Democrats are saying Biden must step aside and allow a stronger candidate to lead the party in November.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Replacing Biden as the Democratic nominee would be difficult, but not impossible, as my colleague <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/357739/biden-trump-debate-democrats-replace-nominee-whitmer-moore-newsom">Christian Paz writes</a>. It would require Biden himself to direct delegates at the convention this summer to vote for someone else and hand over his campaign funds. No party operative can force him out.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Friday, Biden <a href="https://x.com/kaylatausche/status/1806675665845903645">indicated</a> that he does not intend to drop out and remains committed to a second debate in September. But if Biden changes his mind, there is a roster of potential candidates who could replace him — the most obvious being Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Harris would be the most practical alternative to Biden</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Voters have already grappled with the notion that Harris is just one 81-year-old heartbeat away from becoming president. Only a little over a third of voters said in a September <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/23979668-671717605-cbsnews-20230917-sun">CBS News/YouGov</a> poll that they thought Biden would complete a second term.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When up against other Democratic presidential contenders, she performs well. A <a href="https://www.politico.com/f/?id=0000018f-f8f8-d844-a1ff-fffed00f0000">June Morning Consult/Politico poll</a> of registered voters found that 21 percent would want her to be the nominee if Biden weren’t running — more than any other candidate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She’d be the easiest person to swap in, as she could also pick up campaigning right where Biden left off. Unlike other potential contenders to replace Biden, she could start using his campaign funds immediately because she’s already on the presidential ticket. Otherwise, Biden would have to transfer his funds to the Democratic National Committee, which would then disperse them to another candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden campaign has also been trying to boost Harris’s profile by sending her on a tour of the country to talk about abortion rights, a key issue that has contributed to Democratic victories in elections from North Carolina to Kansas in the years since the Supreme Court overturned <em>Roe v. Wade</em>. And since <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/353753/new-york-trump-conviction-justice-department">Trump’s criminal conviction</a>, she’s proved <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2024/06/13/kamala-harris-trump-conviction-hush-money/">capable of going on the offensive</a>, leveraging her experience as the former San Francisco district attorney and California attorney general.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These facts, however, may not be enough to overcome the fact that Harris is unpopular, even relative to <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/kamala-harris-approval-rating-2024-problem-1853029">her predecessors as vice president</a>. Her net disapproval rating is currently about 49 percent, according to <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/approval/kamala-harris/">FiveThirtyEight’s polling average</a>. That’s better than Biden’s <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/biden-approval-rating/">disapproval rating of 56 percent</a> — but he’s also <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/644252/biden-13th-quarter-approval-average-lowest-historically.aspx">historically unpopular</a>, and Harris would be running on the same record as Biden. Moreover, the Morning Consult/Politico poll found that just a third of voters and 3 in 5 Democrats believe it’s likely that she would win an election as the Democratic nominee.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is partially a result of the White House’s failure in the first half of Biden’s presidency to give her the kind of exposure that might have boosted those numbers, instead giving her a portfolio that included the ever-intractable issue of immigration. That reportedly contributed to <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-60061473">tensions between her office and the White House</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Attacks on Harris — the first woman, the first Black woman, and the first South Asian vice president — have also been <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/3/27/23655248/kamala-harris-vice-president-approval-criticism">colored with sexism and racism</a>, as former <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/04/27/ron-klain-kamala-harris-sexism-criticism-00094166">White House chief of staff Ron Klain</a> has noted.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Replacing Biden with Harris, therefore, would require the Democratic establishment to go all-in on her in a way they have yet to do.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The other possible contenders to replace Biden</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If not Harris, a Biden replacement could also come from the bench of talent that Democrats have been eyeing for 2028: California Gov. Gavin Newsom, Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg, Michigan Gov. Gretchen Whitmer, and Illinois Gov. J.B. Pritzker.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, when asked about whether they would be willing to step in, they have demurred so far — which is as expected given all of them have been strong Biden surrogates.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the Morning Consult/Politico poll, Newsom and Buttigieg came second after Harris as favored Democratic presidential contenders with 10 percent support. Whitmer came in third with four percent support. (Pritzker was not polled.) Newsom, Whitmer, and Pritzker also have<a href="https://www.multistate.us/insider/2023/8/4/decoding-2023-gubernatorial-approval-ratings"> strong approval ratings in their states</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gavin Newsom</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Newsom’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/23832897/gavin-newsom-ron-desantis-debate">recent debate</a> with Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis has boosted his national profile. His record includes further protecting reproductive rights in California, <a href="https://calmatters.org/housing/homelessness/2024/01/california-homeless-encampments-2/">clearing homeless encampments</a>, phasing out <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/24/climate/california-gas-cars-emissions.html">gas-powered vehicles</a>, <a href="https://calmatters.org/health/2023/12/undocumented-health-insurance-new-california-laws-2024/">expanding healthcare for undocumented immigrants</a>, imposing a <a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/politics/article/california-death-penalty-18711016.php">death penalty moratorium</a>, enacting <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/09/30/us/california-police-reform-laws-decertification/index.html">police reforms</a>, and more. But his tenure as governor hasn’t been without challenges: He’s faced <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/02/26/newsom-recall-budget-2024-00143252">multiple recall campaigns</a>, and the state is reeling from a multibillion-dollar deficit that required deep budget cuts this year. </p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Gretchen Whitmer</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whitmer led Democrats to win majorities in both chambers of the Michigan legislature in the midterms. In the years since, she has worked to <a href="https://apnews.com/article/whitmer-michigan-abortion-election-a4323a955a8dc0b3f4875216289f2e12">shore up abortion rights</a>, <a href="https://www.bridgemi.com/michigan-government/whitmer-signs-anti-discrimination-protections-lgbtq-residents-michigan-law">expand LGBTQ rights</a>, implement <a href="https://www.freep.com/story/news/politics/2024/02/12/michigan-new-gun-safety-laws/72494522007/">stricter gun safety measures</a>, take <a href="https://michiganadvance.com/2023/11/28/whitmer-signs-climate-change-legislation-setting-100-clean-energy-standard-for-michigan-by-2040/">aggressive climate action</a>, <a href="https://www.wilx.com/2024/01/25/gov-whitmer-pushes-free-access-universal-preschool-across-state/">institute free universal preschool</a>, and reverse policies like a <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/politics/michigan-right-to-work-law/">“right to work” law</a> that hurt union membership and was previously implemented by the Michigan GOP.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">J.B. Pritzker</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Pritzker, who has a multi-billion dollar fortune, may have a strategic advantage in being less reliant on donors to fund a bid for president. He balanced his state’s budget and enacted a progressive agenda that included a $45 billion infrastructure plan, increased the hourly minimum wage to $15 by 2025, expanded Medicaid coverage to undocumented seniors, transitioned the state to 100 percent clean energy by 2050, and more. His state will host the Democratic National Convention this summer.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Pete Buttigieg</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Buttigieg made his mark during the 2020 presidential campaign, essentially coming in third after Biden and Sen. Bernie Sanders (D-VT). As transportation secretary, he’s overseen the implementation of the $1.2 trillion infrastructure bill passed in 2021, sought to <a href="https://www.vox.com/podcasts/23698202/pete-buttigieg-roadway-deaths-public-transportation">improve road safety</a>, and addressed <a href="https://apnews.com/article/joe-biden-business-pete-buttigieg-797fc9ea60ee9d9a22181a2622867fd5">pandemic-related supply chain disruptions</a>. But he’s also come under heavy scrutiny over a series of <a href="https://www.deseret.com/2023/11/15/23921286/bad-traffic-pete-buttigieg-transportation/">high-profile train derailments</a> and widespread <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/01/14/pete-buttigieg-airlines-transportation-00077957">flight delays and cancellations</a>, though has since made efforts to <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/05/08/1174853874/dot-secretary-buttigieg-wants-to-hold-airlines-accountable-for-delays-cancelatio">hold airlines accountable</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the public is still broadly unfamiliar with these rising stars in the Democratic party. With only months before the election, it may be late to introduce them now, even setting aside the tricky logistics at the convention. But voters might also be content to cast their ballot for someone who isn’t Biden or Trump: Previously, a generic Democrat has <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2023/11/06/an-ominous-poll-democrats-what-it-says-about-biden-alternative/">polled significantly better</a> than Biden against Trump.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Narea]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 18:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden debate flop leads Democrats to call for new nominee — but replacing him is tough to do]]></title><description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden emerged bruised from his first presidential debate with Donald Trump, raising fears about his age and ability to serve another term.]]></description><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/06/28/biden-debate-trump-democrats-new-nominee-heres-how.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/06/28/biden-debate-trump-democrats-new-nominee-heres-how.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 18:12:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[France's far right looks headed for victory in the first round at the polls. Here's what that means]]></title><description><![CDATA[With just days to go until France's snap parliamentary election kicks off, victory for the far right looks increasingly likely in the first phase of the two-stage runoff.]]></description><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/06/28/french-election-le-pens-far-right-national-rally-election-gains.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/06/28/french-election-le-pens-far-right-national-rally-election-gains.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:48:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia Should Resume Intermediate, Short-Range Missile Production: Putin]]></title><description><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin said on Friday that Russia should resume production of intermediate and shorter-range nuclear-capable missiles and then consider where to deploy them after the United States brought similar missiles to Europe and Asia.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-should-resume-intermediate-short-range-missile-production-putin-5992213</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-should-resume-intermediate-short-range-missile-production-putin-5992213</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 17:28:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Live updates: Supreme Court limits obstruction charges against January 6 rioters - CNN]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vcG9saXRpY3MvbGl2ZS1uZXdzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtamFudWFyeS02LXJ1bGluZy0wNi0yOC0yNC9pbmRleC5odG1s0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Live updates: Supreme Court limits obstruction charges against January 6 rioters</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtcnVsZXMtZmF2b3ItamFuLTYtY2FwaXRvbC1yaW90LXBhcnRpY2lwYW50LWNoYWxsZW5nZWQtb2JzdHJ1Y3Rpb24tY29udmljdGlvbtIBf2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtcnVsZXMtZmF2b3ItamFuLTYtY2FwaXRvbC1yaW90LXBhcnRpY2lwYW50LWNoYWxsZW5nZWQtb2JzdHJ1Y3Rpb24tY29udmljdGlvbi5hbXA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court rules in favor of Jan. 6 Capitol riot participant who challenged obstruction conviction</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqQFodHRwczovL3d3dy55YWhvby5jb20vbmV3cy9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0cy1sYXRlc3QtZGVjaXNpb25zLWp1c3RpY2VzLXJ1bGUtb24tamFuLTYtZGVmZW5kYW50cy1jcmltaW5hbGl6YXRpb24tb2YtaG9tZWxlc3NuZXNzLWFuZC1wb3dlci1vZi1mZWRlcmFsLWFnZW5jaWVzLTE1MzU0ODI5My5odG1s0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court's latest decisions: Justices rule on Jan. 6 defendants, criminalization of homelessness and power of federal agencies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo! Voices</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiYWh0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vcmVndWxhdGlvbi9jb3VydC1iYXR0bGVzLzQ3NDU5NzEtYW15LWNvbmV5LWJhcnJldHQtamFuLTYtb2JzdHJ1Y3Rpb24tZGlzc2VudC_SAWVodHRwczovL3RoZWhpbGwuY29tL3JlZ3VsYXRpb24vY291cnQtYmF0dGxlcy80NzQ1OTcxLWFteS1jb25leS1iYXJyZXR0LWphbi02LW9ic3RydWN0aW9uLWRpc3NlbnQvYW1wLw?oc=5" target="_blank">Barrett breaks with conservatives over Jan. 6 obstruction charge ruling</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiPmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tL2xpdmUvMjAyNC8wNi8yOC91cy9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWphbi020gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court Rules in Jan 6. Obstruction Case: Live Updates</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vcG9saXRpY3MvbGl2ZS1uZXdzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtamFudWFyeS02LXJ1bGluZy0wNi0yOC0yNC9pbmRleC5odG1s0gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vcG9saXRpY3MvbGl2ZS1uZXdzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtamFudWFyeS02LXJ1bGluZy0wNi0yOC0yNC9pbmRleC5odG1s0gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 17:36:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Takeaways from the first presidential debate; what to do this weekend - NPR]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5wci5vcmcvMjAyNC8wNi8yOC9nLXMxLTY5OTkvdXAtZmlyc3QtbmV3c2xldHRlci1iaWRlbi10cnVtcC1kZWJhdGUtdGhlLWJlYXItd2Vla2VuZC1yZWNjb21lbmRhdGlvbnPSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Takeaways from the first presidential debate; what to do this weekend</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL2JvZHktbGFuZ3VhZ2UtZXhwZXJ0cy1icnV0YWwtdGFrZS1iaWRlbnMtZGViYXRlLWFnYWluc3QtdHJ1bXAtbGlrZS1kZWFkLW1hbi13YWxraW5n0gF4aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZm94bmV3cy5jb20vcG9saXRpY3MvYm9keS1sYW5ndWFnZS1leHBlcnRzLWJydXRhbC10YWtlLWJpZGVucy1kZWJhdGUtYWdhaW5zdC10cnVtcC1saWtlLWRlYWQtbWFuLXdhbGtpbmcuYW1w?oc=5" target="_blank">Body language expert's brutal take on Biden's debate against Trump: 'Like a dead man walking'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiQGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndhc2hpbmd0b25wb3N0LmNvbS9uYXRpb24vMjAyNC8wNi8yOC9kYW1hZ2UtY29udHJvbC_SAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Damage control - The Washington Post</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnRoZWd1YXJkaWFuLmNvbS91cy1uZXdzL2FydGljbGUvMjAyNC9qdW4vMjgvd2hvLWNvdWxkLXJlcGxhY2Utam9lLWJpZGVuLWhlcmUtYXJlLXNpeC1wb3NzaWJpbGl0aWVz0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Who could replace Joe Biden? Here are six possibilities</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicWh0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL2ZhY3QtY2hlY2stbWlzaW5mb3JtYXRpb24tZWxlY3Rpb24tZGViYXRlLXRydW1wLWJpZGVuLTU3NzUwNzUyMjc2MmFhMTBmNmVlNWJlM2EwY2VkMmJi0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden-Trump debate: Here are the false claims made during the faceoff</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5wci5vcmcvMjAyNC8wNi8yOC9nLXMxLTY5OTkvdXAtZmlyc3QtbmV3c2xldHRlci1iaWRlbi10cnVtcC1kZWJhdGUtdGhlLWJlYXItd2Vla2VuZC1yZWNjb21lbmRhdGlvbnPSAQA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5wci5vcmcvMjAyNC8wNi8yOC9nLXMxLTY5OTkvdXAtZmlyc3QtbmV3c2xldHRlci1iaWRlbi10cnVtcC1kZWJhdGUtdGhlLWJlYXItd2Vla2VuZC1yZWNjb21lbmRhdGlvbnPSAQA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:53:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Supreme Court allows Oregon city policy that punishes homeless people for sleeping on public property - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQvc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1yZWplY3RzLWNoYWxsZW5nZS1vcmVnb24tY2l0eS1sYXdzLXRhcmdldGluZy1oby1yY25hMTUzMjQ50gEraHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmJjbmV3cy5jb20vbmV3cy9hbXAvcmNuYTE1MzI0OQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court allows Oregon city policy that punishes homeless people for sleeping on public property</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDYvMjgvdXMvcG9saXRpY3Mvc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1ob21lbGVzc25lc3MuaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court Upholds Ban on Sleeping Outdoors in Homelessness Case</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXWh0dHBzOi8va3ZhbC5jb20vbmV3cy9sb2NhbC92b3RlLXNob3VsZC1jaXRpZXMtYmUtYWxsb3dlZC10by1pbnN0aXR1dGUtYS1ob21lbGVzcy1jYW1waW5nLWJhbtIBYWh0dHBzOi8va3ZhbC5jb20vYW1wL25ld3MvbG9jYWwvdm90ZS1zaG91bGQtY2l0aWVzLWJlLWFsbG93ZWQtdG8taW5zdGl0dXRlLWEtaG9tZWxlc3MtY2FtcGluZy1iYW4?oc=5" target="_blank">VOTE: Should cities be allowed to institute a homeless camping ban?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">KVAL</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm15bmJjNS5jb20vYXJ0aWNsZS9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LW9yZWdvbi1ob21lbGVzc25lc3MvNjE0NTMzOTfSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court allows cities to enforce bans on homeless people sleeping outside</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">WPTZ</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiRWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndzai5jb20vdXMtbmV3cy9sYXcvc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1ob21lbGVzcy1jYW1wcy1mM2M2OGE5YdIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court Expands Cities' Power to Remove Homeless Camps</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Wall Street Journal</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQvc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1yZWplY3RzLWNoYWxsZW5nZS1vcmVnb24tY2l0eS1sYXdzLXRhcmdldGluZy1oby1yY25hMTUzMjQ50gEraHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmJjbmV3cy5jb20vbmV3cy9hbXAvcmNuYTE1MzI0OQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQvc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1yZWplY3RzLWNoYWxsZW5nZS1vcmVnb24tY2l0eS1sYXdzLXRhcmdldGluZy1oby1yY25hMTUzMjQ50gEraHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmJjbmV3cy5jb20vbmV3cy9hbXAvcmNuYTE1MzI0OQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 16:46:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Supreme Court weakens federal regulators, overturning decades-old Chevron decision - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaWh0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtY2hldnJvbi1yZWd1bGF0aW9ucy1lbnZpcm9ubWVudC01MTczYmM4M2QzOTYxYTdhYWFiZTQxNWNlYWY4ZDY2NdIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">The Supreme Court weakens federal regulators, overturning decades-old Chevron decision</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiQGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tL2xpdmUvMjAyNC8wNi8yOC91cy9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWNoZXZyb27SAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court Overrules Chevron Doctrine: Live Updates</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm1zbmJjLmNvbS9kZWFkbGluZS13aGl0ZS1ob3VzZS9kZWFkbGluZS1sZWdhbC1ibG9nL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtY2hldnJvbi1yZWd1bGF0aW9uLWZlZGVyYWwtYWdlbmNpZXMtcmNuYTE1OTQ2ONIBSGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm1zbmJjLmNvbS9tc25iYy9hbXAvc2hvd3MvZGVhZGxpbmV3aGl0ZWhvdXNlL2Jsb2cvcmNuYTE1OTQ2OA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court continues power grab by overturning Chevron precedent</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MSNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQvc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1kZWxpdmVycy1ibG93LXBvd2VyLWZlZGVyYWwtYWdlbmNpZXMtcmNuYTE0NTM0NNIBK2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3MvYW1wL3JjbmExNDUzNDQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court delivers blow to power of federal agencies, overturning 40-year-old precedent</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtc2lkZXMtZmlzaGVybWVuLWxhbmRtYXJrLWNhc2UtZGVjaWRpbmctZmF0ZS1hZG1pbmlzdHJhdGl2ZS1zdGF0ZdIBc2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtc2lkZXMtZmlzaGVybWVuLWxhbmRtYXJrLWNhc2UtZGVjaWRpbmctZmF0ZS1hZG1pbmlzdHJhdGl2ZS1zdGF0ZS5hbXA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court sides with fishermen in landmark case deciding fate of the administrative state</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaWh0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtY2hldnJvbi1yZWd1bGF0aW9ucy1lbnZpcm9ubWVudC01MTczYmM4M2QzOTYxYTdhYWFiZTQxNWNlYWY4ZDY2NdIBAA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaWh0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtY2hldnJvbi1yZWd1bGF0aW9ucy1lbnZpcm9ubWVudC01MTczYmM4M2QzOTYxYTdhYWFiZTQxNWNlYWY4ZDY2NdIBAA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 16:44:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iowa's Supreme Court tells lower court to let strict abortion law go into effect - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiX2h0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL2Fib3J0aW9uLWJhbi1sYXctaW93YS1zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LTZlYjVkN2ExNTc0OGFlNTMyZDRjZGNkZjQ3MWQ5ZTFl0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Iowa's Supreme Court tells lower court to let strict abortion law go into effect</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2pvdy1fb0N4R28yMTUwQ09GUmpTZ0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiX2h0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL2Fib3J0aW9uLWJhbi1sYXctaW93YS1zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LTZlYjVkN2ExNTc0OGFlNTMyZDRjZGNkZjQ3MWQ5ZTFl0gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiX2h0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL2Fib3J0aW9uLWJhbi1sYXctaW93YS1zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LTZlYjVkN2ExNTc0OGFlNTMyZDRjZGNkZjQ3MWQ5ZTFl0gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 17:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Supreme Court blocks Purdue settlement in major blow to local governments fighting opioids - PBS NewsHour]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvc2hvdy9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWJsb2Nrcy1wdXJkdWUtc2V0dGxlbWVudC1pbi1tYWpvci1ibG93LXRvLWxvY2FsLWdvdmVybm1lbnRzLWZpZ2h0aW5nLW9waW9pZHPSAYABaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cucGJzLm9yZy9uZXdzaG91ci9hbXAvc2hvdy9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWJsb2Nrcy1wdXJkdWUtc2V0dGxlbWVudC1pbi1tYWpvci1ibG93LXRvLWxvY2FsLWdvdmVybm1lbnRzLWZpZ2h0aW5nLW9waW9pZHM?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court blocks Purdue settlement in major blow to local governments fighting opioids</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">PBS NewsHour</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiYGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNi8yNy9wb2xpdGljcy9wdXJkdWUtcGhhcm1hLXN1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtb3Bpb2lkLXNldHRsZW1lbnQvaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Purdue Pharma opioid settlement that shielded Sackler family rejected by Supreme Court</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnNjb3R1c2Jsb2cuY29tLzIwMjQvMDYvc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1ibG9ja3Mtb3h5Y29udGluLWJhbmtydXB0Y3ktcGxhbi_SAVZodHRwczovL3d3dy5zY290dXNibG9nLmNvbS8yMDI0LzA2L3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtYmxvY2tzLW94eWNvbnRpbi1iYW5rcnVwdGN5LXBsYW4vYW1wLw?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court blocks OxyContin bankruptcy plan</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">SCOTUSblog</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnlhaG9vLmNvbS9uZXdzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtdXBzZXRzLTEwLWJpbGxpb24tMTQyMTI5MDY2Lmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court upsets $10-billion opioid settlement because it shields the Sacklers</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo! Voices</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3MvdXMtbmV3cy9mYW1pbGllcy1sb3N0LW9waW9pZC1jcmlzaXMtZGV2YXN0YXRlZC1zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0cy1kZWNpc2lvbi1yZWplY3QtcmNuYTE1OTM2NNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Families of those lost in opioid crisis 'devastated' by Supreme Court's decision to reject Purdue settlement</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvc2hvdy9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWJsb2Nrcy1wdXJkdWUtc2V0dGxlbWVudC1pbi1tYWpvci1ibG93LXRvLWxvY2FsLWdvdmVybm1lbnRzLWZpZ2h0aW5nLW9waW9pZHPSAYABaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cucGJzLm9yZy9uZXdzaG91ci9hbXAvc2hvdy9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWJsb2Nrcy1wdXJkdWUtc2V0dGxlbWVudC1pbi1tYWpvci1ibG93LXRvLWxvY2FsLWdvdmVybm1lbnRzLWZpZ2h0aW5nLW9waW9pZHM?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvc2hvdy9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWJsb2Nrcy1wdXJkdWUtc2V0dGxlbWVudC1pbi1tYWpvci1ibG93LXRvLWxvY2FsLWdvdmVybm1lbnRzLWZpZ2h0aW5nLW9waW9pZHPSAYABaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cucGJzLm9yZy9uZXdzaG91ci9hbXAvc2hvdy9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWJsb2Nrcy1wdXJkdWUtc2V0dGxlbWVudC1pbi1tYWpvci1ibG93LXRvLWxvY2FsLWdvdmVybm1lbnRzLWZpZ2h0aW5nLW9waW9pZHM?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 22:53:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iran election: Islamic Republic votes to replace late President Raisi - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3Mvd29ybGQvaXJhbi1lbGVjdGlvbi12b3Rlcy1wcmVzaWRlbnQtcmFpc2ktcmNuYTE1OTM5OdIBK2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3MvYW1wL3JjbmExNTkzOTk?oc=5" target="_blank">Iran election: Islamic Republic votes to replace late President Raisi</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiamh0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL2lyYW4tcHJlc2lkZW50LWVsZWN0aW9uLXJhaXNpLWhlbGljb3B0ZXItY3Jhc2gtYmYwOWNjOGMyMTk3NTBkMzFiYzkxMDQyZjIwM2NjMjDSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Iran votes in snap poll for new president after hard-liner's death amid rising tensions in Mideast</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFodHRwczovL3d3dy50aW1lc29maXNyYWVsLmNvbS9saXZlYmxvZ19lbnRyeS9pcmFuLWF1dGhvcml0aWVzLWV4dGVuZC1lbGVjdGlvbi1ieS10d28taG91cnMtdXJnaW5nLXB1YmxpYy10by12b3RlLWFtaWQtbG93LXR1cm5vdXQv0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Iran authorities extend election by two hours, urging public to vote amid low turnout</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of Israel</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiYWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNi8yOC9taWRkbGVlYXN0L2lyYW4tcHJlc2lkZW50aWFsLWVsZWN0aW9uLWp1bmUtMjgtbWltZS1pbnRsL2luZGV4Lmh0bWzSAVpodHRwczovL2FtcC5jbm4uY29tL2Nubi8yMDI0LzA2LzI4L21pZGRsZWVhc3QvaXJhbi1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtZWxlY3Rpb24tanVuZS0yOC1taW1lLWludGw?oc=5" target="_blank">Iranians vote for a new president under the shadow of conflict and economic woes</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNic25ld3MuY29tL3ZpZGVvL2xvdy10dXJub3V0LWV4cGVjdGVkLWlyYW4tcHJlc2lkZW50aWFsLWVsZWN0aW9uL9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Low turnout expected in Iran's presidential election</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3Mvd29ybGQvaXJhbi1lbGVjdGlvbi12b3Rlcy1wcmVzaWRlbnQtcmFpc2ktcmNuYTE1OTM5OdIBK2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3MvYW1wL3JjbmExNTkzOTk?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3Mvd29ybGQvaXJhbi1lbGVjdGlvbi12b3Rlcy1wcmVzaWRlbnQtcmFpc2ktcmNuYTE1OTM5OdIBK2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL25ld3MvYW1wL3JjbmExNTkzOTk?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:29:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Presidential debate fallout: Can Joe Biden be replaced as Democrat candidate?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/111348391.cms" />​​Reports suggest that some Democrat politicians and operatives expressed their hopes that the 81-year-old Biden would step aside, with some even considering going to the White House to publicly voice their concerns about his candidacy.  ]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/presidential-debate-fallout-can-joe-biden-be-replaced-as-democrat-candidate/articleshow/111348391.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/presidential-debate-fallout-can-joe-biden-be-replaced-as-democrat-candidate/articleshow/111348391.cms</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 17:46:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Flood washes away Noem’s false veneer of leadership]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/flood-washes-away-noem-false-213951947.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/flood-washes-away-noem-false-213951947.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 21:39:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kremlin says it hopes calm can be restored in Bolivia after attempted coup]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/kremlin-says-hopes-calm-restored-090219158.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/kremlin-says-hopes-calm-restored-090219158.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 09:02:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Carolina's restrictions on public mask-wearing are now law after some key revisions]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/north-carolinas-restrictions-public-mask-200936826.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/north-carolinas-restrictions-public-mask-200936826.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:09:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>