<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:29:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:29:31 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[The US says an Israel-Hamas ceasefire is close. What’s really happening?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="People run as smoke rises amid a fiery explosion in a residential neighborhood in Gaza’s Deir al Balah." data-caption="Palestinians run away from the blast after Israeli forces carry out an airstrike in Deir al Balah, Gaza, on August 18, 2024. | Ali Jadallah/Anadolu via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Ali Jadallah/Anadolu via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2166602221.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Palestinians run away from the blast after Israeli forces carry out an airstrike in Deir al Balah, Gaza, on August 18, 2024. | Ali Jadallah/Anadolu via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The US claims that progress has been made on a ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas —&nbsp;and that the Israeli side has already accepted a framework the US calls a “bridging proposal” that would end the nearly 11 months of brutal fighting in Gaza.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The announcement is reminiscent of one President Joe Biden made in June; then, he seemed to <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/353558/gaza-ceasefire-talks-proposal-biden-israel-hamas">suggest Israel had created a promising ceasefire proposal</a>. That proposal ultimately went nowhere, and Israel pushed back on Biden’s description of the plan.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This time, Israel has yet to publicly embrace the “bridging proposal,” though <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/19/netanyahu-ceasefire-hostage-deal-demands">reports indicate</a> Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is against concessions that would allow for a successful deal. President Joe Biden <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/biden-raise-egypt-gaza-corridor-call-with-netanyahu-axios-reports-2024-08-21/">reportedly spoke with Netanyahu Wednesday</a>, urging him to back down on demands regarding Israeli control of parts of Gaza. Meanwhile, Hamas claims <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-hamas-war-latest-20-august-2024-0af8804c872792a73a5d9044634dc884">the deal is a “reversal”</a> of previous agreements and has claimed that the US is imposing new Israeli demands upon the agreement.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Multiple rounds of ceasefire talks have already fallen through; the last successful effort to end the violence — albeit temporarily — was in November 2023, when a <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/2023/11/27/23976383/israel-hamas-war-hostage-ceasefire-deal-extension">week-long pause in fighting</a> allowed for the return of 105 Israeli hostages and the release of about 240 Palestinian prisoners held by Israel.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The goals of November’s agreement were limited to the prisoner exchange and getting humanitarian aid into Gaza. Now, the objective is to end the fighting that has killed at least 40,000 Palestinians, according to Gaza’s health ministry. The extent of the devastation, with many bodies buried under rubble, means that the real death toll is likely even higher — possibly by <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(24)01169-3/fulltext">tens of thousands</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The major sticking point in the negotiations, both now and earlier this summer, seems to be a fundamental disagreement about what a ceasefire might look like. Hamas wants a permanent ceasefire in Gaza, while Netanyahu has said an end to the fighting can <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/14/us/politics/israel-military-gaza-war.html">only come once Hamas is destroyed</a> —&nbsp;despite a growing consensus that such a goal is unfeasible. Furthermore, Israel has indicated it would like to have a <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/israel-demanding-control-2-gaza-corridors-cease-fire-112973629">security presence in Gaza post-war</a>, something Hamas will not agree to.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Reaching a real ceasefire agreement has only become more urgent as Israeli <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/aftermath-attack-israeli-settlers-palestinian-village-reporters-notebook/story?id=112906804">settlers in the West Bank continue to attack Palestinians</a>, and as the risk of a regional war that could come to encompass <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/08/21/world/israel-iran-hamas-gaza-war">Lebanon</a> and <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/14/middleeast/iran-response-israel-assassination-analysis-intl/index.html">Iran</a> looks increasingly serious. But despite the renewed attention on the negotiations, there’s reason to be skeptical that this time is any different.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why the prospect of a ceasefire remains dim</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The latest ceasefire news is just the latest in a long string of almost-but-not-quite proposals since November’s week-long ceasefire ended (both sides claim the other broke that agreement).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Most recently, in a <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/18/hamas-rejects-us-ceasefire-hostage-proposal">ceasefire proposal issued by the US on Friday</a> Israel reportedly included a demand for control over two areas of Gaza. One of these is what Israel calls the Philadelphi corridor, which runs along the border between Egypt and Gaza. <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-hamas-war-ceasefire-talks-corridors-03deb20a6c549273fb4b8ce3475fff17">Israel claims it needs to occupy the area</a> to prevent Hamas from using the region to resupply its war material.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The other area Israel wants to control is what’s known as the Netzarim corridor, which divides northern and southern Gaza. Israel similarly says it needs security forces in that area to <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/israel-demanding-control-2-gaza-corridors-cease-fire-112973629">block the flow of weapons</a>. For Hamas, however, additional Israeli control over Palestinian territory is likely to be a nonstarter, reminiscent of <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/23921529/israel-palestine-timeline-gaza-hamas-war-conflict">Israeli efforts to divide the Palestinian people geographically</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Friday’s deal also did not provide for a permanent ceasefire, another of Hamas’s primary demands.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The last major ceasefire plan was initially <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/18/hamas-rejects-us-ceasefire-hostage-proposal">negotiated back in May</a>. Hamas agreed to the proposal, and the United Nations endorsed it, but that deal was reportedly scuppered when Netanyahu introduced new conditions, including control over the Philadelphi corridor and a demand that Israel screen Palestinians returning to their homes in the north, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gex1rl6q5o">according to the BBC</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of what has made a ceasefire deal difficult is the fact that Israel has the military edge: The balance of power in Gaza has always been asymmetrical. The Israeli military is powerful in its own right; aid from the US, including the delivery of <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2024/07/10/us-israel-500-pound-bomb/">500-pound bombs</a>, compounds the advantage. And Israel has continued attacking Gaza amid the ceasefire talks, reportedly killing <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/liveblog/2024/8/20/israels-war-on-gaza-live-israel-kills-35-in-gaza-as-us-buying-time">at least 12 in an attack on a school in Gaza City Tuesday</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Hamas has a degree of leverage “they’ve never had before” in previous conflicts in Gaza, <a href="https://www.crisisgroup.org/who-we-are/people/joost-hiltermann">Joost Hiltermann</a>, the director of the Middle East and North Africa program at the International Crisis Group, said: The group still holds 105 Israeli hostages taken in October 2023. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The fact that hostages remain in Gaza has only been marginally effective in securing Hamas’s demands, however; a weeklong ceasefire and the return of hundreds of Palestinian prisoners is a far cry from a permanent one and full Israeli troop withdrawal from Gaza.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s also not clear how many of those hostages are still alive; <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c23lgy1k22zo">on Monday Israel retrieved the bodies of six hostages from Khan Younis</a> in Gaza. And Hamas has continued its attacks amid the ceasefire negotiations, including an <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/19/world/middleeast/tel-aviv-bomb-hamas.html">apparent suicide attack in Tel Aviv Sunday</a>, for which the group has claimed credit.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Further complicating negotiations is a change in Hamas’s leadership.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Following the assassination of its political leader and chief negotiator Ismael Haniyeh in Tehran last month, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/01/world/middleeast/how-hamas-leader-haniyeh-killed-iran-bomb.html">likely by Israel,</a> Yahya Sinwar, the head of Hamas’s militant wing, has assumed the top job. Sinwar, Hiltermann told Vox, is a “very stubborn fellow.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“He doesn’t give in. I think he would much rather be martyred, in their term — killed — than concede,” Hiltermann said. “So that doesn’t mean he doesn’t want to cease fire, but he wants a ceasefire on terms that he thinks are good for the Palestinian cause. If he cannot get them, then he will say to Israel, ‘Continue to fight.’”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The US role in ending the war – and why talks continue to fall short</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the latest ceasefire news demonstrates, the US also remains a major player in negotiations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/23916266/us-israel-support-ally-gaza-war-aid">scale of US military assistance to Israel</a> could provide a point of leverage to push Netanyahu and Israel toward a deal; at least publicly, however, Blinken and Biden have shown little appetite to use that leverage, even while pushing for a ceasefire and telling Israel that its war is unwinnable. Vox reached out to the White House and the State Department for further clarification on the status of the bridging negotiations, but did not receive a response by publication time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, there’s no clear reason to assume a breakthrough is truly imminent. “Every public indication that the principals are giving is that we’re not close,” said <a href="https://www.csis.org/people/jon-b-alterman">Jon Alterman</a>, the director of the Middle East program at the Center for Strategic and International Studies. “And that either reflects a) an underlying reality or b) the fact that each side is negotiating effectively to try to extract the maximum from its adversary — but I can’t tell you which of those is true.”</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/world-politics/367954/ceasefire-deal-israel-hamas-gaza-blinken-bridging</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/world-politics/367954/ceasefire-deal-israel-hamas-gaza-blinken-bridging</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ellen Ioanes]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RFK Jr. plans to end presidential campaign, will endorse Trump over Harris ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Without Kennedy, Donald Trump and Kamala Harris will be the only serious candidates left in the 2024 presidential race.]]></description><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/21/rfk-jr-ends-campaign-trump-harris.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/21/rfk-jr-ends-campaign-trump-harris.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:14:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump Stands Behind Bulletproof Glass In 1st Outdoor Rally Since Shooting]]></title><description><![CDATA[Donald Trump held his first outdoor campaign event on Wednesday since an assassination attempt, lobbing insults at his surging Democratic opponent Kamala Harris from behind bulletproof glass at a rally in the battleground state of North Carolina.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-stands-behind-bulletproof-glass-in-1st-outdoor-rally-since-shooting-6389421</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-stands-behind-bulletproof-glass-in-1st-outdoor-rally-since-shooting-6389421</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:05:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Live: Tim Walz, Bill Clinton To Speak On Day 3 Of Democratic Convention]]></title><description><![CDATA[The 2024 Democratic National Convention continues today with Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, the running mate of Vice President and Democratic nominee Kamala Harris, set to deliver the keynote address.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convention-day-3-live-kamala-harris-running-mate-tim-walz-bill-clinton-nancy-pelosi-to-speak-at-dnc-tod-6389363</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-polls-2024-national-democratic-convention-day-3-live-kamala-harris-running-mate-tim-walz-bill-clinton-nancy-pelosi-to-speak-at-dnc-tod-6389363</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:49:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vice President Pick Set To Star On Day 3 Of Democratic Convention]]></title><description><![CDATA[The second day of the Democratic National Convention saw the Obamas slamming Donald Trump and calling him a "liar". The third day will witness the Vice President pick, Tim Walz, star at the convention.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vice-president-tim-walz-pick-set-to-star-on-day-3-of-democratic-convention-6388689</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vice-president-tim-walz-pick-set-to-star-on-day-3-of-democratic-convention-6388689</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:37:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel and Hezbollah Trade Cross-Border Strikes]]></title><description><![CDATA[The strikes, in eastern Lebanon and the Israeli-controlled Golan Heights, underscored how months of talks have failed to stop either the war in Gaza or the related conflict along the Lebanese border.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/21/world/middleeast/israel-hezbollah-strikes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/21/world/middleeast/israel-hezbollah-strikes.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:07:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Andy Kim, Who Cleaned the Capitol After Jan. 6, Will Address the Convention]]></title><description><![CDATA[The likely next senator from New Jersey said he would deliver a message about the importance of service and participation to safeguard democracy.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/21/world/europe/andy-kim-new-jersey-dnc.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/21/world/europe/andy-kim-new-jersey-dnc.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:14:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RFK Jr. is planning to drop out of the 2024 presidential race and endorse Trump - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxPcURmNFBrdXJTbHlUV3pOUXRXa2U4NjJGbDdOSWQ1aGtXQmRZNmZGaWtvdmcwMFpnQVdhMmVhLS1LS2VEcm5FUGMtRExtTDItWGo2aHBnd2l0bzI4Z2VaUTBmbmtEU0VlVVJvQ2FBZ1FPNGxtTzlpU25aalU1R0N1VS1ERlFQckhOb1VJSGUtUHhuaVlhZUxMazVqaDNzVWJPWE5lVnJrSkRiSmdxSk5zeExwblVsQnhtU3g5TDVB0gFWQVVfeXFMTU92Z2hVaEVJNm9KNmVrUXhoanRnTndvRFZxSEVvVk5GV29tM0RKUlpQeU5zd2IxZVJyXzRwNnNVMEtzQnBsRXZHUHNaaUdYR0h0S0tTMGc?oc=5" target="_blank">RFK Jr. is planning to drop out of the 2024 presidential race and endorse Trump</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQYTRiZkJmXzNIOUtNWHlJcGZ1ekdEaGlzdU4wVlN2VmNrUWVsbXUzekVkbjc3ZDl4eFJRbmRFNGdGNXFRd2w5SWxPby13aGVsS1NTVnFwdExSMUV6WFQ4aVdreVdTLU5YMGwzSXNyZ2xfdTkxX0RYRXdiaElvNmg0YUM1dErSAYoBQVVfeXFMTVBmclRBalZlVUJCN0pFd1RnSmtIUDNkcWdqb1ZfMEhaTjYtR1lxUXN5QVFBVGJZa2hyOW5DVlVpSHB5OTBQZWdENUhxTkpGMDg0OUY0eGV5Z1RFLWlCMERHT1NhWnUzdzlScHRWWmNNN1ZpZXBHTDlFZm1TbXp4UzkySnItempPNVln?oc=5" target="_blank">Tim Ryan shrugs off threat of RFK Jr. endorsing Trump</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTE14MG1zNENNNzR2Y1ZCWndzamEyYlRhUU8wbXJmZWRncVR5YXBxUTFtVnZDSG9GQ3ZoZjlySVNtcTl3MVY4QmNOc3RHQzNvaUJJcU5rSmNTQU9oaEpRZFpBZE5JU3UzWURpZ045MHlycUVUaURwVzJqbHlESdIBckFVX3lxTE5Tb2lfcjh0YXI0QmFNbGdpS1BJZ3RfVWktTUVYUGk1QWd0WG1HQ2dfRVFYSzllaDlmNlo3Nm5veFYzZmtCTVJPdmMzdHdvRXhhTk85ZDJsNGVkSEZseHRBLTZJbjdRbUMtYjNNX21vcmh5UQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Kennedy expected to end his campaign Friday, in talks to endorse Trump</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxNZFdXajQySDY0U0MzMmNvdmozT056akQtZ2dJYlh0S1hDcXNZTkJpcVBhUlY1cVNzMXNTY3NpNk1xb0JPN0lBcnNhWnJDWXVwVGx3ZVRNb01YWlgtYm5ZeFNWSFFhZEZDRmhtQXFJMzhKWmpLR013STB6LWtjM2ZNU1BoelUzRUZoQXZiaUt5N3ItRDN1bTdBTXFIcjd5QjFKTGZ2YmdYeXZqMFlNSm91U0dXMERnUUZsQzNMNHotb2FMYVNV?oc=5" target="_blank">DNC 2024 live updates: Tim Walz, Bill Clinton, Nancy Pelosi, Josh Shapiro and Pete Buttigieg to speak</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxQd2J2YWFtOU5VOXQzOXQzczQ0Z204OEtwSUhhR3JZaTdyWDQwSGREUlMtaVhLUU5jSXYwcnRGRHhrcjVFSDFBT2p2WnVMZlRIR2p2ZTB2Z2JDdXNHYnJmYmg3ZnRjckI1bEY2UVhIeXlhOUU1V3Vhb1R1eWljWDVlN0hrNmJfMUFWTjE1MmJ0S3lOYmpWa25sMXVSLWs3ZDVfei1RTGpxX1E3TFJsRVZ1OHIwVmNleXVFNW9OZVpoR1JIZ9IBxwFBVV95cUxPOUU4c1FfVEFYNnc3ZmhOOThNbUZlZklianMzU0poY29PbFJFRnpiazNJbERCb1RuWFlzQ21XbHVuNU41NFV1MHdyenNGMmpQNFN4TFJfZHViOERhOUt3Z0xOODNyeUFqa29iR25wbFQ2R1pLOVB5dXNkdEZnMmtSQng2clNUZUpSSnUtLVdtbG5EY1FHVlZYaUlVT1U0amUwZnRpSTZDSmJBVnhLcW5jTXdUMUZZWC02TzFBUWVUTmVYNFhYMHJn?oc=5" target="_blank">Robert F. Kennedy, Jr. to address America on Friday about the 'present historical moment and his path forward'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxPcURmNFBrdXJTbHlUV3pOUXRXa2U4NjJGbDdOSWQ1aGtXQmRZNmZGaWtvdmcwMFpnQVdhMmVhLS1LS2VEcm5FUGMtRExtTDItWGo2aHBnd2l0bzI4Z2VaUTBmbmtEU0VlVVJvQ2FBZ1FPNGxtTzlpU25aalU1R0N1VS1ERlFQckhOb1VJSGUtUHhuaVlhZUxMazVqaDNzVWJPWE5lVnJrSkRiSmdxSk5zeExwblVsQnhtU3g5TDVB0gFWQVVfeXFMTU92Z2hVaEVJNm9KNmVrUXhoanRnTndvRFZxSEVvVk5GV29tM0RKUlpQeU5zd2IxZVJyXzRwNnNVMEtzQnBsRXZHUHNaaUdYR0h0S0tTMGc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxPcURmNFBrdXJTbHlUV3pOUXRXa2U4NjJGbDdOSWQ1aGtXQmRZNmZGaWtvdmcwMFpnQVdhMmVhLS1LS2VEcm5FUGMtRExtTDItWGo2aHBnd2l0bzI4Z2VaUTBmbmtEU0VlVVJvQ2FBZ1FPNGxtTzlpU25aalU1R0N1VS1ERlFQckhOb1VJSGUtUHhuaVlhZUxMazVqaDNzVWJPWE5lVnJrSkRiSmdxSk5zeExwblVsQnhtU3g5TDVB0gFWQVVfeXFMTU92Z2hVaEVJNm9KNmVrUXhoanRnTndvRFZxSEVvVk5GV29tM0RKUlpQeU5zd2IxZVJyXzRwNnNVMEtzQnBsRXZHUHNaaUdYR0h0S0tTMGc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 20:46:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[At least 55 arrested after clashes with police outside Israeli Consulate in Chicago during DNC - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQTlFhaUFzOTNkcjNqX0tfcUEzWWNxb0lQdFFJNklFSGNWdmlnaXhzbFBxdk9qVEltWjhsMzVzeUtDeXRCcDF1Z3NQRTV2OVgzSi0wbHA1Z056cEpjcnVpRS1Ka0dOQWhEZEhHVTNWUmtXZEpqMEtYaU9BbndJUDVDaDBPdjlrMTlVbW1fVHd4LWU1VFduRkFjU2E4OHRWeGstem5rbXJaWWZuQjlMMExJVW81TTl4QQ?oc=5" target="_blank">At least 55 arrested after clashes with police outside Israeli Consulate in Chicago during DNC</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6wFBVV95cUxQbzl6TThxNUVRd0JJaGJYZFBfR3BDRy1WTEQzWldlZ0VZSTF3cFBKVjV5NlVDQzRLcTA3bkNxTzhvOURWM3UxY1d6ekxDSzRFdlhXZEtZbm1YYmg2TGhvWktySUJpNWcyUTJURWN1MnFPT2dNZlhHUlZ6QlBEanRtLWRDTWUyNWJRa3BVRGR0VjRRaUNTcHNDZTBtTXduYkFIQUVnNzFsalZNc3NrTTBjZkZYWVk1a0QzR3JWWWM5NUdXaW9fREhNVmdWOGdlVGhRREpZNGhQNWUyRHJqOFFkSEU5QUE5VTZVZ0xR?oc=5" target="_blank">Dozens arrested after pro-Palestinian, anti-DNC protesters clash with CPD</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">WLS-TV</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE8xOHRqNFY2M2RwSHJ5c0p5SFVnS1N4bmJIRGRZSFAyMXNOLUpXUlZyV3lOTzBxRUFFTDdGajRJNXlJZ09WdDN5ZDBDNXg5UXR4MXNpanR4OV9lejNFVFFTUThCVjZ5TFcxV1dKLWFJSXR5aXNJb0hYZVFR?oc=5" target="_blank">Dozens of Protesters Arrested in Chicago as Democrats Meet</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxNT3R0VGxSUlhGUjFqeXNZeVhHUG5TVkVXOFFmdFA4SW9sd0htRi1PaE5VeXNqa1hlNFBDaHBVV0FXS2dkRTZFRXRnOVN6b3ZVai02QkRBZlRwTmlwX0pIYks0UmdQdzkySmhQTGsxWDZIRG5DMTBZTV9aTzFQdmN0Ml9oZ194Nmk1Z0ptYkpKNHJCZ2tPQWxHT1FDc1RuSU9URVZzUWhHVDVqMDBUMEo2UzB2eVdCZVk5Rzg2ZzdkczhiaUVCRzJfWnBoWVRsTXp4dXBZMkQ4aU5EVU9MVFVGXzFB0gHnAUFVX3lxTE54OFE2ZGowWUtQSWZWblAyS2V5ak5wWjlYM21EQ2pFdnB6UWNZR2l3Z05Ga09TTGVOMUo0Mk5fOGdwa2h4YldmZmFIangwR2J2Smx3YmgtTFFJdUhsZmJOeW15WVBfeW93Z1g2RWRWSWRndmNDVWJBNWYyc0dNcGxBb0F6azhSWmJuZVkwa2tEX0pFd1BzSnNpZFlrclY3RXNiOEYtUDFET3BOcjdBOXpZYXdCQXoydHJGMzFNeHV2WV8tVkdXVkpvTk9GaUNrSS1INmxSVVpzTjJ3QUZNSjhuZldES3F1OA?oc=5" target="_blank">Dozens arrested after protestors clash with Chicago police near Israel Consulate</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">WGN TV Chicago</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxPTE1uQnJKNTQxT05PUk92bmFGR2VRNW1kVnNPUHpza2VSc2R0UUY3X2kxM3pvS2NfSGJrc2xKSXNwY0drd25Ub2VvLUFJcFo0eERUWU44ZE50VTIyLV9qQkpVSkVrbnYtV2dIZjRKdV9qT2dlUTMxanZzWUtPVUNfVTFKZ0tzeE1NSnVieXpzdmlQLXVGNWJ5cVhJaTZOMkwtaGxR?oc=5" target="_blank">Opinion | DNC protests devolve into farce</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQTlFhaUFzOTNkcjNqX0tfcUEzWWNxb0lQdFFJNklFSGNWdmlnaXhzbFBxdk9qVEltWjhsMzVzeUtDeXRCcDF1Z3NQRTV2OVgzSi0wbHA1Z056cEpjcnVpRS1Ka0dOQWhEZEhHVTNWUmtXZEpqMEtYaU9BbndJUDVDaDBPdjlrMTlVbW1fVHd4LWU1VFduRkFjU2E4OHRWeGstem5rbXJaWWZuQjlMMExJVW81TTl4QQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQTlFhaUFzOTNkcjNqX0tfcUEzWWNxb0lQdFFJNklFSGNWdmlnaXhzbFBxdk9qVEltWjhsMzVzeUtDeXRCcDF1Z3NQRTV2OVgzSi0wbHA1Z056cEpjcnVpRS1Ka0dOQWhEZEhHVTNWUmtXZEpqMEtYaU9BbndJUDVDaDBPdjlrMTlVbW1fVHd4LWU1VFduRkFjU2E4OHRWeGstem5rbXJaWWZuQjlMMExJVW81TTl4QQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 19:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scoop: Biden to push Netanyahu to be more flexible on Gaza-Egypt border - Axios]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxNd1BHcWJ6ZHVBMVBKOVNRU09wbUx3ZFBUczUxa3lmenhFOUxjUkVaQmZXVGNQWnZHRm16Yl9PR1RmUzJFOHNHMElCTk12OGlYbzJ2azgtT0tDOU43VjV3RGE4SFF5U0pXN19PSC11dEpBbVhfSi1jZDlkcGVTYU54N3ZtS0ZBaVROTXBSQWxrSk85dDVYS1pZbWVWbjhYdw?oc=5" target="_blank">Scoop: Biden to push Netanyahu to be more flexible on Gaza-Egypt border</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Axios</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxQY1hseFVIWjNJQm9fQkdwVjc2MzFkRXBLWEZZY092dExJd0JqQ2RCWEhiYVZOeF9Fd1plT0xpdDhwYV9CZXJMS25mbmFzMGNlZWwxcUt1U2JFVmk0Qk9fSzkxNGxxOVV0Nl9aeEstb2N1SFhqUlhHWi1CdG1GMEwwZFlYZXdtY0NQUE9tMTZzNA?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden spoke with Netanyahu Wednesday at a critical moment in Gaza talks</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxQVkpSVHNBN1pLUlltSWVjcV9uUUNTX25jNlFHMktHQWNtMkx6M055Tm9WdnhPWHpEQ1hfRWdGa1o2MjRXYU9OUjhvZTg3aUt3NVBENm1iSWdYRjFuTjRoNVdqMW16bEtrZ3BXV21aeXczcDdxQ2JNdDJ1cHBxN3ZYSXdqNkY3emUxR3pNOGZyMURmNXJDTlkzckJkdzUzZDkzT0dCSU9peDlQQ2VRQVBkT29iRzByaVJuWHc1UXpRNDhWZF8xU2Y5Wl9QdHBWN19YTWpxRjBWWQ?oc=5" target="_blank">White House: Biden stressed 'urgency' of finalizing hostage-ceasefire deal in call with Netanyahu</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of Israel</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwJBVV95cUxOTV9LVGxzZEJTbDZaYUM2QWJ6cElrdlRpUmM4RGZzc2RTQlJUZ1dOTnpkX2RsekxyQUNKSjVHdjMyTFlLbTJDZG9yZ1RvYXZzQ214LVlsTjdwMkVCRTRvSVhsOFpINXVQTmNmM3VzRElfV0s4Yy1Kd1NwUlRfM25lcFhKVi0yMFBxbmhjRDZaNjA0U3NNWG5ibG9VXzNheF94b285OFVXQko1NVdRVWpORThqZ3FBZTY2djg3WGFfNmJ0OGo3QVpVLXBIV2JuOEd4OVlMX2Z6Q3hnbW8yQklFVGszOERxNFJuRE9KaS16OWt6RGV6SUg0R0dHcU1TY1BpM2poR0pnVE1ZQXhrcWpn?oc=5" target="_blank">President Biden Speaks With Netanyahu on Call Joined by VP Harris, White House Says</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Haaretz</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiY0FVX3lxTFBjUncyTlhKS3FNRTYybXltMk90MGViS1dWLUM2UjhxSHVpT3c3MU85aXNqN2VnRnBqMklFbEJEWno1djI3MTY1c1lkeTJFeVRzMmdJNVJ3NVU0eWxoSXlZZGVybw?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden speaks to Netanyahu about Gaza deal, as hostage talks falter</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Jerusalem Post</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxNd1BHcWJ6ZHVBMVBKOVNRU09wbUx3ZFBUczUxa3lmenhFOUxjUkVaQmZXVGNQWnZHRm16Yl9PR1RmUzJFOHNHMElCTk12OGlYbzJ2azgtT0tDOU43VjV3RGE4SFF5U0pXN19PSC11dEpBbVhfSi1jZDlkcGVTYU54N3ZtS0ZBaVROTXBSQWxrSk85dDVYS1pZbWVWbjhYdw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxNd1BHcWJ6ZHVBMVBKOVNRU09wbUx3ZFBUczUxa3lmenhFOUxjUkVaQmZXVGNQWnZHRm16Yl9PR1RmUzJFOHNHMElCTk12OGlYbzJ2azgtT0tDOU43VjV3RGE4SFF5U0pXN19PSC11dEpBbVhfSi1jZDlkcGVTYU54N3ZtS0ZBaVROTXBSQWxrSk85dDVYS1pZbWVWbjhYdw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 16:17:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump appears behind bulletproof glass in first outdoor rally since shooting - The Guardian US]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNWkw1NkpoRlBObVZRcFJvRzlqcDdKZ0ZJQ1R6bURjbEZfSHVZUDlnZnBJNGlrNGlYSE1RU0RiUF8xNzJzb0tqZTl5V1p3c0FqYWNwNlYwaDlaNGkzMDVNenJ4aG0wd1k0RnowVEpYWjlOWWQ1UGpkSUpEWlJBSHI3dHp2U01aM1piQWxTUnJrX1RLb0VJQ3VkVmVDZkdYSWdLQUxHUnlGTTl6SWMxWFE?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump appears behind bulletproof glass in first outdoor rally since shooting</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxOcEV0ZEx6cGdyb2loeXFWa3dkeTk3b2pMaWx6VThBbmxTeXVBemdBb3BXY0xwOXFPQk9HNFdoVldDMG9VTWFidmtPVmpNc2NlTnRiV2pJSHU2UjVYOGw5YkJkbWhiWmpHblZYLTdmRWRmeEdqSHRadUhyV043NzNDLVpZUjRDR2ZaaDhwMG1mUkpUUUJjT3hrZDVQUnJpZVnSAaQBQVVfeXFMUEJ6SDZhc2FSeWwtZmNYbHZBNERnVlFrV0VmV1psa2c2Tjk1b2V3b0NjSGpSR0llUm84dXBvNmlXY0J4LVc3UWhzZ3k5LW5CRTUzSWRzcUU4dDNWZmVINmtWLVdCanlhdUVNbHpadGM1bnJXU0FELXZsN0I5OEZ2TDhUQjgwc2x2TDFQNUhodDBwTkFaalpqUGprOU5Eb3Z6MkI2eUM?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump zeroes in on national security at first outdoor rally since assassination attempt: 'World is on fire'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxORXo4YXZzTWQ0ajhZSm5lR1c3VDBNbTVkcl9tbXQzbnNqb3Y3aDZrSVZwWFJFODZIVmlHVURSa3lCeW1VY2ZDcFFPN1RZSDNXdm1FcTl5ZElPelJndnAybF9oYlExWXNjbS1SOFBEam1ic2NWX2RpWUg5UURPczJ4Zmp4V1owUE13RTZobXFyd1V2VnY0ZGZwYXdTRlNESkhPZlh5V2F6UDFMSERQaHdkTElOdTlsSzdlVHY40gHAAUFVX3lxTE93OHhxQnA0ZHAwV2s3dHI5QlhUcy1IUEhRSk5jc0d0bEhjbUhuT3AzU0l3dVhRRjFySl9VVUhpVDZrcG83Q1lnLXVIME1LcFBtXzU5d0ZtRWFIOU9yMGdKVTJpdEVTMFZnODk2Snp0SUxJOXVLclU2WTY5U21oWlhOOHNyVE5odHpHVE91WVQ3TlUtUGVvNmpxeC1rXzJaNUF4SU8wRm4xOEp6ZHFrZ2ZPMDI1RlFyWHY2ZEt1N253TA?oc=5" target="_blank">Former President Donald Trump, running mate JD Vance speak in Asheboro Wednesday</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">WGHP FOX8 Greensboro</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxNVWFQNmRLTFk4LUNzaHRiRXdxOFJkU1A4aVRZQmlxekhPYXc5eFRWalI5V3FyaVljVTJqdllJc2tzMnNRSFZpbjBFdjcwSUJPZ0Frem5YdUxnLXQxNUw4YUw0cHJKWk9CaS15ZVVrY0lUMU53cEtxRHAzb1Vqcm1TOUVjYTI5NFBpa09oc3N6NFhGSWp0VndCanY3djhnbmJhc1JRQVZGMDFhOTRqU0w0V0xJdXNycEp1OHZnZDd5eXE0UHFsOEhRUkk5VmxlSG8ySXZkc3htQmZnUUlpR3RMRjVJU0hHWGdPaEZkNW16M0Y?oc=5" target="_blank">LIVE: Trump speaking in Asheboro, first outdoor rally since attempt on his life</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">WFMYNews2.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxPM0ZRbHF1cFl3UURzdnpkcWlpeTVVUkJISGlCSzhuYUt5UUhRQmRldkJ5bVgyY1JLaGpJVV9qWnpxRG5RblZPTnhjRk5DcXUzdmgtWkstVzM1SmNXWVVrRDJRNXdidmUycTZuSHJMemdhUjk2RjBHdUp0ZTFmZnlKUzV6cGwxU0dBVDFzRHNUbw?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump speaks from behind bulletproof glass at first outdoor rally since his attempted assassination</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNWkw1NkpoRlBObVZRcFJvRzlqcDdKZ0ZJQ1R6bURjbEZfSHVZUDlnZnBJNGlrNGlYSE1RU0RiUF8xNzJzb0tqZTl5V1p3c0FqYWNwNlYwaDlaNGkzMDVNenJ4aG0wd1k0RnowVEpYWjlOWWQ1UGpkSUpEWlJBSHI3dHp2U01aM1piQWxTUnJrX1RLb0VJQ3VkVmVDZkdYSWdLQUxHUnlGTTl6SWMxWFE?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNWkw1NkpoRlBObVZRcFJvRzlqcDdKZ0ZJQ1R6bURjbEZfSHVZUDlnZnBJNGlrNGlYSE1RU0RiUF8xNzJzb0tqZTl5V1p3c0FqYWNwNlYwaDlaNGkzMDVNenJ4aG0wd1k0RnowVEpYWjlOWWQ1UGpkSUpEWlJBSHI3dHp2U01aM1piQWxTUnJrX1RLb0VJQ3VkVmVDZkdYSWdLQUxHUnlGTTl6SWMxWFE?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Grief and anger in Israel as recovered hostages are laid to rest]]></title><description><![CDATA[Over the rumble of gunfire and explosions from Gaza, families in southern Israel eulogized their loved ones and bemoaned not being able to save them. ]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/21/israel-funerals-hostages-gaza-hamas/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/21/israel-funerals-hostages-gaza-hamas/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:52:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[China Wants Big Fleet of 6 Aircraft Carriers to Take on the U.S. Navy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ey0v20/china_wants_big_fleet_of_6_aircraft_carriers_to/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/AhMNFafuiphXFL1mUSRpiV10HxFYP_GTaLO5j8xplRQ.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=e905a313b23036fb5258a45a6107a6fabded087f" alt="China Wants Big Fleet of 6 Aircraft Carriers to Take on the U.S. Navy" title="China Wants Big Fleet of 6 Aircraft Carriers to Take on the U.S. Navy" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Little_Drive_6042"> /u/Little_Drive_6042 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://nationalinterest.org/blog/buzz/china-wants-big-fleet-6-aircraft-carriers-take-us-navy-212110">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ey0v20/china_wants_big_fleet_of_6_aircraft_carriers_to/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ey0v20/china_wants_big_fleet_of_6_aircraft_carriers_to/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ey0v20/china_wants_big_fleet_of_6_aircraft_carriers_to/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Little_Drive_6042]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 20:59:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Brazilians 'struggling to breathe' as Amazon burns]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1exzp8b/brazilians_struggling_to_breathe_as_amazon_burns/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/92WXifIXrwqSEmxkRoYWSC4UahQSwTw9SyuIitnvad8.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=17b6c241ce0de786da59ea9d63ad02cb06ef723e" alt="Brazilians 'struggling to breathe' as Amazon burns" title="Brazilians 'struggling to breathe' as Amazon burns" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/loggiews"> /u/loggiews </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/brazilians-struggling-breathe-amazon-burns-012435528.html">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1exzp8b/brazilians_struggling_to_breathe_as_amazon_burns/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1exzp8b/brazilians_struggling_to_breathe_as_amazon_burns/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1exzp8b/brazilians_struggling_to_breathe_as_amazon_burns/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/loggiews]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 20:12:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia warns citizens to avoid dating apps amid Ukrainian information gathering risks]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/112691840.cms" />]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/russia-warns-citizens-to-avoid-dating-apps-amid-ukrainian-information-gathering-risks/articleshow/112691840.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/russia-warns-citizens-to-avoid-dating-apps-amid-ukrainian-information-gathering-risks/articleshow/112691840.cms</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:52:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Obamas cast Kamala Harris as their heir and ‘flip script on Trump’, says ex-aide]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Former Obama adviser David Axelrod says ex-president and wife ‘made Trump alien to values most Americans share’</p><ul><li><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/aug/21/election-dnc-bill-clinton-tim-walz-kamala-harris-donald-trump-latest-news">US politics live – latest updates</a></strong></li></ul><p>Barack and Michelle Obama have cast Kamala Harris as the heir to their political movement and flipped the script on Donald Trump, former Obama adviser David Axelrod told the Guardian on Wednesday.</p><p>The Obamas <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/20/barack-obama-speech-dnc-kamala-harris">delivered electrifying speeches</a> at the Democratic national convention in Chicago on Tuesday night. The former US president compared Harris’s ascent to his own by observing: “I’m feeling hopeful because this convention has always been pretty good to kids with funny names who believe in a country where anything is possible.”</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/21/barack-michelle-obama-dnc-speech-harris-trump">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/21/barack-michelle-obama-dnc-speech-harris-trump</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/21/barack-michelle-obama-dnc-speech-harris-trump</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 21:21:34 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>