<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 16:11:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 16:11:41 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[The Supreme Court wades into the Israel-Palestine conflict]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Supreme Court Justices John Roberts, Elena Kagan, Neil Gorsuch, and Brett Kavanaugh during the 2019 State of the Union address. | Alex Wong/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Alex Wong/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/12/gettyimages-1094200330.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Supreme Court Justices John Roberts, Elena Kagan, Neil Gorsuch, and Brett Kavanaugh during the 2019 State of the Union address. | Alex Wong/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Supreme Court announced on Friday that it will get involved in a longstanding dispute between the families of Americans killed in Israel and the government of some parts of Palestine in a case called <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/fuld-v-palestine-liberation-organization/"><em>Fuld v. Palestine Liberation Organization</em></a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Realistically, whatever the justices decide, they are unlikely to have much of an impact on the broader conflict between Palestine and Israel. But the case could reshape the rules governing who can be sued, and where, here in the United States.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Right now, if someone wants to bring a lawsuit, they can’t just file it in any court they’d like. They have to bring the suit in a court located in a place where the person or entity they are suing has ties. In legal terms, this idea is known as “<a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/wex/personal_jurisdiction">personal jurisdiction</a>.” Typically, personal jurisdiction operates on a sliding scale, with local courts gaining more and more power over a defendant as that defendant builds closer ties to that jurisdiction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, for example, a company that has multiple retail outlets and dozens of employees in the state of Texas could likely be sued for virtually anything in Texas’s courts. But a company based in Nebraska that only occasionally ships a product to a Texas customer would be less vulnerable to suit in Texas.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That company could probably still be sued in Texas court over a dispute arising out of that product. But the company probably could not be sued in Texas over a matter that had nothing to do with its business in Texas, such as if its CEO was accused of sexually harassing a subordinate at the company’s headquarters in Nebraska. Instead, the sexual harassment lawsuit would likely need to be filed in a court in Nebraska.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the Court were to side with the plaintiffs in <em>Fuld</em>, it could upend personal jurisdiction, at least in cases that interest Congress or a state legislature. Americans might be forced to defend themselves in courts in distant states, and potentially in states with draconian laws and hostile judges.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The issue before the Supreme Court involves several Americans who were killed while abroad in Israel or Palestine. One of these Americans, Ari Fuld, was fatally stabbed during a 2018 attack outside a shopping mall in the West Bank.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The identity of the attacker is not mentioned in the lower court’s decision or in the Supreme Court briefing, but Fuld’s family sued the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO) and the Palestinian Authority (PA), claiming that these two organizations “<a href="https://casetext.com/case/fuld-v-the-palestine-liberation-org-plo">encouraged, incentivized, and assisted</a>” the attack. (The PLO is the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/11/20/18080054/plo-palestinian-liberation-organization-israel-conflict">national representative of the Palestinian people</a>, and it runs the PA, a governmental body that manages Palestinian territories in the West Bank.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fuld’s family, and other family members of those killed, all brought similar lawsuits in federal court. The problem is that neither the PLO nor the PA have any legally relevant connection to the United States. The attacks took place nearly 7,000 miles from the United States. Federal law largely <a href="https://casetext.com/case/fuld-v-the-palestine-liberation-org-plo">forbids the PLO from conducting business of any kind in the United States</a>, beyond maintaining a mission to the United Nations.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Accordingly, federal courts have <a href="https://casetext.com/case/fuld-v-the-palestine-liberation-org-plo">repeatedly dismissed lawsuits</a> claiming that the PA and the PLO may be sued in US court.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, the families in <em>Fuld</em> have a powerful ally in their fight: the United States Congress.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Congress has passed two statutes seeking to revive the lawsuits after they were dismissed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The most recent of these statutes was <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/house-bill/1865/all-actions">included in a broader appropriations bill</a> that President Donald Trump signed into law in 2019. It provides that the PLO and the PA “<a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/PLAW-116publ94/pdf/PLAW-116publ94.pdf">shall be deemed to have consented to personal jurisdiction</a>” in federal court if they continue to engage in activities that the two organizations have <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/pa-under-pressure-over-martyr-stipends-it-pays-to-terrorists-families/">reportedly engaged in for a long time</a>, such as paying salaries to Palestinians convicted of terrorism offenses in Israeli court.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How <em>Fuld</em> could scramble all Americans’ constitutional rights</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <em>Fuld </em>case could potentially reshape the rights of many Americans, who currently enjoy broad protections against being sued in a faraway court located in a state they’ve never visited. The Supreme Court has long held that the rules of personal jurisdiction are grounded in the Constitution, specifically the guarantee that no one shall be denied “<a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/constitution/amendment-5/">due process of law</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the federal appeals court that heard <em>Fuld</em> explained, moreover, “the ‘due process analysis’ in the personal jurisdiction context ‘is <a href="https://casetext.com/case/fuld-v-the-palestine-liberation-org-plo">basically the same</a>’” regardless of whether someone is sued in federal or state court. That means if the Supreme Court rules that two foreign organizations with few, if any, relevant ties to the US can be “deemed to have consented” to being sued in federal court by an act of Congress, a state legislature could also potentially deem that people who’ve had few contacts with that state may be sued in its courts.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Texas’s legislature, for example, could potentially pass a law stating that abortion providers and clinics throughout the United States are deemed to have consented to suit in Texas courts — where they might be sued for violating a Texas law <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/8/31/22650303/supreme-court-abortion-texas-sb8-jackson-roe-wade-greg-abbott">allowing bounty hunters to collect money from abortion providers</a>, especially if the state legislature also amended that law to specifically provide for such out-of-state suits.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Congress, meanwhile, might allow any abortion provider to be sued in federal court in Amarillo, Texas — home of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/12/17/23512766/supreme-court-matthew-kacsmaryk-judge-trump-abortion-immigration-birth-control">notoriously anti-abortion judge Matthew Kacsmaryk</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It should be noted that the Supreme Court ordinarily agrees to hear any case where a lower federal appeals court declares a federal law unconstitutional, and the appeals court’s decision in <em>Fuld</em> effectively neutralized Congress’s 2019 law. So the fact that the Supreme Court took up this case is not necessarily a sign that most of the justices are eager to rewrite the law governing personal jurisdiction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, any issue involving Israel and Palestine inflames passions among US policymakers. So the same sympathy for the <em>Fuld </em>plaintiffs that inspired Congress to enact the 2019 law could also shape the justices’ decision. But a decision in favor of the <em>Fuld</em> plaintiffs could have sweeping implications that stretch far beyond the fraught politics of Israel and Palestine — and that potentially leave all Americans vulnerable to lawsuits before hostile judges.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/scotus/390424/supreme-court-israel-palestine-fuld-plo-personal-jurisdiction</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/scotus/390424/supreme-court-israel-palestine-fuld-plo-personal-jurisdiction</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian Millhiser]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel confirms attack on Syria naval fleets]]></title><description><![CDATA[The BBC has verified videos of blasts in the Syrian port of Latakia.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cqx808q7lrno</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cqx808q7lrno</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:40:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Damascus Dungeons, Torture Chambers Exposed After Assad's Fall In Syria]]></title><description><![CDATA[Syrians lived in terror for decades of what went on behind the concrete walls of Damascus's security compound. Now the Assad dynasty has been toppled, its dungeons and torture chambers are giving up their secrets.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/damascus-dungeons-torture-chambers-exposed-after-assads-fall-in-syria-7218064</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/damascus-dungeons-torture-chambers-exposed-after-assads-fall-in-syria-7218064</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:43:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[MIT Student Prahlad Iyengar Suspended Over Palestine Essay, Sparks Outrage]]></title><description><![CDATA[According to the college, the essay had language that "could be interpreted as a call for more violent or destructive forms of protests at MIT". The MIT Dean of Student Life, David Warren Randall emailed this to the magazine's editors.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mit-student-prahlad-iyengar-suspended-over-palestine-essay-sparks-outrage-7217976</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mit-student-prahlad-iyengar-suspended-over-palestine-essay-sparks-outrage-7217976</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:30:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Syria Rebels Name Mohammed Al-Bashir Head Of Transitional Govenment: Report]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Syrian rebels now in power in Damascus appointed Mohammad al-Bashir as head of a transitional government that will be in place until March 1, state media said Tuesday.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-rebels-name-mohammed-al-bashir-head-of-transitional-govenment-report-7217283</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-rebels-name-mohammed-al-bashir-head-of-transitional-govenment-report-7217283</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 13:57:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Some 250 Israeli strikes hit Syrian military targets after fall of Assad — reports - The Times of Israel]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNTjZGbk80d3NWWE1LaDk4ejlzLXJXMXFaaXVsQ0lUQUZOMy0tcmlWaW9ZOUtIRnZRNUVMZTZ3Zm55cFdLOHBhY3Vva2pEeXp4ejg5dVE4bGhsLTRFb3pHczJMWERUQjlfWGJyTzRadWhHbVlQSXBseG5pTElxd19zVjgwcFRzRC1fdldic3ktRUNuMkVlWEVvQldveUo1OHotR1dpUFdJRjdKNy1sVDVqd9IBtgFBVV95cUxPRXl5ckktWl80Ymk2aU9jZ0N4ajhhQzdTVDNqbnVhQzA2Vm5DZTFSWlNLVHpIODcyZGp2aWx3SkszWng5NzVPNVRoeG9kVnRzclZya1lSalExZ3BVeWoyOVBpbjl5RWZIX1M1ZkZtX3ctdzk1TjNMVjVhU1lUUi1rRk1jUjRiTWRzVHVNZm5YankwRnJYVkhmcE5xR2hTZVBPNXJ6bnl0SzhQNkZBMlZ5azdXc01QZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Some 250 Israeli strikes hit Syrian military targets after fall of Assad — reports</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of Israel</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2pkMDhMb0RCRy01eEk1UnBOSEhTZ0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNTjZGbk80d3NWWE1LaDk4ejlzLXJXMXFaaXVsQ0lUQUZOMy0tcmlWaW9ZOUtIRnZRNUVMZTZ3Zm55cFdLOHBhY3Vva2pEeXp4ejg5dVE4bGhsLTRFb3pHczJMWERUQjlfWGJyTzRadWhHbVlQSXBseG5pTElxd19zVjgwcFRzRC1fdldic3ktRUNuMkVlWEVvQldveUo1OHotR1dpUFdJRjdKNy1sVDVqd9IBtgFBVV95cUxPRXl5ckktWl80Ymk2aU9jZ0N4ajhhQzdTVDNqbnVhQzA2Vm5DZTFSWlNLVHpIODcyZGp2aWx3SkszWng5NzVPNVRoeG9kVnRzclZya1lSalExZ3BVeWoyOVBpbjl5RWZIX1M1ZkZtX3ctdzk1TjNMVjVhU1lUUi1rRk1jUjRiTWRzVHVNZm5YankwRnJYVkhmcE5xR2hTZVBPNXJ6bnl0SzhQNkZBMlZ5azdXc01QZw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNTjZGbk80d3NWWE1LaDk4ejlzLXJXMXFaaXVsQ0lUQUZOMy0tcmlWaW9ZOUtIRnZRNUVMZTZ3Zm55cFdLOHBhY3Vva2pEeXp4ejg5dVE4bGhsLTRFb3pHczJMWERUQjlfWGJyTzRadWhHbVlQSXBseG5pTElxd19zVjgwcFRzRC1fdldic3ktRUNuMkVlWEVvQldveUo1OHotR1dpUFdJRjdKNy1sVDVqd9IBtgFBVV95cUxPRXl5ckktWl80Ymk2aU9jZ0N4ajhhQzdTVDNqbnVhQzA2Vm5DZTFSWlNLVHpIODcyZGp2aWx3SkszWng5NzVPNVRoeG9kVnRzclZya1lSalExZ3BVeWoyOVBpbjl5RWZIX1M1ZkZtX3ctdzk1TjNMVjVhU1lUUi1rRk1jUjRiTWRzVHVNZm5YankwRnJYVkhmcE5xR2hTZVBPNXJ6bnl0SzhQNkZBMlZ5azdXc01QZw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:29:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump wants to end birthright citizenship. Can that really happen? - POLITICO]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxPOTdXeWhYLVNfV19QV2ZYQ1ZpSjNwSW9RWFF0TllzYXFUTFVxUDNRU095NEh3S0FvbGpmRnZjUWFNT0h0TkZqUWtQSlpKSE5GXzBGcUhELVAwaTloOVphd3JXYnZseF93TGVqUjhualNsQk5hUG1jNWJuMWx5YmdHbUI0NXBseDRzTjZRdjY4TjdfbXRvcVE?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump wants to end birthright citizenship. Can that really happen?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOR3R4VkhseXBiRHBzcVRqTzQ3TFUwY25XQm5jeDNxc2xjOEg3WmhkQWYyRHgtbjBhMkREUHZiVWFLSUhxYjBva3pCa24zTXlwNmZQNjJUQUdjX0RVQnJETEJENzREUkZHNjhib0RkTFFUNHFpUUNKOWNaZDJKUzV0SEZKbFcyWXdlcXg5MTRR0gGEAUFVX3lxTE5Da1pkQnIxX2dpQkpXLTdTa2lITW5mMzZSSTBWbEp0bUxMSVlXYzZ1amo2aE9ldDl5VEVtdkl6S3FkSVBLWkppNXVRSDhNck5memNqdUt2a0RRSlFma0pqZ1p1dW5RTVBLZ2dkZW1UMkRmWGF3aFBWLUhqTWd6bDBDRm5xOA?oc=5" target="_blank">Key lines: Trump’s ‘not playing games,’ he says in interview laying out 100-day agenda</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxNZmFkYjhoUkszNlQ4bGEyY3NPWktSUDVuM0NwOTY3cVZUTU9sNnBHYlJ2akM1ZFhLUUQ5cUoxS0VkVTNHTlpTTHM0MzNqV1RWTGhzOGFac214RE5Lbjh0Q3VTWW5ZS3NfUmYtU0g0VHdvTGsyLWRDVTIxNHFWUWNWWExCVzVTanJDdEdfeGRRT2Y0OUF1dWhEOEVBdEd6Nmk3Uk9B0gGoAUFVX3lxTE1pNExOdzVmX00wQW4ySThMc1pPUVJ1blp4SWtRbFFvV0cxdXJ5MG9hU0gzQ3p4c21FS0duNHRuZ1Q2T3BVNUJ5S1FiYVB1LVdUTFhhUWFzYXdQTzEzdE1JMU91QWpjVUVOUHBqLV92UV9NUHdXUldMcUt2RTRDNFVrZHVGNDhQeHUwcHNQdG8zSlZhblQ5a1FKek1PNTFFZEx4aGwxQ0xUUg?oc=5" target="_blank">5 takeaways from Trump’s ‘Meet the Press’ interview</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxQSGZyN3ZHcmhCX2NFTWVjVHV1SG91LUVaMHFsdFhZeTBqR2swcUdJSW1hcGdLU28tSngzdkQyYzB1d1A0aEtXSVdPQXBURktTVzJweUVpaXFYbGxlb2NITGJWRmRZdF8tU0FOMDEtdEhLemhjb2lCS2JvOEdkWk5xQVlUdVR5R3BfRVpYMlBFaXh6NWF3V3NrN295VU1VaU41?oc=5" target="_blank">Analysis | Could Trump end birthright citizenship? Probably not, legal scholars say.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTE9CVXRpaVBsWWlTY2ZQbUdPZWJHaU54QS1tcndOT1lWWllCZ0JiXzgxRGtTNko3c0I1QlY4aS1tdW5NN2F0WGRBRUtKVjVmb3NEZkcwNmoxVENvNldrb3dhZnYzaHpFT0VsZmwwUkkzR3NFeWxlN0oxdmpCZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump Says He Would Let ‘Dreamers’ Stay. But He Once Tried to Gut the Program.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxPOTdXeWhYLVNfV19QV2ZYQ1ZpSjNwSW9RWFF0TllzYXFUTFVxUDNRU095NEh3S0FvbGpmRnZjUWFNT0h0TkZqUWtQSlpKSE5GXzBGcUhELVAwaTloOVphd3JXYnZseF93TGVqUjhualNsQk5hUG1jNWJuMWx5YmdHbUI0NXBseDRzTjZRdjY4TjdfbXRvcVE?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxPOTdXeWhYLVNfV19QV2ZYQ1ZpSjNwSW9RWFF0TllzYXFUTFVxUDNRU095NEh3S0FvbGpmRnZjUWFNT0h0TkZqUWtQSlpKSE5GXzBGcUhELVAwaTloOVphd3JXYnZseF93TGVqUjhualNsQk5hUG1jNWJuMWx5YmdHbUI0NXBseDRzTjZRdjY4TjdfbXRvcVE?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ernst Suggests She Will Not Oppose Hegseth for Defense Secretary - The New York Times]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQdF9vNDNub2pHSG5KenZ6ZEtsSVVLQUx6MUVJUkRFd3ZXR1AtWTVyWk1oSzN3M0o4YnlIS193ZXdpeVBId1FYVkx1NDljSkdTSFc5WTFJVnF4aHQtRUd0dkwxaVZLNlJJT2l3c3lIZk1HVXk1VW52WjNCZGpabG83el92S2NCUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Ernst Suggests She Will Not Oppose Hegseth for Defense Secretary</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiY0FVX3lxTE11SUVyU3Bjcm1RTGdXS1R1S2RFZmVEMDlsZWZnRThQSVlQU2R0ZlY4NWxUVHJHRGJKbWs0Qzk5RVcyTjJhS2NreVVxR2I4YlBkd1Z3cklRQ3FmSlY4X2h4cl9BZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump Transition and Staff Picks: Latest News and Updates</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOWXZPczVXVlZqQlZVaENlTlpZeEVpZkFubk9keWw2YlBPcW9RaDVYQlR6RlZRMXVkczZ3NUh3dVV4clRwa3p5R0MtOTJnYVllVG1tSGx4MWZaMUlBLWdXb3Bwa19YWVdTdkVpV2xXOHIwcDM3WjFjVFFTQ0pYU2pucW9uWlFUQ2p1eFhQZzlhMm5hMXhTM0tqMU1tSnRjYkdh0gGmAUFVX3lxTFBrWTJjbmdNdDB5WmU0OWNwM2hHR3Bmd0xFTE15Um9DWm5DeElCWjBuSkJtazVRYUNOWl9FcXYzQVJfRTVsNnVGbGlkNU1HaEhad3VoN3ZTdUVGRHZiSGRQbEZTVG82c0Z2X3hGeXJWdFVqYmdROXN5UldtalgtX2hOMEI4Q1VZZ1dCS0t0ZGRmZWpTbEYtMk1ScXdDY2dRaGR2clRMbUE?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump's Defense pick goes on offense as support grows for Hegseth confirmation</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxOLU5QbUJ1WFRXUVFuTUVwMEdCaEx6N1BLNWZSOG9nXzZtSHBPdC1LZ0RWbk4zaGNtNzZCbXo4ekhRODhRMTlQR3hXMWhuamF3dEEtd0J5M1dxMEtPdmkxV0NJOFQwbDExU21OdTBVWjExNFV5UmJmampzakVJWi1pUmNzbXMwS19LM2xr?oc=5" target="_blank">Key Republican senator reports ‘good discussions’ with Pete Hegseth</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPd0pmaFJVam1TNVl0SUFwekhYczFyTmhQYS1TU21rZGQ5bk12VjhWNlNpUkFyZGJGeVFaUU1VajJCS3hWaHk5RERSc2I1aWdVeXV5d3FhckVNMG5OeTFVTThCWm1oX2ZjcmFPeDNZeTRQbTlDeElVNkxKcm9pLWI5QXBkUHFfWnZzc2hYNU9ROGxTRzhCb3Z2Z1FR?oc=5" target="_blank">How Trump allies brought Hegseth back from the brink</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQdF9vNDNub2pHSG5KenZ6ZEtsSVVLQUx6MUVJUkRFd3ZXR1AtWTVyWk1oSzN3M0o4YnlIS193ZXdpeVBId1FYVkx1NDljSkdTSFc5WTFJVnF4aHQtRUd0dkwxaVZLNlJJT2l3c3lIZk1HVXk1VW52WjNCZGpabG83el92S2NCUQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQdF9vNDNub2pHSG5KenZ6ZEtsSVVLQUx6MUVJUkRFd3ZXR1AtWTVyWk1oSzN3M0o4YnlIS193ZXdpeVBId1FYVkx1NDljSkdTSFc5WTFJVnF4aHQtRUd0dkwxaVZLNlJJT2l3c3lIZk1HVXk1VW52WjNCZGpabG83el92S2NCUQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 01:30:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan's Defense Ministry says a large Chinese military force has been detected nearby - NPR]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPTmw1WWxlX1BacW9sOXluY3RQcHp2cWxuYVZWb2FWYm41Sm9XRDZZbGFZTjBpR0xDeGdDVGNHdmVWTEJ0dVVpQm14U2lUNEJpM1ZBMklYMkhwVzA5eTlBSDFpcURSMzVSVXlyR2M1aTJVUUoxYk5JNjF5Tno0dEFEUlZiUVhKNlZL?oc=5" target="_blank">Taiwan's Defense Ministry says a large Chinese military force has been detected nearby</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxQclYxR1h2WW0xMFV2NC1Ob2ZXLWhmS2ZQLU1ZYXFEcHFyVHJoOXdUakhMZ0wtZmxmVFFyYkhZMlYwSlN3QUlvLWJTRGRTdXJDSzE4RDVRMnZWd3pDZzZMVGhmcnl0eWJTcVBuYnVRS3B1UEt1Z2hyT2RLMWJKTkM0T0xCdkw5SXVRUEZqZjN2SWtlZ9IBiAFBVV95cUxNdjVjakt1NDVsanoyQUV2YnFHb01rY25OckR4UC0tZW9KVGZUeWVTQXIzN1pZM25aSW8tOFEzdTFURTZVY0NBU05iSEhOR1dBdzZpbmxraTZWM1ZORTkwX2FneXN3T3hVVmx6N241dC1hTGQyd1BNNWxFZ0NOaWotMW1zNUFUR2Qy?oc=5" target="_blank">China’s maritime movements around Taiwan are largest in decades, Taipei says</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxOSHRhWlRXTDhSY3ZxUG9QREFncEhWeS0zcHN5YjNoRkpWampZSllRejdXaFhqNjFuWTV1cnNZR25mblZfa3F5Z1hzRG5tTGFHd1BHWWZ2MUJvTmI3NFZUODYtay1ZSGtfZHQwS25leXZZZHFIZEltd0Fac25VMUs3ZE9KZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Taiwan Says China Has Deployed Largest Fleet of Ships in Decades</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxOcG5VS3M5RmhQS0pxOEFZcmpDYWJXWXJsSnYtLVBsNGFTTjZQTTB4eUlTWjQ5ZEZJYnZTVmlsc2ZCRHFzckkyRnFxbzkwQ1Z1ZkpRTjBNTHlrRnZWYXhIanFVN212b0o2M1lVMXFZdDVqRjB0Qk5JTWZ0Y0NZVW94S1VRT3J1OU01VnJJZVBGU0l3cF9mZmZYQ01JRzFxbl9QWkhzSFZWa003LWlnOTY40gG0AUFVX3lxTE1ITjQ3cW9CLWxjeEtFZFhyQ0dCek5aV01LWE4tY0wxV0R6NHc5X05oaThSN255S3c1alpUUFVueExoYmtGdlZEYW8yN3VZSzJrQ1BlV0VTRlBhUndYZ1lXbXZKdzV6dXFockhEd0FtS1RIakJMTnlfZDRrUlVzTS1XZS1QV2hRU0E2UEFkSUE4eUhjc2JhSnpsMnZ2cm1zQWZqSmJHZFlpbDljYldETldod19rWQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Chinese military makes massive deployment around Taiwan to send 'very simple' message</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxObXQ3MXhUc1ZnN0hTejdESGszbGFrOWJNWmJRanpKallKLVlHS2FtaVNRU2tkZEhXY3hRZVNPZjZRckVJZW1VeTZaV2JVSVI3TWJPUjFzd3l5S0gxYWdvaDc4M3l2Q2FDWUF3QUtPSkdzRzJJSnc2VTNXbU1VUXNjUEFjZmpWZklNQmpqRzhoSWxsX016cC0yeXJBSUhSQkpQRXJJRzJtM3N3SHZxNEFQeTJmeTRob3c?oc=5" target="_blank">China Stages Largest Show of Force in Decades After U.S. Visit by Taiwan’s Lai</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Wall Street Journal</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPTmw1WWxlX1BacW9sOXluY3RQcHp2cWxuYVZWb2FWYm41Sm9XRDZZbGFZTjBpR0xDeGdDVGNHdmVWTEJ0dVVpQm14U2lUNEJpM1ZBMklYMkhwVzA5eTlBSDFpcURSMzVSVXlyR2M1aTJVUUoxYk5JNjF5Tno0dEFEUlZiUVhKNlZL?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPTmw1WWxlX1BacW9sOXluY3RQcHp2cWxuYVZWb2FWYm41Sm9XRDZZbGFZTjBpR0xDeGdDVGNHdmVWTEJ0dVVpQm14U2lUNEJpM1ZBMklYMkhwVzA5eTlBSDFpcURSMzVSVXlyR2M1aTJVUUoxYk5JNjF5Tno0dEFEUlZiUVhKNlZL?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 14:49:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Saydnaya Prison: Mapping the Assads' 'human slaughterhouse' - BBC.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE9WanUyRm5yQ0ZpMUFFb2I3NlU2U21LUFJ3QnBJMVQ1ZlFaZmFIWHZPV1dHTFJlS2FVOVhmSXhWQzBhM2RkX1VWN19yN1pTYTNCSmo4NkwwcXAtd9IBX0FVX3lxTFBTQk1fYjhoNzMzNXFKVGlDYTl0NjREOG5TeENHNUJ3QzhSdW1keHE4eVpXUmJNcmViU1R5VE9JbkdRY0NBVmJ3ZUZrejRXMzAybTlTMkw3aE1YS3BUcXdZ?oc=5" target="_blank">Saydnaya Prison: Mapping the Assads' 'human slaughterhouse'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxNR0s2bUZ5NERTa201c3RnNGxPUGhFMFJjeFlTOE1aTmdsZ19Id0JoR3Y2aWIyTEp1VGN1LUR4Rms5NWtDNkVfMnFPdng0NXYxNjhuMlJwSVNDaWJiRUlYNnZXOFNkeDRlSUVTWkxwQUxWZ2Y1YmtpOUdHVkxvcjNiR19XWThwZ0tLVFhTczR5aw?oc=5" target="_blank">Clarissa Ward goes inside Syria’s infamous ‘slaughterhouse’ prison</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid0FVX3lxTE1lSVdidU8wR1RHMkpkbEFUWkVBUjlPUERXUG02cHl6REE0cHduUmlZMDBzaldrOFQ5YTE0Y01WZ1VJM0NzS3ZzVEh0TXBGYjloUmJPMWdoZ1Vkb1phLURRTl85TGdjT19NWjZDNEVoNUdKdWVFTWVr?oc=5" target="_blank">‘I will hunt them down’: Grief turns to fury as Syrians search for loved ones tortured by Assad’s regime</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo! Voices</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOaS1mdnZfbDFIbW4yU05PNklyV3I0ZXJ3ZUt3LXpTb001ZWh5VzZhWWVDU01MSXJ5dV9CNHVRNVhyOGNOazliUERFc1Qtd3R0YXJJcHNUNlY1Ny1xcHRCX1Byb0tQeHpYTFp3SHZ3eENGZkVDSmpLUncyY3ZHLTZoRmtwMURUcWFTR25EU2dWcnJhWVhSWEo4RnpjRjBJcmpSeEtlWnFoczJIdW16bXBlag?oc=5" target="_blank">Syrian rebels free prisoners from Assad's notorious dungeons who celebrate in Damascus streets</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxOeE1tUnpFR3lQNFJzRnd1cVN2R25mZlRZOHdlWlA0dDVTaVBpMnNzSDlEV1NZMGhhT1JULUlrbmVVcG14MmZYZ3hPZ2tHanlOMWhxLS0zU1BjTi1VTng0UjZoLWw0cDN2UVNpY290NjRUWmhrbE5CLWI4SG5nNDAwQ3NVMXhwclUxTldnMWIxbE1RSVdSZVNVQklUR1ZjMHRzZVQzN0N30gGrAUFVX3lxTE40MkFpdGd5NS15bUJjYTQ2OHFZYnl3Zlg5SnRrVnh6SjJIOU1paWt1QXN1aEk4RjJROHE5T0lidUNOYmdXcUlLM2pKbnVKZk5oTm9IS1VzS0VqZVItUVhUbURlc0ppOWpYTFJCZGswbk1LSloweE1XMzlDdEZKclRWYldxTFlpR3J5NFFoa2JuclRmbk1ILWoyZzhjcGZETlRKUUtBeEJrcms4QQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Al-Assad’s ‘human slaughterhouses’: What to know about Syria’s prisons</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Al Jazeera English</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE9WanUyRm5yQ0ZpMUFFb2I3NlU2U21LUFJ3QnBJMVQ1ZlFaZmFIWHZPV1dHTFJlS2FVOVhmSXhWQzBhM2RkX1VWN19yN1pTYTNCSmo4NkwwcXAtd9IBX0FVX3lxTFBTQk1fYjhoNzMzNXFKVGlDYTl0NjREOG5TeENHNUJ3QzhSdW1keHE4eVpXUmJNcmViU1R5VE9JbkdRY0NBVmJ3ZUZrejRXMzAybTlTMkw3aE1YS3BUcXdZ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE9WanUyRm5yQ0ZpMUFFb2I3NlU2U21LUFJ3QnBJMVQ1ZlFaZmFIWHZPV1dHTFJlS2FVOVhmSXhWQzBhM2RkX1VWN19yN1pTYTNCSmo4NkwwcXAtd9IBX0FVX3lxTFBTQk1fYjhoNzMzNXFKVGlDYTl0NjREOG5TeENHNUJ3QzhSdW1keHE4eVpXUmJNcmViU1R5VE9JbkdRY0NBVmJ3ZUZrejRXMzAybTlTMkw3aE1YS3BUcXdZ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 02:28:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea’s Opposition Leader Determined to Oust President Yoon After Martial Law - The New York Times]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNNUNFSkVtcDdIYzBtS1p4eGZqWkxoQmx4NmNsVnpRWWs4UWMtdUx0SlREV0E1YU8tQmlDeFRZNGJ4NHNhOU1TZ0ZFaEoxc1FCa1ZkZ2U5SEpRNDFleERkRjIxQS1tQjRjbUxESU1KTWw1amFBNGZhRG80eFM4eXJTSUJSTFBadDY3Q3NYMlhOb0tPdw?oc=5" target="_blank">South Korea’s Opposition Leader Determined to Oust President Yoon After Martial Law</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPWGt4dFNuWFVLempaRWMyNFQwbUhlRVY1V0kteVBVUkd5U2FUQ2hSWTlmMnd5N1NXeXVialNoUFBhVDY4SWM3MG84ZXMtWlN1VGQxQzJ4NDZsWW1hMjZKRzkxZ09uYVdWSzFlZEVnWERqWGlhU3lEaDdwcTFyOFlsdFRSSk10THBqb0hibnR5bkd2bnZGaEgxa2F3N0dZV3VwUmxFdU9xNVo?oc=5" target="_blank">South Korean prosecutors seek to arrest ex-defense minister over imposition of martial law</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxNNnpIeXJGak9sVVJESXdYa3dsUzhfOGlFcGFkTWF4SGtCYmlHVHNwV0ZvWWk1eXdvVE55WWVhcmcxOXY5enZ6aVF0Z0lWY0lQZEZOd2VsOFVGN3JuUVlyWHNfYXJ5T1pRTkVib1Q3OEFOQmNJQ0YwbFBnZ3FXRTk4dNIBd0FVX3lxTE1lYldkS3lXTldBTXFFempndWh4TjNtVEczMmdQZThtUXpzYzlfa1RZVFJjNzExNWQxRnlZUWVFRGxhdGM2d2RjbTcydENpWnJ3czJQaEppcHdfV0h0MlFOVDNFRC1oSS04ZkZqLV9XTDhfWDJMdjlj?oc=5" target="_blank">Martial law reversed in South Korea after president’s surprise decree sent shockwaves</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxNNl9zbW5LaUJVdXIxcENjUFRnTVNFZDk0RGt0NzRGMEdTYVJkeUR1YTJIV0pUc05WNjd3U1Z3d0J6TEppc2xUaVc5djhob2R6UDIzMG44RkJsbklRUVRZeFotdlBiWnhxblVEN0ZzaU53VGZ0cTRNY1RJSzJ2V3BEN3BmR1dSTU93U1RLZDV5UGlxMV9mYldDdU9UOFc5UDVYUUhvQkhBZlFLRUU0b3dnQWJkX3ozakJmOV95N3hpUFhqcEVvU3N3dFFJT0I0dw?oc=5" target="_blank">South Korea's Yoon gave orders to 'drag out' MPs during martial law, officer says</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPNnc1azJJWUp1SlRmLV9hZDB4dmdUaS1KcjRZc0FfWjJQWTJLRGhRTm9YYXlZa2c1LWRieW8xNEhZSjQtaGFsMXZvb1lYQlkyRnZPTXVSbTZxN2pEQjZ0RjhUUEQ4RGlEVlkwV1diNVhxbVlDMklqUkFUd1ZKYlNiTl9RMzBQT28zQ2R1VGRWZzU4WlB1SFplenphR2VfQTcxM0doVkVRZk3SAasBQVVfeXFMT3BJbXI5UzcwckYwc1ZaT01Pc1BXRFZjdDRUM1VXTGtLM1hVaWQ0amFUMXR1Q0RfTnhnWnNhWV9xTlVaYWU2UGFzb3RsajBqRTJ1WXZEaW9GQVB4ODBLX0p1M09BUy1OaGc2MXhwcGR3OUx1Q0JDbHdKNDRxd3dTaTBieWpKd25YNkxEbTdYbUN2SVZRWHdwYlpINTZhRjM1TDFrZ2poQjF6S3Fv?oc=5" target="_blank">South Korea’s leadership unclear as Yoon struggles to retain power</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">VOA Asia</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNNUNFSkVtcDdIYzBtS1p4eGZqWkxoQmx4NmNsVnpRWWs4UWMtdUx0SlREV0E1YU8tQmlDeFRZNGJ4NHNhOU1TZ0ZFaEoxc1FCa1ZkZ2U5SEpRNDFleERkRjIxQS1tQjRjbUxESU1KTWw1amFBNGZhRG80eFM4eXJTSUJSTFBadDY3Q3NYMlhOb0tPdw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNNUNFSkVtcDdIYzBtS1p4eGZqWkxoQmx4NmNsVnpRWWs4UWMtdUx0SlREV0E1YU8tQmlDeFRZNGJ4NHNhOU1TZ0ZFaEoxc1FCa1ZkZ2U5SEpRNDFleERkRjIxQS1tQjRjbUxESU1KTWw1amFBNGZhRG80eFM4eXJTSUJSTFBadDY3Q3NYMlhOb0tPdw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 11:12:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[About 26 killed in strike in Beit Hanoun in north Gaza, rescue workers say]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:56:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia’s elite sound the alarm on the economy amid high interest rates]]></title><description><![CDATA[Squeezed by Western sanctions and soaring interest rates, Russia’s businesses fear bankruptcies as President Vladimir Putin pushes ahead with the Ukraine war.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/12/10/russia-economy-rates-central-bank/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/12/10/russia-economy-rates-central-bank/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:46:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Trump White House looks set to recognize Somaliland as the world’s newest country]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1hb3pf3/a_trump_white_house_looks_set_to_recognize/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/UvHliwJjOylJAPoL4I6wKR6jVSCXM-oHrd-1WwMfp_I.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=0f703836541f9a176ef3041fca58c693fa15ca8a" alt="A Trump White House looks set to recognize Somaliland as the world’s newest country" title="A Trump White House looks set to recognize Somaliland as the world’s newest country" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/semafornews"> /u/semafornews </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/12/10/2024/somaliland-trump-white-house-looks-set-to-recognize-the-region?utm_campaign=semaforreddit">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1hb3pf3/a_trump_white_house_looks_set_to_recognize/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1hb3pf3/a_trump_white_house_looks_set_to_recognize/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1hb3pf3/a_trump_white_house_looks_set_to_recognize/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/semafornews]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:02:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Switzerland suspends Syria asylum proceedings after Assad's fall]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1hazqzd/switzerland_suspends_syria_asylum_proceedings/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/Xy8nHEHaTYrqGawYODm7NgYgbOYYq6W-p-W9FzGJNq0.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=99616f00c46a3b62d6013249b3f93b1cc6c3f76b" alt="Switzerland suspends Syria asylum proceedings after Assad's fall" title="Switzerland suspends Syria asylum proceedings after Assad's fall" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/doopityWoop22"> /u/doopityWoop22 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/world-news/switzerland-suspends-syria-asylum-proceedings-after-assads-fall/articleshow/116161829.cms?from=mdr">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1hazqzd/switzerland_suspends_syria_asylum_proceedings/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1hazqzd/switzerland_suspends_syria_asylum_proceedings/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1hazqzd/switzerland_suspends_syria_asylum_proceedings/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/doopityWoop22]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 11:32:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[France begins military withdrawal from Chad as influence in Africa wanes]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Senegal also requests departure of French troops, saying it is ‘not compatible’ with country’s sovereignty</p><p>France has begun recalling its military assets from its former ally Chad, the latest blow to its dwindling influence across its former colonies in Africa.</p><p>Two Mirage fighter jets returned to a base in eastern France on Tuesday, said the army spokesperson Col Guillaume Vernet. “It marks the beginning of the return of French equipment stationed in [Chadian capital] N’Djamena,” Vernet said.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/dec/10/france-begins-military-withdrawal-from-chad-as-influence-in-africa-wanes">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/dec/10/france-begins-military-withdrawal-from-chad-as-influence-in-africa-wanes</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/dec/10/france-begins-military-withdrawal-from-chad-as-influence-in-africa-wanes</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:51:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Buildings in Damascus on fire as suspected Israeli strikes hit Syrian capital]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/buildings-damascus-fire-suspected-israeli-223323139.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/buildings-damascus-fire-suspected-israeli-223323139.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 22:33:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Venezuela's Gonzalez plans to return to take over as president]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/venezuelas-gonzalez-plans-return-over-140015467.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/venezuelas-gonzalez-plans-return-over-140015467.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 14:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[France flies out 2 Mirage fighter jets from Chad to signal beginning of military withdrawal]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/france-flies-2-mirage-fighter-130731473.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/france-flies-2-mirage-fighter-130731473.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 13:07:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>