<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:17:59 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:17:59 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Trump’s health care plan exposes the truth about his “populism”]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Trump, on the left, and Vance, on the right, are both wearing blue suits, white shirts and red ties, and smiling." data-caption="Republican presidential nominee and former President Donald Trump, and Republican vice presidential nominee Sen. J.D. Vance (R-OH) on September 11, 2024, in New York City. | Michael M. Santiago/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Michael M. Santiago/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2171331803.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Republican presidential nominee and former President Donald Trump, and Republican vice presidential nominee Sen. J.D. Vance (R-OH) on September 11, 2024, in New York City. | Michael M. Santiago/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Sen. J.D. Vance has fashioned himself as a different kind of Republican.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He is an “<a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2024/07/18/jd-vance-world-view-sources-00168984">anti-regime</a>,” “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2ZbsiKEhy-8">anti-elitist</a>” populist who believes that America’s social order is “tilted toward the few.” He has decried traditional economic conservatism as <a href="https://www.americamagazine.org/politics-society/2023/12/04/jd-vance-ohio-catholic-values-246559">an ideology</a> that “subordinates human life and community to a false ideal of the market somehow existing independent of our society.” His conception of a just economy is purportedly informed <a href="https://thelampmagazine.com/blog/how-i-joined-the-resistance">by Catholic social teaching</a> — specifically, the imperative to be “sympathetic with the meek and poor of the world without treating them primarily as victims” and “protective of children and families and with the things necessary to ensure they thrive.” In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_8TlBHRtrvM">his address to the Republican National Convention</a>, Vance suggested that Trump holds similar priorities, lauding him for narrowing the “divide between the few, with their power and comfort in Washington, and the rest of us.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And yet, many of the Republican ticket’s actual policies bear little trace of this skepticism of markets or concern for the left-behind.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is especially true of Trump’s newly revealed health care plan — or, at least, what the campaign has revealed of it. On Sunday, Vance <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/trump-health-plan-charge-more-preexisting-conditions-concept-plan-j-d-vance.html">disclosed</a> that the new, “anti-regime” Republican Party’s plan for fixing America’s medical system is… to deregulate the health insurance market, so that insurers can refuse coverage to those who need treatment the most. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The GOP ticket’s dismally familiar health care plan tells us two things about the party’s ascendant populism. First, it is much more novel in its rhetoric than its governing priorities. And second, even where it plausibly privileges “the many” over “the few,” it does not prioritize the weak over the strong.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Trump’s health care policy privileges the healthy over the sick</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&nbsp;At last week’s presidential debate, Trump conceded that he did not have a health care plan so much as “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/12/opinion/trump-harris-concepts-obamacare.html">concepts of a plan</a>.” This admission was a political liability: If a candidate who’s been promising to replace Obamacare for <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/healthcare/249697-trump-replace-obamacare-with-something-terrific/">a decade</a> is still brainstorming his alternative, he might not make the most diligent or decisive commander in chief.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet actually spelling out what the right (still) believes about health care policy might be even more damaging. Or so <a href="https://x.com/atrupar/status/1835322314923053187">Vance’s remarks</a> on <em>Meet the Press </em>Sunday would suggest.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On that program, NBC’s Kristen Welker asked Vance to explain what — if anything — Trump planned to change about America’s health care system. The Republican VP nominee replied, “He, of course, does have a plan for how to fix American health care, but a lot of it goes down, Kristen, to deregulating insurance markets, so that people can actually choose a plan that makes sense for them.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance proceeded to say Trump would protect people with preexisting conditions and ensure everyone has access to the doctors they need. But he did not specify how Trump would do this. More pertinently, the one concrete policy Vance did detail would actually involve making health care coverage less affordable for those with chronic illnesses. Here’s the relevant part of Vance’s answer:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>[Trump would] </em><em>implement a deregulatory agenda so that people can pick a health care plan that fits them. Think about it: A young American doesn’t have the same health care needs as a 65-year-old American. And a 65-year-old American in good health has much different health care needs than a 65-year-old American with a chronic condition.</em></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>We want to make sure everybody is covered, but the best way to do that is to actually promote more choice in our health care system and not have a one-size-fits all approach that puts a lot of the same people into the same insurance pools, into the same risk pools, that actually makes it harder for people to make the right choices for their families.</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance’s sunny rhetoric here disguises his plan’s inegalitarian moral priorities.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is true that the young and healthy have different medical needs than the old and sick. And before the Affordable Care Act’s regulations, the former could sometimes procure cheaper insurance tailored to their (currently) limited needs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this came at a social cost. Insurers were able to offer cheap health coverage to those who barely needed it by screening out those with preexisting conditions. In Vance’s terminology, they constructed low-risk pools: by only including people who were unlikely to require expensive treatments in their plans, they could profitably provide low-premium insurance to the young and well.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, sick and/or older Americans on the individual insurance market either went without coverage or were forced to pay dramatically higher premiums in order to cover the high cost of their care. Some state governments tried to defray this cost somewhat by subsidizing high-risk pools. But enrollees still paid <a href="https://www.kff.org/affordable-care-act/issue-brief/high-risk-pools-for-uninsurable-individuals/">much higher premiums</a> than the typical market rate, and their coverage often excluded the treatments they needed most.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Affordable Care Act effectively forced the healthy to subsidize the sick. It required insurers to include those with preexisting conditions in their plans and cover all medically necessary procedures. To guarantee that insurers could still turn a profit, and that coverage remained (at least somewhat) affordable for all, the government provided consumers with insurance subsidies.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The upshot of all this was that coverage became a little more expensive for some healthy people, while growing much cheaper for the old and seriously ill. If one believes that we live in a society — in which certain communitarian obligations take precedence over individual freedom — then this would seem like a good trade. Better to make a healthy 27-year-old pay a slightly higher premium than force a cancer-stricken 55-year-old to forgo treatment, or incur massive debts to finance chemotherapy — especially since the former can, at any moment, find themselves in the latter’s predicament.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Notably, Americans already accept this arrangement as common sense when it comes to employer-based insurance, which covers a slight <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/323076/share-of-us-population-with-employer-health-insurance/#:~:text=Percentage%20of%20U.S.%20population%20with%20employment%2Dbased%20health%20insurance%201987%2D2022&amp;text=In%202022%2C%2054.5%20percent%20of,insurance%20from%201987%20to%202022.">majority</a> of the population. A company’s older or sicker employees do not generally pay higher premiums than their younger or healthier colleagues. Instead, all pool their risks together, with the medically fortunate subsidizing those who aren’t as blessed. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And yet, for the minority of Americans who purchase insurance on the individual market, Vance wants to unwind this compulsory solidarity. He aims to increase the entrepreneurial freedom of insurers, and discretion of consumers, at the expense of the needy. Some would say this sounds a lot like a policy that “subordinates human life and community to a false ideal of the market.” Vance evidently disagrees.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Vance and Trump are for the populism of the privileged</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance’s vision for health care policy helps clarify the character of the right’s burgeoning “populism.” On trade and immigration, Vance’s ideology may prize a nationalistic conception of the common good above free markets. But on most economic questions, its iconoclastic rhetoric belies its fealty to conservative orthodoxy — and thus, to “<a href="https://thelampmagazine.com/blog/how-i-joined-the-resistance">the ruling class</a>” whom Vance loves to deride.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Trump’s running mate, Vance is campaigning on <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/07/16/2024/trump-backs-a-corporate-tax-cut-which-jd-vance-opposed-two-months-ago">tax cuts for corporations</a> and the wealthy and deregulation for health insurers. The rest of Trump’s economic agenda is rather hazy. But if his first term is any guide, it would also involve <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/unprecedented-the-trump-nlrbs-attack-on-workers-rights/">curtailing workers’ collective bargaining rights</a>, <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/09/trump-trumka-afl-cio-labor-day-15-ways-hurt-american-worker-populism.html">reducing workplace safety standards</a>, and attempting to <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2017/05/biggest-outrage-of-trumpcare-continues-to-be-medicaid-cuts.html">throw millions off of Medicaid</a>. Vance has not seen fit to criticize any aspect of this record.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All this raises the question of what, precisely, Vance means when he decries “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/magazine/2022/01/04/jd-vance-hillbilly-elegy-radicalization/">neoliberalism</a>,” and says he wishes to serve the many and not the few.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In my estimation, he offered a clue to his intentions the day before his appearance on <em>Meet the Press</em>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance’s main preoccupation in recent weeks has been the Haitian immigrant community of Springfield, Ohio, and its <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/371466/trump-haitians-dogs-cats-pets-springfield-alt-right">fictional attacks</a> on longtime residents’ pets. On Saturday, the left-wing commentator <a href="https://x.com/krystalball/status/1835034805303464317">Krystal Ball</a> <a href="https://x.com/JDVance/status/1835080971596841396">took exception</a> to Vance’s hateful rhetoric, which had helped <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/371855/trump-vance-springfield-ohio-racist-conspiracy-theories-haitian-immigrants">inspire bomb threats in Springfield</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance replied to Ball’s critique by <a href="https://x.com/JDVance/status/1835080971596841396">accusing her</a> of believing that “20,000 cheap laborers should be dropped on a small Ohio town.” To Vance, Ball’s intolerance for his demonization of Haitian immigrants proved that she was not really a “populist,” but rather (perhaps unwittingly) a proponent of “neoliberalism.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That latter term is used to describe a <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-big-idea/2017/7/18/15992226/neoliberalism-chait-austerity-democratic-party-sanders-clinton">multitude of different beliefs</a>. But used pejoratively, neoliberalism denotes a commitment to unfettered capitalism above all else.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Vance, deregulating insurance markets at the expense of the vulnerable is not neoliberal or anti-populist. But arguing that politicians should not spread incendiary lies about immigrants is.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Populism, so construed, is not about supporting the weak in their conflicts with the powerful. “The few” it takes aim at are not the economic elite (whom it wishes to shower in tax relief and regulatory favors), but rather, certain categories of the disadvantaged.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Foreign-born immigrants from poor countries comprise a small minority of the U.S. population. And the same is true of the chief beneficiaries of the ACA’s regulatory reforms. According to <a href="https://www.kff.org/affordable-care-act/issue-brief/high-risk-pools-for-uninsurable-individuals/">a 2017 report</a> from the Kaiser Family Foundation, “in any given year, the healthiest 50% of the population accounts for less than 3% of total health care expenditures, while the sickest 10% account for nearly two-thirds of population health spending.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When Vance suggests that the interests of native-born Americans take absolute precedence over those of Haitian immigrants — or that the healthy should not have to pool their insurance risks with the sick — he is technically arguing for the many, not the few. (Of course, the idea that immigrants and native-born Americans cannot mutually prosper is contradicted by more or less the entirety of our nation’s history. And the concept of denying health care to the old and sick <a href="https://www.vox.com/21502189/preexisting-conditions-trump-republicans">is deeply unpopular</a>.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Republican ticket’s problem with free markets, meanwhile, is less that they reinforce privilege than that they sometimes erode it. To the invisible hand, the Haitian worker is not morally distinguishable from the native-born one. To Vance, however, the American-born worker who wishes to improve his station through toil and risk-taking is a hero — while the Haitian immigrant who wishes to do the same is a “cheap laborer” and social menace.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be sure, Vance has occasionally advocated for “populist” policies that <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361417/jd-vance-rnc-trump-vice-president-economy-business">aren’t inegalitarian</a>. But in allying with Trump, he’s whittled his populism down to a reactionary core. The GOP is for the many over the few only insofar as they are for the privileged over the disadvantaged. Vance can call that “anti-regime” post-neoliberalism. I’d call it establishment conservatism.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/372635/trump-health-care-plan-vance-preexisting-conditions</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/372635/trump-health-care-plan-vance-preexisting-conditions</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Levitz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:10:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel Warns War "Centre Of Gravity Moving North" Amid Hezbollah Escalation]]></title><description><![CDATA[In Israel's first reaction since thousands of blasts rocked Lebanon over two days, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's defence minister has announced that the "centre of gravity" of the Middle East conflict is "moving north".]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-warns-war-centre-of-gravity-moving-north-amid-hezbollah-escalation-6596774</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-warns-war-centre-of-gravity-moving-north-amid-hezbollah-escalation-6596774</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 17:54:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US Warns Against Further Middle East Escalation After Lebanon Blasts]]></title><description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Wednesday warned against the risk of escalation in the Middle East after the detonation of thousands of Hezbollah pagers threatened to derail his latest regional diplomacy push.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-warns-against-further-middle-east-escalation-after-lebanon-blasts-6596480</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-warns-against-further-middle-east-escalation-after-lebanon-blasts-6596480</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 17:07:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Republicans poised to reject funding bill with shutdown just around the corner - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxNWW5TelE3c0hoWVhwdURwZWw5RXltdXZjbU5VMk1scmJnSXg5VWhsRkJ3TDU0U05ZaW5sMUZVbGIzODF1T2FoWFhRNnI3aEV3MjFMWHB2UmdoM0NFMEpnT29IWGd0X2RzeWFuUXRqczlwT2RlS2ZlX0Zyd0pOQ2pKVHJ3T2tGLVNSNGk1MkhxaFBOQmFQdUF1cm9IY29NTGx1WFFpR2RaN2t5WFJkbnhicHNn0gFWQVVfeXFMTk9hcC05SzdlNnUxUUtZWkY1eUVRcGd5SlNjU21jYkRXSWY2aWRjbWNfQWZFazU2aXpCOW5DOHpiREhFLUhtbFBuMDlKNHQxV3hBY1RieXc?oc=5" target="_blank">House Republicans poised to reject funding bill with shutdown just around the corner</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxQZVJva2RBMUxiZHhCalhoa0gxcGJrTUdnYzBIOVNhSnBrcHMwMkt3M05OaXNqU3R5NWN5V3lWVklySGx1MURBZG5rQTZJdkdKbmxoY0FmNG5oVmhaMnM1X2w0TGJfQWNQX2RvOXBSRGNiWjVsWUJVckJubzZlQ3N6YVlRbmlQUFUyLUN2d0xKSnpvbUZC?oc=5" target="_blank">House looks poised to reject GOP bill to avert government shutdown</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxNVUtodW4wbVBCZUxtcDRJQ1NiZzZ4OXRQdzdBTTNVX0NwdDRDQlUzWm9ZeWxsWkUxRUdXcmtzc2dmM1NmamxjWDRYLXVmTlQtMXVHbktCcUIxNFp2djJLOUJVY281Wmc0VjBaUHdVM09zaUNJdUhza2E5THVNMlFvZkRwV09rOGtMSVNiWWd3ZTJ6ZGM0UDVBM1lFdVJsU25CZUh1LTlUWDhCVHZVQktGTlY4dU5ITlpRNzlGSTRFWm11RkM4R0NzSTZsd0YxQllOR1NhUjdtWHhLTU5kQUJ3TnF2akVnTGRLVk1Tb9IB8gFBVV95cUxNVGdMNTNRXzJpS1NlSnBNY3RzRG9NYzZyU053VTIwQVVPbW1ROGt2aWtaZzZEeWtBZW1EQURwRDlHU1NrNWZhS20xcHVSampzdzRkZGJ3a3hydVFzeFNyaEhid0MyeHJFOUItQkZjLUIwa3BSaThhMGxBS09va2FGNm84NG50eFppcHFhTF9sVHJVYXA1YWJULWhnNjcwcExWRHlKU2EzMmQya2ZhaEM5eE16aXV0YjgwVzJYRElWZkJhYk1aN0N3WmhhVTlkRWotN1pHc3BMODBZOXpzWWZNbU54Z1B6WGFRVHk3aExTNzladw?oc=5" target="_blank">Speaker Johnson determined to hold spending bill vote despite Democrats opposition due to proof of citizenship mandate</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">PBS NewsHour</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOUXBrYjJKdDRtS3Z4ajRYOWdORzhLWmpFS1RUN19WeTBycGJOaFRCWlJuY1pFUHNQOS01X0x6NlFNM0JNbEJ5NDhLSkVjbW5PQXplZ05xMkNlWWZBTk5IaUNjZW1fVW1QYkR1N1VveGpsNndhcUZpOFozb0hsTjRWdjJaTnB0R1Yta1ozbDZkV2FCOVFpRlVTVXFEQndBZW4wUFdUTHh5TGNuTHZaN0xId9IBtgFBVV95cUxQS2EyVVpzS3NWa1MzbnVPbWsxbE03dVBxbUlvS2FXQzJNQW1FZGR1SkxadVQ4Q183Y3NzM1Ytdl92XzJlV2pUdlJmRW9GZWtva3dGU0x5QU92cUMxTDhMMEZPcHBaV29mWkJjUnU4NnMtMVZrdlc4TWRpNHFqWDhVejMyckpVVnZYSGdyck9lM2pwb0NmZFJES3hpNUhrZlo5TTVmb21pLXg3SzFSYUJvV1JZOVBDQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">House GOP braces for government funding chaos as Republican rebels mutiny before vote</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQb1JRS1dKUUNTOWhYSDh2a0lQYk11NzNpSGNNRldrUl8yVFp0LUFyczJCVjVvYjUzdll0LTlRSkgyRUotUlVSSW9YenNUdVE2Yy1DVnRaNGFudDVsWlRQN1ZCNmtiLV81d1lXSG5MTDhheHhkZ3FKZHJ4N29adTdsU2VCZnF6M1VPNHVCQzZn?oc=5" target="_blank">Mike Johnson leaves colleagues baffled with his "puzzling" shutdown strategy</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Axios</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxNWW5TelE3c0hoWVhwdURwZWw5RXltdXZjbU5VMk1scmJnSXg5VWhsRkJ3TDU0U05ZaW5sMUZVbGIzODF1T2FoWFhRNnI3aEV3MjFMWHB2UmdoM0NFMEpnT29IWGd0X2RzeWFuUXRqczlwT2RlS2ZlX0Zyd0pOQ2pKVHJ3T2tGLVNSNGk1MkhxaFBOQmFQdUF1cm9IY29NTGx1WFFpR2RaN2t5WFJkbnhicHNn0gFWQVVfeXFMTk9hcC05SzdlNnUxUUtZWkY1eUVRcGd5SlNjU21jYkRXSWY2aWRjbWNfQWZFazU2aXpCOW5DOHpiREhFLUhtbFBuMDlKNHQxV3hBY1RieXc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxNWW5TelE3c0hoWVhwdURwZWw5RXltdXZjbU5VMk1scmJnSXg5VWhsRkJ3TDU0U05ZaW5sMUZVbGIzODF1T2FoWFhRNnI3aEV3MjFMWHB2UmdoM0NFMEpnT29IWGd0X2RzeWFuUXRqczlwT2RlS2ZlX0Zyd0pOQ2pKVHJ3T2tGLVNSNGk1MkhxaFBOQmFQdUF1cm9IY29NTGx1WFFpR2RaN2t5WFJkbnhicHNn0gFWQVVfeXFMTk9hcC05SzdlNnUxUUtZWkY1eUVRcGd5SlNjU21jYkRXSWY2aWRjbWNfQWZFazU2aXpCOW5DOHpiREhFLUhtbFBuMDlKNHQxV3hBY1RieXc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:42:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Latest: Trump to campaign in New York and Harris will speak at Hispanic leadership conference - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxNVUpBa3J6VnV2S2RsTkZHRjR3RGlFcUJJTGw4bjFrZHVrZ1RQeURBbHk3cEwweVB0N29nNUVwdm9odldTNGh2NHpyM1ZJNHJEbGJpakN4TF9lQ09vMTZQWW5KYy1qeGdiektTOUVPSmpZQ3M1V1ppN3Z6SEJzOXREZ0N2U2U0YWhGSW1LRkdrOUlmdFp0elh3?oc=5" target="_blank">The Latest: Trump to campaign in New York and Harris will speak at Hispanic leadership conference</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxNd2pSWWJ3WEk4TndnTl9tcTI0aXo1d3p4bG5LN2k4bG1LWlAyOTVBLWYwSW44MldtRmJCX0ljNzBVTE9XRnAtaTVGZ2p2YlhVRF9udzZNNWdDZWF6TWhUaEtxODFSMWpMQ29aTzhzRXNKSkRJdnF3OVYzOW5TOVliRlh6OE1xNENtVWVDMGJ3YzNUb1hqVWwyNU9jT09vUnp4aWtWdHF2SUZ1UHdsZUhDR19YTWRDLUtiUjhGONIBvAFBVV95cUxPR2JyWVRPaThzaFplNWRjZzZ3dTAtdW9WNlVQYlpFSHVZOHlQNjdXYk5rUS1tbHl6Q3ptWG0zaW05cDEtbnFVeWh3bVRhRjN6eTVSS1hQVVNmVm9hUUo2Z3BobWRUOFBiaEs2TDVVbHdsdldZUGNwNUJiSkJrSkNSTENhU3RTU0NTZEZYMjBVTUw4bE1kZmUxR2tZY2pLaHg5Vm41TlVRc0lIQnVNMWFHNkc1QWtQUVdNNGwxOA?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris condemns Trump’s plan for mass deportations in address at Latino leadership conference – live</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMickFVX3lxTE5XX09MSDhZZ0FTLWNYaHVjdGF2TFBBdFFZc2YtZ21ORzRYZVdDLVpzNmNMWUZidmNfMThOejBfVjhVMU1TOTdLcEEzYkN1V2djSTRmZHc4NENMTFFzdEc0eExwUlZMckVTdjlXeFpyVGZIZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Election 2024 Live Updates: Harris Courts Latinos as Trump Preps for Long Island Rally</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTFBjWTV2SU9lakd0eXB3MXl6b0lSenRMTVF5bWw0cUgweU83WW0zOElIcUd6WC0wQmRfRVM5QmEtMzJFTEJEdG5iSlg4TlowOTJXbzgtcGM1RnphMEk3RkZYeXNBX0U2UTVPMndKc2hrZ1k5SVYzT3A5TjJWRnFjZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Why is Trump campaigning in blue New York?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxPN3RhcVV2NlcyLWdTWWN5bGVFdDR5czVIUWJaekI3Y2FXbW96bDZsdHdwMU5tN2l1UzF6N3Q3WXI3UmtMMW44MVpYUTd4TzlVS2U4YkhVZktmTG44VEpKYXZQVDJ5bHlLd2tGTk9Ed0hsQm1uSEpiVDNmOW04NUxFY2ZSdU1FNDY4bkFlM211VG5VRGxaTzJMLVVNZFhyYWpKMFpHaw?oc=5" target="_blank">The latest on the 2024 presidential campaign</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxNVUpBa3J6VnV2S2RsTkZHRjR3RGlFcUJJTGw4bjFrZHVrZ1RQeURBbHk3cEwweVB0N29nNUVwdm9odldTNGh2NHpyM1ZJNHJEbGJpakN4TF9lQ09vMTZQWW5KYy1qeGdiektTOUVPSmpZQ3M1V1ppN3Z6SEJzOXREZ0N2U2U0YWhGSW1LRkdrOUlmdFp0elh3?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxNVUpBa3J6VnV2S2RsTkZHRjR3RGlFcUJJTGw4bjFrZHVrZ1RQeURBbHk3cEwweVB0N29nNUVwdm9odldTNGh2NHpyM1ZJNHJEbGJpakN4TF9lQ09vMTZQWW5KYy1qeGdiektTOUVPSmpZQ3M1V1ppN3Z6SEJzOXREZ0N2U2U0YWhGSW1LRkdrOUlmdFp0elh3?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kentucky governor bans use of 'conversion therapy' with executive order - ABC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQajFWZVF2eUtyOWVBbjBWb0N0WDFOVTRnVGpkRFlwWXRxdDF2eGptN2gwWEZpTG5ldWhXSmZRaGFoQXdaUG1xYWVEbUJSM2p5TGRvYkN5MHdDMVpGZDQ5azBQOExFR1RqTi0wc3BTREExR213SjhJSFpLczRHV0RDY0NqRW94NThVQW4tWlBabURJNzUwanBWd1cxMU9jeHhfX0EwaW9R0gGrAUFVX3lxTE9fNU1ETjlMTkxTZVV1d25uQjRadWc3Sm5qX0Y2TDlzc2tBNURTWC1FenZrbktQUHlqcW05dDBWVWhxM0xNVzFRcEtLLWxyMnBweVhUamRRUGJ6NHN3dXF4TmVvWkszaUJuMk1MYlhYUVI1eHBwbDNVWW5hczJiRmwzVGtxVVVwdTNucGhES3N2c1VMTXdQUVRZTTVKaXpmSWs5dHB3cnJNdmZITQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Kentucky governor bans use of 'conversion therapy' with executive order</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2ktNGU2dURCRXN0b2gtT1B5cll5Z0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQajFWZVF2eUtyOWVBbjBWb0N0WDFOVTRnVGpkRFlwWXRxdDF2eGptN2gwWEZpTG5ldWhXSmZRaGFoQXdaUG1xYWVEbUJSM2p5TGRvYkN5MHdDMVpGZDQ5azBQOExFR1RqTi0wc3BTREExR213SjhJSFpLczRHV0RDY0NqRW94NThVQW4tWlBabURJNzUwanBWd1cxMU9jeHhfX0EwaW9R0gGrAUFVX3lxTE9fNU1ETjlMTkxTZVV1d25uQjRadWc3Sm5qX0Y2TDlzc2tBNURTWC1FenZrbktQUHlqcW05dDBWVWhxM0xNVzFRcEtLLWxyMnBweVhUamRRUGJ6NHN3dXF4TmVvWkszaUJuMk1MYlhYUVI1eHBwbDNVWW5hczJiRmwzVGtxVVVwdTNucGhES3N2c1VMTXdQUVRZTTVKaXpmSWs5dHB3cnJNdmZITQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQajFWZVF2eUtyOWVBbjBWb0N0WDFOVTRnVGpkRFlwWXRxdDF2eGptN2gwWEZpTG5ldWhXSmZRaGFoQXdaUG1xYWVEbUJSM2p5TGRvYkN5MHdDMVpGZDQ5azBQOExFR1RqTi0wc3BTREExR213SjhJSFpLczRHV0RDY0NqRW94NThVQW4tWlBabURJNzUwanBWd1cxMU9jeHhfX0EwaW9R0gGrAUFVX3lxTE9fNU1ETjlMTkxTZVV1d25uQjRadWc3Sm5qX0Y2TDlzc2tBNURTWC1FenZrbktQUHlqcW05dDBWVWhxM0xNVzFRcEtLLWxyMnBweVhUamRRUGJ6NHN3dXF4TmVvWkszaUJuMk1MYlhYUVI1eHBwbDNVWW5hczJiRmwzVGtxVVVwdTNucGhES3N2c1VMTXdQUVRZTTVKaXpmSWs5dHB3cnJNdmZITQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:56:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump, Vance's Haitian smears "need to stop," Ohio Gov. DeWine says - Axios]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxNM1ROWWNNcmpIWlFRX2hTS2hhQjlHQ1N1T2lvQWswTU5vUEZTMkloZkdCYjVTdWdheGxsblZZdDQyZ0g0THpKVV8zdzEyNW5TRkItOUx0YkZvM1NHLW1QSThMZXVvWjZ1em5pMkFmdlVjX1lmQjdtYkFSa1ExNDlvMUV6OA?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump, Vance's Haitian smears "need to stop," Ohio Gov. DeWine says</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Axios</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPRjFZSnpqM0xmMDBFdDV1WDhROXdtOWdIejNrN3htSUJ2b2Q0aGwwSUMyemt5aS1hZ2ktMFVfQmtiVG1YVG9rUnM4X3hNN3lYcDJIZ29yWlNacTNibzZWc19hYnJWSnN6Z3NXb05CbnNZa1lHRV9wSlVwYkt1M1pDOGlOM2dwb2hTOExZbjVIXzdIT19RbjNEcVlUNVJBYmk2dmJ4ZzRR0gGcAUFVX3lxTE8zcVNiWXhQLXBPazk2YlNTNGh2bXFXdjB6LWJoQXBnQlRPckZfYjk4NVZMM0NqT1M1d3UyaWRXR0EteklJcEg5bTJEMm0wLVhHenZZMG9MV0JJQ0laUWIzd0RWMHVVTjIxRXVnU28wLXhYN1Jkc0FSVFB5NHJiZGpzWnQ4SmNNRS0wRl9RMFhTXzdRNWJLMkNDVVo5MQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Ohio Republicans are being very, very careful in correcting Trump and Vance</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxQSV9CTVU1a25ERkpvLWZTbFRKdXZtX3BrZUV1RnJQV1FnY3VFalRUUllnS011RXozN0sydS1FZVA4bmY2eW5NUUh5NXRoMlQ1cXkxUzJ5dWxCaE9RZjFSR21BaUQxSGw2S3I0WjFUUEI3cklSR3lOVlgzMWlKc2FCNms5aUxqUXh1QkVBdF9kcV9zV01pMU9mZXNJOVU?oc=5" target="_blank">Opinion | Trump Knows What He’s Doing in Springfield. So Does Vance.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxONnE3aWV2SHNiWWNoVmxRTHZJRWZnMEUxbmozSE5xSURHWTlHR0FXSWtzUHJ0ZE5NN3NvWVRxdXRxM3lsVzcwYmV2TE93a0dFVEJkcGpSaS1TdVpoR0V0a3JnRllXMldCUWtRdVNaSWV2TUhXby1XQVhwSzlJeEJ4Z2s0WmVXNXVBalBmTEdnN0JYdW5iLW95RGJKWmV6cmF0?oc=5" target="_blank">It’s surreal when the lie machine comes for your hometown</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Seattle Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxOSHlycEdHUTRsRDZ5bndoSjRpSXZDOVBxWnNMc3V3bXNHcnU1eVp4Vkl6OS1lN0VScXZYbWg3TDhTZU1fZEdJSXJTYjJBN0lxMVl6OXRKQ3FKUFFoNWdpMTA2LUw4SUdpNmN3QUwyQmFyUjRRYzlCWTRHSUprNUxGN2FpTU12QllqQ2paZA?oc=5" target="_blank">GOP Mayor to Trump: Don’t Come to Springfield After Your Dog-Eating Slurs</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Daily Beast</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxNM1ROWWNNcmpIWlFRX2hTS2hhQjlHQ1N1T2lvQWswTU5vUEZTMkloZkdCYjVTdWdheGxsblZZdDQyZ0g0THpKVV8zdzEyNW5TRkItOUx0YkZvM1NHLW1QSThMZXVvWjZ1em5pMkFmdlVjX1lmQjdtYkFSa1ExNDlvMUV6OA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxNM1ROWWNNcmpIWlFRX2hTS2hhQjlHQ1N1T2lvQWswTU5vUEZTMkloZkdCYjVTdWdheGxsblZZdDQyZ0g0THpKVV8zdzEyNW5TRkItOUx0YkZvM1NHLW1QSThMZXVvWjZ1em5pMkFmdlVjX1lmQjdtYkFSa1ExNDlvMUV6OA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 03:24:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Suspicious packages sent to election offices in 16 US states as threats mount - The Guardian US]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQTEVBVzdGamxtcTBxZ2pJdlZKLVdVVzJXa193bjJMQXNNbThtd2trLWx2dHRHd1h0QWhnMVF1X29DSXh6aTA5UEllZ0ljZkVFSVB6c1lQN2hSaUE4ZG1MeU1pMi04bHc4Y203UUFCNF9QYXY2VDVOSjd4Yk9VZVVtUk8yTTY1Yk15NUJPZ1N30gGOAUFVX3lxTE5WcVhLNC1HaEVEcllJNEs5c1pFb2RxTUxaVUhrdjNCR0Z0MXhRT0RUbXdqLWZBTU8xNy1SOWRlTmVBajhsb0hjV2d1YjV1R1QtVkpXZkZvSUs2RHFvUkY0VDVvZ0drRHN2WmlFdXNJNk11Q3JGaFlOSGVwTklMTEpFRWtXN2FpOFZZMWJTMmc?oc=5" target="_blank">Suspicious packages sent to election offices in 16 US states as threats mount</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQSGMyd1c0UUZfVmdXanlhdWtIYmo4eEFHT2x0NUEzcnJJSktINUNQbW02QUFUQzhjXzRrWUdwbHFxRUdUVGJMZVdDdWd6dnNrQ0V4c3hyQU43TDl4WkJYRVVMelBseklTTkoxaEVSUFRBejUyamEtTldhQmRSY3I3WnBaOHFBeF9uTTRyd1ZoS1IyOE1YM0JTUnh3cXd3RFR4MThpeGdzd3FLQdIBrwFBVV95cUxQT0l0TFduRTdacFFlX2JhLUM2REdMUFdNQzVjalRwaHZ3LUhsbVh0c3prdFk4RFpVaGhuZnNoY0ozQ1RqMU02Mk8wOHBMeExfTjlVSDBQdWFtVUVEYWlCNVFFcFpFMjRvbjU4VVRtYVNPUnlOaHdydU9uQnRRcnR5SzAyd1A2MmJHSUZfaHR1OW4teV9SZ242M2ZpWkhVNEhLaVlaajVlLW1KeGZ5NmVB?oc=5" target="_blank">Suspicious mail containing white powder sent to election offices in at least 16 states</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxOQ1RlTWZPcWRnMEFRS2k3eUpxRHlpQ1A2S3BrRFhmSXhGUEtncFlES0lzdWMxLUxINkJPWVMwVVVfeEFqUGpJbmhSdFdBdWh3b1RUWmhRLVFRRU11ZkZhMUhPZW9NLV9oYW1mU2E1TFFrU2ZLbHo4SEN3WTdXYnR1Y2JmZS05MVY3cDA0VURWZEtpYkpLc3liNVdqS01ocUF2STFZYWFaY3FicXktb3c?oc=5" target="_blank">FBI, USPS intercept suspicious envelope sent to Mass. elections division</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Boston Globe</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxOZ2NEV0tibmNTSlR3RkljSmJSR1J6N3VWQUFZU2tyVWo3Q042OU9qWFVtU2tMem1sVUZkdnhrc0J3emVTYUFXZm5XSWJXd01uQWF1LUlWN0p2N0FkSlFFTzFibGZXY1NMeVd1cnNLTWFKUFB1Q21PbVhfRk96d0ZxSnRxaw?oc=5" target="_blank">Suspicious packages mailed to U.S. election officials in at least 15 states</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Axios</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxPbnZzSGFaMVB3eTUyOExUMkxObndIRm15YWNTeDNvcEFNdjVaRG9YeE4waUFHRUtBdUt5eWtjaE1lWWFKcHVIaF96TUFXcDVxY0t3dkxfdXFVVXl0aGFENzJSSW5WMG4xRXRCQVloT3RzMWlWblJzMmtPRnprZ1c4NGxfZTFJdHJqZkR3YVZpNnpSQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">FBI confirms no suspicious letter was sent to Maine Secretary of State's Office</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">WMTW Portland</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQTEVBVzdGamxtcTBxZ2pJdlZKLVdVVzJXa193bjJMQXNNbThtd2trLWx2dHRHd1h0QWhnMVF1X29DSXh6aTA5UEllZ0ljZkVFSVB6c1lQN2hSaUE4ZG1MeU1pMi04bHc4Y203UUFCNF9QYXY2VDVOSjd4Yk9VZVVtUk8yTTY1Yk15NUJPZ1N30gGOAUFVX3lxTE5WcVhLNC1HaEVEcllJNEs5c1pFb2RxTUxaVUhrdjNCR0Z0MXhRT0RUbXdqLWZBTU8xNy1SOWRlTmVBajhsb0hjV2d1YjV1R1QtVkpXZkZvSUs2RHFvUkY0VDVvZ0drRHN2WmlFdXNJNk11Q3JGaFlOSGVwTklMTEpFRWtXN2FpOFZZMWJTMmc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQTEVBVzdGamxtcTBxZ2pJdlZKLVdVVzJXa193bjJMQXNNbThtd2trLWx2dHRHd1h0QWhnMVF1X29DSXh6aTA5UEllZ0ljZkVFSVB6c1lQN2hSaUE4ZG1MeU1pMi04bHc4Y203UUFCNF9QYXY2VDVOSjd4Yk9VZVVtUk8yTTY1Yk15NUJPZ1N30gGOAUFVX3lxTE5WcVhLNC1HaEVEcllJNEs5c1pFb2RxTUxaVUhrdjNCR0Z0MXhRT0RUbXdqLWZBTU8xNy1SOWRlTmVBajhsb0hjV2d1YjV1R1QtVkpXZkZvSUs2RHFvUkY0VDVvZ0drRHN2WmlFdXNJNk11Q3JGaFlOSGVwTklMTEpFRWtXN2FpOFZZMWJTMmc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 16:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UN approves proposal for arms embargo on Israel]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fjyf09/un_approves_proposal_for_arms_embargo_on_israel/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/UvjJKVw54BZ2q3e5J6eaUQjRmd5hwdlZm8fnRsYyAko.jpg?width=320&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=f20d63af9e6e96fe5d8668b9d96e1afcc20dd29a" alt="UN approves proposal for arms embargo on Israel" title="UN approves proposal for arms embargo on Israel" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/parski841"> /u/parski841 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.ynetnews.com/article/hj11ja00da0#autoplay">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fjyf09/un_approves_proposal_for_arms_embargo_on_israel/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fjyf09/un_approves_proposal_for_arms_embargo_on_israel/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fjyf09/un_approves_proposal_for_arms_embargo_on_israel/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/parski841]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 17:24:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UK must stop being naive over resetting relations with EU, thinktank says]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>European Centre for International Political Economy outlines a roadmap to bring the two sides closer</p><p>The UK must stop being “naive” about negotiations to reset relations with the EU and show more flexibility in its approach to Brussels, a trade policy thinktank has said.</p><p>As EU capitals question how much has changed in the UK despite the new government, the European Centre for International Political Economy (ECIPE) has outlined a roadmap to bring the two sides closer after a series of reports that the EU doubted Keir Starmer’s commitment to a reset.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2024/sep/18/uk-must-stop-being-naive-over-resetting-relations-with-eu-thinktank-says">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2024/sep/18/uk-must-stop-being-naive-over-resetting-relations-with-eu-thinktank-says</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2024/sep/18/uk-must-stop-being-naive-over-resetting-relations-with-eu-thinktank-says</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:09:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fourteen killed and hundreds injured in latest Lebanon blasts; Israel declares ‘new phase’ of war – Middle East live]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Health ministry says at least 450 injured after walkie-talkies explode; Yoav Gallant does not mention explosions but praises Israel’s army and security agencies for ‘very impressive’ results</p><p>Local Palestinian media is reporting that a 17-year-old child has been killed by Israeli security forces near <strong>Ni’lin</strong>, west of <strong>Ramallah</strong>, in the Israeli-occupied West Bank. The claims have not been independently verified.</p><p><strong>Overnight Israel’s military announced the deaths of four soldiers.</strong></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/sep/18/middle-east-crisis-live-hezbollah-pager-explosion-lebanon-irael-iran-latest-updates">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/sep/18/middle-east-crisis-live-hezbollah-pager-explosion-lebanon-irael-iran-latest-updates</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/sep/18/middle-east-crisis-live-hezbollah-pager-explosion-lebanon-irael-iran-latest-updates</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:07:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia will not recognise Israel without Palestinian state, says Crown Prince]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/saudi-arabia-not-recognise-israel-152438198.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/saudi-arabia-not-recognise-israel-152438198.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 15:24:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel planted explosives in Hezbollah's Taiwan-made pagers, sources say]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/israel-planted-explosives-hezbollahs-taiwan-000753845.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/israel-planted-explosives-hezbollahs-taiwan-000753845.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:07:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Democrats block Cruz attempt to pass GOP IVF bill]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/democrats-block-cruz-attempt-pass-204557153.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/democrats-block-cruz-attempt-pass-204557153.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 20:45:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scientific American makes presidential endorsement for only the second time in its 179-year history]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/scientific-american-makes-presidential-endorsement-135754693.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/scientific-american-makes-presidential-endorsement-135754693.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 09:54:54 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>