<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:49:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:49:30 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[The dubious GOP attacks on Tim Walz’s military record, briefly explained]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Walz walking outside, followed by other people in suits. " data-caption="Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz arrives to speak at a press conference regarding new gun legislation at City Hall on August 1, 2024, in Bloomington, Minnesota. | Stephen Maturen/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Maturen/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2164173466.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz arrives to speak at a press conference regarding new gun legislation at City Hall on August 1, 2024, in Bloomington, Minnesota. | Stephen Maturen/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In a bid to undercut Vice President Kamala Harris’s newly announced running mate, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365416/tim-walz-kamala-harris-vp-vice-president-democrats-left" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/politics/365416/tim-walz-kamala-harris-vp-vice-president-democrats-left">Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz,</a> Republicans are mounting attacks on his military record. The charges, which a closer look suggests are misleading or exaggerated, are a notable escalation against the Democratic ticket by the Trump campaign.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The attacks began in earnest on August 7, when Ohio Sen. J.D. Vance, President Donald Trump’s running mate, sought to tout his own military experience compared to Walz’s. Prior to running for Congress, Walz served for 24 years in the Army National Guard, while Vance served for four years in the Marine Corps. Neither has seen combat.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“When the United States Marine Corps, when the United States of America, asked me to go to Iraq to serve my country, I did it. I did what they asked me to do, and I did it honorably and I’m very proud of that service,” Vance said. “When Tim Walz was asked by his country to go to Iraq, you know what he did? He dropped out of the Army and allowed his unit to go without him.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Vance’s sweeping statement contains some key omissions. For instance, Walz <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/tim-walz-military-record/#">retired in 2005</a>, two months before his unit received formal notice it would be sent to Iraq. Another <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/08/08/harris-walz-military-credentials-00173236#:~:text=%E2%80%9CWalz%20attained%20the%20rank%20of,to%20the%20Minneapolis%20Star%20Tribune.">Republican attack on Walz’s service</a> — that he <a href="https://x.com/GOP/status/1821595739757125876">misrepresented himself</a> as a retired command sergeant major — is also more complicated: While he held that rank at one point, his rank was changed after retirement because he <a href="https://www.mprnews.org/story/2018/10/03/tim-walz-national-guard-career-minnesota-governor-race">did not complete the required coursework</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/republicans-vance-start-tearing-walz-going-military-record-rcna165564">another claim by Republicans</a> is that Walz misrepresented his service by implying in a past statement that he once served in a combat zone. In that case, the language he used appears to have been imprecise.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is precedent for these types of attacks: Republicans appear to be resorting to the same “swift-boating” tactics that they once levied against former Democratic presidential candidate John Kerry. A reference to the small speedboats used in the Vietnam War where Kerry served, the campaign sought to impugn his character by casting doubt on his account of military service in Vietnam.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Notably, the architect of that campaign against Kerry was <a href="https://taskandpurpose.com/news/swift-boat-walz/">Chris LaCivita — now a prominent staffer</a> on former President Donald Trump’s 2024 campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Walz has faced questions about his military service before, including when he ran for Minnesota governor in 2018. And in that instance — and this one — he’s had several veterans defend him as well. Joseph Eustice, a 32-year veteran of the National Guard, <a href="https://www.startribune.com/walzs-24-years-in-national-guard-get-renewed-scrutiny-from-gop-opponent-who-didnt-serve/600216280">told the Minnesota Star Tribune in 2022</a>, “He was a great soldier. When he chose to leave, he had every right to leave.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Harris campaign for its part has responded by stressing Walz’s tenure and policy record. “After 24 years of military service, Governor Walz retired in 2005 and ran for Congress, where he was a tireless advocate for our men and women in uniform,” the Harris campaign told Vox in a statement. The campaign also pointed to Walz’s time as a ranking member on the House Veteran Affairs Committee and his support for funding and mental health resources for the military.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The claims, and the information we know, briefly explained&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The claims that Republicans have made about Walz focus on three issues: his decision to retire from the Army National Guard in 2005, his rank upon retirement, and a comment he made about carrying weapons “in war.” Here’s what we know about each of them. </p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Claim 1: </strong>Walz retired from the Army National Guard to avoid serving in Iraq.</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What we know: </strong>Notably, Walz retired in <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/tim-walz-military-record/#">May 2005</a>, two months prior to his unit receiving an official deployment order to Iraq. He stated in 2009 that <a href="https://www.loc.gov/item/afc2001001.69125/#item-service_history">his reasons for retiring</a> were to pursue a run for the House of Representatives, which he won the following year, and to avoid conflicts under the Hatch Act, which bars federal employees from engaging in certain political activities. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Walz filed for his run for office before the National Guard had notified his unit of the possibility of a deployment to Iraq. It’s unclear if, at the time, he already knew that a deployment could be a possibility.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Below is a more detailed timeline of how this all unfolded.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>February 10, 2005</strong>: <a href="https://docquery.fec.gov/pdf/112/25038731112/25038731112.pdf">Walz files paperwork</a> with the Federal Election Commission declaring his candidacy for the House seat in Minnesota’s First Congressional District.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>March 17, 2005:</strong> <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20050420005951/http://www.timwalz.org/print.php?pr=1">The National Guard informs members</a> of the possibility of deployment to Iraq within the next two years. The public affairs office notes that <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/tim-walz-military-record/#">2,000 members</a> could be sent from the Minnesota National Guard, which could include part of, or the entirety of, Walz’s battalion.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>March 20, 2005</strong>: <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20050420004957/http://www.timwalz.org/pr.php?pr=1">Walz issues a statement</a> responding to the National Guard notice, saying he intends to continue to serve, and to continue his run for Congress.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I do not yet know if my artillery unit will be part of this mobilization and I am unable to comment further on specifics of the deployment,” he said. “As Command Sergeant Major I have a responsibility not only to ready my battalion for Iraq, but also to serve if called on. I am dedicated to serving my country to the best of my ability, whether that is in Washington DC or in Iraq.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>May 16, 2005</strong>: Walz retires from the National Guard, according to a comment the Minnesota Army National Guard <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/tim-walz-military-record/">provided CBS News.</a>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>July 14, 2005</strong>: Walz’s battalion receives an alert order for mobilization to Iraq.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>March 2006: </strong>Walz’s unit is <a href="https://www.nationalguard.mil/News/Article/573070/guard-unit-recognized-for-record-deployment/">deployed to Iraq</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Claim 2: </strong>The<strong> </strong>Harris-Walz campaign misrepresented his title by stating that he’s a “retired Command Sergeant Major.”</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/tim-walz-military-record/">On the Harris campaign website</a> and a Minnesota government website, Walz had been listed as a “retired Command Sergeant Major,” according to CBS News.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans have argued that this is an inaccurate description of his title. That phrase has now been <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/08/08/harris-walz-military-credentials-00173236">changed on the Harris campaign website</a> to note that this title was <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20240808091058/https://kamalaharris.com/meet-governor-tim-walz/">the highest rank he earned</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What we know: </strong>Walz did, in fact, attain the position of Command Sergeant Major. However, after he retired, his title was changed to Master Sergeant, because <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/tim-walz-military-record/">he did not finish the coursework required</a> to retire under the promoted title.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As a result, it’s accurate to say that he was once a Command Sergeant Major, but not that he was a “retired Command Sergeant Major.”&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Claim 3: </strong>Walz misrepresented his involvement in combat in a speech about gun control.&nbsp;</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We can make sure that those weapons of war, that I carried in war, is the only place where those weapons are at,” Walz said in remarks <a href="https://www.mprnews.org/story/2018/02/20/in-about-face-walz-backs-assault-weapons-ban-for-minnesota">about an assault weapons ban in 2018.</a>&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Gov. <a href="https://twitter.com/Tim_Walz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Tim_Walz</a>: I spent 25 years in the Army and I hunt. I’ve been voting for common sense legislation that protects the Second Amendment, but we can do background checks. We can research the impacts of gun violence. We can make sure those weapons of war, that I carried in war,… <a href="https://t.co/3IVaXi2RP2">pic.twitter.com/3IVaXi2RP2</a></p>&mdash; Kamala HQ (@KamalaHQ) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHQ/status/1820918063966962143?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance argues that Walz’s statements imply that he was in combat when he wasn’t.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What we know: </strong>Walz was deployed as part of the National Guard to Vicenza, Italy, in August 2003 as part of Operation Enduring Freedom <a href="https://apnews.com/article/walz-national-guard-military-ae43d684bf1319e535f9f620552155d7#:~:text=Walz%20didn't%20serve%20in%20a%20combat%20zone&amp;text=According%20to%20the%20Nebraska%20Army,before%20graduating%20from%20high%20school.">but was not in a combat zone</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The phrasing of the statement in his gun control remarks, suggesting that he carried the weapons “in war,” was imprecise. While technically correct given the operation he was part of, it appears to suggest an experience he didn’t have. <a href="https://www.mprnews.org/story/2018/10/03/tim-walz-national-guard-career-minnesota-governor-race">Walz has openly acknowledged in other interviews</a> that he hadn’t seen combat while deployed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Harris campaign has stressed Walz’s training with firearms in response. “In his 24 years of service, the Governor carried, fired and trained others to use weapons of war innumerable times,” the Harris campaign told Vox in a statement. “Governor Walz would never insult or undermine any American&#8217;s service to this country — in fact, he thanks Senator Vance for putting his life on the line for our country. It&#8217;s the American way.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/366195/jd-vance-tim-vance-military-record-national-guard</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/366195/jd-vance-tim-vance-military-record-national-guard</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Li Zhou]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The significance of Trump's repeated mispronunciation of 'Kamala' - NPR]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNQmJEdUhOUWFXcW1QbjdEdnJCenFDblhzOGJoSTA0cUpjZHpuY2hEMmx5Nm1Gbk9qQjl5UnFYSWpqTWJ2NFZPeVprV3dNU2ZPQmZiaHNTSnFDRkVETVhCM1BLXzdtU2tiR2dxcU1sZUwzMmFUWkVhazNZMHJ2Vl9Na1JEQUhJdkNWQnhIZ1NaVkhTcGZNZ1QtcWd0VElYWWZ3aVJpY2dUUWVYcGc?oc=5" target="_blank">The significance of Trump's repeated mispronunciation of 'Kamala'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2lxc3ZDT0RCSDZkR0JvS082VE95Z0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNQmJEdUhOUWFXcW1QbjdEdnJCenFDblhzOGJoSTA0cUpjZHpuY2hEMmx5Nm1Gbk9qQjl5UnFYSWpqTWJ2NFZPeVprV3dNU2ZPQmZiaHNTSnFDRkVETVhCM1BLXzdtU2tiR2dxcU1sZUwzMmFUWkVhazNZMHJ2Vl9Na1JEQUhJdkNWQnhIZ1NaVkhTcGZNZ1QtcWd0VElYWWZ3aVJpY2dUUWVYcGc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNQmJEdUhOUWFXcW1QbjdEdnJCenFDblhzOGJoSTA0cUpjZHpuY2hEMmx5Nm1Gbk9qQjl5UnFYSWpqTWJ2NFZPeVprV3dNU2ZPQmZiaHNTSnFDRkVETVhCM1BLXzdtU2tiR2dxcU1sZUwzMmFUWkVhazNZMHJ2Vl9Na1JEQUhJdkNWQnhIZ1NaVkhTcGZNZ1QtcWd0VElYWWZ3aVJpY2dUUWVYcGc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 21:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[U.S. Warns Iran of ‘Serious Risk’ if It Conducts Major Attack on Israel - The Wall Street Journal]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxPMGMyeUJvR0IwdktrV3cyNXU4RUpwRFdQYjF6MFBXaDBqSGRBSmQwMlkxTGEwNEFWdlBrSE5iQ2xMcFNYcGVDdGN1ald5Z2M5ekQzQUlxekdNZkxvbHVCM0I2ekU4RC1YbFFqX1FvRWxqb19JSTBVamFERHA0Unlsc1lORlhiWnhRWW5yNVJJV0V3ZUVDSV9aNXlkTFZzRXVaT1BaMlp4dVpkRFZMSW1NUzFDUm5jZw?oc=5" target="_blank">U.S. Warns Iran of ‘Serious Risk’ if It Conducts Major Attack on Israel</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Wall Street Journal</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxNMWNJVHpFclB4UVo5R3l3VVl4TktTOEVQZmdhMjBxTElNSUI1ZHJFY0VRemhtd0p5cUt5QVFaOGh4UjJyeVVueGQyLWlrcjJIM1RmMzBzUE5nRXpsODVqRGJlQloxT0RXc0R3a1RTbWlGZ0MzOThELVJCd2pEOHdWcXFYRTJTbS16QVRDczd3TWt6OERfU3V6SHdUX21LNG9fVmx4ZE16dV9KLTVVajM1cjJaOG1fZ29YWHlXcA?oc=5" target="_blank">US official warns of ‘quite significant consequences’ if Iran attacks Israel</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of Israel</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOZlMzS0s2Z25SZEV3anltX3Vhb0hmdkNrMlZIeVU4dVhuNk13c2FqV0xQRjVWMkNxNkFlOVFqdGxFUTFjVVVpWC13NmwyUW9ucU4wbnJoYzFHMlNoamlmMXVDZGVzaXVSMVZGS1FVRWVTQWxLUFctejVGUDJYQUt5S2dyelBDXy15am80b0Nn0gGTAUFVX3lxTE9lOHVxWThwRWMtYVRCbXppSV9wODR2aXF2M0tzRXhZNlVWOUZoUDE0VkxLbkRCYW5HbGc2NWdCVFczR3JrcUFabnlzR3AyYzhCS180Q2FSX0VsVk5ZZERTRC1mS3NqSG5TUXJFbUJZQko2eUZ3R3FJX1ZZRlFyUnJVM2F5c2d6MVktS1RIZElkWTFsTQ?oc=5" target="_blank">US F-22 Stealth Warplanes Arrive In Middle East</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Barron's</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE5HNVJaeG40Unl1YUpaWm9UYm9LaHRJd3E2eWtsUlI4dmlsWW9xdnZIRmduQnVHaGpzMVFOQlRLUllTS2hBUWU2M0cyNlNJZVVJb283eXBiOEIxdnJMU3YyeXBBcG82Y2ZlTnNqNTA5Q05mUnJZclRfZmNPeXM?oc=5" target="_blank">As Iran Braces for War, Its Citizens Are Kept in the Dark</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxQTFgzWUxaYjd4VE85cldWbHNuTFpPaHJNU1pYX0dFQllEVVZYLXdQcmloOXJyQzNKRU80Z3l4RFRZazVGYWRXNzJ4UmlOSklKQkpkZ0RlQThtUFY1OUhGVEk0QURubUVIODZPYlQ1NU5zay1xMEVsdThiZmFVcGdibUJfNjZsOEktR0FsaFB2QjF2VHYyLUpJ?oc=5" target="_blank">There’s a Big Reason Things Haven’t Escalated Between Iran and Israel Yet</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Slate</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxPMGMyeUJvR0IwdktrV3cyNXU4RUpwRFdQYjF6MFBXaDBqSGRBSmQwMlkxTGEwNEFWdlBrSE5iQ2xMcFNYcGVDdGN1ald5Z2M5ekQzQUlxekdNZkxvbHVCM0I2ekU4RC1YbFFqX1FvRWxqb19JSTBVamFERHA0Unlsc1lORlhiWnhRWW5yNVJJV0V3ZUVDSV9aNXlkTFZzRXVaT1BaMlp4dVpkRFZMSW1NUzFDUm5jZw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxPMGMyeUJvR0IwdktrV3cyNXU4RUpwRFdQYjF6MFBXaDBqSGRBSmQwMlkxTGEwNEFWdlBrSE5iQ2xMcFNYcGVDdGN1ald5Z2M5ekQzQUlxekdNZkxvbHVCM0I2ekU4RC1YbFFqX1FvRWxqb19JSTBVamFERHA0Unlsc1lORlhiWnhRWW5yNVJJV0V3ZUVDSV9aNXlkTFZzRXVaT1BaMlp4dVpkRFZMSW1NUzFDUm5jZw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 18:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tim Walz may be the next US VP. To those he taught, he's Mr Walz. - BBC.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE5IWThhNWdLWnhnamU2UlktMDhjdmZ2WVlFalRpNU9tcmxVR3loSTAyRTJ4UW53X2lCOVQ5c0hvbWJ5eEl0ZVlnRjZkNW0xaEc4cFhJa2JrZDA4d9IBX0FVX3lxTE51cFFUVmREQzNPa1VIc0ZTMWQ3SjN1VE1ETzJwa3hRT1lGMFg3MnppWmprcmJFZ29yeURmMUp0Tjd4VTlPSFV4YmZzUURkUFd0eDRWVldCSFY4OGN6U1dB?oc=5" target="_blank">Tim Walz may be the next US VP. To those he taught, he's Mr Walz.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxPV3lfUWQ0dUM3dEt1aTkwdVBtNnBVU3ZNTkk4a0ZvQUUzSVZsX0pzZkFjWWQ1NW52Q2ZockJVSVlnTVJ2ckNmV0RrcTFjZ2pfUEo4M0V2MjZVSDQtMWRRMnpralNOQjQ0U01GMGM2UGJwcFdfeU5UNURJR3REQ3kzODljRzZGcE9PSGdHMVJYdzI5TFdkRWY3NzhwbTZ6QQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Tim Walz Was My Teacher 20 Years Ago. Here’s What I Learned.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxPLTRsc0F3a2J0dGphR25GcEh6UktjdGFqak9CaFhIYVFDNHRhaURqQVd4Wk96YUFGbXFSUHdsNjEyTkNjOUZtbUszbGptZW5XX1paN0tSdy1QX0U3YlBLWGMwV0w0cEY2b2RLUlJod1lpMW11dFJUN1Y0R2ZCLWQ0UXUwdy00ZzdxRm83Nk43Z0J0cG1LckQ5US04WmtPSXBfS2hCbDJWQzI5eDRBYjZqOEdvbnFMUEl2Mklr0gFkQVVfeXFMTWE2MkNNSHBSdTkwZU1jSGFQNTF4STMwUUxxalZrTzJyQ3BYaDBkSWs0U0hxaDJlSFlxelJpWTJLTFVxUHQ5QXpDS004SnN2a0VBcm15VVg5TlhDcTV2MGhKamx3MA?oc=5" target="_blank">Former Minnesota student speaks about impact Tim Walz made</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MSNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxOMUVmaHVaLWpHbXl4Rm1wSlN4SlVldlFxZ1g4U3p4ZmJaYk1RTjYzRGtHYVF5dUdMZ0NFYkRxWFBHcGxVVFlaQWtac0NsUFhtdDFqSTBhTUx1M3VrVUkxQlliTWh5bkZNTXliWGxTQm9iXzJKSTNTcjBxNmlDQ1AtTzc1QWJMMjBsOG01UVg3VmhheUwzcmV3VDVwOGRKdlJXQzBHLXJQWW9pV0tmejF1Z19RZ3Y1QW1wY2Jtag?oc=5" target="_blank">What It Was Like to Be Tim Walz’s Student in High School</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Slate</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxQREVFcEFlYmNYRVdDd2F0TXlfVC04ZFpuS1BxZXNocXhReE9VaExDUTBQdEF3RjNhQzVmSjlCejVUQ1BFdm90RjlqU29ZeXR3V2c3eWhBN3E5bHNueWtGOFRacllEcGlGbWkyZXRCbEJYeXR5ajFTUkJadFc2TkFNQ1B3RDMxcUFGWWNETURCaVVYQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">How Paul Wellstone Helped Give Us Tim Walz</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Mother Jones</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE5IWThhNWdLWnhnamU2UlktMDhjdmZ2WVlFalRpNU9tcmxVR3loSTAyRTJ4UW53X2lCOVQ5c0hvbWJ5eEl0ZVlnRjZkNW0xaEc4cFhJa2JrZDA4d9IBX0FVX3lxTE51cFFUVmREQzNPa1VIc0ZTMWQ3SjN1VE1ETzJwa3hRT1lGMFg3MnppWmprcmJFZ29yeURmMUp0Tjd4VTlPSFV4YmZzUURkUFd0eDRWVldCSFY4OGN6U1dB?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE5IWThhNWdLWnhnamU2UlktMDhjdmZ2WVlFalRpNU9tcmxVR3loSTAyRTJ4UW53X2lCOVQ5c0hvbWJ5eEl0ZVlnRjZkNW0xaEc4cFhJa2JrZDA4d9IBX0FVX3lxTE51cFFUVmREQzNPa1VIc0ZTMWQ3SjN1VE1ETzJwa3hRT1lGMFg3MnppWmprcmJFZ29yeURmMUp0Tjd4VTlPSFV4YmZzUURkUFd0eDRWVldCSFY4OGN6U1dB?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 19:41:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[U.S., Egypt and Qatar call for "urgent talks" next week to reach Israel-Hamas cease-fire deal - CBS News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxPdjlnOUlVZm5YMl9IaS1iRko3UkY4dDE0bUdJaWhXMzh2NFZ6R2hRc1VKSTBNMGowSWNPbXpTZTBTUVdqaHpRN2VQTDE4eTVLTC13MzczR3lRc2NKWkFuQ29KWWdjUnlRc0NOeFMxWkszeC1tQnpLUnFCUDI2UlZKMk1xTTdaZE9DOEEwVzJ3TkctYm82T3dTSFNLYWR0elHSAaQBQVVfeXFMTmxmYjhYRXRNdVRxanc3bkw5Wm5HV1JLUHhScW1DbTNiZ0duWXhnSDgzc2FHUEtCTDItUVZzZWNnVG5UTE4tSDVCX2ZGQXVwajdjTjY2U1JTdkdpMGlwQ0Q1WGJUTEFFUkdaQmtma2ZtazFOR1dOUUhKNFM3Ml9yekMxNWlFTkpwQTlYaDZkMTU3LVhvQy1sOUpMS3BoMy1BUk1MY28?oc=5" target="_blank">U.S., Egypt and Qatar call for "urgent talks" next week to reach Israel-Hamas cease-fire deal</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZEFVX3lxTFAwSmNCV3NSdnh2N1RPdkxyZFhEYllhNXU5VmphWXltZEt2R3VnVmd4Rjl0LVhscDhPVS1IcFZyYnh4QUljQVZxM19VZ3cwa1NuOXpWMjFPNXpWUjNLd2JzdUNCSXbSAWpBVV95cUxOOXV1LW1SNzZSSDJzMExQNk54OGpvNWg0N2hLMGtXZnJxR1oyQ1NlMUlhQ0p1VlZMbzNHMzlvWHM2ZWU3UU9STF9GN0tmd0xsajgzRnF4MEE0WWw0cURBU2pSNkZianAzVzNB?oc=5" target="_blank">US, Egypt and Qatar call on Israel and Hamas to finalize deal ‘without further delay’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of Israel</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQTTk0VkFCUzUtZXpMNW9RLTZvdjQwZ1ZNYW9jblJKU2s3bFM2N0liSEVCcG9mNVZseVdybU1HcmE3Q0dOMHE2Uk5BSGRSVElJQWNaMDd6SktqUUt3bXpGU3dWbE1vWXpONjNkTW4weHZvc1lFaEZZd3JjVExsZHptdUdVUUIxUHVVOGtqbDd30gGTAUFVX3lxTE9fd3NsMm5PcU03OENwTG14S1JOZldPcVctbUI5SzNZMTRuNmlROUpQcUF2TFd2dE5fRjctM0h3cEMtQkxtR3oxUWxQS1dLbUJ4TVdhTzZGQUFRM3hTMzBjY3Z2bVpkTUx6TWt0WVJRbi1PS0JCSWpiRHZXQ1dzOEVMRGdtdy1LU0tkRTZPSDlHa2QzYw?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden joins leaders from Egypt, Qatar in urging Gaza cease-fire, hostage release deal</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE1VZDNxVlRXQmFoYTBTZ1hMSkFtaFVXdk1ablBsOTl4WDRCZWVzc0ZGcGZWRkNRdzZYZnd5bVdOY01ESTNFa2l1cUZpNkx5TXdEaXFvXzlKMXNHb3dBMktUSzgtVVRSWWl0ZnExUklSN2lWRVVFbHlXMDdJak8?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel-Hamas War Biden and Leaders of Egypt and Qatar to Offer ‘Final’ Cease-Fire Deal Next Week</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQTVBwdWY3MktJUF9fMnFYQU5lV2w5MG0zQjFhTVpoOVF4b2N1Y1RlMUktUzR3R3A4SUQ0cU5DV1laMURrWllybnlDdFU3MmJDUWt0R2xCbndQaTlJZHNaUjdCd21SN1ROcnNJUGY0NjZBM2N3ZU9zX2c4cFRTM25hZW4tanhXSE1EY0x6Zk9oN2Z2a3hKQi1yTVF6MWhiQXNyTkpWTnh2Q0ZfSzJUZ3R2Z29R0gG3AUFVX3lxTE1DU1F5bnZBZXFXcVhmeW5BZC0zd2xxNktyRTdtdnVIQ1ZFVVBMWmdULUpjYUZoakhHdnEtZmRnM2g0TFlEMGtLbDRxd0s5emlsY2QzN0V0NktzSjJCRWdmSTRiYnZucFhrOUZtR0xReVcyS0NHdnlON2xmekE3cFdHX1J5clBqNkc0QkpDQzNNYm1kNjlDSXo1WWFyOUtyMGUzd1pyVGY1clVTLVE1aTJEdDdvei1FNA?oc=5" target="_blank">Qatar, Egypt, US invite Israel and Hamas to resume Gaza ceasefire talks</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Al Jazeera English</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxPdjlnOUlVZm5YMl9IaS1iRko3UkY4dDE0bUdJaWhXMzh2NFZ6R2hRc1VKSTBNMGowSWNPbXpTZTBTUVdqaHpRN2VQTDE4eTVLTC13MzczR3lRc2NKWkFuQ29KWWdjUnlRc0NOeFMxWkszeC1tQnpLUnFCUDI2UlZKMk1xTTdaZE9DOEEwVzJ3TkctYm82T3dTSFNLYWR0elHSAaQBQVVfeXFMTmxmYjhYRXRNdVRxanc3bkw5Wm5HV1JLUHhScW1DbTNiZ0duWXhnSDgzc2FHUEtCTDItUVZzZWNnVG5UTE4tSDVCX2ZGQXVwajdjTjY2U1JTdkdpMGlwQ0Q1WGJUTEFFUkdaQmtma2ZtazFOR1dOUUhKNFM3Ml9yekMxNWlFTkpwQTlYaDZkMTU3LVhvQy1sOUpMS3BoMy1BUk1MY28?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxPdjlnOUlVZm5YMl9IaS1iRko3UkY4dDE0bUdJaWhXMzh2NFZ6R2hRc1VKSTBNMGowSWNPbXpTZTBTUVdqaHpRN2VQTDE4eTVLTC13MzczR3lRc2NKWkFuQ29KWWdjUnlRc0NOeFMxWkszeC1tQnpLUnFCUDI2UlZKMk1xTTdaZE9DOEEwVzJ3TkctYm82T3dTSFNLYWR0elHSAaQBQVVfeXFMTmxmYjhYRXRNdVRxanc3bkw5Wm5HV1JLUHhScW1DbTNiZ0duWXhnSDgzc2FHUEtCTDItUVZzZWNnVG5UTE4tSDVCX2ZGQXVwajdjTjY2U1JTdkdpMGlwQ0Q1WGJUTEFFUkdaQmtma2ZtazFOR1dOUUhKNFM3Ml9yekMxNWlFTkpwQTlYaDZkMTU3LVhvQy1sOUpMS3BoMy1BUk1MY28?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:37:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Harris continues battleground blitz after Trump’s rambling press conference – as it happened]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This blog is closing for now. You can find the latest US politics coverage <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/us-elections-2024">here</a>.</p><p><strong>In a new tweet on Thursday ahead of her address with workers from the United Auto Workers union in Detroit, Michigan Kamala Harris wrote:</strong></p><p>“This campaign is not just about us versus Donald Trump. Our campaign is about fighting for the future.”</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/aug/08/harris-walz-uaw-detroit-trump-vance-elections-updates">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/aug/08/harris-walz-uaw-detroit-trump-vance-elections-updates</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/aug/08/harris-walz-uaw-detroit-trump-vance-elections-updates</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:34:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dozens of Russian Soldiers Surrender to Invading Ukrainian Forces]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/dozens-russian-soldiers-surrender-invading-170313482.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/dozens-russian-soldiers-surrender-invading-170313482.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:03:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Veteran who served in Tim Walz's battalion addresses stolen valor accusations: 'Far darker than people think']]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/veteran-served-tim-walzs-battalion-023711725.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/veteran-served-tim-walzs-battalion-023711725.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 02:37:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Democrats May Have Found Their Own Version Of The MAGA Hat]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/looks-democrats-finally-maga-hat-175613941.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/looks-democrats-finally-maga-hat-175613941.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 17:56:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>