<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:20:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:20:02 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Has Netanyahu finally lost America?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Netanyahu holds his fist at the lectern. " data-caption="Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu addresses Congress on July 24, 2024. | Bryan Dozier/Anadolu via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-portal-copyright="Bryan Dozier/Anadolu via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2162700786.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu addresses Congress on July 24, 2024. | Bryan Dozier/Anadolu via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was back in a very familiar building. Not only was he making his fourth address to a joint session of Congress — breaking Winston Churchill’s record for foreign leaders — he’s also been a presence in the building’s halls since serving as a diplomat in the early 1980s. Since he made his first speech to Congress in 1996, Netanyahu has been almost as much a fixture of politics in America as in Israel. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Things felt different today. It’s not just that Netanyahu is a controversial figure, one who drew <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/24/netanyahu-congress-protests-security">thousands of protesters</a> onto the streets of Washington. That’s not new; Netanyahu’s 2011 speech to Congress was <a href="https://www.americanrhetoric.com/speeches/benjaminnetanyahujointsession2011.htm">interrupted by a pro-Palestinian protester</a> in the chamber. What is new is that he has become an increasingly marginalized one.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even a few weeks ago, when Netanyahu’s speech was announced, it had the makings of a marquee political event. Today, it was overshadowed by President Joe Biden’s highly anticipated Wednesday night speech to address his decision to drop out of the presidential election. Dozens of lawmakers — <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/07/24/half-house-senate-democrats-boycott-netanyahu">around half of Congress’s Democrats</a> — skipped Netanyahu’s speech altogether.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Soon-to-retire Maryland Sen. Ben Cardin’s presence behind Netanyahu on the rostrum attested to how much of a partisan figure Netanyahu has become. Vice President Kamala Harris, Senate President Pro Tempore Patty Murray, and Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer, one of whom would normally have been in that seat, all <a href="https://www.jpost.com/israel-news/article-811586">declined the role</a>. Netanyahu, who has been Israel’s prime minister for 17 of the last 30 years, has done more than anyone to make support for the country an increasingly partisan issue in the United States, in part through actions like his<em> </em>speech to Congress in 2015. That time, he was invited by congressional Republicans to lobby against the Iran nuclear deal then being negotiated by the Obama administration in what was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2015/02/26/politics/democrats-missing-netanyahu-whip-list/index.html">considered a remarkably partisan speech</a> for a foreign leader.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In today’s address, by contrast, Netanyahu made little news. It was a speech that gave little indication of a plan to end the war in Gaza, and likely undermined diplomatic efforts underway to do so. It was a notably defensive speech for Netanyahu, devoted more to refuting criticism of Israel than to charting a way forward out of the morass it has found itself in. Former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi <a href="https://x.com/SpeakerPelosi/status/1816208313572364356">called</a> it “by far the worst presentation of any foreign dignitary invited and honored with the privilege of addressing the Congress of the United States.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What Netanyahu said — and what he’s doing</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu recounted the horrors of Hamas’s October 7 attacks and vowed to the families of hostages currently being held in Gaza that he “would not rest until all their loved ones are home.” Not all of those families may be inclined to take him at his word. <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/international/4786324-hamas-hostages-netanyahu-speech/">Many of them</a> are calling for the prime minister to accept a ceasefire deal to secure the hostages’ release, but today Netanyahu vowed that “Israel will fight until we destroy Hamas’s military capabilities and its rule in Gaza and bring all our hostages home,” adding, “That’s what total victory means and we will settle for nothing less.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu also said, as he has in several previous remarks, that “[Israel] must retain overriding&nbsp;control [in Gaza] to ensure that Gaza never again poses a security threat to Israel” — a demand likely to be a nonstarter for any ceasefire deal.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite that, Netanyahu <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-says-deal-could-be-nearing-hostages-gaza-2024-07-23/">has said in recent days</a> that a ceasefire deal may be near, and the deal currently being negotiated is likely to be the focus of the prime minister’s meeting at the White House with Biden on Thursday. The Biden administration has tended not to respond directly to Netanyahu’s public statements on the deal, and this time was no exception. Asked if Netanyahu’s remarks made that deal less likely, a senior US administration official told reporters on Wednesday afternoon, “We were in the Situation Room doing some other stuff, so I have not seen the speech.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu didn’t indicate any specific asks beyond continued US military support. “Give us the tools faster and we’ll finish the job faster,” he said, riffing on a famous Churchill line from World War II. As he has in all three of his previous addresses, going back to the mid-1990s, Netanyahu kept the focus on Iran, which he mentioned before Hamas. He made the case that Israel’s fight against Iran-backed groups like Hamas and Hezbollah serves to “keep American boots off the ground while protecting our shared interests in the Middle East.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He pushed back against criticism of Israel over civilian casualties and preventing food from entering Gaza. He ripped into anti-Israel protesters in the United States, accusing them of being “useful idiots” for Iran, criticized university presidents, and compared “gays for Gaza” to “chickens for KFC.” This was likely the first speech on Mideast policy that included a shout-out to the “<a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/white-house-praises-unc-frat-bros-protected-american-flag-anti-israel-agitators-admirable">fraternity brothers of the University of North Carolina.</a>”&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to lose friends and influence</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu praised President Biden for his “half a century of friendship to Israel” and noted that the president describes himself as a “proud Zionist.” But that only served to highlight the shrinking number of Democratic politicians who would publicly describe themselves that way. Polls have consistently shown a <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/472070/democrats-sympathies-middle-east-shift-palestinians.aspx">deep partisan divide</a> opening up over sympathy toward Israel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He also thanked former president and current Republican nominee Donald Trump for actions in support of Israel during his presidency, including recognizing Israeli <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/presidential-actions/proclamation-recognizing-golan-heights-part-state-israel/">sovereignty over the Golan Heights</a> and moving the <a href="https://il.usembassy.gov/statement-by-president-trump-on-jerusalem/">US embassy to Jerusalem</a>. Netanyahu will be traveling to Florida to meet with Trump (<a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/netanyahu-requested-date-for-trump-meeting-falls-on-miami-based-son-yairs-birthday/">and possibly celebrate the birthday of his son</a>, who lives in Miami). Still, while Trump has not exactly turned on Israel, he has clearly soured somewhat on Netanyahu, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2021/12/10/trump-netanyahu-disloyalty-fuck-him">who he is still angry at</a> for congratulating Biden on his election victory in 2020. It doesn’t seem like a coincidence that Trump posted a <a href="https://x.com/BarakRavid/status/1815939398841847899">friendly letter</a> from Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas on the day he announced the Netanyahu meeting.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From a purely visual standpoint, Netanyahu may have gotten what he wanted today: rapturous standing ovations, even if mainly from Republicans. But more than <a href="https://www.jpost.com/israel-news/article-810113">70 percent of Israelis now say that Netanyahu</a> should resign. His own defense establishment is turning on his <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/show/israeli-defense-minister-publicly-criticizes-netanyahus-gaza-strategy#:~:text=Israel's%20defense%20minister%20accused%20Netanyahu%20of%20indecision%20and%20leading%20Israel,he's%20here%20with%20us%20now.">handling of the war</a> and he’s under fire over issues ranging from his long-running legal troubles to the controversial question of whether the ultra-Orthodox should serve in the country’s military.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the past, Washington has served as a sort of relief valve for Netanyahu, a place he could count on strong support, even when his political position looked rocky at home. In that first speech back in 1996, after receiving a five-minute standing ovation from Congress, he <a href="https://www.americanrhetoric.com/speeches/benjaminnetanyahujointsession1996.htm">quipped</a>, “If I could only get the Knesset [Israel’s parliament] to vote like this.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, though, “the magic is gone,” Nimrod Novik, a former senior Israeli foreign policy official who is now an analyst at the Israel Policy Forum, told Vox. “The fellow that mastered verbal acrobatics to the point that different audiences could hear different messages in the same speech —&nbsp;that’s over. Those who were in awe of his verbal skills now take it with a grain of salt.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In more than 40 years of coming to Washington, Netanyahu has surely grown used to being a controversial figure. He may have to get used to being an irrelevant one.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, 7 pm ET: </strong>An earlier version of this story referred to Netanyahu as a former ambassador to the US. He was a deputy chief of mission.</em></p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/israel/362954/netanyahu-israel-congress-gaza-democrats-biden</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/israel/362954/netanyahu-israel-congress-gaza-democrats-biden</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Joshua Keating]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 22:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[FBI director discusses the Trump rally shooter’s search history and drone details]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="A glitching image of Donald Trump" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-mHcOq5Sur1Ia9Wz_uU6z9ZgSII=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73480649/STK175_Trump_Fist_Glitch.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Image: Kristen Radtke / The Verge; Getty Images</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="LiVjG2">FBI director Christopher Wray said on Wednesday that the person who attempted to assassinate former President Donald Trump searched the web for “How far away was Oswald from Kennedy?” one week before the rally shooting, as <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/24/us/politics/fbi-director-wray-trump-shooting-hearing.html">reported by the <em>The New York Times</em></a>.</p>
<p id="hKXkXc">Investigators recovered the search from a laptop linked to 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks, which refers to the 1963 assassination of President John F. Kennedy by Lee Harvey Oswald. “That’s a search that’s obviously significant in terms of his state of mind,” Wray said <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cNZZYxDjvBA">during a hearing</a> before the House Judiciary Committee. “That is the same day that it appears that he registered for the Butler rally.”</p>
<div id="3qto1k"><div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"></div></div>
<p id="GrAozh">As reported by the <em>NYT</em>, Wray said Crooks visited the site of the Butler,...</p>
  <p>
    <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/24/24205527/trump-rally-shooter-search-history-drone-fbi">Continue reading&hellip;</a>
  </p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/24/24205527/trump-rally-shooter-search-history-drone-fbi</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/24/24205527/trump-rally-shooter-search-history-drone-fbi</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Roth]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:09:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A new Chinese video-generating model appears to be censoring politically sensitive topics]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A powerful new video-generating AI model became widely available today — but there&#8217;s a catch: The model appears to be censoring topics deemed too politically sensitive by the government in its country of origin, China. The model, Kling, developed by Beijing-based company Kuaishou, launched in waitlisted access earlier in the year for users with a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/07/24/a-new-chinese-video-generating-model-appears-to-be-censoring-politically-sensitive-topics/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/07/24/a-new-chinese-video-generating-model-appears-to-be-censoring-politically-sensitive-topics/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:07:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Watch: Moscow's Europe Square renamed Eurasia Square]]></title><description><![CDATA[Moscow's Europe Square has been renamed Eurasia Square, as Russian relations with the West deteriorate.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/cnl0pqkyqxko</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/cnl0pqkyqxko</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 22:53:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Salman Rushdie Attacker Indicted On Terrorism Charges]]></title><description><![CDATA[The man accused of trying to kill the author Salman Rushdie has been charged with terrorism for allegedly acting on behalf of Hezbollah, according to documents unsealed Wednesday.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/salman-rushdie-attacker-indicted-on-terrorism-charges-6182166</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/salman-rushdie-attacker-indicted-on-terrorism-charges-6182166</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 22:36:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Middle East Crisis: Netanyahu Offers Full-Throated Defense of Gaza War]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Israeli prime minister portrayed the war in Gaza as a “clash between barbarism and civilization” and declared “we will win.” He called antiwar protesters outside the Capitol “Iran’s useful idiots.”]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/07/24/world/israel-gaza-war-hamas</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/07/24/world/israel-gaza-war-hamas</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 22:59:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Protesters Denounce Netanyahu’s Speech to Congress and Some Clash With Police]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thousands of peaceful protesters gathered west of the Capitol, and smaller breakoff groups clashed with the police nearby and outside Union Station.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/24/world/middleeast/netanyahu-speech-protests-congress.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/24/world/middleeast/netanyahu-speech-protests-congress.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 22:58:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden to deliver Oval Office address on decision not to seek reelection as Harris and Trump hit the trail - CNN]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPYktJYVFvbzF2RkpBT0JnQ09JR2tZdnJydzlmLUQ2VE9weTV4NXJSaXFuRjJzV3Q2aDMzMFo5Rk91cmsyX3VTNHJnZmdVNzlyeklkUThleE84aGRxbDZYRXhiMVVNVmVtSEpqTW1yOUJ1ZGhoVzBYa0MwcHZ3S0ZsSVZlRXIwNkZX0gF_QVVfeXFMTWpIOUNyMHV0RkE1U1VZRUJlblhMazVCcmlNaU5ZYURRLWhqY2pvSnJjZEN3ZTB2Wmd3TVVWQllsMmpJVUdBb0tLb2U2V0xhQ3ZoZGNpR1RlQW5fekNmdHVhWmUtRm1nTE01YVM4Tkt0THMyVFlWdXhrUUh2NzBjVQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden to deliver Oval Office address on decision not to seek reelection as Harris and Trump hit the trail</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxPOFZmZkx1aWJHOGRwcy0xczBvNUJFSFUxWGZka1VlYzI5aUR1dS1FajloUXhtMllOR1d2ajFSOWdXQjVlUWxwOW44enVGQ01Eenc0QlYxR1VRSm56M2p4UXZSaWFVZ0s0UVJCWjVUTndOcThiZ2lxeVFwMW94Y0Z1clhZMWFmTmljRklzdUpWMHp0R0dNaGliaQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden to deliver Oval Office address after dropping out of 2024 presidential race: Live updates</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVkFVX3lxTFBXdVpBOVpYZWt0c3lqM2RCV09oYlN6czVJNTBXRlRyclBQQi1NRE5oLU81NHpJNFBvQTNMRDBLczRTZW8zY0RhMlhkcGtBdzlZOTdMUXdB?oc=5" target="_blank">White House officials are not giving an alternative reason why President Biden is stepping aside</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTFB3bEdoeUJrRTBuZDJYeHFmaHhfem1NQ0xwbkFxZ0Nla18wX3VwLUJnc1NIRnVYMUZVSDdJeUtRVTg5WUZhWmpOT0hpUkxwb1RFWHVwVlF4Wlc4cVZWWExjQ01aUy16M2YyZmdzX0JNdlIyd0VzLXpQWE9sLVk?oc=5" target="_blank">How to Watch President Biden’s Address From the Oval Office Tonight</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxPM3NrVmc0d2hUSkxIbFo0VWc2VWYza3NBdUZpNTIyb2JNeVk3V1lNR2pBVmYxcGp2bjZHZXM3V3lkSVdIY21US05lRE0tdkg2ZlMyel8tSU1lT05EVWt1VkdXNDZXVmR6UVNVTHpFcVZ0eGhZdW50ZHEzUjVEdldtWEs3d2dDVmhqakVwUFBSalZaRk4wNWpEc0xqOG4?oc=5" target="_blank">Election 2024 live updates: Biden to give first speech since dropping out of race</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPYktJYVFvbzF2RkpBT0JnQ09JR2tZdnJydzlmLUQ2VE9weTV4NXJSaXFuRjJzV3Q2aDMzMFo5Rk91cmsyX3VTNHJnZmdVNzlyeklkUThleE84aGRxbDZYRXhiMVVNVmVtSEpqTW1yOUJ1ZGhoVzBYa0MwcHZ3S0ZsSVZlRXIwNkZX0gF_QVVfeXFMTWpIOUNyMHV0RkE1U1VZRUJlblhMazVCcmlNaU5ZYURRLWhqY2pvSnJjZEN3ZTB2Wmd3TVVWQllsMmpJVUdBb0tLb2U2V0xhQ3ZoZGNpR1RlQW5fekNmdHVhWmUtRm1nTE01YVM4Tkt0THMyVFlWdXhrUUh2NzBjVQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPYktJYVFvbzF2RkpBT0JnQ09JR2tZdnJydzlmLUQ2VE9weTV4NXJSaXFuRjJzV3Q2aDMzMFo5Rk91cmsyX3VTNHJnZmdVNzlyeklkUThleE84aGRxbDZYRXhiMVVNVmVtSEpqTW1yOUJ1ZGhoVzBYa0MwcHZ3S0ZsSVZlRXIwNkZX0gF_QVVfeXFMTWpIOUNyMHV0RkE1U1VZRUJlblhMazVCcmlNaU5ZYURRLWhqY2pvSnJjZEN3ZTB2Wmd3TVVWQllsMmpJVUdBb0tLb2U2V0xhQ3ZoZGNpR1RlQW5fekNmdHVhWmUtRm1nTE01YVM4Tkt0THMyVFlWdXhrUUh2NzBjVQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 16:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden was losing Black voters, but can Harris win them back? - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNbUc1Q1BiZVlpQ2RVOU5OSk03TkhXWTV4aHhEZVVlLWQ2b2UzNDA3QUpIeU5IV3laX3UxR2taZE1wbHBtQlBVZUNMVWNwTk1UVEhzeFF1QW8zc2dNaXBVc1NIam9vU2xvUlFRWnZ5Q2FJYlNLb3R0SnBtNEdFaDU3VHNBSHNac3laYWswX01mMzlkQdIBVkFVX3lxTE9RcFo2M2lUMDRaLVNBRFV6M2ppcDdkV2hSXzN3Ukc2MDF3TElIam1YUUVBSUE1Rk43MExqbmcyTXo5ZXJoaHFYdlY5VVBDLTU5NU1WNW1B?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden was losing Black voters, but can Harris win them back?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxQTVUxQUFjSXVUaFh1QXFQOVNweGxKYkh3N08xcUtFWUdqVGRSYjNwcE0xcktzX1NMLWQ4ZUFhWnhlYmJmYU10LXFlYmdkWlljYjhMTTAwNHlaY3Y2QkFHT1FqUlNNRzY0VjE1a3JUbzYxVnFCUE1QY2oyYmVCREVHM015anhFMHplcnBQeUJUR1IxSGg2NktjLXB0b0t2WmJ0a1JlZksxVnNlODTSAVRBVV95cUxNZWpIU3psb3FpVXROWnJfYUh5VzhIeVRveS1ncjlvcFVRc3Y1MW1NX21XSXliX0ZySU1CNksyc0dVYXV5SjJjUnNDSEx1RzlNVzBoS3I?oc=5" target="_blank">Kamala Harris speaking to Zeta Phi Beta sorority is part of a winning strategy</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MSNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxOWGZKdUNHSEJpSjBGc05FNEtPbndIOXF4aW9xZ2JLZ3AxS0Y3ZVVJemdER1hwSzVld211TTNSZUx3VjF1SmI2TW02WkZ6aXJMRXJJMV9oRXY2SVhBMHpscWlhS1FTR1hDSzg4ZjdhdUtlcVpQLUFTY3J0cGxtZUR6OVg4ONIBR0FVX3lxTE0tcW4ydnF5cThZUFhkUDA4bHAxVHg4OUpDMHN1RzVVLXZmWGdFYlp2bVUxSEFRbm9EQkszV1g4cG5IakUyTC00?oc=5" target="_blank">Black women-led stream gets 90K viewers, raises $1.5M US for Kamala Harris in a few hours</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBC.ca</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxQU1JqT1k5UElyUFNiWlZNaTJyeGtjRVdjREJvRGZJR1BWbzlEekFhU3BXZ3VkZ2NYckVOdE1pSEZPaUZJYWdWX2tlT0Y1eXpaWXNwVGxvRFNWdDlZejkxOTlUTmJoS1F2Mzl4dXplcDZFT0VocGN5MVpHeWJaZzVfLQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris taps Black sorority and fraternity ‘family’ for political power</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE1yMmM5bG5iUHVPUWVqUmZNQ3RRZjdFSjVyQS1USldpUG9oNXlrTVlTU3VVX0puVU5SLWRzcDJDNDQ2TGl3NmRSS0xMeEJPMjJ0R1RXZXZxZlNZUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Divine Nine fraternities and sororities get behind Kamala Harris</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNbUc1Q1BiZVlpQ2RVOU5OSk03TkhXWTV4aHhEZVVlLWQ2b2UzNDA3QUpIeU5IV3laX3UxR2taZE1wbHBtQlBVZUNMVWNwTk1UVEhzeFF1QW8zc2dNaXBVc1NIam9vU2xvUlFRWnZ5Q2FJYlNLb3R0SnBtNEdFaDU3VHNBSHNac3laYWswX01mMzlkQdIBVkFVX3lxTE9RcFo2M2lUMDRaLVNBRFV6M2ppcDdkV2hSXzN3Ukc2MDF3TElIam1YUUVBSUE1Rk43MExqbmcyTXo5ZXJoaHFYdlY5VVBDLTU5NU1WNW1B?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNbUc1Q1BiZVlpQ2RVOU5OSk03TkhXWTV4aHhEZVVlLWQ2b2UzNDA3QUpIeU5IV3laX3UxR2taZE1wbHBtQlBVZUNMVWNwTk1UVEhzeFF1QW8zc2dNaXBVc1NIam9vU2xvUlFRWnZ5Q2FJYlNLb3R0SnBtNEdFaDU3VHNBSHNac3laYWswX01mMzlkQdIBVkFVX3lxTE9RcFo2M2lUMDRaLVNBRFV6M2ppcDdkV2hSXzN3Ukc2MDF3TElIam1YUUVBSUE1Rk43MExqbmcyTXo5ZXJoaHFYdlY5VVBDLTU5NU1WNW1B?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 20:57:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House GOP leaders ask members to stop making racial attacks against Harris - The Washington Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxOQ29MUGpSNHgta0R3NVN5elgxQTVVNzJiT1h0dTNONjgwbnB4RnJVM3NIVU5Fa0Y5RkIxcGxMeTdqVWNVRzNjbHFWWm9OWlVMZVBoUGJ6RkNSSzFUbHZXUFpHdE5ncUpUSWZaQ2pxQ2tqSjhJUU53VkJmTkVsTDNXeGlwWWxHTGZ5ZHVSR3gxVnEwSXZXNWEw?oc=5" target="_blank">House GOP leaders ask members to stop making racial attacks against Harris</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOak9BaUlCazJ3SWdpRUtHakVfM0pRNHV4Qm1BdU44aUJKZWlFd0U1MGx3MmRnN1BTaEIzNnU4VHkzZGNwMFZoWHF0ZTJ3MlhjVkoyWDY3UFprOTBsZ1AwZjNKai11VTZMQmZXZWM1UGJTLVAwYy1nWHROWEpvV002VElWMURLMkV3d19VYlNFczZWQzF4UUEyam5Vc0pkN2tseVhOeVBGM280VmpRdHFHY1RhWQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Kamala Harris is already facing a flood of racism and sexism</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxPZG1YZHJGTjNUSkRDS3N5NXFUeEhNeWJhQ1hpVV93a0FwTXFLbjkyRFFEeUhlMjVRa3VhcHVfckZJdm16T0o3emR4NjU0MVpza2pUb0ZkenlZc2R0OG83c0RHclJMTVg4bXlXWDkyWjA0NG1WSjIzbGxENDBNZ1ZYR0NrcVkyR0HSAYwBQVVfeXFMUDFGYzJuTWxpbUFYSHl0cndWMllqbHU4WDlMd0R0X3VIaUJXZFBTYy1aalFIWmUzV29tSDdYZFdtRXpfZTM3MlM0ajY4LUc2VFR2cTB3Y09sOFhxSXdaSEJfMHRUblhqdUdqV1ZvTTRncGp2V1J1MG50RkoxTGFBdlBkTndNMjRWOE9KVzQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Susan Rice: Calling Harris a ‘DEI hire’ is ‘incredibly insulting’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMif0FVX3lxTFA0ZF9rSDZSVTJ4SkluQnd6cWhCOWJKOHVmZ3pGblpKMHhUSU9MY1VfSjhzWmxWVEx1enZUem4tYnp1ai1SQnBwQVB6RzBBLWw5Q3hZMjU4VUlfSVJhOHVvWnhweGQ0eG5QVzI3WGo0eGNXU1IxYldiRG14R3FGYjA?oc=5" target="_blank">House GOP leaders urge members: Stop making race comments about Harris</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxOTV94eThuRzY1Z0xNTGRGUExYaUswZkdnMzNQNUl0c2pCZklnWE96MmVfdEN3eDRRZmh0dG9NQUdMSnIycHBGbE0wX3JhM0JfbGFjYUpRdTJjRlljeWY0dGtIeEZEX1V6NGlyemZHLWtmMDBqaGNGOEg4djR2ZzRzU0Q0dG5YRXNMUld0S0wzanNkTGVIN3RKVjBmUdIBkgFBVV95cUxNTm03ZlRsU0MzSFh6V0llLTdUYVlsd3poYm54LVdMU09wa3lsWmRya3ZHZy1MdmNhWWhQZnpYdlZNQnFHQ0NfcFNWbWNNblFKU1c2azg2a0t3Rk4tUlF5Q1l5dU82WVNIVGFnLWFBOE1zTnhfT09LT2JHaVpDZ2lybVRrQmJfLXpwTERpYmVUeURudw?oc=5" target="_blank">Right-wing media figures target Kamala Harris with race and gender-based attacks</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxOQ29MUGpSNHgta0R3NVN5elgxQTVVNzJiT1h0dTNONjgwbnB4RnJVM3NIVU5Fa0Y5RkIxcGxMeTdqVWNVRzNjbHFWWm9OWlVMZVBoUGJ6RkNSSzFUbHZXUFpHdE5ncUpUSWZaQ2pxQ2tqSjhJUU53VkJmTkVsTDNXeGlwWWxHTGZ5ZHVSR3gxVnEwSXZXNWEw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxOQ29MUGpSNHgta0R3NVN5elgxQTVVNzJiT1h0dTNONjgwbnB4RnJVM3NIVU5Fa0Y5RkIxcGxMeTdqVWNVRzNjbHFWWm9OWlVMZVBoUGJ6RkNSSzFUbHZXUFpHdE5ncUpUSWZaQ2pxQ2tqSjhJUU53VkJmTkVsTDNXeGlwWWxHTGZ5ZHVSR3gxVnEwSXZXNWEw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:21:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Guardian: Number of Russian invaders in Ukraine surge to 520,000 says Commander-in-Chief Syrskyi]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1eb8uas/the_guardian_number_of_russian_invaders_in/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/e_ezDdTKuuf6uGmLsGGsil-DxlWa1ns7pB4ZC5DMwok.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=481c6a18e1bbeaac7489fce0b0e2de28f9f07e2b" alt="The Guardian: Number of Russian invaders in Ukraine surge to 520,000 says Commander-in-Chief Syrskyi" title="The Guardian: Number of Russian invaders in Ukraine surge to 520,000 says Commander-in-Chief Syrskyi" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/creekwhisk"> /u/creekwhisk </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://euromaidanpress.com/2024/07/24/the-guardian-number-of-russian-invaders-in-ukraine-surge-to-520000-says-commander-in-chief-syrskyi/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1eb8uas/the_guardian_number_of_russian_invaders_in/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1eb8uas/the_guardian_number_of_russian_invaders_in/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1eb8uas/the_guardian_number_of_russian_invaders_in/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/creekwhisk]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 18:32:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia news live: Penny Wong imposes sanctions on Israelis over West Bank settler violence; military exercise to resume after crash]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Foreign minister said Magnitsky-style financial sanctions and travel bans would apply to seven Israeli individuals and one entity. Follow the day’s news live</p><ul><li><strong>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl">morning and afternoon news emails</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></strong></li></ul><p><strong>Q:</strong> Why target the individuals when it’s state policy?</p><p><strong>Penny Wong</strong> said the Australian government has been “clear in terms of state-to-state relations about our view on settlements”.</p><p>They are unlawful under international law. We’ve been clear about that … We have also said that we want to continue to take steps towards a two-state solution.</p><p>That may not be the view of some people in the Israeli government, but that is the view of the Australian government.</p><p>These individuals have been involved in violent attacks on Palestinians, including things such as beating, sexual assault and torture, resulting in serious injury and in some cases death.</p><p>We have imposed these after careful consideration and we would expect that all Australians would recognise the weight of these.</p><p>Settlements are unlawful under international law. We are continuing to act in ways that we can to look to how we protect a pathway to a two-state solution, and part of that is to ensure we also impose penalties who perpetrate violence against Palestinians.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2024/jul/25/penny-wong-sanctions-israelis-military-exercise-plane-crash-labor-coalition-politics-climate-olympics-vic-nsw-qld-melbourne-sydney-roundup-nfbntw">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2024/jul/25/penny-wong-sanctions-israelis-military-exercise-plane-crash-labor-coalition-politics-climate-olympics-vic-nsw-qld-melbourne-sydney-roundup-nfbntw</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2024/jul/25/penny-wong-sanctions-israelis-military-exercise-plane-crash-labor-coalition-politics-climate-olympics-vic-nsw-qld-melbourne-sydney-roundup-nfbntw</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:08:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Were Benjamin Netanyahu’s claims accurate in his speech to US Congress?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We factcheck the Israeli prime minister’s statements about letting aid trucks into Gaza, safeguarding civilians and negotiations with Hamas</p><p>Benjamin Netanyahu’s <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/jul/24/netanyahu-israel-gaza-congress-speech-">speech to Congress</a> was filled with combative remarks, as well as claims about the war in Gaza, now almost in its tenth month.</p><p>Israel’s assault on the territory was triggered by the 7 October Hamas attacks on southern Israel, and has so far killed more than 39,000 people, with thousands more believed to be buried underneath the rubble.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/jul/24/fact-check-benjamin-netanyahus-speech-to-the-us-congress">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/jul/24/fact-check-benjamin-netanyahus-speech-to-the-us-congress</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/jul/24/fact-check-benjamin-netanyahus-speech-to-the-us-congress</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 22:10:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden to say he decided to ‘pass the torch’ to unite the US and defend democracy – live]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>President to give Oval Office address at 8pm ET about decision to step aside; excerpts show he will say ‘defense of democracy is more important than title’</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/24/biden-speech-watch-time">How to watch Biden’s speech</a></li></ul><p><strong>Kevin McCarthy</strong>, the former Republican House speaker, has described attacks by his former colleagues on <strong>Kamala Harris</strong> claiming that she was hired as part of diversity, equity and inclusion (DEI) initiatives are “stupid and dumb”.</p><p>McCarthy, speaking to NBC News’ Meet the Press NOW last night, said:</p><p>I disagree with DEI, but she is the vice-president of the United States, she is the former US senator. These congressmen saying it, they are wrong in their own instincts.</p><p>If President Biden is committed to passing the torch to his vice president, and wants to be able to seed her campaign with the current Biden for President campaign war chest, he’ll first have to become his party’s legal nominee. After shuffling through the Democratic National Committee’s planned roll call vote he’d be free to drop out. Ms Harris could seamlessly slip into the driver’s seat.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/jul/24/harris-biden-trump-vance-latest-us-election-news-updates">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/jul/24/harris-biden-trump-vance-latest-us-election-news-updates</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/jul/24/harris-biden-trump-vance-latest-us-election-news-updates</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 23:02:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to watch Biden’s Oval Office address tonight]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>President to speak from White House during prime time, days after announcing he will not seek re-election</p><p>Joe Biden on Wednesday will deliver his first televised remarks since dropping out of the 2024 presidential race. On Sunday, the president pledged to provide “more detail about my decision” to not seek reelection in an address to the nation.</p><p>The president added more detail on Tuesday, saying on X that he will outline “what lies ahead, and how I will finish the job for the American people”. There are six months remaining in his term, and Biden and the White House have said he will serve out the remainder of his time in office.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/24/biden-speech-watch-time">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/24/biden-speech-watch-time</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/24/biden-speech-watch-time</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 22:53:01 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>