<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:49:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:49:41 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Who could be Kamala Harris’s VP? The potential list, briefly explained.]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Harris, in a dark suit, stands behind a podium with the US presidential seal; she points and smiles. The US flag is behind her." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2160744008_a0c39e.webp?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">Following President Joe Biden’s exit from the 2024 presidential race</a>, and his endorsement of <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee">Vice President Kamala Harris</a> as his choice for the Democratic nominee, one of the next big questions that’s emerged is who could potentially be her running mate. Though Harris is not the nominee yet, Biden’s backing gives her a significant boost ahead of <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024">other potential contenders</a>, fueling speculation about who else could join the ticket.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, vice presidents have been selected to complement the main candidate. Biden, for instance, named Harris because she would bring youth, diversity, and legal experience. And former President Donald Trump chose Vice President Mike Pence because he was a traditional conservative and offered legislative expertise that he didn’t have.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc">Does Harris give Democrats a better chance in 2024?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee">Harris’s strengths and vulnerabilities as a presidential candidate</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What might Harris look for? Based on that history, there are a few guesses: Her pick could be someone from a purple or red state, who offers geographic diversity given her roots in California. And — to assuage voters who still hold sexist or racist attitudes, as President Barack Obama did with Biden in 2008 — it might be a white man.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Below is a rundown of some of the possible candidates who might be considered — and what they’d bring to the ticket.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2159037882_26f6dd.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. Roy Cooper, in a navy suit, speaks from a podium to a large crowd holding Biden-Harris campaign signs." title="Gov. Roy Cooper, in a navy suit, speaks from a podium to a large crowd holding Biden-Harris campaign signs." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="North Carolina Gov. Roy Cooper speaks before President Joe Biden at a post-debate campaign rally on June 28, in Raleigh, North Carolina. | Allison Joyce/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Allison Joyce/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Roy Cooper</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Cooper, 67, is the governor of North Carolina, a battleground state that Trump won narrowly in 2020 and 2016 that offers <a href="https://www.ncsbe.gov/about-elections/electoral-college">16 electoral votes</a> (of the 270 needed to win). He’s known for winning repeatedly statewide even as other Democratic candidates have struggled to do the same for roles like the Senate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor, he’s also vetoed Republican bills on abortion and guns, and has strong approval <a href="https://abc11.com/post/2024-elections-could-governor-roy-cooper-replace-president/15011995/">ratings overall</a>. Prior to becoming governor, he served as the state’s attorney general and in the state legislature.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Cooper could help improve Democrats’ chances in a battleground state, though it will still likely be an uphill battle given past contests in North Carolina. He’s also been pretty popular in his role, and has secured backing from some moderates and Republicans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He previously collaborated with Harris while they each served as their states’ AG, meaning they have experience working alongside one another. And more recently, Harris and Cooper <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bsVNTI1BqZo">have campaigned together</a> in the wake of <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357788/biden-trump-debate-winners-losers">Biden’s disastrous June debate</a>, during which the governor cautioned against the return of “Donald Trump’s America.”</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2150001600_c3763f.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.736744421098,100,78.526511157804" alt="Gov. Josh Shapiro, in glasses and a navy suit jacket, waves at reporters and a crowd." title="Gov. Josh Shapiro, in glasses and a navy suit jacket, waves at reporters and a crowd." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Pennsylvania Gov. Josh Shapiro arrives to deliver remarks at a building trades union conference on April 24, in Washington, DC. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Josh Shapiro</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Shapiro, 51, is the governor of Pennsylvania, another likely battleground state (with <a href="https://www.archives.gov/electoral-college/allocation">19 Electoral College votes</a>), which Biden won in 2020 and which former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton lost in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He was elected in 2022, the same year that freshman Sen. John Fetterman (D-PA) was elected to the Senate. Shapiro ran far ahead of Fetterman, <a href="https://www.politico.com/2022-election/results/pennsylvania/">winning 57 percent of the vote, to Fetterman’s 51 percent</a>. Shapiro has established himself as a moderate who helped negotiate bipartisan deals when he was in the state legislature, and is also known for his work as attorney general, when he secured settlements for victims of sexual abuse by the Catholic Diocese. He’s also been a vocal supporter of Israel amid the country’s devastating military offensive in Gaza, following Hamas’ brutal October 7 attack.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him?</strong> Like Cooper, he’s the popular Democratic governor of a swing state and could help the party improve their chances there. He’s also seen as more of a centrist who could appeal to moderate voters and independents, though his staunch backing of Israel could turn away progressive Democrats.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161807297_5538e2.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. Andy Beshear, in a light blue shirt and wearing a lapel mic, speaks to reporters while standing outdoors." title="Gov. Andy Beshear, in a light blue shirt and wearing a lapel mic, speaks to reporters while standing outdoors." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Kentucky Gov. Andy Beshear speaks to reporters following a ribbon-cutting ceremony in Hazel, Kentucky, in October 2023. | Lexington Herald-Leader/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Lexington Herald-Leader/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Andy Beshear</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Beshear, 46, is the governor of Kentucky and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/11/7/23950792/election-day-2023-kentucky-governors-race-results-democrats-republicans">has won twice in a red state that previously overwhelmingly voted for Trump</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor, he’s been praised for his handling of the Covid-19 pandemic as well as multiple crises in the state, including <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/4/11/23679512/louisville-kentucky-shooting-workplace">a mass shooting at a bank</a> and severe flooding. Prior to this role, he also served as Kentucky’s attorney general.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Beshear is the rare Democrat who has been able to win multiple times in a red state and could offer additional appeal to some swing voters. In addition to the support he’s received for his leadership during various crises, he’s also touted infrastructure and private sector investment in the state during his tenure.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unlike other possibilities, though, he probably wouldn’t increase Harris’s chances of winning his home state, which is solidly GOP.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2160763179.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. J.B. Pritzer, in a dark suit and pink striped tie, speaks into a microphone at a podium, with a screen lighting him from the back." title="Gov. J.B. Pritzer, in a dark suit and pink striped tie, speaks into a microphone at a podium, with a screen lighting him from the back." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Illinois Gov. J.B. Pritzker speaks during to a Chicago-area chamber of commerce meeting on June 4, 2024, in Chicago. | Eileen T. Meslar/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Eileen T. Meslar/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. J.B. Pritzker</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>J.B. Pritzker, 59, is the governor of Illinois, a Democratic state that Biden and Clinton both won in 2020 and 2016. Before becoming governor, he was a businessman and philanthropist, and is a scion of the family behind Hyatt hotels, who’ve also been consistent and influential Democratic donors.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor, Pritzker has established a modest national profile, including remarks he’s given attacking Trump and calls he’s made for more federal resources to address immigration in Illinois.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Pritzker has already built some name recognition as a fixture on cable news, and has proven to be a vocal Trump antagonist. Pritzker’s personal wealth could also potentially be a boon to the campaign, though his own state is not a battleground that would expand the Democratic map.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2160744008_a0c39e.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Sen. Mark Kelly, in a navy suit and blue-striped tie, wears a serious expression while speaking to a gaggle of reporters with microphones and smartphones. " title="Sen. Mark Kelly, in a navy suit and blue-striped tie, wears a serious expression while speaking to a gaggle of reporters with microphones and smartphones. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Sen. Mark Kelly (D-AZ) is questioned about the candidacy of President Joe Biden after a Senate luncheon on July 9. | Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Sen. Mark Kelly</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Kelly is the junior senator of Arizona — a swing state with <a href="https://www.archives.gov/electoral-college/allocation">11 Electoral College votes</a> — <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/11/5/21537670/senate-2020-results-arizona-mark-kelly-winner">who was elected in 2020</a> by framing himself as a candidate willing to work across the aisle. Previously, Biden won Arizona in 2020, while Clinton lost the state in 2016. Kelly is also known for his career as an astronaut alongside his twin brother Scott Kelly, and as the husband of gun control advocate and former US Rep. Gabby Giffords.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Kelly has a higher profile than some of the other names on this list, and is respected both for his scientific expertise and contributions as an astronaut in addition to his time in the Senate. He’s been a prominent gun control advocate alongside Giffords and made pushing these policies a priority.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given his efforts to appeal to both Republicans and independents in Arizona, he’d be another option who could help with trying to reach those voters. Arizona also continues to be an important battleground this time around, including in its <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/ratings/senate-race-ratings">Senate race</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1394802139.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Pete Buttigieg, in a navy suit and white shirt, is shown from the side, while pinning an index card onto a wall full of similar cards with handwritten notes. " title="Pete Buttigieg, in a navy suit and white shirt, is shown from the side, while pinning an index card onto a wall full of similar cards with handwritten notes. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg attends a White House correspondents’ brunch on April 30, 2022, in Washington, DC. | Paul Morigi/Getty Images for White House Correspondents Insider" data-portal-copyright="Paul Morigi/Getty Images for White House Correspondents Insider" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Secretary Pete Buttigieg</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he?</strong> Buttigieg, 42, is the secretary of transportation who rose to prominence as a former 2020 presidential candidate. He’s staked out more moderate positions and was previously mayor of South Bend, Indiana.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He’s become known for his media savvy and strong television appearances as an advocate for the Biden-Harris administration. He’s also had to respond to crises including the train accident and <a href="https://www.vox.com/science/2023/2/18/23603471/east-palestine-ohio-derailment-water-contamination-health">chemical spill in East Palestine</a>, Ohio, as well as the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024/1/8/24030677/boeing-alaska-airlines-plane-737-max-door-plug">Alaska Airlines mishap</a> when a door plug dropped out of a plane.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Buttigieg has been a strong spokesperson for the Biden-Harris White House and is well-established among the Democratic electorate. He’s among the youngest of possible choices, would contribute more representation from the Midwest,<strong> </strong>and could appeal to centrist voters. He’d also become the first openly LGBTQ person to be on a presidential ticket.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161013764_474f9c.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752616398754,100,78.494767202492" alt="Gov. Gavin Newsom, in a gray striped jacket and blue shirt, squints into the sun as he speaks outdoors." title="Gov. Gavin Newsom, in a gray striped jacket and blue shirt, squints into the sun as he speaks outdoors." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="California Gov. Gavin Newsom speaks during a press conference in Oakland, California, on July 11. | Stephen Lam/San Francisco Chronicle/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Lam/San Francisco Chronicle/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Gavin Newsom</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Newsom, 56, is the governor of California, and a longstanding political personality. He’s been a vocal advocate for more progressive policies, and for Democrats to more directly confront Republicans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Prior to being governor, he was also lieutenant governor and mayor of San Francisco.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Newsom has already made clear that he wants to be a fighter for Democrats and has supporters who are interested in his approach. He’s also used opportunities like a debate against Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis to make some splashy points for the party and to get more attention, and could do the same for a possible campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor of California, however, he wouldn’t bring additional geographic diversity to the ticket, and he also wouldn’t help with delivering a swing state, as his own is solidly Democratic. In addition, Newsom and Harris are both Californians, so they’d also likely have to contend with issues raised by the 12th Amendment of the Constitution, which prohibits two running mates from the same state.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1953489582.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,9.6422338568935,100,80.715532286213" alt="Walz — white haired, balding, and clean shaven — raises a hand as he speaks at a podium, clad in a navy suit and white dress shirt." title="Walz — white haired, balding, and clean shaven — raises a hand as he speaks at a podium, clad in a navy suit and white dress shirt." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz speaks about funding for the I-535 Blatnik Bridge before a visit by US President Joe Biden at Earth Rider Brewery on January 25, 2024 in Superior, Wisconsin. | Stephen Maturen/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Maturen/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Gov. Tim Walz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he?</strong> Walz, 60, is in his second term as governor of Minnesota. A <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/national/2024/07/who-is-minnesota-governor-tim-walz-one-of-the-top-contenders-for-vice-president/#:~:text=Tim%20Walz%20was%20a%20high,one%20of%20the%20student's%20wallets.">former high school teacher</a>, he’s been in politics for decades, having started as a member of Congress in 2007. He received national attention for leading his party through a <a href="https://apnews.com/article/minnesota-taxes-abortion-health-racial-justice-transportation-marijuana-c3cc7db0cd92c022817ef3ae41097c73">2023 legislative session</a> that saw Democrats in the state achieve a litany of long-held ambitions, including on police reform, boosting education funding, marijuana legalization, abortion protections, child tax credits, and more.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him?</strong> Walz is the <a href="https://www.kaaltv.com/news/approval-rates-for-minnesota-leaders/#">well-liked leader</a> of a <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/ratings/presidential-race-ratings">purplish state</a> with a record of advancing Democratic priorities through his state legislature and with <a href="https://minnesotareformer.com/2023/12/15/public-sector-unions-spend-more-on-politics-in-minnesota-than-in-nearly-any-other-state/">strong ties to organized labor</a>. A Midwesterner, Walz could prove to be a useful surrogate for <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-campaign-midwest-after-clinching-democratic-nomination-2024-03-13/">shoring up support</a> in his own state, as well as ones like Michigan and Wisconsin. And like many of the other potential vice president picks on this list, he’s already proved to be a <a href="https://www.axios.com/local/twin-cities/2024/07/23/tim-walz-vice-president-kamala-harris-vet-minnesota">strong Harris surrogate</a> on television news.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Out of the running</h2>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1247112367.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. Gretchen Whitmer, in a snakeskin-patterned blouse, speaks into a set of microphones, smillng, with the state seal of Michigan behind her." title="Gov. Gretchen Whitmer, in a snakeskin-patterned blouse, speaks into a set of microphones, smillng, with the state seal of Michigan behind her." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Michigan Gov. Gretchen Whitmer speaks at a press conference about an electric-vehicle battery plant in February 2023 in Romulus, Michigan. | Bill Pugliano/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Bill Pugliano/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Gretchen Whitmer</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is she? </strong>Whitmer, 52, is the governor of Michigan, a key swing state with <a href="https://www.archives.gov/electoral-college/allocation">15 Electoral College votes</a> that Biden won in 2020 and that Clinton lost in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She’s been a popular leader in this role, and was initially known for how much she emphasized infrastructure and “fixing the damn roads.” Since then she’s been an outspoken advocate for abortion rights and for gender equity, speaking openly about how she was sexually assaulted in college. Prior to being governor, Whitmer was a member of the state legislature and the first woman to become the Democratic leader of the state Senate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What was the case for her? </strong>She’s among the members of the list who have strong and positive national recognition, and who could help raise Democrats’ chances in a pivotal swing state. Whitmer has also focused on issues including infrastructure and health care, which could broaden Democrats’ appeal to moderate voters. And if Harris and Whitmer were on the same ticket, they would form a groundbreaking all-woman ticket — something that neither major party has run before.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Why she won&#8217;t be the new VP:</strong> Less than 24 hours after Biden endorsed Harris, Whitmer emphatically told reporters that she has no desire to be vice president. “I’m not planning to go anywhere,” <a href="https://x.com/kenvogel/status/1815417822056755621">she said, adding</a>, “I am not leaving Michigan; I&#8217;m proud to be the governor of Michigan.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, July 24, 2024, 3:30 pm ET:</em></strong> <em>This piece was originally published on July 21 and has been updated multiple times, most recently to include Gov. Whitmer’s remarks and the consideration of Gov. Tim Walz. </em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, July 21, 2024, 11:59 pm ET: </strong>A previous version of this story misstated Gabby Giffords’s position on guns. She is a gun control advocate.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/362043/kamala-harris-vice-running-mate-democratic-presidential-ticket</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/362043/kamala-harris-vice-running-mate-democratic-presidential-ticket</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Li Zhou]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:40:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[JD Vance’s sexist comments on ‘childless cat ladies’ like Kamala Harris go viral again - The Independent]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxNVTRLT0piRFNhZWJQTU5PLWU5V2lpTElJT0lMMVY4ZldZUWY1S0Rwa2FISmdrWkVWd0wxeFNXN1ZFUVoxaVdzS2tmUHhoUko5U0I4U0ExdnEya2gzZUxhNnFvMzdOTlRLS29ZV0xkdThCMDN2UUpCOTVlRUdkUU1SbFV1TC1oaFFmMEw1eVlTOWh1cmVnWExwOUZHLTJPeEhrOGg3Q2dzWFdsbU1oR2JBdnlrVlhxdXJh?oc=5" target="_blank">JD Vance’s sexist comments on ‘childless cat ladies’ like Kamala Harris go viral again</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Independent</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxPby1ubHNQdXJFYVVBbHZOZnF5QWxIN1M2cDdBYmFNNVN5dzFZX2NtdXd5d3VTNjZ2TmQ3TEk5LVZwZm5XcWl1c1hKeDI5c053cHFrOWdIRHJ4N0g2SWltUl9lanpKTTZNbVQ1VUhEU0F1VlpiYjRCMlFaZTh6OUlWblZ5b0VBZVpLTkF2MWZnOXJubEhvRW5iZ0lEd0lJZnFYVWxkVi1rNnFQd29lQXdmTFJVQkNrcHdnRGc?oc=5" target="_blank">Video: Pete Buttigieg responds to JD Vance’s criticism of childless Democrats</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxQQzRtejFkc2RuS3RiTGRpNGIyNWlNZzNzaGlpaUJidHUtYjA4Mk9mUnBUYTRhWTc3Ym1jSDJadkdWMmtPck9Xc0NvNlI1NWxVUmtsNGJ3ZHBtdHU4WkdkVTFMWUplTzVwbm5yU3ktaW1XTGVaLVdMZmhUNURYdEIxbDFR?oc=5" target="_blank">J.D. Vance said Kamala Harris has no kids. Stepparents would like a word.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxOeldIdlJQb3ZBT0lOWHBvckhRcnM5cERWZEplN1FWV0pPQ3NBMDhpekcwMkVMdjRLSXRsOHVmdllRdUE1S0FxUEE4U2dYTm93eWdGclM3VUowZGN6ODlyWTJtUDcwSkd6QTBSNWhFaTJOaEo5WVJvMUtkTFpYOE5yV2dkQkVBdkk?oc=5" target="_blank">Opinion | JD Vance Has a Bunch of Weird Views on Gender</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE1XUTlhUE45ZjZIVzlINVFyank1R0xGVm03VjJyNDAzUXduV3pVRHIzM0Y2RFZhVC04MGNkS0pRbVhzMjh3emFHWjQxSDAyenN6RlVzZHFNTDNwZ2RQb2JaYjAyUDBld3YtSmV1aC1Rb0pEVVNiYmVpa25B?oc=5" target="_blank">Opinion | Attacking Kamala Harris for Not Having Kids Will Backfire</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxNVTRLT0piRFNhZWJQTU5PLWU5V2lpTElJT0lMMVY4ZldZUWY1S0Rwa2FISmdrWkVWd0wxeFNXN1ZFUVoxaVdzS2tmUHhoUko5U0I4U0ExdnEya2gzZUxhNnFvMzdOTlRLS29ZV0xkdThCMDN2UUpCOTVlRUdkUU1SbFV1TC1oaFFmMEw1eVlTOWh1cmVnWExwOUZHLTJPeEhrOGg3Q2dzWFdsbU1oR2JBdnlrVlhxdXJh?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxNVTRLT0piRFNhZWJQTU5PLWU5V2lpTElJT0lMMVY4ZldZUWY1S0Rwa2FISmdrWkVWd0wxeFNXN1ZFUVoxaVdzS2tmUHhoUko5U0I4U0ExdnEya2gzZUxhNnFvMzdOTlRLS29ZV0xkdThCMDN2UUpCOTVlRUdkUU1SbFV1TC1oaFFmMEw1eVlTOWh1cmVnWExwOUZHLTJPeEhrOGg3Q2dzWFdsbU1oR2JBdnlrVlhxdXJh?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 04:42:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How the Secret Service Failed to Protect Trump - The New York Times]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxNSWFQUjJ4VlJSSV9CcmhtdXJ6RFZ0LWZRUElOdmM0cW10SExtTDFYRENJMU5mX0stNS1NT3B2d04xajQ3blJKcGNJa1R1aW53bC1UWXdXYm5rQzhvZjVoT05tQ2h6TTVMMXhZXzcxbTJxSWRvMzRHeUM4Z0dNdHZqbTg1aFZNQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">How the Secret Service Failed to Protect Trump</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQRFJCZ29HM2hsTHhMY1JFTWVNUWl2Vk1FaTdQaHBKV19EZGZfTzF0RmJ6VVpQRnVNWWlKQmprTEF6bEN1U0FyTmFrel9JZjlKT1VyVHJKS1B5clR1a20xSVlrd1dWNmhlUEhEQ0tGdEQtREhsLV9hVDAzcF9kNUVwTEpJYU1BN2Fla2I1cW1UQk5PdkI3Unc?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service Director Resigns After Trump Assassination Attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE9pZGo1UmhIcUNQT2RjX3h6Wmg5RnR0RjZoVUtueVA0WnlaRW9NcEJuREphR2t2OTVob1daekt3SEZHMG02SzEyczlSXzBxR0VPS2RJT3ZIeEtoM1d5b1hId1dOUXMzbU1Pb19EMEJvSTdUTy16ejZQNG9LQnNvQdIBgwFBVV95cUxObWpYdzMtYXRqcWZiaXFtQWNnbjBvdlg1a0VrN3ZiN05SZ3pzZ0s5Rm1SamNLVXNSdlkxblBIZEc1UlM1YTZNMUJ3UlU5SUp0UTBDTlE1UU9aRmxBeV9QaWthNndoSmwzUnU0dWVTT1oxUGVucWpRQWtDTkNtWVdPenA0NA?oc=5" target="_blank">What’s next for the Secret Service after Director Cheatle’s resignation?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAJBVV95cUxPQmpIYzF4SHcwejE2YlFWTkdGVE96clQxUEtjNEdhSnJBbUc1aWx6OE1hNl9KVTZlb2JJeC1oZ3pHNVpCY1p1cFEteVc3UmFNX2Uwdk00Smd4MFB6LVlWQ1NoSWJCZGlNSnRDbmxXU2EyRVhHWmhxVDhpdjZCeE5nMTZKSlNObXl3aDBFOWJROHJoODFrOVlmTjJVSkI5OTl6TTNvUU92ZFMwZ3pBRnhQNFJ1SkxJQkhXQ3JMOWUtZ1RIUVVCTUpyWVdQTjFOa19nc3R4YmQyX1ozYzBmQno2OERWWlJoZ2thVXVjam9lUnhaWWJIUHJjdVdYa2pPQW1XZ21Cb1VSREZwREJRelQ4bmtnaUZYOHhQUkVLSVdZaFJZTUV6LUFPWg?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service chief resigns following what bipartisan lawmakers called a 'disappointing' House hearing. Here's the key takeaways from Cheatle's day on Capitol Hill.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo! Voices</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxNQlNVNzBMRjFBd0ZLUV92a2pMWVpEU2c3VWRqMnVpcXE3eDhGcXhaWWxMUkhiUnZlR1V4am1DN0pmSUc2NU5ZVmFvbkJoTUxDbm1LdzdsSGU3S3BkbjZMcHFLbGJIQ2s3YW41S2J4N2wyZzlHTFd0Q19hWmJHRHNwS25wYnBXMEZEQ3NVVURxTEEta0J4U0ZQbXliWQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service director steps down after assassination attempt against ex-President Trump at rally</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxNSWFQUjJ4VlJSSV9CcmhtdXJ6RFZ0LWZRUElOdmM0cW10SExtTDFYRENJMU5mX0stNS1NT3B2d04xajQ3blJKcGNJa1R1aW53bC1UWXdXYm5rQzhvZjVoT05tQ2h6TTVMMXhZXzcxbTJxSWRvMzRHeUM4Z0dNdHZqbTg1aFZNQQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxNSWFQUjJ4VlJSSV9CcmhtdXJ6RFZ0LWZRUElOdmM0cW10SExtTDFYRENJMU5mX0stNS1NT3B2d04xajQ3blJKcGNJa1R1aW53bC1UWXdXYm5rQzhvZjVoT05tQ2h6TTVMMXhZXzcxbTJxSWRvMzRHeUM4Z0dNdHZqbTg1aFZNQQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 10:00:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[New wave of North Korean trash balloons hits U.S. Army base and Seoul presidential compound - CBS News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxQMzV5bXdrRC13MEdYb0lGcVd0SXJmRXJydTM0dS1mYXNfckRaR182OEZudUdYTXlNajBoRkJWYzJfYWplQ2NCRWZhQjJPQlhpNkVaZHJFSURmQ3Q2YlZDVE1oZzJ0VGRqY0pFNHpRNVRnS1lyQlJxVTNvcFRXTHlNYnJaVzR3d09pUGlDT2JBNG1IeU41MVYxTDFPbFNpRHRhZ09Z0gGoAUFVX3lxTFBXbVo4WGV4aDJlUEYxNUVtZk9VVTFCVXZJT1BlczZKcERreElkZkdnXzUyeWRmUkQydG1uUlRzLWNvVWY5VG1LQ1FlNXBDT0NVa3FmQlBVS1JpdUF2X0FoSV96eXRlRklQRFpXanRrdUxmSTd0dnZweHFvNGRJZXVXbzJsWHdsTldzdEhGV21hdHdhSkFGVHQ2VXhWeGVCWGdCR1lVVC10Xw?oc=5" target="_blank">New wave of North Korean trash balloons hits U.S. Army base and Seoul presidential compound</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNVnJfcUN6TWp5cHFObF95YkJINFBpaDBXVVllcU0tdTdEczR1Uk1ock5Ga0kyNkd4V0VzdUlyRmVyamoyb3ZmQkhOVndhcTdpWFlrcmtabzRrd2pnNnlmdmNpSWRpbDNUOWV3Rm14WkpHWXBtaEN6M3ZqOXdVMV9IVEdMZF95ZVY2WWRoR3ZranRPUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">North Korean Trash Balloons Hit South Korean President’s Compound</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxPb2dmdmFocDZHUk1vUm1TeXkyWFZwMUNzR19aRmE3MHRLQ0JMS0FOT1VydzVzeFVTWWJwRkt0Q3RaSTJKc1BWSzMya3o2cG9WaE9BWlB2Yll2X0FCYXVpLTdQazBLdjQ2M1lqalJIMThmWHJBbFF1S1RLcl9kQlJfNV92clZkQV92UGVZNWFoV3RNdXRfcUVzR2JVekV3WUdla2NGQ1k5dm9ZZGVB0gFWQVVfeXFMTnE1UmN6bkVLYWRvQTgyelphTWhycmZtOWZvRmNSWXdHNVhkY0ZxQWRoMTR6MFFpWV9CT2NOQmVteURGcFA0cXdubWtvTXo2cnNvc2ZUX1E?oc=5" target="_blank">North Korean trash balloon lands on South Korea's presidential compound</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxQcW44RXRIM1pEa1duX25tUGVJZzRGS1JGTG5pLUpOTzJsMEcteWJOR0NxMkdMLW9nVlBxY3FPVHhTMk9mQXkzOTRzS1plMGU2VDJoNWJlSDEwOTJIcHoyZV9pOHJqT0NMZEZ1Uk9kTTZKVVMtczJKMjlYc1dhTzRZYUlveDB6ZUR4ZWV1ZUtTUm8wWGhBcm1PV0pYS2tuMnZpQl9GWUZlWW5QN21XVlVkQ0ZUdHjSAbQBQVVfeXFMT2pubHVuTDFBaEVpanlhQlVhNWgyUDJOYzBveGZJR3RTVVVvYUh3cXE4ME9LbDZ4bWJ3V3lETkpUVGhVMXJaaFRoQXRBTmx5ZUtLdXVod3VaTk5VUFUxSDZhZjRLRFJEMlZ4b1NwMGt6V0x2b3JqUDVTR2VQQWtndDVmeWkxd1pLTW9XNDBQVDBfUDJYckl2NDNHVlpIcjhHWTJVbWVjcmhNZzR1ZDZhQlFxRm5m?oc=5" target="_blank">Rubbish balloons from North Korea land on presidential office compound in Seoul</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE9mQk1XdGFRTnBMTFk5VUI3ektqNHVsYk9sdkxsOUN4bllUSVItVkF6bUtYQkt6TzhmcGh6YlpLRmxFZ1ZUQzBocEFpWktteGVfcUdVZWdRZHBfdw?oc=5" target="_blank">N Korea's trash balloons land on S Korea presidential compound</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxQMzV5bXdrRC13MEdYb0lGcVd0SXJmRXJydTM0dS1mYXNfckRaR182OEZudUdYTXlNajBoRkJWYzJfYWplQ2NCRWZhQjJPQlhpNkVaZHJFSURmQ3Q2YlZDVE1oZzJ0VGRqY0pFNHpRNVRnS1lyQlJxVTNvcFRXTHlNYnJaVzR3d09pUGlDT2JBNG1IeU41MVYxTDFPbFNpRHRhZ09Z0gGoAUFVX3lxTFBXbVo4WGV4aDJlUEYxNUVtZk9VVTFCVXZJT1BlczZKcERreElkZkdnXzUyeWRmUkQydG1uUlRzLWNvVWY5VG1LQ1FlNXBDT0NVa3FmQlBVS1JpdUF2X0FoSV96eXRlRklQRFpXanRrdUxmSTd0dnZweHFvNGRJZXVXbzJsWHdsTldzdEhGV21hdHdhSkFGVHQ2VXhWeGVCWGdCR1lVVC10Xw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxQMzV5bXdrRC13MEdYb0lGcVd0SXJmRXJydTM0dS1mYXNfckRaR182OEZudUdYTXlNajBoRkJWYzJfYWplQ2NCRWZhQjJPQlhpNkVaZHJFSURmQ3Q2YlZDVE1oZzJ0VGRqY0pFNHpRNVRnS1lyQlJxVTNvcFRXTHlNYnJaVzR3d09pUGlDT2JBNG1IeU41MVYxTDFPbFNpRHRhZ09Z0gGoAUFVX3lxTFBXbVo4WGV4aDJlUEYxNUVtZk9VVTFCVXZJT1BlczZKcERreElkZkdnXzUyeWRmUkQydG1uUlRzLWNvVWY5VG1LQ1FlNXBDT0NVa3FmQlBVS1JpdUF2X0FoSV96eXRlRklQRFpXanRrdUxmSTd0dnZweHFvNGRJZXVXbzJsWHdsTldzdEhGV21hdHdhSkFGVHQ2VXhWeGVCWGdCR1lVVC10Xw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 15:16:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Netanyahu dismisses critics, scolds protesters in defiant speech to Congress]]></title><description><![CDATA[Evoking Israel’s sworn enemy Iran, Benjamin Netanyahu told Congress his nation’s campaign against Hamas in Gaza is part of a broader fight against “barbarism.”]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2024/07/24/benjamin-netanyahu-speech-congress-israel-gaza/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2024/07/24/benjamin-netanyahu-speech-congress-israel-gaza/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:39:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korean balloon drops trash on South Korean presidential office]]></title><description><![CDATA[The airborne garbage delivery was the latest, and perhaps most humiliating, episode in the ongoing trash-offensive. ]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/07/24/korea-trash-balloon-presidential-office/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/07/24/korea-trash-balloon-presidential-office/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:32:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk sits in Netanyahu's private box while Congress members boycott]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/111996980.cms" />Tesla CEO Elon Musk didn't only make a surprise appearance at the US Capitol when Israel PM Benjamin Netanyahu addressed the Congress but say in the PM's private box in the visitors' gallery above the House floor, alongside Netanyahu's wife Sara. He was there at the event as Netanyahu's guest -- while more than 30 members of the Congress boycotted the address amid widespread protest against Netanyahu.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-sits-in-netanyahus-private-box-while-congress-members-boycott/articleshow/111996980.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-sits-in-netanyahus-private-box-while-congress-members-boycott/articleshow/111996980.cms</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:44:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Salman Rushdie stabbing suspect indicted on federal terrorism counts]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Hadi Matar, 26, faces three new charges almost two years after writer was attacked on stage in Chautauqua, New York</p><p>The man accused of attacking and stabbing the author Salman Rushdie in 2022 in New York has been charged with new federal terrorism charges.</p><p>Hadi Matar, 26, was indicted by a grand jury on three counts including attempting to provide material to support a foreign terrorist organization, committing terrorism transcending national boundaries for the stabbing of Rushdie, and providing material to support terrorists, according to <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nywd.151724/gov.uscourts.nywd.151724.1.0.pdf">court documents</a>.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/article/2024/jul/24/salman-rushdie-attacker-terrorism-charges">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/article/2024/jul/24/salman-rushdie-attacker-terrorism-charges</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/books/article/2024/jul/24/salman-rushdie-attacker-terrorism-charges</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:03:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>