<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:55:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:55:49 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Why is everyone talking about Kamala Harris and coconut trees?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="WASHINGTON, DC - SEPTEMBER 30: U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris (R) laughs while listening to second gentleman Doug Emhoff during a reception to celebrate Rosh Hashanah, the Jewish New Year in the East Room of the White House on September 30, 2022 in Washington, DC. Rosh Hashanah began on September 25 and ended on September 27, 2022. (Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-1429079905.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>WASHINGTON, DC - SEPTEMBER 30: U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris (R) laughs while listening to second gentleman Doug Emhoff during a reception to celebrate Rosh Hashanah, the Jewish New Year in the East Room of the White House on September 30, 2022 in Washington, DC. Rosh Hashanah began on September 25 and ended on September 27, 2022. (Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It started with a coconut tree. Sorry — actually it starts with the context of what came before.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re an active internet denizen, you might already know what I’m referencing: a viral clip of Vice President Kamala Harris delivering a speech while repeating a question that she says her mother often posed to her: “‘You think you just fell out of a coconut tree?’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But if you’re fortunate enough not to live online, this is your guide to catching up on all the Kamala Harris memes. Many have been percolating for months (or even longer). Now, after <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024">Biden’s disastrous debate has prompted speculation</a> he’ll drop out of the race, the memes are everywhere.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The coconut line is more than a year old: from a swearing-in ceremony that Harris led in May 2023 in the Eisenhower Executive Office Building. But it’s also a stand-in for how the vice president is often perceived in pop culture, in mainstream media, and online: as a bit of a punchline, someone lacking serious power and with a perplexing political track record, and as the closest we’ll get to recreating Julia Louis-Dreyfus’s character in HBO’s <em>Veep.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Call it ironic or unironic #<a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/7/25/20697783/khive-twitter-kamala-harris-2020-candidate-doug-hive">KHive</a> posting, being “Kamalapilled” or “coconutpilled,” or simply feeling “unburdened” (I’ll get to that in a second).  The resurgence in Harris memes is a symptom of the angst and uncertainty many Americans are feeling as the country and the Democratic Party navigate yet another crisis.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, to guide you through this discourse, I’ve rounded up a few of the most popular memes, starting with the foundational one.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>“Coconut trees” and the context of what came before</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When the vice president referred to her mom’s question about falling out of a coconut tree, she was <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2JWR29RT5sw">recounting a lesson</a> about the importance of history. Speaking to government appointees who would work on economic and education equity for Hispanic Americans, she emphasized that their task would be to aid not only young people, but also their parents, grandparents, teachers, and communities, “because none of us just live in a silo. Everything is in context.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And she <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2023/05/10/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-swearing-in-ceremony-of-commissioners-for-the-white-house-initiative-on-advancing-educational-equity-excellence-and-economic-opportunity-for-hispanics/">continued</a>:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">“My mother used to — she would give us a hard time sometimes, and she would say to us, ‘I don’t know what’s wrong with you young people. You think you just fell out of a coconut tree?’ </p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">You exist in the context of all in which you live and what came before you.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, the takeaway is clear enough, something that’s been said for centuries: No person is an island.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it was her delivery that turned it into a meme: in a joking voice, with exaggerated hand and arm gestures, and with a signature Kamala Harris laugh.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the time, social media users and right-wing accounts <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/fell-out-of-a-coconut-tree">accused</a> her of behaving strangely: “Obviously drunk,” one <a href="https://x.com/Rifleman4WVU/status/1656441274906320896">viral tweet</a> said, while others used clips of the speech to describe being intoxicated or inebriated (which itself is another Harris meme).</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">“mr. gorbachev, tear down this coconut tree!” <a href="https://t.co/2ZvmfuUWL0">pic.twitter.com/2ZvmfuUWL0</a></p>&mdash; gregor samsung 𖢥 (@slimjosa) <a href="https://twitter.com/slimjosa/status/1808303666203697643?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Being “unburdened by what has been”</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Around the time of the most recent return of the coconut tree clip, another of Harris’s quotes began to circulate: not a memorable one-off, but a catchphrase she uses over and over.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was a <a href="https://x.com/KamalaHarris/status/1310607188566724610">go-to line</a> during her 2020 presidential primary campaign and into the general election as Biden’s running mate: “What can be, unburdened by what has been.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And thanks to a <a href="https://x.com/RNCResearch/status/1736468129528602811">Republican Party supercut</a> of all the times Harris has used the phrase in speeches, interviews, and appearances, the phrase went viral again. “Four straight minutes of ‘what can be, unburdened by what has been.’ It’s incredible. I had no idea she used it this much,” one Republican staffer <a href="https://x.com/thejcoop/status/1806867772988625316">said</a> as he reshared the clip in the aftermath of the first presidential debate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The literal meaning of this catchphrase varies from speech to speech, but it’s often used in the context of Harris’s trailblazing career, marking historic firsts as a woman of color in elected office and carrying the weight of history, or as a call to arms to dream bigger and leave the past behind.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a way, this quote contradicts Harris’s coconut tree line. As one <a href="https://x.com/Sturgeons_Law/status/1807513289330450566">X user</a> put it: “How are you supposed to exist in the context of all in which you live and what came before you AND be, unburdened by what has been at the same time? Waiting for her 3rd great revelation that synthesizes these two.”</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">How are you supposed to exist in the context of all in which you live and what came before you AND be, unburdened by what has been at the same time? Waiting for her 3rd great revelation that synthesizes these two. <a href="https://t.co/pDzyxaQdKk">https://t.co/pDzyxaQdKk</a></p>&mdash; Sturgeon&#039;s Law (@Sturgeons_Law) <a href="https://twitter.com/Sturgeons_Law/status/1807513289330450566?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The “significance of the passage of time”</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Speaking at an <a href="https://www.c-span.org/video/?518860-1/vice-president-harris-remarks-affordable-broadband-access">event in Louisiana</a> to announce millions of dollars in funding for broadband access, Harris referenced touring a library and reflected on historical inequities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We were talking about the significance of the passage of time, right? The significance of the passage of time. When you think about it, there is a great significance in the passage of time in terms of what we need to do to lay these wires.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She repeated the phrase a few more times, as noted in a clip widely <a href="https://x.com/EndWokeness/status/1808533077271990424">shared online</a>, and especially by right-wing users in the last few days.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The wheels on the bus </strong><strong><em>do</em></strong><strong> go round and round</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When seeing her campaign tour bus for the first time in 2019 during the Democratic presidential primaries, another video of Harris being a little awkward was shared on social media.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the camera pans 180 degrees around her, she walks across a lawn and onto the bus as she giggles and sings “the wheels on the bus go round and round,” slightly <a href="https://x.com/drmistercody/status/1808229682825122190">off-key</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The vice president does impressions</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More recently, clips of Harris showing another kind of less polished persona have also reappeared online: one from the ceremonial swearing-in of senators in January 2023, when <a href="https://x.com/_natemorris/status/1610652197968089088">Harris imitates</a> Colorado Sen. Michael Bennet’s deep booming voice, and another from 2019, when she <a href="https://x.com/GraduatedBen/status/1808276737005916267">imitates</a> her husband’s parents’ voices <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jtAPOKDV-nY">during an interview</a> at the 92<sup>nd</sup> Street Y in New York City.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Kamala does a great Jewish mother impression <a href="https://t.co/BmWTcRqrR9">pic.twitter.com/BmWTcRqrR9</a></p>&mdash; Dr. Ben Braddock (@GraduatedBen) <a href="https://twitter.com/GraduatedBen/status/1808276737005916267?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>There are plenty more</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You might remember other classic Harris deliveries — or you might be encountering them for the first time:&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/we-did-it-joe">“We did it, Joe.”</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://x.com/findareaction/status/1588718308060168193">“I love Venn diagrams.”</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://x.com/TheMemesArchive/status/1557191149424713728">“I love good news.”</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How she <a href="https://x.com/CapehartJ/status/1595526310335586305">seasons a turkey</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://x.com/SirajAHashmi/status/1794818668200608070">“Do not come.”</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s stint as vice president has often been pretty unremarkable, but it has provided a rich vein of memes, in part because she can be an awkward communicator.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s part of what fueled critical media coverage of her during the first year of her tenure, and which led the White House to largely sideline her during the first half of the Biden presidency.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other Kamala memes are rooted in the hokey nature of a lot of modern political speech: derived from aphorisms and pseudo-philosophical diction in the hope of echoing something like former President Barack Obama’s oratory.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the first female, Black, and South Asian vice president, Harris was always doomed to receive an extraordinary amount of scrutiny and bias — and emphasized her persona as a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iuEZcAgOQs0">“joyful warrior”</a> in part to combat some of those stereotypes. The joyful warrior, it seems, is sometimes a goofy one too. Harris delivers many of these lines in a genuinely funny way, with an affect unlike many politicians (described sometimes as just <a href="https://x.com/Chelsea_Fagan/status/1591478294444400640">vibing</a> along).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, all this talk about being KHive pilled, or coconutpilled<strong>,</strong> especially from people who were skeptical or critical of the vice president just a few weeks ago<strong> </strong>speaks to the uncertainty of this moment. Plenty of people are wondering whether Biden will still be the Democratic nominee by the end of the summer. They’re meme-ing their way to a new celebration of Harris — unburdened by what has been. </p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Paz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Middle East Crisis: Israeli Strike Kills Hezbollah Commander in Lebanon, Adding to Fears of Broader War]]></title><description><![CDATA[The strike, which was followed by a barrage of rockets from Hezbollah, came as a Biden adviser met with a French official to discuss the cross-border exchanges.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/07/03/world/israel-gaza-war-hamas</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/07/03/world/israel-gaza-war-hamas</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:11:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden has privately acknowledged next stretch of days are critical for whether he can save his reelection bid - CNN]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiU2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMy9wb2xpdGljcy9qb2UtYmlkZW4tMjAyNC1jYW1wYWlnbi10cm91Ymxlcy9pbmRleC5odG1s0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden has privately acknowledged next stretch of days are critical for whether he can save his reelection bid</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMDMvdXMvcG9saXRpY3MvYmlkZW4td2l0aGRyYXctZWxlY3Rpb24tZGViYXRlLmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden Tells Allies He Knows He Has Only Days to Salvage Candidacy</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vaG9tZW5ld3MvY2FtcGFpZ24vNDc1NDcwOS1iaWRlbi1mdW5kcmFpc2luZy1jYW1wYWlnbi1kZWJhdGUv0gFUaHR0cHM6Ly90aGVoaWxsLmNvbS9ob21lbmV3cy9jYW1wYWlnbi80NzU0NzA5LWJpZGVuLWZ1bmRyYWlzaW5nLWNhbXBhaWduLWRlYmF0ZS9hbXAv?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden in fundraising pitch: ‘No one is pushing me out’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiT2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vcG9saXRpY3MvbGl2ZS1uZXdzL2JpZGVuLXRydW1wLWVsZWN0aW9uLTA3LTAzLTI0L2luZGV4Lmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Live updates: Pressure mounts on Biden as some Dems question reelection chances</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiU2h0dHBzOi8vNmFiYy5jb20vcG9zdC9wcmVzaWRlbnQtam9lLWJpZGVuLW1lZXQtdnAta2FtYWxhLWhhcnJpcy1nb3Zlcm5vcnMvMTUwMjQ4OTkv0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">President Joe Biden to meet with VP Kamala Harris, Governors Gretchen Whitmer, Gavin Newsom, Any Beshear amid calls to dropout - 6abc Philadelphia</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">WPVI-TV</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiU2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMy9wb2xpdGljcy9qb2UtYmlkZW4tMjAyNC1jYW1wYWlnbi10cm91Ymxlcy9pbmRleC5odG1s0gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiU2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMy9wb2xpdGljcy9qb2UtYmlkZW4tMjAyNC1jYW1wYWlnbi10cm91Ymxlcy9pbmRleC5odG1s0gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 17:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UK election: Tories set to suffer total annihilation, final mega polls predict - POLITICO Europe]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmV1L2FydGljbGUvdWstZWxlY3Rpb24tZmluYWwtbWVnYS1wb2xscy1wcmVkaWN0LXRvdGFsLXRvcnktYW5uaWhpbGF0aW9uLWxhYm91ci13aW4v0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">UK election: Tories set to suffer total annihilation, final mega polls predict</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO Europe</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiLmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmJiYy5jb20vbmV3cy9hcnRpY2xlcy9jNzI1dzNwNDluNG_SAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">UK election is nearing its end - here's what you need to know</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnRoZWd1YXJkaWFuLmNvbS9wb2xpdGljcy92aWRlby8yMDI0L2p1bC8wMy91ay1nZW5lcmFsLWVsZWN0aW9uLXBhcnR5LWxlYWRlcnMtaG9sZC1maW5hbC1kYXktb2YtY2FtcGFpZ25pbmctdmlkZW_SAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">UK general election: party leaders hold final day of campaigning – video</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiS2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMy93b3JsZC92aWRlby91ay1lbGVjdGlvbi12b3RlcnMtc29hcmVzLWRpZ3ZpZNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Hear what issues matter most to these first-time voters in the UK</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiR2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5wci5vcmcvMjAyNC8wNy8wMy9ueC1zMS01MDI2NTgzL3VrLWVsZWN0aW9uLTIwMjQtZXhwbGFpbmVk0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">What to know about the U.K. election, with Labour forecast to knock out Conservatives</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmV1L2FydGljbGUvdWstZWxlY3Rpb24tZmluYWwtbWVnYS1wb2xscy1wcmVkaWN0LXRvdGFsLXRvcnktYW5uaWhpbGF0aW9uLWxhYm91ci13aW4v0gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmV1L2FydGljbGUvdWstZWxlY3Rpb24tZmluYWwtbWVnYS1wb2xscy1wcmVkaWN0LXRvdGFsLXRvcnktYW5uaWhpbGF0aW9uLWxhYm91ci13aW4v0gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:43:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Replace Biden & Beat Trump: Jim Zogby Proposes Process to Pick New Nominee - Democracy Now!]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmRlbW9jcmFjeW5vdy5vcmcvMjAyNC83LzMvamFtZXNfem9nYnlfMjAyNF9iaWRlbl9yZXBsYWNlbWVudF9vcHRpb25z0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">How to Replace Biden & Beat Trump: Jim Zogby Proposes Process to Pick New Nominee</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Democracy Now!</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMDMvdXMvcG9saXRpY3MvcmF1bC1ncmlqYWx2YS1iaWRlbi1kcm9wLW91dC5odG1s0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Raúl Grijalva Is Second House Democrat to Call for Biden to Drop Out</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMy9wb2xpdGljcy92aWRlby9iaWRlbi1oZWFsdGgtY2FuZGlkYWN5LXdoaXRlLWhvdXNlLXByZXNzLWJyaWVmaW5nLWthcmluZS1qZWFuLXBpZXJyZS1kaWd2aWTSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Reporters press White House press secretary about Biden’s candidacy and health</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmJsb29tYmVyZy5jb20vbmV3cy9hcnRpY2xlcy8yMDI0LTA3LTAzL2JpZGVuLWRlYmF0ZS1kaXNhc3Rlci13aWxsLWNvc3QtdGhlbS1ob3VzZS1hbmQtc2VuYXRlLWRlbW9jcmF0cy1mZWFy0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">House Democrats Consider Demanding Biden Withdraw From Race</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Bloomberg</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFodHRwczovL3d3dy5hYmMxNS5jb20vbmV3cy9wb2xpdGljYWwvZWxlY3Rpb25zL3JlcG9ydC1yZXAtZ3JpamFsdmEtc2Vjb25kLWRlbW9jcmF0LXRvLXB1c2gtZm9yLWJpZGVuLXRvLXdpdGhkcmF3LWZyb20tcHJlc2lkZW50aWFsLXJhY2XSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Report: Rep. Grijalva second Democrat to push for Biden to withdraw from presidential race</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC15 Arizona in Phoenix</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmRlbW9jcmFjeW5vdy5vcmcvMjAyNC83LzMvamFtZXNfem9nYnlfMjAyNF9iaWRlbl9yZXBsYWNlbWVudF9vcHRpb25z0gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmRlbW9jcmFjeW5vdy5vcmcvMjAyNC83LzMvamFtZXNfem9nYnlfMjAyNF9iaWRlbl9yZXBsYWNlbWVudF9vcHRpb25z0gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:42:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[White House weighing options to respond to Supreme Court presidential immunity ruling - MSNBC]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFodHRwczovL3d3dy5tc25iYy5jb20vam9zZS1kaWF6LWJhbGFydC93YXRjaC93aGl0ZS1ob3VzZS13ZWlnaGluZy1vcHRpb25zLXRvLXJlc3BvbmQtdG8tc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtaW1tdW5pdHktcnVsaW5nLTIxNDE1Nzg5MzU0M9IBNmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm1zbmJjLmNvbS9tc25iYy9hbXAtdmlkZW8vbW12bzIxNDE1Nzg5MzU0Mw?oc=5" target="_blank">White House weighing options to respond to Supreme Court presidential immunity ruling</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MSNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMi9wb2xpdGljcy9zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LXRlcm0tdHJ1bXAtZmF2b3IvaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">From unanimity to ‘fear mongering’: How the raucous Supreme Court term turned in Trump’s favor</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiX2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndhc2hpbmd0b25wb3N0LmNvbS9vcGluaW9ucy8yMDI0LzA3LzAzL2dhcmxhbmQtdHJ1bXAtcm9iZXJ0cy1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtaW1tdW5pdHkv0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Opinion | Don't like the Supreme Court's immunity ruling? Blame Merrick Garland.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFodHRwczovL3d3dy5mb3huZXdzLmNvbS9tZWRpYS9kZW1vY3JhdC1mbG9hdHMtdGhlb3J5LWJpZGVuLWNvdWxkLWRpc3BhdGNoLW1pbGl0YXJ5LXRha2Utb3V0LWNvbnNlcnZhdGl2ZS1qdXN0aWNlcy11bmRlci1pbW11bml0eS1ydWxpbmfSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Democrat floats theory Biden could dispatch military to 'take out' conservative justices under immunity ruling</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib2h0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL3RydW1wLWZhY3QtY2hlY2staW1tdW5pdHktc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1leG9uZXJhdGlvbi1mNWVlOGZmNzFkMjE1M2RhM2VmYmY3YmIwODE4ZDI0OdIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">FACT FOCUS: Trump wasn't exonerated by the presidential immunity ruling, even though he says he was</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFodHRwczovL3d3dy5tc25iYy5jb20vam9zZS1kaWF6LWJhbGFydC93YXRjaC93aGl0ZS1ob3VzZS13ZWlnaGluZy1vcHRpb25zLXRvLXJlc3BvbmQtdG8tc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtaW1tdW5pdHktcnVsaW5nLTIxNDE1Nzg5MzU0M9IBNmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm1zbmJjLmNvbS9tc25iYy9hbXAtdmlkZW8vbW12bzIxNDE1Nzg5MzU0Mw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFodHRwczovL3d3dy5tc25iYy5jb20vam9zZS1kaWF6LWJhbGFydC93YXRjaC93aGl0ZS1ob3VzZS13ZWlnaGluZy1vcHRpb25zLXRvLXJlc3BvbmQtdG8tc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1wcmVzaWRlbnRpYWwtaW1tdW5pdHktcnVsaW5nLTIxNDE1Nzg5MzU0M9IBNmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm1zbmJjLmNvbS9tc25iYy9hbXAtdmlkZW8vbW12bzIxNDE1Nzg5MzU0Mw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:40:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA['Everybody's in panic mode' as House Democrats scramble after debate - POLITICO]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmNvbS9uZXdzLzIwMjQvMDcvMDMvaG91c2UtZGVtb2NyYXRzLWJpZGVuLWRlYmF0ZS0wMDE2NjUzM9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">'Everybody's in panic mode' as House Democrats scramble after debate</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMy9wb2xpdGljcy9ob3VzZS1kZW1vY3JhdHMtY2hhb3Mtd2l0aGluLWNhdWN1cy1iaWRlbi1jb25jZXJucy9pbmRleC5odG1s0gFeaHR0cHM6Ly9hbXAuY25uLmNvbS9jbm4vMjAyNC8wNy8wMy9wb2xpdGljcy9ob3VzZS1kZW1vY3JhdHMtY2hhb3Mtd2l0aGluLWNhdWN1cy1iaWRlbi1jb25jZXJucw?oc=5" target="_blank">Three House Democrats describe chaos within caucus as party navigates Biden concerns</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFodHRwczovL3d3dy5tc25iYy5jb20vY2hyaXMtamFuc2luZy1yZXBvcnRzL3dhdGNoL2JpZGVuLXNwZWFrcy13aXRoLXNjaHVtZXItcGVsb3NpLWFuZC1jbHlidXJuLWFmdGVyLWRlYmF0ZS1mYWxsb3V0LTIxNDE2MzAxMzgwM9IBNmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm1zbmJjLmNvbS9tc25iYy9hbXAtdmlkZW8vbW12bzIxNDE2MzAxMzgwMw?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden speaks with Schumer, Pelosi and Clyburn after debate fallout</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MSNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiQ2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmF4aW9zLmNvbS8yMDI0LzA3LzAyL2hvdXNlLWRlbW9jcmF0cy1iaWRlbi12ZW50LXNlc3Npb27SAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Scoop: Biden was the "donkey in the room" at House Democrats' vent session</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Axios</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnJldXRlcnMuY29tL3dvcmxkL3VzL2JpZGVuLXJlYXNzdXJlLWdvdmVybm9ycy1kZW1vY3JhdGljLWtpbmdtYWtlci1mbG9hdHMtbWluaS1wcmltYXJ5LWlmLWhlLWxlYXZlcy0yMDI0LTA3LTAzL9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">'I am running' Biden says, as he scrambles to reassure Democrats, campaign staff</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters.com</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmNvbS9uZXdzLzIwMjQvMDcvMDMvaG91c2UtZGVtb2NyYXRzLWJpZGVuLWRlYmF0ZS0wMDE2NjUzM9IBAA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmNvbS9uZXdzLzIwMjQvMDcvMDMvaG91c2UtZGVtb2NyYXRzLWJpZGVuLWRlYmF0ZS0wMDE2NjUzM9IBAA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 20:46:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hezbollah launches barrage of rockets at Israel after top commander killed - Al Jazeera English]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmFsamF6ZWVyYS5jb20vbmV3cy8yMDI0LzcvMy9oZXpib2xsYWgtbGF1bmNoZXMtYmFycmFnZS1vZi1yb2NrZXRzLWF0LWlzcmFlbC1hZnRlci10b3AtY29tbWFuZGVyLWtpbGxlZNIBdmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmFsamF6ZWVyYS5jb20vYW1wL25ld3MvMjAyNC83LzMvaGV6Ym9sbGFoLWxhdW5jaGVzLWJhcnJhZ2Utb2Ytcm9ja2V0cy1hdC1pc3JhZWwtYWZ0ZXItdG9wLWNvbW1hbmRlci1raWxsZWQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Hezbollah launches barrage of rockets at Israel after top commander killed</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Al Jazeera English</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiamh0dHBzOi8vYWJjbmV3cy5nby5jb20vSW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC9pc3JhZWwtcHJlcGFyZXMtd2FyLWhlemJvbGxhaC1oYW1hcy1jb25mbGljdC1kcmFncy9zdG9yeT9pZD0xMTE2MDY2NDPSAW5odHRwczovL2FiY25ld3MuZ28uY29tL2FtcC9JbnRlcm5hdGlvbmFsL2lzcmFlbC1wcmVwYXJlcy13YXItaGV6Ym9sbGFoLWhhbWFzLWNvbmZsaWN0LWRyYWdzL3N0b3J5P2lkPTExMTYwNjY0Mw?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel prepares for possible war with Hezbollah as Hamas conflict drags on</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiNGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnRpbWVzb2Zpc3JhZWwuY29tL2xpdmVibG9nLWp1bHktMDMtMjAyNC_SAThodHRwczovL3d3dy50aW1lc29maXNyYWVsLmNvbS9saXZlYmxvZy1qdWx5LTAzLTIwMjQvYW1wLw?oc=5" target="_blank">Hamas submits updated ceasefire proposal after last offer was dismissed by US, Israel</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of Israel</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiMmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lmpwb3N0LmNvbS9icmVha2luZy1uZXdzL2FydGljbGUtODA4ODc50gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">IAF attacks three Hezbollah rocket launchers in southern Lebanon</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Jerusalem Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiX2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmR3LmNvbS9lbi9taWRkbGUtZWFzdC11cGRhdGVzLWlzcmFlbC1zdHJpa2Uta2lsbHMtaGV6Ym9sbGFoLWNvbW1hbmRlci9saXZlLTY5NTQ0Mzcw0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Middle East updates: Israel strike kills Hezbollah commander – DW – 07/03/2024</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">DW (English)</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmFsamF6ZWVyYS5jb20vbmV3cy8yMDI0LzcvMy9oZXpib2xsYWgtbGF1bmNoZXMtYmFycmFnZS1vZi1yb2NrZXRzLWF0LWlzcmFlbC1hZnRlci10b3AtY29tbWFuZGVyLWtpbGxlZNIBdmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmFsamF6ZWVyYS5jb20vYW1wL25ld3MvMjAyNC83LzMvaGV6Ym9sbGFoLWxhdW5jaGVzLWJhcnJhZ2Utb2Ytcm9ja2V0cy1hdC1pc3JhZWwtYWZ0ZXItdG9wLWNvbW1hbmRlci1raWxsZWQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmFsamF6ZWVyYS5jb20vbmV3cy8yMDI0LzcvMy9oZXpib2xsYWgtbGF1bmNoZXMtYmFycmFnZS1vZi1yb2NrZXRzLWF0LWlzcmFlbC1hZnRlci10b3AtY29tbWFuZGVyLWtpbGxlZNIBdmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmFsamF6ZWVyYS5jb20vYW1wL25ld3MvMjAyNC83LzMvaGV6Ym9sbGFoLWxhdW5jaGVzLWJhcnJhZ2Utb2Ytcm9ja2V0cy1hdC1pc3JhZWwtYWZ0ZXItdG9wLWNvbW1hbmRlci1raWxsZWQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 20:19:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore prepared to recognise a Palestinian state with an effective govt that accepts Israel's right to exist.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1dun7a1/singapore_prepared_to_recognise_a_palestinian/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/RPYO_z_C1o1M1CaVu_YqW9tx-y4I3dEeemqXolukUEc.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=1552035765f43f6cc05611deb5beb1399672cd86" alt="Singapore prepared to recognise a Palestinian state with an effective govt that accepts Israel's right to exist." title="Singapore prepared to recognise a Palestinian state with an effective govt that accepts Israel's right to exist." /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Marciu73"> /u/Marciu73 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.channelnewsasia.com/singapore/palestine-israel-singapore-prepared-principle-recognise-state-reject-terrorism-4450696">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1dun7a1/singapore_prepared_to_recognise_a_palestinian/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1dun7a1/singapore_prepared_to_recognise_a_palestinian/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1dun7a1/singapore_prepared_to_recognise_a_palestinian/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Marciu73]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 19:38:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[About 90% of people in Gaza displaced since war began, says UN agency]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Many have moved more than once, with estimated 1.9m Palestinians relocating since Israel’s invasion, says OCHA</p><p>About 90% of the population of the Gaza Strip have been displaced at least once since the war between Israel and Hamas began, according to the UN’s humanitarian agency.</p><p>Andrea De Domenico, head of the UN’s OCHA agency in the Palestinian territories, said on Wednesday that about 1.9 million people are thought to be displaced in Gaza.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/jul/03/about-90-of-people-in-gaza-displaced-since-war-began-says-un-agency">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/jul/03/about-90-of-people-in-gaza-displaced-since-war-began-says-un-agency</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/jul/03/about-90-of-people-in-gaza-displaced-since-war-began-says-un-agency</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:14:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[General election live: Sunak says he will take full responsibility for election result after Tory minister predicts Labour landslide – as it happened]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Rishi Sunak rejects Mel Stride’s claim Labour are likely to win a large majority</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/article/2024/may/23/sign-up-for-the-uk-general-election-2024-newsletter">Sign up to our Election Edition daily newsletter</a></li><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/ng-interactive/2024/jun/03/what-constituency-am-i-in-map-uk-general-election-2024-boundary-changes-votes-postcode">What constituency am I in? New boundary map</a><br></li></ul><p>It has just gone 7am: let’s look at today’s stop stories. With 24 hours to go until polls open, the <strong>Guardian</strong> leads with Keir Starmer accusing the Conservatives of desperate tactics amid claims that Tory criticism of <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/article/2024/jul/02/jewish-figures-criticise-stigmatising-tory-attack-on-starmer-family-time">his defence of family time was insensitive and had antisemitic undertones</a>.</p><p>The <strong>Times</strong> has Boris Johnson saying a Labour landslide would be “pregnant with horrors”:</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/jul/03/uk-general-election-2024-live-updates-tories-labour-polls-boris-johnson">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/jul/03/uk-general-election-2024-live-updates-tories-labour-polls-boris-johnson</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/jul/03/uk-general-election-2024-live-updates-tories-labour-polls-boris-johnson</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:13:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[White House efforts to shield Biden’s missteps are unraveling]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reducing press conferences, interviews and meetings with Congress members exposed as damage control measures</p><p>For three and a half years, Joe Biden was wrapped in a metaphorical ball of cotton wool by an anxious White House staff eager to protect him from the worst of himself.</p><p>Worried about signs of ageing and an increasing propensity for verbal missteps, they cut press conferences and media interviews to a minimum.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/03/biden-white-house-missteps">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/03/biden-white-house-missteps</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/03/biden-white-house-missteps</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:27:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mark Cuban Asked ChatGPT Whether It Would Hire Trump Or Biden For A 'Job' Based Solely On The Debate Transcript — Here's Who It Chose]]></title><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/mark-cuban-asked-chatgpt-whether-155504071.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://finance.yahoo.com/news/mark-cuban-asked-chatgpt-whether-155504071.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 15:55:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Turkey's Erdogan offers to help end Russia-Ukraine war; Kremlin rules him out as intermediary]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/turkeys-erdogan-offers-help-end-195045843.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/turkeys-erdogan-offers-help-end-195045843.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 19:50:45 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>