<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:25:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:25:38 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[How white victimhood is shaping a second Trump term]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="RACINE, WISCONSIN - JUNE 18: Republican presidential candidate former President Donald Trump speaks during a rally at Festival Park on June 18, 2024 in Racine, Wisconsin. This is Trump&#039;s third visit to Wisconsin, a key swing state in 2024. (Photo by Scott Olson/Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-2158175261.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>RACINE, WISCONSIN - JUNE 18: Republican presidential candidate former President Donald Trump speaks during a rally at Festival Park on June 18, 2024 in Racine, Wisconsin. This is Trump&#039;s third visit to Wisconsin, a key swing state in 2024. (Photo by Scott Olson/Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Republican party is going in two directions on race&nbsp;at the same time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Electorally speaking, the modern GOP has never been so diverse. Each of the past two elections, and most available 2024 polling, reveals the GOP making real inroads with Black and (especially) Latino voters. These gains <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/23982907/trump-democrats-republicans-working-class-voters-latino-black-voters">shouldn’t be overstated</a> —&nbsp;Democrats still dominate among non-whites as a whole — but they are real.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But at the elite level, conservative intellectuals and operatives are developing a new doctrine of white identity politics. And it’s already shaping the Trump administration’s plans for a second term.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A new book on “anti-white racism” — <em>The Unprotected Class</em>, by Claremont Institute fellow Jeremy Carl — illustrates this trend clearly. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Its April release went unheralded outside conservative circles, but it received laudatory attention inside them. Tucker Carlson praised it as “outstanding”; leading activist <a href="https://www.vox.com/23811277/christopher-rufo-culture-wars-ron-desantis-florida-critical-race-theory-anti-wokeness">Chris Rufo</a> described it as a “must-read.” Nate Hochman, a former speechwriter for Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis, called it “<a href="https://x.com/njhochman/status/1773026164765872213">the most important thing you read this year</a>.” Carl got friendly interviews on <a href="https://x.com/realJeremyCarl/status/1793780627201782177">Donald Trump Jr.’s web show</a> and on <a href="https://x.com/realJeremyCarl/status/1794074114312806660">Fox News during primetime</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Carl’s book centers on the claim that “anti-white racism is the most predominant and politically powerful form of racism in America today.” What mainstream scholars of race call “white privilege” is, in his view, a series of “informal evanescent cultural legacies.” By contrast, anti-white discrimination “is increasingly legal and formal.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This discrimination is, for Carl, primarily the product of a pernicious ideology popular among elites (nonwhite and white alike). “Anti-white racism is the all-but-official ideology of our ruling regime,” he writes —&nbsp;and they have acted in such a way as to ensure that whites are increasingly shunted to the bottom of America’s social hierarchy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Carl’s arguments for this view resemble a funhouse mirror version of American racial history: roughly the same series of events, but with the roles of victim and perpetrator reversed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Everyone agrees, for example, that the integration of America’s cities led white people to move to suburbs and other outlying areas. Traditionally, <a href="https://press.princeton.edu/books/paperback/9780691133867/white-flight">historians</a> and <a href="https://cepr.org/voxeu/columns/why-us-cities-are-segregated-race-new-evidence-role-white-flight">social scientists</a> see this as a manifestation of white racism: either white urbanites worried about the effects of integration on property values or they simply disliked living near Black people. The flight of white wealth then deprived Black people and neighborhoods of high-quality public services, recreating the inequalities of de jure segregation on a de facto basis.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Carl argues that white flight can more accurately be described as a reaction to anti-white racism. He claims that integration brings crime, often involving minority perpetrators targeting longtime white residents (Carl sources data on “interracial murder” to the anonymous Twitter account @fentasyl). The situation for whites is so perilous, Carl argues, that it’s akin to state-sanctioned mob assaults on Jews in czarist Russia.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Anti-white crime functions as a twenty-first-century <em>de facto</em> pogrom, driving whites out of areas where they have lived for decades,” he writes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Carl’s version of white identity politics is hardly isolated on the intellectual right. He cites two other prominent book, by <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Age-Entitlement-America-Since-Sixties/dp/1501106899">New York Times contributor Christopher Caldwell</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Origins-Woke-Corporate-Identity-Politics/dp/0063237210/ref=pd_bxgy_d_sccl_2/133-8685539-4311037?pd_rd_w=tvrkS&amp;content-id=amzn1.sym.d09bc3f2-0166-4869-be1b-350c42c0f80c&amp;pf_rd_p=d09bc3f2-0166-4869-be1b-350c42c0f80c&amp;pf_rd_r=X3Z9GHD990895R7011R0&amp;pd_rd_wg=XjAKK&amp;pd_rd_r=645481f5-5e00-405f-ab81-7d8858bf46b7&amp;pd_rd_i=0063237210&amp;psc=1">think tanker Richard Hanania</a>, to argue that the legal roots of anti-white racism were created by the legislative victories of the civil rights movement. Their accounts align on the idea that the basic structure of anti-discrimination protections —&nbsp;including the Civil Rights Act of 1965 —&nbsp;needs to be overhauled or repealed entirely.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, conservatives have complained about “reverse racism” for decades. What’s new is not just the aggressiveness of Carl’s claims and others like them, but their direct connection to radical policy proposals — and the fact that people in positions of power appear to be listening.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In April, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/04/01/trump-reverse-racism-civil-rights">Axios’s Alex Thompson reported</a> that “close Trump allies” are planning a second-term overhaul of anti-discrimination law, one that would “dramatically change the government&#8217;s interpretation of Civil Rights-era laws to focus on ‘anti-white racism’ rather than discrimination against people of color.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Much of this work, per Thompson, is coming out of America First Legal — the law practice of infamous Trump aide Stephen Miller. Since leaving government, Miller has filed a number of lawsuits alleging anti-white discrimination. Examples include <a href="https://aflegal.org/america-first-legal-blasts-the-nfls-illegal-and-racist-rooney-rule-files-federal-civil-rights-complaint/">a suit against the NFL’s “Rooney Rule</a>,” which requires teams to interview a minority candidate for some high-level coaching positions, as well as a successful bid to block pandemic assistance <a href="https://thehill.com/regulation/554361-federal-judge-says-biden-restaurant-fund-discriminated-against-white-male/">for women-and-minority-owned restaurants</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Miller is poised to play an important role in a second Trump administration. Ty Cobb, Trump’s former attorney, told <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/dec/08/trump-second-term-lawyers-stephen-miller">the Guardian</a> that “Trump is looking to Miller” when it comes to choosing his White House lawyers and Justice Department officials. With that kind of power, Miller’s quest to write white identity politics into law could well start succeeding next year.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/357963/republicans-white-identity-politics-newsletter</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/357963/republicans-white-identity-politics-newsletter</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Beauchamp]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:21:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Supreme Court leaves Illinois assault weapons ban in place as it sidesteps new cases on the right to bear arms - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQvc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1pbGxpbm9pcy1hc3NhdWx0LXdlYXBvbnMtYmFuLXJpZ2h0LXRvLWJlYXItYXJtcy1yY25hMTUzOTcx0gEraHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmJjbmV3cy5jb20vbmV3cy9hbXAvcmNuYTE1Mzk3MQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court leaves Illinois assault weapons ban in place as it sidesteps new cases on the right to bear arms</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8wMi9wb2xpdGljcy9ndW5zLWZlbG9ucy1hYnVzZXJzLWlsbGlub2lzLXN1cHJlbWUtY291cnQvaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBVmh0dHBzOi8vYW1wLmNubi5jb20vY25uLzIwMjQvMDcvMDIvcG9saXRpY3MvZ3Vucy1mZWxvbnMtYWJ1c2Vycy1pbGxpbm9pcy1zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court declines to hear a series of challenges to laws barring felons and drug users from having guns</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnRoZWNlbnRlcnNxdWFyZS5jb20vaWxsaW5vaXMvYXJ0aWNsZV8yZGI4MjA2OC0zODdjLTExZWYtYWQ3OC04ZmE0M2FhZWE3MTcuaHRtbNIBXmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnRoZWNlbnRlcnNxdWFyZS5jb20vaWxsaW5vaXMvYXJ0aWNsZV8yZGI4MjA2OC0zODdjLTExZWYtYWQ3OC04ZmE0M2FhZWE3MTcuYW1wLmh0bWw?oc=5" target="_blank">BREAKING: SCOTUS denies Illinois' gun ban challenge as not ready yet</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Center Square</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiYGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmxhdGltZXMuY29tL3dvcmxkLW5hdGlvbi9zdG9yeS8yMDI0LTA3LTAyL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtMm5kLWFtZW5kbWVudC1hc3NhdWx0LXJpZmxlc9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court turns down a 2nd Amendment challenge to state bans on assault weapons</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Los Angeles Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVGh0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vcmVndWxhdGlvbi9jb3VydC1iYXR0bGVzLzQ3NTE1MjMtc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1pbGxpbm9pcy1ndW4tYmFuL9IBWGh0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vcmVndWxhdGlvbi9jb3VydC1iYXR0bGVzLzQ3NTE1MjMtc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1pbGxpbm9pcy1ndW4tYmFuL2FtcC8?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court won’t review Illinois ban on certain semiautomatic guns</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQvc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1pbGxpbm9pcy1hc3NhdWx0LXdlYXBvbnMtYmFuLXJpZ2h0LXRvLWJlYXItYXJtcy1yY25hMTUzOTcx0gEraHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmJjbmV3cy5jb20vbmV3cy9hbXAvcmNuYTE1Mzk3MQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm5iY25ld3MuY29tL3BvbGl0aWNzL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQvc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1pbGxpbm9pcy1hc3NhdWx0LXdlYXBvbnMtYmFuLXJpZ2h0LXRvLWJlYXItYXJtcy1yY25hMTUzOTcx0gEraHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmJjbmV3cy5jb20vbmV3cy9hbXAvcmNuYTE1Mzk3MQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 14:37:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Former dissenting Labor MP backs Fatima Payman and says party needs to reconsider rules]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Last time a Labor MP voted against the party position was 2005 when Tasmanian MP Harry Quick opposed anti-terrorism legislation</p><ul><li>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl">morning and afternoon news emails</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></li></ul><p>The last federal Labor MP to vote against his party has urged Fatima Payman to “stick to her guns” as the senator faces intense pressure to toe the line on Palestinian statehood or leave Labor.</p><p>Federal Labor MPs and senators on Tuesday unanimously endorsed Payman’s indefinite suspension from the party’s parliamentary caucus after the 29-year-old said she would cross the floor again if faced with a similar Senate motion to last week’s vote.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed">Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup</a></strong></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/02/former-dissenting-labor-mp-backs-fatima-payman-and-says-party-needs-to-reconsider-rules">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/02/former-dissenting-labor-mp-backs-fatima-payman-and-says-party-needs-to-reconsider-rules</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/02/former-dissenting-labor-mp-backs-fatima-payman-and-says-party-needs-to-reconsider-rules</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:04:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Older Australians pressured into paying unfair robotax debts will not be compensated, government says]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Finance minister Katy Gallagher says people who felt intimidated into paying back ATO debts so old they are impossible to verify will not get their money back</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2024/jul/02/australia-politics-live-health-bulk-billing-medicare-labor-caucus-fatima-payman-coalition-wes-fang-mark-speakman-energy-economy-cost-of-living">Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates</a></li><li>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl">morning and afternoon news emails</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></li></ul><p>Older Australians who felt pressured into paying decades-old debts as part of the troubled “robotax” campaign have hit out at a government decision to deny refunds after describing the tax grab as coercive.</p><p>The federal government has disclosed it intends to amend laws that will allow the Australian Taxation Office to keep debts put on hold before 2017 <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/may/14/australia-federal-budget-2024-robotax-details-ato-savings-wages-households-inflation">on ice indefinitely</a>, rather than extract them from future tax refunds, as was planned.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed">Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup</a></strong></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/03/elderly-australians-robotax-debts-not-compensated-ato">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/03/elderly-australians-robotax-debts-not-compensated-ato</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/03/elderly-australians-robotax-debts-not-compensated-ato</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:00:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A third of land set aside for restoration in worse state than before, Australian offset audit finds]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Federal review sparks fresh warnings that biodiversity scheme is increasing risk of animals going extinct</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2024/jul/02/australia-politics-live-health-bulk-billing-medicare-labor-caucus-fatima-payman-coalition-wes-fang-mark-speakman-energy-economy-cost-of-living">Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates</a></li><li>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl">morning and afternoon news emails</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></li></ul><p>A review of some of the areas chosen for nature restoration as part of Australia’s biodiversity offset system has found a third are in worse condition than before, prompting fresh warnings that the scheme is increasing the risk of animals going extinct.</p><p>In one instance, the majority of a site that should have provided grey-headed flying fox and koala habitat was found to be “cleared paddock with negligible foraging value”.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed">Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup</a></strong></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/03/australia-biodiversity-offset-system-land-restoration">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/03/australia-biodiversity-offset-system-land-restoration</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/03/australia-biodiversity-offset-system-land-restoration</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:00:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mass purge of frozen sperm donations ordered as Queensland audit exposes misidentification risk]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Health ombudsman says ‘thousands’ of sperm samples at fertility clinics are at risk of potentially devastating identification mix-ups</p><ul><li>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl">morning and afternoon news emails</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></li></ul><p>Queensland’s health ombudsman has ordered the destruction of thousands of frozen <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/sperm-donation">sperm donations</a>, as a new report reveals 42% of all audited samples in the state were of medium or high risk of being misidentified.</p><p>The state had more than twice as many potential errors identified in audits as the next worst state, Victoria.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed">Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup</a></strong></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/03/mass-purge-of-frozen-sperm-donations-ordered-as-queensland-audit-exposes-misidentification-risk">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/03/mass-purge-of-frozen-sperm-donations-ordered-as-queensland-audit-exposes-misidentification-risk</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/jul/03/mass-purge-of-frozen-sperm-donations-ordered-as-queensland-audit-exposes-misidentification-risk</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:00:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Post Office: next government urged to consider transferring ownership to operators]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Questions over future of state-owned business after victims of Horizon IT scandal receive compensation</p><p>Britain’s next government has been urged to set up a taskforce to explore the future for the state-owned Post Office including mutualisation – once victims of the Horizon IT scandal have been financially compensated.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/post-office-horizon-scandal">Post Office Horizon IT scandal</a> has been described by MPs as one of the biggest miscarriages of justice in recent years and was highlighted by the recent ITV drama <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2024/jan/01/mr-bates-vs-the-post-office-review-toby-jones-is-perfect-in-a-devastating-tale-of-a-national-scandal">Mr Bates vs the Post Office</a>.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/article/2024/jul/02/post-office-government-operators-horizon-it-scandal">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/article/2024/jul/02/post-office-government-operators-horizon-it-scandal</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/business/article/2024/jul/02/post-office-government-operators-horizon-it-scandal</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 15:00:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Defense Secretary Austin says the US will provide $2.3 billion more in military aid to Ukraine]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/us-defense-chief-austin-says-143642682.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/us-defense-chief-austin-says-143642682.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 14:36:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA['Very Bad News' For Trump: Lawrence O'Donnell Says Ruling Could Backfire Quickly]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/very-bad-news-trump-lawrence-050034007.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/very-bad-news-trump-lawrence-050034007.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 05:00:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roblox and the BBC have teamed up for UK election coverage]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ahead of the UK's General Election on July 4, the BBC is bringing Larry the Downing Street cat to Roblox.]]></description><link>https://mashable.com/article/roblox-bbc-uk-election-july-4-larry-downing-street-cat</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mashable.com/article/roblox-bbc-uk-election-july-4-larry-downing-street-cat</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 14:51:48 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>