<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:10:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:10:58 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[The winners and losers of the Biden economy]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Stacks of coins at various heights with red downward and upward trend lines." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Joan Wong, Paige Vickers/Vox; Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/FactsOnTheGround_Economy.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden’s economic record is a bit like a certain orange-hued ex-president: It’s perpetually on trial.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For years, politicians and commentators have been arguing over the merits of the Biden-era economy. And the question of whether Americans have prospered under the president’s watch is certain to feature prominently in his Thursday night debate with Donald Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The answer to that question, though, may ultimately hinge on which Americans we’re talking about. Any set of economic policies and developments will inevitably impact different sectors, workers, and regions differently. Some Americans are indisputably better off today than they were in January 2021. Others are not.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Specifically, the real winners of the Biden economy have been 24-year-old student debtors who lost their jobs during the pandemic and now work in hospitality, own a house in Tampa Bay, Florida, live in Minneapolis, have savings in an S&amp;P 500 index fund, lease an electric vehicle, and hate fast food. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is not to say that only people who fit that elaborate description have prospered since January 2021. But the closer an American comes to possessing that odd assortment of characteristics, the more likely they are to have benefited from virtually all of the Biden era’s major economic changes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To see why this is the case, consider seven ways that the US economy has changed under Biden.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">1) <strong>Unemployment rapidly fell</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When Joe Biden took office, America’s unemployment rate sat at 6.4 percent. By the end of his first year in the White House, it had fallen to 3.9 percent, roughly equal to its pre-pandemic level.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The pace of this labor market recovery was extraordinary. After the Great Recession of the late aughts, unemployment didn’t return to its pre-crisis level for more than nine years. After the Covid recession, unemployment returned to its pre-pandemic mark in just two.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like most features of the Biden-era economy, the president cannot claim full responsibility for this development. In 2020, the Trump administration and the House’s Democratic leadership united behind <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2020/7/7/21308450/extra-600-unemployment-stimulus-expiring-cares-act">historically robust relief spending</a> that laid the foundation for a swift recovery.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Biden’s policies accelerated job growth. And this was no accident. The White House chose to prioritize rapidly restoring full employment over minimizing the risk of inflation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To appreciate how big a premium Biden put on a speedy labor market recovery, consider the state of the economy in early 2021. By the time his American Rescue Plan was drafted, US households <a href="https://www.barrons.com/articles/u-s-households-net-worth-hit-130-trillion-in-2020-51615543202">were already $12 trillion wealthier</a> than they had been before the pandemic, and boasted <a href="https://www.barrons.com/articles/americans-are-sitting-on-a-lot-of-spare-cash-it-may-not-boost-growth-as-much-as-youd-think-51614366901">more disposable income</a> and less debt than they did at the peak of the Trump-era expansion. Unemployment was already recovering at a healthy pace.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Facts on the Ground</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">This is part of Vox’s series exploring the realities of American life and policy as the presidential campaign ramps up. Read more:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/explainers/356314/abortion-laws-roe-wade-dobbs-decision-mifepristone-supreme-court">What two years without Roe looks like, in 8 charts</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/356761/bidens-border-record-trumps-claims-vs-reality">Biden’s border record: Trump’s claims vs. reality</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/356269/falling-crime-trends-public-perception-voter-concerns">Why do Americans always think crime is going up?</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The administration could have looked at this state of affairs and concluded that only a modest additional Covid relief bill was warranted. After all, the unemployment rate was 2 full points lower in March 2021 than it had been in February 2009, when President Barack Obama and congressional Democrats authorized only $787 billion of stimulus spending.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, Biden proposed a <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2021/3/10/22320350/biden-sign-stimulus-bill-covid-19">$1.9 trillion relief bill</a>, including $1,400 checks for most Americans, enhanced unemployment benefits, and a <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/8/30/23317834/child-tax-credit-ctc-ira">temporary child allowance</a> for most families, among myriad other economically stimulative measures. This injection of cash into Americans’ bank accounts boosted consumer spending and, thus, job growth.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is impossible to know exactly how much that legislation contributed to Biden-era inflation. In hindsight, it’s clear that the economy’s reopening was all but certain to trigger an inflationary surge, no matter what Biden did in office. After all, developed countries the world over witnessed historically large bursts of inflation in 2021 and 2022, despite enacting significantly less fiscal stimulus than the United States.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless, America bought itself considerable economic benefits with all that relief spending. The Biden-era US did not suffer significantly higher inflation than the European Union, but it did enjoy a <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/7240265e-0157-428b-9c47-fb07c360dfc2">much stronger rate of economic growth</a>. As Martin Sanbu noted in Financial Times, in 2023, the US economy was only 1 to 2 percent smaller than it would have been had its pre-pandemic economic trajectory continued uninterrupted; the European economy, by contrast, finished the year 5 percent below its pre-pandemic trend. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This said, it’s undoubtedly true that Biden’s fiscal policy centered the interests of the unemployed, at the cost of somewhat higher inflation.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">2) <strong>Real wages rose sharply for young workers, especially in low-wage sectors</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The question of whether American workers as a whole are better off now than they were when Biden took office is a complicated one. By conventional measures, <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LES1252881600Q">real weekly earnings</a> — which is to say, earnings after inflation is taken into account — are about 2 percent lower today than they were when Biden took office.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But that figure is misleading. The Labor Department’s wage data measures median pay among Americans who have jobs at a given moment in time. For this reason, changes in the composition of the labor force can raise or lower “real weekly earnings,” even if no single worker in the economy has actually received a raise or pay cut. For example, if companies throughout the economy lay off a bunch of their lowest-paid workers, then real wages will rise, even if pay for all remaining employees remains the same.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And something roughly like this happens in every recession: Low-wage workers are the first to be fired and last to be rehired. Thus, real weekly earnings skyrocketed at the start of the pandemic, even though very few employers were actually increasing worker pay in the middle of a recession. Conversely, as low-wage workers regained their jobs during Biden’s first year in office, real weekly earnings appeared to fall — even before inflation took off — merely because the composition of the workforce was changing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A better measure of wage trends comes from the Atlanta Federal Reserve. The central bank <a href="https://www.atlantafed.org/chcs/wage-growth-tracker?panel=2">tracks the wages</a> of the same individual US workers over time. And as the labor economist Aaron Sojourner has shown, the Atlanta Fed’s data <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/aaronsojourner.org/post/3kl6dqnvcph2w">suggests</a> that average hourly wages have grown by more than consumer prices since Biden took office.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, no measure of real wages is perfect. And once the impact of interest rates is taken into account, the picture can get a bit murky.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But such ambiguity disappears for certain subsets of the labor force. For example, American workers under 25 have <a href="https://www.atlantafed.org/chcs/wage-growth-tracker">seen their wages soar</a> during the Biden era. Wages for US workers between the ages of 16 and 24 were growing at a 7.3 percent rate in January 2021, according to the Atlanta Fed. By October 2022, young workers’ wages were rising at a 13 percent clip, and were still advancing by an 8.6 percent rate in March of this year. In other words, throughout the Biden presidency, young workers’ wages have grown much faster than prices. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, workers in the bottom 25 percent of America’s income distribution have seen much stronger wage growth than higher earners, according to the Atlanta Fed’s data. And this trend is also reflected in data on wages in America’s leisure and hospitality industry, the nation’s lowest-paid sector. Even using the <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/CES7000000003">Labor Department’s data</a> (which likely underestimates wage growth due to the compositional issues mentioned above), pay for hospitality workers has far outpaced inflation during Biden’s time in office.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By contrast, workers in the top quarter of America’s income distribution, and those over age 55, have seen exceptionally slow rates of income growth in the Biden era. Taken together, these trends translate into a steep reduction in pay inequality.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">3) <strong>Homeowners prospered (at renters’ expense)</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden era has been a great time to own a home, but a lousy one to buy or rent a residence. Between the president’s inauguration and this May, the typical home price in the United States increased by 46.6 percent, according to Zillow’s <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/FLUCSFRCONDOSMSAMID">home value index</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One person’s rising home value is another’s declining affordability. And for would-be homebuyers, the burden of high home prices has been compounded by a rapid jump in mortgage rates. When Biden took office, <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/MORTGAGE30US">the average rate</a> on a 30-year fixed mortgage was 2.77 percent; today, that figure is closer to 7 percent. As a result, the median monthly mortgage payment jumped by roughly 50 percent between 2021 and 2023, according to an analysis from <a href="https://www.bankrate.com/mortgages/average-monthly-mortgage-payment/#by-loan-type">Bank Rate</a>, a financial services company.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The president does not set interest rates. The Federal Reserve determines borrowing costs. Yet the central bank hiked rates in recent years in response to rising inflation (by increasing borrowing costs, the Fed aims to discourage debt-financed spending and investment, which theoretically slows the growth of prices). Therefore, to the extent that Biden’s fiscal policies contributed to inflation, he bears partial responsibility for rising interest rates.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, rents have soared. Since Biden took office, the average rent in a US city increased by roughly 21 percent, <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/CUUR0000SEHA">according to</a> the Bureau of Labor Statistics.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, trends in shelter costs vary widely by location. In the Biden era, rents and home prices have risen especially rapidly in the Sun Belt region. Between January 2021 and March 2024, home prices in Tampa Bay, Florida, surged by roughly <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/TPXRSA">51 percent</a>, while those in the Phoenix metro area <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/PHXRNSA">appreciated by 40 percent</a>. And rents have followed a similarly <a href="https://zillow.mediaroom.com/2024-05-07-New-York-City-rents-grew-seven-times-faster-than-wages-last-year,-tightening-affordability-crunch">steep upward trajectory</a> in both markets. By contrast, Minneapolis, Minnesota, saw only <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/MNXRSA">an 18.4 percent</a> increase in home prices, and similarly modest rental inflation. In fact, according to a recent <a href="https://zillow.mediaroom.com/2024-05-07-New-York-City-rents-grew-seven-times-faster-than-wages-last-year,-tightening-affordability-crunch">analysis</a> from Zillow and Streeteasy, the typical rent in Minneapolis increased by only 13.5 percent between 2019 and 2023. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the most part, today’s housing affordability crisis has been decades in the making and thus has little to do with Biden’s policies. Restrictions on multifamily housing construction in major US cities have prevented America’s housing stock from keeping pace with demand. Meanwhile, millennials — now America’s largest generation — have entered their prime home-buying and childrearing years en masse, ditching roommates and seeking floorspace. Add in remote work, which has led to an increase in demand for square footage as professionals prefer at-home offices, and you end up with a severe housing crunch.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The tools for alleviating that crisis exist. But they’re primarily available to local governments, which generally have sovereignty over zoning. Minneapolis relaxed restrictions on housing construction in recent years and <a href="https://www.kare11.com/article/money/twin-cities-inflation-rate-among-lowest-in-the-country/89-40f01101-c8e4-4be8-a9ad-d737fa865697">has enjoyed relatively low housing inflation</a> as a result.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">4) <strong>The stock market boomed</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As of this writing, the S&amp;P 500 is more than 42 percent higher than it was on the day Biden took office. Such growth pales a bit in comparison to that seen over the entire course of the Trump presidency, when the index grew by about 68 percent. But it still represents robust gains for investors.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s more, the Biden-era stock market rally may have an unusually large impact on the broader economy. During the Covid pandemic, Americans dedicated a <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/24159281/consumer-spending-economy-inflation-interest-rates">historically high</a> percentage of their income to savings, as public health concerns rendered vacations, dining out, and all manner of other in-person leisure activities less appealing. And many plowed those savings into the stock market: Between 2019 and 2022, the percentage of US households that owned stocks <a href="https://www.wsj.com/finance/stocks/stocks-americans-own-most-ever-9f6fd963">jumped by 5 points</a> to an all-time high of 58 percent. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Combine equity gains with the Biden-era appreciation in home values, and US households in general — and high-income ones in particular — have seen their net worths grow considerably in recent years. When the value of a person’s assets rises, they tend to eventually increase their spending on goods and services. The Biden-era run-up in wealth has therefore likely helped the economy weather inflation, as consumers have been able to sustain high levels of spending by drawing on their savings, home equity, and capital gains — or else, merely by telling themselves that they can afford to spend more, given how good their 401(k) is looking. Indeed, according to <a href="https://economics.td.com/us-household-wealth-props-consumer-spending#:~:text=With%20a%20range%20of%20two,spending%20over%20the%20next%20one.">an analysis</a> from TD Bank, rising wealth explains between 15 and 30 percent of the increase in American consumer spending since the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">5) <strong>The green economy swelled</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, the US government and private investors collectively spent $102.5 billion on the green energy transition, according to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2024-opinion-biden-accomplishment-data/#schrager-income-inequality">BloombergNEF</a>. Last year, that figure exceeded $200 billion. And when investments in the power grid are taken into account, total climate spending in 2023 hits $303 billion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This surge in green spending is a direct consequence of Biden’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/7/28/23282217/climate-bill-health-care-drugs-inflation-reduction-act#">Inflation Reduction Act</a> (IRA), which provided generous subsidies to American producers of renewable energy and electric vehicles, among other low-carbon technologies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All Americans will theoretically benefit eventually from the green transition, which will lengthen our lives by <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2020/8/12/21361498/climate-change-air-pollution-us-india-china-deaths">reducing air pollution</a> and render the Earth less inhospitable for our grandchildren by curbing global warming. But the IRA’s direct beneficiaries are principally American green technology makers, Sun Belt manufacturing workers, and climate-conscious consumers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/01/23/red-states-are-winning-big-from-dems-climate-law-00078420">Politico noted last year</a>, most of the green energy investments spurred by the IRA have been in Republican districts, with a highly disproportionate share concentrated in the American South.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, under Biden, most Americans became eligible for a <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/23498215/ev-tax-credit-2023-heat-pumps-solar">$7,500</a> tax credit on purchases or leases of electric vehicles.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The law made a given vehicle’s eligibility for that tax credit contingent on where its various inputs were produced: To promote American manufacturing of EVs and their batteries, a certain (and steadily rising) percentage of a car’s inputs must be sourced from the US to qualify. But the eligibility requirements for purchased cars are stricter than <a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/cars/what-to-know-about-leasing-an-ev-or-phev-with-tax-credit-a3007689035/">those for leased ones</a>, so Americans who leased an electric vehicle have done especially well in the Biden era. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">6) <strong>Many student debtors saw their loan balances shrink</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s plan to forgive at least $10,000 in student debt for the vast majority of US borrowers was <a href="https://www.vox.com/23762367/student-loan-forgiveness-supreme-court-biden-cancellation">blocked</a> by the Supreme Court last year. But his administration has successfully executed many smaller-scale acts of forgiveness that add up to a prodigious total. As of March, the administration had canceled roughly <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/biden-harris-administration-announces-additional-77-billion-approved-student-debt-relief-160000-borrowers#:~:text=Today's%20announcement%20brings%20the%20total,approved%20for%20some%20debt%20relief.">$167 billion</a> of federal student loan debt, more than 10 percent of all such outstanding debt in the country. All together, 4.75 million borrowers have seen at least a portion of their student debt forgiven under Biden. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">7) <strong>Fast food got pricier</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Precisely because pay for hospitality workers has surged, the cost of fast food has risen sharply. Between May 2020 and May 2023, hourly compensation at American limited-service restaurants <a href="https://www.bls.gov/oes/2020/may/oes353023.htm">jumped</a> <a href="https://www.bls.gov/oes/current/oes353023.htm">by</a> 23 percent, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the same period, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/1/9/24027094/fast-food-prices-wages-mcdonalds">fast food prices soared</a>, rising 8 percent in 2021, 6.6 percent in 2022, and 6 percent in 2023, far outpacing the overall inflation rate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tight labor markets — in which jobs are abundant and workers scarce — benefit Americans in their capacities as laborers. They give workers more bargaining power at their jobs and more freedom to ditch a bad gig without risking prolonged unemployment. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is especially valuable for workers who lack rare skills, face discrimination in the labor market, or require special accommodations. When labor markets are loose, employers can afford to pay meager wages to lower-level staffers, or pass over Black applicants, or refuse to make postings accessible to people with disabilities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When finding enough workers to satisfy customer demand is a struggle, however, firms have no choice but to pay higher wages, consider applicants of all races, and make positions accessible to a wider pool of workers. This is why the Biden era has been so good for low-wage workers. And it is also largely why the unemployment rates of <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNS14000006">Black</a> and <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNU04074597">disabled</a> workers have fallen to record lows during his tenure.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But tight labor markets have less beneficial effects for consumers. Rising wages generally translate into higher prices, especially for goods and services that are labor-intensive. And strong demand for workers also means that many businesses are going to struggle with retention and hiring, and be understaffed as a result.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many consumers of fast food, child care, taxi rides, and other labor-intensive services have therefore found themselves paying more — often for lower-quality service — in the Biden era. For upper-middle-class consumers, whose educational backgrounds and special skills provide them with a modicum of bargaining power even in times of elevated unemployment, the trade-offs of tight labor markets might not be favorable. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The Biden economy works well (albeit not for everyone)</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In my view, more expensive Big Macs are a small price to pay for higher growth, more worker power, and low unemployment. And I also think that the broader strengths of the Biden economy outweigh its weaknesses.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Recovering from the pandemic was always going to be painful. Covid shuttered entire sectors of the US economy and disrupted factory production the world over. At the same time, consumers suddenly shifted their spending away from in-person services and toward manufactured goods, a development that producers weren’t prepared for.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These disruptions had unavoidable economic costs. We could have paid those costs by immiserating America’s most vulnerable workers through a prolonged period of high unemployment. Instead, under Biden, we all chipped in to pay Covid’s toll through inflation while protecting the disadvantaged. I think this was a sound decision.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I understand why some older, high-income Americans — especially those who never lost their jobs during the pandemic, keep all their savings in cash, paid off their student debts long ago, own no home, love fossil fuels, and live off Taco Bell — might disagree.&nbsp;</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/356775/trump-biden-debate-truth-about-biden-record</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/356775/trump-biden-debate-truth-about-biden-record</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Levitz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden’s border record: Trump’s claims vs. reality]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="An image of Trump and Biden is in the shape of the United States on a bright red background. A tangled barbed wire sits on top." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Paige Vickers/Vox; Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/FactsOnTheGround_Border_Final_6-26.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Unauthorized crossings at the US southern border soared higher and higher during the first three years of Joe Biden’s presidency. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, in the first half of 2024, they’ve fallen sharply, but they’re still significantly higher than in the decade before Biden took office.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s the basic numerical trend, according to numbers from US Customs and Border Protection (CBP). How much Biden’s policies have affected that trend is tougher to untangle, and that will likely be a major area of dispute at his debate with Donald Trump this Thursday.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The dramatic surge in unauthorized immigration in Biden’s first few years was spurred by major factors outside of the president’s control, such as the ebbing of the Covid-19 pandemic and upheaval in several Latin American countries.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is also plausible that Biden’s more lenient immigration stance, relative to Trump, contributed to some degree. He has tried to strike a balance between humane policies toward migrants (like offering <a href="https://apnews.com/article/immigration-biden-haiti-cuba-nicaragua-venezuela-trial-fac9dc853231ba04ff0ea4e7442057ef">new legal pathways for entry</a> or <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/immigration/biden-plans-new-policy-shielding-undocumented-spouses-us-citizens-rcna157604">protections against deportation</a> for some already here) and more hard-headed actions trying to cut down on unauthorized arrivals. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet for his first three years, the number of such arrivals remained quite high. His defenders often argued that the main drivers of immigration were not within the president’s control and that his responses were constrained by a broken legal and political process, insufficient resources, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/1/25/24050278/senate-immigration-border-ukraine-trump-mcconnell-romney">Republicans’ refusal to act</a> on legislation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The twist in recent months is that the number of unauthorized arrivals finally <a href="https://www.wola.org/analysis/why-is-migration-declining-at-the-u-s-mexico-border-in-early-2024/">has dropped</a>. “Illegal crossings at the southern border continue to plummet,” Fox News reporter Bill Melugin <a href="https://x.com/BillMelugin_/status/1805272872967090201">wrote on X this week</a>, adding that CBP was now seeing “the lowest border numbers of Biden&#8217;s presidency.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We don’t know how long those lower numbers will persist, of course, and there are still more unauthorized migrants arriving than was typical in the Obama or Trump years. But it’s a notable change, and it’s worth digging into why it appears to have happened.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Unauthorized immigration did soar during Biden’s term. Was it due to Biden’s policies?&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There really was a major unauthorized migration surge under Biden. For most of the decade before he took office, US Customs and Border Protection had in the range of <a href="https://sgp.fas.org/crs/homesec/R46999.pdf">300,000 to 500,000</a> “encounters” with migrants at the southern border each year. Under Biden, the average number has been about 2 million a year, with <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/21/us/politics/cbp-record-border-crossings.html#:~:text=There%20were%20more%20than%202.4,more%20than%201.7%20million%20apprehensions.">last year being the highest yet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are frequently cited as “record breaking” and “highest ever” migrant arrival numbers. But some analysts say it’s more complicated than that. Justin Fox <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2024-03-20/illegal-us-border-crossings-aren-t-really-breaking-records">argues at Bloomberg Opinion</a> that the true numbers were likely higher from the 1980s through the mid-2000s because back then far more migrants escaped CBP’s notice.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it does seem to be clearly true that far more people are coming in unauthorized under Biden than under Obama or Trump. So why?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Conservatives argue that there are specific features of US and Biden administration policy and messaging that drove the migration surge. Biden did, after all, run for office promising to reverse many of Trump’s cruel policies toward immigrants. More broadly, they believe many people are coming because they’ve heard that, with the way our system is set up, they have a pretty good shot at getting into the US and staying there for a good while. (The asylum claim system is incredibly backlogged and detention capacity is limited, so it’s common to release claimants into the US during the long wait until their claims are heard.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In contrast, progressives prefer to emphasize the conditions that drive migrants to leave their home countries, like the catastrophic collapse of Venezuela’s economy and degradation of conditions in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/27/world/americas/nicaragua-us-migration.html">Nicaragua</a> and <a href="https://www.migrationpolicy.org/article/haitians-flee-collapse">Haiti</a>. Crises like these, they argue, have simply gotten worse in recent years, both in the region and around the world, and people need help. (Also, notably, the Covid-19 pandemic ebbed when Biden took office, making migrants more free to travel.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Both narratives likely have some truth to them. The president cannot simply wave a wand and make this issue disappear — otherwise Trump would have done it. (CBP still had more than 300,000 migrant encounters in each year of the Trump administration; in fiscal year 2019 that <a href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/stats/sw-border-migration/fy-2019">number rose</a> to nearly a million.) The administration is indeed constrained by real-world practicalities and global forces outside its control.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet it’s also true that Biden’s policy, even if viewed charitably, has been a bit messy, in part because the Democratic Party is deeply torn about their fundamental values and goals on this issue.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Biden’s border policies have shifted during his term</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since taking office, Biden has tried to strike a balance between Democrats’ desire to help people seeking a better life in the US and their fear that too many unauthorized arrivals brings practical and political problems. But he has struck that balance in different ways at different times.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At first, his administration’s policy was aimed at “<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/06/19/bidens-dilemma-at-the-border">managing the flow</a>” of migrants under the implicit assumption that policy could do little to actually reduce the overall demand to enter the US. Biden’s team did try to stress that the border was “<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/us-homeland-chief-says-us-mexico-border-not-open-irregular-migration-2021-06-15/">not open</a>” and clearly viewed chaotic border scenes as a political risk, but they also <a href="https://www.nilc.org/issues/immigration-reform-and-executive-actions/biden-administration-day-one-immigration-actions/">rolled back</a> harsh Trump policies with great fanfare. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By 2022, with the number of arrivals rising sharply, Democratic politicians in blue states and cities seeing an influx of migrants <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/07/nyregion/eric-adams-migrant-crisis-response.html">increasingly</a> complained that they were <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/chicago/news/mayor-lightfoot-gov-pritzker-migrant-crisis/">overwhelmed</a> — with their shelter systems, schools, and budgets being seriously strained by the challenge of helping so many needy people. “It’s in our DNA to welcome immigrants,” New York Gov. Kathy Hochul (D) <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/kathy-hochul-new-york-governor-face-the-nation-transcript-10-01-2023/">said</a>. “But there has to be some limits in place.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In late 2022 and early 2023, then, Biden <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/2/22/23610849/biden-border-asylum-app-transit">embraced a two-sided policy</a>. Because so many recent arrivals had come from Venezuela, Haiti, Nicaragua, and Cuba, he used executive authority to let hundreds of thousands of people from those countries come legally if they followed an orderly process. He also changed policy to presume more asylum seekers ineligible if they didn’t follow an orderly process. The goal was to change chaotic and unauthorized migration into organized and legal immigration. Still, unauthorized border crossings remained at high levels.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In late 2023, Biden argued that the problem was really an outmoded <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-administration-urges-us-court-uphold-asylum-restrictions-2023-11-08/">asylum process</a> and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2023/12/06/remarks-by-president-biden-urging-congress-to-pass-his-national-security-supplemental-request-including-funding-to-support-ukraine/">insufficient resources</a> — and that the only solution was a big <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/12/14/23981077/immigration-deal-biden-senate-asylum-ukraine">new immigration bill</a> (which would be linked with a stalled Ukraine aid package). Bipartisan talks about this stretched on for months, and Biden was willing to give Republicans a whole lot of what they wanted. Ultimately, Trump <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/1/25/24050278/senate-immigration-border-ukraine-trump-mcconnell-romney">got the GOP</a> to nix the deal, and Senate Republicans <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6wmxbJFbD_A">say</a> that <a href="https://twitter.com/JakeSherman/status/1750295162310349121">Trump</a> openly <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/1/25/24050278/senate-immigration-border-ukraine-trump-mcconnell-romney#:~:text=%E2%80%9CWhen%20we%20started,is%20really%20appalling.%E2%80%9D">admitted</a> he did so because continued border chaos would be good for his election chances.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This year, unauthorized border crossings have sharply declined. Why, and is it sustainable?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With no bill in hand, unauthorized arrivals quite high, and the 2024 election getting closer, the Biden administration acted on its own. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, officials got the Mexican government to agree to do more to stop migrants from getting to the US border in the first place. This, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/immigration/2024/04/30/united-states-mexico-border-surge-biden/">analysts believe</a>, is likely the main reason why the number of arrivals dropped quite a bit in the first half of 2024.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Second was Biden’s <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/white-house/biden-signs-executive-order-shutting-southern-border-rcna155426">executive actions</a> this month to restrict asylum claims even further, shutting down the asylum process if too many people are coming. Many had previously argued that he doesn’t have the legal authority to do this, but he’s <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2024/06/04/biden-authority-border-executive-order/73968735007/">decided to try it</a> anyway, leaving it up to the courts whether to block his policy. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So Biden may well claim some measure of victory in finally reducing the number of unauthorized arrivals, though it’s far from clear whether that will hold up over the long term. Still, if Biden’s recent actions did end up changing the situation, that may make some wonder why he didn’t take such actions much earlier in his term.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Additionally, progressive critics have noted that Biden’s moves to divert more migrants to Mexico and pause new asylum claims resemble policies pursued by Trump. “Though his Administration has avoided its predecessor’s belligerent rhetoric, its goal appears essentially the same: to push the border farther south and to hold Mexico responsible for managing the flow of migrants,” the <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2024/06/10/will-mexico-decide-the-us-election">New Yorker’s Stephania Taladrid writes</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That similarity shouldn’t be overstated. Biden’s policies also dramatically differ from Trump’s because he is still letting hundreds of thousands more people in legally, through his <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/04/23/us/biden-immigration-humanitarian-parole.html">new</a> legal<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/09/20/nyregion/biden-adams-migrants.html"> pathways</a>, and is protecting many already here from deportation (when Trump has promised an unprecedented crackdown). Biden is still trying to seek a middle ground. But overall, his border policy has been a case study in the difficulties of governance. </p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/policy/356761/bidens-border-record-trumps-claims-vs-reality</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/policy/356761/bidens-border-record-trumps-claims-vs-reality</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Prokop]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sunak v Starmer: PM candidates clash over immigration, tax and Brexit - BBC.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiLGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmJiYy5jb20vbmV3cy92aWRlb3MvYzlyM3BwMDJwbHFv0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Sunak v Starmer: PM candidates clash over immigration, tax and Brexit</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnRoZWd1YXJkaWFuLmNvbS9jb21tZW50aXNmcmVlL2FydGljbGUvMjAyNC9qdW4vMjcvcmlzaGktc3VuYWsta2Vpci1zdGFybWVyLW1hbmFnZXJzLWdvbGYtY2x1Yi1maW5hbC1sZWFkZXJzLWRlYmF0ZdIBfmh0dHBzOi8vYW1wLnRoZWd1YXJkaWFuLmNvbS9jb21tZW50aXNmcmVlL2FydGljbGUvMjAyNC9qdW4vMjcvcmlzaGktc3VuYWsta2Vpci1zdGFybWVyLW1hbmFnZXJzLWdvbGYtY2x1Yi1maW5hbC1sZWFkZXJzLWRlYmF0ZQ?oc=5" target="_blank">With our futures at stake, Sunak and Starmer argued like managers of an imperilled golf club</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFodHRwczovL3RpbWVzb2ZpbmRpYS5pbmRpYXRpbWVzLmNvbS93b3JsZC91ay9hcmUteW91LXR3by1iZXN0LXdldmUtZ290LXZvdGVyLWZydXN0cmF0aW9uLXNjYW5kYWwtZG9taW5hdGUtZmluYWwtZGViYXRlLWJldHdlZW4tc3VuYWstc3Rhcm1lci9hcnRpY2xlc2hvdy8xMTEyOTU4OTAuY21z0gGqAWh0dHBzOi8vdGltZXNvZmluZGlhLmluZGlhdGltZXMuY29tL3dvcmxkL3VrL2FyZS15b3UtdHdvLWJlc3Qtd2V2ZS1nb3Qtdm90ZXItZnJ1c3RyYXRpb24tc2NhbmRhbC1kb21pbmF0ZS1maW5hbC1kZWJhdGUtYmV0d2Vlbi1zdW5hay1zdGFybWVyL2FtcF9hcnRpY2xlc2hvdy8xMTEyOTU4OTAuY21z?oc=5" target="_blank">'Are you two best we've got?': Voter frustration, scandal dominate final debate between Sunak & Starmer</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of India</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmV1L2FydGljbGUva2llci1zdGFybWVyLWRlYmF0ZS11ay1lbGVjdGlvbi0yMDI0LXJpc2hpLXN1bmFrLXBvbGl0aWNhbC1yb2JvdC1wb2xscy1qdWx5LTQtdm90ZXJzL9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Keir Starmer lost the debate — but he'll still win the UK election</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO Europe</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmluZGVwZW5kZW50LmNvLnVrL25ld3MvdWsvcG9saXRpY3MvcmlzaGktc3VuYWsta2Vpci1zdGFybWVyLXR2LWRlYmF0ZS1rbm9ja291dC1iMjU2OTg3MS5odG1s0gEA?oc=5" target="_blank">Rishi Sunak 'failed to deliver knockout blow' he needed in last TV debate</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Independent</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiLGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmJiYy5jb20vbmV3cy92aWRlb3MvYzlyM3BwMDJwbHFv0gEA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiLGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmJiYy5jb20vbmV3cy92aWRlb3MvYzlyM3BwMDJwbHFv0gEA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:06:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia says Israel tests missile able to reach Tehran, report]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1dpn9nj/russia_says_israel_tests_missile_able_to_reach/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/KaJeHYJ9kInl7Pa9bd2mEeJUt5OstLeZjSCyMNZUo0A.jpg?width=320&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=c10c5737ed57c47fd47fe44fe10cbdfae8b0282c" alt="Russia says Israel tests missile able to reach Tehran, report" title="Russia says Israel tests missile able to reach Tehran, report" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/itseytan"> /u/itseytan </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.ynetnews.com/article/skray2qia">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1dpn9nj/russia_says_israel_tests_missile_able_to_reach/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1dpn9nj/russia_says_israel_tests_missile_able_to_reach/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1dpn9nj/russia_says_israel_tests_missile_able_to_reach/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/itseytan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 09:38:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[EU leaders meet to discuss situation in Ukraine and decide bloc’s future leaders – Europe live]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>European Council summit sees heads of state and government deciding on top roles including European commission president and  European council president</p><p>Good afternoon and welcome to a special edition of the Europe blog, coming to you from the European Council summit in Brussels.</p><p>Today, the EU’s 27 heads of state and government are expected to discuss the situation in Ukraine – and make a decision on the bloc’s next top leaders.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/jun/27/eu-leaders-meet-to-discuss-situation-in-ukraine-and-decide-blocs-future-leaders-europe-live">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/jun/27/eu-leaders-meet-to-discuss-situation-in-ukraine-and-decide-blocs-future-leaders-europe-live</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/jun/27/eu-leaders-meet-to-discuss-situation-in-ukraine-and-decide-blocs-future-leaders-europe-live</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:03:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘We feel dispirited’: striking junior doctors worn down but determined to fight on]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Five-day strike by junior doctors is the 11th action in their long-running pay dispute</p><p>“I’m itching to get back to work, to get back to the grindstone,” said junior radiology doctor Matthew Alexander. “Nobody wants to be here, nobody wants to be on strike.”</p><p>Alexander, 30, is one of about 50 junior doctors on a Thursday morning picket line at the <a href="https://www.southtees.nhs.uk/hospitals/friarage/">Friarage hospital in Northallerton</a>, a bustling market town in Rishi Sunak’s sprawling North Yorkshire constituency.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/27/we-feel-dispirited-striking-junior-doctors-worn-down-but-determined-to-fight-on">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/27/we-feel-dispirited-striking-junior-doctors-worn-down-but-determined-to-fight-on</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/27/we-feel-dispirited-striking-junior-doctors-worn-down-but-determined-to-fight-on</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:59:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UK general election live: at least seven police officers under investigation over bets on timing of general election, says Metropolitan police]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Force says number of officers under investigation has risen to seven, including prime minister’s protection officer who was arrested last week</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/article/2024/may/23/sign-up-for-the-uk-general-election-2024-newsletter">Sign up to our Election Edition daily newsletter</a></li></ul><p>Rishi Sunak is returning to the campaign trail on Thursday, PA reports, after a two-day hiatus for the Emperor and Empress of Japan’s state visit and preparations for the final head-to-head debate with Sir Keir Starmer.<br><br>
 With one week to go until polling day, the deepening gambling scandal is still likely to feature heavily when he faces the media during a tour of the East Midlands and Yorkshire.<br><br>
 He is expected to visit a factory in Derbyshire and hold an evening campaign event in Leeds.</p><p><strong>Keir Starmer</strong> accused <strong>Rishi Sunak</strong> of using transgender issues “as a political football to divide people” during their head-to-head debate on Wednesday.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/jun/27/uk-general-election-2024-live-updates-debate-betting-scandal-rishi-sunak-keir-starmer-tories-labour">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/jun/27/uk-general-election-2024-live-updates-debate-betting-scandal-rishi-sunak-keir-starmer-tories-labour</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2024/jun/27/uk-general-election-2024-live-updates-debate-betting-scandal-rishi-sunak-keir-starmer-tories-labour</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:50:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden and Trump prepare to debate | First Thing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump and Joe Biden will take part Thursday in the first presidential debate in a race currently in a dead heat. Plus: Life in the DMZ</p><p>Good morning.</p><p>Joe Biden and Donald Trump will face off once again in a CNN studio in Atlanta for <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jun/27/biden-trump-presidential-debate">the first presidential debate of the campaign</a>. Though this will be the earliest in any US presidential campaign that a debate between the two main candidates has been staged, polls currently indicate that the race is essentially tied, upping the stakes for both candidates to perform well Thursday night.</p><p><strong>What do the polls say?</strong> A national polling average for May and June showed <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/us/elections/polls-president.html">the candidates at 46% each</a>, while polls in seven key battleground states – Wisconsin, Michigan, Pennsylvania, Nevada, Arizona, Georgia and North Carolina – give Trump a narrow advantage, though usually within the margin of error.</p><p><strong>What should we expect?</strong> Biden will likely be aiming to dilute criticism of his age with an energetic performance, and could be prepared to go on the offensive regarding Trump’s criminal record. Meanwhile, Trump advisers who know he needs at least some moderate voters to win will be hoping he can tone down his most virulent rhetoric, such as saying immigrants are “poisoning the blood of our country”.</p><p><strong>What have the candidates been saying ahead of the debate?</strong> Trump has unleashed <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jun/26/trump-biden-presidential-debate">a fusillade of baseless accusations</a> against Biden and CNN moderators in a familiar rehash of tactics used in previous campaigns.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jun/27/first-thing-biden-and-trump-prepare-for-tv-debate">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jun/27/first-thing-biden-and-trump-prepare-for-tv-debate</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jun/27/first-thing-biden-and-trump-prepare-for-tv-debate</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 11:05:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gag order in classified docs case may lead to Trump’s ‘arrest’ after debate with Biden | Reporter Replay]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/gag-order-classified-docs-case-125100839.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/gag-order-classified-docs-case-125100839.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 12:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Panicking Trump Tries Yet Another Get-Out-of-Debate-Free Card]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/panicking-trump-tries-yet-another-134945473.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/panicking-trump-tries-yet-another-134945473.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 13:49:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Three female GOP state senators who filibustered S.C. abortion ban lost their primaries]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/three-female-gop-state-senators-142126813.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/three-female-gop-state-senators-142126813.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:21:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Marjorie Taylor Greene Swung at a Drag Queen—and Missed]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/marjorie-taylor-greene-swung-drag-173631552.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/marjorie-taylor-greene-swung-drag-173631552.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 17:36:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[She managed to flee Gaza after half her family was killed in an Israeli strike. She blames Israel and Hamas for what happened]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/she-managed-leave-gaza-half-040142161.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/she-managed-leave-gaza-half-040142161.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 08:03:43 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>