<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 19:22:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 19:22:53 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Trump’s VP pick is a naked authoritarian]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Republican U.S. Senate candidate JD Vance speaks to supporters at an election watch party at the Renaissance Hotel on November 8, 2022 in Columbus, Ohio." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-1244627787.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Republican U.S. Senate candidate JD Vance speaks to supporters at an election watch party at the Renaissance Hotel on November 8, 2022 in Columbus, Ohio.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">I met Sen. J.D. Vance (R-OH), Donald Trump’s new choice for vice president, in the summer of 2022. I was <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23271726/cpac-goes-to-israel">covering a conservative conference in Israel</a>, and Vance was the surprise VIP attraction. We chatted for a bit about the connections between right-wing movements across the world, and what American conservatives could learn from foreign peers. He was friendly, thoughtful, and smart — much smarter than the average politician I’ve interviewed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet his worldview is fundamentally incompatible with the basic principles of American democracy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance has said that, had he been vice president in 2020, he would have <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/02/05/vance-trump-upend-democracy/">carried out Trump’s scheme for the vice president to overturn the election results</a>. He has <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/01/08/politics/fact-check-jd-vance-capitol-charges/index.html">fundraised for January 6 rioters</a>. He once called on the Justice Department to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/12/07/trump-dictatorship-retribution-jd-vance-robert-kagan/">open a criminal investigation</a> into a Washington Post columnist who penned a critical piece about Trump. After last week’s assassination attempt on Trump, he attempted to whitewash his radicalism by blaming the shooting <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360557/trump-assassination-attempt-republican-response-political-violence-irresponsible">on Democrats’ rhetoric about democracy</a> without an iota of evidence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This worldview translates into a very aggressive agenda for a second Trump presidency. In <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/abc-host-abruptly-ends-interview-jd-vance-supreme-court-remarks-no-no-george">a podcast interview</a>, Vance said that Trump should “fire every single mid-level bureaucrat” in the US government and “replace them with our people.” If the courts attempt to stop this, Vance says, Trump should simply ignore the law.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“You stand before the country, like Andrew Jackson did, and say the chief justice has made his ruling, now let him enforce it,” he declares.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The President Jackson quote is likely apocryphal, but <a href="https://www.vox.com/23055620/supreme-court-legitimacy-crisis-abortion-roe">the history is real</a>. Vance is referring to an 1832 case, <em>Worcester v. Georgia</em>, in which the Supreme Court ruled that the US government needed to respect Native legal rights to land ownership. Jackson ignored the ruling, and continued a policy of allowing whites to take what belonged to Natives. The end result was the ethnic cleansing of about 60,000 Natives — an event we now call the Trail of Tears.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For most Americans, this history is a deep source of shame: an authoritarian president trampling on the rule of law to commit atrocities. For Vance, it is a well of inspiration.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">J.D. Vance is a man who believes that the current government is so corrupt that <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2022/04/inside-the-new-right-where-peter-thiel-is-placing-his-biggest-bets">radical, even authoritarian steps, are justified in response</a>. He sees himself as the avatar of America’s virtuous people, whose political enemies are interlopers scarcely worthy of respect. He is a man of the law who believes the president is above it. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The authoritarian wing of the authoritarian party</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">J.D. Vance wasn’t always like this.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He grew up poor in Middletown, Ohio — escaping a difficult childhood to make it to Yale Law and, subsequently, to the lucrative world of venture capital. This narrative served as the backbone of his 2016 book, <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>, that turned into a mega-bestseller: a book that seemed to explain Trump’s appeal to America’s downtrodden. It put Vance on the national map.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Vance of <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em> was very different politically. Back then, he took a conventional conservative line on poverty, describing the working class as <a href="https://democracyjournal.org/magazine/43/a-hillbilly-left/">beset by a cultural pathology encouraged by federal handouts</a> and the welfare state.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">2016 Vance <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/how-trumps-potential-running-mates-harshly-criticized-him-in-the-past">was also an ardent Trump foe</a>. He wrote a New York Times op-ed titled “Mr. Trump Is Unfit For Our Nation’s Highest Office,” and wrote <a href="https://ohiocapitaljournal.com/2022/04/19/americas-hitler-old-j-d-vance-message-turns-up-in-heated-senate-primary/">a text to his law school roommate</a> warning that Trump might be “America’s Hitler.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Eight years later, Vance has metamorphosed into something else entirely. Today, he pitches himself as an economic populist and cosponsors legislation with Sen. Elizabeth Warren <a href="https://www.warren.senate.gov/newsroom/press-releases/warren-vance-bipartisan-group-of-senators-renew-push-for-legislation-to-claw-back-big-failed-bank-executive-pay">curtailing pay for failed bankers</a>. In an even more extreme shift, he has morphed into one of Trump’s leading champions in the Senate —&nbsp;backing the former president to the hilt and even, at times, outpacing him in anti-democratic fervor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I spoke to Georgia state Sen. Josh McLaurin (D) — the former law school roommate who had received Vance’s “America’s Hitler” text — I asked him how the Vance he knew evolved into the Vance we see today. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The through line between former J.D. and current J.D. is anger,” McLaurin told me. “The Trump turn can be understood as a lock-in on contempt as the answer to anger” — specifically, contempt directed at Vance’s political enemies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">McLaurin’s comments suggest that Vance’s conversion to Trumpism is genuine. I’m inclined to agree, though the timing of his MAGA conversion surely is convenient: He converted to right-wing populism just in time to run for a vacant seat in Trumpy Ohio.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, whether Vance truly believes what he’s saying is secondary to the public persona he’s chosen to adopt. Politicians are not defined by their inner lives, but the decisions that they make in public&nbsp;— the ones that actually affect law and policy. Those choices are deeply shaped by the constituencies they depend on and the allies they court.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And it is clear that Vance is deeply ensconced in the GOP’s growing “national conservative” faction, which pairs an inconsistent economic populism with an authoritarian commitment to crushing liberals in the culture war.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance has <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23373795/curtis-yarvin-neoreaction-redpill-moldbug">cited Curtis Yarvin</a>, a Silicon Valley monarchist blogger, as the source of his ideas about firing bureaucrats and defying the Supreme Court. His Senate campaign was <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/05/03/jd-vance-win-ohio-primary-00029881">funded by his former employer</a>, Vance’s former employer Peter Thiel, a billionaire who <a href="https://www.cato-unbound.org/2009/04/13/peter-thiel/education-libertarian/">once wrote</a> that “I no longer believe that freedom and democracy are compatible.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He’s a big fan of Patrick Deneen, a Notre Dame professor who recently wrote a book <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/6/15/23734340/patrick-deneen-regime-change-review">calling for “regime change” in America</a>. Vance spoke at an event for Deneen’s book in Washington, <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2024/03/15/mr-maga-goes-to-washington-00147054">describing himself</a> as a member of the “postliberal right” who sees his job in Congress as taking an “explicitly anti-regime” stance.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance is also an open admirer of Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orbán, a right-wing politician who has systematically torn his country’s democracy apart. Vance praised <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/jd-vance-viktor-orban-smart-decisions-face-the-nation/">Orbán’s approach to higher education</a> in particular, saying he “made some smart decisions there that we could learn from in the United States.” The policies in question involve using national dollars to <a href="https://www.economist.com/leaders/2021/05/01/viktor-orban-seizes-control-of-hungarys-universities">impose state controls over universities</a>, turning them into vehicles for disseminating the government line.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a profile of Vance, <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2024/03/15/mr-maga-goes-to-washington-00147054">Politico reporter Ian Ward</a> quotes multiple leading Republican figures —&nbsp;specifically, the leaders of the faction trying to turn these postliberal ideas into practice — saying that they see Vance as a leading advocate for their cause.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Top Trump advisor (and current federal inmate) Steve Bannon told <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2024/03/15/mr-maga-goes-to-washington-00147054">Ward</a> that Vance is “at the nerve center of this movement.” Kevin Roberts, the president of the right-wing Heritage Foundation and the driving force behind Project 2025, told Ward that “he is absolutely going to be one of the leaders — if not the leader — of our movement.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Enacting Trump’s dark ambitions</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is little doubt that Vance will continue in this role if elected vice president. He would enable all of Trump’s worst instincts, and put a brake on none — deploying his considerable intellectual and intrapersonal gifts toward bending the government to Trump’s will.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Trump’s first term, he faced considerable opposition from inside his own administration. People like Defense Secretary James Mattis and Vice President Mike Pence served as brakes on Trump’s most radical impulses, challenging or even refusing to implement his (illegal) directives.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance’s ascendance represents the death of this “adults in the room” model. Backed by people drawn from the lists of loyal staffers <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/04/20/us/politics/republican-president-2024-heritage-foundation.html">being prepared by places like Heritage</a>, Vance would not only support Trump’s radical impulses but seems likely to spearhead efforts to implement them.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He would be a direct conduit from the shadowy world of far-right influencers, where Curtis Yarvin is a respected voice and Viktor Orbán a role model, straight to 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2004, Democratic presidential candidate Howard Dean described himself as hailing from “<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2004/jan/20/uselections2004.usa8">the Democratic wing of the Democratic party</a>.” If the GOP under Trump <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2021/6/15/22522504/republicans-authoritarianism-trump-competitive">has indeed evolved into an authoritarian party</a>, then Vance hails from its authoritarian wing.&nbsp;</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/360283/jd-vance-trump-vp-vice-president-authoritarian</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/360283/jd-vance-trump-vp-vice-president-authoritarian</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Beauchamp]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 19:10:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump chooses J.D. Vance as VP running mate]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="Photo collage of former President Donald Trump and his vice presidential candidate, J.D. Vance." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i6PsXziHurLaYPDzwh1BYqNtkg8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73462157/STK175_DONALD_TRUMP_CVIRGINIA_E.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Image: The Verge; Getty Images</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="J1SdQg"></p>
<p id="MWyZfQ"></p>
<p id="8vPiw1">Former President Donald Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/112792061935980928">has announced Ohio Senator J.D. Vance</a> as his running mate. Trump is expected to accept the Republican nomination on Thursday. Vance would serve as vice president if elected to office in November. </p>
<p id="Rlsang">The selection came on the first day of the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee and just a couple days after Trump survived an attempted assassination at a rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday. <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/112782066045321247">Trump said on Truth Social</a> that a bullet pierced the upper part of his ear, and law enforcement confirmed one spectator <a href="https://www.cnn.com/politics/live-news/election-biden-trump-07-13-24#h_00cc0d2040c20f6fde508d9f8fd58acf">died during the incident and two were critically injured</a>. The Secret Service killed the gunman, who the FBI has identified as Thomas Matthew Crooks, a 20-year-old from Pennsylvania.</p>
<p id="HNOJOo">After his close...</p>
  <p>
    <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/15/24199043/trump-vice-president-running-mate-2024-election-jd-vance">Continue reading&hellip;</a>
  </p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/15/24199043/trump-vice-president-running-mate-2024-election-jd-vance</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/15/24199043/trump-vice-president-running-mate-2024-election-jd-vance</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Lauren Feiner]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 19:12:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[JD Vance once criticised Trump. Now he's his running mate]]></title><description><![CDATA[The junior senator from Ohio shot to fame writing about his hard upbringing and morphed from a 'never-Trumper' into a Maga champion.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn07dv4mrg2o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn07dv4mrg2o</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 19:11:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RNC kicks off after Trump assassination attempt - CNN]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vcG9saXRpY3MvbGl2ZS1uZXdzL3JuYy1yZXB1YmxpY2FuLW5hdGlvbmFsLWNvbnZlbnRpb24tMDctMTUtMjQvaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">RNC kicks off after Trump assassination attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBvbGl0aWNvLmNvbS9saXZlLXVwZGF0ZXMvMjAyNC8wNy8xNS9ybmMtbGl2ZS11cGRhdGVzLWNvdmVyYWdlL3RydW1wLXZwLXBpY2stZG91Zy1idXJndW0tMDAxNjgzMjbSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump's VP pick won't be Doug Burgum</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZ2h0dHBzOi8vYXBuZXdzLmNvbS9hcnRpY2xlL3RydW1wLXZpY2UtcHJlc2lkZW50LXZhbmNlLXJ1YmlvLWJ1cmd1bS1ybmMtNmNjNDM4YTgzNzBhMjFiMjYzMWY1YTUzYjA2YjcxZDDSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump makes his vice presidential pick. Rubio is told he is not the choice, an AP source says</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiQWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNuYmMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMTUvZG9uYWxkLXRydW1wLXZwLWFubm91bmNlbWVudC5odG1s0gFFaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuY25iYy5jb20vYW1wLzIwMjQvMDcvMTUvZG9uYWxkLXRydW1wLXZwLWFubm91bmNlbWVudC5odG1s?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump will announce VP at RNC around 4:30 p.m. ET; Rubio and Burgum told they were not picked</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVGh0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vaG9tZW5ld3MvY2FtcGFpZ24vNDc3MzI2Mi12YW5jZS10cnVtcC1ydW5uaW5nLW1hdGUtZnJvbnQtcnVubmVyL9IBWGh0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vaG9tZW5ld3MvY2FtcGFpZ24vNDc3MzI2Mi12YW5jZS10cnVtcC1ydW5uaW5nLW1hdGUtZnJvbnQtcnVubmVyL2FtcC8?oc=5" target="_blank">Vance emerges as Trump’s VP pick, with Rubio and Burgum out</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vcG9saXRpY3MvbGl2ZS1uZXdzL3JuYy1yZXB1YmxpY2FuLW5hdGlvbmFsLWNvbnZlbnRpb24tMDctMTUtMjQvaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vcG9saXRpY3MvbGl2ZS1uZXdzL3JuYy1yZXB1YmxpY2FuLW5hdGlvbmFsLWNvbnZlbnRpb24tMDctMTUtMjQvaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 19:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[WATCH LIVE: 2024 Republican National Convention | RNC Day 1 | PBS News special coverage - PBS NewsHour]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvcG9saXRpY3Mvd2F0Y2gtbGl2ZS0yMDI0LXJlcHVibGljYW4tbmF0aW9uYWwtY29udmVudGlvbi1ybmMtZGF5LTEtcGJzLW5ld3Mtc3BlY2lhbC1jb3ZlcmFnZdIBfGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvYW1wL3BvbGl0aWNzL3dhdGNoLWxpdmUtMjAyNC1yZXB1YmxpY2FuLW5hdGlvbmFsLWNvbnZlbnRpb24tcm5jLWRheS0xLXBicy1uZXdzLXNwZWNpYWwtY292ZXJhZ2U?oc=5" target="_blank">WATCH LIVE: 2024 Republican National Convention | RNC Day 1 | PBS News special coverage</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">PBS NewsHour</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiRGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8xNS9wb2xpdGljcy93aGF0LXRvLXdhdGNoLXJuYy9pbmRleC5odG1s0gE9aHR0cHM6Ly9hbXAuY25uLmNvbS9jbm4vMjAyNC8wNy8xNS9wb2xpdGljcy93aGF0LXRvLXdhdGNoLXJuYw?oc=5" target="_blank">What to watch at the Republican National Convention this week</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiOmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNic25ld3MuY29tL25ld3Mvcm5jLXJvbGwtY2FsbC1vZi1zdGF0ZXMtMjAyNC_SAT5odHRwczovL3d3dy5jYnNuZXdzLmNvbS9hbXAvbmV3cy9ybmMtcm9sbC1jYWxsLW9mLXN0YXRlcy0yMDI0Lw?oc=5" target="_blank">See RNC roll call of state vote results for the 2024 Republican presidential nomination</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndpc24uY29tL2FydGljbGUvbWlsd2F1a2VlLXJuYy1vcGVuaW5nLWRheS13aGF0cy1vbi10aGUtc2NoZWR1bGUtanVseS0xNC82MTU5MjUzMdIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">RNC 2024 Milwaukee: Opening day schedule and key events</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">WISN Milwaukee</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijQFodHRwczovL3d3dy5qc29ubGluZS5jb20vc3RvcnkvbmV3cy9wb2xpdGljcy9lbGVjdGlvbnMvMjAyNC8wNy8xNS9ybmMtYmVnaW5zLWluLW1pbHdhdWtlZS1kYXlzLWFmdGVyLXRydW1wLWFzc2Fzc2luYXRpb24tYXR0ZW1wdC83NDIxODAwOTAwNy_SAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Republican National Convention begins Monday in Milwaukee following Trump assassination attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Milwaukee Journal Sentinel</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvcG9saXRpY3Mvd2F0Y2gtbGl2ZS0yMDI0LXJlcHVibGljYW4tbmF0aW9uYWwtY29udmVudGlvbi1ybmMtZGF5LTEtcGJzLW5ld3Mtc3BlY2lhbC1jb3ZlcmFnZdIBfGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvYW1wL3BvbGl0aWNzL3dhdGNoLWxpdmUtMjAyNC1yZXB1YmxpY2FuLW5hdGlvbmFsLWNvbnZlbnRpb24tcm5jLWRheS0xLXBicy1uZXdzLXNwZWNpYWwtY292ZXJhZ2U?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvcG9saXRpY3Mvd2F0Y2gtbGl2ZS0yMDI0LXJlcHVibGljYW4tbmF0aW9uYWwtY29udmVudGlvbi1ybmMtZGF5LTEtcGJzLW5ld3Mtc3BlY2lhbC1jb3ZlcmFnZdIBfGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnBicy5vcmcvbmV3c2hvdXIvYW1wL3BvbGl0aWNzL3dhdGNoLWxpdmUtMjAyNC1yZXB1YmxpY2FuLW5hdGlvbmFsLWNvbnZlbnRpb24tcm5jLWRheS0xLXBicy1uZXdzLXNwZWNpYWwtY292ZXJhZ2U?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 15:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Secret Service director ripped for 'unacceptable' response to Trump assassination attempt: 'Mind-boggling' - Fox News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL21lZGlhL3NlY3JldC1zZXJ2aWNlLWRpcmVjdG9yLXJpcHBlZC11bmFjY2VwdGFibGUtcmVzcG9uc2UtdHJ1bXAtYXNzYXNzaW5hdGlvbi1hdHRlbXB0LW1pbmQtYm9nZ2xpbmfSAYABaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZm94bmV3cy5jb20vbWVkaWEvc2VjcmV0LXNlcnZpY2UtZGlyZWN0b3ItcmlwcGVkLXVuYWNjZXB0YWJsZS1yZXNwb25zZS10cnVtcC1hc3Nhc3NpbmF0aW9uLWF0dGVtcHQtbWluZC1ib2dnbGluZy5hbXA?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service director ripped for 'unacceptable' response to Trump assassination attempt: 'Mind-boggling'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFodHRwczovL2FiYzcuY29tL2xpdmUtdXBkYXRlcy9kb25hbGQtdHJ1bXAtcmFsbHktc2hvb3Rpbmctcm9vZnRvcC13aGVyZS1zdXNwZWN0ZWQtc2hvb3Rlci1vcGVuZWQtZmlyZS13YXMtbGF3LWVuZm9yY2VtZW50LXN0YWdpbmctYXJlYS8xNTA1NzE1OC_SAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Shooter's rooftop was law enforcement staging area | Live Updates</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">KABC-TV</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZmh0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vcmVndWxhdGlvbi9uYXRpb25hbC1zZWN1cml0eS80NzczMTUwLW1heW9ya2FzLXRydW1wLXJhbGx5LXNob290aW5nLXNlY3JldC1zZXJ2aWNlL9IBamh0dHBzOi8vdGhlaGlsbC5jb20vcmVndWxhdGlvbi9uYXRpb25hbC1zZWN1cml0eS80NzczMTUwLW1heW9ya2FzLXRydW1wLXJhbGx5LXNob290aW5nLXNlY3JldC1zZXJ2aWNlL2FtcC8?oc=5" target="_blank">Mayorkas: Trump rally shooting was ‘failure’ by Secret Service</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL3VzL2Zvcm1lci1zZWNyZXQtc2VydmljZS1hZ2VudC13YXJucy1hZ2VuY3ktc3RyZXRjaGVkLXRoaW4tbmV3LXJlc3BvbnNpYmlsaXRpZXMtbGFjay1tYW5wb3dlctIBeWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL3VzL2Zvcm1lci1zZWNyZXQtc2VydmljZS1hZ2VudC13YXJucy1hZ2VuY3ktc3RyZXRjaGVkLXRoaW4tbmV3LXJlc3BvbnNpYmlsaXRpZXMtbGFjay1tYW5wb3dlci5hbXA?oc=5" target="_blank">Former Secret Service agent warns agency ‘stretched thin’ with new responsibilities, lack of manpower</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMif2h0dHBzOi8vYWJjbmV3cy5nby5jb20vVVMvaG9tZWxhbmQtc2VjdXJpdHktYWxlamFuZHJvLW1heW9ya2FzLXNlY3JldC1zZXJ2aWNlLXRydW1wLWFzc2lzaW5hdGlvbi1hdHRlbXB0LWdtYS9zdG9yeT9pZD0xMTE5NDQ4MDnSAYMBaHR0cHM6Ly9hYmNuZXdzLmdvLmNvbS9hbXAvVVMvaG9tZWxhbmQtc2VjdXJpdHktYWxlamFuZHJvLW1heW9ya2FzLXNlY3JldC1zZXJ2aWNlLXRydW1wLWFzc2lzaW5hdGlvbi1hdHRlbXB0LWdtYS9zdG9yeT9pZD0xMTE5NDQ4MDk?oc=5" target="_blank">DHS secretary says direct line of sight 'should not occur' in wake of Trump assassination attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL21lZGlhL3NlY3JldC1zZXJ2aWNlLWRpcmVjdG9yLXJpcHBlZC11bmFjY2VwdGFibGUtcmVzcG9uc2UtdHJ1bXAtYXNzYXNzaW5hdGlvbi1hdHRlbXB0LW1pbmQtYm9nZ2xpbmfSAYABaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZm94bmV3cy5jb20vbWVkaWEvc2VjcmV0LXNlcnZpY2UtZGlyZWN0b3ItcmlwcGVkLXVuYWNjZXB0YWJsZS1yZXNwb25zZS10cnVtcC1hc3Nhc3NpbmF0aW9uLWF0dGVtcHQtbWluZC1ib2dnbGluZy5hbXA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmZveG5ld3MuY29tL21lZGlhL3NlY3JldC1zZXJ2aWNlLWRpcmVjdG9yLXJpcHBlZC11bmFjY2VwdGFibGUtcmVzcG9uc2UtdHJ1bXAtYXNzYXNzaW5hdGlvbi1hdHRlbXB0LW1pbmQtYm9nZ2xpbmfSAYABaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZm94bmV3cy5jb20vbWVkaWEvc2VjcmV0LXNlcnZpY2UtZGlyZWN0b3ItcmlwcGVkLXVuYWNjZXB0YWJsZS1yZXNwb25zZS10cnVtcC1hc3Nhc3NpbmF0aW9uLWF0dGVtcHQtbWluZC1ib2dnbGluZy5hbXA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 16:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Protesters March in Milwaukee as R.N.C. Opens - The New York Times]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiQ2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMTUvdXMvcHJvdGVzdGVycy1taWx3YXVrZWUtcm5jLmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5" target="_blank">Protesters March in Milwaukee as R.N.C. Opens</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2k1OTlyMkN4RzA1a1QyWEFIMThpZ0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiQ2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMTUvdXMvcHJvdGVzdGVycy1taWx3YXVrZWUtcm5jLmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiQ2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm55dGltZXMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMTUvdXMvcHJvdGVzdGVycy1taWx3YXVrZWUtcm5jLmh0bWzSAQA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 09:03:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[DJT stock soars after Donald Trump survives assassination attempt - Yahoo Finance]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib2h0dHBzOi8vZmluYW5jZS55YWhvby5jb20vbmV3cy9kanQtc3RvY2stc29hcnMtYWZ0ZXItZG9uYWxkLXRydW1wLXN1cnZpdmVzLWFzc2Fzc2luYXRpb24tYXR0ZW1wdC0xODAxMzUzNTMuaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">DJT stock soars after Donald Trump survives assassination attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo Finance</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiQmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNubi5jb20vMjAyNC8wNy8xNS9tYXJrZXRzL3VzLW1hcmtldHMtdHJ1bXAvaW5kZXguaHRtbNIBO2h0dHBzOi8vYW1wLmNubi5jb20vY25uLzIwMjQvMDcvMTUvbWFya2V0cy91cy1tYXJrZXRzLXRydW1w?oc=5" target="_blank">Stocks, dollar and crypto jump after Trump assassination attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lm1hcmtldHdhdGNoLmNvbS9zdG9yeS93aHktdGhlLXRydW1wLXRyYWRlLWlzLWJvb3N0aW5nLWJpdGNvaW4tYW5kLXdoYXRzLW5leHQtZm9yLXRoZS1jcnlwdG8tYTAyYjQ0OGXSAXRodHRwczovL3d3dy5tYXJrZXR3YXRjaC5jb20vYW1wL3N0b3J5L3doeS10aGUtdHJ1bXAtdHJhZGUtaXMtYm9vc3RpbmctYml0Y29pbi1hbmQtd2hhdHMtbmV4dC1mb3ItdGhlLWNyeXB0by1hMDJiNDQ4ZQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Why the ‘Trump trade’ is boosting bitcoin, and what’s next for the crypto</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MarketWatch</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWGh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNuYmMuY29tLzIwMjQvMDcvMTUvdHJ1bXAtbWVkaWEtc2hhcmVzLXJpc2UtYWZ0ZXItYXNzYXNzaW5hdGlvbi1hdHRlbXB0Lmh0bWzSAVxodHRwczovL3d3dy5jbmJjLmNvbS9hbXAvMjAyNC8wNy8xNS90cnVtcC1tZWRpYS1zaGFyZXMtcmlzZS1hZnRlci1hc3Nhc3NpbmF0aW9uLWF0dGVtcHQuaHRtbA?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump Media shares soar more than 30% after assassination attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWmh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNvaW5kZXNrLmNvbS92aWRlby9ob3ctY3J5cHRvLW1hcmtldHMtcmVhY3RlZC10by10cnVtcHMtYXNzYXNzaW5hdGlvbi1hdHRlbXB0L9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">How Crypto Markets Reacted to Trump's Assassination Attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CoinDesk</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib2h0dHBzOi8vZmluYW5jZS55YWhvby5jb20vbmV3cy9kanQtc3RvY2stc29hcnMtYWZ0ZXItZG9uYWxkLXRydW1wLXN1cnZpdmVzLWFzc2Fzc2luYXRpb24tYXR0ZW1wdC0xODAxMzUzNTMuaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib2h0dHBzOi8vZmluYW5jZS55YWhvby5jb20vbmV3cy9kanQtc3RvY2stc29hcnMtYWZ0ZXItZG9uYWxkLXRydW1wLXN1cnZpdmVzLWFzc2Fzc2luYXRpb24tYXR0ZW1wdC0xODAxMzUzNTMuaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:01:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump picks JD Vance as his running mate – live]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has announced that Ohio senator JD Vance will be his running mate</p><p>President <strong>Joe Biden</strong> has postponed a planned trip to Texas today, where he was to speak on the 60th anniversary of the Civil Rights Act at the Lyndon B Johnson presidential library.</p><p>An NBC News interview between Biden and anchor Lester Holt will now occur at the White House, instead of in Texas, as initially planned, Associated Press reports.</p><p>There is no place in America for this kind of violence or for any violence for that matter.</p><p>An assassination attempt is contrary to everything we stand for as a nation. Everything. It’s not who we are as a nation. It’s not America, and we cannot allow this to happen.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/jul/15/donald-trump-republican-national-convention-speech-milwaukee-shooting-joe-biden-us-politics-latest-news-updates">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/jul/15/donald-trump-republican-national-convention-speech-milwaukee-shooting-joe-biden-us-politics-latest-news-updates</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/jul/15/donald-trump-republican-national-convention-speech-milwaukee-shooting-joe-biden-us-politics-latest-news-updates</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 19:07:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[FBI identifies Trump rally gunman, searches his home]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/fbi-identifies-trump-rally-gunman-122352289.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/fbi-identifies-trump-rally-gunman-122352289.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 12:23:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Suspect came within inches of killing Trump, but left few clues as to why]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/heres-know-thomas-matthew-crooks-084127479.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/heres-know-thomas-matthew-crooks-084127479.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 08:41:27 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>