<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 11:12:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 11:12:17 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Why Democrats aren’t talking much about one of their biggest issues]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris standing and speaking at a lectern flanked by flags in front of a blue backdrop that says Leaders Summit on Climate." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Al Drago/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-1313836905.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Climate change remains a major <a href="https://democrats.org/where-we-stand/party-platform/combating-the-climate-crisis-and-pursuing-environmental-justice/">platform issue for Democrats</a>, but you’d hardly know it listening to the hours of speeches at the Democratic National Convention last week in Chicago.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris, accepting her party’s nomination for president, gave a brief nod to the fundamental freedom to “live free from the pollution that fuels the climate crisis.”&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">“Many other fundamental freedoms are at stake…the freedom to breathe clean air and drink clean water and live free from the pollution that fuels the climate crisis.” —<a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> is fighting for your freedom <a href="https://t.co/q81kHmEl9A">pic.twitter.com/q81kHmEl9A</a></p>&mdash; Climate Power (@ClimatePower) <a href="https://twitter.com/ClimatePower/status/1826817665492553803?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet even after the <a href="https://www.vox.com/23969523/climate-change-cop28-paris-1-5-c-uae-2023-record-warm">hottest year on record</a> and following a wave of disasters <a href="https://www.climatecentral.org/report/hurricane-beryl">worsened by rising average temperatures</a>, climate change received just a few passing mentions from a <a href="https://x.com/sunrisemvmt/status/1826792372551754000">handful of speakers</a> on the main stage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s all in stark contrast to the last presidential campaign. In 2019, <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/9/3/20847535/cnn-climate-town-hall-2020-presidential-democrats">CNN gave seven hours of airtime</a> to Democratic presidential hopefuls just to talk about their plans to address climate change. Harris put out <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/9/4/20847387/kamala-harris-2020-climate-change-policy">her own detailed</a> plan to address environmental disparities and hold polluters accountable for their greenhouse gas emissions, drawing on her record as a prosecutor. The eventual nominee and winner Joe Biden made addressing climate change a <a href="https://www.vox.com/22242572/biden-climate-change-plan-explained">tentpole of his campaign</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/362478/joe-biden-climate-change-legacy">his time in office</a>. In particular, Biden signed the <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/7/28/23281757/whats-in-climate-bill-inflation-reduction-act">Inflation Reduction Act</a>, which he described as “the biggest step forward on climate ever.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of the reason for the minimal mentions of climate is the nature of the race itself. <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">President Biden dropped out of the running</a> just over a month ago, leaving little time for Harris and other Democrats to flesh out a distinct, detailed agenda on many issues, including climate, so there’s less to talk about.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The lack of a primary also changes Harris’s incentives. In the 2020 primary, Harris had to try to distinguish herself from a crowded field of primary candidates. Now, Harris only needs to draw a contrast with the Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump, who has <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/trump-has-big-plans-for-climate-and-energy-policy-but-can-he-implement-them/">promised to boost fossil fuel production</a> and undo support for clean energy.&nbsp;He used <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/04/24/politics/fact-check-trump-sea-levels-ocean-climate-change/index.html">made-up numbers</a> to downplay the consequences of climate change.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s another reason why Harris isn’t emphasizing climate change in the campaign: The topic is spurring fewer voters than before, and for those who are motivated by it, the choice is clear. “Very few voters say this issue is determinative to their presidential vote this year,” <a href="https://www.monmouth.edu/directory/profiles/pdmurray/">Patrick Murray</a>, who leads the Polling Institute at Monmouth University, wrote in an email. “Among this small group, they have a clear choice in the race even if the issue isn’t being discussed. Their position seems to be that Democrats have to win this election first and then we’ll push the issue.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Climate change is not the defining issue it was just a few years ago</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the last presidential election, climate change has dropped as a priority for voters in general and Democrats in particular. “We’ve seen a big dip in concerns about climate change since 2020,” Murray said.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-23-at-2.32.48 PM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,9.1513961605585,100,81.697207678883" alt="Graph of polling on climate change." title="Graph of polling on climate change." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Concern about climate change has declined in the US since the last presidential election. | Monmouth University" data-portal-copyright="Monmouth University" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Most Americans do think that climate change is a real concern, but the urgency around it has declined. According to a poll conducted in April, Monmouth University found that 46 percent of Americans thought of climate change as a “very serious” issue, down from 56 percent in 2021.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Republicans, climate change consistently <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2024/03/01/how-republicans-view-climate-change-and-energy-issues/">ranks as a low concern</a>, if it registers at all, and for Democrats, it has <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/362478/joe-biden-climate-change-legacy">slid down the list of priorities</a> as issues like the economy and immigration have climbed up. “For Democrats, there are multiple issues that compete for their highest attention. This includes things like gun violence, health care affordability, racial inequality, education, and, of course, inflation,” said <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/staff/alec-tyson/">Alec Tyson</a>, associate director at the Pew Research Center. “That was an issue that maybe was not on the public radar a couple years ago, but it is now.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Support for climate policies, such as promoting more wind and solar energy, remains high across the board, but it has declined since 2020 as well, with the sharpest drops among Republicans.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-23-at-2.36.26 PM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,28.272601750808,100,43.454796498384" alt="Graph of support for renewable energy. " title="Graph of support for renewable energy. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Americans generally favor clean energy, but support is declining. | Pew Research Center" data-portal-copyright="Pew Research Center" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">For Democrats, the key fissure that’s emerged is how quickly to shift the US economy from fossil fuels to renewable sources. Tyson said that Pew’s polling shows there’s “almost a unanimous belief” in the transition to clean energy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We asked this follow-up question, do you think we should essentially break with fossil fuels entirely and rely solely on renewables, or do you think that fossil fuel should still be part of a mix, even though we prioritize renewables?” Tyson said. “That’s really about a 50-50 divide within the Democratic Party.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That divide has manifested in Democratic policies over the past four years. The Biden administration has set a goal of <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/biden-harris-administration-releases-first-ever-blueprint-decarbonize-americas">net-zero emissions from the energy sector by 2035</a> and imposed <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24106924/epa-vehicle-emissions-carbon-pollution-climate-ev-hybrid">new vehicle pollution regulations</a> that could make more than half of new cars sold electric in the next decade. Biden also signed into law <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/7/28/23281757/whats-in-climate-bill-inflation-reduction-act">the largest investments to address climate change in US history</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the Biden White House has also presided over the country’s rise to becoming the <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24098983/biden-oil-production-climate-fossil-fuel-renewables">world’s largest oil and gas producer</a> and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/05/22/icymi-biden-to-release-1-million-barrels-of-gasoline-to-reduce-prices-at-the-pump-ahead-of-july-4/">bragged about tapping the strategic petroleum reserve</a> to keep gasoline prices low.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These policies didn’t yield many dividends for Biden among voters, with <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/27/climate/biden-climate-campaign.html">few who are even aware</a> of legislation like the Inflation Reduction Act and its provisions to deploy wind turbines, solar panels, and electric vehicle charging stations. Even <a href="https://www.latimes.com/politics/story/2024-05-07/biden-climate-bill-young-voters">young voters</a>, who typically rank climate change as a higher-tier concern, didn’t give much credit to Biden’s environmental bona fides before he dropped out. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So for the Democrats onstage at the convention, there wasn’t much upside to talking about global warming. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Kamala’s California crew is coming</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That said, there’s more to a political convention than the main stage during primetime. Aaron McCall, the federal advocacy coordinator at California Environmental Voters, said that climate change was still a major topic in the side rooms dedicated to discussing issues like LGBTQ rights, vulnerable populations, and economics. In addition, climate change and the energy transition are critical elements in other high-priority issues for Democrats: High gasoline prices <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/inflation-cpi-consumer-price-index-march-2024/">contribute to inflation</a>, more extreme natural disasters are <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/housing-market-2023:-natural-disasters-will-make-affordability-crisis-even-more-dire">raising housing costs</a>, the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/jobs-us-energy-grew-38-2022-led-by-work-clean-energy-2023-06-28/">clean energy sector is driving job growth</a>, and so on.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“In all of the caucus meetings I went to, climate comes up,” McCall said from the convention. “Because those communities are the frontline communities, and they&#8217;re being impacted.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The DNC also provided some hints as to who would join Harris’s team or have her ear if she moves into the White House next year. As a former attorney general in California, Harris has a deep bench of allies who have worked on climate policies. California in recent years has passed laws demanding <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23916295/california-climate-change-greenhouse-emissions-disclosure-risk-business-newsom">companies publish their greenhouse gas emissions</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/23320166/california-gasoline-ban-electric-vehicle-car-diesel-climate">banning the sale of new gasoline- and diesel-powered cars and trucks by 2035</a>. Harris herself oversaw an <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-exxon-global-warming-20160120-story.html">investigation into Exxon Mobil’s statements</a> about the oil company’s contributions to climate change. These personnel will shape her policies. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There is a large California presence — Gov. Newsom, Lt. Gov. Kounalakis, Sen. Padilla,” McCall said. “California activists and organizational leaders, as we&#8217;re coming to talk about Kamala Harris, our next president, we&#8217;re also talking about the priorities and the issues that we care about, especially climate.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How much will climate change matter in the runup to the election? Given the polls, it’s unlikely to alter anyone’s choice of candidate, though it could convince a few more people to get to the ballot box. “Within the Democratic coalition, it has more potential to operate as a turnout issue,” Tyson said. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But since the outcome of the election could put the <a href="https://www.wri.org/insights/interactive-chart-shows-changes-worlds-top-10-emitters">world’s second-largest greenhouse gas emitter</a> on a radically different course, it definitely matters for the climate.&nbsp;</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/368706/kamala-harris-dnc-climate-change-policy-poll</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/368706/kamala-harris-dnc-climate-change-policy-poll</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Umair Irfan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UN urges calm after Israel and Hezbollah trade strikes]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UN says Sunday's major cross-border attacks were a threat to regional security and stability.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cr40dz5524qo</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cr40dz5524qo</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 11:01:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[French police have arrested the founder of Telegram. What happens next could change the course of big tech - The Conversation France]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNc2kxLWx1T1pXWmw1OWJmb2NacVdYdjNYTFRqOUlFSzd6dDgyVXd3ejZDNFA4cXFrRlo0UDV4Q0U5N1RLaEZSYUFCZ1dIS0swbmZBWFctM3dyWXlBVVMzQXVYLXJ2R3A5NkxIcWJadGt1Vk5HTFBoZnU1ZUJJdXVXQkE2VE03M25VZjdFblZsSEY0azdyczZDQXFvZFk2X2Z4UEMtLWJNOHFlOVBJdVplU25wbmxxTVphUmZha1dmejJfekNkZkZQc0RUMElhR3pjOTVfMm9PVQ?oc=5" target="_blank">French police have arrested the founder of Telegram. What happens next could change the course of big tech</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Conversation France</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxNbURxYXdWdEtLTkZKLWhRWjl3Sl9Lc2tmcXlQYWFEaE15bG4waTdPeDkwSENKRkI0bVR3NFNoSk9JdjhKbnlJcUVTQzZ1YmNrcDdZbU9FUzdmb3YtdzN2UGFUdlBFWWY5VHBHRVVUMlcxRGZVdmpmcG9JYWE0YTlJUVlBalVQeWo3TnVIR3RjS3I?oc=5" target="_blank">Telegram Becomes Free Speech Flashpoint After Founder’s Arrest</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxOM1dFMDEtb0R2enhiYlVkMU9lZV8wem1wcTE4WXU2OXNIc2VlZ3hHWjRTYWdRVkdJd3d1ZzdldjRwanI0Y1BDZGtzai1NZkhxVWJXMGNOdUZwTENHaVk3UVVlY2RCVTd1OFU1Q1FvcnI0QUcyOVpWVWFqQ1lUNURwX2x4OUw4UWZsa2FqcHl5MWg3YkFrZ1MybkdPdnltTnAxYko4b0VyeGNvcnM1eGZOWHVJR1MxME5ja2ZqRXBvdngyQjI5eXVSSjdnemxlb1pBS1ktazRXcEtUZ1ZOWWxwRThnQXhkTTlnZmRMZVg4MlptOTh4bS1OSmpzM3ZnOUxX0gGGAkFVX3lxTFBQNGtfbEx0MkFKVC1lcjRPaWlndWdTRUYwZjZOS2xLZGtfRlJ5TTlGek81WHhBVU1abTRtLW5JYlNBWjFib3hIVDNfRzNzenh1WU9PRDNnWFVPbWpKM2JjYkZRenJpUk50SHRJbm9iXzhvM2JWSzRpeHVmS0RHQTVqdmZDN3hnY3ZsMTNzZWNXck8tR2VFZk01M1J5ZS1yTXRJODNuU3pJVTNWdEFuVWFWNVRmZV9Raml0YWJOWUlFaEV1cXJEN3hMRUZlU1NiNDVRQW1QdWs2NFZNbmRiMkNubXlfa182SEd3M1FEdFgwZVZXQkpwblRuZ3ctMjF3aHpYRkVBTXc?oc=5" target="_blank">Pavel Durov's controversial life: From 'Russian Zuckerberg' to 'father of 100+ kids', now arrested in Fra</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Times of India</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxPTW44M3BXT29qemkxZlMzRWxTTlVaelZmVVFreFBPVE83RFlSRjVNV0NXb0F1WW5ORE1ldUh3dGNlQUo5SjFmaXVKUUg1XzNhLWtHaWNuT3F1aFZaNEdHLUZxMzVXamdGMG9vbDV2YWFVUVcyMUdGeXBPdUNzNW5menM5SHl5ODFpVW9scFZncGJVdnNUN3pLNVg3dEx4WDB3SlpBNXFjTDN0Nk9sRjVPc0hRcEduTWlHWjZOZVF0MNIBxAFBVV95cUxQYXBLZTdwaDg0WnViZGo5OHZkS3BUUFNZZ2dvamt1LVNPeXVmcXVJemQ0Ym1Vc2pvM1VDNWFhazAwelZFcGFwYzN0M0JBcF9HVnNBa0QzbTFIS0E4MFdTTmo2VUJhWHBOUHJWcmJNM3N1Qm02djRiZG1XRGhLc09IdXQ4aXVJeEJXc093eFBDb2dNY20yS1k0bGtEdWVUVzkwUlZKZE1ZS3pXeFUxTk1zZ2l2Q0lWWWlYTUxvclY0dS1HekF1?oc=5" target="_blank">Vindman says Musk should be 'nervous' after Telegram CEO was arrested: 'Free speech absolutists weirdos'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOc0daSFJmcDJPc1k5MU5HNG1MU0lyYVU3S2lyd1lVV1UwQi1QM3QwZ3NPZlRWZUlramR6UDhBNzV1NFIwOTJ2S0w5MXkxYnFqeV9RNEF0M0laaWdoLTdWRjNfd2JadmtvQjUyUEd3SUZFLUJoazdLNkNLUmJIWHFfSzFHTG5UaHFkNWlLcW9ObmllcDdtY3U3Z2RSUlnSAaIBQVVfeXFMT1RhWTdiWVJJT2dNVHpVRjhIQ0JVVHhkQ0xFSzA4ZGo1bDNmbHZRc0k3T1NfRVo3ajhjbUJ4WkpJeE9EeDFDS3h1VXoyaFU3WThESE1UYU9lMlFkRE83di1iNmFLRVlsZlFncDdhMkt2V0FLRk4tRXhsOUl5aEtlYzlmX2laVFljN05TbmNtd0ZZLWlxU0NsU1pJSG52ZXVGdFVB?oc=5" target="_blank">Who is Telegram founder Pavel Durov — and why was he arrested?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNc2kxLWx1T1pXWmw1OWJmb2NacVdYdjNYTFRqOUlFSzd6dDgyVXd3ejZDNFA4cXFrRlo0UDV4Q0U5N1RLaEZSYUFCZ1dIS0swbmZBWFctM3dyWXlBVVMzQXVYLXJ2R3A5NkxIcWJadGt1Vk5HTFBoZnU1ZUJJdXVXQkE2VE03M25VZjdFblZsSEY0azdyczZDQXFvZFk2X2Z4UEMtLWJNOHFlOVBJdVplU25wbmxxTVphUmZha1dmejJfekNkZkZQc0RUMElhR3pjOTVfMm9PVQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNc2kxLWx1T1pXWmw1OWJmb2NacVdYdjNYTFRqOUlFSzd6dDgyVXd3ejZDNFA4cXFrRlo0UDV4Q0U5N1RLaEZSYUFCZ1dIS0swbmZBWFctM3dyWXlBVVMzQXVYLXJ2R3A5NkxIcWJadGt1Vk5HTFBoZnU1ZUJJdXVXQkE2VE03M25VZjdFblZsSEY0azdyczZDQXFvZFk2X2Z4UEMtLWJNOHFlOVBJdVplU25wbmxxTVphUmZha1dmejJfekNkZkZQc0RUMElhR3pjOTVfMm9PVQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 05:59:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Judge Cannon tossing Trump’s case raises risk for acting prosecutors - The Washington Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxNTGxEY2lDWEh0TzhoX0ZSc3kwM0JLeS1ycUJmZmp6TE9ObVl0MWFNUlhsZVZuSGg4QkR3dmp6ZWRKaV9VdXFCeEVobnlFbW1qMHNuaExLbXdhMlBwdzJrTW8wRHUyaFFNUWRGd201OS1pbXZ4NEdESlI4SjZTWUtTczZrY0xwZ1JBRlB5SlRkRktPU2p4TEdVSGJ2WkU?oc=5" target="_blank">Judge Cannon tossing Trump’s case raises risk for acting prosecutors</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2lEdWJHYkRCRWZJZFRxSW9MdjR5Z0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxNTGxEY2lDWEh0TzhoX0ZSc3kwM0JLeS1ycUJmZmp6TE9ObVl0MWFNUlhsZVZuSGg4QkR3dmp6ZWRKaV9VdXFCeEVobnlFbW1qMHNuaExLbXdhMlBwdzJrTW8wRHUyaFFNUWRGd201OS1pbXZ4NEdESlI4SjZTWUtTczZrY0xwZ1JBRlB5SlRkRktPU2p4TEdVSGJ2WkU?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxNTGxEY2lDWEh0TzhoX0ZSc3kwM0JLeS1ycUJmZmp6TE9ObVl0MWFNUlhsZVZuSGg4QkR3dmp6ZWRKaV9VdXFCeEVobnlFbW1qMHNuaExLbXdhMlBwdzJrTW8wRHUyaFFNUWRGd201OS1pbXZ4NEdESlI4SjZTWUtTczZrY0xwZ1JBRlB5SlRkRktPU2p4TEdVSGJ2WkU?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 10:51:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Families flee after new Israeli evacuation orders in Gaza as ceasefire hopes dim - Reuters]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxNZFBKUzRSakx2YlRSOWNJdng4TVRRUnlrQTRqUU9HaG0zbV90TldGa2xUakNqbjFhbFQzbnpXWVJlRUNuRGdDQ1lSam1JM280Qlg4ZFhCRVFqemdVSzNKYmJkTlN3RXJkcUFkVVJINElGTlF4LTRMdDNFOWttcnBJVEpkTjF6QXYzLVlXU0JsQzltRkxaaVZscVBaNW14bWFvamk0MjNvY0RxUXljbGw5QVVNcUhsbGFJY2NFMWZHam42OU5BNXRZ?oc=5" target="_blank">Families flee after new Israeli evacuation orders in Gaza as ceasefire hopes dim</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxPN0szeXFMZmIwZFhnS0dtb0Y3eXI5U3FqUzloVW8tc3dSaWdaN2J6R2JJWTNGb2wwOEJBWVEzMlZGbkNqenhockNKczVmUWt2ZkFYYk9Ta1NFOU1hSjN4TW9nNHUyb3c3ank0NkE0cjNNNjB5REN1cWdhVWZQVXNza0RuVGJ6Y291U2hraE04bFZFY3VTdTVfY0RXUm5xV2g3NmpzZFVlalNhYWVMVndHWtIBtgFBVV95cUxNOGZjU2VlVFpJMzBvSjdEekcyQWxaSkRvMjhwZTFDdDZhaklVa0x6eEtIT210TTBlc1FxN0JHekVhWlhKcVZDSThpRlR1cExIU1B6QkJvemtTcmdHNXh6R1gxb2VPdlJ5cnJZOC1wODFSUERvYk1ubjZjRzdpVXlqRFZYR0pLbktVUkpGdndlLUp5cmlBdVlSNzJjVWZPNzktQnZPclRLdWRDVFk5azVSQURkeWZHUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel orders evacuation in Deir el-Balah, patients flee Al-Aqsa Hospital</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Al Jazeera English</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNN2FROU5fSE5HNEhjbnIxNEVSTTEzNXFOSzFJb2xwVEFOdE9NMnFDZi1wYkl2QkdOMk01SmFDNUVpZUw4ODR5ODQ5M01VN3lyVXBVM3B6TzMwbEVCSU91VzllUUwyalNYM1NKaVktX0FVT2w0QTFwU3I1MVZtVC1jdER4eDFWcW9KYktXTkZkNUZ5Z2dhY3VFWkNCTVRWbWNDQ28tZFdXZ182OEk?oc=5" target="_blank">Israeli evacuation orders cram Palestinians into shrinking 'humanitarian zone' where food is scarce</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxNSG9RNDhUci14VktyT1JldU5SckFFNXpHUDZyTU4tZlROUmI0aTFTcXF3VUVIMk81WTdMQXlpU0VYX0lPTkNWcjNQZkx3Z1JyNTNpTF9Id01TUlV6UUZaZkpMWkF6TzlNUVM0VVZ3UzUzTS01TWZTaWprRlZlQUZQeDFSdmdoUmN0UXZuNXFvWUJjVGtCdldz0gFWQVVfeXFMUEowcFRRVjRXdWFpbTIwV1lfeXNyQktXUUswdy1QWlNoLUVWM3RfbVVFVElfd2hXUVI3UGktdjZ0bVF5VjZmaGxMYTd4UG9MSm0xRklOeHc?oc=5" target="_blank">Gaza’s 2.2 million people are confined to a humanitarian area smaller than Manhattan</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxQMlpsXzdhTFd0bWszRzU0WF85ZTF1VmZ3U3J0eVRVSnJaUzFMMDF1QTNrX3VWNWU0UEZ1YzZSVUVXX0xaWU40SzYtdmRYRWRUQ1hvVEJuZFhhVXZvX1d2M2NXWDBXNVhVY0Y1cGRJOEpmMlIyY00weGd0U1RIeG5adXF0Wko3Wm8zZlpj?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel Orders New Evacuations, Forcing Gazans to Flee Again</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxNZFBKUzRSakx2YlRSOWNJdng4TVRRUnlrQTRqUU9HaG0zbV90TldGa2xUakNqbjFhbFQzbnpXWVJlRUNuRGdDQ1lSam1JM280Qlg4ZFhCRVFqemdVSzNKYmJkTlN3RXJkcUFkVVJINElGTlF4LTRMdDNFOWttcnBJVEpkTjF6QXYzLVlXU0JsQzltRkxaaVZscVBaNW14bWFvamk0MjNvY0RxUXljbGw5QVVNcUhsbGFJY2NFMWZHam42OU5BNXRZ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxNZFBKUzRSakx2YlRSOWNJdng4TVRRUnlrQTRqUU9HaG0zbV90TldGa2xUakNqbjFhbFQzbnpXWVJlRUNuRGdDQ1lSam1JM280Qlg4ZFhCRVFqemdVSzNKYmJkTlN3RXJkcUFkVVJINElGTlF4LTRMdDNFOWttcnBJVEpkTjF6QXYzLVlXU0JsQzltRkxaaVZscVBaNW14bWFvamk0MjNvY0RxUXljbGw5QVVNcUhsbGFJY2NFMWZHam42OU5BNXRZ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 09:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oil prices to remain elevated as Middle East tensions threaten a wider conflict, CBA analyst warns - CNBC]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNT05uSXk2cEVLZGFDendQOFpCb3lnWVJ6aTJEWnpHal9KQXJnSXZHaVZMRFdOeVZIRjF2Q2Rqd25qc3N5TGoySEZEX2VmX1I4a05IRjk5d0M4a1NDaVVVYXdmYm9FR0hWZ3FUV0g3bHNOeEhCM3NMY0RIQjczYXRwYk5keWF0NG9DZ2dwNVlPYXBKdHpyT3J3TG1jODNnc0xmcFRDX0JkenZna3BJMmfSAbMBQVVfeXFMUDJCS0Y1RFpEYzJsWG1oTllYUk5GYy1lQ3Y3ZHBkRHRUVGtPLU4ySUVTd1lVOUgwam40Sl9vSjZmb2tUNGlra1Jabi1LUTIxTkNoLUNiSHkwemxnSGxSM050Q25Sa0FBbV83UFN2enRoU3dxQnZiM1ltNV9ObEM1anUyaUg2SXVDVEpJd1R1ckdEMHpoZUdnUElkcTJlQWlTQmhTaXJVUFRzcW1xQVNzQjR2NkU?oc=5" target="_blank">Oil prices to remain elevated as Middle East tensions threaten a wider conflict, CBA analyst warns</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2loN1pTYURCR29LMGZuS19KMUtTZ0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNT05uSXk2cEVLZGFDendQOFpCb3lnWVJ6aTJEWnpHal9KQXJnSXZHaVZMRFdOeVZIRjF2Q2Rqd25qc3N5TGoySEZEX2VmX1I4a05IRjk5d0M4a1NDaVVVYXdmYm9FR0hWZ3FUV0g3bHNOeEhCM3NMY0RIQjczYXRwYk5keWF0NG9DZ2dwNVlPYXBKdHpyT3J3TG1jODNnc0xmcFRDX0JkenZna3BJMmfSAbMBQVVfeXFMUDJCS0Y1RFpEYzJsWG1oTllYUk5GYy1lQ3Y3ZHBkRHRUVGtPLU4ySUVTd1lVOUgwam40Sl9vSjZmb2tUNGlra1Jabi1LUTIxTkNoLUNiSHkwemxnSGxSM050Q25Sa0FBbV83UFN2enRoU3dxQnZiM1ltNV9ObEM1anUyaUg2SXVDVEpJd1R1ckdEMHpoZUdnUElkcTJlQWlTQmhTaXJVUFRzcW1xQVNzQjR2NkU?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNT05uSXk2cEVLZGFDendQOFpCb3lnWVJ6aTJEWnpHal9KQXJnSXZHaVZMRFdOeVZIRjF2Q2Rqd25qc3N5TGoySEZEX2VmX1I4a05IRjk5d0M4a1NDaVVVYXdmYm9FR0hWZ3FUV0g3bHNOeEhCM3NMY0RIQjczYXRwYk5keWF0NG9DZ2dwNVlPYXBKdHpyT3J3TG1jODNnc0xmcFRDX0JkenZna3BJMmfSAbMBQVVfeXFMUDJCS0Y1RFpEYzJsWG1oTllYUk5GYy1lQ3Y3ZHBkRHRUVGtPLU4ySUVTd1lVOUgwam40Sl9vSjZmb2tUNGlra1Jabi1LUTIxTkNoLUNiSHkwemxnSGxSM050Q25Sa0FBbV83UFN2enRoU3dxQnZiM1ltNV9ObEM1anUyaUg2SXVDVEpJd1R1ckdEMHpoZUdnUElkcTJlQWlTQmhTaXJVUFRzcW1xQVNzQjR2NkU?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 02:58:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar reportedly hiding in plain sight 'dressed as a woman']]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1f1kxdy/yahya_sinwar_reportedly_hiding_in_plain_sight/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/ulsC3SpGe8lPpPiTATSfgSob5Nq_S7img2rf-x-6yTY.jpg?width=320&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=23993722041b74ce25ec41b6d2b03bee95f1bcda" alt="Yahya Sinwar reportedly hiding in plain sight 'dressed as a woman'" title="Yahya Sinwar reportedly hiding in plain sight 'dressed as a woman'" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/stgrdr"> /u/stgrdr </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.ynetnews.com/article/byd0y0fsa">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1f1kxdy/yahya_sinwar_reportedly_hiding_in_plain_sight/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1f1kxdy/yahya_sinwar_reportedly_hiding_in_plain_sight/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1f1kxdy/yahya_sinwar_reportedly_hiding_in_plain_sight/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/stgrdr]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 10:32:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jim Chalmers calls Peter Dutton ‘most divisive leader’ in modern Australian history]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Treasurer uses John Curtin Oration to accuse opposition leader of deliberately stoking culture wars and division </p><ul><li><strong>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/article/2024/aug/14/breaking-news-alerts-australia-guardian-email-newsletter?CMP=cvau_sfl">breaking news email</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></strong></li></ul><p>The treasurer has unleashed a stinging attack on the opposition leader, calling Peter Dutton “the most divisive leader of a major political party in Australia’s modern history”, as he defended the Labor government’s economic performance since coming to office.</p><p>Delivering the annual John Curtin Oration in Melbourne, which marks the anniversary of Curtin’s Labor government’s 1943 landslide election victory, Jim Chalmers accused the opposition leader of starting culture wars, dog whistling and dividing Australians “deliberately, almost pathologically”.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/aug/26/jim-chalmers-calls-peter-dutton-most-divisive-leader-in-modern-australian-history">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/aug/26/jim-chalmers-calls-peter-dutton-most-divisive-leader-in-modern-australian-history</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/aug/26/jim-chalmers-calls-peter-dutton-most-divisive-leader-in-modern-australian-history</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 10:58:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Morning Bid: Rate-cut hopes meet Mid-East risks]]></title><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/morning-bid-rate-cut-hopes-100211982.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://finance.yahoo.com/news/morning-bid-rate-cut-hopes-100211982.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 10:02:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Dangerous Precedent’ Rattles Chile’s Renewable Energy Market]]></title><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/dangerous-precedent-rattles-chile-renewable-100000061.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://finance.yahoo.com/news/dangerous-precedent-rattles-chile-renewable-100000061.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rep. John Curtis leads Caroline Gleich by more than 30 percentage points in new Senate poll]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/rep-john-curtis-leads-caroline-012921394.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/rep-john-curtis-leads-caroline-012921394.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 01:29:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine's president says Russian overnight attack involved over 100 missiles and about 100 drones]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/russia-unleashes-massive-drone-missile-065501799.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/russia-unleashes-massive-drone-missile-065501799.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 06:55:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Old US Bradleys becoming 'legend' in Ukraine shows what the country can do when it gets enough of the weapons it needs]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/old-us-bradleys-becoming-legend-091801778.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/old-us-bradleys-becoming-legend-091801778.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 09:18:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump Picked Worst Possible Spot For New Border Wall Stunt]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/trump-picked-worst-possible-spot-061822289.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/trump-picked-worst-possible-spot-061822289.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 06:18:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Drone described by Ukraine as ‘a completely new class of weapon’ hits Russia for the first time]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/ukraine-reveals-attack-drone-hit-160003727.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/ukraine-reveals-attack-drone-hit-160003727.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 16:00:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Evacuees queue to receive aid in Kursk amid incursion by Ukraine]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/evacuees-queue-receive-aid-kursk-031603164.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/evacuees-queue-receive-aid-kursk-031603164.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 03:16:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Syrian president says efforts to restore ties with Turkey have yielded no results]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/syrian-president-says-efforts-restore-142224697.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/syrian-president-says-efforts-restore-142224697.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 14:22:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[China slams US for adding firms to export control list, vows action]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/china-slams-us-adding-firms-044715890.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/china-slams-us-adding-firms-044715890.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 04:47:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>