<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 03:22:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 03:22:06 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[2024 election violence is already happening]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="A protester flying a Trump flag and an upside down American flag on the lawn far in front of the Capitol Building." data-caption="Pro-Trump protesters gather in front of the US Capitol Building on January 6, 2021, in Washington, DC. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-1230734387.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Pro-Trump protesters gather in front of the US Capitol Building on January 6, 2021, in Washington, DC. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Political violence has reached <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-politics-violence/">alarming levels </a>in the US over the last few years.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The January 6, 2021, insurrection at the US Capitol, the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/david-depape-nancy-pelosi-husband-paul-attacked-454cbde088fcae22a356f1f8dd0e9eba">attack on former Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s husband</a>, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/371981/trump-shooting-ryan-wesley-routh-golf-club">multiple assassination attempts</a> against former President Donald Trump are all examples of America’s increasingly polarized and perilous environment. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, the 2024 election could cause another flare-up, especially if Trump loses. Discussion of violence among right-wing extremists has already <a href="https://globalextremism.org/post/online-chatter-election-contains-signs-for-violence/">spiked online</a>, and unlike Vice President Kamala Harris, Trump has refused to say that he would concede.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The polls show a <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/national/">tight race</a> between Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, suggesting that this time, as in 2020, the results may be decided by narrow margins in a few battleground states. Trump has been priming Republican voters to reject the results if he comes up short, making <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/29/politics/trump-voter-fraud-claims-pennsylvania/index.html">unsubstantiated claims about voter fraud in Pennsylvania</a> and <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-noncitizen-voter-fraud-fact-check/">noncitizens voting on a widespread basis</a>. Billionaire Trump supporter Elon Musk has also set up a platform on his social media site X, formerly known as Twitter, for users to &#8220;<a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/31/nx-s1-5165523/voting-election-conspiracy-theories-social-media">share potential incidents of voter fraud or irregularities</a> you see while voting in the 2024 election.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those tactics seem to be working. If Trump loses, about a quarter of Republicans said they think he should do whatever it takes to ensure he becomes president anyway, according to a <a href="https://www.prri.org/research/one-leader-under-god-the-connection-between-authoritarianism-and-christian-nationalism-in-america/?preview=true">September PRRI poll</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That may include resorting to violence. Among Republicans who don’t believe Biden’s win in 2020 was legitimate, almost one-third said in an <a href="https://hub.jhu.edu/2024/08/07/snf-agora-poll-july-2024/">August poll</a> by the SNF Agora Institute at Johns Hopkins University that they expected “a lot” or “a great deal” of political violence after the November election. More <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/10/30/voters-fear-violence-trump-loss/">recent polls</a> have found similar results, including an October <a href="https://apnorc.org/projects/many-voters-are-worried-about-the-electoral-process-and-transition-of-power/">AP-NORC poll</a> that found 27 percent of Republicans, and 42 percent of voters overall, “extremely” or “very” worried about post-election violence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this has put law enforcement and national security officials on high alert about political violence in the days before and after the election. Earlier this month, a joint Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and FBI intelligence <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/election-violence-domestic-extremists-fbi-dhs-bulletin/">bulletin</a> said that domestic extremists &#8220;pose a threat of violence to a range of targets directly and indirectly associated with elections through at least the presidential inauguration&#8221; on January 20.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What kind of political violence might break out?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some incidents of political violence have already been recorded in the runup to Election Day. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ballots in mailboxes and drop boxes in <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-2020-marty-walsh-boston-elections-crime-3d9dd32292187df91d73cb153b9c0a73">Massachusetts,</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/ballots-damaged-usps-mailbox-fire-phoenix-rcna177067">Arizona</a>, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/ballot-boxes-set-fire-portland-vancouver-rcna177611">Washington, and Oregon</a> have been damaged in suspected arson. DHS warned this might happen, based on its monitoring of comments made online in domestic violent extremist circles. In a series of <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/national-security/4957125-domestic-violent-extremists-2024-election/">security bulletins</a> in the last few months, the agency noted, “Some threat actors may perceive ballot drop boxes as ‘soft targets’ because they are more accessible” and that some of these actors had discussed a variety of methods for damaging them. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A man was also <a href="https://www.azcentral.com/story/news/local/tempe/2024/10/29/grand-jury-indicts-man-accused-of-shooting-at-democratic-party-office/75924391007/">indicted on terrorism and gun charges</a> for allegedly shooting at the Democratic National Committee’s offices in Phoenix on three occasions since September.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Things might only get worse from here. Deputy Attorney General Lisa Monaco has <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/u-s-news-decision-points/articles/2024-09-24/deputy-ag-u-s-faces-unprecedented-level-of-political-threats">warned</a> that the US is “facing an unprecedented level of, and increase in, threats of violence against public officials.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to the <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/national-security/4957125-domestic-violent-extremists-2024-election/">DHS bulletins</a>, there is a “heightened risk” that domestic violent extremists could “attempt to initiate civil war.” That kind of chatter has become increasingly common in online spaces <a href="https://globalextremism.org/post/online-chatter-election-contains-signs-for-violence/">frequented by right-wing extremist groups</a>. That said, the DHS noted that the prosecutions of those involved in the January 6 insurrection and hesitation about potential false flag operations designed to entrap them could serve as deterrents.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Law enforcement officials across the country are bracing for the possibility of escalation, particularly in Democratic population centers. For instance, Detroit’s election headquarters have reportedly been reinforced with bulletproof glass and will be protected by armed guards after Trump supporters tried to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/legal/michigan-still-counting-votes-angry-poll-watchers-barred-in-detroit-trump-sues-idUSKBN27K2AL/">interrupt ballot counting</a> by chanting “Stop the count” and banging on the windows in 2020. Philadelphia election staff will <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-swing-states-officials-brace-conspiracy-theories-violence-2024-10-30/?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;utm_campaign=Daily-Briefing&amp;utm_term=103024&amp;user_email=38572e447ae2b3a943d6423dd3d8ad89c2e154a588929a92468b7914f3f4e88f&amp;lctg=66464e6f30f1bc62c305003b">count ballots in a warehouse</a> encircled by a fence with barbed wire, miles from the downtown area where protesters gathered in 2020.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, however, these preparations might not be enough to quell domestic violent extremist activity when Republican leaders are encouraging skepticism about the integrity of the election and are reportedly <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/speaker-johnson-appears-to-confirm-a-secret-election-plan-with-trump">making secret plans</a> to assure a second Trump term. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Being aware of the potential for violence and damage to the institutions we rely upon is important,” retired Gen. Joseph Votel, an executive board member of the Center for Ethics and the Rule of Law at the University of Pennsylvania, said in a statement. “But it is insufficient in the face of legislative acts that are open to broad interpretation, strong political rhetoric that dominates the public information space, and imperfect individuals acting in accordance with their oaths.”</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/381520/2024-election-violence-trump-loses-extremism-civil-war</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/381520/2024-election-violence-trump-loses-extremism-civil-war</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Narea]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:01:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Republicans are serious about cutting people’s health care]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Johnson stands behind and to the left of Trump as he speaks into a microphone." data-caption="House Speaker Mike Johnson said Republicans would pursue “massive” health care reform if Donald Trump is elected president in 2024. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2148449297.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>House Speaker Mike Johnson said Republicans would pursue “massive” health care reform if Donald Trump is elected president in 2024. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re confused, it’s not an accident.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans are trying to have it both ways on <a href="https://www.vox.com/health-care">health care</a> during the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections">2024 campaign</a>. They boast that they want to deregulate insurance and massively cut government spending, yet they also claim that they would never do anything to endanger people’s coverage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That two-step keeps getting them into trouble. House Speaker Mike Johnson was recently <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/morning-joe/watch/house-speaker-mike-johnson-criticizes-obamacare-and-promises-massive-reform-if-trump-wins-223060037976">caught on a tape</a> promising to take “a blow torch to the regulatory state.” Donald Trump, Johnson said, would want to “go big” in his second term because he can’t run for a third one, the speaker told a group of Republican voters in Pennsylvania. And health care, Johnson said, would be “a big part” of the GOP’s agenda.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One attendee directly asked Johnson: No Obamacare? “No Obamacare,” Johnson said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The ACA is so deeply ingrained, we need massive reform to make this work. We’ve got a lot of ideas,” the House speaker added. He wasn’t more specific than that.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kamala Harris’s campaign quickly <a href="https://x.com/KamalaHQ/status/1851604970992263224">flagged</a> Johnson’s comments, and Republicans backtracked. The <a href="https://www.vox.com/donald-trump">Donald Trump</a> campaign <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/trump-campaign-distances-house-speakers-plan-massive-reform/story?id=115313086">said</a> that was “not President Trump’s policy position” and Trump tried to distance himself further in a social media post.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Lyin’ Kamala is giving a News Conference now, saying that I want to end the Affordable Care Act. I never mentioned doing that, never even thought about such a thing. She also said I want to end Social Security. Likewise, never mentioned it, or thought of it. She is the one that…</p>&mdash; Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1852033066157441249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 31, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/no-promise-johnson-blasts-dem-accusations-he-vowed-end-obamacare-dishonest">insisted</a> he had not actually promised to repeal Obamacare by emphasizing his comment that the 2010 law was “ingrained” while ignoring his subsequent promise of “massive reform.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump himself has alluded to having only “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/12/opinion/trump-harris-concepts-obamacare.html">concepts of a plan</a>” for American health care. That has left other Republicans to fill in the gaps and the party’s specific proposals remain poorly defined. But if there are a lot of details still to be filled in, the theme of the GOP’s health care agenda is clear: cuts. Cutting regulations. Cutting spending.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson’s comments were not an isolated incident. Just last month, Trump’s vice presidential nominee, JD Vance, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/372635/trump-health-care-plan-vance-preexisting-conditions">hinted</a> at “a deregulatory agenda so that people can pick a health care plan that fits them.” If you actually parse his words about health insurance risk pools, it would be a return to a world where people could be charged more for coverage if they have preexisting medical conditions, the world before Obamacare.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was the same promise Johnson was making. That is the reality: Should they win control of the White House and Congress this election, Republicans will attempt to cut people’s health care.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Republicans still want to make big health care cuts</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When Obamacare repeal <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/7/31/16055960/why-obamacare-repeal-failed">died in 2017</a>, it might have been tempting to think that a chapter had come to a close. Instead, the fight over the future of US health care had entered a new era.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Make no mistake: Republican leaders still want to slash health care spending and unwind health insurance regulations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And Trump, whatever he might say, has proven before to be malleable to conventional conservative health policy. His people continue to put health care in the crosshairs, sometimes in ways that may not be as obvious.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Elon Musk, who sometimes appears to be campaigning to be <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/politics/elon-musk-eyes-a-shadow-presidency/">shadow president</a> of the United States, has <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/29/elon-musk-2-trillion-budget-cuts-trump-election/">pledged</a> to cut $2 trillion from the federal government’s $6.8 trillion budget. He has <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/the-reidout/reidout-blog/elon-musk-trump-hardship-austerity-taxes-rcna177732">acknowledged</a> that the cuts would result in “temporary” hardship, but insisted they would be to the long-term benefit of the country.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.nationalpriorities.org/budget-basics/federal-budget-101/spending/">About $1 in every $5</a> in the federal budget goes to health care. Barring a severe cut to the US military (unlikely), such a plan would require massive cuts to the health care programs. Trump has often said he will protect Medicare, which covers seniors, but he has in the past endorsed enormous cuts to Medicaid, the program for low-income people that insures <a href="https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/medicaid-and-chip-monthly-enrollment/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">73 million Americans</a>, as part of the 2017 ACA repeal-and-replace bills.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The main Republican bill to repeal and replace the ACA that nearly passed in 2017 was in fact <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/9/15579654/medicaid-cuts-ahca">as much about making massive Medicaid cuts</a> by capping the program’s funding as it was about loosening health insurance regulations or repealing the individual mandate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans could try to pass another Obamacare repeal bill with a comprehensive Medicaid overhaul. Or they could chip away at health care in incremental ways, as we saw during the first Trump term after the Obamacare repeal bill failed. Trump <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/9/8/16268572/trump-obamacare-navigators">cut funding for enrollment outreach</a> for the ACA markets while <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/8/2/17639124/trump-obamacare-short-term-insurance-plans-36-months">rolling back rules</a> for noncomprehensive plans, which resulted in <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/6/30/21275498/trump-obamacare-repeal-short-term-health-care-insurance-scam">catastrophic results for some patients</a> who didn’t know what they were signing up for.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over Trump’s four years in office, the number of people covered by the ACA <a href="https://www.kff.org/affordable-care-act/state-indicator/marketplace-enrollment/?activeTab=graph&amp;currentTimeframe=0&amp;startTimeframe=10&amp;selectedRows=%7B%22wrapups%22:%7B%22united-states%22:%7B%7D%7D%7D&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">fell</a> by more than 1 million, to 11.4 million. Since Joe Biden became president, and Democrats expanded the law’s insurance subsidies as part of the Inflation Reduction Act, the number of people covered by marketplace plans has nearly doubled to 21.4 million.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Trump takes office again, a repeat of that previous sabotage seems likely even if a bigger repeal effort fails to materialize. Republicans could cut outreach funding again. They could make subtler tweaks to the health insurance rules, such as increasing the premiums that older people can be charged compared to younger people or giving insurers more leniency in restricting benefits, networks, and other aspects of a person’s health coverage. They could make more targeted cuts to Medicaid or <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/5/12/23712447/medicaid-work-requirements-us-debt-ceiling">permit states to set up Medicaid work requirements again</a>, as they did in the first Trump term only to be <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/3/13/18263675/medicaid-work-requirements-lawsuit-donald-trump">obstructed by the courts</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Republicans can’t be honest about their health care plan</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The failure of Obamacare repeal is the reason Republicans keep insisting that their health care agenda is not what it plainly is whenever they accidentally reveal their intentions too clearly.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s easy to forget now, but Obamacare was a winning issue for Republicans at first. They <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/blogs/washington-whispers/2011/04/12/healthcare-vote-doomed-13-democrats-in-2010-elections">stormed to historic congressional wins in the 2010 midterms</a> by rallying voters against the new health care law. They then took <a href="https://time.com/4712725/ahca-house-repeal-votes-obamacare/">dozens of votes to repeal all or parts of it</a> while Barack Obama still held the veto pen. For most of its first decade, the ACA was deeply unpopular.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then Trump won the presidency and the Republicans had to deliver on their promises to repeal and replace the law. GOP leaders did get the new president on board with <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/3/15531494/american-health-care-act-explained">a pretty conservative plan</a>: It would have left the skeleton of the ACA, but pared back its rules and financial aid, while making those huge cuts to Medicaid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then something changed. As the repeal plan started to move through Congress, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/24/15685760/ahca-cbo-score-new">projections</a> of millions of Americans losing health insurance dominated news coverage, the politics of health care flipped. The law had quietly grown to cover a sizable chunk of people —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.commonwealthfund.org/publications/issue-briefs/2016/may/americans-experiences-aca-marketplace-and-medicaid-coverage">more than 25 million</a> —&nbsp;and, as importantly, it had started to <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/4708/healthcare-system.aspx#:~:text=During%20most%20of%20the%20years,it%20shouldn't%20be).">change Americans’ minds about the government’s role in providing health care</a>. “Preexisting conditions” became a loaded term, and when people understood that the GOP wanted to unwind the ACA’s health insurance rules, they <a href="https://www.vox.com/first-person/2017/5/3/15530008/health-care-preexisting-conditions-insurance">loudly objected</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Medicaid also flexed a political salience not seen before, with <a href="https://time.com/4831386/disability-advocate-protest-gop-health-care-bill/">disability advocates in particular</a> fearful of what cuts to that program would mean for them and drawing widespread coverage for their protests. Senate Republicans from states that expanded Medicaid through the health care law were ultimately responsible for stopping the repeal effort.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By the 2018 midterms, Democrats were <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/11/7/18070152/midterm-elections-2018-results-trump-obamacare-repeal">hammering Republicans over health care</a> and scoring surprising electoral wins. Today, the ACA is <a href="https://www.kff.org/interactive/kff-health-tracking-poll-the-publics-views-on-the-aca/#?response=Favorable--Unfavorable&amp;aRange=twoYear">as popular as it’s ever been</a> and US voters say they <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/poll-finding/kff-health-tracking-poll-may-2024-voters-views-of-health-policy-issues-in-context-of-presidential-campaigns/">trust Democrats more on health care</a> than the GOP.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This series of events has left Republicans in a bind. The relative success of the ACA has expanded the welfare state and influenced Americans’ perceptions of the role of government in ways that are antithetical to conservative economic thinking. They want to claw back some of those progressive wins. But they also have to be mindful of the changed politics of health care.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once in a while, particularly in “safe” conservative spaces, they slip up, admit they want to unwind the ACA, and then have to backtrack. Mike Johnson’s only mistake was being candid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, October 31, 3:45 pm ET:</strong> This story was originally published earlier on October 31 and has been updated to include Trump’s social media post about the ACA.</em></p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/health-care/381484/2024-election-donald-trump-health-care-mike-johnson-obamacare</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/health-care/381484/2024-election-donald-trump-health-care-mike-johnson-obamacare</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dylan Scott]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:45:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump really could empower RFK Jr. to wreck public health]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Trump stands and smiles onstage with his hand on Robert Kennedy’s shoulder." data-caption="Donald Trump welcomes Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to the stage at a Turning Point Action campaign rally on October 23, 2024, in Duluth, Georgia. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2180628742_f78212.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Donald Trump welcomes Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to the stage at a Turning Point Action campaign rally on October 23, 2024, in Duluth, Georgia. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">For the most part, Donald Trump has been mum on who he’d appoint to his administration if he wins.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he has made one pretty clear promise: Trump has said he’ll let <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/07/13/1187272781/rfk-jr-kennedy-conspiracy-theories-social-media-presidential-campaign">conspiracy theorist</a> and <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/08/30/rfk-jr-trump-campaign-public-health-policy-issue/">vaccine skeptic</a> Robert F. Kennedy Jr. “<a href="https://www.politico.com/video/2024/10/28/trump-says-he-would-let-rfk-jr-go-wild-on-medicines-1466853">go wild</a>” on health, food, and drug regulation. That could have massive consequences for public health and vaccine policy in America. If Kennedy were to completely get his way and deter vaccination, vaccine-preventable diseases like <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23438552/covid-vaccine-refusal-hesitancy-politics-polarization-pandemic-mandates">measles and polio could make a comeback</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kennedy, who ended his third-party presidential run to endorse Trump <a href="https://apnews.com/article/rfk-jr-trump-speech-arizona-a2638f89ddcb5de03edbe4574ca17d45">in August</a>, expects big things. He <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/10/30/2024-elections-live-coverage-updates-analysis/robert-f-kennedy-jr-trump-administration-00186227">told supporters</a> at a recent virtual event that Trump “promised” him “control of the public health agencies, which are HHS and its sub-agencies, CDC, FDA, NIH, and a few others,” as well as the Department of Agriculture. Kennedy has also <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/10/18/rfk-jr-alarms-leaders-in-health-even-many-in-gop/">said</a> he’d be “deeply involved in helping to choose the people” heading those agencies.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump transition co-chair Howard Lutnick <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/robert-f-kennedy-trump-transition-chair-vaccines-public-health.html">said Wednesday on CNN</a> that Kennedy is “not getting a job” at the Department of Health and Human Services, but Lutnick voiced complete sympathy with Kennedy’s beliefs that vaccines cause autism. “I spent two and a half hours this week with Bobby Kennedy Jr. and it was the most extraordinary thing,” Lutnick said, proceeding to say he believes in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2017/5/11/15508006/what-causes-autism-spectrum-disorder-vaccine-theory">debunked theory</a> that vaccines cause autism.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though Trump has a <a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter/366472/2024-election-donald-trump-vaccines-schools">muddled stance</a> on the Covid-19 vaccines his administration approved, he’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/9/17/9346685/republican-debate-trump-autism">long been a believer</a> that childhood vaccines cause autism. He reiterated that belief in a call seeking Kennedy’s endorsement this summer (which was recorded and posted publicly by Kennedy’s son): Trump complained that babies now get too many vaccines and then “change radically.” He added: “I’ve seen it too many times.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hard to make it clearer that Kennedy’s views would have deep sympathy at the top of Trump’s administration. In his first term, experts, scientists, and professionals remained in charge of such issues — hence the Covid vaccine development. But given the right-wing backlash against such experts that the pandemic brought, Trump’s second term could well be quite different. The risk that Kennedy would take a wrecking ball to public health regulation and especially vaccine policy is very real.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tucker Carlson, appearing at an event with Kennedy this week, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/23/health/video/the-lead-dr-paul-offit-trump-rfk-jr-vaccine-covid-government-medicine-regulations-jake-tapper">was positively gleeful</a> about that prospect. “Can you imagine if you’re at FDA or NIH and Bobby Kennedy all of a sudden” came in, Carlson said, breaking off in laughter. “I mean, they must be dying!”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">RFK probably couldn’t be confirmed by the Senate. He could exercise vast influence anyway.</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Public health leaders, including some <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/10/18/rfk-jr-alarms-leaders-in-health-even-many-in-gop/">former GOP</a> and <a href="https://x.com/SherylNYT/status/1850936124220514439?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1850936124220514439%7Ctwgr%5E7446672bcc944cad1d00fb27c5d865ea38ccea8d%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.motherjones.com%2Fpolitics%2F2024%2F10%2Ftrump-rfk-health-hhs-covid-vaccine-adams%2F">Trump appointees</a>, have been quite alarmed at the prospect of giving Kennedy sway over public health policy. Jerome Adams, who was Trump’s surgeon general in his first term, <a href="https://x.com/SherylNYT/status/1850936124220514439?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1850936124220514439%7Ctwgr%5E7446672bcc944cad1d00fb27c5d865ea38ccea8d%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.motherjones.com%2Fpolitics%2F2024%2F10%2Ftrump-rfk-health-hhs-covid-vaccine-adams%2F">said Monday</a> this “could further erode people&#8217;s willingness to get up to date with recommended vaccines” and that he was “worried” about the impact on Americans’ health.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Others have reacted with skepticism to the prospect of Kennedy getting a top agency job, pointing out that a post like HHS secretary <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/10/30/2024/senate-republicans-could-block-trump-from-putting-rfk-jr-in-the-cabinet">requires Senate confirmation,</a> a prospect that would seem unlikely even if the GOP regains control of the chamber. Sens. Susan Collins (R-ME) and Lisa Murkowski (R-AK), the two most moderate Republican senators, serve on the committee that would consider that nomination.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet there is a model for how Kennedy could serve in government and exercise vast influence despite not being Senate-confirmed. Call it the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/373479/stephen-miller-mass-deportation-camps-trump-agenda">Stephen Miller model</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Miller, an extreme anti-immigration ideologue, served as a White House senior adviser (a job that doesn’t require Senate confirmation). But he exercised vast influence at federal agencies that handled immigration policy so much that he was dubbed “<a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2018/08/29/stephen-miller-immigration-policy-white-house-trump-799199">the president of immigration</a>.” He <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2019/08/02/stephen-miller-green-card-immigration-1630406">berated</a> agency officials to carry out his preferred policies and, when he felt some Trump appointees weren’t getting the job done, he <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/04/08/opinions/stephen-miller-immigration-white-house-purge-elliot-williams/index.html">engineered their ouster</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is entirely possible that Trump could appoint Kennedy to a similar role if he wanted one. It’s far from clear whether Kennedy would prove as effective a bureaucratic operator as Miller, but he certainly matches Miller in obsessive monomania over his particular issue, having argued <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/robert-kennedy-jrs-belief-in-autism-vaccine-connection-and-its-political-peril/2014/07/16/f21c01ee-f70b-11e3-a606-946fd632f9f1_story.html">for two decades</a> that vaccines cause autism, as a writer, an activist, and then as a political candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another reason Miller had such influence is that it was believed throughout the Trump administration that he was speaking for Trump, that they had a “mind-meld” on immigration. And Trump’s comments have long made it clear he agrees with Kennedy on childhood vaccinations. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if Kennedy does not officially join the government, he could still have a major impact on policy. If accurate, his claim that he’ll be “deeply involved” in Trump’s public health appointment decisions means he could choose like-minded allies to try and overhaul public health agencies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The real question is whether Trump would stake political capital on what would surely be an intensely controversial overhaul of US vaccine policies. Despite his belief in the autism link, Trump simply didn’t choose to really do anything about it in his first term. If he were to win a second term, though, he would owe Kennedy for his support, and anti-vaccine sentiment has been rising on the right.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps the biggest mystery hanging over a potential Trump second term is just how out of control he has gotten since he left office. The Republican establishment would like to believe that, in practice, Trump will still heavily rely on them and appoint capable people rather than kooks to top posts. But perhaps Trump will feel less beholden to that establishment than ever and more willing to reward his extreme supporters. That’s certainly what Kennedy is betting on.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/381470/trump-rfk-cabinet-hhs-vaccines-health</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/381470/trump-rfk-cabinet-hhs-vaccines-health</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Prokop]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Is Google a bigger threat to democracy than Trump? A debate.]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="A sign with the Google logo on it. " data-caption="Signage at the the Google headquarters in Mountain View, California, on October 10, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2180164057.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Signage at the the Google headquarters in Mountain View, California, on October 10, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden era has witnessed a revolution in the Democratic Party’s approach to policing large corporations. Under the leadership of chair Lina Khan, the Federal Trade Commission has grown markedly <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2024-10-09/lina-khan-on-a-second-ftc-term-ai-price-gouging-data-privacy">more aggressive in blocking mergers</a> and <a href="https://www.economicliberties.us/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/FTC-Accomplishments.pdf">cracking down on big business’s exploitative practices</a>. This has earned Khan’s FTC <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/mar/09/lina-khan-federal-trade-commission-antitrust-monopolies">plaudits</a> from critics of corporate power. But Khan’s policies have also attracted the indignation of the Democratic Party’s <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/opinion/msnbc-opinion/kamala-harris-linkedin-reid-hoffman-ftc-chair-lina-khan-rcna163897">supporters in Silicon Valley,</a> as well as concerns from <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2023/12/lina-khans-rough-year-running-the-federal-trade-commission.html">some longtime civil servants at the FTC</a>, who question the strategic and substantive wisdom of Khan’s approach to antitrust enforcement. Both these factions are now bitterly fighting for presidential nominee Kamala Harris’s favor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a cover story for Harper’s Magazine this month, Barry Lynn makes the case for the “<a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2024/10/the-antitrust-revolution-big-tech-barry-c-lynn/">antitrust revolution</a>.” Lynn is the intellectual godfather of the modern antimonopoly movement. Once a business reporter, he has spent the better part of two decades chronicling the evils of corporate concentration. His antimonopoly think tank, the <a href="https://www.openmarketsinstitute.org/">Open Markets Institute</a>, employed Khan as its legal director before she entered government.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In his Harper’s essay, Lynn frames the fight against Big Tech in apocalyptic terms. He argues that the power of Google and Amazon today is analogous to that of absolute monarchs in the 17th century — and that such corporate titans pose an even more pressing threat to American democracy than Donald Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I sympathize with many of Lynn’s concerns and think that Khan’s FTC has done a lot of good. But I also found parts of Lynn’s Harper’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/379738/progressive-democrats-lina-khan-corporate-power-antimonopoly" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/politics/379738/progressive-democrats-lina-khan-corporate-power-antimonopoly">piece hyperbolic and unconvincing</a>. So I spoke with him about my objections, the impact of Big Tech on journalism and publishing, the political power of small business, whether monopolies have made America more racist, and other topics. Our conversation has been edited for concision and clarity. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>In your Harper’s essay, you suggested t</strong><strong>hat Google, Facebook, Amazon, Microsoft, and Apple wield power analogous to that of absolute monarchs, and that together they constitute a greater threat to political liberty in the United States than Donald Trump.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But is there not a categorical difference between wielding a lot of influence over commerce and controlling a monopoly on the legitimate use of violence, as monarchs and, to an extent, presidents do? Google doesn’t have the power to selectively prosecute and imprison public officials it does not like. But an authoritarian president plausibly could. So why do you think Big Tech is ultimately the bigger threat?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think the clear point I was trying to make is that these are both really disturbing, terrifying concentrations of power. In the case of Trump, the White House, even after the <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">recent decision in the Supreme Court,</a> there&#8217;s still an immense number of restraints on the presidency.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What you&#8217;re talking about — we&#8217;re not there yet. And whatever Trump has said, it&#8217;s going to take him a few steps at least to get there. Whereas what we&#8217;re talking about right now with big tech is where we are now. This is not theoretical. This is the power they have <em>now</em>, so that&#8217;s a really key thing to keep in mind.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But would you agree that there are constraints on the power of these companies in the current context? I think even before the recent revival of aggressive enforcement at the FTC, the government </strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/apr/24/apple-google-settle-antitrust-lawsuit-hiring-collusion"><strong>sussed out collusion in terms of hiring practices</strong></a><strong> among these big tech companies. So are there not limits that these companies need to operate within, just as the president currently does?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In that case, what you had is, some tens of thousands of employees who were being restricted in their ability to go from one company to another through no-poach agreements. Yes, they did win that case. But I think it was like a $5 million fine, and a little pretend slap on the wrist, don&#8217;t do it again. <em>[Editor’s note: The companies </em><a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/tech-industry/apple-google-others-settle-anti-poaching-lawsuit-for-415-million/"><em>paid $415 million</em></a><em> to settle a civil suit over the no-poach agreements.]</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That was affecting the lives of a lot of people, and they got a little slap on the wrist. I don&#8217;t think that that case in itself had very much effect on their sense of the power of the government.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I&#8217;m talking about their power, it&#8217;s not just the power over their workers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I first got into this work, not through Google, but through Amazon. When I published my book, <em>Cornered</em>, it was 2010. And in the process of writing that book, I had really spent a lot of time talking to my editor, to my agent, and then, to other people who were writing books and to their editors. And I realized that American publishers with Amazon were facing a situation in which you had a company that controlled the gate to the marketplace — and was unconstrained by any traditional laws requiring them to keep the gate open equally for all comers. They had the ability to open and close the gate arbitrarily to the marketplace.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Were there any examples of them doing that in an egregious way that illustrates the danger of that kind of power?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oh, yes. I spent a lot of time talking to CEOs and publishers back then, David Young at Hachette USA. I spoke to Drake McFeely at Norton. These are one-on-one meetings. And the basic thing was: When the door was open, they would say, “Amazon is our absolute best customer.” When the door was closed, they&#8217;d say “Amazon is a dictator that was entirely interfering in our business in arbitrary ways. We don&#8217;t have access to the marketplace. We don&#8217;t connect with the reader, the buyer, because Amazon&#8217;s determining how we&#8217;re connecting.” And that&#8217;s only gotten worse over the last 15 years. <em>[Editor’s note: </em><em>Young neither confirmed nor denied this account, saying he did not remember meeting Lynn, as it would have been more than 15 years ago. McFeely could not be reached for comment.]</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In February 2010, Amazon shut off the buy buttons for McMillan. McMillan was complaining <em>[that Amazon was devaluing its authors’ work by </em><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/01/30/technology/30amazon.html"><em>charging only $9.99 for ebooks</em></a><em>]</em>. What Amazon did is they just said no more “buy” buttons. It&#8217;s like: You&#8217;re not selling on Amazon. Back then, Amazon was probably responsible for 40, 50 percent of their book sales in the United States. It&#8217;s now higher, much higher. But even if it&#8217;s only 40, 50 percent, you can&#8217;t stand to lose that much of your capacity for sales, so they gave up.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Were any of the conflicts between publishers and Amazon explicitly about the content of work, as opposed to terms of compensation for ebooks?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">About the content? There was some point at which, I think it was Tom Cotton or somebody who was on TV or Fox — a politician who was having a fit about how they&#8217;re being suppressed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But let&#8217;s just say there is no evidence of Amazon ever trying to suppress a particular viewpoint, right? But, there&#8217;s two things. One is, when you either suppress a particular publisher because they don&#8217;t have the money to pay you the extortionary rates of advertising, then you&#8217;re less likely to be found. You have less opportunity to make your way to the market. Two, when you promote one book, you suppress every other book in the marketplace.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s a two-way amplification of a book — amplification of a publisher — so that there&#8217;s de facto suppression of all the books, de facto suppression of all other publishers. You can have very large effects on what books are being published, how they&#8217;re being sold, what ideas people are connecting with. The effects can be a byproduct of a business model, a byproduct of unconscious decisions that were somewhat automated that have no political intent in and of themselves. But they have a political effect.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I imagine there’s an analogy there to your view of the role that algorithms on social media play, in terms of amplifying. Maybe it&#8217;s a completely neutral algorithm that is just amplifying whatever gets the most engagement. But that has implications for what content ultimately gets the most attention.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah. But the thing is that as these middlemen — who are in between the people who are speaking and the people who are listening, in between the author and the readers, the author and the voter, in between the creator and the buyer, the seller and the buyer — as these masters in the middle gather more and more and more information about each individual person, and about each individual company, they use that information to manipulate both sides of the market.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More and more perfectly, they use it to push you as a reader: Oh, you liked a book about this battle in World War II. Well, you&#8217;re going to like another book about this battle in World War II, and you&#8217;re going to like this third book about this battle in World War II. And then, you know what, there’s this guy who&#8217;s used an analogy to that battle in World War II to talk about Trump politics, maybe you&#8217;ll like him too. So you can see how a couple of things happen when you have this kind of a system, which is that as they feed off their knowledge of you, they drag you more and more to what we used to call filter bubbles.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I feel like there’s an argument that what you’re describing isn’t that different from organic processes of knowledge acquisition, which existed before the internet. Like, say you are a left wing-minded person, and you read a book by Tom Frank in the early 2000s or something. And that gets you interested in other books that he&#8217;s written, and authors that he cites, and you start subscribing to certain magazines, and that self-reinforcing kind of interest or ideology is a natural process that humans engage in when learning about the world, and developing interests, and that this isn&#8217;t necessarily such an insidious</strong>—</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah, absolutely. You&#8217;re absolutely right, and that&#8217;s a good thing. That&#8217;s how we educate ourselves. But, there&#8217;s a huge difference between when Tom Frank wrote <em>What&#8217;s the Matter With Kansas?</em> and then that leads you to a review of it in the Nation; I started reading the Nation. I had to take out a subscription to the Nation, maybe. I take out a subscription to Mother Jones. But maybe, I learned that there&#8217;s actually a left-wing bookstore in Chicago, and I go to that bookstore, and I find a whole bunch of other books. And so, then suddenly, it&#8217;s like I found a bunch of work, and a bunch of people that helped me answer the questions that I&#8217;ve been asking. And so, that&#8217;s fantastic, and I certainly live that life.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But, when you have fewer and fewer, and fewer places that you&#8217;re interacting with, when you get down to one major place where you&#8217;re going to buy books online, when you get down to one major place or two major places — if you&#8217;re getting most of your news off of TikTok or you get it off of Facebook — you&#8217;re not going to read the New York Times, and that&#8217;s going to make it very hard for you to link out to the New York Times site. You&#8217;re getting most of your news off the platform.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At that point, exploration is not something you control. You have then actually lost your sovereignty. You&#8217;ve lost your ability to control your own destiny in this process, and you go where they take you. Now, you went to a really good college; you know how to protect yourself against some of this bullshit. But I bet that sometimes you find yourself getting suckered in on it. But a lot of folks don&#8217;t know how to protect themselves.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>To get to a separate claim in your Harper’s piece: You write that monopolists are a leading driver of &#8220;the surge in racism and homophobia&#8221; and &#8220;the attacks on reproductive choice&#8221; in the United States. I was wondering what you were thinking about specifically here. To me, it is not clear that there has even been a surge in racism and anti-gay bigotry in the United States; support for marriage for </strong><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/646202/sex-relations-marriage-supported.aspx#:~:text=Same%2DSex%20Marriage%20Support%20Near,recorded%20in%202022%20and%202023."><strong>same-sex</strong></a><strong> and </strong><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/354638/approval-interracial-marriage-new-high.aspx"><strong>interracial couples</strong></a><strong> remains near record highs in Gallup&#8217;s polling. And in any case, certainly America has grown more progressive on race and gender since 1981 — the year that you believe that antitrust policy changed for the worse.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what&#8217;s your timeline here? I mean, you gotta separate out the different things. Okay? It&#8217;s like, yeah, okay, in 1981, Reagan makes it easier for General Electric to roll up control over televisions, or he makes it easier for Walmart to roll up control over retail. So at that point, you&#8217;re not actually dealing with communications platforms. So there&#8217;s a revolutionary change in how we do competition policy, which is applied initially to industrial and retail firms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So it didn&#8217;t happen all at once. Reagan starts the process. Clinton then extends it to banking, to the defense industrial base, to oil and gas, to telecommunications. And then what you have over time with telecommunications, you have a shift in business models, which takes place around 15 years ago — 10 to 15 years ago — from relatively unobtrusive forms of manipulation, to manipulation as the foundation of the business model. So to say that, well, between 1981 and 2011, racism and homophobia went down in the United States, and then even though it has increased radically in the years since, that my thesis is somehow wrong, I don&#8217;t follow.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, I think it&#8217;s an open question to me whether they&#8217;ve increased radically since then versus becoming more visible because of the way these platforms amplify certain speech.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You&#8217;re taking parts of the thesis out and you&#8217;re saying, &#8220;Well, I&#8217;m not sure that it works.&#8221; So it&#8217;s like, if you take the thesis apart, then yeah, then maybe things start to fall apart. But the thesis is that the reason that these people have these abilities is because we fail to apply traditional anti-monopoly laws.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Yeah, I agree that that&#8217;s the overarching thesis.</strong><strong><br></strong><br>Yeah. Okay. So what&#8217;s the issue then?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>So I also wanted to touch on the claim about reproductive choice. I agree that large businesses are involved in </strong><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/6/3/18632438/federalist-society-leonard-leo-brett-kavanaugh"><strong>the Federalist Society</strong></a><strong>, and the right’s project there is both to empower big business and to restrict abortion rights. At the same time, when I look at </strong><a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/google-inc/totals?id=D000022008"><strong>FEC filings</strong></a><strong>, the </strong><a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/apple-inc/totals?id=D000021754"><strong>large</strong></a><strong> tech </strong><a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/amazon-com/totals?id=D000023883"><strong>monopolists</strong></a><strong> of our age throughout the past 10 years have generally given a lot more money to the Democratic Party — the pro-choice party — then to the pro-life party. If their money determined these elections, then Dobbs wouldn&#8217;t have happened. And there&#8217;s lots of small businesses and regional businesses that fund the American right.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Eric, corporations are complicated things. They do a lot of different things at the same time. They curry favor on both sides. Look at Mr. Horowitz from Andreessen Horowitz, right? Two months ago, he was all in for Trump. Now it looks like his friend, Harris, may win. So suddenly, he&#8217;s like, &#8220;Oh, poor Harris.&#8221; Andreessen is still out there, totally 100% in. Crazy-ass Andreessen is still out there 100% in for Trump. Musk is leaping up and down like a maniac on the stage in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So really, you&#8217;re going to say because Google threw some money behind some Democrats — and even then, it&#8217;s like, was it Google or is it the individuals in the corporation? Corporations, they do with their money what makes sense for them politically.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Do you think that small- and regional-sized businesses are any different in that respect?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Small- and medium-sized business, they&#8217;re different because they&#8217;re less politically powerful.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But can&#8217;t small business interests pool together in the Chamber of Commerce, in various other systems to &#8230;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah, of course, that&#8217;s their right. But it&#8217;s very different. A Chamber of Commerce is generally much less powerful as an organization than a large corporation. You got a whole bunch of different people who are working through an issue. There&#8217;s a lot of things they&#8217;re going to agree on. There&#8217;s a lot of things they&#8217;re going to disagree on. So the things they disagree on, they tend not to take political positions. So it&#8217;s just a basic rule of democracy that dividing power is going to make it less likely that an actor is going to rise up and threaten the democratic system.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>To play devil’s advocate, what do you make of the </strong><strong>idea that actually, small businesses — precisely because in this country, we have this deep-seated yeoman farmer ideal, and the small proprietor has cultural cache —&nbsp; that this actually gives them pretty significant power over politics.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oh my god, you&#8217;re repeating to me ancient libertarian truisms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, but there are </strong><a href="https://genlawgroup.com/do-you-know-which-laws-dont-apply-to-small-businesses/#:~:text=Small%20businesses%20may%20be%20exempt,%2C%20national%20origin%2C%20and%20religion."><strong>lots of federal regulations</strong></a><strong> — labor regulations — that small businesses are exempt from while large businesses have to abide by them. And so there are these ways in which arguably, the government shows some degree of affection for small businesses that maybe is not extended to large corporations.</strong>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I have no understanding of how you could actually come to that conclusion. I mean, it&#8217;s like the affection for small business is just some little crumbs that Congress tosses to the little people once every four years or once every two years. And almost any one of these, they&#8217;re recent. Go do your homework, go actually look at how the SBA operates. Look at how every one of these laws that&#8217;s designed for farming support, where that money goes to. Very little of it goes to the small actor. It&#8217;s just enough to shut them up. Other than, say, Vance and Hawley, and Warren and Klobuchar, who&#8217;s really making their business taking on big corporations? So where is this imaginary world in which the government is favoring small business over big business?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, I guess I&#8217;m just referring specifically to both proposed legislation and actual laws that exempt companies with, say, less than 25 employees from this or that federal regulation. There seems to be a sensitivity</strong>—</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Wait, wait, wait, listen. The point of this conversation is not to go in and re-litigate antiquated conversations that the libertarians put together in the 1970s. If you want to have this, you go read my book. You can read my first book, you can read my second book, you can read my third book. You can read all kinds of other work that&#8217;s out there. We don&#8217;t have to waste our time — while I&#8217;m driving down the highway — having these arguments. Go do some reading.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, I mean, I’m partially speaking for readers who haven&#8217;t necessarily done all that reading and would like to know what</strong>—</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No, no, this is your job. You can go read and you can explain it. Like I said, go read <em>Cornered</em>. Go read <em>Liberty From All Masters</em>. Go read Sally Hubbard&#8217;s or Jasper T. Scott&#8217;s books. There&#8217;s a lot of books that get it just from different levels, different angles.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s all kinds of articles you can read up on. There&#8217;s been just a broad destruction of independent business across America over the last 40 years. If you want to learn some of the math, you can go get a copy of <em>Liberty From All Masters</em>. I do the math about Walmart.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Retail was designed in the old days to serve everybody. The business was regulated to ensure that any family with some wherewithal could get into it, go out and start a business, to start a grocery. And these weren&#8217;t little rinky-dink groceries. They&#8217;re family-owned supermarkets.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For a long period of time, all of the great technological advances that were made in groceries were made by independent people trying to get ahead of their rival down the street. Now, if you are Walmart and your rival down the street is Walmart, and down the next town, the rival is Walmart, you don&#8217;t have to do a damn thing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Isn&#8217;t Walmart under competitive pressure from Amazon?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oh my god. Yeah, of course, they&#8217;re under a little bit of competitive pressure from Amazon. And Google&#8217;s under a little bit of competitive pressure on certain lines of business from Apple. Right? But it doesn&#8217;t mean that this is an open and democratic system. It doesn&#8217;t mean that it&#8217;s a system that is designed to prevent fascism and the absolute concentration of power over. Again, Eric, you got to do your homework. If you wanted to have a conversation, you want to be the devil&#8217;s advocate, come at me with something that&#8217;s worthwhile.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Great. I will ask you a question that maybe you&#8217;ll like better. So, the other thing I wanted to ask about from your Harper&#8217;s piece: You discussed the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision in Moody versus NetChoice. A colleague of mine </strong><a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2024/2/26/24083652/supreme-court-netchoice-paxton-moody-texas-florida-first-amendment-social-media-facebook-youtube"><strong>wrote about it as well</strong></a><strong>. At issue in that case was whether the governments of Florida and Texas could prohibit social media platforms from taking down posts based on the viewpoint represented in the user&#8217;s expression or another person&#8217;s expression. Justice Elena Kagan argued that Texas’s proposed restrictions on content moderation would effectively compel Facebook to tolerate neo-Nazi and pro-teen suicide content on their platforms and this would constitute a violation of those firms’ rights of free speech.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You suggested that by making this ruling, the liberal justices mounted as “outriders for autocracy,” and you argued that giving social media platforms the right to moderate content at their own whim was as antithetical to democracy as giving the president criminal immunity from official acts. And so, what would you say to a liberal, like my colleague, Ian Millhiser, who believes that allowing major platforms to bar pro-anorexia and pro-genocide content is actually in the public interest, and that enabling right-wing state governments to dictate which points of view private companies must platform would itself put us on a slippery slope to authoritarianism?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you go read the decision, a corporation has First Amendment rights as a corporation. Publishers have First Amendment rights as publishers. The case that we are making and what many other people are making — and this can give you a misunderstanding — is that these are platforms, not publishers. Platforms are curators. And so platforms are places where people come together to communicate with each other, where publishers come to gather with readers to share information with each other. And if you allow the master in the middle, the middle man, to manipulate that, then you have grossly interfered with the rights of the 330 million people in America — I guess, some of them are babies, so they&#8217;re not necessarily using these platforms — but every American youth relies on these platforms to communicate with other Americans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So I&#8217;d say that Kagan&#8217;s thinking is that she&#8217;s basically advocating for the suppression of the First Amendment rights of every citizen of the United States who relies on these platforms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for the idea that Florida and Texas and Ohio are going to force these platforms to carry what the states want them to, no. It&#8217;s like there&#8217;s a missing part of this conversation, and it&#8217;s called the terms of service. All these people have a right to publish terms of service. And under terms of service, they can say, &#8220;We&#8217;re not going to carry racist material.&#8221; We can say, “We&#8217;re not going to carry stuff that we believe is harmful to kids, that seems to promote eating disorders or suicide.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So then, once you publish your terms of service, you can say, &#8220;We&#8217;re not going to publish anything that seems to advocate violence.&#8221; And it&#8217;s like, as long as you apply the terms of service equally without favor to all of your users, then you can shut down whatever you want.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But is there any principle that binds what they can put into a terms of service? It seems to me that, by this logic, if the social media company establishes a politically biased term of service, then that could result in what you&#8217;re concerned about — and I&#8217;m concerned about as well — in terms of deplatforming legitimate points of view. So what legally binds a company from just crafting the terms of service so they can discriminate against whichever point of view they want to suppress?&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Well, the thing is that at a certain point, the Essential Facilities Doctrine, traditional American communications doctrine, is once you get to a certain size, that would be discriminatory. Political discrimination is illegal.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I just want to clarify the principles here. It seems to me there&#8217;s no way to permit all political speech regardless of its perspective on social media platforms </strong><strong><em>and</em></strong><strong> prohibit racist speech from them (since there is a lot of racist, political speech). So I guess, how do you see resolving that? I took you as saying that basically: We should have a situation where you can express any viewpoint on these platforms — no matter how vile — if it isn&#8217;t direct harassment or a direct violent threat, but that the platform shouldn&#8217;t be amplifying that speech. Is that correct? Or what is your view?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People can go to the branded publications, right? If you wanted to hear a certain kind of speech — if your morning&#8217;s not going to be complete without a big plate of racism along with your eggs and your coffee — then you can have a racist publication. You can have a Nazi publication. And the people who need that, they can go sit on the website of the publication and get what they want. That&#8217;s the beauty of America, is that you don&#8217;t need the middleman to boost it. And you can still get it, you can still go find it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Great. Well, there are a few other questions I had, but you&#8217;re running close to time, right?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah. I appreciate you trying to be a devil&#8217;s advocate, but I just encourage you, as you&#8217;re working through this — because you&#8217;re smart, you&#8217;re clearly asking a lot of the right questions — is just continue to do your research. Don&#8217;t react. And whenever you&#8217;re starting to see stuff that is reacting against the kind of stuff that we&#8217;re doing, just question, “Who is paying for that?” Just question who it is. Because almost every single person who&#8217;s coming at us, someone is paying for that person to come at us.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/380978/trump-google-democracy-big-tech-monopoly-lina-khan</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/380978/trump-google-democracy-big-tech-monopoly-lina-khan</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Levitz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Inside Trump’s ominous plan to turn civil rights law against vulnerable Americans]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="Illustration of the presidential seal covered in red, with superimposed architectural columns falling on it." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/DOJ_Vox_10-30.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2016, <a href="https://www.law.georgetown.edu/faculty/christy-e-lopez/">Christy Lopez</a> was living her dream. She was an attorney at the Justice Department’s Civil Rights Division working on policing where, among other things, she led the team that investigated the Ferguson Police Department in Missouri after the 2014 killing of Michael Brown. Lopez believes that her work spurred meaningful policing reforms, both in Ferguson and nationwide.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But when Donald Trump won the 2016 election, Lopez quit. Trump, she thought, would block her team from doing any worthwhile investigation into police use of force. Lopez was right. In Trump’s first year in office, Attorney General Jeff Sessions <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/trump-administration-rolls-back-civil-rights-efforts-federal-government">sharply restricted the use of consent decrees</a> — the legal tool Lopez and her colleagues used to force change in Ferguson.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, she is sounding the alarm: Whatever the dangers of a first Trump term were, the risks of a second dwarf them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If Trump is elected, I would like to look back five years from now and say, ‘Oh, we were really alarmist,’” Lopez, now a Georgetown University law professor, told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“But I do worry that it’s actually going to be far worse.”</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many, many people have warned that Trump is a threat to American democracy. Many others have argued that these warnings are politically inert, that focusing on abstract concepts like “democracy” and “the rule of law” removes political debate from the concrete concerns people want addressed by government. Do people struggling to pay the bills have time to care about such matters of principle?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet in reality, the two things are inseparable. Trump’s plan to turn the government into a tool of his own personal will would have extraordinary consequences for Americans’ everyday lives. It would disrupt, or potentially even devastate, core functions of government that we’ve long taken for granted.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Justice Department’s Civil Rights Division is a case in point.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Founded by the 1957 Civil Rights Act, the Division is tasked with enforcing federal law regarding anti-discrimination and civil equality. This is a mammoth responsibility, covering areas of law that shape the fundamental experience of American democracy. Its attorneys launch hate crimes prosecutions, investigate discrimination in employment and housing, and sue states when their voting rules run afoul of the 1965 Voting Rights Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Trump returns to power, the department could easily be turned from a tool for protecting civil rights into a means of undoing them. Trump and his allies have laid out fairly specific plans for doing just that — plans that, if enacted, would mean a far more radical and methodical transformation of the federal rights civil apparatus than what we saw in Trump’s shambolic first term.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The department’s Voting Section&nbsp;— which played a critical role in defending the integrity of the 2020 election —&nbsp;would be twisted,&nbsp;its attorneys replaced with cronies working to validate Trump’s lies and shield Republican-controlled states from federal scrutiny. Its anti-discrimination litigators would be tasked with investigating “anti-white” discrimination, effectively turning the Civil Rights Act on the minority citizens it was written to defend. And Lopez’s former colleagues working on policing would not only let abusive cops skate, but potentially even investigate local law enforcement Trump believed weren’t aggressive enough toward alleged criminals.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We can see here that a second Trump administration would likely mean the inversion of the traditional purpose of federal civil rights law. Its guardrails against authoritarianism, discrimination, and abuse of power will be twisted toward advancing them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And it’s just one of many ways in which Trump’s pursuit of power at any cost would have tangible and direct consequences for ordinary Americans’ lives.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trump’s plan to invert the Civil Rights Division, explained</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump has vowed to use a second term to enact “retribution” against his enemies.  The Justice Department, and specifically the current Civil Rights Division staff, are at the top of the list. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the end of Trump’s first term, he issued an executive order creating a new classification for civil service jobs — called Schedule F — that would have allowed him <a href="https://protectdemocracy.org/work/trumps-schedule-f-plan-explained/">to fire as many as 50,000 civil servants</a> and replace them with handpicked allies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Trump left office before his team could implement Schedule F, he has promised to reissue the order “<a href="https://www.donaldjtrump.com/agenda47/agenda47-president-trumps-plan-to-dismantle-the-deep-state-and-return-power-to-the-american-people">immediately</a>” upon returning to office. In anticipation, his allies have compiled <a href="https://www.govexec.com/management/2024/09/trumps-second-term-agenda-breaking-bureaucracy/399533/">long lists</a> of civil servants they’d like to fire and loyalists they’d like to put in their place — preparations that have led one expert on federal administration to conclude that 50,000 firings is now “<a href="https://protectdemocracy.org/work/trumps-schedule-f-plan-explained/">probably a floor rather than a ceiling.</a>”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s allies have focused on the Civil Rights Division as one of their chief targets for Schedule F and other power grabs. <a href="https://static.project2025.org/2025_MandateForLeadership_FULL.pdf">Project 2025</a> — <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/373485/project-2025-abortion-ban-trump-comstock-mifepristone">widely seen</a> as the chief planning document for a Trump second term <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/article/project-2025.html">despite the campaign’s disavowals</a> — has an explicit, detailed plan for taking it over.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The document calls on the next Republican president to “reorganize and refocus” the division, aiming to make it into “the vanguard” of the administration’s crusade against “an unholy alliance of special interests, radicals in government, and the far Left.” It is one of three Department of Justice divisions singled out in the document’s call for “a vast expansion of the number of [political] appointees” overseeing and directing its conduct. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is all part of a broader plan for eroding the Justice Department’s traditional independence. While the attorney general is appointed by the president, their staff is given wide leeway to follow the law rather than the president’s dictates. Political personnel are strictly prohibited from interfering with specific investigations and cases. That’s why the current Justice Department could pursue <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/354842/hunter-biden-guilty-politics-david-weiss">a case against Hunter Biden</a> with no fear of retaliation from his father.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump and top deputies have declared their intent to change this.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/AP24214674291537.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Trump stands next to a man behind a podium" title="Trump stands next to a man behind a podium" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Then-President Donald Trump listens as acting director of the Office of Management and Budget Russel Vought speaks during an event on &quot;transparency in Federal guidance and enforcement&quot; in the Roosevelt Room of the White House, October 9, 2019. | Evan Vucci/AP Photo" data-portal-copyright="Evan Vucci/AP Photo" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">“The notion of an independent agency — whether that&#8217;s a flat-out independent agency like the FCC or an agency that has parts of it that view itself as independent, like the Department of Justice — we&#8217;re planting a flag and saying we reject that notion completely,” Russ Vought, a key second-term Trump planner, <a href="https://www.npr.org/transcripts/1192432628">said in a 2023 interview</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When you put these three proposals together — seeding the Civil Rights Division with Trump political appointees, using Schedule F to replace career prosecutors with ideological allies, and ending department independence — the full picture becomes clear. If Trump has his way, a second term means a Civil Rights Division operating not as a (relatively) neutral division dedicated to enforcing civil rights law, but as a tool of the Trump agenda in all the areas it covers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is very threatening for government employees and obviously offensive to the notion of a neutral civil service. But what would this mean for most Americans in practice? What does it matter, really, if one bureaucrat is swapped out for another?</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Election law politicized</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On November 9, 2020, Attorney General Bill Barr directed the Justice Department to investigate Trump’s allegations of fraud in the just-concluded presidential election. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The probe, announced after the election had been called for Joe Biden, was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/11/09/politics/william-barr-voting-irregularities/index.html">controversial inside the Department</a>. It raised fears that Barr, no stranger to <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2020-election/fact-check-echoing-trump-barr-misleads-voter-fraud-attack-expanded-n1240144">conspiracy theories about voter fraud</a>, was trying to validate Trump’s claims of a stolen election.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet the professional probe, staffed by veteran investigators in the Civil Rights Division and elsewhere, found no evidence of mass fraud. On November 23, Barr told Trump the investigation was “<a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/GPO-J6-REPORT/pdf/GPO-J6-REPORT.pdf">not panning out</a>.” The neutral, competent investigation gave the attorney general the ammunition he needed to stand up to the president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now imagine if things were different, if these career investigators had been Schedule F’d out, replaced instead with Trump-aligned attorneys.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What if they had come to Barr and said that, actually, the <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2103619118">bogus statistical arguments</a> that the election was stolen had merit? What would he have done then? How would reports of such findings, however bogus, influence the rest of the country — including Vice President Mike Pence and members of Congress?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s an example that illustrates the importance of the Civil Rights Division. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The American system is unusual, in global terms, by granting most power over election administration to state and local authorities. While this system makes it hard for the federal government to rig elections, it makes it comparatively easy for state-level officials to cheat and discriminate (Jim Crow being the signature example).</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2138366391.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,11.749025795501,100,76.501948408999" alt="Black and white photo of Black people in a long line outside a small rural building labeled “the sugar shack.”" title="Black and white photo of Black people in a long line outside a small rural building labeled “the sugar shack.”" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Following the passage of the Voting Rights Act of 1965, people line up to vote — many for the first time — at the Sugar Shack store, Peachtree, Alabama, May 3, 1966. | National Archives of Fort Worth/PhotoQuest/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="National Archives of Fort Worth/PhotoQuest/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Civil Rights Division’s election work is one of the primary checks on such abuses. It protects the right to vote, enforcing laws like the Voting Rights Act. It also works to protect the sanctity of the results after elections, identifying and investigating allegations of illegal conduct by state and local administrators during the voting process. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Its main area of responsibility is allegations of discrimination, but it also regularly cooperates with other divisions in investigating other kinds of allegations like voting fraud (as happened in November 2020). While the Supreme Court has significantly <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/11/28/23978226/supreme-court-trump-judges-voting-rights-act-arkansas-rose-secretary">weakened the Voting Rights Act</a>, the Civil Rights Division is still able to bring cases that matter.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a second Trump term, this work could be turned on its head. Instead of trying to stop abuses at the state and local level, they might at best ignore them — and at worst try to force local officials to engage in them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The chapter of Project 2025 on the Justice Department, authored by former Trump DOJ official Gene Hamilton, sketches out how this would work in detail. It argues that Kathy Boockvar, who was Pennsylvania’s secretary of state in 2020, “should have been (and still should be) investigated and prosecuted” under a post-Civil War law called the Klan Act — designed, as you might guess, to break the first incarnation of the Ku Klux Klan. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Boockvar’s crime, per Hamilton, was issuing a legal interpretation designed to address the unprecedented increase in mail-in ballots during the pandemic. She issued guidance to counties that if a provisional mail-in ballot were “spoiled” — meaning rendered defective through, for example, damage during the shipping process — that voters would have an opportunity to correct them. Hamilton calls this a “conspiracy against rights,” a crime laid out in the Klan Act. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I spoke to <a href="https://newsroom.lmu.edu/expert-profile/levitt-justin/">Justin Levitt</a>, an election law expert and former deputy assistant attorney general in the Civil Rights Division, he told me “it’s difficult to convey how crazy” such a case would be.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Pennsylvania rule is, in his mind, a very reasonable interpretation of a constitutional obligation to avoid disenfranchising people over minor ballot issues. Even if Boockvar’s interpretation were dubious, nothing in the Klan Act suggests that the DOJ would be empowered to prosecute her for it (as the law simply doesn’t cover good-faith mistakes by elected officials trying to count more ballots).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I know an awful lot of federal prosecutors [and] I don’t know one who would bring this case,” he tells me.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1229479862.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.794243288056,100,78.411513423888" alt="Protesters in an urban street carry signs that read “Count every vote.“" title="Protesters in an urban street carry signs that read “Count every vote.“" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Demonstrators at a protest in front of the Philadelphia Convention Center during the 2020 presidential election, November 5, 2020. | Jennifer Huxta/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Jennifer Huxta/Bloomberg via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Hence why Schedule F is so important. It’s almost certain that no experienced Justice Department prosecutor would bring this case, be they Democrat or Republican, because they would recognize it’s an absurd reading of the law. But if Trump can put the Division under his thumb, inserting cronies in oversight positions and firing a huge swath of the career staff, he can get people like Hamilton in a position to do what they want.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://csde.washington.edu/affiliates/jake-grumbach/">Jake Grumbach</a>, a political scientist who studies state-level voting laws, tells me that such politically motivated prosecutions of state officials is “the most dangerous thing” the Justice Department can do. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even the threat of a civil rights investigation can scare state-level administrators into compliance with what the feds want. A weaponized Justice Department would mean these officials would feel significant pressure to twist their election administration systems into whatever contorted shape Trump was calling for at the moment — with potentially devastating consequences for electoral fairness.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Civil wrongs</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While voting rights law is an especially significant area of the Civil Rights Division’s work, it’s far from the only one.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Civil Rights Division’s raison d’etre, the entire point of it being a separate and distinct component of the federal government, is to enforce the modern consensus that discrimination on the basis of identity is a pervasive and systematic problem that requires significant federal resources to address.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump and his closest allies believe something more like the opposite, that federal civil rights law isn’t a solution to the problem of discrimination against minorities but an agent of discrimination against whites, men, and Christians. As such, they aim to flip the entire civil rights code on its head by using the Civil Rights Division as “the vanguard,” in Hamilton’s language.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Anything [in law] can be weaponized,” says Kristy Parker, a former Civil Rights Division attorney who worked on policing. “That’s the problem.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the last Trump administration ended, top Trump aide Stephen Miller has worked with Hamilton at a new law firm — America First Legal — that <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/03/21/us/politics/stephen-miller-america-first-legal.html">focuses on “anti-white” discrimination</a> in employment.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">America First filed a suit that successfully blocked a pandemic-era program to distribute financial aid to <a href="https://thehill.com/regulation/554361-federal-judge-says-biden-restaurant-fund-discriminated-against-white-male/">minority- and woman-owned restaurants</a>. It sued the NFL over the Rooney Rule, which requires that teams interview at least one nonwhite candidate for high-level coaching vacancies, and it went after <a href="https://aflegal.org/litigation/fasorp-v-northwestern-university/">Northwestern University</a> for allegedly prioritizing hires of minority and non-male faculty members.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In April, Axios’ Alex Thompson reported that <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/04/01/trump-reverse-racism-civil-rights">America First was “laying legal groundwork”</a> for a full-court press against “anti-white racism” in the event that Trump retakes control of the Civil Rights Division.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is something that Hamilton explicitly calls for in his Project 2025 chapter. He writes:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Civil Rights Division should spend its first year under the next Administration using the full force of federal prosecutorial resources to investigate and prosecute all state and local governments, institutions of higher education, corporations, and any other private employers who are engaged in discrimination in violation of constitutional and legal requirements.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In reality, what Hamilton calls “discrimination” are actually efforts to address discrimination. There is overwhelming evidence that American society continues to <a href="https://scholar.harvard.edu/files/pager/files/annualreview_discrimination.pdf">allocate resources unfairly on the basis of race</a>. Without affirmative steps to rectify this situation, entrenched inequalities like the racial gap will never disappear. What Trump and his team call “anti-white discrimination” are efforts to close gaps between groups, not open them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Trump team aims to invert federal oversight over local prosecutors in a similar fashion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2023, the campaign released a policy video in which <a href="https://www.donaldjtrump.com/agenda47/agenda47-president-trump-announces-plan-to-end-crime-and-restore-law-and-order">Trump vows to task the Civil Rights Division</a> with investigating “progressive prosecutors.” The basic argument is that these prosecutors, who see part of their mission as reducing the effects of mass incarceration on the Black community, are effectively engaging in race-based discrimination in favor of Black offenders.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I will direct the DOJ to open civil rights investigations into radical left prosecutor’s offices, such as those in Chicago, LA, and San Francisco, to determine whether they have illegally engaged in race-based enforcement of the law,” Trump said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Much like the attempt to prosecute Boockvar, trying to jail “progressive prosecutors” is not something the department’s professional staff would ordinarily contemplate doing. Even if Trump succeeded in replacing them via Schedule F, it’s hard to imagine any such investigation yielding charges that could stand up in court.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the fact that such investigations would almost certainly fail to yield charges <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/185487/trump-maga-legal-war-slow-burn-authoritarianism">does not make them harmless</a>. Even spurious investigations entail coercive measures — like subpoenas, searches, and audits — that can make it difficult for “progressive prosecutors” to do their jobs. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s also a political aspect to the threat, as many of Trump’s proposed targets are in elected posts. Elected officials are generally responsive to threats to their reelection chances, and being a target of a DOJ civil rights probe looks really bad to prospective voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/6/30/21281041/trump-justice-department-consent-decrees-jeff-sessions-police-violence-abuse">Consent decrees</a>, the mechanism Lopez used to deal with bias in Ferguson, are one of the most powerful tools available to federal prosecutors for addressing bias in policing — and another target in a second Trump term.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The process begins with a fact-finding investigation, uncovering evidence of systematic use-of-force problems and/or racial discrimination. The next stage involves lengthy negotiations with police departments that culminate in a tangible and enforceable set of reform benchmarks for the department. If the benchmarks aren’t being met to the Civil Rights Division’s satisfaction, its attorneys can haul cops in front of a judge and demand answers.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/AP119714094153.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,11.514716612012,100,76.970566775976" alt="The back of a man who holds both hands up while police in riot gear approach him" title="The back of a man who holds both hands up while police in riot gear approach him" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Police wearing riot gear and pointing guns approach a man with his hands raised in Ferguson, Missouri, August 11, 2014. | Jeff Roberson/AP Photo" data-portal-copyright="Jeff Roberson/AP Photo" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The previous Trump administration limited their use going forward, but a second one might roll them back.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Obama administration negotiated a historic number of consent decrees, but these are approaching their negotiated sunset dates. The Biden administration has tried to bargain with departments for extensions, as well as implement new ones, but police departments have been dragging their feet. Lopez believes they are anticipating the possibility of a Trump victory.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Almost any jurisdiction that is currently negotiating a consent decree is going to wait to see what happens in November,” she says.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If this delaying tactic works and Trump’s Civil Rights Division vacates consent decrees across the board, Lopez warns of aggressive police being unleashed across the country. Trump’s wild rhetoric about policing — his recent statement that cops should be permitted “<a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/29/trump-violent-day-policing-crime-00181619">one really violent day</a>” to combat crime — would further encourage abuse.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The attorneys tasked with limiting police abuses would, in a second Trump administration, be responsible for encouraging them.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A government “for the people” —&nbsp;for now</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As important as the Justice Department’s Civil Rights Division is, it is far from the totality of government work.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Justice Department has eight other litigating departments beyond the Civil Rights Division, where attorneys prosecute everyone from terrorists to tax cheats. It has five separate police agencies, including the FBI and US Marshals Service. It oversees all federal prisons and studies federal criminal convictions to see if any merit presidential pardons. It has nine separate grantmaking authorities, which provide funding for local authorities supporting everything from assisting sex trafficking victims to encouraging innovation in <a href="https://www.ojp.gov/topics/community-violence-intervention/resources">local alternatives to policing</a>.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2172231777.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="A US flag on a pole flies in front of a federal building" title="A US flag on a pole flies in front of a federal building" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A US flag flies in front of the Department of Justice (DOJ) headquarters building on September 15, 2024, in Washington, DC. | J. David Ake/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="J. David Ake/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Department of Justice is one of 15 federal departments, each of which has its own diverse and important set of responsibilities. There are also important agencies separate from the department structure, like the CIA and the Environmental Protection Agency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of them perform critical work that contributes to the standard of living Americans have come to take for granted. This work depends on experienced, dedicated civil servants who know how to do the job, and all of it could be disrupted by Trump’s plans to give their jobs to partisan hacks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Every day, the EPA works to monitor and address pollution poisoning our rivers and drinkable water. The Bureau of Labor Statistics churns out job numbers and other reports that the Fed and other places depend on to make good economic policy. US Citizenship and Immigration Services helps keep families together, approving permanent residency and citizenship applications for foreign spouses of American citizens. The Department of Energy manages America’s nuclear weapons and power plants, making sure we don’t experience a Fukushima or Chernobyl-level disaster.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now imagine the people who know how to do this routine stuff are either thrown out of office or put under the thumbs of political commissars. That’s the danger here.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump and his team have laid out their plans in detail, in official statements proposing a revival of Schedule F and semi-official documents like Project 2025. Even if you agree with many of their policy ideas, they need to be implemented competently and lawfully in order to work. Throughout history, in the United States and elsewhere, the imposition of political control on a civil service has been a recipe for incompetence and anti-democratic abuse.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The United States has a democratic government:&nbsp;a deeply flawed one, but one by the people and for the people. Trump’s plan is to make it for him and his alone, and he has a decent chance of succeeding if elected. We often take our <a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/zack-beauchamp/the-reactionary-spirit/9781541704411/">relatively novel form of government</a> for granted; if we lose it, we’ll miss it when it’s gone.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/381094/trump-second-term-2024-election-justice-department-civil-rights</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/381094/trump-second-term-2024-election-justice-department-civil-rights</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Beauchamp]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 10:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How safe is your vote from manipulation?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="People standing at a double line of voting booths." data-caption="Voters make selections at their voting booths inside an early voting site on October 17, 2024, in Hendersonville, North Carolina. | &lt;p&gt;Melissa Sue Gerrits/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;p&gt;Melissa Sue Gerrits/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2178247386.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Voters make selections at their voting booths inside an early voting site on October 17, 2024, in Hendersonville, North Carolina. | &lt;p&gt;Melissa Sue Gerrits/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Vox reader Jason Taylor writes</em>: <em>Should voters be concerned about the possibility of Trump election deniers being in positions of power to count votes in Trump&#8217;s favor that he did not receive in the upcoming election? Thank you for your time and consideration of my question.</em></p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the defining — and troubling — facts of our current political era is that the loser of the previous election maintains he didn’t lose it at all. To this day, Donald Trump refuses to admit he lost the 2020 election to Joe Biden, a stance that many of his <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/372863/2024-election-lies-trump-overturn-harris">followers have gotten in line behind</a>, including some who’ll <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25137148-swing-state-election-deniers-center-for-media-and-democracy-91324">hold positions of power</a> in this November’s contest.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That has understandably spurred concerns like the ones you’ve raised about the current cycle.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Sign up for the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/explain-it-to-me-newsletter-sign-up">Explain It to Me newsletter</a></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">The newsletter is part of Vox’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/explain-it-to-me">Explain It to Me</a>. Each week, we tackle a question from our audience and deliver a digestible explainer from one of our journalists. Have a question you want us to answer? Ask us <a href="http://www.vox.com/ask-vox">here</a>.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite these troubling developments, however, election law experts say that voters should know ample protections are in place to bar election deniers from messing with the vote count or its eventual certification.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There are multiple safeguards built into the process to prevent that kind of thing from happening,” says Gowri Ramachandran, the director of elections and security at the Brennan Center for Justice, a nonpartisan think tank dedicated to voting rights.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What safeguards are in place for ballot counting?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let’s start with the process of counting ballots. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The count involves so many steps, so many layers of double-checking and supervision, that it would be virtually impossible to fake even a single ballot,” <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2020/11/05/vote-count-michigan-no-fraud/?_pml=1">Evelyn Smith, an election worker in Michigan</a>, told the Washington Post in 2020.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These safeguards include the presence of <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/elections-and-campaigns/policies-for-election-observers#table">independent observers</a> at ballot counts, post-election audits to verify the results, and <a href="https://www.eac.gov/sites/default/files/electionofficials/security/Voting_System_Security_Measures_508_EAC.pdf">rigorous record-keeping</a> to keep tabs on voter participation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This all starts with the submission of ballots. When people vote in person, poll workers <a href="https://www.eac.gov/sites/default/files/electionofficials/security/Voting_System_Security_Measures_508_EAC.pdf">keep a clear tally of how many people</a> have voted, which is later checked against the number of ballots coming from each precinct. Similarly, when people vote by mail, election workers confirm that each <a href="https://apnews.com/article/2022-midterm-elections-voting-voter-registration-government-and-politics-609866267baef89dd1513e7c9e2f7509">ballot corresponds to a real person</a> and keep track of <a href="https://bipartisanpolicy.org/report/mail-voting-is-safe-secure/">how many ballots are coming in</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In most cases, the ballots are counted by machines, and those have to undergo their own rigorous <a href="https://www.votebeat.org/arizona/2022/7/18/23268819/logic-accuracy-tests-county-elections-equipment-yuma-voting/">“logic and accuracy” tests</a> by election officials before they can ever be used.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ballots cast in person are often tabulated on location at the precinct, and that information is <a href="https://campaignlegal.org/update/what-happens-my-ballot-after-i-vote?gad_source=1&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwo8S3BhDeARIsAFRmkOMI1xfUcumUJLCHfZuPnu2bEIFWQV3IsYI7du_0a04Qvi_er2oDsyQaAgrjEALw_wcB">printed out on a physical receipt</a> and stored on a memory card. Typically, these results are recorded at the precinct, and both the receipt and memory card are also transmitted in a secure box to a central location.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mail-in ballots are also tabulated at either a polling station or central location after being verified. In rare instances — <a href="https://verifiedvoting.org/election-system/hand-counted-paper-ballots/" data-type="link" data-id="https://verifiedvoting.org/election-system/hand-counted-paper-ballots/">usually in much smaller counties and towns</a> — ballots are counted by hand, a practice that’s increasingly less <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/pittsburgh/news/hand-counting-ballots-explained/" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.cbsnews.com/pittsburgh/news/hand-counting-ballots-explained/">common because it’s prone to errors and delays</a>. When hand counting is used, it’s usually done in teams to reduce mistakes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless of whether ballots are counted by machine or by hand, independent observers, or members of both parties, are able to watch as votes are submitted and tallied, adding another layer of security.&nbsp;(These policies <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/elections-and-campaigns/policies-for-election-observers" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.ncsl.org/elections-and-campaigns/policies-for-election-observers#table">vary by state</a> but most places allow some transparency into different steps of the process.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such protocols make it difficult for potential bad actors to manipulate the count.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many states have post-election audits as well to catch if something is amiss with the vote tally. In these audits, state or county officials will hand count a sample of the ballots in each precinct to spot-check for discrepancies. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Audits would find out if bogus votes were added to the real vote totals,” says Ciara Torres-Spelliscy, a Stetson University law professor and elections expert.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Candidates, as well as the two parties, are also able to lodge a complaint or mount a legal challenge if they believe there have been any irregularities.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What about election certification?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In recent elections, certification of the results has been another point in the process when some officials have caused delays or questioned the outcome.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Typically, certification is a routine part of any election and basically just involves county and state election boards verifying the results after they’ve been tallied. In 2020 and 2022, however, there were examples of officials and federal lawmakers refusing to do so.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, the Wayne County, Michigan, Board of Canvassers <a href="https://www.detroitnews.com/story/news/politics/2020/11/17/wayne-county-canvassers-deadlock-certifying-november-3-election-results/6324274002/">initially deadlocked</a> 2–2 when two Republican commissioners refused to declare Biden the winner. Following significant backlash, they eventually changed their votes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Shortly after that, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/1/6/22218058/republicans-objections-election-results">147 federal Republican lawmakers infamously voted to challenge</a> the election results during Congress’s certification process on January 6, 2021. Despite their objections, the certification was completed, and since then, Congress has passed updates to the <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/12/21/23520649/electoral-count-reform-act-omnibus-trump">Electoral Count Act </a>to make the threshold for challenging the results much higher.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2022, the Republican-led election commission in <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/06/15/gop-commission-refuses-to-certify-new-mexico-primary-vote-00039771">Otero County, New Mexico</a>, also refused to certify primary results due to their alleged distrust in Dominion voting machines. The New Mexico secretary of state ultimately obtained a state Supreme Court order requiring the commission to certify, and they later did.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In past instances, local officials either relented or were ordered by a court or state officials to move forward with the certification of the results. Experts note that the same is likely to occur this time around if there are more attempts to delay or deny certification.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If state-level officials like the secretary of state tried to block a legitimate outcome from moving forward, the candidates and parties could similarly take the issue to court.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Experts note that they aren’t especially concerned that efforts to stymie certification would be successful, though they do note that bad actors could cause delays and confusion that might fuel misinformation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There is a potential for there to be uncertainty,” says UCLA election law professor Rick Hasen.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>So, what should we be worried about this election?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The experts I spoke to broadly emphasized that they have faith in the election system.&nbsp;Despite this, Trump could still foment distrust much like he did in 2020 and gin up violence or unrest as a result.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That possibility, and a potential reprisal of the January 6 insurrection, is <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/372863/2024-election-lies-trump-overturn-harris">unfortunately its own concern</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“When people hear this kind of disinformation over and over and over again, it does lead to real harmful consequences,” Ramachandran told Vox.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All this is to say that one of the largest threats this election faces is many voters’ lack of confidence in the legitimacy of the outcome, even if counting and certification all go according to plan.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story was featured in the Explain It to Me newsletter. Sign up&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/explain-it-to-me-newsletter-sign-up"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em>&nbsp;<em>For more from Explain It to Me,&nbsp;</em><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/explainit?sid=site"><em>check out the podcast</em></a><em>. New episodes drop every Wednesday.</em></p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/378648/election-deniers-vote-count-security-certification-trump</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/378648/election-deniers-vote-count-security-certification-trump</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Li Zhou]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:16:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The big lie behind Biden’s “garbage” gaffe scandal]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Joe Biden during a meeting with Nikos Christodoulides, Cyprus’s president, not pictured, in the Oval Office of the White House on October 30, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2181247572.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Joe Biden during a meeting with Nikos Christodoulides, Cyprus’s president, not pictured, in the Oval Office of the White House on October 30, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Joe Biden is no longer competent at speaking in public. This makes him a poor surrogate for Kamala Harris’s campaign, but he is also the president, and therefore an extremely prominent surrogate for the Democratic nominee.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This generated a problem for Harris Tuesday night when Biden set out to criticize dehumanizing rhetoric at a recent Trump rally and ended up spouting a garbled stream of words that may or may not have dehumanized all Trump supporters as “garbage.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Conservatives have thus <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/30/us-news/republicans-erupt-over-biden-calling-trump-supporters-garbage-its-what-he-and-kamala-harris-genuinely-think-about-you/">expressed their collective horror</a> at the spectacle of a US president disparaging Americans whose only sin was disagreeing with him politically. But even if one stipulates that Republicans’ tendentious reading of Biden is correct, their professed outrage is not merely hypocritical but perniciously misleading.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At worst, the president disparaged conservative voters momentarily, before disavowing that sentiment in his very next breath. During his time in office, meanwhile, Biden has showered federal resources on heavily Republican parts of the country. Trump, by contrast, derides progressives and immigrants as “enemies” and “vermin” without apology, and reportedly sought to block disaster aid to <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/03/helene-trump-politics-natural-disaster-00182419">Democratic</a> <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/25/trump-ignored-disaster-aid-request-from-democratic-governor-00185542">strongholds</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is one candidate in the 2024 race who sees wide swaths of the American public as less than human, and it is not Kamala Harris. The furor over Biden’s disjointed remarks serves to obscure this reality.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Trump dehumanizes his political adversaries without apology or equivocation. Biden does not.&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Sunday, at a rally for Trump at Madison Square Garden, the comedian Tony Hinchcliffe referred to Puerto Rico as a “<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/380818/trump-rally-puerto-rico-tony-hinchcliffe-groypers">floating island of garbage</a>.” During a video call with Latino supporters Tuesday night, Biden said of the incident:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">And just the other day, a speaker at [Trump&#8217;s] rally called Puerto Rico a &#8216;floating island of garbage.&#8217; Well, let me tell you something. I don&#8217;t — I — I don&#8217;t know the Puerto Rican that — that I know — or a Puerto Rico, where I&#8217;m fr— in my home state of Delaware, they&#8217;re good, decent, honorable people.<br><br>The only garbage I see floating out there is his supporter&#8217;s — his — his demonization of Latinos is unconscionable, and it&#8217;s un-American. It&#8217;s totally contrary to everything we&#8217;ve done, everything we&#8217;ve been.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That is the official White House transcript of the remarks, at least. Republicans argue that what Biden <em>actually</em> said was, “the only garbage I see floating out there is his [i.e., Trump’s] <em>supporters</em>.” In other words, Biden says he was calling Hinchcliffe’s demonization of Puerto Rico garbage, while Republicans say he was calling all Trump supporters trash.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is impossible to distinguish “supporter’s” from “supporters” by ear. So, it cannot be known with certainty what Biden intended in the moment that those words escaped his lips. The surrounding context, however, undercuts the GOP’s interpretation. Immediately after uttering his controversial statement, the president said the following:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, Trump has di— tried to divide the country based on race, ethnicity, anything that does harm, to take their eye off the ball about what the terrible things he&#8217;s done and will do. But Kamala Harris has fought for all Americans and will be a president for all of America.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is possible that Biden intended to 1) deride all Trump supporters as “garbage,” and then 2) immediately tout Harris’s commitment to fighting for human trash. But that strikes me as unlikely, particularly since the president has never said anything like that before during his half-century in public life.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whatever Biden intended though, it is indisputable that his very next sentences disavowed the idea that Republican voters are “garbage” whose interests should be ignored. And after his event was over, Biden <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1851436643498037614">insisted</a> that his intention had merely been to describe Hinchcliffe’s rhetoric as “garbage.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump, meanwhile, is unequivocal in his belief that Democrats constitute <a href="https://apnews.com/article/donald-trump-enemies-from-within-5c4a34776469a55e71d3ba4d4e68cf62">“enemies from within” </a>who must be vanquished.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Fox News last weekend, Howard Kurtz told Trump that “enemies from within” is “a pretty ominous phrase, if you’re talking about other Americans.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think it’s accurate,” Trump replied.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Republican nominee has also suggested that some of these enemies might need to be <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/13/politics/trump-military-enemy-from-within-election-day/index.html">“handled” by “the military</a>,” likened his political opponents to <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/11/14/23958866/trump-vermin-authoritarian-democracy">“vermin,”</a> and claimed that undocumented immigrants are <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/trump-says-immigrants-are-poisoning-blood-country-biden-campaign-liken-rcna130141">“poisoning the blood of our country.” </a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Just last week, Trump described America as <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/watch-trump-calls-the-u-s-a-garbage-can-for-the-world-at-campaign-event-in-austin-texas">“a garbage can for the world,”</a> arguing that other nations deposit their human refuse into the United States through immigration.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Notably, Trump’s demonization of immigrants is not confined to those who lack legal status or even citizenship. He has baselessly accused legal US residents <a href="https://www.vox.com/podcasts/372206/springfield-ohio-pets-haitian-immigrants-conspiracy">from Haiti of eating people’s pets</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K7i17bZnJeI">vowed to deport them</a>. And he has described American citizens who came to this country through the diversity visa lottery as “<a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/02/trump-americans-who-came-here-via-lottery-are-horrendous.html">horrendous</a>” and “<a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-says-visa-lottery-rewards-the-worst-immigrants-thats-inaccurate/">the worst of the worst</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump did not feel compelled to disavow any of these statements after making them, nor to reassure the country that he wants to fight for every American. To the contrary, he is unabashedly committed to <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/21/nx-s1-5134924/trump-election-2024-kamala-harris-elizabeth-cheney-threat-civil-liberties">directing the power of the federal government</a> against his political opponents and the millions of US residents whose presence in this country he abhors.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There isn’t the slightest equivalence between Biden’s rhetorical posture toward Republican voters and Trump’s toward Democrats and immigrants. And a similar gap surfaces when one examines each president’s actual governance.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Trump doesn’t just compare Americans he dislikes to garbage — he tries to treat them like it</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During his time in office, Trump explicitly sought to aid Americans who’d voted for him while spurning those who dared to oppose him, multiple administration officials told <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/03/helene-trump-politics-natural-disaster-00182419">Politico’s E&amp;E News</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As deadly wildfires ripped through California, Trump <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/03/helene-trump-politics-natural-disaster-00182419">initially refused</a> to approve disaster aid because the state had voted overwhelmingly for Democrats, according to Mark Harvey, his administration’s senior director for resilience policy on the National Security Council. Harvey says that Trump only changed his mind after being shown vote totals demonstrating that there were more Trump supporters in Orange County, California, than in Iowa.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Olivia Troye and Kevin Carroll, former homeland security officials in the Trump administration, both back up Harvey’s story.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Trump absolutely didn’t want to give aid to California or Puerto Rico purely for partisan politics — because they didn’t vote for him,” Carroll told <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/13/trump-disaster-funding-warning">The Guardian</a>  earlier this month. Carroll went on to say that his former boss, then-White House Chief of Staff John Kelly, had to “twist Trump’s arm” to get him to release federal funding to those areas following the wildfires and Hurricane Maria, respectively.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump also withheld millions in <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/25/trump-ignored-disaster-aid-request-from-democratic-governor-00185542">wildfire aid</a> from Washington in September 2020 because the state’s governor had criticized him, and the aid ultimately was not approved until Biden took office.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis’s memoir lends further credence to these claims. In 2019, after Hurricane Michael devastated the Florida Panhandle, DeSantis <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/03/helene-trump-politics-natural-disaster-00182419">asked</a> then-President Trump to order the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to pay 100 percent of the state’s recovery costs, instead of 75 percent, as was customary.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to DeSantis’s book, Trump replied, “They love me in the Panhandle.&nbsp; I must have won 90 percent of the vote out there. Huge crowds. What do they need?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump proceeded to order FEMA to pay 100 percent of Florida’s recovery costs. And yet, just two months earlier, he threatened to veto legislation that would have extended the same courtesy to Puerto Rico. And his administration proceeded to withhold <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/latino/new-probe-confirms-trump-officials-blocked-puerto-rico-receiving-hurri-rcna749">$20 billion</a> in hurricane relief from the island for a protracted period of time, while Trump <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/top-hud-officials-departure-follows-disagreements-over-housing-policy-and-puerto-rico-disaster-funds/2019/01/16/e6ba5be4-1839-11e9-9ebf-c5fed1b7a081_story.html">reportedly told</a> Kelly and then-Office of Management and Budget Director Mick Mulvaney that he did not want a “single dollar going to Puerto Rico.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden administration has shown no comparable favoritism. To the contrary, its response to Hurricane Helene — which ravaged many conservative communities on the East Coast — has earned <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/03/politics/fact-check-trump-biden-hurricane-response/index.html">plaudits from Republican officials</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, Biden’s signature piece of legislation — the Inflation Reduction Act — has actually <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2023-red-states-will-reap-the-biggest-rewards-from-biden-s-climate-package/">directed disproportionate funds to red states</a>. And Biden has also directed considerable federal funds toward <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/politics/articles/2024-09-05/biden-promotes-administrations-rural-electrification-funding-in-wisconsin">improving infrastructure</a> in conservative-leaning rural areas. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Trump supporters who profess outrage at Biden’s words are guilty of more than hypocrisy</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In sum, one presidential candidate is associated with a man who might have once referred to Republican voters as garbage momentarily — before immediately disavowing that idea, and after dutifully advancing the interests of conservative regions during his time as president. That candidate herself, meanwhile, has said, “I strongly disagree with any criticism of people based on who they vote for” and “I believe the work that I do is about representing all the people, whether they support me or not.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The other presidential candidate has personally likened large swaths of the American public to “vermin” and “garbage” — repeatedly, and without apology — after seeking to choke off federal aid to Democratic victims of wildfires, and pledging to prosecute his political opponents the next chance he gets.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Any public official who condemns Harris for somehow abetting the dehumanization of ordinary Americans is not merely guilty of hypocrisy, but of wildly misleading voters about an issue of vital importance: which presidential hopeful would — and would not — treat their least favorite segments of the American public like trash.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/politics/381150/biden-garbage-gaffe-republicans-trump-supporters</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/politics/381150/biden-garbage-gaffe-republicans-trump-supporters</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Levitz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 22:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk skipped a hearing in Philly about his super PAC’s payouts to voters]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A Philadelphia judge ordered X CEO Elon Musk to appear in a hearing Thursday morning over his super PAC&#8217;s plan to award $1 million a day to voters in key battleground states. But Musk skipped his courthouse appointment after the same judge granted a request to transfer the case from Pennsylvania state to federal jurisdiction. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/10/31/elon-musk-skipped-a-hearing-in-philly-about-his-super-pacs-payouts-to-voters/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/10/31/elon-musk-skipped-a-hearing-in-philly-about-his-super-pacs-payouts-to-voters/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 02:02:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kalshi secures tens of millions in loans from VCs, eyes $50M+ round amid election betting boom, source says]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Investors are rushing to throw millions at a hot startup called Kalshi as loans or even as unusual we’ll-figure-it-out later cash. Kalshi is an exchange that allows people to bet, as official commodity trading contracts, on the outcomes of cultural events, from election results to how long Taylor Swift’s latest album will top the charts.&#160; [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/10/31/kalshi-secures-tens-of-millions-in-loans-from-vcs-eyes-50m-round-amid-election-betting-boom-source-says/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/10/31/kalshi-secures-tens-of-millions-in-loans-from-vcs-eyes-50m-round-amid-election-betting-boom-source-says/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:07:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Seven killed in Israel in deadliest Hezbollah rocket strikes in months]]></title><description><![CDATA[They were killed in two areas, in the deadliest series of rocket attacks on Israel in months.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce8yjr3zyz8o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce8yjr3zyz8o</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US envoys in push for Israel-Hezbollah ceasefire]]></title><description><![CDATA[Diplomats return to the region, as Lebanon's PM expresses cautious optimism over a truce.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c14ln6kkkg7o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c14ln6kkkg7o</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:55:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Drone strikes on civilians suggest new Russian tactics of fear in Ukraine]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ukrainians tell of their fear as BBC Verify analyses videos appearing to show drone strikes on civilians.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c207gz7key6o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c207gz7key6o</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 06:01:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[N Korea fires banned missile in longest flight yet]]></title><description><![CDATA[The test shows that Pyongyang is building weapons that "fire farther and higher", Seoul says.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ckgry8rpzn4o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ckgry8rpzn4o</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 15:29:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Women raped in war-hit Sudan die by suicide, activists say ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Several women raped by paramilitary fighters in Gezira state have taken their own lives, activists say.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8xpqvz0e88o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8xpqvz0e88o</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:46:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[France jails ex-doctor for 27 years in Rwandan genocide trial]]></title><description><![CDATA[Eugène Rwamucyo was found guilty of complicity in genocide and complicity in crimes against humanity.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy918gk20zo</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy918gk20zo</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 09:02:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Deadly Israeli strike targeted 'spotter' on Beit Lahia building's roof, official says]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tuesday's Israeli strike left 93 Palestinians dead or missing, local health officials said. The US described it as "horrifying".]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c6247nwz73do</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c6247nwz73do</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 22:18:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Argentina's Milei fires foreign minister for opposing US embargo on Cuba]]></title><description><![CDATA[President Javier Milei fires Diana Mondino after Argentina backs lifting the US economic embargo on Cuba at the UN. ]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgl4y6w2r33o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgl4y6w2r33o</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 22:50:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tensions rise in Beirut after influx of displaced people]]></title><description><![CDATA[An influx of refugees fleeing Israeli strikes risks exacerbating sectarian divisions in the Lebanese capital.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c99rx89znmlo</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c99rx89znmlo</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:09:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA['I'm not a one-issue voter, but this is huge': Women on how abortion shaped their vote]]></title><description><![CDATA[It is the first presidential election since the top court overturned Roe v Wade, which protected the nationwide right to an abortion.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cew2x50808go</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cew2x50808go</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 14:29:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Harris makes last big-stage pitch to undecided voters, vowing 'different path']]></title><description><![CDATA[Her pitch to voters in Washington DC was at a location loaded with symbolism, Anthony Zurcher writes.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ced9n00n820o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ced9n00n820o</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 02:24:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is Unrwa and why has Israel banned it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[The agency provides aid for Palestinians in Gaza and elsewhere, and has long been criticised by Israel.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8jy9v43z89o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8jy9v43z89o</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 18:25:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What the US election outcome means for Ukraine, Gaza and world conflict]]></title><description><![CDATA[Our chief international correspondent Lyse Doucet hears from leading experts about what's at stake ahead of the vote.]]></description><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgl490zrz45o</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgl490zrz45o</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 12:07:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why US Votes In November But Inaugurates New President In January]]></title><description><![CDATA[The United States has an electoral system and calendar unlike no other country. The nation votes in November but the new President is inaugurated in January.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-why-us-votes-in-november-but-inaugurates-new-president-in-january-6914375</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-why-us-votes-in-november-but-inaugurates-new-president-in-january-6914375</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 01:24:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump May Challenge Results If He Loses, But What Are His Options]]></title><description><![CDATA[As the US presidential election nears, the two primary candidates -- Republican nominee Donald Trump and his Democratic counterpart Kamala Harris -- are making their last pitch to the voters at multiple rallies in a day.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-donald-trump-may-challenge-results-if-he-loses-but-what-are-his-options-6915609</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-donald-trump-may-challenge-results-if-he-loses-but-what-are-his-options-6915609</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 01:18:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea Says It Test-Fired Latest ICBM Hwasong-19 On Thursday]]></title><description><![CDATA[North Korea on Friday said it test-fired the latest intercontinental ballistic missile Hwasong-19 on Thursday, calling it a final and complete version, the Yonhap news agency reported.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-says-it-test-fired-latest-icbm-hwasong-19-on-thursday-6917870</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-says-it-test-fired-latest-icbm-hwasong-19-on-thursday-6917870</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 21:52:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US Elections: 60 Million Cast Early Votes In Kamala Harris-Trump Tight Race]]></title><description><![CDATA[With just a few days to go for the United States elections, a staggering 61.0 million Americans have already made their voices heard by casting their ballots in the November election, according to a report by CNN.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-60-million-cast-early-votes-in-kamala-harris-trump-tight-race-6917811</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-60-million-cast-early-votes-in-kamala-harris-trump-tight-race-6917811</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 21:38:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump Extends Diwali Greetings, Vows To Strengthen Ties With India, PM Modi]]></title><description><![CDATA[Former US President and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has said that the United States' "great partnership" with India and "my good friend Prime Minister (Narendra) Modi" will be strengthened under his administ]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-extends-diwali-greetings-vows-to-strengthen-partnership-with-india-and-pm-modi-6917641</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-extends-diwali-greetings-vows-to-strengthen-partnership-with-india-and-pm-modi-6917641</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:33:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blinken Says 8,000 North Korean Troops Deployed In Russia's Kursk Region]]></title><description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Anthony Blinken on Thursday revealed that approximately 10,000 North Korean soldiers are currently in Russia, with around 8,000 deployed in the Kursk region.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-000-north-korean-troops-deployed-in-kursk-region-says-blinken-6917568</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-000-north-korean-troops-deployed-in-kursk-region-says-blinken-6917568</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:16:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iran Preparing Strike On Israel From Iraqi Territory Within Days: Reports]]></title><description><![CDATA[Israeli intelligence suggests Iran is preparing to attack Israel from Iraqi territory in the coming days, possibly before the U.S. presidential election on Nov. 5, Axios reported on Thursday, citing two unidentified Israeli sources.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-preparing-strike-on-israel-from-iraqi-territory-within-days-reports-6917383</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-preparing-strike-on-israel-from-iraqi-territory-within-days-reports-6917383</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:11:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israeli Foreign Minister Extends Diwali Greetings To Indians]]></title><description><![CDATA[Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz Thursday extended greetings to Indians on Diwali, stressing that his country shares the values of democracy, freedom, and a vision of a brighter future like India.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/israeli-foreign-minister-extends-diwali-greetings-to-indians-6916404</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/israeli-foreign-minister-extends-diwali-greetings-to-indians-6916404</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 15:08:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Germany To Shut Down Iranian Consulates Over Execution Of Dual National]]></title><description><![CDATA[Germany will shut all Iranian consulates in Germany but allow the embassy to remain open in reaction to the execution of a German-Iranian national, the foreign ministry said on Thursday.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-to-shut-down-iranian-consulates-over-execution-of-dual-national-6916065</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-to-shut-down-iranian-consulates-over-execution-of-dual-national-6916065</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 13:58:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US Election 2024: All About Green Party Nominee Jill Stein]]></title><description><![CDATA[American voters seeking a progressive, environmentally focused candidate with a proven history of challenging the political mainstream have achoice in 2024 -- Jill Stein, the Green Party's nominee and a two-time presidential candidate.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-jill-stein-green-party-s-us-presidential-candidate-against-harris-and-trump-6915502</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-jill-stein-green-party-s-us-presidential-candidate-against-harris-and-trump-6915502</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 12:14:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[U.S. Officials Try to Advance Israel’s Cease-Fire Talks With Hezbollah and Hamas]]></title><description><![CDATA[William Burns, the C.I.A. director, made a last-ditch attempt to move Gaza talks along before U.S. elections next week.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/world/middleeast/israel-cease-fire.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/world/middleeast/israel-cease-fire.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:30:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iranian Officials Threaten Retaliation for Israeli Strikes]]></title><description><![CDATA[It was unclear how or when Iran plans to respond, or whether the rhetoric could be bluster. Iranian officials had downplayed the damage of Israel’s last attack.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/world/middleeast/iran-threatens-retaliation-israel-strikes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/world/middleeast/iran-threatens-retaliation-israel-strikes.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:57:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Germany Shuts 3 Iranian Consulates Over Execution of German-Iranian]]></title><description><![CDATA[The rare step of closing the consulates reflected German protests over the execution of Jamshid Sharmahd, an outspoken opponent of the Iranian regime.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/world/europe/germany-iran-consulates-sharmahd.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/world/europe/germany-iran-consulates-sharmahd.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:58:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea, in the Spotlight Over Ukraine, Launches a Long-Range Missile]]></title><description><![CDATA[The launch, into waters west of Japan, came shortly after the United States and South Korea criticized the North for sending troops to join Russia’s war.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/world/asia/north-korea-missile-launch.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/world/asia/north-korea-missile-launch.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 10:56:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Strike on Gaza Hospital Destroys UN Supplies, Palestinian Officials Say]]></title><description><![CDATA[Israeli troops had withdrawn from Kamal Adwan Hospital after arresting most of the medical staff. The Israeli military said it was “unaware of a strike” there.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/world/middleeast/israel-gaza-hospital-strike.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/world/middleeast/israel-gaza-hospital-strike.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:11:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump Had an ‘America First’ Foreign Policy. But It Was a Breakdown in American Policymaking.]]></title><description><![CDATA[A second Donald J. Trump presidency would almost certainly mark a return to an era of foreign policy decrees, untethered to any policy process, at a moment of maximum international peril.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/us/politics/trump-foreign-policy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/us/politics/trump-foreign-policy.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:10:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Friday Briefing: The Global Stakes of the U.S. Election]]></title><description><![CDATA[Plus, Japan's passion for the World Series.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/briefing/friday-briefing-the-global-stakes-of-the-us-election.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/briefing/friday-briefing-the-global-stakes-of-the-us-election.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 21:20:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[U.S. Turns to China to Stop North Korean Troops From Fighting for Russia]]></title><description><![CDATA[American agencies have assessed that China dislikes the growing partnership between Russia and North Korea. The State Department has raised the troop issue with Chinese diplomats.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/us/politics/russia-north-korea-troops-china.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/31/us/politics/russia-north-korea-troops-china.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:16:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mexico Passes Bill Barring Legal Challenges to Constitutional Changes]]></title><description><![CDATA[The bill has drawn criticism from legal scholars who say it would bulldoze any judicial oversight of constitutional matters.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/world/americas/mexico-passes-bill-legal-challenges.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/world/americas/mexico-passes-bill-legal-challenges.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 02:39:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[8 Supreme Court Justices in Mexico to Resign Ahead of Contentious Election]]></title><description><![CDATA[All but three of the country’s Supreme Court justices announced they would quit rather than partake in the controversial elections mandated by a judicial overhaul.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/world/americas/mexico-supreme-court-justices-resign.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/world/americas/mexico-supreme-court-justices-resign.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 15:12:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thursday Briefing: U.S. Voters Focus on the Economy]]></title><description><![CDATA[Plus, what too much sugar does to your body.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/briefing/economy-spain-floods-lebanon.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/briefing/economy-spain-floods-lebanon.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 21:30:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel Demolished Hundreds of Buildings in Southern Lebanon, Videos and Satellite Images Show]]></title><description><![CDATA[At least 1,085 buildings have been destroyed or badly damaged since Israel’s invasion targeting the Hezbollah militia, including many in controlled demolitions, a New York Times analysis shows.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/world/middleeast/israel-lebanon-border-photos-video.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/world/middleeast/israel-lebanon-border-photos-video.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 12:55:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel Orders Residents of Baalbek in Eastern Lebanon to Evacuate]]></title><description><![CDATA[Israel’s military warned civilians to leave Baalbek in the Bekaa Valley via three routes. The city had largely been spared Israeli bombardment until this week.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/world/middleeast/israel-evacuation-baalbek.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/world/middleeast/israel-evacuation-baalbek.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 20:40:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Clean Energy Is Booming in the U.S. The Election Could Change That.]]></title><description><![CDATA[Trump has suggested he would dismantle the Inflation Reduction Act, which has reshaped America’s energy landscape. It won’t be easy.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/climate/clean-energy-us-2024-election.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/climate/clean-energy-us-2024-election.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 13:40:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What Are the Implications of Israel Banning UNRWA?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Humanitarian agencies fear the new Israeli laws could have catastrophic effects for Gazans. They are already drawing sharp criticism from Israel’s allies.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/middleeast/israel-gaza-unrwa-ban.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/middleeast/israel-gaza-unrwa-ban.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 21:57:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israeli Military Hits Gaza Town for 3rd Time in Days, Killing Dozens, Officials Say]]></title><description><![CDATA[Gazan agencies said that children were among those killed in the strike in Beit Lahia. A U.S. State Department spokesman called the strike “a horrifying incident with a horrifying result.”]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/middleeast/israel-gaza-beit-lahia.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/middleeast/israel-gaza-beit-lahia.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 21:00:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[In Botswana’s Election, Diamond Profits Are a Defining Issue]]></title><description><![CDATA[The party that has governed the country since 1966 could lose power as the economy struggles from a slump in demand for diamonds, which made Botswana an African success story.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/africa/botswana-election-diamonds.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/africa/botswana-election-diamonds.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 17:39:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dozens Killed in Israeli Strikes in Eastern Lebanon, Lebanese Officials Say]]></title><description><![CDATA[The barrage of Israeli airstrikes in the Bekaa Valley on Monday night killed at least 60 people, officials said. It appeared to be the deadliest attack in the area since the war escalated last month.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/middleeast/israel-strikes-lebanon-baalbek-bekaa-valley.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/middleeast/israel-strikes-lebanon-baalbek-bekaa-valley.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 21:31:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Names Naim Qassem as Its New Leader]]></title><description><![CDATA[Mr. Qassem had been the Lebanese militant group’s longtime deputy. He replaces Hassan Nasrallah, who was assassinated in an Israeli airstrike last month.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/middleeast/hezbollah-new-leader-naim-qassem.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/middleeast/hezbollah-new-leader-naim-qassem.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 11:10:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zelensky, With Limited Options, Seeks a Path Forward for Ukraine]]></title><description><![CDATA[A muted response to Ukraine’s “victory plan” and steep challenges on the battlefield leave Kyiv searching for a Plan B.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/europe/ukraine-zelensky-russia-war.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/europe/ukraine-zelensky-russia-war.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 09:30:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[In U.K. Budget, Labour’s First Big Political Moment Offers Risk and Reward]]></title><description><![CDATA[British Prime Minister Keir Starmer’s government has stumbled since his party won a landslide victory, but the financial plan to be announced on Wednesday offers a possible relaunch.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/europe/uk-budget-labour-starmer.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/29/world/europe/uk-budget-labour-starmer.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 04:01:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump says "whether the women like it or not, I'm going to protect them" at Wisconsin rally - CBS News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxNajc3eldOTkhDandNWEttUDNjeUJXcTljU2RBNy0wU0UxNllQNHI4SUtPdGNnUFhZZmhuMzlyQmhuTlI2N1ZRY0F4N2Z5YnRqbjJtSVNHLXRDMXpXVTd1eDZLRzRtMzNMeHFKVU1Kc2ZVVUdFZlhMbDBKeFBRRGNRNXNvbko3eF9ESnFBcWwwQUNRUlB50gGaAUFVX3lxTE5yMTZXZ1FNV05keEpDM2JkVmM1YXhFbjNmTWs5cmVmUC1xNVFpX2w0YklGZm5Yc3hEV0hTMlkweTNveGFGcU5RSlI1bFBjMVhUQ0NyOHRTZkg4dVpTT1hKWHplUWdPUXdBV3RIVHBSYngtdTlaQTdDbmJ4OXcxa3R0ODAyZ1E3R0w0Z05uS1l0TkJQNFM4WmhURWc?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump says "whether the women like it or not, I'm going to protect them" at Wisconsin rally</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPc0NRZ1k3b0JfdHp1XzNxRGthc2pySS1xYU9LRkRJdGlrZ2dSUl9kN09tNnFXc1pDcjZQY0ROLS1wN2doby1HS3ptZmhZOGZSWUNab2hJMVZFQlM0NnU3QUFUMXktbFJrMy16Nl9ldm9fZjJnWWVlV3pTckhVX3VMRm9VUWkyX21oRi1GdHJ4M0NFVnBVR0tBNnBJTQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris and Trump Trade Gender Attacks as He Floats RFK Jr. for ‘Women’s Health’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPR2VuMTlLV3FLTUh5T2JwelpIOGlqN3FQWnFaLTNLV1RWN0ZtUG03SFg4REkxZnlTNU9VeEhOSnY4a2ZvVG9ublVVYlZ0UFd2QWJVck5MQ1NRRkxqR0V2dTlPaTk4S0hqQXVTXzRuRjNCaEFrU2lPTmM0ZHhmNmNyejZGVGJDeVBh?oc=5" target="_blank">Kamala Harris says Trump’s comment on women ‘is offensive to everybody’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxPVmdpczM1dWFnU3YyN3VYSHpJNUtmWktWSTVqZktrYy1XejhOOE1qWHlyVFVqSDRMTUd3c3ZjODRFTUIyOFZXdlZjQU5Od0J3ckVGa0hObGlaMi0wMHBqbk55ODF1bFdGVXZoMXRiZlp6Y1FYdmtheWI3S2FXT3lyVkFDQmhYSk9SVDdadEhaMmxFLVpPY1VR0gGcAUFVX3lxTE00R3ltLXNDdXM3bS1INTJRNFFtM3QyblBOb1ZKY01hVlU5T1ZpWUt3Wnc1dm1wdUozSHc4aU43aXZmWWdQOXVXVmlqTUpDZUlqQnB4cEs2cTNwYllJX21BYnk3RGJLamNvc0g5ekRqQjQ5V3NLSmZXczkwTUpfUDZnczd2MkpPTG9nWVRkdWRJX2pldXpuTlc0LUd6TA?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris seizes on Trump's pledge to protect women 'whether they like it or not'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVkFVX3lxTE1GQ1FnTUdvN2lQMjFVY1hqUEZqejFyWlBka1ZYOEZjeTlYcnFYWkUwVTV5OVRpVTZXOTVveXRGcDR3N1dsWTN1WjEtdkJjdXR6U2VaRTJn?oc=5" target="_blank">Tapper live fact-checks Harris speech: Trump's quote on protecting women was 'not as she presented it'</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxNajc3eldOTkhDandNWEttUDNjeUJXcTljU2RBNy0wU0UxNllQNHI4SUtPdGNnUFhZZmhuMzlyQmhuTlI2N1ZRY0F4N2Z5YnRqbjJtSVNHLXRDMXpXVTd1eDZLRzRtMzNMeHFKVU1Kc2ZVVUdFZlhMbDBKeFBRRGNRNXNvbko3eF9ESnFBcWwwQUNRUlB50gGaAUFVX3lxTE5yMTZXZ1FNV05keEpDM2JkVmM1YXhFbjNmTWs5cmVmUC1xNVFpX2w0YklGZm5Yc3hEV0hTMlkweTNveGFGcU5RSlI1bFBjMVhUQ0NyOHRTZkg4dVpTT1hKWHplUWdPUXdBV3RIVHBSYngtdTlaQTdDbmJ4OXcxa3R0ODAyZ1E3R0w0Z05uS1l0TkJQNFM4WmhURWc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxNajc3eldOTkhDandNWEttUDNjeUJXcTljU2RBNy0wU0UxNllQNHI4SUtPdGNnUFhZZmhuMzlyQmhuTlI2N1ZRY0F4N2Z5YnRqbjJtSVNHLXRDMXpXVTd1eDZLRzRtMzNMeHFKVU1Kc2ZVVUdFZlhMbDBKeFBRRGNRNXNvbko3eF9ESnFBcWwwQUNRUlB50gGaAUFVX3lxTE5yMTZXZ1FNV05keEpDM2JkVmM1YXhFbjNmTWs5cmVmUC1xNVFpX2w0YklGZm5Yc3hEV0hTMlkweTNveGFGcU5RSlI1bFBjMVhUQ0NyOHRTZkg4dVpTT1hKWHplUWdPUXdBV3RIVHBSYngtdTlaQTdDbmJ4OXcxa3R0ODAyZ1E3R0w0Z05uS1l0TkJQNFM4WmhURWc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 23:31:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA['The View's Sunny Hostin Calls Out Donald Trump's Garbage Truck Stunt - Deadline]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxONmZFZHg5LWYtWlVWOWZ6aHZjaU55ZE5Nc2phcGwxVVg3YTRFeVdKWEUycHVuMXllMHNVaDhzcXVSY1JHMTdpT3oxVXdOTDBRV3VCY1k5TkRCSV9QZS1BQlM5VXFjZVlodHE4ck9sU0ZaallJMElJbzdrYUtGNnM1QlFEaUFkS29BOFl4MTVRQXlrNkFJUlZQWWdqWjZIWk1vVFVmM0JwbHpXYkRwMWtFajR3U24zSkc2?oc=5" target="_blank">'The View's Sunny Hostin Calls Out Donald Trump's Garbage Truck Stunt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Deadline</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxQclBfRTdBbGlfMWJMV2hKcmNKbzk4OWtXVnc5ZFh1ZG5fZTFLQUVRbmtOaEdJeEZqS1laUkdhRkdZcEtzdXdJbGlyUHBjNzRoRlZxMTI1Tnc2RHhhZWoyOVNnMTRXS0ZDbFp1dFk3dy0wWFpPRHZWbHp4OGQzaHJ5dXRwcVE1czJlbG1XUEFLcWxhdUhmdWxHaXJJQkdHQS1CYkF3SDF5S25XUXN0NGpwS2xvbExCSjNoUFHSAb8BQVVfeXFMTXJuZTdwVFhzQUtEdzN1Uk9GdFVVZ1F1Vk16amZPVlNYTi1HNkgzelFSby1YNHJtdnBvU2RsSUVsd1M4eDFCalFYVTJIbU1rMzhpV2JSakU5TDR1UUl2STJKdXl2NDlyVm9teU5KcGlPREM3dU9wUjVtcFJ5RHozRTRkQkVUVE51LUhnTjhQZ2VDb1J0ZW1CdUxfTTFkUmZqNl9XaWg5SmFaWWxua1BxR2FUYzQtSFBWS05ZMF84bWM?oc=5" target="_blank">Driver of Trump garbage truck shares how viral moment came about: ‘Didn't really believe it at first’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxQam54b3UtU25NaEt0Umlkc2JUTkpMQUJkTGVkU0p6UkVHeldXTml5bTRDLWo4Ui1OQlBMcmpzcXFZTUFUQldLU3BmcjIzYy1KYXU0MjZxNU9iMlNmN2cyOXhqYk9oak1YX1NLNnFfUjZEODE4bU8tYTlSNHEtQlB2cU1wM3I1ZFpqbmlRQ1hZWlpIUFBoUFpFRA?oc=5" target="_blank">Video of Donald Trump 'Struggling' to Enter Garbage Truck Goes Viral</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Newsweek</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxOdzRoMDk3M3kyQkJsUk9obFUyd0JsUjNvQTlGZ3ZyVlVicnJKSUxYYWx4N3duNjlOMXhtNlVBUWdMemdKRWZqWjhoLURZbW8yU2N4MU15ckYyWTNnS2wybktUdnZfU0hHN0dHNkNkN2ozZWM4bE9oQWZpeDd1MHhJQk1B?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump uses garbage truck to needle Biden, Harris</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxNS25CN256VFg2bVBpRm9Uck1xbktMLW1xc2xSc2ZMRllKSVZqZ3NmYnB3SDYxclBYNy1KeGgta2xjUlJlLW1fLWNHdUo1R0ZzU0JNRnkxUUR4V05TUkxWT2ZxUm5Ra25rWFpkWmtMUTEtNlZvOXhlS05hYzRmYThLQmlqLVhCRWxmTHluVnhnbGNRZ29tQ3Q4TVhnTUZUbHZwVXFmLXkwLU1NRm1SWE4yTFpVcWpsa0dKS3ZZ?oc=5" target="_blank">Who won the day? Trump</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxONmZFZHg5LWYtWlVWOWZ6aHZjaU55ZE5Nc2phcGwxVVg3YTRFeVdKWEUycHVuMXllMHNVaDhzcXVSY1JHMTdpT3oxVXdOTDBRV3VCY1k5TkRCSV9QZS1BQlM5VXFjZVlodHE4ck9sU0ZaallJMElJbzdrYUtGNnM1QlFEaUFkS29BOFl4MTVRQXlrNkFJUlZQWWdqWjZIWk1vVFVmM0JwbHpXYkRwMWtFajR3U24zSkc2?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxONmZFZHg5LWYtWlVWOWZ6aHZjaU55ZE5Nc2phcGwxVVg3YTRFeVdKWEUycHVuMXllMHNVaDhzcXVSY1JHMTdpT3oxVXdOTDBRV3VCY1k5TkRCSV9QZS1BQlM5VXFjZVlodHE4ck9sU0ZaallJMElJbzdrYUtGNnM1QlFEaUFkS29BOFl4MTVRQXlrNkFJUlZQWWdqWjZIWk1vVFVmM0JwbHpXYkRwMWtFajR3U24zSkc2?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pennsylvania Puerto Rican veteran blasts Biden for trashing Trump supporters: ‘Garbage literally flies out of his mouth’ - New York Post ]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxObzNVRUl1bGZNeWVadDBRVmV1bDUweXI3SGN0QUxMbWFna3pyWXg2MzNnT3RfbmNEdjUzcktFaGp2MzZEYTFoSlRzU1dFVHd5VkJ4SlJqSVhvMTFXajJVTy1FbTM1eUcwQ3JDUVRoTjZySlNjdmI2LWhodDlfNWxHbTZna2FhVGlIYk45NGRDZ3BIZldFcDlmeWlRcFNZUHVUUHQ5QlFIZXlTYlRsRzZwRjJGMmw1Q0lhbGs3a1RfWE12cGdmekp1My1QUWtTaXN2X3JtbG9SWm4yUWVkYThTb25zVXhYYUx0WUdiTQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Pennsylvania Puerto Rican veteran blasts Biden for trashing Trump supporters: ‘Garbage literally flies out of his mouth’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">New York Post </font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNOXBZVkJhVXNOWWp2M05IVkFNRDByT2JEczBwcTlGbEwyTHl2ZV9QQlUwS1NTWHh5NkphUEZxcmJrODh6VE55OEpBeHFacFA3LUdkLU5qOVdDbUdRbXNGN1hZVnBYc2RFMXhDNlNpZ2JwNURLaUxOMTJYd3JONlZfWndxWTAweUpGSy1qYWNQUl9xbkM5NDNHRktWbHFENVVNS19zTXRxODlPRkVZaF9EZtIBtgFBVV95cUxOZGJSRWZiRDdlUGRZeUxhRXF0bUxqUHZvOVNhWVpQdllfSE9zeTNBQ3daNW5lS200TzJ0S2F5MWgzLUU5TjZuNHF0d1ZOTkQ0el85VGxFSDEwaEx6MENtbnlxaUxwYlBWMnVDaUxUV2ItMEF1MTc3b29ZVkZ1WDU4T2Zia3VucTBycG5hSUQwNEVEZWpqT3pOaGlTMG5Rd2ctNzJOUVhCS1g2ZFA3ckUxbTRCNnI0dw?oc=5" target="_blank">White House altered Biden's 'garbage' transcript despite concerns from stenographers</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAFBVV95cUxPOHhubXVsN0djTmNESGNINDZwOU5iRDlOREM4Qzc2QjVpOF82aFBJUUpJaFhhSXM1WmplVE1mSnVabm81akFhV003c084YmhZMjRFZzhjZnVhQklMaXhKNEJJcFFSM0hGQXZXUGM3NVlnWmttQjM3X2VXbXBIY0haM3pZcmhkZGI4?oc=5" target="_blank">'View' star Alyssa Farah Griffin says Biden 'needs to stay off all media' until election day</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Entertainment Weekly News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxOTXNhU3dXZks1NzItMjRDZDlDMUlTX1lnRXRtV2c3bkk0Z1VWd045V3lCeGZqSnV4NUwyc0tVYlFQTEJRSVRBMmcwNmwtbkV5Z1U5NE9CVlRMcUxJbVk0dTVDbnhGSmI0M2E5X3lSUk5fX3RqSEh6U3JZV1BVNlZGeDJ6N2xTTWFrWmZmcC1jN0QwZC1SZ0pDeDNaSlBBemEtRVk3TWI5NUJpUm56NWtTM18xNTlSdTZmUjVfOGdSdTbSAVZBVV95cUxQc0R2ajdicjdUdFZzRndSbkVTQnRNeWpJcGhCUFdNVVZaLUktQjhPOWI4aFFod1FOeldoX2lNV1NTd2p6OWo0VjhDMFpiS3Z0ZnY0LW9nUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Kamala Harris says she strongly disagrees with criticism of people based on who they vote for</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxQdElIOWZyeW5XTFBBNDI0MUMxdjZPUUV0dk1la1NNbjdoRVFsV1RGNlhvOURDRDRDb1ZHMFFzNDZFOEhNZ1pCbUpta1FZRXMzYkNoZjZRN093Q29pV3dFX3RVQTJJM2pnalZqaDg1VG1Iei0tcEhDWWhhMzJzTUk4LU9uMF9yZ1U?oc=5" target="_blank">Kimmel and More Late Night Hosts Mock Trump’s Garbage Truck Stunt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxObzNVRUl1bGZNeWVadDBRVmV1bDUweXI3SGN0QUxMbWFna3pyWXg2MzNnT3RfbmNEdjUzcktFaGp2MzZEYTFoSlRzU1dFVHd5VkJ4SlJqSVhvMTFXajJVTy1FbTM1eUcwQ3JDUVRoTjZySlNjdmI2LWhodDlfNWxHbTZna2FhVGlIYk45NGRDZ3BIZldFcDlmeWlRcFNZUHVUUHQ5QlFIZXlTYlRsRzZwRjJGMmw1Q0lhbGs3a1RfWE12cGdmekp1My1QUWtTaXN2X3JtbG9SWm4yUWVkYThTb25zVXhYYUx0WUdiTQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7AFBVV95cUxObzNVRUl1bGZNeWVadDBRVmV1bDUweXI3SGN0QUxMbWFna3pyWXg2MzNnT3RfbmNEdjUzcktFaGp2MzZEYTFoSlRzU1dFVHd5VkJ4SlJqSVhvMTFXajJVTy1FbTM1eUcwQ3JDUVRoTjZySlNjdmI2LWhodDlfNWxHbTZna2FhVGlIYk45NGRDZ3BIZldFcDlmeWlRcFNZUHVUUHQ5QlFIZXlTYlRsRzZwRjJGMmw1Q0lhbGs3a1RfWE12cGdmekp1My1QUWtTaXN2X3JtbG9SWm4yUWVkYThTb25zVXhYYUx0WUdiTQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[CNN Polls: Harris and Trump remain neck and neck in Georgia and North Carolina - CNN]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxOVWlyM3ZYeHFOcHY1X0VSMFpnRFlIUWRGWV9uU2NHd0ZZMW1HbXAyUXdoWUZjd1doQVpQWVR2MHRxLUN1akxiWXJmUnlaSHJ4TG54bFpldEhMSGZxY1A0R3Y4UExDNTFCWmxrTFRKSll4SUlHM1BzZU5KWTVaeDgzVjBrREdVVjlPNEHSAYABQVVfeXFMTkxIRWtrb05GRXVBNzBNNU5fRXBqSlJnZUpmWHJnOE8wUEs1TEFRMkVxaWp0Rm03b3NpTDd1LXU1YnQ4YlB0eHU3QlM0MlVnc3RPVDdpZ2hMSHM1STMwTEx3NVpDN2xOTzhuUXA1ZXlaV1dxdjYxYVhGdl9RQ1Ric1E?oc=5" target="_blank">CNN Polls: Harris and Trump remain neck and neck in Georgia and North Carolina</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxQUTFUVDlEbmJISHNfSEEyQ2VyUkJ4Q2tfbERJVFJ1dlFrajZjZGdMeF9MQldLbk02U05NRktjMloyRjdsdHZzVXUtXzlsNjNoUHd5X1c0TjBzbm5nNXJGSzBXaDllb1NMQXprUWVDckdfSEVyZWVtQTg3OE9laTY2S0ZuMHNNQ0QySXdKSW9XOEljZVlWMGdPOW5QcFNTdG03eG9GcThDbXRPTVk3RXdMNUVKSkRjZ3Vwc05kR0UyWjNmWFhyNEJRTjVweHhpNDJXcWZrbjBjSGhCOEdnajBLZGZ5XzlBM1A5?oc=5" target="_blank">Election 2024 Swing State Polls: Georgia, North Carolina Still Razor-Thin—And Pennsylvania’s A Tie (Updated)</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Forbes</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxQRFI2T3lZYkU1c010b2FDSU9CcGg5aXNfcFRkUnd5U09DSDV4YkVfdG9HaEpzcjQ4Mi1CQmZQOXFvZGZDZldCR2c4WGVJSlB2UDIzdU5JeE9tNl82RnVlVzdYeUpIRjRkY2NmWkZzaGx0RjM3dXdPUHFCZm9sT1BDenYxaklpQ0pvSU1BdGVUZ3YzZjBDNmd5R0VRWTA4bk5OOWZN0gGoAUFVX3lxTE1WRG1xdDd3OXRYb1lmVVktb2VNSWI2dEVjNXVJSmNEY0hmcjhqYzdWRDRYWGRkRDR6QWZZaFhzb2hYTGJNWW1YMjNLNDFlSENhX2dZVmdzSTRlSGFUZUVoeE8yaXJXeERxbnBhWmZWQktWX2d4WmFmOHVxcmFPcklBV3dCQU1LaVlMaTc1VDdfZnR3TU5YME1POEp1WHhIaE1ka1JON2NyRg?oc=5" target="_blank">Fox News Poll: Trump still narrowly ahead of Harris in North Carolina</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxNMy1takU5YUxqWkhWbkVXMWJIakxWdUlTMkJaTzcwdjIzUE1fUHgwa182cXhtajR4WjRtWWZxb2NiOTFvazQxdGJxMnBoWmZ5RzJjcmNtN3RRYXBCdEEwaTRfSlFoV2NjdlRJa1ItYzdHMWNSd3RlU2VTdlVfSndIR1NOQ21na2gwRV9STC1QNkZmR1VELTZKbnlodXhEeHZKMmJkMWdxZ0VHVEhsNmFIdmh2allVa21OZm5z0gHAAUFVX3lxTFBzWDhfUDFTbF9lQ1FGQll0dUlySmd4c0d0cHdDeW9TcERKU3JyVlhxUW1KVU9KbFdVY3Z5MDRENmxSc3dVUmRiVlA3eEpGUE9VUUc2ckJwZXlhTDEzdjdCZkxhWlRRcnVpcnNtcFFwRk1JU2FabDl6aDdRVUNHR3F0TFhZTlFuLVIxNHdCRk1ZUi1Yd1czWGVYckprckpPQTNvS1pXcmVKYm5qUm1xSy1WSjFlQ0pUVGN4X2IwcXFhTw?oc=5" target="_blank">‘On the razor’s edge’: How North Carolina could decide the US election</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Al Jazeera English</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxQR1ZmcVhMN3VYNE10enhtQWlONTJQMS00VWFHdnhOQ0JmYXJGYktvalV2TFFKLXFLbUd4YWZmRW1VRi1nNEtjVUtQZW9NdkJDdjFfMnpKdkpTSFh6THV0Y2lRMWROWTkzWXU3QnV0QnJfTHhnZjlvN0Z1ak9JQ2FhTlg4LV8tNHdCSHo1a05kLUd2eUlnRWdJdjNaWnNQRmRyTnJ4c1ZPdnhRc19oM1pHSnNJQlhmaEg0RHBvR2JqbXA0N3JyQVZhNUoxM0JNVDFDWTRadU0xQUdPZkk?oc=5" target="_blank">Kamala Harris and Donald Trump tied in latest North Carolina poll by SurveyUSA</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">USA TODAY</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxOVWlyM3ZYeHFOcHY1X0VSMFpnRFlIUWRGWV9uU2NHd0ZZMW1HbXAyUXdoWUZjd1doQVpQWVR2MHRxLUN1akxiWXJmUnlaSHJ4TG54bFpldEhMSGZxY1A0R3Y4UExDNTFCWmxrTFRKSll4SUlHM1BzZU5KWTVaeDgzVjBrREdVVjlPNEHSAYABQVVfeXFMTkxIRWtrb05GRXVBNzBNNU5fRXBqSlJnZUpmWHJnOE8wUEs1TEFRMkVxaWp0Rm03b3NpTDd1LXU1YnQ4YlB0eHU3QlM0MlVnc3RPVDdpZ2hMSHM1STMwTEx3NVpDN2xOTzhuUXA1ZXlaV1dxdjYxYVhGdl9RQ1Ric1E?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxOVWlyM3ZYeHFOcHY1X0VSMFpnRFlIUWRGWV9uU2NHd0ZZMW1HbXAyUXdoWUZjd1doQVpQWVR2MHRxLUN1akxiWXJmUnlaSHJ4TG54bFpldEhMSGZxY1A0R3Y4UExDNTFCWmxrTFRKSll4SUlHM1BzZU5KWTVaeDgzVjBrREdVVjlPNEHSAYABQVVfeXFMTkxIRWtrb05GRXVBNzBNNU5fRXBqSlJnZUpmWHJnOE8wUEs1TEFRMkVxaWp0Rm03b3NpTDd1LXU1YnQ4YlB0eHU3QlM0MlVnc3RPVDdpZ2hMSHM1STMwTEx3NVpDN2xOTzhuUXA1ZXlaV1dxdjYxYVhGdl9RQ1Ric1E?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 23:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[About 8,000 North Korean troops at Ukraine's border are expected in combat in days, US says - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPaDJUb3o2d3RLYndYdXl0M1dOaFV1UnhBQW40NkRRRkhxQVNqa1lPUnBjMVRYRlB0MHBSdDJWeEtERkVVSWR3VUFVRlU3Xy1qcU1qVEtMbHU3dFg3bm5Vc3Y2dmh1ZXZMVkRoY2JyT3lSMF81dXh1TEotVTNoRk4xZWZuakl1THZ6eG5lTzJrRjA2WjBMNU1xOTlwUXVRYTBlNkx4VTdOTkw?oc=5" target="_blank">About 8,000 North Korean troops at Ukraine's border are expected in combat in days, US says</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQLTEyd1ZMN2tZbkg5M1RzblM1NkZySVF3dDJQTm16LWhfQ3MtdG56eU9ZdVdJRkMyM0R2dW5HVFhsRE1xNFBEdHA3bWl3MDF3MExVd0tKTjFKZlEyQl9zVUZ1V3RkVGRzNTFMazlGWmNDME9oNDF6emwzTkstcFZJN2JZejhYbU5rRk55T21mQzE5azhuU055ZWU5M2dxTkhuRDNKWS1yMzk3LUNudmM5S1Y3RFdMd1hzWFp0TlNRRm1lNFJmRzNCV1owcms1Qm5qeERLVHU5bUtxQzVINkdFcG1B?oc=5" target="_blank">'A war of two countries against one' — Zelensky urges Western allies to take decisive action on North Korean troop involvement</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Kyiv Independent</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxNVVJGWHpVQVVnSEtWVl9CNnk4YVVVQ2lwZHlYeGpEYTVLNzExUFRYbk9RekJaT3o5R01KTDBSY3ZSUG5ueHB1Nlh4bC1SRnV3WURXRzZScm9sZ0NaUVpKTzJaZkF5NUh0N3h5bm1rc3FGTWpMYzJUcTBtWDE5TW05WWxhNWZmcm8tbUs0dFlqSElNZWpKOG9FNVVGRk85TmxiN0QwMk9ZUHNlVTFmRS0yd3pqaEdTVmNtLVNVZnk4bzFmeDd1S1E?oc=5" target="_blank">North Korean Soldiers Likely to Enter Russian War on Ukraine</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Department of Defense</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxQMXh6WnNVd3VpOXlOdjhrZG5pVHZUZlY2cGZXMDBzeExBaDRPLWd2X0VuSXVQZHRmNmRuRFpWaEVMZWlhVWp0TlVYdkNYMkJmSldaWDNLQ2M4VDhOYVlQVlN2Z193LTVoN0VuWGdJVU9lcU8xd0hucnptOGQ4OHhpSWRjR0RZa0ZjbXpr?oc=5" target="_blank">U.S. Turns to China to Stop North Korean Troops From Fighting for Russia</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxNTzk4NW9Ja0tDWkwzNXJaUTdFSWg3dVhGekZnRlhTV2hQLS02VGJJZklpMFVFWEliQVBtVU9sY01fWV96aEN6SlF4TnZwYnB1eWhNV3ZZcUQxZWpIZy1Gb2ZLMnhiT3UxekNTbzc5V1hqNmRaUlpuUTdBNkN4dzlxM1AxaE5tTXR5VlRnM1k2NWFMa05UOU5CMjVwMA?oc=5" target="_blank">US says 8,000 North Korean troops in Russia's Kursk</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPaDJUb3o2d3RLYndYdXl0M1dOaFV1UnhBQW40NkRRRkhxQVNqa1lPUnBjMVRYRlB0MHBSdDJWeEtERkVVSWR3VUFVRlU3Xy1qcU1qVEtMbHU3dFg3bm5Vc3Y2dmh1ZXZMVkRoY2JyT3lSMF81dXh1TEotVTNoRk4xZWZuakl1THZ6eG5lTzJrRjA2WjBMNU1xOTlwUXVRYTBlNkx4VTdOTkw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPaDJUb3o2d3RLYndYdXl0M1dOaFV1UnhBQW40NkRRRkhxQVNqa1lPUnBjMVRYRlB0MHBSdDJWeEtERkVVSWR3VUFVRlU3Xy1qcU1qVEtMbHU3dFg3bm5Vc3Y2dmh1ZXZMVkRoY2JyT3lSMF81dXh1TEotVTNoRk4xZWZuakl1THZ6eG5lTzJrRjA2WjBMNU1xOTlwUXVRYTBlNkx4VTdOTkw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump lagging in early vote with seniors in Pennsylvania, a red flag for GOP - POLITICO]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxQOTR2X2wxeXhLc3pxTTJheklwREhlRUpPQ2xEYklKT0dwX2pjcjN4Vzc0S0F6aTRyS1RFcmNhdEpyT2ZGN0x5SmVlN09aNXBIT1hpbmpkOG5HZFZQdDRQSlNhd0R1MGR2c3BpUnlrVVdFNEFtOWZFcV9BbFF5aEVsbWl0SFFfWWFJcExqRkJ5bWJudEx2SU9rN3g1bkI?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump lagging in early vote with seniors in Pennsylvania, a red flag for GOP</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxOeHhFbUE5b3F1X21vSTFKNDFYYW8xNEdPWGRzWGpobHNDNHRvRm1VZGp1VjVfamxDVlByZXlZQUxfS2l4WW9ISjRXTHg2WUdwZDhCQW44TjRtbFdhU05IdVZfV3pPUElaMUprTlIwSF9telR0TU1neVZzY1R4SEgxOEw1UzB1VXI0enpsV3ZxWDVDUW41MkJvcURtb2lHT2JkVURCc0pfWjZwUVpVdzZaYllTbXFvTFFUT1V3cGZtUC1FRU5Td1d6bHpGeXhkajdGUkYyVE1uOXNQS2pkcnVSUzF4bUNQaXo4eGsxUVBQS05Wd09lOWdLcTQ4d1hzZ2hP?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump-Harris Swing State Polls: Here's Who Leads In The Key 2024 Election Battlegrounds</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Forbes</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxPOFVhbUVTTXZTQmNiSk5JU0l0cVhJMVVWcUk0MUp1UTRueTQ4R0FGMzhrWm9TYkFVX1d1dUVwSDZEcHB0REhwNUM3enlTb0tsNG5pM3V3NmxKWDd4VUlWSFIyY09mRzZyV3JlTmR1QTRsTE9qNFpOSEhrazF3by1kODF1elE?oc=5" target="_blank">The 2024 election could hinge on Pennsylvania</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMif0FVX3lxTE9ISFVtY2ZCLXlzQlNmYm1kVHAyTDRMOHhEbXFaaklKZGkxNDJpUHR0TE9aY2dYX2RqTUYySzhRVkdEcDkwUm9JZC1JNF94dE05WkNpcm9EcUVJOG9TWW00Q0NrSzlJNHlKVUJOc2drUzMwajJUZTlUMWlmTEllTVk?oc=5" target="_blank">It’s Really, Really Close</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Monmouth University</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQenNYVk9GQ1lrRUg3ZC1fWkpPU3AxS25kNlZld0VGSUVacmNGaXRzdXpHcV9xQnhNOUdlNUJnSTZIenRsYmF6TG40a0NrcVczcExIbHJmM2xISGlJaC1TWDliRUNJckJjWVJ0ckJxWDZLZDlMcXU0cEVLaUxpUTRSN01TemNmOG41SkZGR2V3dUFaS1ZCODlrS0RxT3M4a2FvaEd2NDM3SXZEQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump Allies Issue Warning That He Could Lose Critical Battleground State</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Newsweek</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxQOTR2X2wxeXhLc3pxTTJheklwREhlRUpPQ2xEYklKT0dwX2pjcjN4Vzc0S0F6aTRyS1RFcmNhdEpyT2ZGN0x5SmVlN09aNXBIT1hpbmpkOG5HZFZQdDRQSlNhd0R1MGR2c3BpUnlrVVdFNEFtOWZFcV9BbFF5aEVsbWl0SFFfWWFJcExqRkJ5bWJudEx2SU9rN3g1bkI?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxQOTR2X2wxeXhLc3pxTTJheklwREhlRUpPQ2xEYklKT0dwX2pjcjN4Vzc0S0F6aTRyS1RFcmNhdEpyT2ZGN0x5SmVlN09aNXBIT1hpbmpkOG5HZFZQdDRQSlNhd0R1MGR2c3BpUnlrVVdFNEFtOWZFcV9BbFF5aEVsbWl0SFFfWWFJcExqRkJ5bWJudEx2SU9rN3g1bkI?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:15:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Republicans criminally refer Andrew Cuomo over 'false' Covid report statements - NBC News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxNQXk1XzI4RnRPWFhLS1gydEFnUjBXZUtHZVRzQVVvS0J0cVV2X2t2R1ZMY2VQelVmRk4wLVZzX2lfMnRTeXZrb1ltNDRTaHBEeW45dWRNMjJfLW9RbElsS2ZaVlRmRGhZLTM4cHp0V0kxWUEtZi1aREd4VFlaQkFkQVJrRUctamVwSjJPQTNNQktNaFNPQlZZSExTVHFsR2gyZl9IdW5YaFQ2SEJEaThpX3F1a3dtNk1vNTZBT1dmZ01jUWh5aC1V0gFWQVVfeXFMTW01YzRWMDJocTQyTFlNWjJQb3liQzBaZENkSXIyU2FVcnFYUFlxbmdIZUx6bWdRWWwxM3B0eFRMT1FIalcxX2dnZVhHdjhBRVl1Y1ZVN3c?oc=5" target="_blank">House Republicans criminally refer Andrew Cuomo over 'false' Covid report statements</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQak5JdDZwajJwc2FMc0tHYVF0LTRzeGM4SmVzSHl6QkFsMnpfbGVkc1preG1QVVhKZWpSRUQzN0ladkgyTGRQQ3lhYzRrb2VkOEF3c2pPb2cwV2dNOWdUcEZkeGgtN3FnV3ZaaExHTFpaRV9sSXVTTC1rVWwxSV9RMzdMNktoZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Once a Covid star, ex-Gov. Andrew Cuomo stares down criminal referral</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPNXZmVk5PWjZGZDZaQmNVVDRGNTNwTzJDakJDd0wzbG5UWFpKeWdWLUdoQXlSOGVZWDMtRWV5Q2dodkFxS3BpcDUydFozNkZfeEt4QzVETzZMSm81MTRxTVF3X0tEZUJ0M2FiMF9VWkxGR05MaDVtcFVxZDduUG9ZSngtOHRwRzFFcFN6Y3lqNEtNRXVaRS1tUld5SXFjYmFXQXBqMGJIRFfSAZ8BQVVfeXFMUGlXZjJHUFVKNHUxblZHMUhLSS1TaVcyX052dXdocGMweXg3eS1waTJTVkJMWm40X2taRTF5MHZVYzVoX0ZkbktSZkdLWHNqazc1cGxUTHA5NU9DblJYM0tSUXhZTnVveUlsb2p1amh4VHQxVVJSUmdDNzJFV2lyZmtXNVE1WkdkakJHVnluUFJ6UG9uOHVtWGI1eW9FWm5Z?oc=5" target="_blank">GOP-led House panel to refer former NY Gov. Cuomo to DOJ for potential prosecution over report on Covid nursing home deaths</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE5VUHRrc1E3NE5GUXczQl9aQlN1RE9LNjdjbFdhTVhuUEZCazFqNzYxemk1X1owYWhGOFZ2QkUzcm1PTUtmYU92bTFiZzA4V0QxNDNRNkcyVGx0eTRTYVQzMW00bjdJejhBeXpuTFY1UU9wSDg0WkwwaE15T1otdw?oc=5" target="_blank">Cuomo Told a House Panel His Memory Was Hazy. Is That a Perjury Defense?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxPT0swQXozRWdUeXplYnVhdzUzSXVoSElsekVTTV9xZ3JsTEJldS04OGdNMTVoNnVVZXR0NDQ5Z3FVc0FHRWRLaEk4bmNZQUlfbjlQSlo2NEtaMmwzVXRDS0NGY1RtQ0thRTFibEgwQkVjSlU1NVJ2djl4OFR0dndMd21UR0hyMHNZUVUtdE91Mm9xRWdENi1rMHdrQ25zbU1PRGczeDB6V0JRbVZ5WTA4N0c2OXN4Q3ViblHSAb8BQVVfeXFMTVRmcVJoVDY3NVo5djFMcE9RMVlCVDJJeFVUMHoxMzRPekJTVkY1ZElxVHlVR01CekFJVlh3M2JRUEU5Z2lLVWhxcnRyWW1PWDNuZEFpRkhaYnJGUlVKRDNDaGIzS3ZrMTNVU1dvb2NXT1p4ZEk0S3c5MS1tcnk5blU1LWRsR1F1WGNLaUJsTDdOeEdHaXF0WC0yZHFpNWRWeDJRR2ozMTh6cTN1aDhLaFQ0UHpnVnRhQW1EdF9xRW8?oc=5" target="_blank">Former NY Gov. Andrew Cuomo referred to DOJ for prosecution by House subcommittee: report</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxNQXk1XzI4RnRPWFhLS1gydEFnUjBXZUtHZVRzQVVvS0J0cVV2X2t2R1ZMY2VQelVmRk4wLVZzX2lfMnRTeXZrb1ltNDRTaHBEeW45dWRNMjJfLW9RbElsS2ZaVlRmRGhZLTM4cHp0V0kxWUEtZi1aREd4VFlaQkFkQVJrRUctamVwSjJPQTNNQktNaFNPQlZZSExTVHFsR2gyZl9IdW5YaFQ2SEJEaThpX3F1a3dtNk1vNTZBT1dmZ01jUWh5aC1V0gFWQVVfeXFMTW01YzRWMDJocTQyTFlNWjJQb3liQzBaZENkSXIyU2FVcnFYUFlxbmdIZUx6bWdRWWwxM3B0eFRMT1FIalcxX2dnZVhHdjhBRVl1Y1ZVN3c?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxNQXk1XzI4RnRPWFhLS1gydEFnUjBXZUtHZVRzQVVvS0J0cVV2X2t2R1ZMY2VQelVmRk4wLVZzX2lfMnRTeXZrb1ltNDRTaHBEeW45dWRNMjJfLW9RbElsS2ZaVlRmRGhZLTM4cHp0V0kxWUEtZi1aREd4VFlaQkFkQVJrRUctamVwSjJPQTNNQktNaFNPQlZZSExTVHFsR2gyZl9IdW5YaFQ2SEJEaThpX3F1a3dtNk1vNTZBT1dmZ01jUWh5aC1V0gFWQVVfeXFMTW01YzRWMDJocTQyTFlNWjJQb3liQzBaZENkSXIyU2FVcnFYUFlxbmdIZUx6bWdRWWwxM3B0eFRMT1FIalcxX2dnZVhHdjhBRVl1Y1ZVN3c?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 17:12:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel strikes Lebanon’s ancient city of Baalbek, as tens of thousands of people flee - NPR]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxOMG5xWVQ2bUhvOW1mUjFwdFFtR1FHMWlRUXFuWnJ4NDFXUzdCSUp5TWJLSjU2a2xGdFdTR3ZVU0tnbkRuNWxxdE5NOWtnQV9GNlVLSUp5d0swMzNTUWdQbGthbHhrUGRzbVc5cmJiMjd0NWp1Zll2d2ZpOWx6aU5aMVpnaUs?oc=5" target="_blank">Israel strikes Lebanon’s ancient city of Baalbek, as tens of thousands of people flee</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font><strong><a href="https://news.google.com/stories/CAAqNggKIjBDQklTSGpvSmMzUnZjbmt0TXpZd1NoRUtEd2pSOHY3UURCRVFwYkZFQURXbUxDZ0FQAQ?hl=en-US&gl=US&ceid=US:en&oc=5" target="_blank">View Full Coverage on Google News</a></strong>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxOMG5xWVQ2bUhvOW1mUjFwdFFtR1FHMWlRUXFuWnJ4NDFXUzdCSUp5TWJLSjU2a2xGdFdTR3ZVU0tnbkRuNWxxdE5NOWtnQV9GNlVLSUp5d0swMzNTUWdQbGthbHhrUGRzbVc5cmJiMjd0NWp1Zll2d2ZpOWx6aU5aMVpnaUs?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxOMG5xWVQ2bUhvOW1mUjFwdFFtR1FHMWlRUXFuWnJ4NDFXUzdCSUp5TWJLSjU2a2xGdFdTR3ZVU0tnbkRuNWxxdE5NOWtnQV9GNlVLSUp5d0swMzNTUWdQbGthbHhrUGRzbVc5cmJiMjd0NWp1Zll2d2ZpOWx6aU5aMVpnaUs?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:04:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea’s long-range missile test signals its improved, potential capability to attack US - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxNT1Vjek1IbnVTb0VDc29fNzRMbklxWmx6QWt6T0c2MU1oN0F4U2F3WlJzZk9JU2NpcnROLXJmbVVReFdOb2kyR0VVWjRnZEF4WDB3d08zS3dxRnhOR3haQU1ySzROR0pyeU56bDdwRzE4R0xIaW9ISEI3VzlZTkY5MGo1OHY4ekVVVC02c1IyZw?oc=5" target="_blank">North Korea’s long-range missile test signals its improved, potential capability to attack US</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxQSTZLS0hmNVotekFQdlR2cjYteDc0dmliY3YtZGhlaWlBb3E3NXJiQ21tSkNESzRtUkQ4ajlZcmFVbW5CYkczRi02RGx5YnBEdGUtS3dhdVRvWm1jd0Vnd2xZMHhJNjctRWV1dG5XMy1DNlhIdXUtWE1rODZIeWhaMFk4WG9CVXN6T1pOakJEUGV4VEZZ?oc=5" target="_blank">North Korea tests new ICBM as its troops appear set to join Ukraine war</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNandEVlQ2S1VnZ0xDS2JCU2tmVE14d3FzeHpfVlVrYjh5RDNVN3hDSm1hbExIM1pjcl9WOFhSa3IweVJQVzRzOEwyQWxic1ZNajd5cWNMb3lUSWFMUmNNX0dJQXJHeHpwNHd2cWt5M0NHMXRJX3ozdkZqVUljMWdCdTJlMGNRRF9vbjZ6WUhzVVZBYk0zZTZBcHZJNkMxaHlJTjQteUptVXJ6RkXSAbABQVVfeXFMTlB5alF2WFJHU3lZdjZ6ck1qUS1SeWtES001TXpjOUtYaVlYYkZiN2FaSF9RbDZaZEFqMkZmeHFwRy1HTTN2eGRiNE9CZWJfYmRBOXlNYjRvc3FickpIU0huUGc1Q09sMnNPSFdTWmtFN2lZa2tvTENLZ21nbndHUHZ6czQ0SWgxS0tFY1F2QUVJWUh0Q0dNZDlBOXY0OWdOQ0lfbHZaMHJtUEI1bkJpQk8?oc=5" target="_blank">North Korea ICBM launch intended as message to 'rivals,' Kim says</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxPNDRLMXZvd1R5TFBNWk5iLTVCUnFHMTduOEV6N1RYWDZVdTM1X2Z5LUw1MnhIUldONXUzekNwXzRueFYydU1xVjU2b3ExakYwR0JQbjdZenpLVWVZRmVrOUtlVllodXR2VktuZXpSQjFFaDRhTVl6X1RUSU9QMFdZMk5acHhRcHVMbkgydkNQMHFXbWZYX3Rnc3JHUW5jQ1pfbE1TSENXS0daNE1PWU9oTmNpaXZMbzNuUU1fSklzclZXd09XSnJMa2VNWG4?oc=5" target="_blank">North Korea says record test was new Hwasong-19 intercontinental ballistic missile</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxQTDFldnFRSzhwNjl0c2FJRWN1LUFSRFgycEVBcm5vZ1ZuTVZHclJvOUJjM1I0X1pMa0tHRDVZR0pMN2NlWVpXV052T3ZfSUR1cUd0LXRGVlRVUFNDRklyTXgzZEE0RTl6YUg5TjhMWmFWRl94bmdLQzVKcWNzVjFhcjNkRC1hQlo3bEJzRFZndjJ1S1lkenpkM3NR?oc=5" target="_blank">North Korea test-launches long-range missile</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxNT1Vjek1IbnVTb0VDc29fNzRMbklxWmx6QWt6T0c2MU1oN0F4U2F3WlJzZk9JU2NpcnROLXJmbVVReFdOb2kyR0VVWjRnZEF4WDB3d08zS3dxRnhOR3haQU1ySzROR0pyeU56bDdwRzE4R0xIaW9ISEI3VzlZTkY5MGo1OHY4ekVVVC02c1IyZw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxNT1Vjek1IbnVTb0VDc29fNzRMbklxWmx6QWt6T0c2MU1oN0F4U2F3WlJzZk9JU2NpcnROLXJmbVVReFdOb2kyR0VVWjRnZEF4WDB3d08zS3dxRnhOR3haQU1ySzROR0pyeU56bDdwRzE4R0xIaW9ISEI3VzlZTkY5MGo1OHY4ekVVVC02c1IyZw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:56:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[IDF hits north Gaza’s last functioning hospital, officials say; U.S. envoys visit Israel]]></title><description><![CDATA[Israel attacked Kamal Adwan Hospital, Gaza authorities said. White House officials Amos Hochstein and Brett McGurk are in Israel to meet with top leaders.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/31/israel-iran-war-news-lebanon-gaza-palestine/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/31/israel-iran-war-news-lebanon-gaza-palestine/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 23:54:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[On Baalbek’s edges, the displaced watch strikes rain down on their city]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fleeing the Lebanese city of Baalbek ahead of Israeli airstrikes, thousands find shelter — but not necessarily peace of mind — in Deir al-Ahmar.   ]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/31/baalbek-lebanon-israel-hezbollah-displaced/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/31/baalbek-lebanon-israel-hezbollah-displaced/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 23:07:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea tests new ICBM as its troops appear set to join Ukraine war]]></title><description><![CDATA[U.S. officials condemned Pyongyang’s launch of a powerful new ballistic missile and called on China to rein in North Korea’s cooperation with Russia.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/30/north-korea-ballistic-missile-launch-icbm/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/30/north-korea-ballistic-missile-launch-icbm/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 21:02:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel has damaged or destroyed nearly a quarter of buildings in Lebanon’s south]]></title><description><![CDATA[More than 5,000 structures have been affected in border villages, including at least nine religious sites demolished in controlled explosions, a Post analysis found.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/31/israel-war-lebanon-south-destruction/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/31/israel-war-lebanon-south-destruction/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:18:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[U.S. diplomacy over Lebanon, Gaza sees little apparent progress]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:49:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Canada prepares for U.S. election that ‘keeps people up at night’]]></title><description><![CDATA[Canada is dispatching top officials across the United States to stave off policies that could harm its interests if Trump returns to office.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/31/canada-election-trudeau-trump-harris/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/31/canada-election-trudeau-trump-harris/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:45:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[China built a $50 billion military stronghold in the South China Sea ]]></title><description><![CDATA[See how China has spent tens of billions of dollars turning farm fields and seaports into military complexes on Hainan and remote outposts in the South China Sea.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/interactive/2024/china-built-50-billion-military-stronghold-south-china-sea/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/interactive/2024/china-built-50-billion-military-stronghold-south-china-sea/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:52:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israeli attacks in Lebanon kill 6 paramedics, government says]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:49:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel attacks north Gaza hospital amid growing concern over humanitarian conditions]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 11:35:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Russian drones hunt civilians in streets of southern Ukrainian city]]></title><description><![CDATA[With Russian forces just over the river, Kherson has turned into a hunting ground for drones that appear to be focusing mainly on civilians. ]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/31/kherson-ukraine-russia-drone-attacks/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/31/kherson-ukraine-russia-drone-attacks/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 08:00:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How U.S. elections could shape Israel’s multifront Middle East war]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 06:21:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea’s elite troops are in Russia to fight Ukraine: What we know]]></title><description><![CDATA[The North Korean special forces sent to Russia are the state’s best trained troops but they will face challenges with modern warfare technology, experts say.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/29/north-korea-elite-troops-russia-ukraine-war/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/29/north-korea-elite-troops-russia-ukraine-war/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 05:01:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel issues first citywide evacuation order in Lebanon; new head of Hezbollah delivers first address]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Biden administration has asked Israel to explain what it called a “horrifying” attack on Beit Lahia, in northern Gaza, that resulted in heavy civilian losses.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/30/israel-iran-war-news-gaza-palestine-hamas/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/30/israel-iran-war-news-gaza-palestine-hamas/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:34:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel orders Baalbek evacuation as Hezbollah chief vows to fight]]></title><description><![CDATA[It was the first citywide evacuation notice Israel has issued in its five-week war, forcing thousands to flee the ancient city and UNESCO world heritage site.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/30/israel-baalbek-lebanon-hezbollah/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/30/israel-baalbek-lebanon-hezbollah/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 21:58:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel issues first citywide evacuation order in Lebanon]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 20:33:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[U.S. inundated with claims that American arms killed Gaza civilians]]></title><description><![CDATA[The State Department has received hundreds of reports that Israel’s use of U.S. weapons is responsible for excessive civilian casualties in Gaza.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2024/10/30/us-weapons-israel-gaza-civilian-deaths/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2024/10/30/us-weapons-israel-gaza-civilian-deaths/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 20:30:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hezbollah, seeking stability, names new leader after Nasrallah’s killing]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hezbollah said Naim Qassem — the former deputy of Hasan Nasrallah, who was assassinated by Israel last month — would helm the militant and political group.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/29/hezbollah-new-leader-naim-qassem/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/29/hezbollah-new-leader-naim-qassem/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 19:22:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How U.S. elections could shape Israel’s multifront Middle East war]]></title><description><![CDATA[Officials and analysts say the outcome of Tuesday’s vote between Donald Trump and Kamala Harris could have major implications for Israeli actions in Iran and Gaza. ]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/30/us-elections-trump-harris-israel-iran-gaza/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/30/us-elections-trump-harris-israel-iran-gaza/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 19:00:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Naim Qassem, new head of Hezbollah, delivers first address in role]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 14:29:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[IDF provides first explanation of circumstances surrounding north Gaza strike]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 12:14:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[U.S. inundated with claims that American arms killed Gaza civilians ]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 12:01:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine accuses Russia of sudden spike in POW killings]]></title><description><![CDATA[Russia has denied reports of a spike in the killings of those surrendering, but Russian officials have called for showing Ukrainian soldiers no mercy.]]></description><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/30/russia-ukraine-pow-executions/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/10/30/russia-ukraine-pow-executions/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 07:00:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How U.S. elections could shape Israel’s multifront Middle East war ]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 05:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hezbollah, seeking stability, names new leader after Nasrallah’s killing]]></title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 05:03:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zelenskyy: Ukraine will not cede territory, regardless of US election results]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggpiev/zelenskyy_ukraine_will_not_cede_territory/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/4nM7r36gYv4X4BfJtJC3lv5OAdo63UUyjCu3vxOVRIE.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=5d28e1bc80fe6b19dada0a1d8a883a858084ffe1" alt="Zelenskyy: Ukraine will not cede territory, regardless of US election results" title="Zelenskyy: Ukraine will not cede territory, regardless of US election results" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Silly-avocatoe"> /u/Silly-avocatoe </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2024/10/31/7482361/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggpiev/zelenskyy_ukraine_will_not_cede_territory/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggpiev/zelenskyy_ukraine_will_not_cede_territory/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggpiev/zelenskyy_ukraine_will_not_cede_territory/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Silly-avocatoe]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 21:25:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zelenskiy blasts allies for 'zero' response to North Korean deployment]]></title><description><![CDATA[&#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/VictorEmmanuelIV"> /u/VictorEmmanuelIV </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/ukraines-zelenskiy-blasts-allies-zero-response-nkorean-deployment-2024-10-31/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggmxl7/zelenskiy_blasts_allies_for_zero_response_to/">[comments]</a></span>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggmxl7/zelenskiy_blasts_allies_for_zero_response_to/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggmxl7/zelenskiy_blasts_allies_for_zero_response_to/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/VictorEmmanuelIV]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:32:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hezbollah rockets hit UN peacekeeping base]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggq051/hezbollah_rockets_hit_un_peacekeeping_base/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/fZ6ME8p4Z2oWCgVdeHTEIZOTP4fCTGgJevixsW8ia3U.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=f52e15930217cae9b88a1fa7c8af4f0ef1a11de8" alt="Hezbollah rockets hit UN peacekeeping base" title="Hezbollah rockets hit UN peacekeeping base" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Gato__negro"> /u/Gato__negro </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cqxw9ny2dyeo">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggq051/hezbollah_rockets_hit_un_peacekeeping_base/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggq051/hezbollah_rockets_hit_un_peacekeeping_base/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggq051/hezbollah_rockets_hit_un_peacekeeping_base/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Gato__negro]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 21:47:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iran preparing major retaliatory strike from Iraq within days, Israeli intel suggests]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gglwm4/iran_preparing_major_retaliatory_strike_from_iraq/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/c8vtsgHwqGQF4rZMfcuvLi1QUmPkxwtEgNjbHSybfEc.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=b5bb04a0d72ddb90abf0e680461124d13c88d2e5" alt="Iran preparing major retaliatory strike from Iraq within days, Israeli intel suggests" title="Iran preparing major retaliatory strike from Iraq within days, Israeli intel suggests" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/DerpDerper909"> /u/DerpDerper909 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/10/31/israel-iran-planning-attack-iraq">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gglwm4/iran_preparing_major_retaliatory_strike_from_iraq/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gglwm4/iran_preparing_major_retaliatory_strike_from_iraq/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gglwm4/iran_preparing_major_retaliatory_strike_from_iraq/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/DerpDerper909]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:48:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iran’s Ayatollah orders retaliatory attack against Israel after IDF strike deemed too big to ignore: report]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggs3qu/irans_ayatollah_orders_retaliatory_attack_against/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/la8h5rvkd1fW0xKW6M2v-PcUovz8IQlT2De-Ys5NT58.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=69aab253bb363c5c7e9434e6e7004396be44056c" alt="Iran’s Ayatollah orders retaliatory attack against Israel after IDF strike deemed too big to ignore: report" title="Iran’s Ayatollah orders retaliatory attack against Israel after IDF strike deemed too big to ignore: report" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/ObjectiveAd6551"> /u/ObjectiveAd6551 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/31/world-news/ayatollah-orders-retaliatory-attack-against-israel-after-idf-strike-deemed-too-big-to-ignore-report/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggs3qu/irans_ayatollah_orders_retaliatory_attack_against/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggs3qu/irans_ayatollah_orders_retaliatory_attack_against/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggs3qu/irans_ayatollah_orders_retaliatory_attack_against/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/ObjectiveAd6551]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 23:29:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[About 8,000 North Korean soldiers at Ukraine border, says US]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gguv36/about_8000_north_korean_soldiers_at_ukraine/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/KUuVuL2juXLyGLk7bVp_m5QQQiHkqL_TXk6gAJ4MTHo.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=ccbde92678bb3d5b0e1456333045aa9f7ba392d1" alt="About 8,000 North Korean soldiers at Ukraine border, says US" title="About 8,000 North Korean soldiers at Ukraine border, says US" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Gyro_Armadillo"> /u/Gyro_Armadillo </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/north-korean-soldiers-at-ukraine-border-says-us">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gguv36/about_8000_north_korean_soldiers_at_ukraine/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gguv36/about_8000_north_korean_soldiers_at_ukraine/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gguv36/about_8000_north_korean_soldiers_at_ukraine/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Gyro_Armadillo]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 01:52:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US puts 19 Indian firms on sanctions list, says helped Russia with materials, tech]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggucb3/us_puts_19_indian_firms_on_sanctions_list_says/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/B9_IHaWnYtAD2Zsn-MEWzm684y817enT1ot92Zum608.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=3eae801afcbc0855b7bf0923ee614353174f942a" alt="US puts 19 Indian firms on sanctions list, says helped Russia with materials, tech" title="US puts 19 Indian firms on sanctions list, says helped Russia with materials, tech" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/BlitzOrion"> /u/BlitzOrion </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/us-sanction-indian-firm-supplies-russian-companies-9647140/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggucb3/us_puts_19_indian_firms_on_sanctions_list_says/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggucb3/us_puts_19_indian_firms_on_sanctions_list_says/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggucb3/us_puts_19_indian_firms_on_sanctions_list_says/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/BlitzOrion]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 01:23:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea: North Korea troops will become cannon fodder in Ukraine]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggckha/south_korea_north_korea_troops_will_become_cannon/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/n1VD_2dauYQGpt0xA7GZvUJqadx2FcKUp39rtz2yg90.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=c6420f6e3833bd02163c997390088ae21c7c2c2d" alt="South Korea: North Korea troops will become cannon fodder in Ukraine" title="South Korea: North Korea troops will become cannon fodder in Ukraine" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/ObjectiveAd6551"> /u/ObjectiveAd6551 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/north-korea-troops-become-cannon-fodder-ukraine-2024-10">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggckha/south_korea_north_korea_troops_will_become_cannon/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggckha/south_korea_north_korea_troops_will_become_cannon/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggckha/south_korea_north_korea_troops_will_become_cannon/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/ObjectiveAd6551]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 11:49:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Germany orders shutdown of all Iranian consulates – DW – 10/31/2024]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggeyx0/germany_orders_shutdown_of_all_iranian_consulates/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/5YVUlSbTu7wvbXQrIe11R0m4Ljit77UMD8eUcIIF7P8.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=c301674017bf58f31ab93d2de82f778bd65aeb76" alt="Germany orders shutdown of all Iranian consulates – DW – 10/31/2024" title="Germany orders shutdown of all Iranian consulates – DW – 10/31/2024" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/_M_F_H"> /u/_M_F_H </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.dw.com/en/germany-orders-shutdown-of-all-iranian-consulates/a-70650421?mobileApp=true">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggeyx0/germany_orders_shutdown_of_all_iranian_consulates/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggeyx0/germany_orders_shutdown_of_all_iranian_consulates/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggeyx0/germany_orders_shutdown_of_all_iranian_consulates/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/_M_F_H]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 13:49:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukrainian drone strikes Russian oil refinery 1,500 km from border, Russian official claims]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggtrfy/ukrainian_drone_strikes_russian_oil_refinery_1500/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/TUX1rixeWkeeCnIzKnHabznCBvev0epbBuzCZnTNn9o.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=ec21c136ff7c13d3506e5ba2cb84e4e73d2a03ab" alt="Ukrainian drone strikes Russian oil refinery 1,500 km from border, Russian official claims" title="Ukrainian drone strikes Russian oil refinery 1,500 km from border, Russian official claims" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/BothZookeepergame612"> /u/BothZookeepergame612 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://kyivindependent.com/ukrainian-drone-strikes-russian-oil-refinery-1-500-km-from-ukrainian-border-russian-official-claims/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggtrfy/ukrainian_drone_strikes_russian_oil_refinery_1500/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggtrfy/ukrainian_drone_strikes_russian_oil_refinery_1500/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggtrfy/ukrainian_drone_strikes_russian_oil_refinery_1500/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/BothZookeepergame612]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:53:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Backlash builds over Hungary joining Russia, Syria and Belarus at security summit]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggcku1/backlash_builds_over_hungary_joining_russia_syria/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/McosXy2Fn4EpHUpzdFgomJ3QkvS8fyoRB1OCax2eK9I.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=65e3dc23359c3afce27fd259c8d29cfaa09543eb" alt="Backlash builds over Hungary joining Russia, Syria and Belarus at security summit" title="Backlash builds over Hungary joining Russia, Syria and Belarus at security summit" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/IndistinctChatters"> /u/IndistinctChatters </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/european-officials-react-to-hungary-joining-russia-syria-and-belarus-at-security-summit/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggcku1/backlash_builds_over_hungary_joining_russia_syria/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggcku1/backlash_builds_over_hungary_joining_russia_syria/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggcku1/backlash_builds_over_hungary_joining_russia_syria/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/IndistinctChatters]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 11:49:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spain searches for bodies after unprecedented flooding claims at least 158 lives]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gggwnb/spain_searches_for_bodies_after_unprecedented/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/9T10H5y4tPoCH4v0Nuy9HBe394-8UVGuip8rHEWvL8w.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=c1b7f51787741fb4680e72c6341bf731150e8a1d" alt="Spain searches for bodies after unprecedented flooding claims at least 158 lives" title="Spain searches for bodies after unprecedented flooding claims at least 158 lives" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/ItsHollyHunt"> /u/ItsHollyHunt </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://apnews.com/article/flash-floods-spain-valencia-climate-change-30c6ef59ddf27598c691c89d0ba41442">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gggwnb/spain_searches_for_bodies_after_unprecedented/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gggwnb/spain_searches_for_bodies_after_unprecedented/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gggwnb/spain_searches_for_bodies_after_unprecedented/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/ItsHollyHunt]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 15:13:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[21,000 workers dead in 8 years of Mohammed bin Salman's ‘Saudi vision 2030’: Report]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gg6zzf/21000_workers_dead_in_8_years_of_mohammed_bin/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/QzwoHw73hJ5vJn3PYe04AUF7sVrZsiFO0dPoexZGV_o.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=948fca8a3334afdb2fe33760989154f24adc22c5" alt="21,000 workers dead in 8 years of Mohammed bin Salman's ‘Saudi vision 2030’: Report" title="21,000 workers dead in 8 years of Mohammed bin Salman's ‘Saudi vision 2030’: Report" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/rustyyryan"> /u/rustyyryan </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/21000-workers-dead-in-8-years-of-mohammed-bin-salmans-saudi-vision-2030-report-101730127065962.html">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gg6zzf/21000_workers_dead_in_8_years_of_mohammed_bin/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gg6zzf/21000_workers_dead_in_8_years_of_mohammed_bin/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gg6zzf/21000_workers_dead_in_8_years_of_mohammed_bin/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/rustyyryan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 05:04:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine's UN envoy names North Korean generals sent to aid Russia's war]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggjpi1/ukraines_un_envoy_names_north_korean_generals/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/BqtXo5VLntCcnHhdpAr9gu-_IBeaIG1PTZ6IH32hRhg.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=45647dd2f2ba9f2e3171e208581aa2c7eea0fd7e" alt="Ukraine's UN envoy names North Korean generals sent to aid Russia's war" title="Ukraine's UN envoy names North Korean generals sent to aid Russia's war" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/BothZookeepergame612"> /u/BothZookeepergame612 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://kyivindependent.com/ukraine-names-north-korean-generals/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggjpi1/ukraines_un_envoy_names_north_korean_generals/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggjpi1/ukraines_un_envoy_names_north_korean_generals/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggjpi1/ukraines_un_envoy_names_north_korean_generals/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/BothZookeepergame612]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 17:14:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukrainian troops fighting on Russian soil have an advantage they've never had in this war]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gghm6n/ukrainian_troops_fighting_on_russian_soil_have_an/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/Soql6q-WESXywB-IlxY9R47h0W6a00kv9TooZHdz8hk.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=4ae0ffd9dd5e5bc42a74943d23ec01259a42d685" alt="Ukrainian troops fighting on Russian soil have an advantage they've never had in this war" title="Ukrainian troops fighting on Russian soil have an advantage they've never had in this war" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/ItsAvaMorgan"> /u/ItsAvaMorgan </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/ukrainian-troops-fighting-russian-soil-090702654.html">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gghm6n/ukrainian_troops_fighting_on_russian_soil_have_an/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gghm6n/ukrainian_troops_fighting_on_russian_soil_have_an/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1gghm6n/ukrainian_troops_fighting_on_russian_soil_have_an/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/ItsAvaMorgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 15:43:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Global LGBTQ group suspends Israeli organization, angering queer Jews and allies]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggb5xi/global_lgbtq_group_suspends_israeli_organization/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/us8SJLrYL7PGPtQwYFaDHhOQorMevNPSLx0_NZB5ryw.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=bd84731710029c00004779ded802f7ddfa6529f0" alt="Global LGBTQ group suspends Israeli organization, angering queer Jews and allies" title="Global LGBTQ group suspends Israeli organization, angering queer Jews and allies" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/walrus_operator"> /u/walrus_operator </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/global-lgbtq-group-suspends-israeli-organization-angering-queer-jews-and-allies/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggb5xi/global_lgbtq_group_suspends_israeli_organization/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggb5xi/global_lgbtq_group_suspends_israeli_organization/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggb5xi/global_lgbtq_group_suspends_israeli_organization/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/walrus_operator]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 10:21:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA['Hamas entered UNRWA and took everything,' Gazan staffer says]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggvagb/hamas_entered_unrwa_and_took_everything_gazan/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/JbtwhFWG1F427FSk_BpMGvF59AI1W9Aau2mWZOrTB6o.jpg?width=320&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=78fd9e33e1917272416a8e427b2e9ba4e6de7cee" alt="'Hamas entered UNRWA and took everything,' Gazan staffer says" title="'Hamas entered UNRWA and took everything,' Gazan staffer says" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Brilliant_User_7673"> /u/Brilliant_User_7673 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.ynetnews.com/article/h1rqvrb11je#autoplay">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggvagb/hamas_entered_unrwa_and_took_everything_gazan/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggvagb/hamas_entered_unrwa_and_took_everything_gazan/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggvagb/hamas_entered_unrwa_and_took_everything_gazan/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Brilliant_User_7673]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 02:16:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Khamenei gives the order to prepare for an attack on Israel, report]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggs4cv/khamenei_gives_the_order_to_prepare_for_an_attack/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/NTtRkd_-BfM7cYRhZZ08qPtL1bgT_MeSYmQd62nsuvM.jpg?width=320&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=e407e64d4f309a52a3a2eb218edcaba23ed6d2d3" alt="Khamenei gives the order to prepare for an attack on Israel, report " title="Khamenei gives the order to prepare for an attack on Israel, report " /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Brilliant_User_7673"> /u/Brilliant_User_7673 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.ynetnews.com/article/bjsaiwwzjl#autoplay">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggs4cv/khamenei_gives_the_order_to_prepare_for_an_attack/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggs4cv/khamenei_gives_the_order_to_prepare_for_an_attack/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggs4cv/khamenei_gives_the_order_to_prepare_for_an_attack/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Brilliant_User_7673]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 23:30:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rocket fire from Lebanon kills 5 in deadliest attack on northern Israel since invasion]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggkn84/rocket_fire_from_lebanon_kills_5_in_deadliest/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/3H7UpY9HtI1JFAyYa7IAPln8PFlX5GBKvvrcDfE_Fw0.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=1c1e6935b4c5e60de66d1d88ffd1d3a594fac98f" alt="Rocket fire from Lebanon kills 5 in deadliest attack on northern Israel since invasion" title="Rocket fire from Lebanon kills 5 in deadliest attack on northern Israel since invasion" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Winterisbucky"> /u/Winterisbucky </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/several-killed-in-rocket-fire-from-lebanon-on-northern-israel/article68817946.ece">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggkn84/rocket_fire_from_lebanon_kills_5_in_deadliest/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggkn84/rocket_fire_from_lebanon_kills_5_in_deadliest/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggkn84/rocket_fire_from_lebanon_kills_5_in_deadliest/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Winterisbucky]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 17:54:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese hackers had access to Canadian government systems for years]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggpjqr/chinese_hackers_had_access_to_canadian_government/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/WcESQgfjgNxkcQFT11Pa_AKM927-LGWI6k8feyZ7bME.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=0ac4548962b2469efee0255c863ce18bbd2f1225" alt="Chinese hackers had access to Canadian government systems for years" title="Chinese hackers had access to Canadian government systems for years" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/QuantumDriveRocket"> /u/QuantumDriveRocket </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.techradar.com/pro/security/chinese-hackers-had-access-to-canadian-government-systems-for-years">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggpjqr/chinese_hackers_had_access_to_canadian_government/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggpjqr/chinese_hackers_had_access_to_canadian_government/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggpjqr/chinese_hackers_had_access_to_canadian_government/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/QuantumDriveRocket]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 21:27:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iran said threatening ‘definitive, painful’ response to Israel, likely before US election]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggqq36/iran_said_threatening_definitive_painful_response/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/0h14BHUWFpzVJUJk5uP8m0vooTcLYLwf_kX_GMiatQM.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=e32a817e3f17132f11014981c2ce28c8dcd6679a" alt="Iran said threatening ‘definitive, painful’ response to Israel, likely before US election" title="Iran said threatening ‘definitive, painful’ response to Israel, likely before US election" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Southern-Jury-4262"> /u/Southern-Jury-4262 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/iran-said-threatening-definitive-painful-response-to-israel-likely-before-us-election/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggqq36/iran_said_threatening_definitive_painful_response/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggqq36/iran_said_threatening_definitive_painful_response/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggqq36/iran_said_threatening_definitive_painful_response/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Southern-Jury-4262]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:21:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia braces for more tax rises to fund the Ukraine war]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggc6vs/russia_braces_for_more_tax_rises_to_fund_the/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/dvG4NNodo76PDbv2867E25hBxhy8HLpBfy0rcA9jzTo.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=d8f550e64d22ceca2e5beb086fe71572dc780690" alt="Russia braces for more tax rises to fund the Ukraine war" title="Russia braces for more tax rises to fund the Ukraine war" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Silly-avocatoe"> /u/Silly-avocatoe </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.straitstimes.com/world/europe/russia-braces-for-more-tax-rises-to-fund-the-ukraine-war">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggc6vs/russia_braces_for_more_tax_rises_to_fund_the/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggc6vs/russia_braces_for_more_tax_rises_to_fund_the/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggc6vs/russia_braces_for_more_tax_rises_to_fund_the/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Silly-avocatoe]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 11:27:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Canada spy agency says India is using cyber tech to track Sikh separatists]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggewv3/canada_spy_agency_says_india_is_using_cyber_tech/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/3sT8ZcNKafTk3whjqNfMNR4i7Fjcmh2MUwN-nZnf2_M.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=a8e48be54dfc3650b9a13cd19ef81f24a830ff7a" alt="Canada spy agency says India is using cyber tech to track Sikh separatists" title="Canada spy agency says India is using cyber tech to track Sikh separatists" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/imgurliam"> /u/imgurliam </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/30/canada-india-sikh-cyber-technology">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggewv3/canada_spy_agency_says_india_is_using_cyber_tech/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggewv3/canada_spy_agency_says_india_is_using_cyber_tech/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1ggewv3/canada_spy_agency_says_india_is_using_cyber_tech/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/imgurliam]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 13:46:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Will strengthen partnership with good friend PM Modi’: Trump's Diwali message to Hindu Americans]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/114831442.cms" />Former President Trump vowed to protect Hindu Americans from the radical left's anti-religion agenda, pledged to strengthen US-India relations, and condemned violence against minorities in Bangladesh. Trump contrasted his administration's policies with those of Biden and Harris, emphasizing economic growth and regulatory reform.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/will-strengthen-partnership-with-great-friend-pm-modi-trumps-diwali-message-to-hindu-americans/articleshow/114831442.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/will-strengthen-partnership-with-great-friend-pm-modi-trumps-diwali-message-to-hindu-americans/articleshow/114831442.cms</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 02:13:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Who is Karthik Naralasetty? Indian-American tech innovator who could be Texas’s youngest mayor]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/114820425.cms" />]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/who-is-karthik-naralasetty-indian-american-tech-innovator-who-could-be-texass-youngest-mayor/articleshow/114820425.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/who-is-karthik-naralasetty-indian-american-tech-innovator-who-could-be-texass-youngest-mayor/articleshow/114820425.cms</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:37:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Russian bomb hits residential building in Ukraine's 2nd largest city, killing 12-year-old boy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/114815325.cms" />Russian forces attacked a residential building in Kharkiv, killing a 12-year-old boy and injuring at least 35 others. The attack utilized a 500-kg glide bomb, part of increased Russian assaults using powerful glide bombs. President Zelenskyy urged the U.S. for long-range American missiles to combat these attacks closely.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/russian-bomb-hits-residential-building-in-ukraines-2nd-largest-city-killing-12-year-old-boy/articleshow/114815325.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/russian-bomb-hits-residential-building-in-ukraines-2nd-largest-city-killing-12-year-old-boy/articleshow/114815325.cms</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 10:16:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA['If they want to stop ...': New Hezbollah chief open to truce with Israel if offer is made]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/114813606.cms" />Hezbollah's new leader, Naim Qassem, signaled willingness for a ceasefire with Israel, demanding specific conditions. Negotiations include Israel's call for Hezbollah's withdrawal and Lebanese army deployment along the border. Lebanon and Israeli officials express cautious optimism, while US diplomatic efforts continue amid ongoing conflict in Lebanon and Gaza, generating significant casualties.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/if-they-want-to-stop-new-hezbollah-chief-open-to-truce-with-israel-if-offer-is-made/articleshow/114813606.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/if-they-want-to-stop-new-hezbollah-chief-open-to-truce-with-israel-if-offer-is-made/articleshow/114813606.cms</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 09:30:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea conducts ICBM test to boost nuclear deterrent, US slams move]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/114804961.cms" />North Korea tested a new intercontinental ballistic missile under Kim Jong Un's orders, aiming to showcase its military power. The US, Japan, and South Korea condemned the launch as destabilizing. Officials are concerned about North Korea's emerging solid-fueled missile technology and potential military involvement in the Ukraine conflict.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/north-korea-conducts-icbm-test-to-boost-nuclear-deterrent-us-slams-move/articleshow/114804961.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/north-korea-conducts-icbm-test-to-boost-nuclear-deterrent-us-slams-move/articleshow/114804961.cms</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 05:21:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese company wins contract to print Nepal's new notes with revised map including Indian regions]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/114792142.cms" />Nepal Rastra Bank awarded a contract to a Chinese company to print new 100-rupee notes featuring Nepal's revised political map, including Indian territories. The Chinese firm will print and supply 300 million notes at a cost of $8.99 million. The updated map has strained India-Nepal relations since 2020.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/south-asia/china-company-wins-deal-to-print-new-nepal-notes-with-map-including-indian-areas/articleshow/114792142.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/south-asia/china-company-wins-deal-to-print-new-nepal-notes-with-map-including-indian-areas/articleshow/114792142.cms</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 21:11:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea fires long-range missile with potential to reach US mainland]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/114799323.cms" />North Korea launched a new long-range missile, reaching a range of over 7,000 km, causing reactions from the US, Japan, and South Korea. This test heightens tensions amid reports of North Korea's rising cooperation with Russia. US national security condemned the launch and suggested potential military drills in response. Concerns grow over North Korea's advancing missile capabilities.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/north-korea-fires-long-range-missile-with-potential-to-reach-us-mainland/articleshow/114799323.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/north-korea-fires-long-range-missile-with-potential-to-reach-us-mainland/articleshow/114799323.cms</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 02:13:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel demands resignation of UN expert Francesca Albanese over 'genocidal campaign against Palestinians' remark]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/114799057.cms" />Israel has demanded the resignation of UN expert Francesca Albanese after she accused Israel of carrying out a genocidal campaign against Palestinians. Israeli officials have labeled her remarks as anti-Semitic and a distortion of the law. Albanese defended her statements, highlighting the risk of Palestinians being eradicated from their land.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/israel-demands-resignation-of-un-expert-francesca-albanese-over-genocidal-campaign-against-palestinians-remark/articleshow/114799057.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/israel-demands-resignation-of-un-expert-francesca-albanese-over-genocidal-campaign-against-palestinians-remark/articleshow/114799057.cms</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 02:03:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UN: Must probe all deaths during Bangladesh uprising]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/114798121.cms" />UN human rights chief Volker Turk urges investigations into recent killings in Bangladesh and stresses the importance of freedom of assembly, expression, and political participation. Turk highlights the need for accountability for attacks on minorities, emphasizing that thorough investigations are crucial for building trust and social cohesion.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/south-asia/un-must-probe-all-deaths-during-bangladesh-uprising/articleshow/114798121.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/south-asia/un-must-probe-all-deaths-during-bangladesh-uprising/articleshow/114798121.cms</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:55:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US eyes 60-day Lebanon truce even as Israel bombs key city]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/114798110.cms" />US mediators are pushing for ceasefires in Lebanon and Gaza during Biden's final months. Key proposals include Israeli forces withdrawing from Lebanon for a ceasefire with Hezbollah, and a four-week ceasefire in Gaza with Hamas releasing hostages. However, deep distrust among parties remains a hurdle.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/us-eyes-60-day-lebanon-truce-even-as-israel-bombs-key-city/articleshow/114798110.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/us-eyes-60-day-lebanon-truce-even-as-israel-bombs-key-city/articleshow/114798110.cms</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:54:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Canada alleges Indian minister behind plot to target Sikh separatists]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary committee told of Narendra Modi ally’s alleged role in campaign of violence and threats</p><p>The Canadian government has publicly alleged that India’s home affairs minister, Amit Shah, the prime minister, Narendra Modi’s, closest political ally, was behind a recent series of plots to murder and intimidate Sikh separatists on Canadian soil.</p><p>Testifying before a parliamentary committee, the Canadian deputy foreign affairs minister, David Morrison, acknowledged he had leaked information to the Washington Post about Shah’s alleged role in a campaign of violence and threats against the Sikh diaspora over the last few years.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/30/canada-alleges-indian-minister-amit-shah-plot-to-target-sikh-separatists">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/30/canada-alleges-indian-minister-amit-shah-plot-to-target-sikh-separatists</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/30/canada-alleges-indian-minister-amit-shah-plot-to-target-sikh-separatists</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 10:37:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How will the outcome of the US election affect Australia, Aukus and our region?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Australia’s future is closely tied to the future occupant of the White House. What impacts could a Kamala Harris or Donald Trump presidency have?</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2024/nov/01/australia-news-live-qld-election-cabinet-sworn-in-business-cost-of-living-house-prices-power-bills">Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates</a></li><li>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl">breaking news email</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></li></ul><p>More people have gone to a ballot box in 2024 than in any other year in human history. Billions have cast votes across scores of countries, including some of the largest, most powerful democracies on Earth.</p><p>But America’s remains the world’s global election, the most forensically examined, the most consequential all over the world. America matters.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed">Sign up for Guardian Australia’s breaking news email</a></strong></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/01/us-election-2024-result-trump-harris-presidency-australia-impact">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/01/us-election-2024-result-trump-harris-presidency-australia-impact</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/01/us-election-2024-result-trump-harris-presidency-australia-impact</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:00:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea missile test reaches record height and duration, says Japan]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Test of apparent ICBM theoretically capable of striking US mainland comes amid warnings over North Korean troops in Ukraine</p><p>North Korea has test launched a long-range missile theoretically capable of striking the US mainland in another display of defiance by the regime amid growing <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/30/north-korea-troops-russia-kursk-ukraine-lloyd-austin">warnings</a> over its troops’ participation in the war in Ukraine.</p><p>US officials said they believed Thursday’s launch was that of an intercontinental ballistic missile [ICBM] but did not say how they had reached that assessment. Japan’s defence minister, Gen Nakatani, said the missile had flown higher and for longer than others tested by North Korea.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/north-korea-missile-test-record-height-icbm-japan">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/north-korea-missile-test-record-height-icbm-japan</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/north-korea-missile-test-record-height-icbm-japan</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 10:02:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Corruption referral for senior Victoria police officer Neil Paterson over alleged school road rage incident]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Deputy commissioner referred to Ibac over potential misuse of position in school traffic argument</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2024/nov/01/australia-news-live-qld-election-cabinet-sworn-in-business-cost-of-living-house-prices-power-bills">Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates</a></li><li>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl">breaking news email</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></li></ul><p>A senior police officer has been referred to Victoria’s anti-corruption watchdog over an alleged road rage incident outside a school.</p><p>Victoria police on Friday confirmed it had referred deputy commissioner Neil Paterson to the state’s Independent Broad-based Anti-corruption Commission (Ibac) over an incident at a Melbourne school in July.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/nov/01/neil-paterson-victoria-police-deputy-commissioner-ibac-referral-ntwnfb">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/nov/01/neil-paterson-victoria-police-deputy-commissioner-ibac-referral-ntwnfb</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/nov/01/neil-paterson-victoria-police-deputy-commissioner-ibac-referral-ntwnfb</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 01:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Final recount confirms Georgia ruling party victory, says electoral commission]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>EU and US demand investigation as opposition and pro-European president cry foul  </p><p>Officials in Georgia said a partial recount confirmed <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/27/georgia-election-calls-for-protests-as-ruling-pro-russia-party-declared-winner">the ruling party had won its disputed election</a>, while a global research and data firm called the official results reported by the electoral commission “statistically impossible”.</p><p>The pro-western opposition on Thursday repeated its earlier assertions that the parliamentary vote had been “stolen” by the ruling Georgian Dream party and it refused to recognise the results, plunging the Caucasus country into uncertainty.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/georgia-election-final-recount-ruling-party-victory-electoral-commission">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/georgia-election-final-recount-ruling-party-victory-electoral-commission</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/georgia-election-final-recount-ruling-party-victory-electoral-commission</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 17:12:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US says Lebanon ceasefire talks making ‘good progress’ – as it happened]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>US secretary of state and defence secretary express hope of ceasefire in near future as Hamas rules out short-term truce for Gaza</p><p>Reuters reports that the<strong> Israeli</strong> military said on Thursday it had shot down a drone smuggling weapons from <strong>Egyptian</strong> territory to Israel on Wednesday.</p><p>No other information was provided. We will update the blog as more details come in.</p><p>Rafael and Lala Goliev … residents of Lod, were arrested after they carried out tasks on behalf of an Iranian cell that recruits Israelis from the Caucasus countries in Israel.”</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/31/middle-east-lebanon-israel-gaza-war-hezbollah-hamas">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/31/middle-east-lebanon-israel-gaza-war-hezbollah-hamas</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/31/middle-east-lebanon-israel-gaza-war-hezbollah-hamas</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:30:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UN should consider suspending Israel over ‘genocide’ against Palestinians, says special rapporteur]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Francesca Albanese, who was stopped from appearing at US Congress this week, said Israel defied UN resolutions</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/31/middle-east-lebanon-israel-gaza-war-hezbollah-hamas">Middle East crisis – live updates</a></li></ul><p>The UN should consider suspending Israel as a member state due to its continuing “genocide” against the Palestinians, the divisive special rapporteur on the Palestinian territories has said.</p><p>Francesca Albanese was speaking to a UN committee on the inalienable rights of the Palestinian people in New York the day after she published her latest report alleging that Israel was not just committing war crimes or crimes against humanity in Gaza, but a genocide.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/un-should-consider-suspending-israel-over-genocide-against-palestinians-says-special-rapporteur">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/un-should-consider-suspending-israel-over-genocide-against-palestinians-says-special-rapporteur</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/un-should-consider-suspending-israel-over-genocide-against-palestinians-says-special-rapporteur</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:20:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US attempts to broker ceasefire as civilians killed in Lebanon and Israel]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>IDF airstrikes kill 45 people while seven die, including four Thai workers, in rocket attack on northern Israel</p><p>Senior US officials have held talks in Israel aimed at brokering a ceasefire with Hezbollah in Lebanon, on a day when more civilians in both countries were killed in the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/25/israel-lebanon-strikes-beirut-us-ceasefire">year-long war</a>.</p><p>Lebanon’s caretaker prime minister, Najib Mikati, who had expressed optimism of a speedy settlement “in hours or days” earlier on Thursday, said that Israel’s “ongoing escalation” in his country “does not inspire optimism”.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/us-attempts-to-broker-ceasefire-as-civilians-killed-in-lebanon-and-israel">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/us-attempts-to-broker-ceasefire-as-civilians-killed-in-lebanon-and-israel</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/31/us-attempts-to-broker-ceasefire-as-civilians-killed-in-lebanon-and-israel</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 17:48:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia World Cup bid report accused of ‘whitewashing’ rights abuses]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Law firm AS&amp;H Clifford Chance failed to include alleged abuse of migrant workers in assessment for Fifa 2034 bid, say rights groups</p><p>A report by the Saudi arm of a global law firm on Saudi Arabia’s 2034 Fifa World Cup bid has “whitewashed” the Gulf kingdom’s record of exploiting and suppressing the rights of migrant workers, rights groups have claimed.</p><p>AS&amp;H Clifford Chance was commissioned to independently assess the human rights implications of the bid, but the report “contains no substantive discussion of extensive and relevant abuses in Saudi Arabia”, <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2024/10/saudi-arabia-fifa-organizations-demand-a-credible-human-rights-assessment-for-2034-world-cup-bid/">according to a statement</a> released by 11 organisations, including Amnesty International and Human Rights Watch.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2024/oct/31/saudi-arabia-football-world-cup-bid-report-asandh-clifford-chance-fifa-2034-rights-groups">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2024/oct/31/saudi-arabia-football-world-cup-bid-report-asandh-clifford-chance-fifa-2034-rights-groups</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2024/oct/31/saudi-arabia-football-world-cup-bid-report-asandh-clifford-chance-fifa-2034-rights-groups</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 10:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Middle East crisis: UN security council warns against attempts to dismantle Unrwa – as it happened]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This live blog is now closed. For the latest on the Middle East, read our full coverage <strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/middleeast">here</a></strong>. </p><p>Under the laws – which will not be implemented for several months – <strong>Unrwa</strong> could not “operate any institution, provide any service, or conduct any activity, whether directly or indirectly”.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/30/middle-east-israel-gaza-lebanon-hamas-hezbollah">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/30/middle-east-israel-gaza-lebanon-hamas-hezbollah</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/30/middle-east-israel-gaza-lebanon-hamas-hezbollah</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 19:22:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US identified 500 cases where its weapons harmed Gaza civilians but hasn’t taken action]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Some the incidents might have violated international humanitarian law, according to the sources</p><p>US state department officials have identified nearly 500 potential incidents of civilian harm during <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/israel">Israel’s</a> military operations in <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gaza">Gaza</a> involving US-furnished weapons, but have not taken further action on any of them, according to three sources, including a US official familiar with the matter.</p><p>The incidents – some of which may have violated international humanitarian law, according to the sources – have been recorded since 7 October 2023, when the Gaza war started. They are being collected by the state department’s Civilian Harm Incident Response Guidance (CHIRG), a formal mechanism for tracking and assessing any reported misuse of US-origin weapons.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/30/civilian-harm-us-weapons-israel-gaza-war">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/30/civilian-harm-us-weapons-israel-gaza-war</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/30/civilian-harm-us-weapons-israel-gaza-war</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 18:55:23 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>